late now we're very happy to present to
Jeremy Zimmerman here with his hacking
with care and making tradition keynote
let's give a round of applause to Jeremy
[Applause]
thanks so much Alex
thanks everyone for being here it's such
a pleasure it's such an honor to be here
it's such a beautiful beautiful camp we
should all be immensely proud of this
and again thanks to to to everyone who
put it together and thanks for the
invitation it's a real honor I'm Jeremy
oh hi some of you may know me from a
previous life where I used two different
freedoms online with a tiny organization
I founded called la quadrature du net
that was before that was some some years
ago I spent roughly 10 years doing this
kind of things and I I burnt out and in
the in the process actually before I
completely hurt myself already started
this idea of a project that is called
hacking with care that I want to tell
you a little bit about but before that
and almost instead of that because it's
actually so important
I wanted to well to open an avenue for
discussion and actually to ask you some
some questions to ask ourselves some
questions about this make tradition
thing that you've seen on the on the
logo of bone hack it um it it asked me
questions when I read it for the first
time at first I was a bit uncomfortable
with that because you know tradition
usually is associated with the religious
or cultural secular things that some of
us may not be comfortable with then I
wondered if it was a joke if it was like
the make comment in comment line but
figured that there's an uppercase M M so
it cannot be so I wanted to try and
understand this and and and see how how
far we can go with that what is it we we
make
what is it we we hack really I've been
doing this this political activism as I
told you for about ten years I've run
the LA's of the the parliaments in
France and in Europe I've done all the
entertainment thing on TV and bla bla
bla and written hundreds of fresh three
diseases sometimes sometimes I'm the
very same subject some of you are
familiar with these processes we we run
into some some tactics we think are
efficient at the given time we put all
our heart or all our passion in trying
to make things change in this world
but in the end what we are trying to do
is to is to hack reality is to hack do
the world around us or or ultimate
objective a common goal I think is to to
hack the future really and I think this
is what we are doing whether we like it
or not when we invent ourselves when we
reinvent ourselves when we invent those
spaces around ourselves like we are
doing it right now
I think hacking the future is this is
what's at stake and that it requires to
take a little bit of a break a little
bit of a pause like maybe a little bit
of a step backwards a little bit of
distance and and question ourselves
question our current realities question
or habits question or movements in the
end we all know we want a better world
we all know we want to be part of
changing it but you know this is the
certain old question what what we what
would we do with freedom anyway we very
rarely ask ourselves those questions so
I'm I think we are using this time here
to to ask ourselves this question and I
just wanted to put this on the table so
we can maybe discuss it think about it
together or also later on you're very
welcome to join us at the bar we're with
amazing Sarah from the fantastic a
foundation we'll be throwing some very
special cocktails but I'll get back to
this later I want this to be an open
thread for discussion
because this is in the end what we do we
make tradition we invent what will be
our own traditions in a nearby future
and maybe these traditions we will also
be transmitted we share will be shared
over this is actually what defines
tradition is that it is our maybe you
can call them patterns or values it's a
bit of an ambiguous terms but those
items that that stay over time that we
transmit somehow cultural resilience we
build when we make tradition we hope to
that the values we carry around with us
are so important or so how to to deny
also beneficial to people around that
they will become resilient that they
will be transmitted over and so we know
that the objective is to change the
world we know that we have what it takes
to invent a future well where do we
start I've been privileged to survive
this burnout somehow to organize my life
to to reconfigure my life and and reboot
after a bad crash it's a very it's a
privilege really I got some some state
money and employment money to help me do
this but I know for a fact I've been the
head in the tunnel for years that's
asking these kind of questions for
oneself well yeah
requires a bit of an effort so what I'm
what I'm bringing here is mostly
elements that I collected around that I
may be found out for myself and that I
invite you to consider trying to think
of definitions for ourselves
it's never easy it's never easy for
oneself as an individual but sometimes
even less easy when we are trying to
define what are the parameters of our
communities or villages or movements we
are defined by our tools but this is of
use to us you know what
throw we use what laptop have VI versus
Emacs and this kind of things that's a
very easy thing for us to understand we
defined by our tools but also our tools
define us look at us getting in in those
positions looking like losers on on to
ourselves with your shoulders bent
rather than looking like winners you
know with or torsos ahead the the fact
that we are using these devices all they
turn us into something else alter the
shape of a very body alters the
functioning of a muscles of our bones so
that's the most obvious part what define
us all tools great where hacker people
we're not surprised by this also our
environment is a great deal in defining
us it takes sometimes before you admit
this you remember when you were teenager
your genius you understood everything no
one has anything to bring to you because
it's all out there and someday oops
usually you crash against reality and
you figure that well what's around you
what's behind you is as much part of
what you are then what you thought was
so so great about yourself our
environment is always a culture to is
what has been transmitted by people
around therefore and I guess that if you
take an anthropologist view on this or
sociologist view you'd have different
answers to that but weather or culture
or address or relationships are part of
defining us is a question that is that
is also open the way we interact with
each other who we interact with again
through which tools but also at every
level how do we connect to other to
other people so very often we look at
these parameters without really
questioning them we accept implicitly
you know we create associations fine
because this is what exists or we create
companies
we create social groups that are very
often modeled after existing structures
we borrow patterns that pre-existed us
so maybe one way of thinking a way to
make tradition and to make this
according to to what we fundamentally
believe into would be to try and
reinvent some of these patterns whether
they're environmental cultural or
concern or relationship but another of
these of these parameters that define us
is a very bodies and that's something
again that may sound very obvious to all
of you but quick survey here who among
you ever had let's say some chronic
pains either in the neck or the
shoulders or the arms or the hands from
using computers or tool yeah that's a
vast majority close to the whole room
here who practices regular physical
exercise oh that's that's so radio
that's I would say half the room I think
that's way more than your average nerd
crowd I I don't I try but I don't really
so that's something that is obvious to
many people but that is not really
obvious to at least some of us at least
half of the of the crowd here from the
quick quick survey we know these things
we know physical exercise is good for us
right but it's not necessarily part of a
culture it's not part of the patterns we
used to grow up with or through which we
organized ourselves so I'm not trying to
to convince you into some athletic
movement of some sort the point is not
that we go and run in the woods after
this session but I want also to open
reflection and you see me coming with
that point about hacking with care if
you heard of it before is that we are
equally defined by your bodies and the
shape of our bodies and how our bodies
feel and react on a given time as we are
by our relationships by our culture
by our environment and bio tools so all
these are patterns that are open for us
to hack all these are avenues all these
are objects that we have somehow in
front of us to try and fiddle with to
try and change yourselves to try and
change things around us and eventually
to change the world and make tradition
so hacking with care some of you may
have heard of it before it's a very
loose collective it's born really from
the encounter of my dear friend Emily
and I when I met Emily she she happened
to be a massage practitioner massage
artist she's she's teaching massage in
massage schools she's mixing lots of
different techniques together and when I
met her I figured I knew as little about
massage as she knew at the time about
cryptography since a few years that we
know each other I learned a lot about
massage and she learned a lot about
cryptography and this is what happens
spontaneously in between ourselves and
this is also what emerge from the very
first day we met together she thought
that she wanted to contribute to our
movements
she was very familiar with with the work
of WikiLeaks for instance and some of
the struggles that were going on in the
world at the time we met she wanted to
support all movements but what she knew
was massage so she wanted to support us
while contributing massage to the cause
and and by speaking about this and
myself being in this advanced state of a
burnout already where I
I forgot how to sleep I was constantly
in an airplane would constantly with a
warm device against my head you may know
this states of being and she helped me
with the massage and well my heartbeat
and my breathing were the lowest they
were in years I I for a few minutes I
found myself very much centered on
myself like nothing else around was
[Music]
mattering and I fell asleep and it felt
really really good and so you meet him
immediately so house
a very simple air-quote act of giving
somebody a massage could at a given
moment on the trajectory of somebody
where the time was a self-defined
activist could really change a lot could
really contribute so the idea we had is
to aggregate a joyful bunch of people
who share this common interest in mind
we want to collect and package those
technologies of care that we understand
as a really a way to to hack the bodies
and the souls care as a kindness care as
some shared goodness the act of sharing
something good with somebody else at a
given moment we want to build a common
understanding of some of these
technologies and we want also to to hack
them we want to hack care therefore we
want to hack with care we want to bring
these technologies to to people like us
- to hackers to activists - to people
who are otherwise born in front of a
computer and do not practice regular
exercise that's a bit of a cliche but
most importantly we want to bring these
technologies these tools to people we
fear are particularly exposed to sets of
pressure that are very rarely met we
have people around us who are exposed to
direct pressure by government agencies
by companies by other well State or
non-state actors we know some
journalists some sources some activists
people in countries where if the police
catch you well they just beat you up and
and people whose life are otherwise
exposed and we feel that these are the
people who may need that first who may
need that even more that some other
among us but what we figured is that if
we want more people willing to share
these tools to share these technologies
with such exposed individuals well we
need them the caregivers to understand a
few things for instance about
operational security
we need massage practitioners yoga
teachers Chinese medicine and other
caregivers to understand that sometimes
you just remove the battery from your
phone or do not take the phone at all
that sometimes you do not take notes on
a computer that some communications must
be encrypted and to end so the idea of
hacking with care is to explore both
sides of this coin to bring care to
hackers and activists and also the other
side be bringing hacker tools and hacker
ethics to the caregivers and caregiver
community understood again as a very
large concept so in order a full bunch
on the mailing list where I think we
must be between 80 and 100 we have
massage practitioners you get
practitioners psychotherapists motion
therapists clinical practitioners I
think we have some pediatric nurses and
other other medical personnel as well as
a bunch of activists hackers and people
concerned by the more political or
technological part of it all so the
point to me is that care is not only a
long-term strategy for movements and for
communities whatever we understand by
this
whatever we understand by this whoever
we are whatever social environment we
are part of care is a strategic
objective we want people to go as little
sad depressed burnout or otherwise not
feel good as we can we need to be able
to share a common understanding of what
happens when this happens we need to be
able to detect when people don't feel
well
the same way as we need
to have a clue on how to to enable them
or how to to contribute to have them
feel better of course it doesn't mean
that we will start doing brain surgery
some of these skills some of these
technologies are of course to be
mastered only by trained practitioner I
don't pretend like I'm trained in
anything that I'm not of course we are
not that close to build or open hardware
electromagnetic resonance scan or such
complex equipment that you only find in
hospitals and the point is not to oppose
some rosy hippie plant-based vision of
the world to the traditional Western
chemical based medicine but a lot of
these technologies are our secular are
very well documented and are sometimes
very easy to to package to share and to
and to use around so care as an as a
strategic objective but also care as a
tactics and this is what interests me
the most as a former activist as a
burnt-out activist care as a package
tactical tool I could well you could go
and take a look at the wiki of hacking
with care for those looking at the
stream its hacking with care dot iron
slash wiki or something like this on the
wiki you'll find quite a lot of
resources that will give you an idea of
what I mean by packaging these care
technologies I can't help but read one
of these documents to you because it's
one of my favorite and it will also give
you a sense on how we're trying to do
these things of course as I told you we
don't pretend like we know things we
don't so we use this humble approach
somehow do the hacker approach to do
things as open as we can be open to
acknowledging your mistakes and
improving upon them so we define one
document it's a one one pager sorry I'll
be reading it's always a bit leaner I'll
try to make it quick it's called a few
words on ethical conduct in massage
first point always observe the
precautions and contraindications
consult the massage precautions and
contraindications sign that's another
document we have second respect each
other
no discriminative up rigidly speech
attitude or behavior no violence
harassment coercion is ever appropriate
you notice that we don't impose rules
here
next in observe hygiene and safety rules
wash your hands before and after each
session use disposable paper covers or
clean towels protect the table cushion
closes work in a safe clean ventilated
space use only good quality products
next be transparent and honest about
your actual qualifications in caregiving
do not pretend to have skills or
knowledge you don't have and attentive
amateur can accomplish a great deal
already so no need to brag next do not
give a massage to someone who is not
quite sure they want one here like in
love it has to be an uppercase bald yes
from the beginning to the end
anyone can decide to stop whenever they
want respect physical reserves no one
has to take their clothes off for
massage if they don't want to very good
messages can be provided with clothes on
similarly if you the giver a not
comfortable with nudity you should say
so next because massages induce
relaxation of the nervous system it can
sometimes trigger erection or reaction
similar to those of sexual arousal in
both men and women it's not so frequent
that you should worry about it and
besides it is really nothing to be
ashamed of the masseur massage should
bear in mind that however sexual in
appearance these reactions might not be
experienced as such by the receiver and
so they should never be considered as an
invitation to act on them they can be
sometimes surprising emotional release
during massage or other forms of case of
care sorry please familiarize yourself
with this possibility reading or article
emotional release during massage what's
happening and how best to respond stay
calm composed kind we especially worry
and mindful of the possibility of
personal information being revealed to
you in that moment do not encourage
words or let the person tell you too
much about themselves if necessary let
them know that your reluctance to hear
more is for their own good next discuss
privacy settings with your partner prior
to the session what would they be
comfortable with
you talk about this message later to
someone else the default privacy setting
in messages whatever happens in a
massive room stays in the message room
period don't mention to others that you
have given a massage to that someone and
next and final point massage for
children only in presence of the
apparent adult tutor no one-to-one
sessions so you've probably recognized
here some of the of the patterns or for
very own accurate ethos and the way we
organize things on wikis by being humble
by declaring openly what we know and
what we don't know so that's the way we
we're trying to do it and on this wiki
you will find such other resources such
as for instance the hand massage guide
the handshake we call it as an obvious
reference to the handshaking the
protocols of the of the Internet
it's a guide package a bit like a manual
with beautiful hand-drawn illustrations
that you can use in five minutes
in ten minutes in half an hour to just
make a present to your neighbor whether
you're in an office in a super stressful
situation because you're trying to save
the world and maybe it's the coffee
break or after the lunch break whether
you're in a train or in a plane maybe
getting getting tense preparing for some
event or some presentation whether it's
in a bar late at night on a dance floor
you can give your friend your colleague
your peer a hand massage that is
extremely relaxing that would
considerably alleviate the stress
chronicle pain in the hands wrists and
fingers that you get from so much
keyboard and overall you'll notice that
it's a very different way of being in
contact with somebody you know already
it's some form of intimacy somehow it's
some form of direct physical contact we
are all I even in Scandinavia where I
think it's even less of a thing but
something that is usually not a thing in
our communities and you'll found out
that just transmitting some strength
transmitting some energy in a very
peer-to-peer way from hand to hand
literally is
something of great power and of great
impact
we also have a similar resources on our
wiki a premenstrual massage a full-body
massage to alleviate the pain of the
demonstration we also have in the in the
becoming this monkey mind head massage
I invite you maybe tomorrow to to ask me
more about the monkey mind massage or
later on at the bar while I'm showing
delicious cocktails such as the monkey
mind cocktail maybe it's a delicious
head massage I had no idea you could do
so much with massage of a heads it helps
calm people down when they when they get
anxiety or even panic attacks it can
help people go to sleep when they can't
in some cases it can even alleviate some
of the strongest migraines I've heard
about and it's not about any medical
claims you know of curing anything all
just the power of taking care of
somebody's skull and scalp in between
your hands for a few minutes is again
something I wish all of you have the
chance to experience sometimes and again
I can tell you more about this
so we could we could go on we could go
on forever with going through the wiki
maybe you'll do this some times later
maybe we talked about it around the
cocktails such as the monkey mind or the
contagious courage or maybe you'll want
to indulge yourself with one Chelsey's
kiss but again we'll talk about this
later
what I wanted to to bring here also
beyond the practical aspects of hacking
with care of course you can join of
course we want more people to contribute
in any ways to to what we do of course
there is a mailing list and and you're
very welcome to join it
but beyond that what I learned through
this development of hacking with care
and from my past in previous experience
with quite a number of movements and
organizations and and and social
structures
sorry are those reflections about the
movements themselves with hacking with
care we're having a reflection about
technology
I mean hacking massage hacking yoga
hiking meditation who would have thought
but again who would have thought 10 or
15 years ago that we would be hacking
hardware and doing our own circuits like
those beautiful badges who thought we
would be end up hacking food together
like what's happening over there or the
food hacking base at the congresses and
camps who thought we would be hacking
even plastic with our 3d printers so
it's not the first time that we
surprised ourselves with oh wow there's
a whole new technology here we can take
on an hack so we have this reflection
and the technology and the nature of
technology is very low-tech technology
that is pressure bones and muscles and
and a few other tissues but also we we
we have this reflection about the the
formats and the way we organize
ourselves for years I was running till
he was answering the phone I had one day
with 71 incoming phone calls most of
them interviews and a few days with more
than 50 incoming phone calls during my
activist life I was really really in the
tunnel so with hacking with care we
decided we will completely emancipate
ourselves from the traditional formats
sure we join some events that have been
organized before and we are very happy
to be part of it but more importantly we
will organize our own events or own
sessions on moments or on spaces in in
space and time we've done that once in
Berlin in the sea bass with or hacking
with care sessions we've done that many
times and many one-to-one encounters or
small group encounters last week at this
fantastic micro festival to change we
organize the monkey mind head massage
session where I trained nine people to
give themselves a monkey mind massage to
nine other people so we want to have as
open as possible as in as a palette to
invent ourselves in terms of
that's what I what is so refreshing to
me is that we're not running after time
it's been now I think almost four years
four years that we in cept it hacking
with care and if you look at it if you
try to put this in numbers you know in
figures don't look at the budget and the
number of employees well it's zero
basically so one would say oh it's it's
not a success because there you have no
numbers that are growing but on the
contrary it's not a bug it's a feature
we we we grow this on a very slow very
steady rhythm that is all rhythm that is
the rhythm of humans taking time to
think and be together for me this is
something completely new it's not a
bloody Parliament or journalists who
decide when it's time to do something
it's or common mood shared overtime that
we take time to to to interpret to
listen at and to me that's something
also very refreshing we invent all time
and we invent all space to make this
happen I've been I've been speaking for
too long already I'll try to make a
final point here is that we make
tradition we hug the world we hack
reality and everything is possible to us
the science fiction we read when we were
kids is somehow already reality today so
what is what is left to dream about what
is left to invent what science fiction
can we write today that may possibly
become the world of tomorrow so we have
this clear line of a dystopian future I
mean it's not even cool you know it's
not even it's not even in the books it's
a reality it's now called video
protection we have these drones that
will be autonomous soon all these
devices are tuned to the bone there is
not much left to to write under the
field of dystopian science fiction these
days it seems because we we are doing it
so what what science fiction shall we
write for the future how do we want to
define the world we want to make happen
is this fundamental question that we
must
take the time to discuss we want a world
in which we will be free as liberal to
use the technology we we want to share
the knowledge we want to not be afraid
to speak to not self-censor we want to
be free as Leoben we want to a world to
be decentralized we want to
communications and our data to be
decentralized but we also want power to
be decentralized
we want our social structures to be
decentralized we want as many small
camps as possible and you guys should
come to camp plus plus
by the way in Hungary we want as many
small camps as possible rather than
those big enormous ones except the one
of the CSA which is yeah but but in
theory we want as many small camps as
possible we also want the mathematics
and other forces of nature to provide us
the comfort of expressing ourselves of
being who we are of trusting each other
we need mathematics and trust in some
machines to be in our hands and I think
there is very few chances that we could
ever achieve that if it is by
propagating the the reflexes the
structures and the patterns from the
past traditions it has to be based on
reflections on our very own lives on our
very own movements that we will embed
those values not only in the way we we
collectively create and handle resources
not only in the way we will collectively
handle infrastructure together whether
the real power lies today but also in
the way we we will look at each other
and organize those solidarities that at
the end of the day are what is really
left when the structures and the
movements
are gone when we make tradition this
tradition is in between ourselves what
matters is the links between ourselves
whatever the label whatever the the name
of the structure we want to put around
and so here we are living in this
dystopian world of the science fiction
of our young ages with the tremendous
opportunity to write our own science
fiction for world that wouldn't be
dystopian for a world where or values
and our ethos will be at the at the
heart of everything we do and my deepest
conviction is that this can only be made
through love through joy through care
and and through the the immense power
that brings the sharing of all of this
together I think you all and let's
discuss this further yes so I I want to
hear you about this I these are
questions that I mostly send you and I
yeah it's your turn now
[Applause]
do we have any questions for Jeremy it
can be questions comments trolls
shameless advertisements songs answers
yeah no Jerry I mean I know you're a
front-runner and four pertains let me
just say that the people at a nice
things think tank has been inspired by
you and your work in France right so it
will be interesting in three years if
everybody is doing massage to each other
but it it just seems sort of weird yeah
but I know you're front-runner so who
knows maybe you're right but my question
is actually about the mental health
because what has heaven in Denmark the
last column years is that the white hat
hackers have reported companies and then
cut the report to the police
instead of saying thank you for your
help
right and that that keeps a lot of
mental stress do you have anything good
to say about that oh wow anything good I
don't know but anything to say yes for
sure
first of all yes thanks thanks so much
for this diss comments and and yes it's
about an attempt a shameless attempt at
hacking ourselves and all culture but
somehow you may have noticed that we're
already doing it you've been to Congress
you know this tea house that used to be
on the fourth floor of this building
that doesn't exist anymore who would
have thought when HM happened four years
ago we thought let's come and build
something nice that contribute to the to
the infrastructure and I had this stupid
idea a tea house like one I've seen in
some desert some day and people none
explained the thing around okay why not
and we went there and worked our ass off
and and everybody liked it from day zero
and we figured that there was so little
laptops here that people remove their
shoes and were comfortable you know
being in contact with each other people
who were at
chanting a lot you know very beautiful
energy and vibration emerge from that so
the tea house and hacking with care
emerged exactly at the same time it's
hard to say if the tea house is a
project from hacking with care or if
they but that's that's a part of a hack
that worked wonderfully there was a tea
house at every Congress since then I
brought one to chem plus plus I brought
one to change if I find a cargo next
year I will maybe bring one here to the
island you know and who would have
thought again five years ago that
hackers would hack tea and and sit down
around on the floor run run tables and
have a good time chatting not through
computers I mean to you a question about
mental health of course of course it is
an enormous area that we are interested
in to hear like on the rest there is
some empirical knowledge that is
abundantly documented there is some
knowledge you can only acquire by being
a practitioner and having years of
practice so we don't try to overstep or
our competencies here there's a few
pages on the wiki with resources on
mental health some very concrete guides
that have been written by some activist
communities here and there you have lots
of LGBT groups who produced material on
this lots of people in Latin America in
some remote rural areas so some of these
documentation is there already what
we've done so far at the hacking Wistia
sessions we had I'm a I'm a
psychotherapist ask me anything session
and as a way to bring or occur efforts
to do the thing we thought we would
anonymize the communications on this so
we had this box and his post it and
people would write questions and put
them in the box so they wouldn't be
embarrassed to speak them loud so we
could then read the question and ask
them to a practitioner and was one of
the most interesting discussions ever
because of course some of these
questions were personal but so many of
these cases resonated among each other
because we all knew of some cases you
know oh what was when you don't want to
wake up in the morning you know what
when somebody doesn't want any help
and answers very grave questions well at
least this time it happened that we
could also hack this together hack the
knowledge out of this practitioner and
turn needed to precise concrete pieces
of advice dude another very concrete
item was this workshop called hack
anxiety where breathing exercises that
you some somehow force on somebody's
chest and belly and you would hack the
breathing together and make them come
down from a panic attack
I've practice that unfortunately a
couple of times and it's it's it just
works you know so maybe we'll turn that
into video maybe we'll turn that into a
guide it will depend on all the energies
and resources we have in the future but
of course it's a major area of research
I mean look at how many people around us
are getting you know depressed or
anxious or all burnouts it's I think
it's particularly vivid you know in our
communities where lots of introvert
people are under tremendous amounts of
pressure cool do we have additional
questions we have one over there in the
meantime maybe I can use the well the
time you walk with the microphone to to
mention that we will be with Sara making
cocktails later on at the bar and that
you can come and enjoy one of these
monkey minds or a contagious courage or
Chelsea's kiss there will be delicious
we just need to fix a few things
wonderful probably not poison
probably not poisons Thank You Jerry
very much for the talk and thank you
also to Sara for the cocktail party
you're gonna do it soon I look forward
to that and I just wanted to mention
that that about the part of burning out
and about the part of doing this kind of
work that a lot of people in here are
engaged in which is especially when its
global like political activism and
things I've I've taken
I've done a lot of political activism as
well and like in the physical world in
my experience one of the best groups I
was in ever was deliberately built and
planned from beginning was having like
every meeting there was a longest
session talking about how we were and
how the group was then the actual
subjects that we were discussing it was
it also took place in a sauna place so
there was chilling in the sauna and you
know really really relaxing was a very
big part of it and and yeah I've been
wishing to see that kind of thing in in
hecka environments and I think that this
project you're doing is a way for will
make it easier for some people who maybe
have a little bit of difficulties with
some certain kinds of group dynamics to
actually go in and read a wiki page
where it says like you know EPP get
install your hands on their muscles and
press there so I enjoy that because in
some of the environments I was in people
had an easy time like with physical
intimacy or asking and looking somebody
in the eyes and saying you know how do
you feel um so I I'm I'm very
appreciative of the work you're doing
here and especially because it's like
you say also your growth curve is it's a
very small one so that you're planning
this you've you've experienced stress
you've burned out from it you say this
is not something I want on my worst
enemy and let's try to do that and I
will support you guys in that thank you
very much
thank you sir you have nothing to add on
this Thanks
do we have anybody else yes you have one
yeah when you earlier asked the thing
with the exercise into the room like I
kind of thought to myself it's something
that just became quite important for me
in the past couple of years but I
thought I think I have never discussed
this with anyone in this community which
is kind of an interesting thing to just
note and also like I don't know I
recently read that there was a study
that left wing left wing people tend to
do less exercise than no right wing
people
and I think I don't know probably most
of the people in the room here what more
consider themselves as left wing maybe
there's also some stigma within our
community around exercise if it's
something like with people do or yeah
and totally unrelated but you asked the
question about getting stressed by
companies if you report security issues
to them I have quite some experience
with that and I have also like helped
people relay reports yeah so I
definitely would like to talk about that
more and I think I could also try to
help if people have issues with that
yeah
thanks for your comments this is really
true and I am I don't know if it's a
left or right thing in my case I was
keeping Jim to just spend more time in
front of my computer you know so I yeah
I don't feel that proud of it because
now I'm not even forty and my back is
the one of elderly so we are using those
laptops that are completely anti
economics that are bound to hurt either
or back or necks
or hands because you cannot stand
upright and look at the top of the
screen while your arms be along your
body and 90 degrees angle for typing you
just can't have both with laptop so we
bound to hurt ourselves using this type
of machines so of course an external
keyboard or screen can fix that but
we're in very bad shape overall I would
say I could use two minutes to show you
a routine of exercises that I learned
when my neck got stuck at least once a
year I just couldn't move the last time
was so painful that for three days I
stayed in bed crying of pain and I I had
the chance to learn these moves I could
show them to you exactly now we planned
also tomorrow morning that that urea may
show us a series of stretching that she
learned that are apparently very
efficient so around the food area around
morning find us and we could we could
share this together I figured that this
thing I was traumatized with when I was
a kid or that I completely neglected
because you know I was a being of pure
mind
who needs body anyways that those things
were not as painful and scary as they
were and somehow a way to to to really
hack the body whenever I have pain
somewhere now I try to understand is
that a muscle is that a tendon is it
when I contracted when I you know in one
way or the other where is it where does
it go from and try to to feel it apply
some pressure
does it help or not does it and it's
it's really like hacking it's really
like finding a bug and experimenting
with it and I figured this also and I
started doing massage when you when you
get into it with your hands at first you
do a scan you really you probe the body
of your partner I couldn't describe what
goes on some would see some mystical
energies or whatnot I think for myself
there's lots of things science hasn't
found
yet and I not even trying to place words
here but you would care about somebody's
body and tryin and feel and understand
what's going on in in their in their
back for instance and feel like oh wow
hey there's something here does it hurt
yes ah then let me you know and it's
it's extremely rewarding and extremely
fun and it's it's it's very cool hacking
actually to try and understand these
things and try to have an impact on it
let me show you we have two more minutes
right let me show you this little gig
again it will sound like fucking
marketing and like it like I'm trying to
sell you something but since I've been
practicing this it has been about 10
years I never had again this neck stock
and as soon as I have a little pain in
the in the upper part of the neck from
now and as soon as I do it it usually
goes better in five or ten years from
now and maybe I'm not saying it will
work for everyone all the time
it's not the point but to me it
considerably helps and if you have any
chronic pain here don't force it don't
try too hard as a general rule if it
hurts just cool it down so the principle
is you'll get your your arms next to
your body you can do this while sitting
and we're gonna work the area of the
upper back and eventually the neck so
you go with your shoulders on
progressively up then off let them know
on up and off at once ah off and you do
that a couple of times that's the first
gig enough then you go like this you
roll this goes very well with funk music
wah wah wah then in the other direction
slowly change direction
the funky thing then disjointed a
synchronous somehow or de sing de face
what like this this is more house thing
but funk will do as well do that like a
dozen times or something then in the
other direction and now you may feel
already this warmth in the upper part of
your back those triangular muscles that
take lots of shit with those backpacks
and laptops so now is the right moment
to go all the way to the left slowly
slowly then all the way to the right
slow as far as you can you may feel some
cracks at the back of your neck it's
usually a good sign except if it hurts
in which case you stop immediately and
you do this and these cracks you feel
are directly proportional to some
tension going away from your yo neck
then you go back in a central position
and like a turtle you just move your
head like this dubstep this is
definitely a dubstep move and go very
slowly back and forth you may feel some
other cracks at the back of your neck
and that's it if you're comfortable with
it you could add one like this on the
left and one this on the right but if
you're in pain it might not be a good
idea so I run this again quickly on off
on off roll roll roll roll in the other
direction a synchronous in one a
synchronous in the other left right left
right and then the turtle so you can do
this in one minute really any time it
hurts
maybe everyday if you have some some
issues here I hope it's as useful to you
as it was to me
very cool hack now
[Applause]
do we have any additional remarks or
comments or questions to Jeremy if not
it means it's cocktail time thank you
very much for the keynote Jeremy thank
you