so okay moussaka zone okay so now we are
starting and please welcome
Klaus acne lady I hope that's the way
yeah whatever I'm not those brows it
anyway want you can do it the better
yourself maybe and Klaus is it's going
to talk about hacking information
security maturity assessment yeah well
first of all about the title my
experience from last year was I had two
talks and the first talk had had hanging
twice in the title so I figured by Putin
hanging in the tile as well I would draw
out or crowd I don't know if I could see
I succeeded in doing that um my name is
Dallas I've worked with IT security
since 2004 I have a lot of facets of
certificates and I've worked with a lot
of companies that's about it um first of
all since we're being recorded well I
want to have a little disclaimer not
that not that I'm saying in different
controversial at least that's not my
intention but whatever I say is my own
personal opinion and has nothing to do
with any former current or future
employee sorry employer yeah first of
all I will talk I will be talking about
how I see the state of information
security primary in Denmark because
Denmark that's where I live and that's
why I work and then I want to talk about
how I think security assessment should
be rethought because I see a lot of
companies out there selling security
assessments that I don't really think
this finger very effective and by doing
that I want to tell you a little bit
about this critical cyber security
controls or this is 20 controls as
they're also called there and what you
can do to do with them to extend them a
little bit maybe and a yeah to give you
a good assessment or a good view of our
company's security is then I want to
tell I don't want to talk to you about
what do you do with your results because
one thing is that you live at a company
and you see
he's a piece of shit pardon my french
but you need to tell that to someone to
service or someone so they can address
it and give you some money so you can do
something about it but how do you do
that um yeah and yeah exactly how do how
do you present in a way that management
understands first of all I want to tell
you about who I intend to give this talk
to if you live if you if you live at a
camp sorry if you work at the company
and you care about security and you can
see that things aren't really very good
in that in that sense in your company
know what you want to do something about
it and maybe maybe you have even tried
talking to a boss and that really didn't
help well then you've come to the right
place
um first as I said as I see to save
security and then am I getting the
comedies where I've I used to see two
two situations I see two scenarios the
first one is it's all crap nobody paid
us anything Network is segmented nothing
is hardened everybody our local admins
and a number of domain admins are is at
least and twice as a number of fear of
of the total people in IT and maybe
they've even have even had Ranger
outbreaks a lot of times and knob and
nothing has really happened that's an
error number one
Sarah number two it's it's that is if a
company has a security governance
department they have a C so they're
being audited and and they have a
governance the partner where the focus
is on order saying that so where
whenever the auditor comes around he
looks at governance how things are
supposed to be but they don't really
look at IT because I see something it's
something different people in IC don't
understand security and the people in
governance don't understand I see so
whenever you start digging a little bit
if you start one ability scanning
friends you'll see everything is crap
anyway so unfortunately that's what I
see I hope that someday I'll be seeing
something else but I haven't so far yeah
well but watch how she like how to do SS
security Dwight way well first of all
you should look at the whole picture and
at the whole picture I see you'll get
people look at process look at Luger
technology don't just look at one
because then you have failed and what
usually happens is that the people in
the process
box are being audited that's it because
if you look at these two tooth 27001
that only looks at people we have we
have a security culture framework that
measures people's awareness states or so
to speak that's also that's also peope
also just people I subscribe to 27,000 -
that looks at processes but then we have
Kobe it we have this is 20 controls we
have ISIL we have well card hosting well
that Signori we have been we have a lot
of other technologies down here um yeah
if you want look at all this
specifically their benchmarks there are
the stakes of hardening guidelines
whatever vendors probably also have
guidelines and you can look at those
yeah well how do you look at the entire
picture well first of all I'll start off
by talking about this is 20 controls and
and and by supplementing them with
specific ways of assessing the the core
technologies of the company like
exercise rectory like the network and
how they're in yeah then if you want you
want to make it a little bit more
advanced or big if you want if you want
to look at look at root causes rather
than just finding symptoms because
that's what this is 20 is good at then
didn't indicate pool in some ISO stuff
but I'm not going to talk very much
about the ISO because there are a lot of
people who know who knows much more
about that than I do but this is
critical security controls as they're
called or this is 20 controls and in my
in my mind it provides an easy way to
get started with security and you know
it can also help you compare what you
during your company - what's considers
boil it was considered best practice
it's very operational yes as the name
suggests it has 20 power ties control
domains and is free to use which is
which is good the way the critical
controls comes about is that some smart
people in the US has looked at a lot of
security cyber attacks and the hit
didn't have sort of turned around see
which controls can be actually implement
in order to make these cyber attacks go
away and that's what the 20 controls are
bar yeah I have them there you probably
can't read it and that's not in that
section at the point control number one
that's the first that's the fur control
you want to start with that is that's
called inventory of authorizing on earth
right devices put it to put it another
way if you don't know what you have then
you can secure it you don't know what
hardware you have control number two
it's the same thing just for software if
you don't know what software we have
well how given - how can you control it
control number twenty that's called the
penetration test and red team exercise
that means that is the last thing you're
going to do because it doesn't make
sense to spend I don't know two or three
hundred thousand kronor on whatever on a
penetration test when you know you know
you're going to fail when you don't but
you don't patch anything you don't
secure anything you don't do anything I
mean what's the point so that that's the
whole idea - first thing first and
whenever you think you're secure do some
of the more advanced stuff like testing
for instance testing that you have
something that works um I'll be focusing
osan yeah each each control has a number
of sub controls and all control has a
wise biases critical at all and all sub
controls they're marked as foundational
or advanced basic stuff and the more
advanced stuff for us and the interim
guidance on how to implement the
controls and the system any controls are
very technical focused which really the
goal is that that all twenty controls
should be implemented just by primarily
doing technical stuff and so that's
where the focus is
and it even has kpi citations up meaning
how do we measure how good you are at
doing each control yeah and I have links
in the Indian that we're giving you the
URL to the slide set so you can take a
take a look at yourself and look at the
links also yeah well how do you use the
system controls the way I use them in my
work is a combination of interviews and
Technology workshops and and and and
then then the den flavored with a bunch
of Robo relevant technical tests
focusing on under technologies the core
technologies and company then I then for
each control I give them a score based
on the CMMI scale if you don't know it
it's it's a scale rating from 1 to 5
where one is well not completely not
completely big bad because then I'll
give them a zero and up to five which is
completely automated controls said that
that will get better over time to have
it they even have a process for doing
that stuff like that that's very
advanced and usually when I when when I
do this do this is 20 Assessment III
involve IT management I want them to be
in the room when do where the I see
people say how things are because
sometimes there are some i opening
spirits of scones that going on I mean
like the Seas of thinking things are in
the in one way but in fact they're not
friends that's the the most common
scenario and that's that's a good thing
um I'll be focusing on the top only to
five control for the for the rest rest
of the speak top-25 control at least CSS
so that that by implementing those five
controls you will be you'll be reducing
your risk of getting a cyber attack or
whatever by 85 by eighty percent
compared to doing nothing at all so the
five the five most bit the five the five
first controls they are their most
important so do the so I'll be turning
on I'll be focusing them a bit more in
them and and talking about how I use
them and also yeah I'll talk about our
recommend using them in in real life
assessments
yes as I said this is a very controlled
inventory of all of authorized that on
also write devices serpent's all says
something about having automated tools
when it was that that discovers when
every percent gonna network it'll pop up
an alarm friendless and this is
something our TCP locks and / but
they're very operational which is a good
thing but also a bad thing because if if
the company is very very immature then
it doesn't really matter how they do I
mean for instance couldn't so
controllable so control one two says use
TCP locks to improve asset inventory
well it doesn't really matter how
specifically they do it the point I
usually when it when is very immature
companies I look at the essence after
control seeing what what are they trying
to accomplish well they're trying to
accomplish that
somehow when if you're something at a
network it'll be it'll be detected and
you can't put something on a network
that IT doesn't know about that's the
whole point so so how I do this in an
assessment for example I will do it I
will do a pink sweep test that
double-double put that will give me a
list of device of onion on the network
and I'll talk to IT about that see is
there anything in the list that they
don't know for interest if there are
well then we have a problem if the if
the if and I if I ask them if they have
a control and it's to do this and they
say well we don't well that's also a
problem so yep the same thing just for
software I use and this Edisto girl
before or before using what I see out
there and what I see out there's windows
so that's that's why I'll be asking I
see
well local admin I uses local admins
because if they are then if then have
failed it says already because then the
news can install whatever they want and
nobody knows about anything yeah and and
similarly I will be doing some kind of
some kind of power shell tool is
something that part that gives me a list
of all the stuff that's that's being
installed on here
on computers and then I'll talk to IT
and say well it's all this on the list
of software that you have approved I
told them a free a secure configuration
for basically everything but network
equipment so what are we doing in a
real-life situation you said I start
talking to IT do you have baseline
implemented at all because usually they
don't and and if they say they have well
then we can always test if that's the
case sis who does that really controls
they also have for what they call sis
benchmarks which is hardening guides for
Windows and a lot of different other
stuff so you can always test and see if
they see if they have done that and
again their number of very concrete sub
controls which has good and bad and bad
things and on these first first five
controls every also controls are
foundational more or less that's what
the eff says that's that's what should
be implemented in order to to implement
its winning controls number four this is
one the builds the assessment and
remediation I usually never never never
C never see this out there if they have
a scanning the scanning process well
then nobody nobody really looks at the
broad looks at the report and nobody
really does anything about it so this is
this is a two-step to a three-step
process first of all somebody has to has
to make sure that updates to 12 to
whatever she's told or the computer gets
get pushed out there's a process for
that then then this would be a process
for scanning sis
scanning the if everything at a network
wanna build scanning seeing see if this
control actually works is everything
being updated do we have anything that
that that that aren't that hasn't been
updated and and where security is really
bad and then and then when they have
scanning results somebody has to do
something about it meaning somebody I
see it's a nice it needs to actually
first of all patch things they need to
make sure everything is configured
because
for nobility management also that's not
not just patching but also configuring
yeah and basically that's what the
subcontrol says a fun fact if you can
call it that and the the single biggest
cause of successful malware attacks at
least in 2006 and 16 they're they're
caused by these guys over here as you
can see there's a lot of Adobe going on
like flash PDF shockwave Internet
Explorer it's also it's also we're very
well on the list
and and the end end of end of and this
and the fun thing about this is that
most of these pages most both of these
has already been patched at the time of
exploitation so it's it's just a matter
of nobody it's installed an update
control number 5 control use of
administrative privileges meaning well
do it do it has does people have the
ministry purely state they need and
nothing else meaning for independence of
Windows Windows administrators are they
all domain administrators friends
because they shouldn't be but so so so
so usually when I have to clean up when
I assess this control I'm I look I look
at the Active Directory because that's
what our customers asked half and nobody
I would be nobody knows how to do
securely if you want to you can even do
a password analysis to see one thing is
that instead you've set a password
policy but the parts of policies it's a
state of its a state of time or whatever
that's that habit that can be changed
anytime so so so by doing a password
analysis bike by cracking old password
you can actually see if there are some
bad you can figure passwords on when
done some uses yeah yeah as i said i
focused an ad because that's very little
literally everybody screws up and and if
and if you and if you do the assessment
to you should also focus on that because
i mean if a hacker gets in there and
gets
gets to be domain admin well then he has
its access to all data in the in the
company probably yeah
just to sum up the 20 controls it's very
practical technical it metrosexual
actual controls it helps a company so
whoever uses it to prioritize our
efforts because as I said focus on the
first five it's based on empirical
Imperial data on actual attacks it's
it's not like the ESO in COBIT where a
lot of people who may or may not know
terribly much about IT security has to
has to agree on something and that can
take like forever ever with the 20
controls they usually make a major
update every once once the second or
second year them as I said before if the
choice is really low don't take all the
sub controls too literal because that
will only mess you up look at the
essence of to control and see how well
that is being done yeah so you're not
missing a paper tiger by by using these
it's waiting on tools but yeah and the
the situated controls are really good at
finding symptoms but not root causes I
mean if the organization is bad if IC
doesn't doesn't our security doesn't
have any money or anything that like
that that's the situating controls won't
won't find find that find out that but
maybe that is that is the real problem
so if you if your problems like that you
could you reduce the ESO and user and do
an assessment to watch that it's not a
silver bullet
you're still have as a company you have
to find your own business risk your own
threats and assess them yourself you can
outsource that and also the twin
controls that's that's very much focused
on technology but not but not a human
security security awareness for instance
it's there it's it's controller number
18 or something like that so it's not
very they don't consider that to be very
important I don't agree in that I mean
no technical solution can ever
save you from users who really doesn't
get it and there are a lot of doors out
there
yeah well that was assist to any
controls but on top of that I also do an
assessment on on key security or cows or
a key security technologies for instance
like workstations but that's these days
the that that's the firewall so to speak
that's the first line of defense from
all wear I also usually look at VMware
hyper-v whatever they using because if
they're using it 95 percent at least of
the servers are virtualized and if they
don't secure that well then what exit
directory I said before designing and
maintaining a secure active directory
that's not trivial there are so many
things to screw up and people do their
work opponents yeah maybe maybe they
haven't they have a perimeter firewall
so that you can't so it is so you can
detect them from from the outside but
internally they probably don't have
anything they're probably not segmented
at all this this means that if if
ransomware kids gets inside to network
well then it's all over the place and
just good so yeah well how do you assess
the technologies well what I usually do
is that I Google I ask uh see if the
vendor has a has some kind of hardening
guide and most most vendor says and
that's usually a really good starting
point for instance the the VMware we be
in VMware has a really thorough and
really operational hardening guide on
how to secure your your your environment
if you're on an ordinary company or if
you're the DNS a they have they sort of
they have more security levels and they
tell you exactly what you should do to
hard enjoy your you're being wary of
your vSphere environment so they're
really good and not to mention Exeter
victory Microsoft has a lot of the
signed documents telling you how to
Sakai design your Active Directory
securely they have a lot of document
telling you how to administer your ad
securely they may even have guidelines
telling you exactly how to set up the
workstation that you're assessing the
jump
that you're using to administer yeah the
active directory very very far oh we're
very operational because the big problem
with Active Directory is that the way
people or the way we know some interests
are using it is that the first of all
that dough made a minister a toast which
they shouldn't be but that's easiest
things so that's what they are they used
this domain admin credentials on all
computers and Internet at the network
even their own workstation with and that
means that if their own voices get own
workstation gets compromised then the
hacker is domain at and just like that
so and we don't want we want to avoid
that so that's that's far for microsoft
says that you should have special
dedicated at workstation and you and you
should have special dedicated servers
that you connect to from the secure
jumper from the security service so
sorry there's a go way stations because
you don't want the scenario to happen as
I just got before yeah but no one no one
seems to know all these all this vintage
documentation about Microsoft which is
the same network components well
depending on your vendor they live but
they probably also have some hardening
guidelines this has something at least
for Cisco I think I don't know how much
sales there um segmentation it's not
really as such a signal DSS but like
that because I don't I don't I don't I
don't want to use the tool for to rev
your firewall rule faintest I want I
want I want to talk to the firewall
admin or the network admin and and and
get them to tell me how the network is
designed and then and then we'll take it
from there and that's that's more or
less a a manual thing but as a starting
point well first of all server server
should be separated for workstations and
and if they have a more branches more
brain services they shouldn't be like
completely connected because nobody in
one branch office has has a hessen has
any need any real need to talk to
regular to a workstation another painter
of his friends and also if if if the if
if they're really good or if it's
possible some switches has this
possibility that to put every
workstation on a separate VLANs all
right
can intercommunicate which is a good
thing because when we French on we're
kids into an int gets into a network
then well then it can propagate if you
do this so that's that's that's some of
the things I look at when I look at
segmentation you also want to do a model
ability scanning because one of all the
bill is getting so it tells you where
things are patch it sells you if you're
using crab old servers and it also tells
you if they're configured correctly so
that's that's a really easy test to do
and it's just so much and cloud services
yeah the problem with cloud service is
that they are very very easy to
implement so they can be implemented
outside of IT and and and if that's
being done nobody knows what sorry part
my friends what hell is on it how it's
being secured if it's being secured who
knows yeah sorry and the vendors usually
has some kind of guideline to hardening
my Microsoft again are really good at
preparing a lot of documentation and
building tools if you have the right
licenses for the products which are of
course expensive but they do it at least
yeah well how do we come from this to
this and this is yeah well this is a
prioritized action plan where you fix
all the easy stuff that has a has a big
impact first and then all the rest later
on yeah first of all be realistic if
maturity is low you there's no reason to
talk about all 20 controls there's no
reason to talk about ISO and advanced
stuff so about the five first controls
and the prioritize uneasy fixes with
high impact because the good thing about
having having having a really bad
security is that it doesn't really take
much to be better it becomes much harder
once you have a decent here to level and
then management well
management decides how and when and you
provide the input the management needs
to know what costs management needs to
know how will you mitigate what risk if
we do that and what could be saved if
safe if we do it and what order should
things be fixed then that's
that's basically what they need to know
maybe they need they need to know how
does this signal to build a map into the
business and the business risks if this
risk is it signal vulnerability isn't
fixed well then it may may have an
impact on on our business and that cost
money and we don't want that and that's
that's what potential management want to
know because management in the end of
the day they think of one thing and one
thing only
um well management as I said they're
from a different planet literally
perhaps I think because as a security
professional on a signal level you think
very different from them to you that's
an almost human being sorry
you think security comes naturally you
do it just because you can you do this
just because you should um to management
you know it only makes sense if it pays
off so security is very much about
communication if management doesn't
understand what business risks this
technical thing does something against
then it's not going to happen also
management don't don't like to feel dumb
because of course they aren't dumb they
they're different so so if you talk
about tech stuff dumb it down pardon
pardon pardon me for for calling that
it's not it's not like you should be
talking to like like a two year old two
years old but just don't talk just don't
talk too much ticked off because they
need ten they feel stupid and then you
don't get any money um the more they
understand the more likely they are to
listen that makes sense
and of course as I said before
management needs to know what does it
cost
yeah when company's a real low one low
on IT security they usually see IT
specifically an IT security in general
as a cost and I send this as a curse
that has to be cut down it has to be as
cheap as possible to run IT and IT
security it's your job to try to mate to
make them think differently about
security so make them think think of
security as an assurance I mean if I to
goes down so does business and and I
said before management don't want
business to go down maybe security get
be a business enabler it is it is yours
that IT is always available because
because availability that's also
security em and in a deadweight occur
the company can make money and have a
lot of more but of more Costner's but of
course depending on what they are doing
it can also be a competitive factor
because I've seen this a little bit when
people come to me and ask me what about
GDP are as we talked about before our
customers has to has to start talked
start asking about the GDP our so we
need to do something so so security is
slowly starting to become a competitive
factor and one thing that's very
important when you communicate security
to management is that if you know what's
important to the business then you
should then use that then then the ball
the builds is you you assess you'd be
addressed mapped to those for both to
those business concerns meaning for
instance that if you have a lot of all
servers that aren't paid well then the
server then the service mag might go
down and if the service go down that
will influence business and Deborah
Custer that will that will mean downtown
downtime to business and that cost money
yes pardon Alfred yeah that's math yeah
it's like I'll be talking a little bit
about that am too low artists curative
maturity companies as I said it has to
be as low as it has to be as cheap as
possible so that also means that it's an
uphill battle it's not going to be easy
for you for you to make security bid on
your company and
and also you can't do that alone but
that's not that's another case um but
thanks to Rick thanks to rain somewhere
and CEO fraud this is changing actually
that is that is one of the best seeing
the best piece of awareness that's going
on that's all the ransomware it's like
so thank you very much for that um
before all enterprises fear - fear the
curse of a masked I'll attack and well
there's no reason to tell your
management that the mask wasn't brain
somewhere but that's another thing and
just to get you just to give you a
feeling of what I mean I will go through
a very simple assessment of a real low
maturity company I'll be coming up with
some conclusions and some
recommendations don't take that too
little too literally your mileage may
vary
first of all you do it's a five
assessment you want you by interviewing
you will do a similar build scanning
then when you have a vendor who couldn't
have some results you'll make a simple
report sea level loss report that are
simple and easy to understand
I mean that means few words fungus
spiderwebs they love that precise cost
estimates and the funky colors that's
what you want to do um when you present
your conclusion you assess risk and
impact to business as I said before base
your assessment on what you know
business cares about and along with the
bad news you also prove it you also
provide them with with a solution
because they said this is the key to
everything you say something bad you
come up with solution management says
thank you you get money everything is
everything is good that's that's at
least my plan when you perform the
assessment if you don't know that know
the answer to all the questions yourself
find someone who does just been arranged
like a little like a small half-hour
meeting with them or something like that
and since since we know maturities lower
there's no reason to go into sub
controls and all that stuff that I
talked about before
yeah these are what this is what I would
be talking about first friend is like
friend
on control number one inventory
inventory of authorizing on or
authorized devices of desk I'll just ask
IT well do you have anything to have a
sort of invent to be like a list an
excel sheet or whatever of devices on
your network and also the next next
thing I would ask about this but but
would the IT find out if I put something
at the network find some my own computer
or an access point do they have anything
automated the second the second the
control in an inventory for authorized
known or thought of I software I will
simply ask them to have lift lift list
of software that's allowed to install
and you're on your workstations because
I mean that's not a bulletproof control
but that's some sort of indication at
least secure configuration control more
free I'll simply ask them well do you
know do you know this this vendors
hardening guidelines that I have
downloaded they have seen it before I
using it and if you are I would probably
go through a few to control and ask them
to do you have this implemented go to
number four do you with missus
vulnerability scanning do it you perform
overly busy scanning on a regular basis
and what do you do with the results
yeah goes on about number five for
instance the administer pivot is the
first thing I would ask is our users
local admins I said before that's a
really important thing and also I would
dig into how many admins admit has
permanent membership of the domain admin
group and enterprise admin groups on the
ad and also user access to network
shares are they limited as much that
they need to because one of the easiest
things to address these days of
ransomware attacks so why so why would
so I figured that that that's that's
what we will be reporting in this report
that everything sucks and and one of the
things they could do is to limit access
to a network drive because that's one of
the things that I usually never see
either I mean granted granted
permissions on an on a Windows network
that can be done easily or they can't be
done so so that you have no of you who
are seconds to what but I have never
seen
gun practice usually it's just a big
part of weird permissions that nobody
knows anything about yeah the Molly
build scam I would use open bass that's
part of Kali Linux and it's free to use
that I would perform what would what
them what's called an authenticated scan
that means that the vulnerability
scanner can log into the computer and do
some local tests to find out exactly how
are how are the computer configure to
what is installed all that stuff
and basically you want to you want to
you want to scan everything you want to
scan workstation service network devices
appliances to get it together to get a
big overview and also important thing is
that whenever you're planning to do the
scan please talk to someone about it
because you don't want somebody in IT or
even somebody on and/or the sea level to
get pissed because somebody something
goes down when you start scanning that
hadn't that happens occasionally Freight
for anyone yep this is the report not
surprisingly I've talked to IP I've
talked to IT all five controls they suck
everything is red I even have a little
legend so they could see well it could
it could have been a different color but
it's not alright this is the initial
reading little result what this is mean
well the conclusion this would be on top
of the report the gluten is that but the
level of I t's good controls are
consistently non-existence yeah so and I
say before we want we want to talk about
range somewhere so the risk is that this
equation is the risk of workstation
service getting attacked by ransomware
and and and and well through up until
now is mostly gibberish to to to and
management so you want to tell them well
what's the business impact of this and
that is what I've written here is that a
range of our check would likely make all
days on network shares unavailable
putting us out of business for at least
the time it takes to restore worst case
since we don't know that them you know
no way if our backup works then we could
be out of business because maybe
potentially we don't have a bag of
because nobody has tested it that's a
dead is more that's the conclusion next
section of the report a section plan
I've decided to put that into two parts
one part is immediately what should we
do right now and what should we do a
little bit later on right now we want to
we want to put out the fire so we were
to patch everything we want to segment
the network that network a little bit as
I talked about before we want to
separate things as much as possible so
that so that if something comes into our
network it can propagate and also we
want to lock down user access to shares
next part of texture plan is implement
so five controls of course so that we
get a little bit more in control of
what's going on investigate technical
into more work controls like our web
proxy secure DNS Network intrusion
detection systems that can they can look
for with traffic on the network
sandboxing yeah their sandbox and more
where filters educate users users need
to know how to avoid infecting their PC
and also IT needs to be need to be
educated as well because if you get
arraigned somewhere on your kind of
computer the user needs to know what he
should what he or she should do secondly
ITP IT personnel or where is and
helpless they need to know what to do if
somebody calls them up and says I have
range somewhere because when that
happens second seconds matter you need
to do something as fast as possible so
you have to you have you have to create
a plan
what about what I teach to do whenever
that call comes like logging down
Network shares access or whatever make
everything read-only something like that
and oh and since we don't know what's
going on with the bag up we need we need
to make sure first of all the right data
is backed up and we can restore it
that's also pretty basic and so in terms
of cord of course
well there's bad and good news of course
I won't put that they were in debt in
the report the bad news is that we don't
know exactly what it will cost bitter
because we see we don't have an overview
but the good thing is that I as an
employee has done DSS
and I'm already employed so it would be
relatively neutral in terms of cost to
to get started together to get an
overview of things um but one thing one
thing you should remember if you put
yourself in this situation you said you
can't do it alone you need you need you
need management to think it's a good
idea and also and and if management
thing is a good idea that that should be
invested money and well then they would
hire someone else that would hire like
responsible for IT security for his day
but they would make security policies
all the right stuff but we're not
talking about that now we're talking
about racing CEO some wariness too so
security just a little bit yeah this is
what I told you this is the I told you
how how I think things are when I when
I'm on all my clients I've told how you
think how I think you should rethink or
think of security assessment I've told
you about this 20 controls I've told you
about ssing ssing technologies how you
prioritize results how you create a
roadmap and how you address your
findings so management yep any questions
yes
oh yeah we need we need a mic sorry yeah
well my question is about the build
service because I'm a developer and what
I often experience is that in the
operations department there usually are
quite clever guys and they would really
like to do all the stuff that you
mentioned right they just don't have the
time for it and at the same time you
don't have automated deploy and you
don't have a very mature development
department or something like that right
so so how do you see a automated deploy
build service that actually can do
everything but of course it's locked so
it's not a user right and that security
gap because in some way even though I
don't believe in a silver bullet is then
I still see that as the Silver Bullet to
to free up the skill to operation guys
yeah but that is there is the key to the
situating controls that also made the
everything so I think in terms of a
field service I would say you use a
control access to whoever has access to
the code right into the code coded
process I don't know that terribly much
about it so I'm not going to say
anything that that could be stupid but
but but you say something very important
you say that you say the developers
don't have time but that's that's what
that's what I dressed before that is
that that management needs to be
involved management need to buy in on
this and the same thing with with
Windows administrators they if they are
if they're going to work like
Microsoft's assist I should well then is
completely different and and it may take
more time but they can't do it if
management don't approve of it um in
terms of security I will probably look
at the rest of ten controls I don't know
if you know that but OS is it's an open
free organization who has made made a
list of the ten most most critical
errors in security when it comes to web
security at least and also on mobile
development and just we'll go through
that or tell them and tell them about it
and says well there's these are really
good controls that you do get it even
has immense implementation guides on how
to program securely
and there is Microsoft security
velopment lifecycle that's a complete
framework that describes how you should
develop securely made by Microsoft yep
yeah it's actually not the developers
that don't have time in my world it is
the operation guys it's just that the
reason that they don't have time is
because they get knocked down by for
instance deploying manually stuff that
developers have made and such right yeah
it's more like okay all right yeah I
hope that I said that I said something
that I could that you can use even
though I don't really know that much
about it
wait yes you seem to be focusing quite a
lot on ransomware and viruses are you
afraid that that would take your focus
away from other security aspects oh I do
that for two reasons the first reason is
that it's very easy to to tell your CEO
about the risk from wayne's where
because he is if he hasn't tried it
himself his wife probably has or his
mother or his father has probably tried
it tried having it so everybody knows
what that is
and if you if you try to do something
about ransomware it will automatically
you'd say do something else about your
war security level so well of course
you're right there there are other
things in the world but when were born
somewhere is on the rise
I'd be I mean in my in my mind we hadn't
seen anything yet everything can be
ransomed in two years time you'll be
ransom so we can't get into a house
Frances I stuff like that so rain
somewhere well that's the future yeah I
hope I your question
yeah anything else all right thank you
for your time if you have any questions
or need the inputs input to whatever you
need to do in your own situation come
talk to me I'll stick around until
tomorrow evening and I'll I'm even on
Twitter and I've set up a special custom
URL to to the full slide set because I
had three times that minute slice so I
decided to cut them so maybe there's
something in there that you can use yep
thank you