okay we have will Scout on the stage now
who is going to talk about messaging
without metadata cool yeah so the the
basic structure of this is to sort of
survey over what is going on in secure
messaging so the different efforts that
that are that are working on sort of
different problems and and to try to
systematize a little bit the different
threat models that we're trying to
address and what's what's left and
what's happening there right so so in
the context of messaging we've got
people who want to talk and we've got
some network in between that is that is
managing getting messages back and forth
and we've we've sort of split this into
two things maybe there's there's
asynchronous email style where the
server is responsible for holding on to
things for a while and then there's the
the instant messaging the chat where
we're just sort of relaying it but we
still have generally some infrastructure
that's doing that but this this ends up
being sort of two different solution
spaces there's two different types of
systems that are getting built one on
trying to secure emails and how do we do
that better and a different set on how
do we do better on our on our instant
messaging side the the thing that we've
really I think as a community had
success with is is end-to-end encryption
we've got signal and that's really taken
over at the instant messaging side and
then email has you know we have
solutions there is GPG and as a whole
set of encryption things that that
aren't nearly as prevalent and there's
there is a large set of efforts right
now I think to to try and figure out how
do we get the same ubiquity of
end-to-end encryption on an email style
transport that we have on is - messaging
and and so what we got with signal was
this this axolotl protocol where we are
with each message providing a new key
for the other person to use as they
respond and we're ratcheting through the
the encryption key that we're using
which gives us a couple sort of
properties that are that are useful for
this format
and and those are forward secrecy and
deniability in an in a semi asynchronous
setup and and so I think that's that's
where I want to start is talking about
what these properties are and then we'll
keep building from there so in terms of
this forward secrecy and deniability
what this is talking about is how what
happens if one of these devices gets
compromised either key material gets
leaked or or the device actually gets
captured what what signal gives us with
this ratcheting of changing keys is that
with one participant even if they've
kept all of their network logs
afterwards they can't prove that it
wasn't them who said what the other
person message to them that by releasing
and changing keys each time the the
signal protocol has this nice property
where I as one of those two participants
I'm able to have reconstructed that
whole thing purely from my side I now
know enough in what is released in the
new key that comes in in these in the in
these in these new ephemeral keys part
of that message is to release the
additional key material from the
previous one so that the whole
conversation up to the last message is
something that a single participant
could have we have all done themselves
consistently so that if they turn this
over to the authority there's there's a
potential that they just made it purely
themselves and that's sort of a cool
property technically that we can say
this is cool unlike you know Digimon
emails I can't prove it was actually
sent by this person servers that someone
who sees the the leak you know says well
maybe you just did this in yourself and
there's no way to deny that and and and
then we also have this sort of
asynchronous thing where the key
exchange the initial handshake that
we're making to set this up one of the
participants can be offline and do it a
little bit later and the protocol still
works so that's the other major sort of
crypto thing that we that we got
recently on these instant messaging
things there's a lot of times like with
the initial OTR handshake and things
like this both participants need to sort
of relatively quickly complete this
handshake
and you've got some
periods where you're sort of in a
dangerous partially created state and
now we've got something where we can
sort of wait partway through and finish
this and so what this has given us is
the Alice and Bob our two participants
can talk to each other and the server is
passing messages back and forth but it
doesn't know the contents of those
messages right so and n means we've
we've encrypted the contents but there's
still a lot of things that the server
knows and there's still a lot of things
that the network knows and this is the
metadata so we've got this threat model
that we we are starting at this is I
think in a lot of ways for us as a
community the baseline where at least we
want to be able to ensure that the
network and server that's sort of
passively watching we want to be ready
for them if someone is trying to surveil
the contents of the messages we want to
make that hard for them so we've got
these base set of things that we're able
to say okay even if this is happening
which it probably is I'm good right I've
got I've got this end end encryption
thing these are things that they can't
do but there's a lot of stuff that this
doesn't cover right and so I'll get
there in a second I guess let me finish
on the signal side first signals now in
a bunch of apps so we've got this sort
of ubiquity of signal now and and the I
think development of sort of the signal
protocol where that effort has gone is
into a bunch of how do we now expand
this to multiple parties so how do we go
from the one on one to a group chat
setting n plus one sect just came out
but we've had a couple earlier so ASN
did I guess it was piccolo and now is
flute which is over IRC how can a group
do an encrypted style messaging and then
and then we had Megas MP ank earlier I
sort of like the proof of this is we
actually do know some of the crypto and
and algorithms for getting the multi
party thing working so what's left the
server knows a lot it knows when each of
the users is online it often knows the
users contact lists right so with signal
you the server knows who your contacts
are it knows when you are sending
messages and to whom
and it knows the size so it knows how
big these messages are and that's a lot
of metadata right and this is the the
classic trope that this is enough for
for the people who are surveilling us
that we haven't really fully solved this
problem or closed the window of hiding
our messages so what are the what are
the new ideas how do we how do we get
past that so we've got our baseline of
we've we've encrypted our contents how
do we make the you know this metadata a
little bit less easy to get I think a
lot of new ideas came out in pond so
this was a while ago right so so pond
was saying how do we do better for a
networked adversary how do we do better
against what this sort of NSA Monitor
style monitoring has and it did this by
by having a network protocol that that
tries to protect against a bunch of
things it's gonna send fixed sized
messages and it's gonna send them sort
of irregularly regardless of how much
you're actually sending so it has an
envelope around your actual
transmissions it will every few minutes
send a message to the server and get a
message back from the server regardless
of whether you actually have a message
to send or not so it's gonna try and
keep the communication pattern constant
punned as a result is flipping more to
the email side it's sending that message
every few minutes and so you're not
going to have the real-time
communication as easily
it also comes up with this one of the
early implementations of a protocol
called panda for for adding a new
contact where the goal is how do I add
that new contract without having my
whole contact list in in the server so I
need to exchange these initial keys I
need to send them to someone often we
just sort of say that's out of scope
that's not right this is our out-of-band
initial rendezvous to have a secure
Channel well what is that
and so pond is saying well actually we
probably don't necessarily have that so
how do we bootstrap this initial thing
without the server knowing who those two
people are by some unique handle or
identity in terms of communication it's
doing this thing called an exponential
this the exponential decay which is a
cool idea in terms of how often you're
sending messages so the
you you have this this curve that has
the property that at any point in the
curve the probability distribution is
sort of the same so in terms of rare
event statistical probability just
because I've waited five minutes I don't
know if the next one will come any
sooner then then if I hadn't waited
those five minutes and so it's hard for
the server to predict if a client has
actually gone offline or is just hit the
the long tail of this probability curve
right so it's a you know the server can
probably list eclis say well it's been
two hours it's less likely that you're
still online but it doesn't know for
sure for a while so you get this grace
period of jitter and being able to sort
of make someone who's watching you less
sure about what you're actually doing so
we've got you know this property where
I'm just sort of sending messages
regardless of whether I'm actually have
something to say and so this this sort
of updates are our threat model who's
gonna keep doing this we're now if we
have someone who's trying to watch the
traffic patterns we're also protecting
against them so we've we've got one
additional thing but the server's still
knows some things right so the server
knows when there's an actual message
versus not so we're not we're not hiding
the frequency of messages and when I'm
actually sending and receiving messages
from the server because the server does
have the concept of some identity that
I'm sending this message to and I don't
now have the same linkage of all of my
contacts to my user as much but I do
have this property that the server still
knows when I'm actually active and
sending messages versus when my client
is online okay cool so the the point was
so the server doesn't actually know when
you're sending but it knows when you're
getting messages that you're receiving
so the identity is sort of the mailbox
destination and that's what the the
server is able to see but it doesn't
know who's sending I guess the other
thing on protecting the network is the
pond traffic goes over tor so your IP
address to the server is anonymized over
that to our real
which is giving you right we're in an
asynchronous model we certainly don't
care about the latency which is pretty
minimal that tourism playing and that
that gives us an additional sort of D
linking that my connections are going to
come from different places the other
asynchronous thing that we've got that
came out somewhat recently is called Lu
pics this is on the mix Network side and
so this is I think sort of a modern
reimagining of some of the early mix
style networks so we got this this is a
concept that came out fairly early in
email I think if you have mutt as an
email client you might see that there's
this mixing option deep in some of the
the sending options that you can use to
do a mix master style routing of your
emails and and there's now sort of an
attempt to bring that back Lou picks is
basically the the thought here is I'm
going to send my my messages not through
a single server but we're going to have
a chain of servers and each of those
servers internally is going to shuffle a
set of messages so it's going to wait
collect a set of messages shuffle them
in a way that it knows pass them on to
the next one
that will also shuffle them and pass the
that's set on to the third one or and
however long your chain goes and each of
the servers will shuffle them and so by
the end server it won't know which
message is coming from which client and
and so in in a similar style to to these
multiple hops to delink that we see in
in a tourer system what what a mixed
system is doing here is unless all of
the nodes on your path are sort of
colluding and talking to each other at
the end you've got this set of messages
where you don't know which message is
coming from which source and and by
doing it in a batch you're ensuring that
you're getting this que anonymity where
some set of messages que all got bashed
initially but they were encrypted so the
initial guy who was waiting for that
batch to form just knows okay so I got
messages from some set of people but
they're all encrypted and they're all
fixed size so I don't know much about
them I'm gonna shuffle them around I'm
gonna give them the next person who
shuffles them around and the next person
who's
you know shuffles them around and has
decrypted enough now to see okay so I've
got these messages with contents but now
unless I talk to all of these servers I
don't I don't know right so by doing
this batch we're we're able to get this
additional sort of level of anonymity
where we now are trusting less about the
servers to be able to say anything about
who's active one so this is this is an
ongoing thing that a set of people are
are doing David stating and yawning and
a set of people are working on this
under the name Kotzen post and so we're
sort of saying instead of having this
sort of fully distributed thing if I
have a few different entities that I
trust a little bit or at least not to
collude I can I can stop trusting the
single server to know quite as much this
is I guess maybe also somewhat similar
to to ricochet in a sense right which is
which is saying we're going to do
messaging over tor and again in order to
not trust the single centralized server
we're going to use the Tor network
itself as a set of relays and we're
gonna send our messages through a bunch
of different hops to do that so right if
I've got a bunch of different hops I'm
not trusting any individual server with
knowing sort of these paths and when I'm
active by by splitting that out among a
set of mutually distrusting servers I
can I can get similar properties
Ricochet also is getting some work under
the Ricochet go project or repo that is
under that organization so there the
current work is splitting the the
front-end user interface which is you
know how we interact with it from the
actual protocol implementation which is
getting rewritten and go and that has
both some security properties that that
are nice that that actual implementation
of logic can get sandbox a little bit
better and also maybe gives us some some
ability to do have more flexibility in
terms of the user agent that we're using
so you can now imagine potentially
you've got a mobile client or something
that talks
to this go implementation of the
protocol where you've got some some
communication between your different
devices and then you've got your your
agent that is how you're interacting
with people so so again we're seeing
this set of mix approaches or tor based
approaches that are that are trying to
solve the server now so in addition to
our network adversary we really want to
prevent the server from being able to
watch information about us and and
understand the patterns of traffic so
either the timing you know when I'm
online and who my contacts are right
we're trying to take we're trying to add
to our adversary model and add these
additional entities that we're not sure
we really want to trust cool and then I
want to talk about the other one as well
which is private information retrieval
and this is a thing that came out of Ian
Goldberg's group a while ago and and has
been getting I think mostly academic
attention still which is saying how do
we get a single centralized server and
still know less about it and so the
hypothetical question to start getting
this one which i think is maybe I'm
gonna spend a little bit more time and
dive into this one is how do I retrieve
a message from a server without the
server knowing which message I gave it
right and so there's there's this the
sort of straw man answer where you say
well if the server just gives me the
whole database then I can grab out the
one that I care about and I haven't told
the server anything about which one I
wanted and so then the next question is
can I do that with a reasonable network
cost where I haven't had to download the
entire database and PIR is saying well
maybe and so the basic idea is we're
going to do something similar to this
mix net thing of distributing load I'm
gonna have a couple or a few servers
that I say aren't going to collude and
what I'm gonna ask from the different
servers is I'm gonna say hey you XOR
some set of your elements that I tell
you and give me that that sort of
superposition of them and on the other
one I'll also ask for an XOR and to each
individual server the requests I'm
making should look random but if I then
XOR all of the individual requests
together
they should all cancel out because if I
ex or something with itself I get back
zero so if I acts so if I ask for
elements an even number of times they
cancel out when I XOR them back on my
local machine and so I've asked for a
network bandwidth of one element from
each of the servers and then what I get
back at the end is only one element that
I've that I'd asked for an odd number of
times so I have I have this nice
property from the client that I they
haven't revealed to the server which
which thing I that it has that I
actually have asked for but at the cost
that the server has had to take this
request for a random subset of things
that it has and and do this map or this
computational thing which is you know
it's a it's a basic operation that CPUs
are pretty fast at but still if you have
many users and many elements in your
database this is a lot of computation
that you've sort of asked the server to
do on your behalf it has to read half of
its database and put it all together and
so if my database is gigs and gigs this
is problematic right so this this
problem of scaling is really I think the
the thing that has caused people to say
this is impractical and that's a pretty
good reaction
so with this primitive what do we do the
the thing that came out a couple years
ago is is DP 5 a privacy-preserving
protocol and so this is sort of like the
the presence messages in in XMPP if
you're familiar with with your jabber
client it there's sort of a couple basic
types of messages there's the actual
chat message that you send which is you
know the contents of a message and then
there's the signaling of online and
offline and so what DP 5 did was it said
ok so we can't necessarily fit our whole
protocol of chat through this mechanism
because it's gonna be very slow and
it'll cost us a lot so instead what
we're going to do is we're just going to
use it for initiating a new session so
when I have a contact and I want to
begin talking to them I'm going to use
the PIR style message
just once to tell them where I am and
then we'll talk based on where I am
currently and so in fact what I'll do is
every conversation when I start it I'm
going to make a new tour connection to
an XMPP server I'm gonna register a new
account and then I'm going to use this
XMPP or this this PIR system which is my
long-lived way to talk to my contacts
and say hey contact I'm now connected
via tor at this account you should also
connect over tor to this account and
we'll chat on two totally ephemeral
accounts that we only use for that
single conversation so I'm gonna deal
link all of my conversations as totally
separate sessions and I'll use this
long-lived but but with this theoretical
lack of connection to get better
anonymity where the server doesn't
necessarily know how to link them so
I've split again I've got some data
channel that's separate from my my serve
long-term identity channel and and we
can get it for that at the beginning of
I think this year they they actually
they built the XMPP implementation of
this and released it so there is a thing
called ex called DP v proxy that is the
the the sort of you run it and it acts
like a local jabber server so you you
connect your XMPP client to this thing
that's running on your your local
machine and it does this translation
where you have a normal-looking buddy
list and when you initiate the
connection it does this PIR thing to the
PIR server set that they're running and
then and it makes the new account and
and so why why are we doing this well
hopefully we're now moving up to a
global passive adversary so we're saying
if someone even if they can monitor a
significant fraction of network traffic
right so that that's what we didn't
necessarily get from tour is towards
great if if we're if we're talking about
someone who has some a s's that they can
monitor or some set of these nodes but
if there's someone who can actually
monitor a sizable amount of the internet
or all Boehner and sees all of the
different links we need something where
we're getting something more theoretical
rather than just
Mystikal to solve this right so so that
that expectation that someone's not
watching the whole network breaks down
and we need to go to this next step cool
so then I guess the the final thing and
this is what I've been working on to try
and extend EP five is something that
we're calling talaq and you can look at
it and read about it if you want but
we're basically taking the same approach
and we're saying can we actually scale
it so that instead of having to do these
two things as as split can we do it all
just through this PIR mechanism and so
the question is can we get enough
efficiency out of this thing that it's
practical for four basic messaging and
so it's the same basic PIR thing but but
the the the the things that we're doing
on it are two things one is how do we
deal with writes we're going to do
something like pond where all of the
clients are regularly writing some
message to the server it won't know
which ones are actually a message to
someone else or just a random message as
long as they're all acting the same
whether or not they have a message to
send so you're doing the same thing
there and you're putting it somewhere
random in the database the way that
you're coordinating with the person
you're trying to talk to is the two of
you are sharing a deterministic seed for
your shared random number generator so
you both stay in sync and know which
next random element in the whole
database it is you're looking for and
because there there's enough flexibility
in this PIR request that the client can
keep asking for and basically pulling
for the item where it expects that next
element to be that it can keep sort of
doing that regularly until it sees the
next message in the stream that's
following this random number generator
and then update its random number seed
to the next one in the series so right
if I if I've got the same seed my random
number generator will still stay in step
well the two of us will get the same
thing you don't want your database to be
too big there's there's a thing called a
cuckoo hash table which is basically
just we've got hash tables right so I'm
going to
take an element I'm going to hash it it
goes somewhere in a known set of things
and and the problem we're that we have
with with hash tables is how do we deal
with eviction how do we deal with two
messages ending up in the same place
this this is where we have to deal with
our sparsity how dense can I pack this
thing and the thought here is if each
element actually has two different
potential locations so so I have two
separate hash functions and so each
element can hash to one of two places so
every time I read I need to read in both
of those places to see if it's in either
of them but that gives me a lot of
flexibility because whenever I go to
evict because I've now written too many
things into a box I can look at the ones
that I'm gonna throw out and say well
you have some place else and maybe that
one has a free spot and so you you you
have enough flexibility that you can
load your your hash table up to a
density of about 95% full without having
performance impact which is pretty
reasonable so you can get a pretty dense
database where you've you've compressed
how big that final thing is and then I
think the the thing that I'm there's
maybe at the core of why this is
interesting and why this is maybe not
quite as crazy as we think is that we've
actually not us as a community but like
this this we're computer science AI
community has spent a lot of time
solving this exact problem which is when
I do the query on Google or when I when
I have to do my machine learning model
lookup it you it's it has to go out and
look at a huge amount of data in
parallel and then pull back to some
element and and really this PIR a little
PIR operation in a lot of ways is doing
something very similar right it's it's
going out to a lot of data and it's
doing a pretty simple thing to reduce it
back down to a single item and that that
looks a lot like what our modern GPUs
are designed to do they've got a lot of
parallel cores that are able to do
something simple like an XOR operation
and pull back to to a small amount of
bandwidth that they can use to
communicate between the CPU processor
that's the general purpose thing and
this is this GPU thing so we've got the
basic implementation of the GPU version
of this where as long as
per GPU we've only got 8 or 12 gigs
worth of data we can do a millisecond or
a few millisecond lookups for this PIR
operation and so we can get individual
computers that can't support thousands
of requests per second maybe even tens
of thousands but somewhere in that
thousand to ten thousand range and so
that maybe gives us enough to do
something that's synchronous or if not
synchronous but but what we expect from
our messengers right because I really
want to be able to read every second I
see the new message like if you write a
message to me I'd like to see it within
a couple seconds if I'm gonna have a low
latency conversation with you once it
gets to order of five ten seconds it
starts to be a little bit harder to have
that interactive conversation but you
could imagine a latency of five seconds
that that's enough to make this cost
efficient it's written and go there's a
there's a library that integrates and
it's this concept of a stream basically
where I have a a sort of a handle that I
give to someone else and then they can
watch it and I'm putting stuff into it
and I set up a website that has the
basics of how you can run this thing
this the there's a command line
implementation of it that is pretty
stable I've put messages into it and
other people have been able to read them
so that's that's a start but but this is
we're sure about the scaling from like
me and a few friends to maybe tens or
hundreds of people to make sure that
this is actually working the way we're
expecting and then in terms of ease of
use so that it's not just a command-line
client I'm most of the way done and it's
linked here on this page for the same
sort of XMPP style shim where you can
use an existing jabber client and you'll
just talk purely to this back-end system
rather than than the DP five cell thing
but but to get some UI on this that
that's easier than than just a
command-line client I think more
generally the the thought is we've got
these trade-offs right signal everyone
is using
but I'm trusting the server quite a bit
more mix networks are giving me a good
style of anonymity and what I'm trading
off for that is latency that it that in
order to ensure that I'm getting that
guarantee of anonymity I'm potentially
waiting a while
tor is mostly about this global passive
adversary of am I willing to believe
that that the set of notes that I'm
hopping through are disjoint enough that
no one's able to watch and correlate my
traffic across you know my entry and
exit right if I'm talking to someone
that I know is also on Comcast right
like if we're both on the same ISP and
we're both in the same country well it
sure sounds like there's some adversary
who potentially can see those two ends
and and is the traffic pattern shielded
enough to prevent them from linking
those two communications and then we've
got this PIR primitive which is
computationally quite expensive
comparatively but does give me this the
same sort of mixed isle I only have to
assume that one of the end servers that
I'm talking with is trustworthy that
unless all of the different servers that
I've chosen are colluding together I get
us some theoretical guarantee which is
you know what we might hope for so I
think you know this is as I understand
it where we are and and the the things
to be thinking about is are there other
like primitives that we can that we can
have that they give us other you know
ways to get these properties to reduce
metadata or or how do we develop these
sets of primitives that we already have
to get somewhere where we add versary
knows a lot less about us because we've
got a long ways to go from anything
that's you know getting real use right
now to prevent people from knowing when
we're talking and we're talking to cool
[Applause]
yeah very cool does anybody have
questions yes so you're going Clement a
tional zoned in the front end or all of
it so yeah yeah go implementation the
two thousand lines of five thousand
months amid the front end and you still
rely on the db5 for the server-side know
that implementation is all all of the
components so it's it's three pieces
there's a Lib talaq is a client that
will talk this it'll do the encryption
operations for our PIR style reads and
writes there's something called the
front end the way we have it set up is
the the client will only talk to a
single front end but it will encrypt its
message to the different servers and the
front end will then talk to what we're
calling replicas which are the different
trust domains the different entities
that are actually running that so that's
again to like minimize the network
bandwidth between the client if it's
mobile for instance and who it needs to
talk to so it basically sends a request
to each of the different trust domains
and then there's a rep there's this
front-end component that basically
batches up a set of incoming requests
over a time period and sends the batches
to the appropriate replicas and then
there's the replica code which actually
does the PIR zon a batch the replica
code there's a pure go cpu-based
implementation and then we have both a
open CL and a CUDA GPU thing that it can
talk to using go bindings to those two
are there many of these replicas running
yet or what's what's the current status
of the of these things so I put up and
and on that on this link there's there's
a sample like Khan file that you can
download that will that is the working
alpha instance that that I've been
maintaining with a friend it has two
nodes right now one that I run at the
university Michigan and one that he runs
at the University of Washington
so you're trusting us basically not to
collude which is probably a bad
assumption so so right now that's that's
like a a pretty simple like proof that
this is working and operating correctly
a per protocol what we really want to do
is get a set of probably three that are
GPU based and can do the sort of higher
scape higher scale of messages for two
people to communicate with this do they
need to be using the exact same set of
servers or would it be okay if I was
also sending messages to a server that
you're not I mean it seems seems like we
just need an overlapping set of servers
and are obviously relying on the the
intersection of our two sets but if so
what you need is when I make the request
that is this XOR superposition of the
different server databases those
databases need to be in sync so that
they cancel out so if I ask for item in
position one from server a and from
server B I need to they need to cancel
out to zero appropriately and its
position 1 so the servers need to be
exact replicas of each other
right so so it needs to be sort of a
lockstep sort of we're now so this is
also what like that front end thing does
is it tells the server's okay you've
gotten all of these rights over the last
you know second or five seconds now
update to incorporate all of those and
now requests from now on will be in the
next sort of epoch of the database that
has these rights applied so they talk to
the coordinator right so so I mean yeah
so how we have it structured is you talk
to a coordinator and and your
coordinator is defined to have a set of
servers behind it and you need to be
encrypting to those same keys that it's
going to actually forward your messages
to
so so right now it would be and I think
you know there's the potential to be
able to do this with overlapping but not
identical sets of servers but it's
probably it's not something I've
actually thought about how you build and
it's probably non-trivial thanks for the
talk yes there's no one else let's give
a big hand to will thanks