yes anyway so yeah as Lauren mentioned
this presentation will be about one year
review of Group one to three different
campaign we were able to identify some
are very similar and some are really
different I get in completely different
region of the world and at the end you
will see that this team is growing have
more and more skills and in January this
year as I start to use zero day we will
explain to you everything at the end it
would be worried so I bought me I'm Paul
has Kenya so I'm French sorry for the
accent it's not my choice basically I'm
Miranda Stanford researcher at Cisco
Telus I work on several case inside
CCleaner or Group one two three we
present to you or MP destroyer and a lot
of different fun stuff like that and
yeah yeah that's the slight issue for
example black/white oops
oh nice
Thanks that wasn't me someone at the
same pointer and previous oh yeah
so yet I worked with Palmer gets his
guitars our researcher threat
intelligence alder etcetera pull and I
work on pretty much everything together
so ccleaner olympic destroyer bond
Robert etc and we're gonna go through
today I doomed apologize for my accent
because like I'm finally in a place
where everyone understands me so it's
great here so here is a timeline we will
speak today so first campaign it's the
first one we identify but it's the first
one on on the timeline is a golden time
campaign here it was due during 2016 and
until March 2017 so basically everything
on this group Morris Austin everything
start by email in this name in this
campaign see Atticus use an email from
an even named Korea Global Forum so it's
a real conference and it's hosted by
University and this email really come
from the University if you look at the
either some a really come from sever
from University so basically Atticus
compromised this account and was able to
send the email if you I think everybody
speak Korean here yeah of course so I
want translate I'm kidding
so basically you have an attachment and
it's hwp file in fact in Korea's they
don't use office Microsoft Office they
have their own office it's name angle
word processor hwp and but you will see
this basically is just the format is
very close but it's about the characters
in fact which is complicated for weather
and they have a lot of tactile device
and they are able to write recommend
technique device and it translate on
Korean and it's really useful for them
so they have their own file format hwp
and this document
it's basically is the forum send this
email we assume to several attendees
and it's a survey when they ask to open
an attachment and save it was good bad
extra another example during the same
period is this one this one is
completely different it's someone we are
alleged to be in North Korea that send
an email and ask for help and how we
could move in South etc so it's the same
thing in the DWP document and in this
case see Atticus work on the empathy of
the target to open the attachment both
document the form for the conference and
the email email saying I was born in an
84 X direction so let's go on the hwp
document so as I said it's a kind of
office document so you can use all Edom
if you are used to analyze office
document it's tool and open source tool
you you probably use often the biggest
difference is you have object with the
object a zip that lip compressed so it's
the only difference so the tool is able
to list the object but is not able to
extract and read the content because you
can extract it but you need to unzip it
before working on it
so yeah in this case you have an EPS
document it's embedded PostScript
something like that and they use a
vulnerability in the EPS parser they use
a well known vulnerability so this may
worse and in 2007 gene I think and it's
just vanilla from 2013 so it's old one
and something if you are used to analyze
share code generally you've got a lot of
90 it's not you got 1990 1998 blah blah
in this case I think it's to avoid
detection they use zero four zero four
zero four zero four it simply make a
useless add-on register so I think it's
simply to bypass some some detection he
don't note the purpose of this share
code is to download to fake JPEG on
website you will see this actor rarely
loved JPEG file he always tries to
download JPEG file but it's never
real epic fight it's a real peanut and
the website our legitimate website she
compromised website put a fake JPEG file
and use this file for the second stage
of of the compromise in this case you
can see WP content it's wordpress so
each time you have a big wiener bitten
WordPress he compromised WordPress
website which is Maru on it and provide
campaign what is the purpose of this
back so it's obfuscated with
several boring stuff but anyway at the
end we have a sample we named it hot hot
it's a remote administration tool
the purpose is basically to have more
control of the remote system and I'm
gonna explain real quickly some some of
the picture we found them on them first
he check the version of your system and
if it's a Windows XP it simply go on
infinite loop because nobody has Windows
XP normally and it's basically used by
syndics system so if you have Windows XP
he think it's a sandbox we do nothing
she look on running process and it's
recommend to check for understood such
as I don't know we're shocked and in
this case I think it's the same reason
it's to avoid detection he doesn't look
for the complete world like I don't know
V bugs like wire shot but he's looking
for Aisha so if you make the diction
based on the world where you're shocked
it doesn't work she look for small step
part of the specific process here is the
complete list that is really really
common under restore if the Marwa find
one of this tool she makes something
really really weird start watching a TV
show the Japanese TV show and she's
starting to watch the TV SH we don't
really know why the TV show is I think
Japanese or Korean TV show name golden
time that's why we need this company
like that so if you look
if you exhibit on sandbox and do your
sandbox is a Windows 7 but the Mirada
text one of this tool running here we
download this TV show and start watching
it so the infrastructure for forces
Mario is very specific usually you have
a server and do you send that data to
see several the server give order to
compromised machine and it's how it
works in this case it's completely
different
the atticus used legitimate platform in
order to administrate compromised system
for example here you've got a Twitter
account so the malware uses the Twitter
API to get the infected machine and give
order to this machine it's it's clever
for cause on some organization it's
really hard to block Twitter because
it's used some time it's normal to be
used inside of the organization and
Twitter of course use HTTPS so it's
boring to make massive SSL interception
in your company we notify seven upgraded
Twitter tokens on the binary another c2
channel in this case was Yandex it's a
cloud storage platform it's very famous
in Russia maybe not here it's like a
Russian Google Drive Molly's in same
thing the expectation document was
thought inside of this Yandex right we
form four different tokens in the binary
if it doesn't work they'll have a
peoplein and major fire cloud platform
so same thing they send fire directly on
media fire and download them author yeah
and yeah it's like Morris every remote
enemy social to today he's about to
perform a screenshot of of the machine
and yeah it's simply either capture to
say that so it was a first campaign and
we don't find a second campaign more
lessons in same time we named it every
new year and in this case it start by
malicious as
documents or like previously so
basically if you see hwp document it
means Daggett Korea because nobody else
use this file format and it in this case
it's in Korean and if you look at the
logo and the text on bottom it's the
logo of the Ministry of unification
so it's Ministry of South Korea well the
goal is to have one day unify country
between north and south and the name of
the document is North Korea New Yor
analyzes so basically it's a document
that explain to speak about the last
speech of North Korean leader and they
explain which will he choose and why and
how to interpret it
extra extra in this document you have to
link it's mentioned you can click here
to have more detail and obviously if you
click here something happen it basically
drop executable on your machine and
execute this file share is credit
sandbox output so everything is right of
course and it's a document it's
basically two thousand sixteen and
seventeen the world choose the Ringo
speech in sixteen and the world chose
the regular speak in seventeen and why
the leader choose this one on this one
it's really dude political
interpretation of of the end of your
speech what was the purpose of the
dropped executable it was to make a
fingerprint of the system so first he'd
get the computer name secondly your user
name execution path so where is executed
the big Z if you look it should be there
but the atticus get the path and finally
you get our specific registry key this
registry key contain your BIOS model and
if you use VirtualBox for example you
have VirtualBox mentioned here so all
this information are sent to the c2
server and here an example of the data
sent from virus
so the elf named the Aquila boom-boom is
the esteem of the virtual machine over
statin use the username is the username
of by default on on virustotal
and you have a path so with virus
that'll execute the binary directly from
the root of your file system with the
ash the file name is ash basically if
the attacker is waiting in that and he
received that he would say it's probably
not a real machine
and at the end you've got to buy a small
database VirtualBox 1.2 and how does it
works in fact this data sent to the PHP
file here and if it matched expectation
of the attackers if the path is a
correct one if the name is a correct one
if it's not VirtualBox it generated JPEG
and also to pay and this JPEG is
downloaded and you have the final stage
of the Marwa it's how he detects senders
and if you look at the domain GLS dot or
dot PR it's a real government and
website in Korea so they compromised his
website to put PHP page and JPEG and the
point is you don't blacklist
governmental website normally or you
have very very good reason and here is
the map of this campaign to different
servers a JPEG file extra another one
it's completely different than the
previous the two previous one were very
close but this one is completely
different
it's a campaign name are you happy it
was between February and a print and in
fact with on wrote rat we have some
strings and on these strings we were
able to know to see that a module was
named er SP but we were not able to get
it on the previous campaign we know it's
exist but we did not have it at this
time we finally have a way to to have
this specific e RS p dot and sample and
once we analyze it we understood what
means ER
it's a res partition and he's a wiper
basically he's hoping your physical
drive and wipe know this and he put how
you happy question so when you reboot
your system you simply have a black
screen mentioning how you happy so
that's why we named his campaign like
that of course another campaign always
by the same guys completely different is
a campaign name named Freeman in between
open in June engine and in this case the
guy didn't target Korean entities so
they cannot choose hwp fight because it
doesn't make any sense outside of Korea
so yeah nothing fancy
they use office document because you
know it works so use a public severe at
this time and the purpose was to
download an additional HTF a stalled on
on a compromised website if you look at
the source code may be too small for you
but gee peg as usual it don't know the
additional JPEG file and it's obviously
not JPEG file and here is the sample
drop its name booming we didn't choose
the name it's just by developers since
on the PDP third computation path we can
have to milk name and the purpose was to
execute another binary name in it same
thing it's not our name and yeah it's a
remoter discussion to the purpose was to
have access on the machine and be able
to do what they want to do ya know it's
your time so that was like the first
sort of eight months of when we started
to observe this from a an interesting
camping point of view and if he notice
July August maybe not so much September
but July August or summer so these guys
clearly take time off we go through June
who thought let's have a rest and then
they didn't do anything for three months
that we observed or that any other
person campaign Vander etc so we picked
them all begin November time actually
have till we're tenants
sorry early November late October and
what we found was the North Korean Human
Rights Campaign again we see the hwp
thing and it's totally peas a really
cool form up to analyze and look at if
you're into malware research I don't
know if anybody has ever looked at it
but as Paul said that all it entails
work really well on one thing disorder
Newt there's always a default JavaScript
element there it's generally nothing but
generally if you see JavaScript in an
office fight or whatever it's something
bad but with hwp it's default it's there
so it'll go out if you are looking Auto
so this was a parley written by a lawyer
and it was basically saying hello we're
representing the community of North
Korean human right on unification people
and we're basically wanting to discuss
with all these other peoples how we can
make people more interested and the
activities that they're trying to do no
one reads Korean so let's hope it says
that but we've currently gosu we knew it
says that we're able to do is actually
start looking at this and see okay
what's it in obviously is some of the
other campaigns Paul went through
generally it's pulled on a malicious
script whether it be partial based
whether it be just a binary pay lupus
and what they're looking to do is put on
something more interesting and different
here so what we find was a bit 64
included payload so he pulled that down
and actually used W scripts so when
there's command script deke who did it
drop the payload do this and then
execute and that was the malicious
script to contend that what we find
there of his process injection so this
is a from Ida and what you'll see is any
command XE hewed probably can't see that
actually trust me that says command on
XE and the student process in jackson
using command XE it doesn't virtual
allocate and that does a read process
memory a critical thread and we get away
and for the attacker to inject his own
information is in library is okay to
Sarah so from here we started to get
decoy documents and then once Paul
talked abut
we got decoy display pictures and we
don't know what any of these are they're
just Robin pictures that appeared and
some of the resource files okay
so they don't mean anything to us we
weren't really able to find anything so
you see it's sliding a little bit so
we're gonna talk to in the bottom two
middle tier who's like a politician's
political activist a people and I said
what are we fine because that's the
interesting stuff so we found a new
grant aurora rock res so when we track
for a long time it's called rock rock
because of Republic of Korea rock it
primarily attacks
I say primarily attacks Korean based
users in Korean this victimology it has
no I'll be sandbox technics and it has
library distance Jackson for all our
same major but all some sound off
platforms or there's of some boxy TFI
and Microsoft debugging tools it may be
in use we find stealers so browser
Steelers are effectively pieces of
malicious code that will try and seal
any username password combinations that
you use because I'm very lazy and when I
click on a website and I've been there
before it says do you want me to login
I'm like yes because I don't remember
all my passwords and don't say you do
this can help until all this is my point
here be careful where you store your
information where you store your
passwords at SUNY I think debug that we
started the C so I use x64 debug so this
never happened for me Paul is stuck in
1970s and uses per debuggers like windbg
and immunity and all a DBT and what we
find here was an anti debug or a
compilation error we're not really sure
we've seen it in other platforms and
other pieces in our sir what this
basically does is crashes the debugger
which stops you from trying to debug it
is the long and short of them so that
was the first instance of a debug that
we saw within rock rot we then seen this
skin again the use of legitimate cloud
platforms these are really hard to block
because well maybe Yandex isn't because
it's Russian this client storage p-card
box and dropbox are legitimate resources
that loss
and Marcus use so these are these make
it really difficult to actually walk
that much the same with Twitter ban use
with the last one mediafire at the end
Yandex might be something you could have
some sort of reason or rationale for
blocking by using these traffic analysis
becomes difficult that's all HTTP it's
all API based or I mean it's very
difficult the Chronicle and basically
see what they've done is been really
sensible with the people that are trying
to attack using this kind of
infrastructure doesn't mean I have to go
and compromise a box somewhere like they
did in some other campaigns but these
are much easier platforms to get access
to a much less likely to be blocked and
then we've seen the evil new year 2018
campaign they like New Year because they
did this for the last two years even new
year 2018 campaign was the same sort of
idea it was the Korean Ministry of
unification again the idea here was a
Spearfish the email sent and that
Spearfish the Emil was usually this
analysis of the last Korean speeches
that have been performed baba pleased
when they stopped me to find it all
information of course when you will not
talk when you get a high goal workforce
tears talking with an encapsulated
PostScript front and within that object
is more shellcode what do you think that
shellcode does what do you think that
co2 does so what we find is it could
actually execute chakra and memory and I
was the first viola scampi and we seen
of rock rock rock rock generally was but
this time it actually wasn't it executed
rock route within memory so it was the
first time we sing the real sort of
evolution from let's compromise this
random website let's put a jpeg up here
let's put a JPEG time that worked really
well let's do that again let's see that
again
and then no that's wallet as a finest
memory or so have fun small work on
executed in memory so what are the links
look like they all note the title there
is a series of typos come up so please
ignore well they all had the same
recurrences fees the number constants
fears was looking at certain objects or
register Keys within the system to tell
what type of machine it was
fingerprinting a victim is very popular
by the more sophisticated actor they
don't want the waste time compromising
someone they don't want to compromise
visible so you try and determine thing
you want to compromise why you want to
compromise it this is a graph overview
from Ida the choose no a lot from this
point of view but basically what we're
trying to say here is they have the same
reconnaissance proof lights through
they're using the same paths the entries
functions et cetera the reason why we
have two is they're two different
samples but you can see they look pretty
much identical from a call call
similarities that then existed between
Rock rut and free milk so free mode was
actually discovered by Palo Alto I think
not not by us but we were able to do
obviously the linkages back to see what
we had so we see the use of browser
stealer so I Chrome Firefox we see the
use of this bolt CLI DLL and then all
the vault enumerate API cases that are
used as functions that are used to try
and get that information and what we're
trying to do is an attacker is select
your username and password values and
click that all from the login
information basically we want your
username and password for potential
Harvison
we then obviously look for some more
what's really interesting to look for
when you're dealing with non-native
actors is v sorry I'm file type oops so
registry we all know is not spelt like
that however this attacker maybe has
made the assumption and they've typed it
in and they reuse that code and you can
then use that to track campaigns
similarly this almost of constant Chris
we're talking about are there if you're
writing our rules this is a really
really easy are in the capture this kind
of stuff really easy you just look for
asking code that says registry spelled
incorrectly very simple so again we
started linking it to those campaigns
which is how we were able to say rock
rot is also free Millie PDP product so
this is complet oh that's really hard to
see so I'm computation popular from
using that you can determine so we're
able to look back at all the samples
that we've seen and you'll see that they
go from version 12
what's after 12 13 after 13 was 13 first
dragon feeling particularly good that
day this
but we're looking at the dolphin
speedpaint path and in the dog called
peony pot so these are different
campaigns that we watched and then the
last one wiper again you see the high
school version information so that's why
we're able to use them small link it's
just these are not things that attackers
are gonna put in these are things that
are taka-kun prudent potentially is a
false fly but it's more likely that this
attacker has reused code and reused it
seems sort of engine and stage and
information to be able to create this
last one fly through this because
everybody loves here it is so the K is a
which is the Korean sir as I say Paul
and I have a fascination with Korean
malware as you probably realize they
published an advisory for February I
think 2018 and this basically said in
Korean there's a fuss every day for
nothing it's like right okay that's
really helpful so we were able to start
finding out a bit more and we determined
ok the flash new day is actually rooted
to this because they don't release the
Security Adviser
or we will say let's go back now and we
can see what we find in terms of what we
see with rock ground etcetera as we find
an office document and then that office
document was an embedded flash object
sorry walking from the screen
what embedded flash object that executed
a connection to the first command
control channel which was a PHP file
what this did was obtained an encryption
key sorry a decryption key to decrypt
the second flash object so the first
flash object launched not an encrypted
brawl included in it but had no
decryption key crimson key was created
in a remote server so I needed internet
connectivity so if you're only missing
the Sambo's new internet connectivity it
didn't do anything first stage growl the
decryption key
send the decryption key back to me as a
victim I will then decrypt an encrypted
blow within this flash object and I will
give you another flash object and within
this flash object is where they started
to use that CV B then and what that is
is shelter and they pull the shellcode
back down again it started the decode to
P within the exploit that they've used
created execution the table script and
then had Rob transaction that we've seen
so we've went from let's say on the
Spearfish name email okay that's fairly
sophisticated particularly when you're
compromising colleges et cetera to be
able to send you're compromising
government platforms so we sent those
let's know I hike a couple of boxes and
use things like ping code and the on Dex
okay okay it's like they had a check box
of fun things they wanted to do and then
they came the flashy everyday what's
really interesting is when attacking
groups and actors like this start using
zero days it shows their evolution has
came to a peak either they have lots of
money to be able to buy these exploits
or they've got lots of very good very
skilled coders and developers they're
experts obviously what we call was rock
rod as I mentioned he's still in high
school as you can see and he's still
using the same PDP pots were able to
link it directly to rock radically and
based on that conclusion of all but
sophisticated attackers will use
multiple methods of tradecraft as I was
discussing they'll send you an email one
day they'll maybe send me a flash object
another day they'll maybe send you
decrypting decryption keys another day
but we step through and see the clear
evolution of rock route that we've seen
in one two three four five six campaigns
over a year period we seen them move
from not using browser stealers to using
browser stealers so we've seen them up
on their game in terms of what
credentials they wanted to harvest we
seen them using its WP documents in some
instances and then within free milk the
first time they attack the non-koreans
unknown korean victim where they were
using office documents so they clearly
have capability to be able to create I
say you spoke like that but I mean from
a malicious perspective it was useful
they were creating useful documents
across booth hwp an office platform so
they clearly had the skill set to be
able to do both of these allows us and
we find this very interesting if you
knew anything about a row you want the
talk to us about it please feel free I
don't know if you've any questions if
you do please ask otherwise thank you
you