hi everyone I'm Sahara
I work at the a systems and I'm a threat
intelligence analyst today I'm gonna be
talking to you about Lazarus and going
through some Swift bank heists so let's
kick it off so I'm first gonna start by
looking at just briefly the evolution of
kind of how we've gotten to this gotten
to this spot and and the bank heists
that we see today I'm starting out with
kind of more criminal operations
low-level stuff then we'll talk about
the entrance of Lazarus to the scene and
get into the swift bank heist he studies
and then I'm just gonna look at a little
bit of a evolution of tools and kind of
compare their back doors just just
high-level stuff and then talk about
some unknowns that um all of us who have
been investigating the the actor and
these cases kind of are still mystified
by and maybe some potential theories and
then I'll wrap it up with some
conclusions and outlook for future
future attacks so it used to be that you
know attacks would really be a low-level
kind of opportunistic target the
low-hanging fruit and really didn't need
many resources so you're looking at
phishing and web attacks and things like
that we moved on to kind of getting more
planned and maybe even in small groups
but more commercialized so kind of
buying off the shelf tools and then
we're getting into more organized kind
of attacks with full teams and people
that can be hired and developing you
know banking Trojans and ransomware and
then moving on to kind of the tailored
attacks that we see today and how
targeted intrusions are becoming the
norm so this is kind of where I want to
start introducing Lazarus and this is
you know an investment of time and
sophistication and a lot of planning and
coordination and the payoffs are
actually a lot better as you'll find out
so just to recap I'm sure a lot of you
have heard of the bum bass bank heist
because we never stop talking about it
and this was pretty pretty big milestone
and kind of kicked off the
investigations into this group in the
Swift heist capacity so this was back in
2016 and really at the time it was it
was pretty high-profile in terms of the
intrusion itself but also the subsequent
money laundering I'll kind of talk about
that a little bit but I think one of the
important things to note now obviously
is that it definitely wasn't a one-off
which people thought it was at the time
so just a quick rundown of what happened
so basically there was a lot of again
planning and coordination that went into
this so there's the set up in May 2015
the attackers have set up accounts in
the Philippines and Sri Lanka in
preparation presumably and there was
recon up to 18 months before the actual
heist the intrusion happened on a
Thursday the attacker has executed the
Swift transactions to send money to
those accounts that they had set up
Bangladesh Bank noticed issues with the
printers on the Friday and the Swift era
showed up on Saturday as did the
messages from the Federal Reserve and
the last activity that we saw from the
attackers was on was on Saturday so this
happened over a bank holiday weekend the
Monday was Chinese New Year and in
Bangladesh the weekend is the Friday and
Saturday so there was basically four
days where people weren't able to notify
and basically caused a bit of a delay in
terms of addressing addressing the issue
which obviously was well thought out by
the attackers so then finally Tuesday
comes around and
stop orders are issued from Bangladesh
Bank to the Federal Reserve and 850
million ends up being blocked 20 million
doesn't go through to the sri lankan
accounts because of a typo and then the
81 million goes to the accounts and the
Philippines and then goes on to be
laundered through the casinos so really
what I want to point out here is kind of
the sophistication and the inside
knowledge of how the Swift systems work
so the attackers were able to manipulate
the printers the balances on the swift
messages and then the printer is to
cover them up to hide those fraudulent
transactions so really good knowledge of
the banking operations and and business
processes so fast forward to 2018 and
two years later we see the heist not
only continuing but increasing so just
in 2018 I think we've seen eight public
ones at least so I'm gonna get into a
couple different examples but basically
what you see here is that we got
definitely gone global
they had the attackers were definitely
focused on kind of Southeast Asia
regionally but expanded to Latin America
and India has become quite a hot spot so
the frequency is also increasing see
almost one a month so this is definitely
kind of a continuing continuing threat
and now I'm gonna get into some of the
examples so the first one will be banco
de chile which happened in 2008 2018 and
basically what happened was some very
nice friendly people posted on twitter
about how their computers wouldn't boot
and this was employees of the bank and
luckily the bank tags their monitors
with locations so we were able to figure
out what bank and then start
investigating this particular case so
this was you know a targeted intrusion
just like the others and went after
millions so there was the theft but
there was also kind of the
destructive element which I will get
into in a second
but basically that was to divert
attention away from the actual heist so
you know occupy the IT teams the
security teams and basically present
them with a bigger problem than the
actual money getting stolen so there
they did use a new tool MBR killer which
I'll which I'll talk about but actually
it wasn't the first time that we saw
destructive tactics and I think that
would have been Taiwan which was in
October 2017 so now I'm going to just
high level view of how I'm be ocular
kind of the highlights of it so this
targeted secure NTFS it sorry targeted
partitions and the wiper was implemented
in an sis language so the installer was
doing the wiping as opposed to dropping
a wiper which then did it it matched
with kind of previous Lazarus tools and
ops that we've seen so protected with VM
protect so the kind of the same cracked
version as before we what was
interesting is that we didn't actually
identify other samples that were similar
to this one and it was it might be
because it was used as a one-shot tool
even though we which I'll talk about
later with with how Lazarus is acquiring
all these wipers so the second case
study that memo pad is cosmos and this
one is quite interesting for a different
reason so the wiper aspect of Banco de
Chile made it made it pretty significant
and definitely the the bank's kind of
services went down I'm sorry went down
for for several days and just took out
the bank's network and it was completely
inaccessible so I'll talk about kind of
how the the tactics are have been
getting more aggressive so thank you
Chile at this right cosmos happened last
month in August and it's cosmos is a is
a co-operative bank in India which again
has become
a favorite of Lazarus these days so
basically this started when the FBI
released an alert on August 9th about an
imminent ATM cashout scheme so at the
time we didn't know that this was
related we only figured it out after her
two days later the actual cashing out
started so in total this was about
15,000 transactions and I think 11
million 11 million dollars across 28
countries mostly visa and mostly outside
of India and then a couple days later we
see the Swift transactions happen so
these were I think a total of 2 million
and then cosmos pick up on this and
reports to the police and and they kind
of issued the press releases and things
like that and we you know we keep
investigating the bank's cut and network
went offline for a couple weeks at least
I don't think they've reached full
functioning capacity still but it was
basically a pretty big hit so I'll just
talk through the ATM cash ups this was
kind of the really interesting bit of
the this particular attack so the
attackers got hold of cloned card
details and we actually still don't know
how this happened
it's possible they got them directly
from the bank but because of their you
know really good and prolonged access
but actually there's been no
confirmation of this so then they make
the request to withdraw money from the
ATM oh sorry that there's sorry there's
a network of mules across those 28
countries and they make the request to
withdraw from the ATM so these
transactions you know go through the
normal ATM processes the transaction
process or the interchange Network and
finally the issuing bank which in this
case is cosmos so the cloned card
details are one thing but then now when
you put that kind of request through
the the bank will want the details of
the transaction so how much money you
want to withdraw the pin number and then
they have to authorize it so usually
this is where such transaction would
have been stopped if it looks fraudulent
but the attackers in this case had a way
of manipulating the authorization
mechanism so that it would just approve
them straight away so again this is
pretty unclear about how they've
actually done that and again they could
have compromised some infrastructure
earlier on and it could just be due to
their they're really good access to the
network but that still remains remains
mystery so then the request comes back
through the ATMs and the meals are able
to withdraw the cash so this is a point
that I'll cover our kind of at the end
and the unknowns and conclusions but in
terms of where the money goes with the
other heist that's been a pretty big
pretty big mystery and having a
coordinated effort across that many
countries and likely through organized
kind of crime criminal gangs only
because I doubt Lazarus has personnel on
the ground and in that many places is is
like it is a pretty big pretty big deal
so just to go through the tools just a
little bit so nest egg is the old
backdoor that we saw that was likely
used in in in the Bangladesh Bank heist
so this is a late-stage implant I'm used
for persistence it was there are some
really interesting parts of it so the
dropper would be securely deleted from
the system and so we actually weren't
able to look at that in depth but what
we were able to see is the the back
doors modular so there was a bunch of
plugins and that includes a key logger
and a screen shutter and those were
actually the interesting bit so the
attackers would be recording kind of all
all the keystrokes and all the
screenshots of the admin and be able to
kind of if they put these together
theoretically they would have been able
to reconstruct kind of the way to get
access into the access into the network
and
admin privileges pretty easily in a
step-by-step process so that was that
was pretty significant so we saw nest
egg being used over over a couple years
and then up until about six months ago
when there was a new backdoor which is
called catch we called catch-22 so this
is the one that was used in banco de
chile and has been seen in several other
intrusions it's particularly used to
target banks very specifically and
haven't hasn't seen hasn't been seen
anywhere else also an late-stage attack
tool and deployed on admin laptops but
also hot on alliance access and alliance
web platform so these are the swift
systems these are both in the secure
zones that you can see in the in the
graphic so called catch-22 because it
has 22 functions but all the ones you
would expect of a backdoor and to carry
out this kind of attack the interesting
bit about this backdoor is the command
and control so usually malware is gonna
run as a client and communicate with
with the C&C but this one can also run
in server mode so theoretically it could
give commands to other other malware on
the network so this is pretty
interesting and it kind of plays into
the segregated segregated networks
attacks so the infected machines that
sit on on the network boundaries can
proxy connections on to other other
machines on either side so this acts as
a client and a server and has ability to
kind of initiate new connections and
proxy traffic between multiple instances
so the attackers are able to
transparently traverse internal networks
and issue commands or do recon against
machines not connected to the internet
so this is like pretty deep access and
again so this will show you how they got
access to the payment zones payment
systems in the secure zones so Swift is
trying to kind of
commenced new security controls and you
know use jump boxes but catch-22
basically circumvents that whole effort
so now just to get into some of the
interesting stuff that we don't know and
maybe just speculate on some potentials
so one why are there so many unknowns so
there's a couple reasons for this the
banks that have been targeted again as I
mentioned regionally are you know
Southeast Asia Latin America and now
India in more vulnerable vulnerable
areas of the world maybe less kind of
less attention on security but some of
it they could probably target Western
institutions and similar things would
happen but some of it is more their
ability to be kind of really vigilant
and diligent about cleanup so deleting
logs they're very careful not to leave
traces and another thing is their
presence in the network during these for
these bank heists is usually a minimum
of several months up to kind of 18
months that we saw in Bombay
so the time between infection and cash
out is really long so most of the time
you're not going to have access to kind
of logs or anything like that and so the
origin is really really difficult to
discover and yeah it kind of creates a
lot of mysteries for people who
investigating in terms of intrusion
vectors so this was a mystery up until
pretty recently and even then it's only
been a couple cases that were that were
kind of covered in the recent Department
of Justice indictment and some of the
spear phishing emails were kind of shown
in there for a couple cases but really
for the most part like I said because
the infections happen so so much longer
ago and they're usually not discovered
in the network so much so much later we
don't really know what the where the
infection came from one interesting
point is that the the watering holes
which I haven't mentioned in this
presentation but we have kind of blogged
about and stuff so watering holes in our
for 2016 and these we found them
targeting financial regulators in Poland
and Mexico so the interesting part about
this is that they had IP whitelist
because they didn't want just anyone
getting infected so they had IP
whitelist and it has whole list of
organizations on them and banco de chile
actually shows up on one of those white
lists but it's still unclear if it was
actually connected that was that would
have been 19 months before the actual
before the actual attack so we're not
sure if the watering hole was actually
the intrusion vector but an interesting
point that they were thinking so far
ahead so next one is really interesting
and kind of terrifying so the access to
the Swift Alliance access server so we
again we've been investigating these for
for over two years now and Swift has
been also obviously implementing new
controls and kind of trying to respond
to these these threats and these
intrusions but every time they implement
new controls it seems like pretty much
like child's play for Lazarus to kind of
circumvent those and they don't seem to
have any trouble oh really so the theory
is which again totally speculation but
might have access to a live Swift server
either through compromise or some other
way but basically there that seems to be
the only explanation for them being able
to keep up so so easily and without
having any of these new controls deter
their deter their attacks another thing
is the wiper acquisition and
distribution so acquisition this I mean
so there was a ransomware that was used
in the Taiwan heist called Hermes and
this one there is there are similar
versions of the of the ransom more out
there but this particular version was
only seen being used by Lazarus but
because of the overlaps we suspect it
might be a shared tool or purchase tool
and again with their use of MB our
killer in
banco de chile it's it's possible that
these are just commercial kind of off
the shelf tools and they may customize
them a little bit but it looks like they
have kind of just easy access to to
these whether they're buying them or or
finding them so this is probably
something we'll keep seeing but again we
don't actually know where they where
they come from but it's a low-cost kind
of high-impact way of advancing their
their attacks distribution is an
interesting point for mb our killer in
particular we don't actually know how
they managed to get all of that wiper to
across all the machines on the network
kind of at the same time there's no
evidence of worm-like propagation it
still seems pretty unclear but because
of their access again we assume this
could be due to some kind of built-in
Windows functionality or kind of through
through deploying tools the tool as an
update or something that will basically
be able to impact the entire network at
the same time just by leveraging
legitimate legitimate processes and
lastly where does the money go so this
is a pretty interesting one and kind of
out of our jurisdiction a little bit I
don't really do money laundering mostly
just look at the intrusions but since
Bangladesh and up until cosmos in
between there's been pretty you know
very kind of few insights into what
happens to all those millions so in the
Philippines for the Bangladesh bank
heist
they definitely laundered that money
through casinos but because there are
the casinos are exempt from reporting
you know that kind of activity in that
jurisdiction so really it kind of ended
up being a dead end and likely the
theory is that you know again because
they have mules everywhere which we kind
of saw evidenced by the ATM cashout for
cosmos that they're using kind of
criminal networks local criminal that
to kind of get the money out and it's
likely just being funneled to places
where there where kind of a they operate
again how people get the funds this is
still this is still really new the ATM
cashout is something that is gonna is
something I'm trying something new and
it seems to be a pretty successful
compared to compared to the Bangladesh
Bank heist and yeah so that's the
mystery about money I'm still working on
that for a wrap up I just want to look
at a couple kind of conclusions again
like I said these targeted intrusions
haven't been slowing down if anything
they're increasing getting they're
getting bold even more than before so
this is something that definitely should
be looked out for and I think the
important thing to note here is again
cosmos being a good example of the
overlap between a financial crime and
and cyber operations so there's multiple
kind of aspects to this to these attacks
diversify and techniques I keep
mentioning the cash out but this is
actually it pretty new they did try that
but two days later you can see them
reverting back to their old kind of
their old habits which is the Swift
transactions because getting money out
of the system is probably one of the
harder parts arguably more more
difficult than the actual intrusions
themselves because those seem to be
pretty pretty easy for them but getting
that money out of the system has been
tricky and especially because with
decision is such a hot topic now and
people are paying a lot of attention so
this is a much more decentralized way of
doing that but because the payout is so
good and you know you can take millions
out of at one time we kind of anticipate
seeing Swift targeted more more just as
much like I said I just mentioned the
the tools that they've used again nest
egg sort of them pretty well for a
couple years it's really kind of
advanced you know back door and I was
doing well they've kind of implemented a
bit a bit of a new
tool set now and we've seen catch-22
used in kind of multiple intrusions
they're still really invested and
developing so I wouldn't be surprised if
they got even more creative so I do want
to mention that with these wipers
especially the nature of these attacks
is getting more aggressive and though
they're just using them kind of as a
diversion and to cover up the heist
themselves and it's not really investing
much in the wipers themselves
considering they've probably just
grabbed them again commercially they're
they're really playing with fire so I
don't think they have quite got the hang
of controlling them but again that's not
really their problem because it has the
kind of does the job that they wanted to
do but for the bank's this is quite
impactful and again banks networks going
offline for that long and creating
accessibility issues this is kind of a
severe hit to the financial system
potentially if they get worse yeah so
like I said there's been a lot more
attention on Swift controls and kind of
improving those defenses that being said
not only have they been able to
circumvent those but also it still
leaves national banks vulnerable and
again if you look at their targeting in
terms of which banks they're going after
regionally some of these will not have
as good not have as good security and so
this is like this is pretty advantageous
for them to continue targeting and
there's obviously a whole long list and
they are in kind of multiple banks at
the same time around the world and one
of the other things that we don't really
know is kind of when you know when
they're going to when they're going to
kind of stage those heists doing recon
for months and months and you know with
one Galatia Bank we saw kind of the the
timing over the weekend it was really
coordinated and there was a whole there
was a big reason for why they did it
that way
and those particular dates but with the
kind of increased attacks that we see
now there isn't really any rhyme or
reason that I've seen so far
doing basically doing pretty well that's
pretty much all I have so thanks for
listening and if you have any questions
let me know
[Applause]