all right next up where's my notes yeah
is Edwin Fernando Telecom Evelyn he's
not here yet but he will be soon he was
going to talk about yeah basically all
Phil's a name for sex so I hope you will
enjoy it give him a warm round of
applause and have a lot of fun take it
away
[Applause]
[Music]
hello thank you thank you for the
introduction right awesome you are all
here let's have a bit of fun but first
some seriousness have you heard this
story it's a Dutch guy he did a lot of
info security stuff he helped a lot of
researches be secure and he helped a lot
of press be secure he's missing he went
on a holiday in Norway and he's missing
now for over a month so if you have any
friends in Norway or whatever please
inform and try if we can find him
because it's very horrible for us
because we were on stage a lot and for
his family so serious things there as
always warning I fly too much so if I
cuff I mean yeah I'm sorry when you're
flying you get a call to keep having
colds everybody knows who does this work
so excuse me in front
oh yeah the audio guys I really loved
how he was near the blue points so I
took a little further
he's called Sam but let's now call him
Mickey and Cooper as always thanks for
all the video work and of course all the
awesome besides guys you're perfect
anybody on the 15 no is it legal no it's
not legal okay some slides are a bit
scary but you could use it as always I'm
giving away some matter I know you can
get it in for free but I do it anyway so
if you anybody never drank my tea by the
way yeah would you like to try it's
really awesome
it tastes like cigar makes my friends
tease yeah
is really cool right do you know what
this is by the way the picture no give
it guys the guy in the back yeah this is
the Internet 1973 somewhat so you want a
bottle congratulations you can get it
here or over there
whatever ah leave it leave it it's just
for the idea alright Who am I I'm Edwin
and some of you may know me from last
year I pushed a lot of buttons when I
was younger played with the old modems
anybody remember the modems yeah for
sure yeah awesome times right for the
people who don't you downloaded Ferdie
floppies in that floppy 29 you might
have picked up the phone and everything
was gone that's the area where from it
was horrible and now what I'm doing now
is basically building a company with all
my heck of friends that's the idea I
mean there's so much brilliant minds
even in this room and why not drive in
washing machines cars or whatever and
you can build and you can hack them and
everybody knows what the firm abilities
are and that's what we're doing at the
moment we're running researcher program
we do a lot of coordinate vulnerability
disclosure for clients and we run
scanners so that's the the business part
but basically what I'm doing and as I'm
doing now is just this you know I fly
around the world can hack attacker
conferences have a lot of friends it's
really awesome that's one of my best
buddies and I'm still yeah pretty amazed
that the suit is in this size but he
made it so please happy free time I'm
doing this the guilt of the grumpy old
hackers or in touch with some notes cup
from the hekawis hackers try that if
you're any listen what we do is we help
younger kids who try to do things
yeah like hacking and finding databases
and not knowing what to do with him and
going to the criminal site we try to get
them back as a lot of older hackers and
it works it works we work with
government Justice Department etc and
it's awesome and I'm doing the cavalry I
think a lot of you know I am the cavalry
some okay what what we do there is we
try to educate car manufacturers medical
manufacturers and stuff just to make
things more secure which is really
needed because a couple of years ago we
had a talk with a car manufacturer and
we say the device in your car we can
take it over and we can
dear the car and it's broken and he said
yeah we know we were like but if you
know why don't you fix it and they say
well there's no law and that I need to
fix it and my competition doesn't have
to fix it and I if I fix it it cost me a
lot of money and then we say what if we
kill somebody with your car and you say
are we just gonna pay the people's
family that's it and those conversations
for us are really hard but we're not
here for that we're here for a little
bit fun so I thought let's talk about
experts you know the idea of experts the
experts idea is that you get some hex
somewhere or some problem with him for
security and people asked experts for
television programs it's really awesome
to see in the Netherlands we had a
couple of this year sorry earlier this
year we had this Dutch banks are
targeted by DDoS attacks and it impacted
people because they couldn't get their
money out so then it's national news so
every news station was asking for
experts and yeah I suddenly have to say
I was one as well but luckily they had
beer so I have fun this was one show and
and of course we talked about the
contents but on our national television
there was this lady
Rihanna from Rye Brook and Riaan phone
right was sitting there and she was
talking for an hour on Dutch primetime
television about the DDoS attacks which
is good but our phone started ringing
while we were at the other show and we
thought what's the problem the problem
was this lady had written a book
together with a politician who was known
to write books with experts and she was
world's best hacker for over 40 years
that's cool but a bit weird that nobody
in the hacking community had ever heard
of this lady so we were a bit skeptical
she talked about security and how she
broke things in her life and one time
she mentioned this so can you guess what
she was telling no it's like we call it
latest in the Netherlands combine the
two things what do you see on the left
sorry yeah
but what's what's deploying in his face
basically yeah and this one is what is
it it's a network so she was talking
about airbag networks
I think Siemens air gap networks but huh
everybody took it for granted
so that was a little indication that she
might be a little off then she was
talking about she had an app on her
phone where she could walk to an ATM and
get all the money out I think you still
need a drill for that it's true but then
yet in the end the most brilliant
solution for all of our hacking problems
and that one is still a big hit with the
hacking community in the Netherlands
because she said that every hacking
problem could be solved by putting your
stuff in the smart blockchain I'm not
sure I don't know what smart blockchain
is and the problem is nobody knows what
smart blockchain is but see that after
this he got two states presents assists
and then they found out the book was
copied from a lot of different sources
and she is now gone and nobody knows
where she is oh yeah Kaspersky also sued
her because he said she broke into
Kaspersky Wow
brilliant all right so you reminded me a
little bit of this guy do you know this
guy you guys know this one right guy
Gama awesome good for the people who
down now he got interviewed by BBC for a
job I'm not sure what data scientists or
whatever and I put him on the show
because somebody has to tell something
about iPhone security and he had no
fucking clue it's a really awesome video
if you look at it different problem we
have is focus in the Netherlands we have
a major hotel chain and they had a new
thing namely that they had an app and
with the app you get your room keys on
your mobile you walk through your door
and you open the door with your mobile
awesome service but to launch this stuff
they invited hackers because when they
fought what better a commercial failure
can we give this if we invite Equis put
it on the television and let's see how
safe our APIs so they invited me as well
which
she was a bit of a stupid idea and they
I came there and and they showed me the
look and they showed me the app and I
said what do you want us to do and they
said well we made a beautiful app and we
a solve it and now you can see if you
can break it I said but what's the point
of this exercise and they were like what
do you mean and they were all in suits
you know the bow tie
and I said I think the essence for me is
to get into the room right yes that's
the idea you have to get into the room I
said cool I calculated that in our
broader 80 pounds fishing magnet put it
on the lock did this and the lock was
open and then the whole board was like
no that's not what we mean it's about
focus people
if you hire your hackers they are not
going to break an app for three days if
they can walk in by an open door
what should we we are lazy that's what
we do we think completely different who
of us Tesla no one I look under your
seats
you never know okay you know Tesla's the
the self-driving mode right and you have
to every 10 minutes you have to grab the
steering wheel just to make sure you're
still awake you don't need to if you
have an orange
[Music]
this shit works works you have to do
this though but if you look and think
about how this works then this stuff
scares me I'm not sure if you're aware
of it but there are some acyl standards
which indicates the you had the need for
safety in the car so if it is D is very
very needed and I think a is not so much
and if you look at how this works in for
instance with the Tesla self-steering is
D so it's very very important
but sensor data sensor feedback
incorrect Rebecca's just to be how are
you gonna match that if your car as
sensor feedback which is not right and
you do self steering I mean I know a guy
who has Tesla and they told him that if
you put it on outer steering but you
near a traffic light you have to put it
manually off because it doesn't
recognize traffic lights I can get it I
don't get that stuff and I think a lot
of people don't get it and yeah even
people there was talk about people
already but this stuff have you seen it
Strava yeah
military bases were completely mapped
because of all the fitbit's everybody
wears even into which barrack they go
and you know outside on the table you've
seen this so for you it's not a big
question I think was this the training
padlock Falak picking you want a bottle
have fun with it
geez and cigars but this thing shouldn't
be I think on an RAF base what
what is there I don't know I'm sorry
talking about Breaking and Entering
which if you smoke still here nobody
yeah it's a guy yeah you but it's a
dying dying thing and I mean it used to
be so much fun for us to walk in with
the smoking people but it's difficult
for us now we have to do dumpster diving
to get all the passwords and the broken
keys we found a lot of RFID cards for
entrance cut through half doesn't make
any sense because there's this little
sensor area which we you can still clung
so it's really awesome and what also is
really fun for us is their first aid for
four companies what we do is we look at
a company and we see who are responsible
for first day we get to people in
supposably when one of those guys is on
holiday and we say yeah this is an
unannounced drill from the guy who was
in holiday and he did it because he is
on holiday so nobody will expect it at
your offices and one guy has a burn here
and we say he had had an accident
in the server room and nine out of ten
times we are walked into the server room
we can put some USB in we lay down
somebody comes give us a bandage and we
walk out it's that easy to get into a
building and the finger almost surprises
me if we are in buildings is this if you
are in the security mindset and this is
not a trick question which lock would
you pick which a big lock number one to
the left or lock them - to the right -
right everybody chooses - then why are
all the keys still behind one if we are
in availing the most easy heck of a lock
is the lock for all the keys that we are
it's stupid
and you've got all these stacks right
you're a very secure but you have people
sitting like this in toilets and then
it's so easy for us to clone keys and if
we have a lot of money we buy stuff like
this the bus clone or kit do you know it
it's really awesome you get a bag with a
big antenna and ten carts and different
frequencies and app on your mobile and I
stand within about I think it's 40 feet
here or sorry three feet and I can just
say clone and it clones all the cards it
can see I can take it out of my bag
again it's fun to do that but it's
expensive so we have also stuff like
this and I brought this one with me this
is $19 $19 and you can have so much fun
with it I will put it on it is from
China so don't plug it in and it has a
warning you know it's it just says if
you're going to use this for illegal
purposes press cancel so I vote L key
and I will try if it works this time and
the button beneath this is right
so with empty cars you can have a lot of
fun for just $19 we and the office just
got this an espresso machine for coffee
and you get a card with it with 300
credits on it we are a hacking company
let's see how long this takes
well we just cloned this one on that one
and we ordered one cup of coffee and we
looked at the differences wow it's just
four bytes difference so now everybody
in the office is 999 cups of coffee and
we tried of course SP like hello and
stuff like that but then the machine
died so don't do it but I think if this
works let's see yeah this is me trying
with the white card yeah awesome
really cool stuff but elderly people
don't get this you know and and
everybody says the older we get the
better and it was so good in the old
days and what I see now is is criminals
even thinking this way because last year
in the Netherlands and you don't believe
it this came via mill by someone regular
meal and it states dear blah blah blah
at week 29 a DDoS attack will take place
on your business and you can prevent it
if you pay and there was a Bitcoin
address underneath and they cut it out
of papers and send it via
most really awesome really awesome
people don't get it I mean the set of
slide I have is coming up now are you
ready so said she does this every day
it's so sad she has no clue that we are
building harpoons stuff in cables you
know you cannot trust any cable and even
the Chinese now have upgraded this
there's a version with a cell element in
it so you can see remote what kind of
data travels through a cable this came
out I think two weeks ago researchers
can now spy on your laptop via the sound
of your USB or your microphone of your
camera they hear pixels change and
they've made a system that maps out the
pixel noises to data they have and they
can predict what's on your screen Wow I
mean this stuff awesome have you seen
this blue spoof it was on DEFCON I think
last year this guy for that next right
part is basically sound so we recorded
max stripes on it on this laptop made
web files out of it and played it back
to a Bluetooth speaker where he replaced
the speaker with a coil and this works
this gets you free drinks if you replay
your web files via this speaker it's
really cool we should do more and this I
mean although people don't get it but
but just imagine that you do you know
what this is by the way a Furby yeah
without the skin they're better without
the skin if we just imagine that it's
Christmas and you just gave your
four-year-old needs this Furby and she's
playing near the fireplace near the
window right and we'll see how this
works now is audio coming up do you hear
something yeah
[Music]
you can just write everything to move to
sex Oh your little meat is now scared
yeah this is it this is what I did a
couple of days ago because I had to
write this talk but I'm easily
distracted I know if you guys know that
but I was yeah waiting and trying and I
was a bit bored so what I did is I
thought what if I make a Twitter search
based on cards and info and see TV and
stuff like that so I just resolves
quitters Twitter scraper and search for
card and number and is and I thought
this will not get much right okay
so what I got back was a little bit
scary for instance this one I love this
one there's a something about a nectar
card I'm not sure if it's something
maybe yeah you know what it is okay is
it something a loyalty card okay but I
like it and they said give this please
in a DM well what's DM anyway it's my
card number ok but this is pretty normal
so this one also don't think that DM is
an issue
please DM your number and Raymond says
well my ID number is this I'm a customer
number says I'm a car normal is this
it's easy it's just Twitter here's the
bank who was a bit more loyal I think
because this lady wanted a waiver on 40k
and spell
interracial statements this microRNA Moe
blah blah blah and then the back said
please delete this tweet wow that's nice
surface of the bank you know we have to
see more stuff like this and this area
cannot show this one yeah this one was
also there sir
no no idea why I can read this I think
it's mostly yeah people are a bit like
this most of the time all right
um I work at zero copter above manatee
platform yeah come on is also coming to
tell something yeah soon yeah like one
friends on the other side of the of the
big blue ocean let's put it that way and
also by the way there's there's a
gentleman in the back I have to do this
I'm sorry man he's head of security of a
very big firm and he's still laughing
it's awesome I never meet security guys
who are still having so much fun so
absolument awesome why bug bounties why
pentest well basically this is one for
me in apparently people have lots more
fun and lots more time to find stuff i
mean we still have a lot of companies
that say yeah i do a pen test once a
year out at school and what's your
development cycle every two months we
release a new tool that doesn't mess you
know you have to make sure that you have
something matching Burkman these are
great cvd is great but we get a lot of
questions from companies who are a
little bit scared and one of the
questions is always are they qualified
well i don't know if you can see the
lady's hand
see is not that qualified but yes
they're qualified they don't do anything
else there are a bug when tiaras making
more than a million a year with with
finding stuff and keeping company safe
to sure they're qualified and then the
next question is yeah but are they from
the netherlands no of course they're not
from the netherlands we are very small
country we don't have that many acres we
have a lot but not enough so basically
this is our researcher location map we
have 60 percent the mayor 20 percent in
america etc etc then the big question
how do you check those guys and that's
the question what we in our platform say
is we check everybody who is a member of
our platform so we do ID checks
background checks etc this guy checks a
lot of
I'm not it this is also not me do you
know lick build I advise no it's awesome
I do another CCC conference in Germany
yeah go there and then for 10 euro she
get one of those house Weiss's and it
says Leif build housewives with whatever
you want on it and from the back it's
also just an ID card and a lot of
companies public buildings government's
accept this because they have no fucking
clue what it is it is really awesome it
looks so legit they look like yeah okay
looks like an ID welcome really cool we
even had the reporter in the Netherlands
try this to get into the home of the
Queen and it works it's really really
scary so buy this shit but we check them
and and once they did yeah bad stuff on
the net we don't let them in and then
the final question which always pops up
is they are hackers you cannot trust
them and then I always tried to counter
but if you go to a hospital and there's
doctors wearing fucking masks yeah do
you think that if you have an operation
they will steal your kidney why would
they do it it's the same with our guys
and of course there are some stupid guys
doing web bounties and that's always
there but if we have to just work around
it I mean this is what we see a lot I
want to warn you you have tcp 3-1 to 804
a bottle of matter what is it no it's
not remote desktop and next one squid
yeah your local proxy or those people
are hacking their own networks awesome
and we get still a lot of people doing
shit like this this one is also great
the guy warning a company which our
friends with us that there was a login
page somewhere and if an attacker could
guess user name and password they would
get in how is this in the first place a
security vulnerability and they have
even didn't look because there was also
two-factor authentication on the page
but don't bother to do
stuff like that we get a little bit more
scared with when we see stuff like this
I want to warn here you are vulnerable
to CVD blah blah blah now we're
interested but then you look at it and
it's a PHP mailer remote code execution
while we are running a Ruby on Rails
framework it's sometimes gets you in the
walls you know so yeah this is not a
really nice picture but I love it
this one heck own props due to improper
configuration the following directories
open and the files are listed okay that
could be scary but it's basically a
remote distribution of deviance so have
you had the time to consider whether
this might be intentionally left like
this people are still reporting shit
like this and if you want more of this
go to book Monte dot fill by Melvin he
has a lot of bug bounties which were
opened where you can laugh your asses
off if you are if you are in mood also
responses is always a problem and yeah
last year I think I did this as well so
I will go pretty quickly through this
but this one brilliant who were closing
a report on Echo one and this guy says
you beeping beeping beeping beeping I
know this is out of scope and your team
member Bella bloody BBB taxi driver
you don't say taxi driver to River that
doesn't work you don't get a lot of
creds but also the replies from the
other side suck this cross-site
scripting you know what it is the best
response ever came from a guy I think
whose name is Kevin who told the people
it looks like you are trying to add
javascript in the gallery which isn't
possible you should need to add letters
and numbers only do you get this it
means that even the guys who build stuff
like that thing that if you can put code
in your fields that is not an issue and
you shouldn't just put code in the field
because it's not intended to put code in
the field
that's what we live for you know get off
my lawn and this is also a big problem
we run for a lot of big companies we do
a lot of CVD scored on either fun or
ability disclosures what means that a
company says if you have anything to
submit or if you find a security issue
on my site or my product please report
it we triage it for them and then it
goes to the client but then when
somebody reports something in the end
when it's off they want to brag about it
you know if you find something really
cool at a big site you want to write
something about it and still that's a
big issue with a lot of our clients
because they don't want the publicity
even after it's fixed that they had a
problem so we have this guy in the
Netherlands Jonathan Bauman I promised
to put his name and his stuff on it just
because yeah I borrow his stuff now
and he had a problem with one company
can you guess which one
yes okay it's a little bit Swedish but
let's go what he did as most of those
guys do is he scoured for interesting
domain names and he found a lot of them
and he was interested by one which was
the bathroom planner and in the bathroom
planner you can plan your bathroom and
you can later build it which is really
awesome if you are done with selecting
all the stuff you have an option
together PDF out of it how to generate a
PDF that's pretty cool so what he did he
he looked at the county put burp suite
or whatever in between and he found an
interesting string which he decoded and
there was a lot of stuff going on with
getting the images from the server so he
thought what if I just put my own stuff
in it and asked for etc' password would
this work and he tried and he failed
which is good of course but then he
looked something further and he found
out that the library they used wasn't up
to date completely so there was another
option with an annotation file so he put
in this code in his replay attack it's a
password content etc and it's write it
and voila
in his new PDF wasn't
annotation with the passwords of the
IKEA server that's cool
so he reported this but whatever we
tried he could not get the allowance to
publish this so in the end we basically
put IKEA people together with him he
explained it we tried to help them and
now he finally has made this beautiful
stuff so you can look it up and it's
really awesome but I think if you do bug
money's if you do responsible
disclosures of course you can pay
directly you can give him shirts but
also let them please tell everybody what
they found because it will help awful
lot of other companies who have the same
problem so try to do stuff like this hug
them like you mean it
yeah teams after this conference you see
but what's in it okay now I'm gonna piss
some people off is there tell us people
in the room no no okay now I'm not gonna
piss you off of course not but sometimes
I wonder because if you see this Siemens
was act foreign the Giga bytes of
information on SCADA systems is out
there I'm not sure if they found it yet
but it's pretty scary because it runs a
lot of factories waterways etc etc etc
but they say indictments for ft3
and I always get worried I mean I saw
the keynote this morning I saw it a
little bit and they were also doing what
I'm going to do now but they say it
works the Internet is pretty big it
isn't one country we have in the
Netherlands by the way one politician
who says we have to border and caption
the Internet so that there will be
internet only in the Netherlands and not
connected to other parts of the world
wow I'm really looking forward to that
one this one we have seen it of course
one a cry and what they say as well this
was North Korea and the other guy said
it as well and they do it because of
this type of stuff you know I used to
write an assembler so I noticed they say
if you're matching code lines then it's
probably the same as I can cut and paste
some code lines in it how am I sure that
this is the issue I mean if I was North
Korea I would be laughing
and we have a picture of them laughing
their asses off on this news
this one also yeah now we also know it
because we hacked into North Korean
networks and we saw them type it well if
you hacked into somebody's computer and
saw them type it can't you just type it
yourself on their computer I'm just
wondering you know I'm not saying it is
true or whatever but I'm just wondering
this also US official say Russian
digital fingerprints on election X and
why because somebody used a keyboard
with Cyrillic characters I have one
wanna borrow it you know now a Russian
criminal awesome
this is stupid you know people still
don't understand you can help and you
can use different countries to get in
and out and you can use tor to do all
the stuff you want people don't know and
we have to educate them we have to know
how it works and I think there's only
one only one who has it right all the
time when it goes to this sort of stuff
I want to see it um yeah but what's
right again you know why because it's a
looping gif yeah I'm going to the end
because we're always running out of time
so I'll make this quick I have a dream
and I'd shared this last year with you
as well but I would still want to share
it if you look at all the ecers we have
about five to seven percent does it for
good just want to help don't want
anything in return maybe about me or
whatever you still have 30 percent of
companies looking into other companies
espionage will still be the same 50
percent anonymous and people like that
perfect ten percent basically script
Cadiz and then 40 percent people go in
the criminal way well in the Netherlands
we find that going the criminal might
means mostly that people are 14 15 16
years working in there there are small
rooms upstairs
finding a database with weird accordion
for knowing they cannot use it but
shouting about it to their friends then
the criminal
says for 10,000 euro I'd buy their
database of you what do you do when
you're 14 years old you get ten thousand
euros for database you can't use
yourself you do it but they don't think
about the fact that after a month the
criminals are coming back and saying
give me another one give me another one
give me another one or I will do this or
that or this or that what if and we can
help those kids and we can make sure
that they connect on platforms like
hacker one on platforms like dike what
will zero copter for instance and get
them money for hacking you know let them
do what they like and just make money
out of it and help the world get more
secure if the 10% of script code is we
have why don't we educate them why don't
we take them in and our security firms
and learn they want to learn how to act
why don't we help them we are doing it
in the Netherlands even with government
people who are mildly punished for stuff
that they do we take them in and we let
them see what security is and how it
works and what we can do with it if that
will work in an ideal world 55% of all
the hackers would be on the good side
now then we will have a safer internet
and I'm sure it's it's utopia but the
more we can build to it the better and
the safer we will be so I will go to my
last and final slide as always I hope
you had a bit of fun you can forget
everything I always tell you doesn't
matter as long as you remember the right
part of the last slide ready there you
go hackers are sweet people hackers can
help you yourself might be a could just
spread the words and make sure that
everybody uses everything here thank you
very much
other questions no questions no time
okay see you guys later bye