I'm gonna run through really quickly
just to welcome everyone tell you where
things are important things like Wi-Fi
passwords and then Boston at the front
we'll be doing a keynote so I'll be very
quick we will make up the time probably
during the coffee break
hopefully all been well M so yes thank
you everyone for coming along obligatory
new working keyboards to accent the
polygamy wall of text here just to tell
you not to do things so we're gonna run
through tracks as we did last year
schedules and all the booklets you have
in your bike and online if you need it
room the zero day event again sorry CTF
event with zero days ie so you can do
that as an individual or a team guys are
all there if you want to take part I
think we do have prizes so you can win
some nice stuff and sponsor as you came
through is out there so all of our
beautiful sponsors is paid for us all to
be here today we have a lock-picking
clinic with jester who's white but not
on here yes there's more in a t-shirt
that says mr. hacker has long hair a
beard and he'll teach you how to
lockpick it feels very interesting we've
a CV clinic this year so IP Security's
quite hard to get into for a lot of
people's who CVS or where a lot of
people stumble off so we have a nice
recruiter here with us who actually
calls herself an evil recruiter but if
you find rooms Rouge will take you
through in the CV clinic if you want to
update your CV if you want a few hands
in tips etcetera
we have club motto for I don't know why
we have love mat takers it's awful boy
boy those nine people who like it it's
awful well we do have Matteo at the
front tea coffee etcetera we do have an
after-party as well which I'll tell you
about in a minute
my keyboard is grid trackball is gonna
be me in here today organising kicking
things off a track - we will have Edwin
who will show you in a minute
importantly Wi-Fi password here's things
please don't pack the Wi-Fi or take a
boy with a Wi-Fi I know I shouldn't have
to say that but but please don't hear
things are very nice to let us use it so
don't break it please the man you're
looking for in track 2 is admin if any
of you guys been coming for the last few
years haven't I noted for us the first
year so he's gonna look after everybody
in track 2 so if any of the tops you
won't see or anything you need sorted
out and track to just grab admin and
there he is beautiful
tall man
I was keeping her if you've any issues
find any one of us in Reb so me Ryan
Cooper TJ Michelle etc a couple of
people by just any woman read and we'll
try and help you order get to supervise
toilets just outside I walk in the door
go right man upstairs within downstairs
yes please make sure your phones are off
or silent or write to appreciate people
probably are still working in and
sellers and emails but have a better
respect to the speakers and stuff and
obviously Cooper's recording and things
so just be quiet with your fool if you
need to use it Sarah and if you've gone
it annoyed just watch some of the doors
this one particularly will slam so it
can be a bit off-putting if you're
speaking yeah respect the venue is
imagined don't do break the Wi-Fi we
could launch 1230 all right yes so that
will be out there so we'll have lots of
food for everyone obviously if you
didn't want this feel free to go I don't
in the industry there's a couple
sandwich areas and stuff like that if
you need anything else just lastly learn
but clearly that's not last because we
had to add some stuff into not not
lastly have fun talk Network learn meet
friends we run this event because we
want to bring people together we bring
some really interesting and really
awesome speakers here to try and teach
you guys and obviously try and give you
guys the ability to be able to talk to
and stuff tweet and follow us so at
besides Belfast if you want to tweet and
hang pictures hashtags etcetera we do
have a photographer greenness in here in
the corner if some people do not want
their photograph taken please let me
know snoop he'll be taking group shots
it's heiress who if you don't want to be
involved we totally respect and
appreciate your privacy just never eNOS
knew and we'll try and make sure you
know involved in a shots badges
everybody special this year new
different parties everybody's the same
the only different thing we have is like
I said blue t-shirts are any of the
staff or any supporting crew members so
fat suit if you need anyone grab us
speak to us blue t-shirts or your
beautiful people put them on if you want
weather for another day etcetera we've
brought them all I for everyone very
quickly sponsors thank you Game three
returning sponsors and new sponsors
towels this year our our diamond sponsor
our top-tier sponsor they very kindly
sponsored an after-party as well which
I'll tell you all by the moon so thank
you to them
platinum sponsors we go returning I was
on Roberts
we've got new from an online synopsis as
I said all these guys are right here so
please do good chapters and talk to him
free swag which everybody likes to go
grab stuff we've then got logically
secured a new sponsor this year and an
alert logic a returning sponsor and
improve point another and you sponsor in
our cool section a keen mingle with them
talk to them find out what they do growl
some other swag see if they've any jobs
silver is brown human consulting
Sylvia's consultant from dinosaur I've
been assured that all of our sponsors
are trying to recruit so if anybody is
looking just please have a discussion
with them speak tune there should be new
recruiters here I'd say I take that back
we welcome recruiters but we don't
please want you to try and recruit on
the day we do want you see the
harvesting CV hunting our sponsors have
paid to be here and we appreciate if you
didn't do that we haven't had any issues
with in the past but if there are
recruiters here please do we do not
actually sponsors so yeah awesome guys
we do some work with across the water
besides Manchester Glasgow to London and
guys they can't so these are just guys
we talked to in rona Vance Cooper very
kindly videos moves to these I believe
Cooper to G over 1m so yeah Cubert very
kindly does this for free which saves us
a lot of money as well make sure all the
videos are available online so if
there's a talk you want to see and it's
two at the same time don't worry we
publish everything you'll be on youtube
on our website after party is there any
more like skin drug for free so after
party is in Lavery's and mr. Tom's loins
Gihon if you've been here the last few
years that's where we've had it it's a
private event you will need a wristband
that I don't have on but you will need a
risk fund and through the talos booth
there is where you will get your
wristband the wristband will allow you
and will allow you to drink for free
which is obviously quite important so
thank you for Tallis for investing an
essential Network opportunity which
allows everyone to benefit greatly and
have fun be sad we'll enjoy yourself
don't get too drunk be careful with what
you're drinking at Sarah if you need any
help here just let us know that's going
to be kicking off at half seven yeah so
we're probably going to finish about
half six and then let people get food
etc and then up there for half seven all
being
and thank you for listening we've got
our keynote speaker next and that's mr.
Coston drive from kaspersky Causton is
gonna be talking about super charging
threat hunting I think that right so
thank you everyone have fun like I say
if you need any help grab someone and
we'll get this all right thank you