okay perfect
so now we are going to have our last
session which is the contributor talks
we are going to have six interesting
talks here
and we are going to start the first one
uh but just to let you know you can ask
all your questions at the end of each
talk uh either by raising hands and
opening up your mic
or you can just write it in the chat so
we can ask you a question from the
speakers so the first talk is uh called
nora crypt is not private uh which the
speaker is going to tell us how they
could attack this nora crypt library
uh said mahuji fire is going to speak
for us and the floor is yours say start
please
thanks do you see my screen
yes perfect
great thank you very much uh onsite
knowledge fire we'll talk about our
world no crypt is not private this is a
joint work with nicholas sanja somash
mohammed and
floyd right let's start
let's start with the problem setup so we
have two parties alice and bob alice has
access to a data set bob has access to a
learning algorithm and the computational
power to
run that learning algorithm alice wants
to use this learning algorithm to get a
model but she doesn't want to send the
data in plane so she first encodes her
data using some
encoding scheme that potentially takes
keys and sends this data set to bar
bob trains the model on this encoded
data and sends it back to send the model
back to alice and now alice can use this
model in a very specific way that is
before feeding the instances to the
model she has to encode it with the same
key and only then she can expect to see
the right answer
they call this uh
primitive uh private learning with
instance encoding
and uh neural crypt is a recent uh
proposal that tries to achieve this
primitive uh through
encodings by random neural networks
so let's see how it works um
it basically only introduces a new
encoding algorithm that uses neural
networks and it doesn't change anything
about the learning algorithm learning
algorithms is a typical learning
algorithm that you apply to neural
networks but before doing that you use
their encoding scheme which has two
procedures the key generation and
encoding the key generation just samples
a neural network with random weights
and that will be the key and when you
want to encode you just run your input
on this
random run network so this bottom
picture has the exact architecture of
the rockery
it has some other details like the
random
permutation at the last layer but you
don't have to worry about that you can
just think of this as a
new neural network with random
widths so what is the privacy definition
here so they define the notion of
perfect privacy that is uh saying for
any two
instances or images with the same label
you expect the distribution of the
encoding to be exactly equal
and the distribution is taken over the
the different keys so that this when you
change the key you expect for any two
distributions of the encodings to be
exact
this is the privacy definition how do
they analyze this
their encoding so they first show a
proof of concept and coding called ideal
encoding that does the following so it
takes an instance and maps it to another
instance with the same label for example
it takes a cat image and maps it to
another cat image
in in the space of all possible cat
images
so
they they show that this skin can
actually achieve perfect privacy and it
could also be used for learning because
um you are preserving a lot of good
information you are just mapping the
chat to another child so it should be
still learnable and
at the end they they claim that murakrid
approximates the idea that
so this is the intuition behind the
privacy of this
so
uh
to to back their claim they provide two
challenge datasets the first challenge
is a
combination of 10 000 images with their
encodings and they ask the community to
match these encodings to the plain
images
they also have another challenge that i
don't want to talk about it here but
i'll get back to it a bit later
so in our paper our contribution was to
first of all break challenge one
so we show that with hundred percent
accuracy you can match the uh
images with their encoding in the
challenge data set we also instantiate
this challenge with our own data set and
we
get the same result so this shows that
neural crypt is not
does not have the perfect privacy and is
not an approximation of the idea of
coding
in a high level the the idea behind
their attack the the high level
intuition is that we use the statistical
invariance in different layers of a
random neural network
for example if you look at the mean
of the pixels in the image you expect a
particular behavior as you go through
the different layers of the network
specifically when your rates are
selected and run
we use this intuition and design our
attack to match the final encodings and
the inputs and we do it specifically in
three steps
so the first step of our attack uh we
train and embedding
uh
that its goal is to map images and their
encodings to almost the same point in
the embedding space so we want the
embedding of the image and its encoding
to be close to each other
but for any other image we want the
encode the embedding of it to be far
from the embedding of the originals so
this is the property that we want in
this embedding we do this by training a
neural network using
standard loss functions for the school
but before that we
calculate the moment vectors of these
images and
give us the give the neural network some
hints of where to look at so we just
asked the neural networks to just look
at the this moment they towards the mean
the variance and up to eighth moment uh
and calculate the embedding just based
on this and this is
why i call it a statistical invariance
because what the embedding is doing is
basically finding some
invariance in the statistics
uh so in the second step what we do is
we use this uh embedding that we trained
on our own data set to find uh some
similarity metric between all the pairs
of encodings and images and after we do
this we just solve the maximum matching
problem on the quadratic graph and that
will be our final match
and as we show this this tag obtains 100
percent accuracy
all right so what about challenge 2 so
uh i didn't tell you what challenge 2
was challenge 2 gives us the encoded
dataset and asked us to find an
approximation of the neural network that
was used to create this encoded dataset
and approximation is done in a very
specific way that is based on the
nearest neighbor match in the encoding
space
so this we don't find challenge 2 to be
an interesting challenge first of all
because it's a cipher text only
challenge and it just tricks the
adversary too much
we believe this is not a good definition
for privacy and uh
it's also it's not clear how this
definition and how this challenge is
related to privacy uh at best this
challenge is analogous to a key recovery
challenge but but we don't see why it's
necessary to break this uh to show
neural crypt is not private in
particular we actually make this formal
and we show uh encoding a scheme
that is provably secure in challenge two
yet it reveals the whole input in plan
so we could try for years to break the
uh
challenge too for this encoding and be
unsuccessful while it's clear that is
broken
so this is another reason that we
don't study this challenge tool because
it's not uh
necessary to show uh neural crime is not
private and we already have a strong
attack which was a sniper
all right so now invite us what about
the ideal encoding they had this ideal
encoding that they analyzed and they
showed it's uh
uh has the perfect privacy
uh can something else approximately
neural crypt doesn't what can something
else does uh approximate this ideal
including to answer this question we
have a formal impossibility result here
saying that if you can approximate the
ideal including for some console
function c
then there is an oracle ppt algorithm
that can extract this concept function
from this encoder by just querying the
encoder
so what does this theorem mean it means
that the the encoder must already know
the concept function which makes it uh
like there is no point in learning c
from data you could just learn it from
your encode
so either the encoding is impossible or
the or learning the concept function
itself is kind of true
all right so
the proof idea here has three steps so
the first step we use the encoder to
sample a data set of points we take one
child we take one dot we use different
keys to generate our own data set and
then in the second step we use this data
set to train a classifier that gets some
non-trivial accuracy on the state on
this distribution
and in the third is that we use this
classifier and use this boosting idea to
make the accuracy of this class for
almost 100 percent the reason we can do
this is again because we have access to
the encoder that can distribute the
error across all points so given a point
x i just sample a bunch of keys uh and
uh encode the x based on those keys feed
it to the classifier and take the
majority vote and you can easily show
that this gets
very close to 100 percent actors
okay to summarize we showed that newer
crypt is not uh
private it doesn't have the perfect
privacy that it claims we show that
challenge two is not uh
much relevant to privacy and we are
at the end show that approximation of
the ideal encoding is basically
impossible that was it thank you very
much
uh thank you very much said um
please if anyone has any question
and raise your hand or
unmute yourself
okay thank you saeed
so we can move on to the second talk uh
which the topic is secure past and
regression
and mahimna kelkar is going to show us
how we can compute poisson regression
into two-party secure computation
mahima take it away
oh thank you i'm gonna
share my screen
yes perfect
okay awesome so i'm not and today i'll
be giving a talk on our recent work on
secure poisson regression and this is
joint work with fee mariana and karn
so privacy preserving machine learning
has been kind of a very active research
area as evident by workshops like these
and a lot of the previous work has
focused on efficiently learning
different types of useful functions in a
secure setting so some common functions
that we've been usually thinking about
have been like
linear regression where the goal is to
jointly learn a linear function or a
logistic regression where you want to
learn the probability of a binary
response variable
there's also been significant progress
on learning more complex functions like
neural networks
so in this work we want to focus on
another common model used in practice
that has not been explored in the
privacy preserving computation
literature so far so we'll look at
poisson regression for which uh the
ghost for the parties to jointly learn a
poisson model without revealing their
inputs and our emphasis will be on
efficiency of this secure computation
so what is a poisson model poisson model
is used to model count or rate based
data
so this is usually modeled by the
function expectation of y given x equals
e to the power dot product between theta
and x where y is the response variable
and x are the predictor variables and
theta is the weights vector
there's also times where you have
another variable called t which models
the exposure for different inputs
which is what's used to model the raid
base instead of the count based data
so poisson models have actually been
used extensively in the past to measure
as i said count or rate based data so
for example in medicine they've been
used to predict mortality rate or
susceptibility of diseases based on age
or gender pre-existing conditions or
habits like smoking or alcohol use
they've been used in politics to
understand voter turnout and engagement
based on demographics or news exposure
they've been used in finance and lending
to predict credit default rates based on
income
or more recently in advertising to model
click rates for online ads
but in all these use cases there's a lot
of private or sensitive information
that's used in the training of the
poisson model so for instance we could
have sensitive medical or demographic
information in this training set which
we don't really want to reveal
so the goal for us is to try to learn
this poisson model without revealing the
sensitive information
so we focus on the semi-honest
two-server model we have two servers a
and b that have uh shares of the
training data uh so the data id is split
between two servers uh as the shares da
and db and these are given to the two
servers and now the goal is to jointly
train a post on model
so
the data here will be given in uh in a
fixed point ring parametrized by three
parameters l f and h
so all the values are given in a fixed
point ring z2 to the l and the fixed
point numbers are represented with f
fractional bits and the absolute value
of all the numbers that we work with is
less than 2 to the l minus h and this is
done to
have a gap between the representation of
the fixed point numbers and the overall
ring to reduce the probability of errors
so more formally for our poisson
regression problem we have a training
data where we have n data points and the
i data point is given with m
variables and t i is the exposure and y
i is the response variable so we can
also represent them using matrices and
now we want to learn a weight vector
theta such that y each y is
approximately t i times e to the theta x
and unfortunately exponentiation is
quite difficult in npc and usually any
kind of nonlinear function is the most
challenging and probably uh the
bottleneck so here we'll need to compute
fixed point exponentiation which is
usually hard and so one of our
contributions is a very efficient
protocol for secure exponentiation
so this surprisingly makes it so that
it's no longer the bottleneck of the
poisson regression function
so in practice to do this poisson
regression
the natural choice is to use gradient
descent to learn the weights
so we start with this loss function l of
theta given the data um where for the
minimization we've computed the gradient
of the loss function as the gradient of
l of uh given theta is like the sum of
um the
sum of how much
the error is between the learned weights
and the actual um function
and of course we can represent this
using matrices again and now the
gradient update function is as follows
where the k k plus 1 iteration
will learn the weight is theta equals 1
minus beta times the previous data
plus alpha times this gradient of the
loss function and here alpha is the
learning rate which is helpful
to tune for better conversions
and beta is a regular regularization
parameter which is used to prevent
overfitting
so this is pretty standard from taking
from uh just post on regression
and trying to understand what kind of
gradient updates we need to do or
replicate in the secure settings
so in our work we'll make the following
contributions first as mentioned before
we'll give a very efficient protocol for
secure fixed point exponentiation
in this semi honest two-party setting
second we'll provide an optimized secure
matrix multiplication that specifically
benefits our setting by amortizing the
cost of multiplications over many of the
iterations of the gradient descent
and finally
this results in
a highly efficient secure post on
regression protocol
so i'll very briefly describe our secure
fixed point exponentiation technique
so
there it's split into um
so here's the high level technique the
first thing that you do is you split the
exponent into fractional and integer
parts and the second thing that you do
is you exponentiate both parts locally
so you exponentiate the integer parts
separately and the fractional parts
separately and then you combine to get
approximately multiplicative shares of
the final computation
so here uh the integer exponentiation
can be done using firmware's little
theorem so it'll give you shares in a
field f2 rather than the fixed point
ring
and for the fractional exponentiation we
have a new technique where rather than
using standard polynomial approximation
we can enable the parties to compute the
fractional exponentiation locally
by exponentiating in real numbers or
floating point and then combine it with
the integer exponentiation also
completely locally
and since the computation is local
and you you're using floating point or
real numbers this actually makes the
error much smaller than polynomial
approximation
and finally now we can take these
multiplicative shares and convert them
to additive shares using only one round
of communication
and this is the only communication step
that would be used in the protocol and
only requires sending a single field
element
to be communicated per party
so just to compare our exponentiation
protocol um a little with other
techniques as i mentioned the error is
much smaller than polynomial
approximation it's usually at least
a couple orders of magnitude smaller and
the gap widens the more fractional bits
that you use for the protocol
we also have a very efficient online
phase where the communication is just
one field element per party and here fq
is a l bit
prime
q is an l bit prime so the field is
roughly the size of the uh
of the fixed point ring
so for the online phase we have one
micro second when we're using a 63 bit
ring and 55 microseconds for when we're
using a 127 bit ring for
the exponentiation computation
we also have a huge advantage when it
comes to pre-processing so our
pre-processing is only for the
multiplicative to additive shares
conversion which only takes two elements
in fq compared to
several megabytes using other techniques
that rely on bit decomposition or
polynomial approximation
so this means that even in like an
online only setting the performance will
be
very good where you can't do
pre-computation earlier
the second technique we'll use is what
we call correlated beaver triples so
briefly recall that multiplication or
beaver triples are used as
pre-processing to compute multiplication
of two shared inputs and these can be
easily generalized to matrix
multiplication so now if you look at the
loss optimization function again you'll
notice that there's in each iteration
you have one multiplication with x
transpose and one multiplication with x
and these are kind of used for each
iteration and the uh x's are the same
and just the theta's change so basically
for the ice iteration we have a
multiplication of the form x times the i
where the zi's change but the x remains
constant
so now with this observation we can do
something clever so instead of using
standard matrix triples as
pre-processing we can use these
correlated triples since one of the
matrix is constant it does not need to
be shared again
and now this means that the
reconstruction phase for the
multiplication needs to be only done
once for the uh first matrix and later
iterations can reuse this
so now the computation cos sorry the
communication cost can be
amortized over many iterations because
the cost of doing many many iterations
is only slightly larger than that of one
iteration
and typically since we're doing hundreds
of iterations of grid of the gradient
descent the efficiency gains are quite
substantial
um as a conclusion our poison regression
only takes four rounds for the entire
protocol and if our data set does not
contain an exposure variable t
then uh we can shave off an additional
round so it only takes three rounds and
we can also use the same protocol for
secure inference
so as a comparison of our secure
protocol to plaintext regression we plot
how the weights change for different
data sets compared to secure versus
plain text and the lines for secure and
plain text regression and these
graphs are essentially identical
so i'll say like the root mean square
error that we computed between the
plaintext weights and
the secure weights is less than uh 10 to
the negative 3 or 10 to the negative 4
depending upon what learning rate we use
and the data set we use so this is um
saying that our secure weights that we
learn are very very close to the weights
that are learned by just the plain text
regression
in terms of just a brief uh
brief data point for the protocol cost
for a data set with 10 000 training
samples and 100 binary predictors the
amortized cost over 100 iterations is
1.35 seconds per iteration online cost
is 2.88 seconds and 1.3 megabytes of
communication per iteration so the total
cost over something like 100 iterations
is a little over two minutes for offline
phase five minutes for online phase and
about 136 megabytes of communication
and i'll sort of end with that here's a
link to the paper in case you're
interested
thank you
thank you very much
it was a great talk
i don't see any questions in the
comment part but if you have any
questions please ask
i think there's a question someone's
raised their hand
yeah it's just it's a quick question
thanks a lot i just would like to ask is
the method that you design for
exponentiation is very specific to two
parties and passive security or can't
extend it like basically so it's
relatively straightforward to extend it
to n parties uh because the only thing
that needs to change is the
multiplicative to additive shares
component which can be generalized it is
a little unclear how to do it with um
malicious security because one of the
advantages of our approach was we can
exponentiate in like real numbers
locally and then combine so it's hard to
prove a correctness of that using
generic techniques so it's unclear but
it's an open question for malicious
security
okay great so thank you so much again
mahinda we are going to
start with the next talk
next talk is called muse secure
inference resilient to malicious clients
you're interested to hear about that uh
pratish mishra is going to give a talk
so please start
everyone let me just
share my screen
okay
get started so hi everyone i'm pratyush
and i'll be presenting muse which is a
protocol for secure inference of neural
networks that's resilient to malicious
clients and this is a joint work with my
excellent co-authors ryan akshay and
reluca
so
okay so what's secure influence the
problem secure inference is developing a
protocol for a client and server to
interact to obtain a neural network
prediction the client has some input x
and the server has some neural network
model m
and the goal is that the client and
server should learn only the prediction
m of x
so that the client does not learn
anything about the server's private
model rates and the server doesn't learn
anything about the client's private
input next
so this is many applications for you
know a lot of cases where uh both x and
m can be sensitive such as you know home
monitoring or baby monitoring or
other
applications so as a result there's been
a lot of work over the past couple of uh
past few years on secure two-party
inference
and these have sorry
a variety of efficiency and security
properties
however like all of these protocols we
can basically classify them into two
quadrants either you have protocols
which achieve a very strong malicious
security
but have relatively slow performance due
to the use of generic sub protocols
all you have protocols which achieve
very good performance on
state-of-the-art neural networks but
which only achieves semi-honors security
so ideally what we want to do is we want
to develop protocols which lie in this
bottom right most quadrant
that is they achieve both malicious
security as well as good performance
but you know militia security is uh
usually very expensive so let's take a
step back and see if we actually need
full malicious
security so okay so in the threat model
of secure inference what you have is
that there's usually only a single
server which has the model but there are
many possibly many clients which
interact with the single server right
and these clients have different kinds
of setups incentives could be operated
by different people right um and for the
more the clients can oftentimes easily
remain anonymous like i can just sign up
with a new account
for an application for example
right um so this setting it maybe makes
sense to consider a slightly weaker
threat model where we only try to
prevent malicious clients we allow the
server to be semi-honest but we allow
the client to be uh malicious right so
we protect against fully malicious
clients
and this makes sense because um in this
threat model at least right it's much
easier for their client to cheat you can
just spin up a new um you know client uh
very cheaply
but if the server gets caught cheating
then then there can be heavy
repercussions for example you know
people might just stop using your
service if you get caught cheating right
okay so in this
so this client malicious security model
seems to make sense and indeed it allows
us to construct
much more efficient protocols and would
be possible in the fully malicious case
as we'll see
so in particular in this paper muse
we provide two contributions first we
show that existing semi honest secure
inference protocols including the
state-of-the-art ones
are vulnerable to a very powerful model
extraction attack uh that is you know
much more efficient than prior attacks
and this is enabled by the fact that
they're using the secure inference
protocol
and then we develop a new
secure inference protocol that is secure
against malicious clients and achieves
good efficiency in particular it's not
vulnerable to our model extraction
attack
okay so let's quickly go through each of
these contributions
beginning with a quick recap of neural
networks so in neural networks you have
alternating in particular convolutional
neural networks you have alternating
linear and non-linear layers the linear
layers
consist of
for example fully of convolutional uh
layers fully connected layers average
pruning layers and so on
meanwhile non-linear layers um the most
popular one and the one we'll consider
in the stock is the value so relu is
zero when the input is negative and the
identity function when the input is
positive right
and looking
slightly ahead
what makes model extraction attacks
often difficult is that is the existence
of these non-linear layers right without
them the network would simply be a
linear system which is fairly easy to
recover just by querying it
a number of times
right okay so quickly a quick recap of
model extraction attacks so model
extraction attacks what we want to do is
you have a malicious client which makes
specially crafted malicious queries to
the server and then the client uses the
responses from these special queries to
learn information about the model so
that eventually after making enough
queries it can
construct a
rough approximation of the clients of
the server's model
right
so this is problematic for our secure
reference case because we don't want to
reveal information about the service
model right and indeed like so far like
all of the attacks that have
been explored generally have been black
box attacks where the client simply
makes input output queries uh so yeah it
makes it only gets input output access
to the model right um and the question
we want to ask is whether the fact that
a client
or whether you know the secure interest
protocol
um
is being used can that fact just enable
new model extraction attacks and i won't
go into the details here but basically
what we show is that by
leveraging leveraging properties of a
particular class of uh
protocols which rely on additive secret
sharing
um we can actually con construct
very uh new very powerful attra attacks
that um
basically eliminate the non-linear layer
entirely from the
from the network
and
in summary what this allows us to do
with our new attack is um
get a much lower query complexity so up
to 300 times fewer queries um we are
able to extract the model weights
perfectly you know rather than
approximating them this is up to
floating point error
and we scale with the number of
parameters in the in the model not the
depth of the network
and to get together put together this
allows us to evaluate our attack on
networks which are 100 times deeper than
prior work and which have
60 times
more parameters right so maybe we're
getting up
close to
deployed models right
and this is just enabled by the fact
that this class of secure inference
protocols they have a semi honest uh
structure which allows
basically the malicious client to
malleat its messages
all right so
let's see if you can solve this so what
we do for that is we construct muse
which is a system for secure inference
on convolutional neural networks which
achieves uh strong security against
client against malicious clients
it supports arbitrary uh
relu based convolutional neural networks
and finally um
achieves much better performance
compared to existing alternatives which
rely on uh maliciously secure protocols
or sub protocols and whose online phase
is very similar to existing semi honest
protocols so you pay most of the cost of
this client maliciousness actually only
in the pre-processing or offline phase
all right so the starting point for our
protocol is
a prior secure inference protocol which
is semi honest called delphi
so delphi there are two phrases a
pre-processing phase and an online phase
and the pre-processing phase itself
divided into two components
first the client and sub interact to
pre-process the linear layers right and
this produces some
material
technically underneath it you use some
homomorphic encryption to compute
correlated randomness
right so once they get the linear
pre-processing done
they can
go ahead to compute the
non-linear pre-processing
and this basically involves the server
gobbling some circuits and the client
obtaining labels for those circuits
and these labels correspond to the
output of the linear preprocessing
right
so basically at the end of the step
the client and the server they have
pre-processing material for both the
linear and the non-linear layers in the
network
then during the online phase when the
client has its
input x
the client and server they can use
their preprocessing material to go ahead
and complete the inference and obtain
the prediction
okay so that's laughing right
um let's see what a malicious client can
do in delphi
first during the pre-processing phase
it can act maliciously to generate some
incorrect
pre-processing material so this is
illustrated here by the
uh red
uh right so you can compute the cl prime
and cn prime
and then during the online phase uh you
can use this again you can act
the client can act maliciously to
deviate from the protocol and uh maybe
compute some malleated output right
so what we need to do actually is two
steps first we need to ensure that
during the offline or preprocessing
phase the client follows a protocol and
then during then we need to make sure
that the output of that preprocessing is
what is fed into the online phase right
so we need to commit the client to the
pre-processed state and make sure that
these are consistent between the offline
and online phases
so let's see how we can do that
so first for the linear layers it's a
pretty straightforward idea we attach an
information theoretic mac only to the
client's linear state because remember
the server is semi honest so we don't
need to authenticate the server state
so the
server generates a mac key and then this
is used to authenticate the client state
and then you proceed as before
computing the non-linear pre-processing
and you feed these uh
these two components into the online
phase
and the idea here is now because it is
that because the
the linear state is authenticated the
server can use the mac to check the
that this the consistency of the output
of the offline phase with the input the
online phase right
um
and furthermore for the non-linear
layers uh basically kabul circuits they
already provide
malicious security against malicious
evaluators right
so if you make the client uh become the
evaluator then we already obtain
security against
uh in the in the non-linear layers for
free in some sense
but actually that's not quite sufficient
because if you remember in delphi we
actually feed the output of the linear
preprocessing into the non-linear
preprocessing so what we need to do is
actually make sure that these are
consistent as well and we're not doing
that right now because
oblivious transfer can't actually
authenticate this it can't check that
the input is consistent
so to overcome this we design a protocol
for conditional disclosure of secrets
which first checks if the input is valid
that the mac is correct and if so it
outputs the global circuit labels that
correspond to the client's input
and then by doing this basically we were
able to authenticate both the
linear and non-linear layers
and
obtain security against malicious
clients so that was muse in a you know
very rapid
uh
yeah yeah i covered it very rapidly
um
the cool thing is that the online phase
is basically equivalent to semi honest
uh delphi there's only a very small
overhead
um we implemented our protocol um it's
available online here
um yeah and in terms of evaluation we
compared it against
[Music]
a couple of baselines both semi honest
and fully malicious
and what we found was that compared to
the fully malicious we have very low
overhead 21x better and we're only
slightly worse than
the semi honest baseline in delphi we
pay in communication but i think in the
future work we can try to reduce this
and this is also true for the online
phase
again we have uh only a little bit
overhead over the semi honest protocols
yeah so in summary in this in the stock
i
yeah in news we developed a new model
extraction attack that is much more
efficient than existing ones
um and then we developed a secure
reference protocol that is not
vulnerable to our attack and particular
provides client malicious security
thank
you
okay thank you very much pratyush uh we
have two questions in the chat uh amit's
first question asks how is the honest
client supposed to query
um the honest client supposed to query
in which case and uh
and the second question you ask is isn't
uh cbs just ot plus garbage circuit
um so cts actually we designed a
protocol not based on global circuits we
designed a protocol based on arithmetic
and circuit mpc so in particular
variant of speeds that is
we we modify it to only
have client malicious security which
that is which is sufficient for our
application um we could implement it
using ot plus global circuits but that
would be more we can't actually be more
inefficient
um i'm not sure like what the in what
context the first question was about but
if it's about the model extraction
attack um
in the model extraction like instead of
black box attacks you're just querying
inputs and there's no constraint on what
your input can be like i as a client can
make any malicious input
um
and so like there's no constraint there
in the in our particular attack um
[Music]
the client basically does some
undetectable tampering of the of the
shares um
that's how it works i can explain more
offline if there's any questions
okay
okay uh thank you very much uh we can
start uh you can go ahead with the
second with the next talk
uh the topic is cerebral a platform for
multi-party cryptography collaborative
learning and waking trend is going to
give us this talk
so
take it away
hi
uh so hi everyone um my name is whitten
chen and i'm presenting our world
cerebral
which is a platform for cryptographic
like collaborate collaborative learning
and this is a joint world where i
several of my colleagues
okay let me go to the next slide so the
motivation of our work is anti-money
laundering so we have been that are
responsible to predict and prevent money
laundering and they want to use machine
learning model to detect them but this
is actually quite challenging because
actually each of the like money transfer
involved usually involves two banks
and one single bank doesn't have all the
information that's necessary to do this
prediction
so one good idea is that maybe we can
have many bands to train a model using
their joint data set but in the real
world this is quite challenging just
because banks have many reason that they
cannot share the data due to privacy
concerns regulation and probably
competition
and so the question is simple is that
how to enable this organization to share
data for learning a model without
showing the data and people here already
think that's the answer is to use secure
multi-party computation
and always liberal is trying to have
like developer who are not expert in
cryptography to use secure multi-party
communication
okay so uh
how can we have the developer what are
the challenges that developer are facing
today so we find that the first thing
that developer might find challenging is
how to choose the right protocol and
implement that algorithm efficiently and
now let me let's assume that we have a
developer who has a very cool learning
algorithm
the first question that the developer
need to answer is
well should i implement the algorithm
using boolean npc protocol or arithmetic
mpc protocol
like we know a little bit more about mpc
we know that like well they have some
trailer
but unfortunately the developer doesn't
know this trail and if we explain this
trail it's also very difficult for the
developer to figure out the differences
between them
and aries and the like debate between
like boolean and arithmetic is just the
beginning of the story because there are
so many protocols for boolean and
arithmetic and we know that they perform
very differently for example we we have
some heuristic like for example we know
silent ot is good
when you have a slow network and low
gear is very good when you have lower
number of the party
but once again our developer doesn't
know this and in the real world what may
happen actually usually is that the
developer who is an expert in data
science but probably non-expert in
cryptography
implement the same protocol in different
platforms and to measure how slow they
are and then they will learn the same
lesson that we show here but in a very
painful way
and moreover in the real world actually
in a lot of the learning algorithm some
of the computation can be done local
that is it doesn't need to be inside the
mpc
and if you are training the model in
your semi-only setting
this is a very important opportunity
that you don't want to miss but once
again the developer might not be able to
figure out like what is the right local
computation to do
and so uh cerebral provides a compiler
that tried to help the developer and
there is and uh actually two ways that
we have that firstly is that like well
our compiler can firstly using
information flow to see which variable
in the learning algorithm is like
visible to some party and by doing that
we can split the program for the
developer into a local one so it doesn't
need to go to the npc
second is that we were estimated the
cost of different options to run the mpc
protocol
and
then we will choose the best one for the
developer and this is not a simple
decision because whether protocol is
faster or not actually depends on many
factors including whether you have good
network whether you have a lot of
computational power
one example is that if you are thinking
about silent ot but you also have very
good network maybe you will just do
non-silent and classical classical ot
instead
and so and actually we have some
observation sometimes this compiler can
tell you something that you don't know
like
so let's look at this figure the first
observation that we can have is that
while it's really important to choose
the right protocol because there is a
performance gap that's actually not
small
and second
so our heuristic on which protocol is
better might not be always true like in
this figure which will actually evaluate
a 10 layer decision tree in the seminar
on the setting you can see that like
when you when you have more party
subsequently arithmetic protocol becomes
faster than the boolean one
and we and we and then we solve another
challenge that like some of the like
developer might also face in developing
like efficient protocol in real world
when we are doing training we may
actually have like as like basically
party might not be the same
and especially they might not have the
same network condition now let me give
you a specific example let's consider
that like we are doing a global npc
we have two parties who are in the us
and they have very good network between
them locate latency and very high
language
unfortunately we have the third party
who is far away from them
and the network between them is very
slow
which means that the latency is very
high and also the bandwidth is quite
slow
and this is a very challenging situation
today for our mpc and let me just give
you a specific example if we are doing
the semi on this version of the speech
protocol
a significant part of the offline phase
is actually to broadcast a lot of the
ciphertext and then the party will sum
this subtitles up
and as you can see because party 3 have
slower connection with everyone else
it means that like well actually party 1
and party 2 will be waiting for the
party 3 to finish
and this light will just slow down the
entire computation by the slow
disconnection
and in other words reboot file that
there are ways to have the party 3. and
our idea is that we try to send and
receive last data to and from the party
threes the first thing we can do is that
let's send less data to party threes
if we are like broadcasting cyber class
but they will eventually be summing up
together
maybe party one and two can sum them up
first and then just send one server
class to the positive three instead of
sending them individually
second we can lab the position last data
to the party one and two by doing some
sort of forwarding and the idea is that
well if but we need to send the
subtitles to party one and two let's
just have the party do it saying to
party one where party one forwarded to
party 2.
and we did an experiment which actually
showed that this will give you an
improvement we did an experiment with 12
parties located in two different regions
inside the same region they have very
good network but between these two
regions there is a very slow connection
and we found that like by just using
this optimization that you try to not
send too much data in the slow this
connection you can actually get a very
significant improvement in the like
computation
and we and scribble also have other
components that i don't have time to
describe
you can see our paper for like our
domain specific language
we have some release policies that have
ensured parties incentive and we also
have an auditing framework to try to
have cash party who provide like bad
data to the training
and we also have released a lot of our
code and if you are working on this area
we actually implement a lot of the
example program for machine learning and
which might be quite helpful
and in the end i want to tell you a
little bit of some of the open problems
that come to our mind when we are
developing like cerebral and as you can
see from like the previous figure our
a very good life opportunity is that is
we miss the different types of the
protocol together we have so many
wonderful words in the recent year about
misprotocol computation
cerebral doesn't support such
computation it have to choose one of the
protocol either arithmetic or boolean
and this we actually we are losing a lot
of the opportunity to get better
performance so uh open problem our
future well that's people might actually
would quite be very useful is that
whether we can have a compiler that
automatically split the program into
different circuits
and you also have an optimizer that
actually try to lower the cost this is
not trivial because you now involve the
conversion and conversion have an
overhang it's not just to decide whether
or not it's also
you need to decide when to do the
conversion
and another open problem that some of
the audio might already know that is
that our protocol for the network
planning which try to have the party 3
who have a slower connection only work
in the semi-only setting and we don't
know how to do that in the malicious
setting we know that it's challenging
because that in the malicious setting
party often need to send out some sort
of proof of plain knowledge to ensure
that the plaintiffs are included
correctly
and also you need to prove that the
party actually aggregate the subtitles
correctly and we don't know how to do uh
idea that seems to work is more fit like
commitment but it must be efficient in
now otherwise it will become the
performance bottleneck
and okay and that's all i have and
thanks everybody for listening and i
actually i i think there is a question
in the chat i will take a look
um number of training sample institute
learning we so the compiler actually
needs to learn some of the information
about the data set because that can also
like influence how the decisions are
being made
yeah
okay
any other questions
yes i guess daniel
yeah yeah it's gonna be super quick
thank you so
just to be sure i i'm not sure i got it
like the full implementation you have
after it compiles the code that you
provide as input does it give like
recommendations on what to execute or
does it actually provide the full
execution environment to run the the
proper
mpc protocol
uh actually it's very close to that
because that the
so one very good thing about this
library is that the domain specific
language allow you to write in one
python file and then you can compile it
to both the boolean one and the
arithmetic one so you don't need to
write a program quite twice
but when the like when the clause lie
accidentally tell you which one seems to
have a lower cost you can then go ahead
and compile that into that format and
you don't need to write rewrite the code
so it's very close to that
that's easy thank you
okay so if there's any no any other
questions so we can go ahead with the
next talk uh the next talk will be
called
privacy preserving machine learning for
support vector machines
and hernan vanegas is going to give us
the uh talk
uh i would like to actually welcome anon
to the research community and especially
in pc i know that you are finishing up
your bachelor degree so kudos to you
and the floor is yours take it away
thank you and i will share my screen in
do you see my presentation
yes i see that oh okay
[Music]
okay
hey hi my name is hernandez baneras i
will be talking about privacy preserving
machine learning for support vector
machines in particular i will be talking
about how to use a multi-party
computation to train support vector
machines this work was
done jointly with daniel cavacas and
daniel escuero at this moment we are
working a full paper that will contain
all the details of this work
our contribution is divided in six parts
the first contribution is that we
implement uh three stm training
algorithms securely uh with the mpsp
framework a second
it is important to mention here that it
is a full-fledged implementation a
second we discuss the precision
and the scalability of the secure
implementation using the fantastic four
protocol
we
place a special tension in the impact of
the fix pointing the quality of the
model for example in the accuracy and
also the the training time and the data
sent and
we compute some upper bounds for the
least squares approach that are critical
to avoid the overflow when we use fixed
point
representation
we train an sdm with real world data to
analyze a develop the viability and the
the
scaling of our solution and finally we
obtain an accuracy comparable to clear
implementation
using a floating point that presentation
in the related
work we found only few works that uses
npc
to train a super vector machines most of
the works using we use homomorphic
encryption or do not carry the world
training process privately
now what is the picture of this work uh
in the first part we have a methods
method selection and we
train an svm using the gradient descent
algorithm the sequential minimal
optimization algorithm and they list the
squares all of them are implemented and
in an npc in in mp speeds framework
and we train an svm with these
algorithms and we select the best
sweetheart method according to some
metrics
in this case the least squares algorithm
performs better and we compute some
upper bounds
to
for for the least squares algorithm
the importance here is that a this this
upper bounds will help us to uh compute
the
number of beats needed in the fixed
point arithmetic
finally
we have an experimental evaluation over
synthetic data and real-world data
and we unveil some practical limitations
and we conclude about them practical
limitations like a training time a bit
sizing the in the fixed point
implementation and so on
now
in the training method a selection we
have the gradient descent algorithm the
sequential minimal optimization a
algorithm that is a very well-known
method for training super vector
machines and at least the squares
approach
it's important here to mention that
in the
in all the experiments of this work we
are training all of our super vector
machines
locally it is in a laptop that simulates
all the communication between the
parties but in the local host
so we generate an artificial data set
with 50 rows and two columns and we
found that the gradient descent
algorithm is the fastest
but it has some limitations because the
gradient decent algorithm does not
allows us to use the kernel trick and
the kernel trick is important uh to find
a non-linear boundaries in the
classification
uh algorithm and the sequential minimal
optimization is just this is load due to
some heuristic the the
heuristics uh causes some branching in
the source code and they and and these
branchings
slows down the npx then ps5 execution
so we select select the least squares
approach because it performs better than
the than this sequential minimal
optimization algorithm and has a
comparable accuracy
now
a the least squares approach in
the core of this method is to solve a
linear system of equations presented in
the equation one
to solve this a this linear system of
equations we select the the steepest
design algorithm that is very similar
and to the gradient descent algorithms
with some variation in the steep size uh
in the line 7 precisely we
compute the steep size the step sizing
the in the optimization step
so let's
take a look at this a quantity because
it is very important
a
the numerator and the denominator of
this quantity depends heavily on the
number of rows and the columns of the
data set
so
a it is important to to
compute an upper bound to avoid overflow
due during the training execution so
if we compute an upper bound for the
denominator we found that is it is of
the n to the seven c to the sixth so we
will use this this upper bound and the
logarithm of this upper bound
precisely to find the number of
bits that avoid the overflow
so if we look at this table we compute
uh
some bits needed the ring size of the
fantastic four protocol for some number
of rows and columns and we found that
for relatively small data sets uh there
is a
high a relatively high number of
fixed point bits
needed to avoid the overflow
now
let's a evaluate a
let's evaluate what happens
with the number of rows a and the number
of columns
of this data set
in
in this case
if we leave the number of columns
and we generate a multiple data sets
with a a variety of number of rows
we found that the training time and the
data send increases polynomially
with the number of rows of the dataset
and there is a linear relationship
between the number of products and the
data set and training time so it tells
us that most of the time
the the training time is spent
uh sending data and the local uh
computer computation is is
spent a a low number of
a long time so hey the most important
the most important results here is that
a there is a similar accuracy between a
training an svm securely
and training a nice vm in a clear
implementation using floating point a
arithmetic
and and this fact is not modified it
will increase the number of rows
and finally
what happens if we change the number of
columns
and we leave the number of rows fixed
and we generate artificial data sets to
do this and we found that the training
time timing increases almost linear
and uh
and the the gap in the between the fifth
and sixth sixth columns is
a technicality in the mpsp framework
with the local computation and the word
size for the local computation of the
protocol the accuracy here is not
affected as well as in the rose
experiment
finally and
maybe the one of the most important
results here is that what happens if we
leave the number of rows fixed the
number of columns fixed also
and
we change the separation between the two
classes that we want to separate in the
data set
we generate multiple artificial data
datasets for this and we found that the
training accuracy
in the secure implementation and the
clear implementation is very similar
the accuracy is not affected by the fact
that the training is done securely
so it is a good point in favor though to
to the use of multi-party computation to
train support vector machines with the
least squares approach
finally we train an svm with a real
world dataset a heart attack dataset
taken from cable with 303 samples and 13
features
we train the super vector machine with a
70 percent of the samples and 14
features
after some pre-processing
and we use a linear kernel here
so we found that the training accuracy
and the test accuracy are very similar
the compact the secure implementation is
very competitive with respect to the
clear implementation that uses uh
floating point arithmetic the data sent
is high it took some hundreds of
bits so we will talk about this in the
conclusions uh the the secure
implementation took more time that the
clear implementation bodies are very
well known result it's a trade-off
between security and and time
so a in the conclusion we have that that
yours is not affected by the fact that
that the training is done securely this
is an
important result i and we
we see this with artificial data set and
real world data set as well uh most of
the training time is spending sending
data it's spent sending data as we see
in the rows experiment
and finally the number of bits and the
ring size of the fantastic four protocol
depends heavily on the number of rows
and columns and we must take care here
because then the if we use another
polling another kernel
a
rather rather than linear kernel for
example a polynomial kernel of degree 3
we have that the the upper bound is
increased
in a considerably in a considerable
quantity see this is a problem because
it will increase the training time and
the data center in the protocol
execution in the least dispersed
approach
as a future work what happens if we use
a small fixed number of bits and we use
it
wisely
in in order to to compute
uh
the operations that cause an out of
range operation of another flow in the
in the least squares algorithm
and and this will help us
to to
to attack the problem of the of the
of the in creation of the increase of
beats
uh
all the experiments here were executed
locally what happens with a more
realistic environment for example a
distributed network when we consider a
bandwidth and other things that the data
the data send that took some hundreds of
gigabytes and the training time will be
affected as well thank you for
everything
okay thank you very much hernan uh since
we are having a lack of time
uh let's uh next move to the next
speaker uh the talk would be about
improved multi-party fixed point
multiplication
and hernan or other
authors of this
support vector machine work if you can
reply to the questions in the chat that
would be great
so
uh sai krishna badly nayaran
if i pronounce your name quite correctly
so please
floor is yours
let me just share my screen can you see
my screen
yes
um
so thanks for the introduction um my
name is saikrishna welcome to my talk
i'm going to be talking about improved
multiparty fixed point multiplication
and this is joint work with isa payhan
and peter
so first let's
look at our machine learning training as
or if you are aware through all the
talks today
typically in training we have data that
is stored across multiple different
sources
and each party could have very similar
or even different types of data and
ideally we'd like more data because more
data applies we can train a better model
but unfortunately due to
competitive or regulatory reasons
parties are not
authorized to share the data with each
other and um so
it's not uh
so we would still need some sort of
privacy preserving machine learning
training um and the similar similar
problem also arises in the case of
inference if we have a pre-trained model
that is shared across multiple parties
right
and as we roll away there's a long list
of works on using mpc to solve this
basically the different parties come
together and run an mpc protocol to
generate the trained model or to
to perform inference on the pre-trained
model
right
so much of the prior work in this space
of using mpc
has focused on the setting of two three
or maybe four parties with
at most one corruption
and the goal in our work is to extend
this to the end party settings so can we
design mpc protocols for secure training
or influence
with a larger number of parties
and
a natural question one might ask is
there has been a tremendous improvement
recently in
designing very efficient general purpose
npc protocols so can we just use those
protocols directly
um unfortunately it's not as simple as
that as um as we've seen in previous
talks machine learning typically
requires uh dealing with fractional or
decimal values while mpc
works well with modular arithmetic
um and so these two don't necessarily
fit together
uh natural naive ideas can we just scale
the machine learning computation to work
with a large enough modulus so that we
can do everything
over this modulus
and as you might expect this would fail
for
if you wanted to perform a large number
of multiplications it would just not
scale
well enough
and another idea could be that we just
perform the fixed point multiplication
and start using boolean circuits and
then run our favorite mpc algorithm
once again this would also be very
expensive either in terms of number of
rounds or communication depending on
which flavor of mpc that we use
and indeed a lot of the focus in prior
work has been
on building efficient fixed point
multiplication protocols where we want
the inputs and the output to be secret
shared amongst the parties
and in our book
the question we'd like to ask is can we
design efficient uh multi-party fixed
point multiplication protocols where the
inputs and outputs are secret shared and
we want it to work for larger values of
x
and
before i go into uh the results that we
obtained i'm just going to briefly
recall the notion of replicated secret
sharing um
maybe most of you already heard it but
just for the sake of completeness let's
uh let's say there are three parties
here and we want at most one party to be
corrupt the secret shadow value x we
just additively split it into three
components x1 x2 and x3 and we give each
party two of three two of these three
components right so p1 gets x1 and x2
and so on
um addition would be pretty easy to
perform you could just locally add your
respective shares if you have shares of
x and y to get the sharing of
the sum
unfortunately multiplication is not so
simple you cannot just directly multiply
your shares as you might expect
but if you just spend a bit of time
thinking about it you'll notice that
multiplication is also not too difficult
uh if you just wanted to do regular
multiplication each party can compute
one of these three terms ci locally
um so pi computes zi locally sends it to
pi plus 1 and this way parties get
dashes
you would need to add some additional
zero shares uh just for say privacy
okay so replicated secret sharing
provides you a nice way to
do
arithmetic computation
and this can be generalized to any
arbitrary and parties and it's a useful
way of secret sharing data if you care
about uh relatively small values of n
for larger n uh the number of shares
would grow exponentially so it might not
be suited
with that in mind let me briefly recap
our results um we design a new technique
for uh shared truncation what i mean is
if you have a sharing of x and now you
wanted to truncate it um
or if you think of x as a decimal value
and you want to divide this value x by 2
to the d for some public value d
so we design a new technique to perform
this task and we use this technique to
design efficient protocols for fixed
point multiplication
where the data's secret tried using
several different schemes
so um sorry the first scheme is the
first protocol works for replicated
secret sharing with semi honest security
uh the second protocol builds on the
first one and achieves malicious
security and both of these protocols
work in the honest majority setting the
first protocol has two flavors it can be
a single round one or a two round one
the third protocol is once again in the
semi honest security model with honest
maturity but works for me secret sharing
and finally the fourth protocol works
for additive secret sharing with semi
honest security
but we do not tolerate also a dishonest
majority of corruption
and then we plug in these protocols to
design general mpc protocols where the
arithmetic circuits can have addition
gates as well as fixed point
multiplication gates
um
so very briefly let me show you uh some
comparison of our protocol the semi
honest protocols with some prior work
let me use n to denote the number of
parties t to denote the corrupt parties
and let's focus on the replicated
setting where
let me call k to be the modulus
and so
our protocol performs better than um the
prior work of um
marcel and rendell uh where we unlike
their work we don't have any offline
communication or uh interaction between
the parties the online communication is
roughly identical except we have a minor
optimization that allows us to reduce
the communication uh to trade off for
more rounds
and then in the context of shaming
secret sharing once again we have a
protocol that works identically in the
online setting in terms of communication
where we improve on the offline
communication cost once again here k
denotes the log logarithm of the prime
modulus
so the takeaway message is that our
protocols
improve on prior work in terms of better
offline communication costs
and
the remaining few minutes i'm going to
use to briefly uh describe the
techniques in our replicated sharing
based protocol i just focused on the
semi honest setting for now um
so let me recall the approach taken by
marcel and rendell in the network title
aby three
so the idea is let's say you have three
parties uh and you have inputs x and y
that are replicated uh the shared using
replicated secret sharing and you want
the output z uh which is approximated as
x times y by
divided by this public
value d
so now in the pre-processing phase uh
parties interact to generate shares of r
and s
where r is random and s is computed as r
divided by two to the d
okay so r s is a truncation of r if you
can think of it that way
and so what happens in the online phase
first uh parties run the regular
multiplication protocol
that we saw briefly earlier to compute a
sharing of x times y
now notice that this sharing
needs to be truncated or divided by
d
um sorry divided by 2 to the d there's a
type of here
and the idea is that
instead of doing the division locally
anymore what parties do is they compute
arithmetic
additive secret shares of
this product subtracted by this value r
so they compute the rate of shares of x
y minus i and reveal all these shares to
the first two parties p1 and p2
so now p1 and p2 compute their share of
the product as z z prime divided by 2 to
the t so their share would be x y minus
r by 2 to the d and then the second and
the third shares could just be
the truncated shares of s
directly
and the idea is that now these three
shares would now
give you shares of x y by d and this
will be very close to the resulting
output that you would get for except
with some negligible error okay
and as you can imagine this can be
easily generalized to end parties as
well uh if you just expand on this
protocol and make it work for the
n-party setting um unfortunately in the
n-party setting this pre-processing is
pretty expensive because parties need to
interact together to compute these
random shares
and the goal in our work is um
can we generate these truncation pairs
locally without needing parties to
interact
and here is
quickly the brief idea for
non-interactive sampling um let's say we
have a value x that is in
the range c2 to the k
now instead of generating shares of r in
the same space what if the shares of r
were from a larger space so the idea is
if we generate each share of r to be
lambda bits more than the space in which
x is from
okay now we have a few observations
first suppose we're working over um
an even larger space so let's say we're
working over z 2 to the k prime where k
prime is larger than both k and k plus
lambda
so now recall that if you uh or observe
that if you reconstruct r using these
various shares ri
the reconstruction would not wrap around
c to the k prime
and so the distribution of r and r plus
x would be statistically close and
since r is lambda plus 2 which is more
than our
x
and finally
these shares of r can be generated
locally just by uh sharing prf keys
right
and
once you have these shares so far you
can just locally truncate each way to
get shares of r by two to the d uh
replicated shares and you don't need to
interact in the pre-processing at all
um
so with this idea let me show how to
plug in this idea uh into
a replicated sharing a fixed point
multiplication protocol that the
approach is very similar to what we saw
earlier
um
x y in the product z would be over the
space c two to the k but we'll be
working over z to the k prime where k
prime is larger than k
it need not be significantly larger so
you just need k k prime to be
k plus 2 lambda plus logarithmic of the
number of parties
um
m denotes the number of shares so if you
have n parties you would have n choose n
minus t shares
where it is the number of corruptions
and so the pre-processing parties just
jointly sample some prf keys which is
not expensive
um
and
it could be done locally whereas in the
online phase now just to generate shares
of these uh random strings are parties
locally compute uh their individual
shares all right and each share is uh at
most uh k plus lambda bits long
and then the rest of the protocol
follows quite similarly
but is compute additive shares of x y
minus r
the first
n minus t parties
get get all of these shares um they they
can then reconstruct to compute c prime
and they set the first share of the
product to just be z prime by 2 to the d
plus r 1 by 2 to the d where r 1 was the
first share of the randomness i and then
the rest of the shares of the product
are just truncations of the randomness
respectively
um i won't have time to go into the
details of the malicious protocol
but the protocol sort of builds on this
to enforce honest behavior across these
steps and one more thing to note here is
we also want to add some zero sharing to
ensure privacy of these additive shares
and once again you can add these zero
sharing by using prf keys and locally
generate them
and uh how do you modify this to a two
round protocol to reduce communication
um you just don't reveal every share of
these additive shares to all the parties
but just reveal them to one party and
have that party uh
compute z1 and send it to the others
um
yeah i'd like to stop here
thank you for listening
okay thank you very much um
i guess we are done with all the talks
for
the workshop i would like to pass the
mic to
antiguani if she is available
so i would like to thank all the
speakers uh in the whole workshop and
also
this country attack session
thanks everyone
and antiguani the mic is yours your
music