I'm going to say it's the internet of
bad things because right now there's a
lot of bad things out there and they're
incredibly powerful machines at the edge
I chipset the cost just a few dollars in
fact probably less than a dollar can
push a megabit a second tribulation of
these things out there and they're uh
they're you know they're controlling
your thermostat there you know watching
your child they're watching your cat
your fish tank at home if endless sort
of opportunities I was at a friend's
house in Rotterdam earlier this week and
he had a hundred twenty plus IOT devices
in his house mostly light bulbs for all
types of visual effects to echoes to
ring you know the doorbells to it I mean
it's just endless and this continues
this is a hundred machines that are as
powerful as a pc i might have worked on
you know 15 20 years ago all connected
to the internet capable of driving
traffic crazy world that we live in now
and but the reason that we have these
things is they fulfill a social and
personal need so I'm not saying to stop
that and I'm not saying that I OT is is
the problem so let's talk about
infections human infection versus
machine infection you can compare the
two but the issues with human infections
is they tend to burn themselves out we
have yet to have that pandemic in my
lifetime and so they will burn
themselves out but with these machine
infections and particularly these this
last you know most recent set of
instances they just revert back to being
susceptible and that's where the zombie
metaphor is coming and is that they they
come alive they know they do their thing
they exhaust memory in the case of them
are I specific one they die off they
become susceptible again so it's a
zombie just waiting to come back to life
and come back to life just control based
on the speed of light basically the
Internet backbone and the ability for
scanners to so refined these compromised
places and you know just sort of kick
start the whole thing again so
tremendous amount of scanning activity
going on I can't really speak to the ice
that I'm not a security researcher but I
get what's going on here and
the more these are out there the more
world scans are occurring and it's just
taking off and now it in bizarrely
thankfully may be open sourcing Mariah
seems to be blunting its propagation
it's mutating it's fragmenting some of
the compromise hosts are cut off as the
injected target puts up its defenses yet
loses you know but possibly loses its
controller and so they fall out of the
network for a while but a power cycle is
all it's going to take at some point for
them to become zombies again so how are
we going to solve this survive the
zombie invasion