and okay
welcome to the life talk am opting to
take a break and the announcement
between the picket wats
an blocked two guys could be present
today are
on everest and can you mend a an making
for dr. NW
and they're presenting the results okay
security research paid our
a contract they're doing adults and the
he's getting the prize
while Islam soul Scott and
especially i think im you to maybe be
presented so it will be a very
interesting
your content entity and %um with
recommittal
all hotel to look more fancied Negri
than before so it easier to
get so hello everybody I'm night that
got it to the last talk and we have some
quite something interesting companies
and deep
technical stuff award presented to you
and its all about the school enterprise
wireless
security and I mean I'm we can
nearly skip the who we are I mean
everybody knows as historical trends and
that
some two things all one thing that
a we have apparently you some kind of
but a company blog week going but 20
it video insinuated top cop a dotnet
salty fried with it 232 subscribe to the
RSS feed
and get all the news that would being
out on the world of
wonderful what a security so long
this is just too stay in touch with
what's going to
happen in this talk with just the
talking all
little bit about what's weedy meeting
with her
when we say enterprise-wide as land
security all solutions
we talk about so a bit about what's
behind
that what's not thats make the
difference between wireless and
enterprise wireless
and of course the technology overview
and the potential attack as you have in
that
just because of the the overall decide
and hey dig into
to freeware sins of Cisco enterprise
Wales
land where and the first one is the
at small world and the devil the second
Walton
is the cumm wall and we will not walk
is interesting from the security
standpoint within these generations of
awareness security and
of course we have some all blank and
this is an ongoing research grade take
so long
for the next don't know how long it
takes
time you will the a new findings your
stuff we can talk about that
because protest with just in the middle
of
and analyzing so
an what briefing we're doing
not only security research but we don't
do
also doing practical implementation of
all that stuff and
we did practical implementations of and
and the price gain wireless networks
and we had the complementary read the
documentation all that stuff nothin
some parts of the documentation when I
think is this really
with doesn't work said that his defect
just read by reading documentation you
say this
can't be possible this shouldn't be the
way it is
so every time you read it every time we
set it up with that
and now with this this hurts you don't
do we
it like dad if you want to do with the Q
as always like a
reading documentation senior potential
liabilities
it was like that we said okay in germany
you say it
mild an in away like a okay that's
something wrong to say it like that
you say now than we said Kate just been
reading documentation
be see that at something going wrong and
we want to do at this couple
that you want to see what is the
potential of that
missus exploitable it so which are the
circumstances you have to make it
exploitable it
are you we able to write to me for it to
really have not only and you're reading
When abilities but really practically
vulnerabilities
network and that than exploit and say
hey
nope you have to you have to secure this
to happen you have to say
do that step to be secure or it doesn't
sometimes it's not even
possible to be really secure with these
environments
so this is something that caught us just
been reading documentation can we say
this is interesting topic we can do a
lot of stuff in there
and this is hard all started the thing
is
that course not of security research
about
while balding crypts and wireless about
a khomeini's how many times it
or how many hours just research has been
ban Gong WPP protection to break it all
down
this is all almost done this is nearly
and this is not what we're talking about
we think this more in
enterprise environment it's the ball
manageability in enterprise environments
that coming and points like you're
roaming
and when you have noise overview on for
example
an enterprise environment which has
somehow to be covered
so that more and we say we focus on the
more stop
more than what is shortly already done
and
in that field nationally-known research
done on to now
that some back hey we know this protocol
is law
and that may be used in there but this
nobody looked at these devices itself
nobody look at this
setup at the configuration inside 8 keep
an eye on
the following function and so
second point was also a very large
company
just paid us a little bit of money we
also got 10 the more hardware
completing the model we can work on and
to do some
testing with so this just
happened like it what it wants would
really good for us because we
good mix the two things together gotten
a girl taking research paid research
and even had access to hardware you
normally wouldn't
by because the costs like more than
I don't know what is that like 2004
30,000 euro
the largest control Cisco so normally
nothing a nobody of us would have that
just
lying around for research Nationals a
great thing
and so the missus all how all this
started
I what are the goals
I of course meal want to provide you
with a result of a security researcher
cause we say thats things going on that
need
to be public people need to know all
that so that they can fix your
that environment in be incorrect way
so that Wireless if SA-six your
as it should be and
course best also wall ng are you will
see the previous heart
that some whole protocol decide and
bolted
go three lost some protocols was just
day it's just in secured by the side UK
you can
say you can no for example yes thank
authentication you can say hail to
secure protocol design it for you in
secure authentication
boss missus long life follow people you
need to tell you need to show them you
need to be
some whole let say let this exploitable
by toolkit
and of course nothing really up to you
all things going on that expressly in
the Cisco wall
that we just wanted to show you that
some slight
the which just make it on the end of the
day I would say
soul what we're currently talking about
it in
can be poured in a cool picture like
that
what you have is a corporate network
in all in for the understanding of this
talk is just all the way it network
missus we don't have all but this is
just wide a corporate network
of course we have a amount of access
points which
delivered the and wireless mobility and
we have the small white notes here which
I'll the end users on the wireless
service
what is always the cases that you have
in some way some kind of control
which is responsible for controlling the
Larchmont Access Point thing about some
from large company campbell's with
that's a housing access points there
needs to be some way to control that in
a centralized manner
and this is what the controllers of for
depending on
which generation they do more or less
stop these controllers
nearly all have in common that they
support some kind of
an don't wanna 8.o 2.1 it authentication
song there's always some authentication
server and more
that are sometimes even split up for
like of indications up
inspector devices like excess point
because they may be placed in hostile
environments
the think about a conference room
and the authentication service for como
by
nolte the end users of the wireless this
is sometimes even split up
and of course better credential database
for the authentication services itself
which is in interesting part and
the funny thing is authentication
service in and controls a
typically always administrated beyond
that interfaces
and I mean application the
better education security is a field of
its own that mean
everybody has a me over if you all that
whole
many things can go wrong in dat and it's
not the core business of such a
controller to have a secure web it
by the way sold this what all the
generations of Cisco Wireless
and field on and weaving
hanging there hack all after your I'll
treat
different generations Wireless new for
small business
so-called structured Wireless where
networks
and often called as long
and then there's things all the great
difference between the first generation
into
in the second and third is that you have
some may call it autonomous
access points meaning nearly all our
tickets place in a
in the access point and nearly all
function is take place in the access
point
and then the the second and third
generation
and built awning some really control a
model
the exact point get down really dumb
sometimes
the access point is nothing more than a
pretty between why it
and what your last nothing more an
this came from the acquisition of every
space in 2005
and which originally built that model in
Cisco quite every space
and with that the complete product
and the complete model of came this
wireless with controllers
I'm what if the control dot and if you
look deeper into the vices your the see
some parts where
you really see the brand name every
space in it even if this quiet
right now so I'm you see this is Justin
like an
a like an ongoing switch from Ari space
to fiscal which does not have finished
the third the the second generation is
built on a protocol called
like wide x this point protocol about
this will not be covered in that Paul
the third generation will be covered the
new protocol
the called Cup what and its integrated
into
the vision of fiscal called Cisco
Unified
why let network this this will be the
second generation will talk about first
vietnam
then the CNN generation we'll talk about
going
tell you something funny ratings people
and
so what are the main attack has if you
look at such an
complex environment it's not only in ask
that point with some configured SSID
but it's all about management and having
this integration into existing wired
infrastructures
there of course is attack have like
attacking traffic which is currently in
transit thing about
to he's dropping on the wireless
interface if you're
being if you may have access to wired
connection an access point but just an
alternate from the wall in
take that cable for example so this
isbn: part
get attack against cryptographic
material use a lot of cryptographic
material on
one-sided on the y los interface
and of course on the why it
interfacing access point to because the
access point might be placed in a
hostile environment like a conference
room
all public area so confidential data
which is transmitted from
the access point to its control and must
somehow be secured
typical an field for cryptographic
so excess main apec have all that
cryptographic material can we break
cripple can we
some how do you write the key that is
you for
securing that can we may be in check the
devices
and Wintek packets into all that data
stream
and menu late as we want to
and the last thing of course the salt
complex compliment with a lot of
software on it
attack against the continent itself
like attacks against what interfaces
physical replacement of
interfaces to statistical tampering with
these devices all that stuff many a
physician
of course attacked again management
interfaces
this also involves protocols like ATP as
SNMP SSH Telnet whatever is all
they're used for management
Nikon the main attack pat and that we
figured out for
this kind of environment
so it's got over to include the s1
myriad
the S 10 10 will now be say
filled with some devices the
idea between it behind yes one is yes
so-called why Islam control domains
which is nothing more like a the
dysfunctional eighty called is a while
if the main
services the WTS
in short so you have some kind of
control
within the certain state that's a
part of the network and within
that domain York or you have of course
these wireless access point the way they
think that points and the WD
its mobster dates change Massachusetts
on a protocol called WN CTP
and these all
for example of Education data which is
transported
this could be cut graphical material
like
pair was masa keys which is reported on
that
so this thing protocol which is
interesting for us
thing about the main attack have
stripped the traffic take
against cryptographic than
panties everything's and all that
and of course these the WTF moscow has
some kind of
authentication the within
aquarium authentication server discuss
that you are
ACS in normal and that's the kind of
monitoring device
called the widest lens solution engine
WLS
he which can lead to a mall then one of
these
and playlist domain so you can
spread like a while if the main an
pit office you have alway this domain
building you have
and within such an domain for example
services like
roaming and from one access point to
another
touring having was over Whiteland called
forty-some
stuff like that going on dig deeper into
debt
great guys about the complex structure
mean that is behind
is because it's not that easy the
important
and one important thing the solution
engine right here
communicate to the masa also using WS
TCP
and so on the youth this improbable but
they Chris Paul
different types of data like radio
frequency measuring date on all
still the the idea is
to say okay an access point has quite a
bit of logic in it it does the group in
a while is packets for example
and its ok enormous but it needs to be
configured in a sensual way
so you take a the while a plan to use an
engine for it
all the away as long service medal which
can be placed in a cup
65 for example
an did with WL CP
it became really interesting the
protocol itself is
the documented in to US Patent
applications
the but its you can save new like
little bit divided in two parts their
message types in it
and some messages types carry non
critical data
the unencrypted male
and documented within the attend
application
and a message hide which carry
attends a dictator they aren't repeated
and they are document
so you have to revise engineer these if
you wanna see
what's in there
the the the figures
you depending and what just set up is
and what the the kind of day two AC-one
to transport your
different types of encapsulation and
a one thing and many really hard its you
don't have a really good
possible that network and I'm quite sure
that in Brumbies to a pic potential
application
the Wireshark corning guys only called
the first one because it
has in the name of the protocol itself
and
but it does not contain many this
package description
on SSI description and so you have
like let's say really basic message
paldon everything else you want to know
you have to read invite and headache
and sometimes in binary soul
I'm you have to realize engineer it and
you have to take
in account that it encapsulated data in
different ways
sometimes it's even at encapsulated
sometimes it UTPA encapsulated
and the protocol itself is a really I
think complex monster
because you can do :p the only thing it
can't do this cooking
what it dogs in the background is it
delivered
well one thing is it delivers
authentication services
authentication services in two different
menace
the first one is every excess point
authenticated
within the whole infrastructure to be
sure that
the nor ok devices able to join that
infrastructure
a good idea by its cool into effect of
Education
is done by protocol called light white
expendable authentication protocol all
the principal bro
proprietary the second thing is you have
of indication of client devices como my
notes
and this is this is not bound to any
AP method it every yet he met to discuss
support
so you have need to have support a
client side and on the authentication
server
and then you can used that
authentication method
be authentication method Bowl
weary here retrieve encryption material
informal keys
so you have something like that
so-called network session key and SK
the NSK he is what you get
after your successfully authenticated
yourself
we are typically and that's something
additionally in the infrastructure
authentication call
the is the so-called context rent spare
key
CPK which is derived separately
of the FT Wright the net an escape
but this of things we will talk about
will be later
soul an what are they really
been parked in year is
an siskel is giving you
possibility is like having really fast
roaming
imagine like an at the clinics
and say can take up to several seconds
if you have a pic Voice over IP phone
call you want from one access point or
the other
got it roaming you have it re of
indication process
that takes that long your call dropped
Cisco says we have money fight that
process
weekend the the process roaming
can be done in less than 150
milliseconds
which is quite possible home call
doesn't roll what they do
it with even the slightest the main
service
they cashed your encryption key for the
wireless
interface and they distribute the key to
the new
access point you wrong to that system
this is the idea
you don't have to ago the fall
techniques the
message on often the case in
authentication exchange
but you have some whole you have to
transport
the key from one access point to the
other excess
which is done an using
wsftp and of course because it's
ban if encryption material it's an
the key it security relevant
these data is protected encrypt it by
the so-called
CPK so and if you want
ever wanna showing
into this the city paid
becomes really interested interesting
for you if you are able to get that
you can you able to communicate within
that interest you
the second thing it a.m. you have these
a while if the main service ma sis
that's an election protocol
if anybody knowles is this cohort that
by meeting people
each a rst
use maybe remember they have strong
like mobster election and
bill up on the priority you can
configure
with halting kinda authentication
the same paying is here
it just happened priority value in a
packet
and the one with the higher priority
that's good while estimates are some of
that
and I mean this is quite obvious if you
can create these packets
your able to pin the master collection
you able to be the one who controls the
complete
Wireless to main West Mitt
potentially excess every pairwise
masakane
that encrypts why industry at in traffic
and if not okay if you both the master
and don't behave like a must see what
happens this is typically
a denial-of-service so it just bring
down the whole infrastructure
and Wales becomes unusable so
I this is one point he said take what
does this have to do
we've got a protocol this time and
or weekly with a if this is usable
you can exploit that yet to then
that might not might not be a good
practical decide
so I I think it's time to head over to
die not because they know that the
coding
and he will show you old bed
a act all the talking about the
left they'll actually and just
all the ball and then
acting it can't be that hard to just pay
duty right back up to 30 we left
electing
and for start creating
and you about a deadline to seek aid I
got a team which sends out there at
negative and all the access point
up with that the I day a W
yes Matthew so my connected to the
theory line with one of these exit
points and
and as you can see they
just elected one of that which is in
this case
and the exit point with the got turned
on the left act at
and a business done automatically
they both adults and yes it the packages
and
like them i three all mean
okay still coated small to me
which is called a evaluate the puter
cricket
many to name but and its recipe
one sec so I am wanted to deliver to the
green
won the IP address all the you
an added yet more of the revised and
make a trip up the method
in this case I just used the and layer 3
in there to address of my
physical interface so I will get all the
and traffic the exit points we try to
authenticate
with me with the new Matthew and 42
traffic
and of both I won't get into your role
you must be because I don't behave like
that
a WTF so it
that the area it will end up in Internet
it 123 and just
wait a few seconds to get enough I could
just generated
and all the access point and
just get noticed
all all me up than you may think and
at the few seconds to beat the they both
got it
and you WTS and three which is goodnight
address delivered at
material and the IP attracted in this
case they both try to be
just and authenticated with the new
yesterday
which we gotta be done because I don't
entity that and authentication request
thing at mate thing kind of did I look
at it
you see okay these which to thank the
Lord because they don't got a
W the peace-loving and
all day and the and distributed
and W land get this guy yet
funny thing about that course have to
configure on an access point which at
that point is the WDS master
and the moment to configure that
and the their excess morning
to or hadn't certain priority work for
value it 10 Alden these packet the
priority value can be up to 255
and they send all the number 254 so you
always
able to school from austin because
that's just one number let
and you can configured the priority pace
yourself
it's just to say if this is the master
it take
nearly the highest value but not expect
the highest value available
so we always able to do that that meant
a whole
how you configure that divided so
Monday I will sleeping aid yet
briefly then long to do the
and and though missus
like really simple the more I don't know
how long did it take
for you to call Det young so quite and
easy if you own it on BluRay documented
a
you'll be values within the protocol
which acted dumb from
original packet is a paper and bite by
bite into the cold
saying as all about that it's not
located
quite easy peasy but can be a very
successful if you have existing
that they unlock button excess Boynton
typically these the while 31 access
points
Houston and hanging on the wall
typically this
kind of infrastructure behind it but
that more
an reset okay the the communication
between a piece
is some have to queue its base of
indication of Education sleep
remember back it was a I think it was
2005 some
great actually a ride he sold 8
you able to break me because just need
the beliefs Ellefson some by
10 a.m. touring encryption the it leaves
at
value 0 so we can retrieve the key all
that's a part of that
and you can't break need it the pastor
is not strong enough
boldly the and going to krissi001
pay how clever is it too Houston
already broken authentication scheme
for such a thing at the school
this girl really says within these
potential applications we know that
leave this insecure
this is why we derive special key 56 you
critical data in that infrastructure
but the me this new key
is based on the key that is delivered by
me sorry operating the
I have that the key for deriving
the new key and so I broken to get
and this with again the question about
lead protocol the site
in the pain it said it
50p 50k its right to know
really easy manner and these PRF hunting
is the
a is the function defined in the
meanwhile bandits
operating key material
and you give these a password this is
the
so-called network session key which is
the right by Lee
and then you have some pics and some
ideas which I mean
nothing more than Mac oppresses and some
make arrests Hyatt getting on to switch
it
random numbers and you have to keep
secrets counter to ensure every time you
create a new key
I'm doing Reiki met you get a new key
and then you get all that information to
the PI function at all
comes here contract context transfer ke
with 32 died a blank that all
and I know that he's you don't
transmitted in cleartext so I had every
information I need to get that context
in fact to break
the the whole infrastructure so
the only thing is how do I get in there
all done all want to break who all
we speaking by video city
and it's quite easy because these kind
of packages for authentication
a European capsule 8 so just taken and
that
with 10 of the cables on on the net that
point
and drive bring the whole network
segment and you will get
all devices which do speak W SEP
easy but hit me authentication scheme is
look like the the WTS late
or all the access points in a
WTS environment which are not moscow
authenticate against the mafia in that
environment
and the monster is just like Danny
already sold
it says the package you sent alternate I
think its height
second space to broadcast so you know
which
who is the mobster in take your
Queen authentication data and you know
what up this late
use initiate the authentication so
there's only one thing that you need to
opt on the day
on the access point to get all that data
other than that particular
and guess what because these devices
goal will be to
up school so it's totally easy to get
that
you can get the and the NSK
truly cricket that the grateful for that
you get the 50k an effort after work
it's just you both could be the WTF late
newsday
the following no more by an old with
that mac Address
is roaming to make that point give me
the pair was masakane
forty before the wireless interface that
which is established that no one told
and then access point will give it to
you because you at
that contact transfer K European that
you belong to the environment
but you do not and is broken
so the end result is
you have week of indication
on infrastructure and if an attacker you
able to get
every encryption key for wireless
transmitted date
for wireless transmitter traffic and get
all that date all of that
so why does is mean all the whole
infrastructure is not secured at that
moment you get
excess to the why its second open access
point
so calls we have a deal for that
to dunno takeover the
the mall an all that say the coal
jointly stopped at the point where you
have the TTK
because we say the rest it's like um
you want to talk to people and we don't
have to called
all up and ready that from when back in
it
for and but we can show you we got the
CPK
between two devices so dunno it
building we need to disconnect 18 impact
point just the poor thing really
indication
and then need dated you could do
anything
acting texting are you can just do this
why an taking out the a
WDS small then and just delivering
day packets at all forget yourself mark
the
and after that exit points
Justin bold another order a
you yes then you got all the
authentication data
a different way with the of sporting
interests not for wanting
packet to see because that some people
out mechanism IP based
of opened on Paul call a packet where
like two minute the connection between
this late animosity
onto I'm still nothing fancy you have to
do
to drop these connecting official ways
to
blockade you okay still
with that and nipping and interfaces and
at the moment we won't see anything
because their Kb
and thinking and have a look at the
council
should see it
okay it just switch to send an opening
then they again song
there most disliked available
written like indicating a good
thing
didn't at the field while when the
applications by
you with the and communication
popping up up
and
good
you
in master its I'm
consistently indication
a it still indicating
a strange only should cool thinking
okay it
there is actually be a communication and
at the theater state
we just than sniffed all in
to the reached request and rethink it
think we got all the material long or
and
lead working with attack hopeful that we
just have to be
selecting a quiet day this best-prepared
work well with Bay
an matching past gate and wide at the
beginning of the parties to take time
and then no reckons that
trekking day sleep at night at the
theatre body just
all the pathway which is a 123
and ewwy and
at the getting out there leap ethnic
this a
communication weekend says generate the
and it
K which is displayed and the body
and want to get the Noke just need to do
the
an show on the repudiating
running hey pointing and that and
do we get the ticket it miss key now is
to use
for like if you're on promoting excess
point another
the request for you that was my sticky
will be encryptor an authenticated by
that he'd
we had that key we can don't in polls
we're
what we are a ballot access point and of
course
we have the picky itself to authenticate
against that infrastructure the weekend
not only say like okay we stay in a man
in the middle of the
can't participate with like own expense
point in that infrastructure all
our own people software within that in
perspective said
completely open for snow so
we get the band was not the key out we
get the we get way less traffic
and then your vision for that too
is like the you connect with your cable
to
the white side of the Internet by
unplugging and I P
and it just get the
get about 50 K and then you to fade hit
me
me pat was not the key for the following
the
make it s Wireless mecca and I
automatically to trip the data
of it maybe place it in a peek at what's
up like that shouldn't be that
shouldn't be that hard to place it in
the Peak Avenue kinda open it with
Wireshark interest nope
into what the white
motto of the mobile client the you on
the that interface
okay
hidden
goal an in
net interest for that they it's a reason
this environment what
or at all and build and back toward
and this is a security advisory wrong
what is it to to help the poor
which that that was all for it default
username and Bell
the username and password within that
w/o
St device which made you
able to have complete control of the
device so
that you see that some from
missing parts for real the your for your
secure environment
which a which need to be in place just
to use it in a
incorporate passionate secure fashion so
we say
the this case generation is broke
maybe we don't have all the cold up for
showing entry
Iranian lied butter it's not a problem
the rest is just some but they
Corningware
but the the breaking it up completely
done song
after that we began to focus on the the
carrot generation and the so-called
fiscal Unified wireless Netgear
and the interesting parts in that
network
are so-called fiscal wireless control
system
which is some that's a
very blind spot briancon even the system
to control your whole wireless
infrastructure
and
called the these Whiteland controllers
excess points and big
different in in that infrastructure
is that the access point get Dom
and the on the coordination of wild
Alliance of indication of all but halted
all that stuff this
all done on the White House lawn
controllers itself so
you can imagine X excess point like
really allay a1
preach between the wired interface and
the wireless interface
sometimes this bridge that the crips not
packets sometimes not depends on your
configuration that
not much more the devices doing
goal and we set up this environment
because
with a this what part of the customer
brought take the
we gotta really big control all that we
get
the same access points we set up the
whole paying
and this was the first thing we stop
that
you see some traffic going from
and more or less on the client IP
address to
colonial I P broadcast using protocol
this lock stating involved the
all displaying the current day of
devices in that case access points
trying to authenticate against that in
fact check that take
bed it up cool it
transmitting this long in
away like this and this is like a oh I'm
a lot able to in to keeping my eye my
automated
automated discovery process honestly
you been you set up these devices in
their automatic discovery process
which should enable them to stated in
and have working environment including
just
this is like if you see stuff like that
it just ate
West the security in that in that and in
this environment
so if you think a little bit deeper
you come about you step over the
protocol FL
called Cup up and
what it is is this a UPPP based protocol
it encrypt it using data from TLS btls
which if nothing else like TLS WDP
ended uses certificates Paul
education itself like okay
why did the sand mechanism to secure
your data
and all security relevant data
is encryptor an authenticated using key
material
I'm derived in during that's the TLS
authentication with the certificates
full but they formed
the first point a few looks quite good
I messin
axes of course involved this goes
i think is going the way of designing
protocols and trying to reason that
mister
public protocol and the main
our thesis so for 118 a hockey ticket
a taxonomy for control and and
provisioning of wireless access point
and hours see if I for one 5
and controller provisioning wireless
access point spread
hope specification the summit to you
main hours the switch to
define couple and of course quite a lot
of up protocols involved
and that for automated
a of all the automated some
that DHCP involved even for access point
call to have why it was involved you
have a involved
the things like a syslog that this and
then he and I ate and
all what think this long
want political
gonna anyway and quite some protocols in
what is that
complex structure so
an the pain is man who really is that
the ball
what like reading this r/c just sees
things like 8 when you a couple
and you encapsulated Cup what you TP
only with i ke version for addresses
leave the IP check some feel at the role
because although why didn't like that
you repeat take some otherwise the
packets will be dropped
what's that this is a text every day I
should economic package to
make sure that your information is
correct
so this is like a another being that
part of what we say
we really have to the it deeper into
that environment because nothing
really some point going wrong an
say in Indy today they determined that
protecting the couple practical detail
and even implemented got like a
and the reordering negative that look at
all that bad
and stuff like that for this protocol is
it's really really playing
yet so we just part about today
missed what quite in bed quite different
to the first generation
soul I'll attack perhaps Ali
on time and and look for it especially
about the
50 stuff is that okay what's this I'm
this is
even if it's documented in RFC with this
comes out of the
let's face it collapsed this convention
all that an
today we have all profit or stop did to
implement btls which is a
an artist on their did the implemented
themselves
did they use open like respond that for
example
it it like trees like a what may well as
you know
the OPP on the type to use is it
winnable called the protocol
if go with it like united visited remote
code execution whatever
and to Courtney question but on the
other hand
in encryption they you and
death certificates certificates are
to pick up the courts all I'm cut
you know that some questions like a
certificates is
displaying trapped between two entities
and
question is that whose trusting and who
says that these two entities contract
its a bit
if there was a like certification path
and all that stuff for certificates and
maybe things like a
that sayin relocation of certificates
which is it
widened part of all this is that okay I
interest you
just doesn't that work is it implement
the correct they're all that
so this will cost you 1 attack
and assessment I'm that will
need to be look at all soul and
the first thing is we looked at the
Sofitel unpacked the image in all that
stuff like a
okay on whether except for the mix just
let's see what
in that to second text strings on it and
resolved all ASCII strings and
in that long lineup ASCII string know
what need
include the critical
they use within the and the image access
point image itself
is open Excel based
on Verizon the 0.97 be from
to of victory this is from an
really decent operetta excess point
image
is it you don't know is it packed
that it had one abilities if so and Ave
can exploit them on that that and
because it's not a
normal x86 like a policy that poem in
all that stuff
and the court did mate also be like
licensing issues and all that stuff at
this could hold up
okay back in 2003 as we're programming
initially program that thing weak
hearted
open SSL continue
add to that that could an and we had to
do some stuff like okay
it's not possible compatible the image
you have an access point and all that
stuff
so that quite some potential sport just
mistakes that
say like that that may be introduced
during
application all that may not have beaten
peaks
and but and to leave the
holes indicate that point and
implementation up
still that's good for the certificates
the certificates Rs
there signed by the so-called COO
manufacturing CA
of the MIT and they are pre-installed on
expect point during
process of manufacture during you you
not able to overwrite the images
your not the you can read them all only
the public park the private key salt in
it
they say secure are real the excess
point all the
the flash drive we don't know this might
be some
interesting part 4 somebody who's
willing to revise and musical II
point access point but the interesting
heart is
that everything you buy has a
certificated which is signed by that the
eight
meaning if I take the Speck this access
point
and stick it into your wireless
environment
between be authenticated because fiscal
feel
across in to it its people
everything's good devices capable on at
successfully authenticate itself
into your environment as long as you
don't replace the second on the device
so misapplied of all quite funny imagine
like a
unblock an access point and like a
controller into it would complete
different configuration
complete different networks and I just
recreate you all wireless network from
wpa2
down to no encryption because that
locked in a control stuff like that
I'm so this is one thing was that okay
thing about the crossing behind that
that this is no
this is not a good decide if you track
every
hardware which come from Cisco your call
stress hot weather that
and hacker country into your environment
and difficult and attacked again
management
people we found an MP which is enabled
by default
which has of course some people
configuration guess what
public-private conversion to see
or read and write access and the
complete call
communication between that wireless
controls to
which control to a complete
infrastructure
and Whiteland control which is
and the intelligent which is like had
OpenAccess
on the talent in part were the access
point communicates with
its all done yes and it P and I think
this is a good part for Daniel
to hand over because he's the classical
SNMP guy
and he will tell you a little bit mobile
that a good thing
and took a look all more we get them all
yeah okay
pick that up all about that very thing
presidents ripping into a pick up a
small
okay and nothing special
hey I took a look at the at 9p and
all the Mitt behind exit points
a W the Selanne
their worst song had from all that
interesting
and values you could get all case warm
is and
yet been released Monday a gave
manufacturing date all
the ISTH think about and chill gazing
and
II that's good advice and it
alton page b2 identified
period a situation through the exit
point
so I can see the which while its client
is connected to reject this point
I get all the latest information a
goodly 3 information
and of the client an
ok well up the exit point feel I get all
the
a IP configuration of the exit point
itself
and what that could be set why I think
you're right
exit King and I could just reconfigured
you at this point
my attending militias ethnic he
commanded
bTW healthy an
and the walls all kinda strange that in
the
and message information-based a
opal most ultimate still owned by
every space so you see the all those
products a
just all in and and that girl immigrated
to fiscal
an friend asleep you walk
with in a bit and you see them
them long strings by the way this a 4839
is every space and
kitty very reflected and rank
AP detected or anything about the truth
like
a linked only got think this is
actually who think they did in the
had as an MP met the truth commission
based
for all Latin ppl bleak you could just
read all all the
loading that the truth of you wht
and which in this case okay bill like
the information exported
an all told there is warned you idea
in the irish-based admitted which is
called
agent at 9p community name which in fact
is the community 3 configured and at 9p
still with all at the MP reject this
you could easily read all the S&P rights
community 3
its fifth level I don't think
and by the way it recreate
so if you got and right exit
3 gate a keep making basic
you could just an attached on you
red an 83 just be effected
an one more you could redoubled
all the name all and using
a twat and ok nopee admin
on the EEOC unfortunately and
the path kid obfuscated by expires
you can't read all pass gate but
all there to be all 33 create
you could just create new admin using
and then we did this in all tests that
I just extending one ethnic peace at
command
and getting in your local administrator
you
and by the way there local administrator
user is
able to lock in on the web interface and
change
every configuration option like it
administrator should do so you have
it with one packet needed the whole
device
okay and 33 an
K week and reset the password of an
existing using
bad as I just that UK create and you at
menu
yet only a local admin but also an admin
user
which got them more privileges a
on in a bit more about a can
a normally we go to the mall here by
showing you how easy it is to create and
yet music that we don't get the
a wht with a thing unfortunately we
can't
presented at: like believe it it's
really really the
just fire at Wally I think he said to
make set the right already is to use a
and it has made
that then you thirty at me anti-roll
okay so long you can read me
K when I can I'm okay so
the thing is i mean this is ongoing
research met some topics we have to
admit
to look into but this whole saying
compact
haven't nearly of a dusty protocol
in there doctor call different purposes
that are configured to know let's aim
all that your way I'm
of sometimes it even obscure way thing
about this is like paying
and this is default configuration if you
wanna hack
if you wanted disabled that you have to
enter as
separates the slaughter got this look is
enabled by default
thought an and this get
the deeper you dig the mall security get
nason
broken truck model in it with brings you
to the point that I can inject nearly
every Cisco hardware which belongs to
that generation
in and by the way the switch from the
second to the third generation is just
an image
upgrade so you can take off in the
second generation put a new image on it
and iPod before the party generations of
that enough heart valve that
and when that you can use to abusing
all that stop and of course they are
controls and and you can configure
nearly everything you can configure SNMP
version 3
on everything why is you have six you
ought to
mechanisms in there like a shahal often
TSR
hasting and ATS in
encryption all that stuff but it all
disabled by default
and you know the more complex in an
environment get
thats time spent hardening
because every administrators happy that
bought environment self up and running
and that's what it's all about
availability
so I'm this one paula when we say hate
this is so complex that so many wrong
default configuration
really if you try to use that you
think about it pics read the document
said think about that first look at
every
configuration option and think about it
first before deploying that thing
because it can really make you insecure
and don't forget
the basic network building plot like
segmentation and all that stuff because
if you
don't forget that and I we get to you
SNMP traffic
and you forget to use SNMP version free
because maybe your
fiscal works which does a monitoring
to is not capable of doing it we got
we owe you always pain
and make it more or less insecure this
evening's
sometimes ways to break it and
my personal opinion is that if you look
deep into that scientific 8
I quite sure we able to break that too
because
verifying certificates is a cop is
really tough call
unit everybody says hey we do it every
day in have
all the time it's not easy so
if they let may be talking a hot here
may be here late
militia we are quite confident tell you
more
on that sony Mobile abilities and show
you more
obscure things a on these environments
and hopefully also get a break
generation to which will
just at the moment other I'm that they'd
like that
but it can it on the it's on the agenda
so and any questions
you want warm everybody's tired
combat tonight Christian it's like good
can't all your W guy it's maybe around
questions course hey I pretty sure that
we have a long-term
day-to-day I S&S Monday that's just not
enough Martin
okay maybe tonight shortly so I am
diner only thank you very much for your
day and inside you too
to school enterprise-wide Islam and
systems thought that maybe I'll ask talk
and detect track thank you very much
for joining all to this country in and
I am maybe happen very nice trip stratus
trip home
at hope to see you next year I'm pretty
sure you do it again
say thank you very much thank you okay