the
title of this talk as tools of two
traits
home what a nice also see as those
a dose a kind of I'm sorry behind to
talk about this
lassie and about term something august's
la CI I was for several reasons I was
quite often Austria
and I have some contacts to
to saw the University in Austria and
they approach me like them
I okay an arm can you all we have a arm
a curriculum for information security
management
them move in that direction on can your
provider
say a free day all walks of one
I
say are roles and tasks and challenges
son what have all of
ISO some I i said well
I could probably do that us
my lot of my walk includes
solving nasa kind of from I call it to
insinuate a
so I'm seles are on to
to I saw this is something we i there
were some
several ISO psych consult to own a very
ongoing basis
like him I'll I we once in some
some weeks are reviewing documents are
providing and why some
terrorists on the line by women who are
pretty much every week I get something
on my desk like him
what's your opinion on this so can you
have a look at on this
so I know say there was a high sauce
what I think quite a lot so I i downside
yes I could probably do that
onstott that discussing
sadik potential contents of such an
curriculum on
on a possible level may never for me my
old friend Brian fy2
gave yesterday stock on are tossing
security
and who's the boss of the packet loss
and
he done came around some I mean he's
organizing another you went in in the US
and
he said all lesson once you have to
prepare to stuff anyway what about
giving a keynote on this
at the the US Conference I agree it's
on one you will see today is that exact
keynote
so compared to other presentations I
think giving in the past
which usually had some more or less
technical content or some
arm yeah let's say
some some structure are to somewhere you
have a
stuff that was prime spot at this one
might be a bit different
it was intended to be a keynote I'll
which it usually means it should be a a
bit thought-provoking not too technical
not too overloaded with stuff
and I saw I've done this I was some
approach several times when I discussed
this were from
I saw up colleagues at some level
I like cocoa could you give this again
on so true plus obviously it's an
opportunity to
if this again CX sector same stuff
no modifications since some essential
house what I think stayed more or less
the same
and I I put it in the afternoon of the
second day
as usually thats people get more relaxed
and
a I mean you can't hold attention
of taking high-level input a
in a foreign language for two days so it
seemed to him
having at this in the afternoon of the
second might be an idea
so enough Sat do not expect some
the same level of technical accuracy
that maybe other presentations are given
apostate
I skipped this I'll skip this
block there are so many free piece S&S
talk that s I discuss say that costs and
challenge us
be the past
tasks on it car and to all those on that
I see in the future
often I saw a alarm discuss
say what what is the role of a nice all
within an organization
as I think this has changed and I will
spice it up with some
references to movies I
from what I get many of you are mainly
say India the same H that I am
WEA no more 22-year-old Sudan so
you might know some of the movies some
the
might be part of the audience not being
present here who have no idea what what
kind of movie is that
so there were some some emotional well
you at the taco
which might even stimulate you up yeah
at that time
when I when I was young I was at movie
at the intended audience
obviously s as I cells that Desai I want
to kind of
I wouldn't even say I have a message to
deliver I'd say I
like 20 make your thoughts going on
body or olive in your organization and
the way
your you fulfill your daily Tosca and
maybe
I get some ideas so what could be a
all waste 2002 considered under
by elements to consider in the future
and I cystoscopy my
wetland congress talk I'll what I did
was a i
a contact at some ice also that I
no or no on slightly possible level
like okay done I am facing BDA
the task of preparing a talk on walk
from your focus back to
automate failed five main
responsibilities
I often I saw land I collected those
I put those together and those on a5
that are mainly
that the on with them most on
say points like number of citations:
that is a long time security strategy
creation of policies and guidelines risk
assessment
analysis of security incidents on taking
care of compliance
this is a pretty common I'd say
description of what I saw
usually das what is interesting about
this
s a this is heavily say circulate at
around the let's say security space
which might not be surprising given I
saw stands for information security
officer
so obviously this possum has to deal
with security
sure admit it %uh still
on when Mike the two-man introduce
himself
us the head of application security and
to information security office i'd
at the I W I was tempted to at
that at the time when I have a save gave
him the responsibility the role of being
the other ISO the understanding
overnight so warsaw okay this possum
has to be a a some body like it
teria gonna send I'm I mean I'm
I'm not sure if this is the correct
translation into English
likable the doc somebody who iz a
paranoid about security
and by being paranoid some about
security
balance assault biznass forgetting about
so you need a a bulldog on this site
I'll to a to have a say a balanced
living the overall organization
this was an a very commandant I
understanding of the role of a nice or
in at that sometimes and me
classifying this ass at sometimes means
I think this role
might have changed some I in the
meantime
mom I think that kind of how I
understand
a and future I saw is so what i'll would
call on
and thus a Thomas the sunday weak point
by point wife item
across a business and Liza so not so
much as a bulldog
trying to are to correct was caught what
goes wrong security wise in the business
Walt
and someone who might
agreed that this role hasn't performed
so well in the past
are so it might be time for kind of
role adjustment in the sense of all I'm
I'm know what a bulldog I'm
I should be I should try to establish
myself as a
process lights um
this the say it just meant of
for a potential adjustment after all
often often I saw
a is some I mean they're worse
elements coming in which make this
adjustment
say maybe even haha that is so was
getting ever more complex
I'll their wrists stuff like outsourcing
on which at so some say contractor
complexity
think about the price of yesterday doors
new technology showing up
heavily are changing the picture of how
security a
all Aug heavily affecting say the
overall picture
security like what relation on
a there was limited we sauces and it
says
always be like that have limited
resources and it will
believe me about be so long
the SATs some spice to the challenge has
a nice oh might
face anyway and there is the Harry touch
of being say to spice to your own
organization
for a long time it's not like t.i so I
saw
most well you'd turn mosul of passing
within the organization
are to say it cautiously on
soul there were seven tests and this
challenge ass
have to be face on its arm
not even easy to face them given the the
role
I and DNA match that business might now
for fun
of a nice on what i'd saying
charm makes some al amounts of job often
I saw
rds.a a sudden persistence
so if you don't have to if you're not a
pup has a certain type of guy
you might not be qualified to be nice
all on it's a job that
week why are some constantly going into
battle
that's and battles that are all
quite a number of them might get lost to
some degree year so on
having some persons house it absolutely
hot summers and the business
on that s what I think a key requirement
for one and I saw the ball the doc at
the time
obviously I'm given he was powerful
organization arm had some maybe to
dispose of some
knowledge of the business but it was
some at a time it was a
know we gotta take a key qualification
for being a good I saw
about it was regarded like okay this one
has to be our
someone who knows about security and
hoot carries to bed now security
and thereby balances out to stuff from I
think I'll
knowing I'll business walks and then
prying I mean again this is so I'll
not that new but them a trying to add to
our
allying business and security
this %uh some what are Izabella
elementary part of a nice life and again
this is
not that use of all for you I
and yeah although this is one of the
movies by the way
on who who recognizes which movie is
that
yet taxi driver are and there is a
famous scene on
I mean doesn't many famous scenes in
taxi driver but
some argue might know that some he's
kind of our
I what's his name in the movie on Travis
arm Travis s kinda preparing for its
mission for its job going out safe to
walk
any talks with Mara a resume famous
email he's there with a crazy
expression on his face like talking to
me
Outlook email are have a look at the
issue you what you will find
that one on he goes he he's on a mission
and it kind of goes postal orders
mission
and yet this might happen to a nicer as
well on
but are Arteta get
law seriously I think there were three
peace S I'd like to to bring on the
table today that assess a technology and
technological change us
communication until Sun sound
assay mindset so mental attitude often
of a nicer to what some his mission and
this job for asphalt technology
again this is a loose collection of
thoughts there was no
by was stricter structure a in it I'd
like to
mention free things I see going on of
if we things I we got some
maybe in parking for nicer to understand
that's what I call the house of security
on that s the chanting changing Fred
landscape
anti evaporation of network-based
controls
i gay for some of the those of you who
have fun
seen my troopers king of last year all
with
recognize some slight said happy news
before
this is one of those this is what we
call the house up security at
on think about it doesn't I saw
%uh sitting on this on this task
and della sua like security control its
all like a firewalls and antivirus on
policies sound
maybe some process us and
one of the year say approach
us 2002 well to rate
they don't walk ought to understand the
on lock could be like to classify all
the
all the elements all the instruments
contributing to security
and discuss education can be done in two
major ways
other foster that I'm not going to
tackle is the one number
preventative stuff the to Texas stuff
and we action stop
arm and usually I
a money spent on prevention is better
than money spent on detection reaction
but that left be cites another approach
of classifying all the components
components not just mean products of
tactic the peace S but process is a
swell of guidelines
on all the pieces contributing six to
security
can be on in move in some
classifications scheme
been broken down broken down to
components
file on sandy Weisz whatever stuff that
you buy products
second I what I call implementation
holiday stuff buy something
put it into your environment
I am hoping at to somehow to contribute
to our
on security and operations how you
operate
the stuff within your environment
and from those free say pale ass
and in the end of the day already
will have to to get some security
on and implementation can even be split
into
say two pieces like to sign an
architecture
and configuration how you assemble the
peace S
for made products coming in box us
all your net for this belt how these
pieces are brought into the network
and how those pieces are configured from
these p
free pilus arm
ought to look to maintain to their arse
we saw says need it
I usually for of all components is money
for this I type of
first of its some FTEs
unfortunately it so looks like this
I and I'll what i'd like 20
delivers a message from the slide
usually
organizations to some degree focus on
one of the
safe repair Las I in the US
there are so strong there are set so
called best of wat
approach large US organizations
a look at it got no we part so who's in
the Magic Quadrant all we have a
security problem to solve
by this I'll get one of the freemen
dozen
I'll that I and got us Magic Quadrant
a let them pay for 5 Kos
there now with a ship crews and arm
than decide on what to spend a huge
amount of money
arm of all for some
components a plus associate at
maintenance
contracts are not sure if this works out
there was a other organizations which
put a very strong
perspective fun
say this one aware you have to
say on the Golem all fall forms to be
filled out
a and some background checks on whatever
our
a to get access to assist some and then
this access as
implemented but %uh not abut
still they think they are secure so they
have a strong
element of from what they call
all what call operational security
understanding
that there are three pillars trying to
figure out okay in my organization
we mentally focused on this one or that
one on this one I
might help to get a better understanding
of our house security Watson Dr
on organization in general as a rule of
thumb
spending we sauces here the URL
a Manowar spend he usually
will fund your mileage might vary I
contributes launcher security at than
the
a unit spent here
again willful um
but the think about just spending money
here are bringing on I mean this is so
we're quite some amount
of Jesus band on it's good to
half security in this space but some in
the end of the day
Iran WV perform a lot of a security
assessments
the Securities say holds the findings
we stumble across usually are located
this
space it's not like a the ass a a good
fight was in place it's not like they
have been configured correctly
when the they went into operation 12
months ago
but today I rule number for
487 as a are
kind of a allow any any 4 side neck
network segments
and this means that we saw sales went up
band
the right place so this house a security
a
might be a some approach
to get an idea how security is some
I strive for in your own organization a
second thing
again citing from my last year's keynote
Asus one on that the changing
Fred landscape Indl
all that data some degree malicious code
guidance system
awful ISA long by missing Pacha
a diss has changed to a large degree and
this is
absolutely no on nothing new I'm telling
you here
are what happens in the meantime Asus on
their way to use a is
saw I involved and arm
the user performs lots of functions were
by means of a browse our mate line and
as well as i hasa
all kinds of additional functionality is
I
and locating at say
I'm off on that security incidents
Condrey
in a sufficiently large organization I'd
say
75 eighty maybe eighty five percent
Brian I'm not sure what your perception
s
I what put them into this I
into this space are so this is a space
remember limited we saw sus limited we
saw so self repair Las
and a mission to make the water secure
ma secure placed otherwise of the
organization
this definitely as: I
the stuff you have to focus on currently
as for technologies
arm if I'm everyone sign some weeks I
have a discussion about
this and
a I use a time like a way for
a if area a come out right on the
roundout I had three vicious
disabling XY I would be one of my wish
us
usually I get out okay what's the other
two on overall
I mainly to us we are to far over onto
the set afire
over there say depending on for my speak
to
but those five I'm name them at some
point the friendly
during the presentation on pretty much
status a min and one of dollars says saw
I this aiming de vise grips and Acrobat
Reader
which hassle-free
think I Ali I mentioned thing what a
business
there has to be a line the business I'm
currently a
I'm in the technological space if that
harry turned up when I had some wish us
in the technological space
like down to increase the level security
disabling JavaScript what be
this is one of those are getting way to
win the CDI is another one
no one eats that that has been therefore
10 years ago following disappointing in
the days of possible pointing
know what any pretty much no one in its
a GTI and TDI accounts for
Heights a6 si VI critical Connell other
liabilities and Windows since some
in the last 24 months so does the
component sitting around
know what he needs which assets every
year
armed security problems us okay without
this will
immediately I'd say increase lot
decrease the overall
%uh level of fun security
are an ailing DP
would be not a one I mean does up this
stuff is from the time when I get to get
the keynote
but this stuff is so we covering I could
have fought founder
a similar I
one in the in the February edition of
Microsoft patch day and
a deal with this year had this always so
many
stuff in both way to and flash its it's
easy to find
such a piece as well on so we are eager
to get your free
on the other two after the talk
are this is simple stuff
but some given the con tread landscape
I'd like to
this is my personal mission to on
delivered a message
they're worse it's not about buying
XY set I D S IPS
are d-pa whatever kind of inner product
space
it's simple things that can greatly
a increase security and to these are
some of those
of thought point and it technology space
s
there s what I call a evaporation of
network-based controllers
in times of our con la chance staff from
the growing together offer was lies
Asian
of maybe put putting things into the
clout
the traditional approach of
network segmentation of filtering at at
same network come
upon us this this approach
which I've mean preaching for many many
years I'm in my and my pa some
I'm a security guy a yeah I'm sorry I'm
a network guy I have a better a
background in networking I have a
background in that have operations I've
been working in
lots carry environments are I have been
singing the tune of all you have to
second-guess to fill it up for many
years and
I kind of cool I still do but I have to
recognize
that this stuff for in in the currently
on growing ma Jing
watchful eyes so walt's on
doesn't make sense too much anymore
which some
again possibly this house as I I'm
network I
but what idea consequence some
there are side of security control its
that gain importance
that is so mostly what I call the host
hardening
are so hot ending of entities host
doesn't does not necessarily mean a
physical holes
but my dolly the as well i mean that was
a machine
but a look at the entities processing
date are
and try to increase their security level
as they have nobody out so
to rely on in the old days one could
rely on OK testify a 101 day life
sitting in a in a dedicated
segment arm not everything can get into
here
the state's elvira PS
might be responsible for your own
security
and encryption my play a large role
think about a whole cloud discussion
I'll
what can you do on a national level once
a day doesn't clout
nothing you can try to encrypt a which
brings in new problems
like a so that easy to such databases
that I'd quit and stuff but
some I'll
decir a slight shift of control its from
the network level to us a system-level
whatever system means atom but about a
moment might mean in the pic
cation are some some some box
be at wasabi be it physical
so to summarize his first piece
operations is key
take care of operations prevention pace
prevention mean some ton of
functionalities
on that you might not need I have from
going to this discussion so many times
and
I love it tired of it still I like to
discussion
or get you shouldn't have Flash and
suddenly most people in the room
would agree but your business needs it
up okay if is in its at we have to
understand business that was one of my
past my such a southern
be de flash stale whenever I have the
opportunity
I I tell you the frat landscape is
changing
and stuff like flash this is dangerous
stuff
if you can get rid of it so be it but be
have error
that if you cut could get rid of it and
beat
Justin say sup departments a subpart
with the diminished at the frat expose
it to
logically a second communication tools
again and for the last time no I I
inform you that this is a loose
collection of things some
I just want to bring up again some some
mids are some elements somewhat
what you show it and lot of Eli cyl
I saw several already practice some of
the stuff for
anyway I'll just so what I think
arm given that initial moment
for to talk a lot showed a nice so today
sigh so
are we consider what should to: she know
and think of from salomon
understand who s the money I mean this
is as again it's a simple thing
but I obviously
are the approach of being a baller doc
within your organization doesn't walk
anymore
arm I mean you you might %uh still
approach that
a was so so far law a practice that
approach but nobody will listen to your
business will do
what business wants to do anyway I
maybe your have good luck in the San
Siro
there's an a governance instrument like
a risk it sat down and saw that
cause a lot a lot on your desk like okay
the Swiss government business ask me all
they have a policy violation
year okay other less followers this up
except on Sun
so everything's months you have to get
it I was like oh said the
analysis %uh firm se me to get it up you
at now now it is OK baby prolong atom
and a than the might come out
appoint a little you come maybe you had
you can to save prolong
the risk that separates us more than say
24 months
a but then something else happened so I
it's named a bit differently arts are
I it's some gets a second chance even
high on the hierarchy level
aughts its just paper on a fun anyway
I so you have to have a release if you
want to get your mission accomplished
you have to have at least within your
organization
on I ass simple ass assaults
my experience some try to understand
so who has money all with power-law
and with money who you might Katze
say into some millions of the quality
guys
said they might have been a funding and
you and
I somehow come of laws your mission with
their mission
I try to find out where to get funding
for your
for your mission I and who have
even if the SAR early as this you might
have not had to a
in the past some don't going to fly to
country
their wrists faces are not some
are there was flights technologies you
content have it I
regardless how hard you try I think
about BlackBerry's
think about what yeah
maybe on suddenly on the stand for it
some
are what make sense a fight and wet
doesn't make sense
some and if terrorists are if it doesn't
make sense some
don't don't try that this this isa
ass sad as this might sound for for my
first moment
on this is an otherwise some I was
suddenly gif
those people into and University cause
like okay if you are
don't be naive there will be fights you
Conklin
don't spend your energy up
policies on
remembered its life where I had us one
of the tasks of my soul writing policies
in quite a number of organisations the
dusts it's not like there's 1i saw
who performs lot of tasks and writes a
policies
himself them I P divisional I saw some
likely I so so contrary I saw
all this and they do not why the
policies
there are some maybe some group for at
the CES although department or
I if things some all the nice in Assam
way is they said
somewhere in compliance and
compliance upon whatever law arm
if you have not written them yourself
establish a line of contact the policy
people
you will most probably is tom brokaw
situations
again if you'd not not what number South
year a
you had a policy you know it by heart
maybe i shud i sell
but there are some discusses coming up
if some behavior of business
is aligned with policy and then you have
arm
a stuff like cum policy mandating for
strong authentication
strong authentication for Preval sxs so
what does it mean what a strong
authentication
and are there are cases where this is
defined in the policies
just quite some cases where this is
Marty find what this means what it what
a strong authentication
does it necessarily mean two factor
authentication
I'll what are those factors us are two
say different pass what some not good
enough farm
are too packed us %uh to pass what's a
factor some
so if there is something in the policy
like a strong locational
a strong authentication populist access
arm
you have to understand what it means
especially in a situation when you're
get menu unwilling to chop it's not like
a organizations not disposing of
policies right now
but think of our arm 30-year-old pason
authority fire farm who wassup promoted
to be and I saw
on divisional I saw I mean in that
say space of from 500 to 5000 use all
annotations
yes they'll plenty of them who don't
even have a nice all
but they will I say should have one bead
only for compliance we sense and then
some money from mobile network security
appear
I high-quality all that lies named the I
saw
asahi this POS inherits a policy
try to find out what is meant
I if from there was classes like this in
the policy and this happens very often
in case you write them yourself in case
you still have TV
position and Tosca writing policies sup
of business
this some most important point even
thought this might sound process
security people like him
oh wait a we we surrender
we we say our love their business at the
those all enemies son now that
while later I have to write a policy is
not to control them to steer them
but to support them a believe me I've
seen so many things are
sup of business you won't get out of
your position
as a bulldog nobody listens store up
if you do not change your mindset to a
mindset that is not
I'm at the fight all say the the
approach of fun
his policies his business and his people
behaving
and now policies come in and have a
controlling impact and what's get better
this is naive
this has been an understanding of policy
of yes sir
2002-2005 this does not walk
so we have to find not a model and the
other one s
maybe sadly but it is what it is. yes
business and in the end of the day been
as winds
so change your mindset to one that s
okay I understand
I'm on a fight some on the last
possession
I can still try to pursue my mission but
I must support business and this should
be
saying that we're loading in the in the
arm mental attitude is policy is
as written where which might mean to
provide some flexibility
I you can still be a precise like
prescribing
very end the watering arm
stuff like strong authentication must be
you list
on if this is feasible for the
organization and air from
people can find out what us strong
authentication mean
and if they have a a parson ideally you
to approach I okay we want to implement
this or that some
I'll technology a this user some
a weapon to face the authentication is
done by on a pin it on
this is good enough s what's wrong with
authentication or isn't it
arm they should not decide on their own
they should no who to ask
you are maybe some other departments are
women the organization
and went to our ask I think some point
within the project
this is a setting you have to be a arm
trying to prescribe how the white
behaves by policies
that'll another thing come when talking
about
talking about policies are
there was some business while change
dress
us whole while change us and their arse
are more and more
things like john Lynch us corporations
I large corporations
buying smaller ones selling longer
industry
operations all this kind of stuff there
are smaller and more business partners
or more like stun parties
try when again you in a position of
writing policy I just in policy
try always to I'll
say we consider this perspective
writing whatever kind of from policy or
guidance you want to provide
Joss looking at all these %uh my user us
might be shot side the soyuz us but
the next day somebody turns out it turns
out there was a joint venture with from
I'll some company in the Emirates like
the example i gave yesterday
to I those passes will have access to
your sister
to to some degree I
to develop a new product out to make a
lot of money this is what business wants
are take my twice try always to think
about what this about
Extang parties coming into my
organizational into my network
this is a perspective growing have a
more important
lastly in the essay to its escape from
to a spacer it's all about or scan the
end of today
%uh so honestly I already said it
yesterday I I can understand how any I
saw si ESO can walk without
say it will perform so hot water
efficiently without
wis.-based some who space approach
in every day decisions a soul one
should have fun some influence from and
so wat whisk
which I summarize as for a second
section
find their ideal lease on the stand one
your mission is lost some from the way
first moment
there was some a changing role of
policies
were in the overall implementation of
security and was placed
plays a major role thought part mindset
and approach
arm this one this kind of
repetition when I had earlier be able to
take punch
us thus if you
are you don't have I say personality and
mindsets
that some able to do so
you should to maybe I saw the best shop
for you on the wall
this one is some more important and to
some degree
associate thats to that angle of
business
you might recall from those of you who
have been present my yesterday's talk
on director risk assessment
I mention that case %uh DVR we've abroad
and
to perform their up a risk assessment
are and the
heart was a soft open discussion
were the that project
as I call it now I argued with for okay
we can for
size safer 325 million US dollars a year
on the security people the Bulldogs
well-liked 0 wat we can do this saw
this will arm %uh just the sky will fall
on and that will be my lover I want to
all
corporate assets will be a ex post
just talking about this you can
certainly understand
are which of those parties have my
sympathy
which s believe me but just may be funny
are some ways you might my time funny I
feel secure doing security since 97
I love what I do
I for family and I'm doing some spots
but besides this
pretty much everything I do in my life
some as we dated to
security I do this and let everyday
level I have been
one of the Bulldogs in the all the time
so it's a it might sound crazy seen this
possum
Collaroy I'll who is a security guy
and having sympathy for business %ah
being about cost savings
and making fun of of the Bulldogs still
this is part of my pasta line Inc of
the Bulldog approach doesn't walk any
longer
I'll you you will lose South the fights
anyway
soul try to adjust your mindset
from I'll
some action so we take
hot told us we place bets of tokens all
that this might mean was a falling out
that everything will break we will have
a tax on
to I'll we will get out of mocca
to a mindset that this okay
on suddenly there might be some
impact on the security arm
on some aspects of security try to find
out which
this is again by the way do you want to
risk assessment will come in
but some obviously changing something
technology and architects are a contract
the modding
a model of operating I T I will f
Atlanta chess and this is one such as:
we a security people in the past
has been used to understand just
ought to focus on a disadvantage us what
can go wrong
about the risk definition
um I kind of gave yesterday all that is
using it for a sec
is usually a can cause harm risk
something
oh and yes where that late so negative
impact to harm
which is completely conto rear to the
understanding of risks a natural
language
and and German we have that time like
and physical forty going to name our
a risk in that case is not
it's not a bad thing and he's all he is
a cool guy he takes risks
to which some call it together which
whatever our up to got to them of polled
by swimming
tools runs the whole what about and
that's a positive outcome
try to understand that what happens
might have positive outcome and Mike
even have positive outcome on security
getting rid of hot opens sup
suddenly I I'm cautious okay
I take might increase some attacks %uh
face
but might at the same time free a lot of
are we saw service
needed for operation so far are
those of you who have been sayin
inflatable operations
I in a sufficiently large organization
you will know that
there is some
given a certain size of an organization
there was one ft E
that s dealing everyday somehow us
with hot topics of it has been at a time
got that up but the hot helping sell
which had lost which had to a place
which I'll the same can all this
so a technological change might have
this atlanta just but might have
advantage us
try to adjust still mental attitude not
just from looking at risks
things causing harm but maybe things
having positive outcome
which is perfectly a depicted in this
some are described in this
a piece I took from one of the main
I books on risk i John Adams
whisker certainly II week away reading
it
it's not the it's not about it for a sec
risk what was once an hour
and I he describes the situation of old
people not leaving the house
us as some might fall fall slipping on
ice
are which obviously it would you assess
the risk
but still not being able to leave the
house anymore
takes quite some say life quality
away from that so it whiting risks
I might mean you miss opportunities and
this a SWAT
I i want to the Picts assists our
again try to adjust a mental attitude
some thought at a value of trust on
some love you already know this stuff of
contra dance
which I described like being able to
sleep while
up being built on to sauce
that distrust in control on
if I want to if i living in Hollis Rd in
my capacity of sleeping well of feeling
cozy warm and safe might depend on
a decision that goes like al-qaeda so
this is a friendly neighborhood some
on I'm far away are from bat
a create just some things anyway so that
I don't have to lock my door I I don't
even need a lock at a doll
banda de sus this is trust I
obviously I could be paranoid like I
laughed a lot my house and they are any
defense and
II needa motion sends on all this
on these elements of control both
might some contribute to the fact that I
sleep well to some degree
problemas you can control everything
your we saw some limited to you have to
trust
some were you just have to figure out
we have to trust them not to control and
the ball doctype
10 store to use controllers all we have
to
control it is we have to bring the same
you might know term
I have a different stance or something
so them price I would be hot soccer
to today armed you have to trust some
well
soul we got crossed as a good instrument
it's not just about controlling on Monte
tarring and putting
we saw sis into is so immense
try to understand where you can apply
control
over you can apply trust so again this
is about a mental attitude
term there are situations where you can
trust our situations way
contrast on and you might need some
control saw at least
trust might not be applicable way of
handling the situation
but understand this in the end of the
day I should be confidence
are confident sleeping well not only in
the past
level but a saying have a climate
our farm of productivity within a given
organization
and this is saw sauce from two sauces
trust
and control not just focus on this one
and this costs money discuss operational
at fault
no went to use this a try to understand
that has long time on Sat paramount
there was this can we walked the wat is
not always an dingbat
and technological change us are have
towers want it's a chance
chance to and to be able to maintain
a level of farm felt security
of art security tools for those process
who I factor
thrust sauce are so
to summarize some there might be a
at that cooperate in for a sec wat is
complex and
even gets more complex every day I and
it might be a battlefield for
for boycotts %uh still
I am optimistic that and I so has a
has a very important role and command
given the right mindset given the right
tools
certainly accomplish a mission
and this mission should not be the
wonderful bulldog
but if a trusted business thanks
all about by the way which show which
movie Sat
knowing us yeah
that scarface that's that only went on
arm-in-arm
I haven't on currently I effort to Kates
a boy 27 your than a my god whose
five years old and anti there's a very
famous quote from
scarface that goes lies on my name is
Tony McDonough on I got a mani and I
gotta J journal
dangerous of in that
in that context I mean it's a it's a for
a lot drug-dealing follows
you who know do not know I'm
scarface and I do remember why but I i
talk my little boy
like that's an some my name is Tony
Donna are I gotta money I got a date Jul
and he or she found it very funny in
here he will get it all
all-time a my wife hated me for this and
obviously he osco what is to change a
law
that said oh wait this is something like
sweet some I am i buy IBM
even more soil scarface Sr yet process
business advice of that should not be
necessarily
to perform the role of Tony went on
about that should be
how to understand you're a slice back
arm are giving the keynote style I'm
I'm not sure if there were some need for
questions are there any
iMac to discuss some the stuff
and the remainder of the conference
on it's anybody of you staying overnight
anti-lock
although you are leaving today and
decides to speak %uh so I mean
difference because they know tonight
if any of you want to say for that feel
free to approach me
that can be arranged thanks for your
attention
and have a a softer conference are
in Co