good afternoon welcome to a two-part
panel on new diplomacy for new conflicts
as tentatively has been described in the
description of the panel you may see
that it deals with a new volume that is
assumed to be out and it's a special
issue in the Journal of global policy
and the first part of this panel is
going to introduce the main ideas that
have been at the core of this special
issue it is my distinct pleasure to
introduce the panelists of today what my
far right is professor emeritus bill
zartmann from Johns Hopkins University
School of Advanced International Studies
one of the pioneers of the field of
conflict resolution and a relentless
worker on publishing as much as possible
as quickly as possible in the middle of
the of the panel is Valerie Rousseau
professor from University of Leuven in
Belgium an expert in reconciliation
processes and Michael turetsky director
of the Magee Moe Institute for
International Affairs in Moscow all
three members of a very unique group of
experts and scholars
if international negotiations called pin
processes of international negotiations
which is now hosted at Giga my name is
Sunita Vukovich I'm associate director
of the conflict management program at
Johns Hopkins University School of
Advanced International Studies and I
will moderate today's session without
further ado I would like to give the
floor to Professor resort Minh to
introduce the volume and set the stage
for our further discussions professor
zartmann I don't does that carry yeah
okay I I don't know whether the
organizers of this conference realized
the deublin tanka that they had in the
classy title that they gave to this
navigating through disruption that is
obviously finding your way through the
disruption
but it also means and this is what we
want to focus on navigating by means of
destroy disruption and that's very much
the topic that we're looking at we're no
longer in a system of world order we're
in a system a world disorder in which
entropy is rising tremendously at a
number of different levels we have a
multi-state system with non-ideological
power plays both on the international
level and on the regional level
there's no blocks there's no hegemon and
what the players like above all to find
is vacuums that they can move into
before somebody else moves in to fill
vacuums for power reasons and there's
normative chaos in the current system
and as somebody said earlier in one of
the sessions the rules and norms that we
all that we all believe in are being
mantled dismantled as we speak and that
was a very good in an earlier session
introduction to what we're talking about
norms what norms are we talking about
norms of the conquest of territory the
treatment of refugees and IDPs and
treatment of dissidents international
territorial integrity weapons of mass
destruction trade practices national
self-determination protection of
population humanitarian assistance are
all subject to crumbling norms in
international regimes are also melting
down international regimes on
international trade on non-proliferation
and climate change on security through
the United Nations Security Council and
the ICC and of of territorial waters we
no longer go by organizations that carry
out norms on these important subjects
state dysfunction is rampant in many
parts of the world the states aren't
breaking apart as they used to a
recession is section but they're
crumbling into little pieces and
and non-state armed groups are taking
over security functions within pieces of
the state with no goal particularly in
in mind the non-state and proto state
actors are impervious to international
attempts to try to bring conflict under
control they don't care they continue
and do what they want again I say rather
aimlessly and finally there's the rise
of national disasters national disasters
are always around for us but they're not
not the disasters because of nature but
because of what man does not do about
them opioid drought the migratory fish
cholera and water deficiency for some
states in addition even more striking
perhaps for the interests of all of us
here in the last decade there have been
a number of striking attempts serious
attempts at conflict management that
have failed not simply conflicts that
continued but it attempts to bring the
conflict under control and that have
have broken down and not gotten anywhere
I needn't remind you of the list of them
Yemen and and Libya and Syria and the
GCC and Somalia and South Sudan in
northern mountain of northern Nigeria
and Mali in the Central African Republic
in Afghanistan and in the Philippines
Abu Sayyaf in the NPA and then when you
get off land in the South China Sea
attempts made to bring conflicts under
control that have failed why and it's
striking that they all have some common
elements that have kept them from
arriving at some kind of reconciliation
first of all they're all stalemated but
the stalemate doesn't hurt and the
countries either arm themselves against
hurt or won't feel it or else their help
from the outside so that the hurt isn't
felt so bad and so we don't have a ripe
solution a situation for resolution
there are no searches for trade-offs one
side is saying I won't accept anything
that you're offering me because you're
bad and
and shouldn't be there anyhow and so
people are not looking for trade-offs to
resolve the conflict and at the same
time there's no interest in reframing
the conflict in such a way that perhaps
we can redefine it in a way that's
beneficial to to both of us there's no
support for the mediator and the
Security Council sends out mediators
cuts his hands off and says tries to try
to walk through this conflict as best
you can cuts his feet off in fact so
that you have Kofi Annan coming up with
his guidelines in Syria the the UNSC did
not publish those guidelines for two
years a striking example of mediator set
out without any support from the
mandating agency and then outside states
are interested not in conflict
management but in the conflict and they
see a vacuum a role to play there either
for proxies or or simply to keep other
states from getting in there and so we
have navigating by means of disruption
somebody earlier today said what are the
little things that we can do to change
the momentum and our project here is
trying to come up with little things not
systems of world order that we put in
place by Fiat but little things that we
can do to make a difference and I'll
just tick them off in the same haste
that I've talked about the earlier
problems we can it's important to return
to the idea of state building it's
important to build States
internationally it's important to build
problem-solving groups that is groups of
states and NGOs who are interested in
solving a problem without waiting for a
mandate from the the UN it's important
to give mediators support again by
individual states who are interested
even if the UN falls through as it does
it's important to build multilateral
coalition's to deal with problems
including coalition's of the Willing
when a legal coalition is not legal by
institutional laws
it's important to bring together teams
of rivals states that are competing over
a particular issue or conflict or place
and say ok you all have different aims
but let's try to see if we can't meet
somewhere to bring these under control
and to stop the killing of human beings
as we did in Cambodia in ninety or as we
tried to do a good process with the
six-party talks in in Korea it's
important to encourage regional security
communities so that states in a region
get together share defense information
pledged not to attack each other and
then turn to solving their problems in
this type of increased security
situation these are all procedural
suggestions that we might take up and
apply in various places and there are
some substantive suggestions as well
it's it's worthwhile thinking about
reviving historical mechanisms such as
marches or neutral zones or autonomy or
non sovereign self-government or
self-determination it's important to pay
attention to status concerns because
many of the conflicts that we see now
are people whose status has been
insulted they feel with a historic
background it's important to develop
mechanisms for the accountability of
humanitarian aid humanitarian aid goes
to southern Sudan
it goes to the rulers of southern Sudan
it never gets to the humanitarian tire
targets it all goes into their pockets
and then we wonder why they can't find a
solution to the to the conflict it's
important to work with local communities
if the government is unmanageable it's
important to get into local communities
and help strength of them as the United
States for example did with as a year
back in the last days of Mobutu it's
important to pay attention to post
vention that is prevention by attention
to
happens after an agreement because we
tend to make an agreement and go home
satisfied that the job is open and it's
important and more broadly to restore
the level of permissibility to raise the
threshold of what one dare not do so
that we can think of normative
limitations on our actions and I could
go on thank you Thank You professor
sermon gallery your paperwork was on
reconciliation processes in the Middle
East
you'd like to share some thoughts about
that limits of reconciliation Mora
thank you very much Tunisia yes the
question is rather simple is what is the
role of mediators in dealing with the
past basically and the starting point is
the following in the aftermath of
violent conflict the significance of
memory issues is paramount
the israeli-palestinian case is very
telling in this regard the succession of
crises and tensions over simplified and
radicalized narratives of of both sides
and today the representations of the
past are not only diverging but
incompatible think about the
interpretations given to the 1948 war or
to the origins of the Palestinian
refugee question or to the plethora of
the mosques enriched in Jerusalem
so all these examples illustrate the gap
between contradictory narratives so the
question is how can mediators address
contradictory narratives
well I suggest in the in the article to
me to maybe take into consideration
three potential attitudes the first one
could be summarized by the formula
neither nor its tabula rasa attitude if
you want needed the Israeli
representation nor the Palestinian one
and the argument is simple there is a
race
that telling stories of the violence may
justify the next round of violence so
it's wise not to explicitly address the
past that was the explicit argument
during the Oslo process negotiators
explained that they could debate the
past four years and never agree so the
objective was to agree about the future
and they concealed all the references to
the past I would have a lot of examples
I have one one another one just one
concrete example Bill Clinton confirmed
this position during the Camp David
talks one of the Palestinian negotiators
referred to the situation that followed
the Shoah in Europe to justify the call
for compensation for what happened in
1948 and this analogy this historical
analogy was instantly rejected by the
Israeli negotiator who considered that
both contexts were fundamentally
different and Bill Clinton agreed of
course we cannot compare so that was
really the attitude let us not argue
about the past
first attitude well in the field the
concealment of historical narratives
does not mean that the emotions not the
narrative but the emotions that are
attached to the the narratives are can
disappear it can be concealed like that
as well so from a psychological
perspective that's interesting to see
that all social psychology studies
demonstrate that children of the second
the third and the fourth generations
still has strong feelings of resentment
shame guilt and victimhood a
victimization sorry
especially when passed in justices have
not been addressed by their parents
generation that's something that we
really we work on that with a team in
Leuven and the University of Van and
it's obvious so a second attitude might
might also be considered not the tabula
rasa just the opposite would be a can of
just juxtaposes
juxtaposition
we say that in English as well right so
not neither nor but we take all the
interpretations of the past what do I
mean that the mediators considered that
they are neither judges nor historians
so that they could that they should
respect all the interpretations I give
you an example concrete one jacque
shellacque former French president who
was talking and listening - yes arafat
at that time it was just after in the
aftermath of Camp David and yes Arafat
was explained that there was no trace
literally there was there is no trace of
any Jewish people a temple in Jerusalem
you know the argument and then Jacques
Chirac intervened quite brutally to say
the point is not to know whether these
roon ruins exist or not it is to respect
the representation of the other side
so here it's ok this is the
representation you have another and
representation we take them all and we
combine there is a textbook history
textbook that was based on this
principle made by six historians coming
from both sides and they could the only
the outcome that the the could reach was
for each page three colons
with Israeli narrative of 1948 Oh
an event blank and then the Palestinian
narrative and it should children could
make comments between the two narratives
first attitude neden or second attitude
both interpretations of the past third
attitude new common interpretation of
the path much more ambitious I would
call that kind of zigzag between the the
notions so it's on the one hand on the
other one much more ambitious yes since
the purpose is read to develop a shared
vision and to go to good to better form
stories it's a reexamination and you
know it requires to go beyond denial and
to acknowledge not only the facts but
also responsibility
but we can have discussion about that
it's a huge huge question to me it's far
too ambitious I would like to go to the
conclusion because right
the initial question was so if mediators
can reconfigure incompatible narratives
and Sue me the answer is no the
israeli-palestinian case reminds us that
third parties cannot control narratives
of the past yet third parties have a
role to play to remind the parties that
their narratives are not stable and
fixed once and for all there are stories
under construction right altum Utley I
think that the the question to me is
probably not about changing narratives
the way parties talk about the issues
but rather maybe changing postures in
terms of loyalty and it's one single
question in whose name do negotiators
refer to the past to whom should they
keep their promises to past current and
or future generations you could argue
but it's not incompatible well that's
not so easy but I guess that
consideration of children and
grandchildren can bring a dose of
much-needed creativity and flexibility
so one last question for each of you
isn't it crucial to honor no it is
crucial to honor past generation but
isn't it even more fundamental to
protect the interest of those to come
that's it Thank You Valerie
thank you Miko I won't introduce your
paper I think you'll do better justice
than I do so yeah thank you sanusha and
good afternoon thank you everyone for
coming
so as the Russians should probably do I
did I wrote a policy oriented discussion
piece for the journal addressing the
challenges to regional conflict
management arising from great power
rivalry and the most conflict ridden
great power
relations are those between the
established great powers the United
States and to the extent the European
Union on one hand and what end and and
those powers that we call aspiring and
aspiring doesn't mean rising it just
means dissatisfied with its current
status and and wanting wanting more
okay so inspiring and global powers
often leverage against each other the
conflicts that occur in in the
neighborhoods of those aspiring powers
the neighborhood such as the South China
Sea or post-soviet Eurasia so as we all
know China and Russia consider those
regions their spheres of special say
privileged historical zones of special
interest irrespective of the legal
grounds for such a view but the United
States and the European Union are of
course also interested in in those
contested regions because of their trade
and investment because of the security
concerns diaspora politics pressure
groups from the expert pressure from the
expert community and other groups that
have strong views about the global
powers policy towards those regions and
so as professor Hartman just noticed at
the end of the Cold War we witnessed
some surprising comity among or between
the the two superpowers
that actually ended up sorting out
cooperatively quite a few conflicts
across the globe beat Cambodia in Asia
one goal in Africa places in Central
America and so forth but over the
following two decades the spirit of
comity the spirit of cooperation in
managing regional conflict somehow
dissipated faded out so we are now faced
with the need for some new conflict
resolution mechanisms or at least some
ideas as to how we can overcome either
escalating or simmering conflicts in in
those contested neighborhoods or in some
more remote places like like Syria and
essentially the puzzle is as I think
professor zartmann also just hinted the
puzzle is whether the leading powers the
US and the EU could concede some status
to the aspiring powers in return for the
aspiring powers actually cooperating in
the mediation of those regional disputes
and and whether and how and and and and
how much the regional powers can
appreciate the benefits of conflicts
actually being resolved while they
receive credit for for their resolution
so that is something these are the
factors on which the actual willingness
of the parties to jointly may manage
those regional conflicts and resolve
them may actually I may actually depend
and you certainly cannot think in terms
of grand bargains that would delineate
geographic areas of responsibility or
not speaking about spheres of influence
but what could perhaps be tried and I'm
trying to play with this notion in my
article is a web of negotiation fora
that would span and transcend the sports
and the regions that are contested by
global and aspiring powers and
negotiation in a way is a pragmatic
give-and-take right so it doesn't
compromise any principles neither does
it imply interference in domestic
affairs and and we already have some
negotiation for in place such as the OSI
later Russia Council Shanghai
Cooperation Organization and so forth in
in in Eurasia but we need more
comprehensive platforms we were asked to
be normative in our pieces written for
the journal so I I played with the idea
that we could perhaps formalize some
regular security consultations involving
the United States Russia and China and
any number of relevant stakeholders in
post-soviet Eurasia abroad Eurasia
depending on the issue under under
discussion perhaps belt in road
countries plus the United States then
some key you members and the US a whole
could also Foom a negotiation platform
perhaps we could also think in terms of
trade zones plus that could involve
China the European Union and some states
in post-soviet Eurasia Asia and and
Europe so the point is that such a web
of bilateral and multilateral fora could
be relied upon at least as at least a
canary in the coalmine of conflict it is
supposed to be on what the international
relations school Robert Cohen called
diffuse reciprocity and that is the
aspiring powers whose status is being
elevated would have to owner the
concerns of the global powers to keep
you know those valued negotiation for
running and of course they are play
there are plenty of stumbling blocks
there are plenty of obstacles that you
you need to overcome in order to put
those four in place or even make this
this proposal realistic and I guess you
you would first need to tackle the
widespread conviction among the on one
hand the global powers and and aspiring
powers on the other hand convictions
about their mutual weakening so you
think that the other party is is
actually in decline while your clout is
actually increasing and of course you
know you don't want to negotiate and
compromise now if you are getting
relative
stronger so you need to address those
narratives in virtually all of those
nations that would somehow that would
somehow prioritize that would somehow
reflect the beliefs of their own rise
while their opponents I believe to be
declining and second weed we do have a
fundamental lack of trust for example
you can believe that you negotiation
counterpart is never an amenable to to
compromise has no track record of
compromise and that looked to be the
actual mutual perspectives of all the
policymakers in in the United States and
China in Russia and it ruins any
possibility of good faith negotiation
but but hopefully and that's my kind of
bottom line hopefully there's this
mighty challenge of all the rising cost
of uncertainty that that is going to
actually challenge those convictions and
so you you're going to have uncertainty
you're going to face it if you plan if
you really plan on waiting your opponent
out and so the actual trends in the
distribution of power are much more
complicated than someone's linear rise
or decline or someone's belief in a
linearized or decline and so as we look
back at history we'll will see that the
aspiring powers have successfully
negotiated their way into a number of
cool multilateral institutions on more
than one occasion look at the World
Trade Organization and China or Russia
in the Council of Europe and there's no
reason why that experience of overcoming
hurdles to mutual accommodation cannot
be replicated cannot be repeated
thank you thank you Michael I will try
to expedite the Q&A and just jump on it
and I would like to invite you to join
us at slide Oh calm as you can see on
the big screen and please post your
questions as we go by
Valerie I think this question was
intended to you but please everyone is
more than welcome to jump in the
question is what do you mean by changing
the narrative of the past especially
when it comes to the Palestinian case
is there any suggestion at least on a
policy level how this could be done and
potentially expanded to other examples
that are similarly salient and difficult
to fathom in the palestinian-israeli
case I have one very concrete example
maybe and otherwise I will give an
example in another case during the Taba
conference in 2001 Israeli negotiators
explicitly considered the right of
return of Palestinians refugees and one
of them started to acknowledge the
Palestinian tragedy that was the
first-ever reference at this level of
negotiation and it was really a shift in
the negotiations and and this shift was
made possible that's what we can see in
the testimony of the negotiator this
shift was made possible thanks to the
work of the so-called new historians in
Israel I do you remember it a long time
ago but it's not it's not the current
rent anymore but this was an official
shift if you want another one which is
more stable I hope when Jacques Chirac
in France in 1996 explicitly as for
apologizes on behalf of friends for the
druids raffles of the veld if that was a
major shift in the narrative that was
stressed in France and we have plenty of
cases like that I don't know whether it
makes sense thank you very much
last question if I may just jump in and
following up on professor assortments
and Miko's remarks can you just briefly
remind us why is it so problematic to
create grand systems over again and why
should we focus on the more regional or
local realities instead
well I think for my side that on the
part of both parties there's a
disinterest in grand systems there is a
feeling that the grand systems the last
being the bipolar system for the United
States the the unipolar system were
ineffective were demanded too much of us
didn't pay enough attention to us so we
felt badly served by the previous
institution constrained by by them and
then we were surprised on both sides to
see that the other side taking advantage
of that vacuum of commitment and
commitment is power vacuum and
commitment to jump in and fill the
vacuum there's an absolute rule of
politics that vacuums will be filled and
then when you have status questions as I
both the mahalia and I know then it's
obvious that there are candidates to
fill that vacuum and then this increases
the disillusion and distrust of the
parties with a global type of system we
do have grand systems in place we have
the United States and its allies we have
this transatlantic relationship we have
more or less you know the European Union
in the United States with a global kind
of purview but my argument was rather
that in order to resolve some proxy
conflict so conflicts that risk that for
which there is a risk of becoming proxy
actually we need to strike a balance or
the right balance between on the one
hand the the scope of all the
stakeholders the the number of
stakeholders that there are that we want
to we want to bring to the table to
discuss those conflicts on one hand and
here I advocate for broad
for trans regional approaches to
discussing those conflicts whose only
then you may be able to address the
whole gamut of issues arising from from
seemingly local conflicts but conflict
but the one that has transfusion
repercussions so you have this number of
stakeholders that you involve on the one
hand and on the on the other hand that
has to be balanced against the depth of
engagement of your all of those tech
stakeholders in in a negotiation fora in
in an arrangement let's say that is
going to address those regional issues
and here we are not going to anything
very much institutionalized is not going
to work it's not going to fly no binding
institutions are not going to work so I
was thinking in terms of just showing
goodwill in negotiation fora where the
fairly broad a number of participants
that would value those fora as a
platform for for interaction for
negotiation and perhaps I thought that
could be an optimal way of addressing
those regional conflicts that are
long-standing that are becoming
intractable and that that have more and
more features of being you know proxy
conflicts and and and actually being
embedded into the you know into the
international structures in the system
thank you Michael
last question because we have to
introduce another group and it goes back
to the issue of narratives do the
narratives of the past actually shape
the idea of nationalism and collective
memory so I wouldn't say that they're
mutually exclusive and if yes how not by
definition a narrative is ambivalent and
memories ambivalent so it's neither
positive nor negative assert it depends
on the the objective which is pursued
but in the aftermath of mass atrocities
you you don't have spontaneously a
narrative which is not nationally
you see what I mean because you are just
focusing on your victims and and I
completely understand that from a
psychological perspective what is
interesting is maybe the shift in the
German narrative if there is a so-called
German narrative an erotic narrative
when I say just to come back to a detail
in the presentation I I said the Israeli
representation and the policy of course
there is no there are no there is no
like kind of two or Moschino and stand
standardised narratives but there are
less and less dissonance ease and and
and creative voices I have to say though
and so it's really I think that there
are two major factors to know whether it
is nationalistic or not nationalists
first timing when are we how many not
how many years but how many generations
after the violence and second factors
leadership leadership is key thank you
very much for Larry please join me in a
round of applause for our first group of
panelists in presenting this special
issue and I would like to recommend that
you look into the special issue because
the articles are now out on wiley
website and on the website of global
policy we will have flyers that you can
take with you to see the very impressive
collection of work policy relevant work
by academics and prax on the issues that
are most pertinent for today's global
order thank you very much and let me