I'd much rather be engaged in with the
u.s. involved 40% of the world's market
then disengaged be on the outside
looking in financial crises are now
global if one country sneezes the whole
world catches the cold it's really the
wrong time to be putting more frictions
more cost more uncertainty around the
short-term economic picture we are now
negotiating the budget but we do not
have a vision so we are first looking
how much we have and then how we will
send it I think it should be always the
opposite but there is no perception of
sunshine Europe in Brussels and that is
something that people in this region
have to do I would love to see the
Europeans not talk about the theory of
European defense but actually produce
capabilities and then also to use them
to spaces that I feel Express the
technological gold rush of our time one
is cyberspace and I did that a lot of
stuff with NATO
the other one is outer space our elected
leadership has to understand that the
future of liberal democracy depends on
our capacity to defend ourselves in the
cyber domain exposure and public
awareness are really critical to
building resilience if data is a
lifeblood then that's going to be the
driver of competitiveness we should
regulate for openness for democracy
you
[Music]