hello again from our glowstick
headquarter in Bratislava in exactly
four months we'll be opening the doors
of the 14th edition of blocks in
Bratislava forum we will be welcoming
over 1,000 guests from all corners of
the world
we'll run again with three main stages
in parallel and we'll make sure our
participants and partners enjoy a rich
and thought-provoking conversations and
a space for hundreds of side events and
bilateral meetings when the conference's
started 14 years ago it dealt mainly
with security challenges here in
Slovakia and in Central Europe today we
are covering a generous range of global
topics that equally affect every region
of our world back in fall when we kicked
off our planning process we look at
what's happening around us and we
identified six major priorities of
course 30 years since the fall of the
Iron Curtain and the start of the
democratic process in cee 70 years of
NATO and 20 years is the first eastward
expansion the fate of EU following
brexit and European Parliament elections
the OSCE and osed chairmanships of
Slovakia and subsequent priorities and
lastly the wrap-up of the vichy drug
group presidency with this in mind we
structured our content into five topical
streams future of Europe defense and
security digital future sustainability
and global economy and democracy in
disconnect we are looking at Blob SEC
Forum as a platform for structured
dialogue between public private civil
society and academia we are moving
beyond just the place to meet into a
space where policy agendas are initiated
and we look at how through collaborative
efforts and ideas we can adapt the
future for the benefit of all more
updates are regularly aired via our
social media channels and on our web
site plopsa dot org and as every year we
will be welcoming carefully selected
cohort of young leaders the applications
are open for those interested to apply
hope to see you in June in Bratislava
and stay tuned for more exciting updates
from our side