so good morning ladies and gentlemen my
name is Martin Al and I'm moderator of
this session with pessimistic or
optimistic
title a global economy disarray looming
on the horizon this will be the session
we will stretch the depths of our
optimism or pessimism is a V the future
development of of world economy and
because it's Saturday morning of the
third day of the conference so those who
are here now right now really need to or
are interested in Indo topic so it's a
challenge for me as a moderator and for
our super panel I would like to
introduce we have a taraji former US
ambassador to Sweden and wall street
practitioner of the world of finance we
have a Linda Yueh who is a fellow in
economics at University Oxford so the
economic and we have a professor Daniel
she loves key who is also professor of
economics at the Hebrew University of
Jerusalem so mix of practitioners and
academics I would like to start with a
couple of headlines or numbers from last
last couple of days there is a Reuter
reported Moody's report about the with
the title US economy will lose pace this
year after peaking in 2018 new president
of World Bank has lamented deepening
slowdown in global trade World Bank
lowered its forecasts of global growth
for 2019 from 2.6 from 2.9 to 2.6
percent
German German Institute for made a
survey which resulted in in the
globalization has reached limits of
acceptance among respective populations
in major industrialized economies
so and it's a stretch and German export
expectations are in decline in the long
term and there is a fresh news from this
this morning or this night that there
will be no US tariffs on Mexico but not
not the good numbers in the US about the
US jobs so picture seems to be quite
gloomy but I would be interested to know
at the beginning of each from each of
you if we have a reasons ten years after
the last big financial crisis if you
have a reasons for optimism or pessimism
maybe we can start with the like three
reasons for optimism and three reasons
for pessimism from each of you I will
start with you for example good morning
well I had to start with reasons for
pessimism on a Saturday morning but I do
think that we're more vulnerable now
than we were 10 years ago and the
financial crisis happened ten years ago
we were we dug ourselves out of that
hole by utilizing low interest rates and
a balance sheet that was handed by the
Fed and the Treasury and today in this
environment we have even more divided
Congress and higher deficits and so I
think that we may not have access to the
same emergency measures that we had back
then
in dealing with another crisis not to
mention the fact that interest rates
couldn't be any lower so I guess as they
say in the economics profession it would
be pushing on a string right I did pay
attention in that class I also think
there have been market and structural
changes over the last ten years again we
used low interest rates to spur economic
growth and for the last ten years and
that growth has masked some changes
fundamental changes that have occurred
for example climate change and its
impact on human population is being felt
more frequently and in greater levels
and the cost of financial cost of
hurricanes droughts tornadoes fires and
extreme weather events is will continue
to pose a drain to resources of
governments resources that could
otherwise be available to address
financial challenges so I think that the
combination of a more divided political
situation at least in the u.s. higher
deficits and less flexibility and
leverage on the part of governments
because of their lower resources in
being able to respond to the next crisis
those would be the reasons that I would
think that we're more vulnerable now
than we were 10 years ago and I'm going
to have to think about ten we know three
reasons for optimism so maybe I'll let
my colleagues thank you thank you I
forgot to mention that live so there's
always hope that's why I forgot to
mention that we have this nice
application slide also if you want to
propose the question please do that or
login with the globe SEC 2009 login and
and put a question there otherwise we
can then discuss in classic way as well
so please Linda three reasons for both
or for just pessimism I'd like to start
with the bad news first so let's do the
reasons for pessimism I think you know
as we've already heard global growth
probably peaked last year in advanced
economies and so we are in a cyclical
slowdown so you see that in terms of the
policy responses everywhere from the ECB
as well as Japan okay Japan's been
easing for a long time China and of
course the latest out of the United
States so in that sense it is part of
the business cycle but the problem the
pessimistic problem is in this part of
the business side
you don't want geopolitical tensions to
worsen the downturn so like I said
counter cyclical monetary policy has
already been in effect in a number of
economies to try to counteract as you
would normally expect the slowdown in
this part of the business cycle but if
you have the us-china trade tension and
you have a rise in protectionism because
of a backlash against globalization it's
really the wrong time to be putting more
frictions more cost more uncertainty
around the short-term economic picture
and I suppose another reason for
pessimism is that it's been 10 years
since the the last financial crisis and
one of the things the International
Monetary Fund and others are quite
concerned about is this buildup of debt
which is related to having had very low
interest rates in advanced economies
which means liquidity money is abundant
not just an advanced economy it's a lot
of it went into emerging markets so if
you never predict that they'll not be
another crisis because there will be so
you're sort of hitting the down part of
the cycle you're seeing probably quite a
lot of buildup of debt which is always a
precursor to crisis and quite a few
years since the last financial crisis so
if you just think back over crises right
so before 2008 we had the dot-com bubble
in 2000 2001 before that Asian financial
crisis or 1998 before that the global
recession early 1990s and then before
that the global recession in the early
1980s and then of course a number of
other crises in the middle the peso
crisis in the mid 90s I'm not even going
to go back to the 1970s because that was
a mess and so essentially we could be
looking at another debt field crisis and
then I suppose another third reason for
pessimism is whether or not there will
be enough coordination if necessary
globally not just within as your
they say the political system in the US
because of how interlinked markets are
today will there be the same type of g20
response that we saw ten years ago where
there was an absolute willingness to to
coordinate and certainly you know given
the tensions that we see now between
countries whether or not that's going to
be as easy to do I'm going to give you
quick reasons for optimism and then I
think the optimistic reasons are there
always business cycles so it's okay
they're always crisi I mean we've come
through it and over the medium term the
underlying strength in advanced
economies and emerging markets is
actually pretty considerable and it's
fueled by technology so just to give you
quickly a couple of examples so if as
the economy's obviously secular
stagnation this idea that over the
medium term we're all going to grow more
slowly it's because of an ageing society
and advanced economies although the
older I get the less I accept you're
less productive as you get older but
this you know this worried that somehow
we're all going to end up in a slow
growth world and yet you know where the
term secular stagnation comes from so
I've just written a book called the
great economist that looks over 250
years of economic history it was coined
in 1939 by Alvin Hansen who said oh my
god after the Great Crash two recessions
in a decade it's all and we're getting
older that was followed by the Golden
Age of growth the strongest period of
growth we'd ever had and per capita
income growth so I think that's just
worth berry and then we didn't hear
about it again and then in emerging
markets just finally the number of
people entering the middle class is
astounding we're at a point now where
around three billion people so this is a
billion more than ten years ago a
billion more than ten years ago are
actually in the middle
class out of seven billion people in the
world and it is coming from newly
emerging economies joining the middle
class becoming middle-income countries
by 2030 more than half the world will be
middle class we've never had this many
people not just emerge from poverty but
actually enjoy a standard of living that
we all hope for the rest of the world so
if we could get through the short-term
the medium-term I think actually looks
quite promising thank you so we have a
new definition of optimism there are
always crisis professor well I was
getting depressed here increasingly as I
was listening to my colleagues and I was
thinking my but then finally there was a
bit of an upturn no I think you probably
know that the economics what's called a
dismal science you know because the
economists always tend to say you see
the problems and see the the dangers and
so forth
and we did you know of course the good
stuff is always under under lying but
but has to point out the dangers because
if you don't point out the dangers and
there won't be action to deal with the
dangers so it's good economists have
this mission we need to alert everybody
to where the lurking dangers are and
then we can we can try to deal with them
now you know one of the economists that
Linda wrote about of course is Keynes
and if you think about what the
alternatives are monetary policy can't
do much anymore because you're down to
very low interest rates but then there's
always fiscal policy in Kingsville it's
simply smiled and said well but we have
another leg to stand on
wouldn't he so you know I think if
governments really if there is really a
problem there always is fiscal policy
now you know mr. Paws works a strange
sort of way so you you have Trump saying
we need to spend more now you know I'm
not particularly a partisan of mr. Trump
oh I should say to you just in terms of
full disclosure I'm a citizen to Peru
not of the United States and although I
now teach at the University I was a main
bank regulator in Peru so you know I
come this at this from from the
viewpoint of a small latin-american
country on the west coast of South
America that you know how
no waitin in world affairs particularly
but we do try to make noise once in a
while and we do have Cusco not your
picture some of you are probably
familiar with those were those locations
they're very interesting yeah yeah I do
have a rather positive view of what's
gonna happen in this developing world
and Linda just told us that there's
gonna be a lot of people coming into the
middle class now a lot of that is China
of course I'm trying out so big that
China overwhelms all the statistics in
in South America its Brazil overwhelming
all the statistics when you when you do
the aggregate data it's always Brazil if
you take out Brazil then everything
looks different if you take out China
everything looks different also and then
take out India on top of that and then
things look even more different okay
but what are they you know what are sort
of the underlying some of these things
that are happening and that happened
happening all along and there have been
accelerating since 2008-2009 one is
Financial Inclusion starting about 2010
alone a convictions been to grow that if
you don't deal with Financial Inclusion
you don't bring people into the
financial system then we're not gonna
make progress and then there is even an
RN in an organization called the
Alliance for Financial Inclusion
now that didn't exist ten years ago I
guess it just celebrated tenth
anniversary so just about when it
started and this collects most of the
regulator's around the world not the
OECD regulators it's all the non OECD
people they've gotten together 8090 of
them or it used to be of us because that
was one of them and you know the concern
is to get the poor into the financial
system now you basically do that by
making it easier to get in now if you
want to open a bank account and all you
want to do is move a few hundred dollars
a month you don't need you only more
than a phone number basically you don't
even need an address and you don't need
a formal ID so it's all it's very easy
but if you didn't want to make it bigger
then you have to show ki k YC right know
your customer so then there are
requirements but the first entry point
is easy didn't used to be that way so
the norm has changed in financial
inclusion most countries have a National
Financial Inclusion strategy now that is
also an innovation and that makes a big
difference now then the next thing that
happened is cell phone banking we're
have my cell phone I used to have a very
simple Nokia cell phone that didn't do
much you oh you could just talk on it
but with that kind of cell phone you can
actually do remittances now in China
because that's no problem
in Sweden there's no problem either in
browser and in the rest of the world
it's moved a little more slowly but it's
so true that a mother is sitting
somewhere in Kenya wants to send her son
who's in Nairobi you know ten shillings
can do that on the telephone so this
used to not be so cell phone banking is
the greatest innovation since the
creation of paper money it's been 200
years nothing else has been as this kind
of impact and it's gonna sweep the world
it's not there quite yet because there's
p2p person-to-person functions but
person's anything else doesn't function
quite yet except again China and and and
Sweden but it'll be there you know five
years from now it's gonna look very very
different yeah you know with fin tank
and every herbalist innovating so this
is a lot is happening there and I think
that's gonna change the world and if of
course how do they in the developing
world the I did the this morning I
looked up about 12% of the population
where populations in developed countries
88% in less developed countries that's
where the big action is going to be and
if you start taking average of weight
growth rates if you don't if you weight
them by population you're gonna find
that the growth it's gonna be higher if
you waited by income that's a different
story
so it tells you something about
statistics we can all live with
statistics right we know how to do that
now the second thing that I think is
very important is that there's an
enormous change in the attitude between
companies it through extractive
industries such as mining fishing
logging and how they deal with their
neighbors used to be that people would
go in somewhat abusively to get the ore
out and if the neighbors complained
tough luck
and if the name is completeness Morton
and we shot them you shoot them you
bring in the police and if they object
then you know you beat them up and if
that doesn't work you shoot him well
that's no longer so there is something
called the Equator Principles - it's all
major banks have subscribed and the
banks basically would they'd say when
they talk to the customers see look
you're in a place where there's gonna be
conflict you're going to open a new mine
the neighbors are probably going to
object because they're going to believe
rightly or wrongly that you're gonna use
the water and you're gonna pollute but
you have to deal with that
that's risk from our point of view for
the bank's wannabe that's risk we don't
want conflict conflict creates losses
and therefore you better you better see
where you're putting your feet now
that's an enormous change you know they
started in two thousand four or five
more or less the IFC let some of this
city back then followed now there's no
bigger bank that doesn't subscribe to
the Equator Principles with a notable
exception Chinese banks they haven't
quite yet signed up that will happen can
you give me another minute and a half
two minutes 45 ah minute and 45 45
seconds very good okay
next I can come back there if you like
the next thing is disasters financial
systems don't worry and regulators don't
worry about disasters storms earthquakes
typhoons that's not the financial
regulators problem but it is when you
have a disaster the mortgages the houses
the roofs get blown off the mortgages
are worth repenting anymore so you know
but this is beginning to percolate
through the notion that this matters
climate changes the next one you're
probably aware of governor Carney the
Bank of England who said this is a
stomach problem and the central banks
are better worried about finance about
the climate change well that's a sea
change when central bank's take on a
problem it's going to be dealt with
maybe not perfectly but central bank's
the mobilisation of central bank's on
climate change is a massive difference
in the nature of economic policy and how
it's gonna be implemented and that's
sweeping the world it's back opening its
Bank of France its Bank of the
Netherlands there's now I believe 30 or
35 banks central banks are involved not
yet the central bank of Slovakia but
it'll get there and so once you have
central banks involved that means the
problem is going to be dealt with to
some extent now central banks can't do
everything but they're very very
powerful and the banking system the
financial system who is going to be
different five years from now because of
this initiative it won't be recognizable
anymore it'll have a different set of
mandates so these are the positive
long-term things we do have to get
through the winter but you know the
spring does come it's pointed out you
know whatever it comes down it's gonna
have to go up that's it in the nature of
elevators right
it bounces back and so I'm on the
optimistic side even though I practice
at dismal science but you don't have to
be consistent on these matters professor
thank you very much for turning the mood
in the room I would have a question
azita as a practitioner from Wall Street
professor didn't call it like that but
he spoke more more or less about lessons
learned after 10 years after let's let's
put it like what's the is there any
particular thing you see in Wall Street
that has changed as a lesson a lesson
learned or two three lessons learned
which which are changing the Wall Street
way of functioning thinking about what
what is happening they're saying that
someone once made an analogy between the
culture of Wall Street and the culture
of competitive cycling I don't know a
few recyclers you know what Lance
Armstrong ended up doing and so the
point is that the cultures are very
similar they attract very competitive
people who like to win sometimes at any
cost and there's not a lot of regulation
so that sometimes ends up not in a good
place and so the point is that the
lesson is that we need to regulate the
behavior I want to just say that we have
to at the start we have to make a
distinction between financial crises and
market shocks not all market shocks lead
to financial crises that impact the real
economy and real lives example Black
Monday 1987 I was there the market the
Dow dropped 22% next day it was up there
was injection of liquidity by the Fed
and so forth and that didn't impact the
real economy it was just a market shock
same thing in 1989
the US financial system today is built
on lessons that were gained from the
financial crises of the Great Depression
1929-30 and 2008 the Great Recession
arguably the largest financial crisis
we've had since the Great Depression out
of that came FDIC the SEC Social
Security out of the 2008 crises we had
the dodd-frank consumer protection laws
the problem is the lessons are there but
a sometimes they are not the right
lessons and they're just technical
lessons so of course we need to change
leverage ratios or have stress tests or
have rules for regulators and
impartiality and so forth but then the
reality of those lessons those lessons
don't survive contact with reality of
politics basically so almost as soon as
dodd-frank was passed the next the GOP
was arguing for its repeal or parts of
it to be repealed there was there's
always attention at least in our system
about the role of government and so the
lessons learned on the one hand are
technical we put in rules to protect
against another financial crises similar
to what has just happened we had
glass-steagall or Volcker rule and these
are technical rules and they're lessons
to be implemented one lesson that we
learned is that it's extremely important
for the integrity and the trust in the
financial markets to to be for them to
be perceived as impartial the
impartiality of regulators the
impartiality of the Fed of the SEC this
that needs to be maintained for the
trust in the financial markets we need
to keep politics out of the financial
markets that's a lesson
fortunately that was their possible with
Donald Trump tweeting well you just took
the words out of my mouth I think that's
the challenge that's being stressed
tested but that is a real danger the
uncertainty that that politicize
politicization creates is a real danger
to the financial markets because
investors don't like uncertainty under
most circumstances but unless they're
trading volatility but they certainly
don't like it when it comes to not
knowing whether politics is going to
affect a financial decision when I was
there and one of the crises that
happened and my money supply that
whatever the the Fed was doing that was
always separate from whatever the
government government was doing so that
that helps create some trust and and I
think at the end of the day I agree with
Danny that those reasons are reasons for
optimism but all of this goes back to
value system because market systems I
think ultimately our value systems and I
say that partly based on my experience
also as in diplomacy and in politics
connecting that to my experience on Wall
Street in that when we create market
systems that respond to certain
incentives we are validating or we are
responding to the values that we have so
in the United States and a culture that
values individualism and and profit and
rewards risk perhaps disproportionately
to having a safety net that protects a
basic level of safety we have a certain
outcome in Sweden where I was you have
more of a safety net but you also have
the upside for capitalism in each system
there's give and take but it reflects
our values and our social values and I
think that may be where we need to look
more for signs of optimism what is the
value system that's going to inform our
market system in our economic system
that ultimately leverages and harnesses
in in its most complete form the human
capital in a society
so that we have resilience in the labour
market when we have a financial crisis
this value question leads me to the like
analogy we had a fail Wall Street which
ended up of Eko being being jailed for
breaching the law we had a wall street
to film well it was more about a clash
of two generations views on how to make
money in this big Wall Street world we
have a wall street 3 film where for
example newvalue climate change or the
climate the protection of the climate
will be kind of a new value which will
play a role in the decision-making
either on Wall Street or in economic
theories is this new thing which is
coming shaping you know in Europe now we
live with the with the Swedish Swedish
girl protesting against the climate
change and it's it's a I would say kind
of hype a little bit but it's bringing
attention to the to the topic is this
being included already as one of the
lessons learned maybe or completely you
think Linda I think the values debate is
absolutely what we need to have and it's
not the first time in history the issues
are always particular to the context of
today and today we do need to talk a lot
more about climate change but again if
you look back over history when you have
time to break down in consensus around
the best economic system it's always
because there are issues but the
economic system isn't adequately
addressing and it hasn't kept up with
the the values that people hold so let
me give you a more concrete example so
the there's been numerous breakdowns in
consensus around the best economic
system and the issues which ought to be
addressed I'm going to point out one
which i think is quite important which
was I'm gonna take you all the way back
to I'm 1846 so that was when the corn
laws were repealed in Britain okay
nobody remember says unless you're
historian but it was actually momentous
because yeah so at the time essentially
the consensus was for mercantilism so
this is the idea that country should run
trade surpluses and this is I'm stemming
even better if you could find some gold
and silver and bring it back to your
country that's it that's great so it
actually took great economist cough the
classical economists like David Ricardo
to argue that actually no that isn't
that is not the way to engage and this
is remember 1846 this is the nineteenth
century when the world is becoming
connected and so and the the consensus
was overturned because it seemed it was
better to to trade and to be open to
exchange and specialize and oh by the
way the prime minister who repealed the
Corn Laws a Robert Peel he lost his
Premiership shortly thereafter and then
his political party was cast out into
the wilderness for generation but the
outcome was a much more interconnected
world and prosperity accompanying the
industrializing British economy German
economy American economy but that
consensus quickly broke down in 1873 so
the long depression of the 19th century
is happened after the panic of 1873 a US
financial crisis spread across the
Atlantic and made people extremely
disillusioned about the financial system
about capitalism and about globalization
that led to unemployment becoming a word
for the first time it led to the rise of
trade unionism and the rise of Marxism
so by the early 20th century 60% of the
world lived in either communist or
socialist regimes so this eventually led
to the market-based economies arguing
their position and the creation of the
welfare state so by the 20th century by
really the middle of the 20th century
the so took a long time welfare state
capitalism was created the welfare state
here in Europe and the NHS in Britain
another example and of course the early
part of the 20th century saw the
establishment of social security in the
United States so essentially it seemed
as if capitalism was picking up the need
to have a social safety net and more
inclusiveness to address some of this
backlash and this battle wasn't won
until probably the end of the Cold War
at the end of the 1980s even China the
biggest communist country in the world
injected market-based incentives into
its economy and in fact there's a great
quote by JK Galbraith this great
economist I write about he said at that
point you might think China's communist
but he said politically but economically
he said the difference between
capitalism and communism is that under
capitalism man exploits man under
communism it's the exact opposite and so
the and so by so it seemed like we had a
new consensus by the 1990s but now
thirty year on after the biggest
financial crash since the 1930s the
consensus is broken down we're now again
questioning whether the economic system
is dealing with the issues that we'd
care about things like climate change
high levels of inequality the elites
doing better than any but then everybody
else a re-examination of not just
socialism but I've heard people admire
Marxism once again so we are now at a
point where consensus is broken down we
need to talk about values we need to
talk about how you can take a to take
this opportunity like the great thinkers
of the posited and craft a new system
that's much more suited for the 21st
century and the issues that we're facing
today
I just want to remind you you are in the
country surrounded by the countries
which has we had have had quite a
extensive experience with applied
Marxism and what we hear this Marxism
being again in kind of fashion as we
hear it from the Western Europe and from
the West and I recently met a group of
American New Yorkers not Americans New
Yorkers specific and and they and I was
you know amazed how they were talking
and and it was the reaction of the
trumpian calling from fascist I told
them well we have a fascism experience
here as well so be careful about about
this labeling and these were the real
Marxist you know but we have a practical
experience so that's that's I think that
one of the experiences this region could
add to this debate about the values that
it's quite careful but I just want to
add one other thing one important lesson
from the 2008 crisis which is that what
is different today from this really
fascinating history that you just
described is that markets financial
crises are now global if one country
sneezes the whole world catches the cold
right so you could be sitting here
minding your own business and doing
everything right and we in the u.s. do
something and suddenly your economy is
in a tailspin because you're affected by
what's happening globally and that makes
it even more it's more of an imperative
than for each country to be able to have
some preventive measures in a sense to
protect themselves or to inoculate
themselves from something like that
affecting them affecting their economy
and that's why creating a resilient
labor market and workforce is really
important I just want to share this
statistic that I just read that I just
blew my mind there's a rand study that
showed that one in four American
Americans cannot cover an expected
expenditure of $400 $400 without
borrowing or selling something
one out of four the second one that was
even more astonishing is that 78% of
American workers live paycheck to
paycheck I thought that would be like 40
percents almost 80% of Americans live
paycheck to paycheck doesn't mean they
live in poverty but they're used to
certain spending habits
financial crises don't always come from
market shocks we just had a big one in
the US when we had a 35 days shutdown of
the government where people those that's
78 percent had a financial crises but we
don't think of it that way so and then
financial crises are not systemic either
so every American that lives paycheck to
paycheck is one L nasaan one job loss
away from their own financial crisis and
that is not a sustainable way for any
economy to thrive when we're very very
vulnerable in that sense we have a
couple of questions already on slide oh
I would maybe merge two of them one is
about cryptocurrencies what do you think
about them and how they can help to
prevent further possible further for the
crisis plus there is a there's a
question about the new technologies we
see the new technologies everywhere
except for productivity statistics any
recommendation how to increase the
productivity growth what is the role of
the new technologies cryptocurrencies
included in in this because these were
not like part of the crisis last last
time is are they helping or making
situation more complex or harder I'll
just say that I was in structured
derivatives and I don't understand
cryptocurrencies I can explain it to you
but I don't understand how they work so
I'll let you do it
if I may I just like to add a comment to
the previous topic you know what's
different now than a hundred years ago
and what why is why is it changed what's
what's moving is you know if you think
of the 1800s
you know 1850 or something like that
what happened in one place
who didn't impact much what happened
somewhere else you'd been in London and
Birmingham didn't matter much you went
on and certainly what happened the
United States was of no concern or
impact as somebody they was living in
England nor nor Germany what happened in
China mannered to nobody so but now
that's different in that there has a
there's a name for that in economics
it's called externalities whence what
person a does affects what person D does
but indirectly
used to be there is something James
dusenbery wrote about keeping up with
the Joneses you're happy in accordance
to what your neighbors do right and if
your neighbor has got richer you feel
poorer
now that's denied by economic theory
that that's not included and when I went
to graduate school externalities was
something that you read one article
about and then you just concluded that
it was irrelevant today the big
externalities climate climate affects
everybody and if we don't intervene
individual doesn't take into account
what they do on climate and how climate
impacts on them then we're all worse off
so this isn't sea change and that
affects interdependence everybody is now
interdependent with everybody else
externality is actually what we call is
to in turn to interconnector to fail
exactly exactly you big to fail to
interconnect exactly exactly but the
problem is that we can't each of us
individually can't do very much about it
now there's some folks again you know
the united countries can do more about a
little little countries that the big
companies could do more about in the
little companies the central banks can
do a lot about it the the stock market
regulators can do a lot about it so
there are institutions that can have a
global impact others cannot individual
simply cannot but insofar as individuals
force their governments to do something
then the government's can so but this is
a tremendous change and we need to
understand it realize this
interdependence once we have then that
things follow what kind of capitalism
and we need to have follows where
economic system we need to have follows
and even the Chinese government it's
kind of wound up recognize it already
has in something climate change that's
recognized clearly that what they what
they do in Beijing affects everybody
else so this is I think the great you
know that the next version of the book
that you that you write you're gonna
probably have to have you know something
about who thought about externalities
and you know P goo what did he did see
in 1900 or not generated five you know
there are this people did think about
this but it wasn't important now it's
important and I think that is something
that once we recognize it
we're totally able to deal with it but
first they don't know it all starts up
here
we don't understand what's going on we
can't cope with him just on the
cryptocurrencies and financial
technologies I think cryptocurrencies
are just the latest form of private
money privately issued money so in one
sense the this has been talked about for
a century by economists like Milton
Friedman who said why not you know if
you had a currency which is recognized
by somebody else you can always use it
as a medium of exchange that's all money
really is so I think but in terms of
policy it complicates the policy-making
process because it's already the case
that central bank's find it difficult to
essentially both measure and control
money so interest rates are the price of
money and we already know where we are
with their quantitative easing is a form
of controlling the supply of money so
you either control the price of the
quantity what you try to do both and the
quantity of money is going to be made
more complicated by cryptocurrencies and
the other thing central banks have to do
is they have to anticipate the movement
of the money supply so again we knew we
learn 10 years ago there's a disconnect
between the measures of inflation and
the measures of the quiddity so by
targeting inflation you miss still
build-up and credit which fed the
housing bubble
so clearly cryptocurrencies as another
measure and another level of liquidity
which is already very difficult for
central banks to try and tackle which is
why currently macro prudential measures
which are new ministry of tools employed
by a number of major central banks now
is geared at trying to control or at
least try and measure that leverage
credit liquidity growth so i think those
are some of the things probably too to
think about but i think you know
generally and danny mentioned this
financial innovation so around
productivity so one of the big puzzles
of our time is productivity growth is
slowing across
the world and this is so this is called
the solo paradox Robert Solow the great
economist said you can see the computer
age everywhere except in the
productivity data and in fact there's a
Bank of England study that shows that as
penetration of this goes up productivity
actually goes this way
so can the digital inventions of today
raise productivity in the way that
electrification or the internal
combustion engine did that is the big
question of our time and I suppose one
thing to think about in terms of FinTech
which is just innovation the financial
sector most of that is around making
payments easier so it addresses
financial addresses under banking and
increases Financial Inclusion so I wrote
a piece for the World Economic Forum
which essentially argues FinTech could
be the technology that could give us
that economy wide productivity boost
because it does something very different
than perhaps even what uh you know what
time some of the digital like social
media tech does FinTech translates
savings into investment and that is one
of the most important drivers of growth
investment becomes funds for industry it
becomes funds for investment and so can
we see productivity across the economy
be increased
I think vintage gives us a good chance
of it but ultimately this is as I say
you know the puzzle we are surrounded by
tech and yet somehow we are finding
productivity is actually slowing
everywhere including
economies like China I just went to
speaking of technologies if you are shy
to you slide oh you can also raise your
hand to have it to have a question but
Professor had some some remark oh I just
just a note of caution about in
interpreting productivity data because
you know computers are wonderful and but
it's something called garbage in garbage
out so
you know it's only the data that comes
out of computers only as good as what
you put in productivity is must have one
of the most difficult things to measure
so economists have measures they
extremely imperfect you know you have a
lot of employment and the people sit
around doing nothing so you know how do
you measure that with the wages paid
with how many hours they worked you know
when you have different mixes of labor
and capital and different kinds of
capital the issues of aggregation
extremely difficult and you know Luna
knows all about this and you know it's
it's something economists wrestle with
we don't have a good answer
so when you see productivity edit data
take them with three spoonfuls of salt
they're not very good figures they're
not very good figures don't believe them
very much it may turn out that
productivity as measure is going down
but purgative a Tyrian reality is going
up totally possible totally possible so
when I see particulate and I said to
myself hmm interesting okay now let's go
on to the next topic I don't believe
what I see on paper much less what I
hear on the radio yes
my name is Bobo lo I'm an independent
analyst ambassador you mentioned that
we're more vulnerable to the next
financial crisis than we were ten years
ago
Linda you speak about the period you
know economic crises are periodical
we're going to have a have them anyway
it's so my real question is what does
the next global financial crisis look
like how bad will it get I'll tell you
where it starts ambassador will tell you
how bad it gets okay it's in start in
the clearinghouses the the concentration
of clearinghouse data is extremely very
extremely large so clearing houses and
they're very very thinly capitalized if
somebody large defaults and obviously
goes through a clearing house clearing
house may fall and then you have a major
crisis
now you know there's been the Economist
wrote about this recently you know so
you're not saying something that is
confidential any sense
there's a real danger there now
ambassador will tell us what the what
the outfit might be thanks for giving me
time to think I think the next one will
be triggered by student loan bubble of
student loan debt in the United States I
have worked through a couple of
financial crises there was program
obviously program trading was blamed for
the 87 one there was the SNL crisis then
the 2008 was blamed on counterparty risk
and derivatives of which I was a part of
creating those structured derivatives I
have they have a good use but then again
they have to be regulated I think the
next and then emerging markets was
another one so and I remember after one
of those crises we were sitting around
with my colleagues in the trading floor
and and he was saying well you know
they're so pass and there'll be another
one and it's exactly what happens
because we the lesson to learn is that
we don't learn lessons so what do we do
to protect ourselves from ourselves we
have to have structures and and
frameworks I think the student loan debt
is a serious bubble and I hope that we
can have policy solutions to to lessen
the burden I mean how do we feel it in
the general population should I take
that in terms of yeah so it's true that
not every financial crisis has a
significant real economy impact so
market crashes like the ones that have
been mentioned and in some respects
that's the best kind of outcome you can
hope for in other words there's enough
regulatory safeguards that a crisis is
essentially contained
and doesn't become widespread across the
economy and that it's not systemic
because the systemic crises are the
existential ones and what we see is
generally speaking financial crises are
triggered by debt and exuberance so if
you look at any measure of asset bubbles
in different countries those are
essentially normally they're telltale
signs so macro Prudential Regulation is
intended to try and curb the growth of
bubbles and this is the lesson of in
2008 when Alan Greenspan said I don't
want to be the person who takes away the
punchbowl when the party gets started
now they do lean against the wind the
question is it's hard to spot whether
something is a bubble or whether
something is just underlying strength in
say technology that boosts the Nasdaq or
limited supply that boosts the housing
market or high demand for higher
education that boosts debt it's really
difficult to differentiate but what we
do know is that you don't have a crash
without a bubble so you have to look for
what you can do now my feeling I started
my career as a corporate lawyer and I
don't ever believe that or all
regulations are tailored for the last
crisis and you can understand why how
could you know what you all you can do
is hope you've put in enough what I call
safeguards against a crisis becoming
systemic because what happens with a lot
of these crises think about to the early
1990s there was a coordinated housing
market crash across Europe it was
devastating for people who went into
negative equity is scarred a generation
of graduates if you graduate and during
a period of high unemployment your
lifetime earnings are lower you're
scarred so the impact is extensive much
worse than what you normally think of
and
oh the government's up allotted debt
yeah that's bad but to be honest is much
worse for people who've graduated at you
know at such a time so to me it's
whether or not there's enough awareness
that is a systemic nature of any asset
market there needs to be some type of
break to make sure that it's contained
just on that point both the ambassador
and your point in terms of graduating
you can imagine graduating with this
little huge amount of debt just from an
undergraduate education in the United
States so this is a u.s. problem it's
something the ambassador's talked about
as far as debt but in terms of Society
in the United States productivity
efficiency not having a skewed to
workforce of young people who come in
and they can't take certain jobs like in
public health or in the government
because they have a student debt they've
got to service and they go off and they
do other jobs that's that are good jobs
well-paying jobs but they might be more
effective in terms of society if they
went into Social Work or something like
that so for the United States what you
were just mentioning whether it's the
housing issue here in Europe or just
what happens in the United States with
debt on these young people who come out
of colleges they're ready to go and
they're hobbled it's it's terrible and
then you have the debt problem on top of
that as the Ambassador was saying just
as a statement but as a question for you
Linda
you mentioned the Bank of England report
and the productivity and you held up
your iPhone and said you know you would
think things were more efficient because
of this but actually the productivity is
going down and as this proliferate and
it's it's not just iPhones just the
computer world if you will that's not
intuitive vyas for a lot of us who are
assuming that the efficiencies are going
up I mean I when you said that I thought
about myself and I said yeah I guess I
spend more time on my iPhone that I
should therefore I'm not as productive
so I could see that but what did the
Bank of England reports say that product
productivity going down so those are the
reasons what else did they say yeah it's
a great question so um essentially if
you look at the
so again the other observation from
Robert Solow so he said the biggest
difference between giving his secretary
a computer is that before she had one
she worked for him and afterwards he
worked for her there's a there so but I
actually I actually subscribe so there's
a big debate between the economy so the
Economist Robert Gordon has written a
book called the rise and fall of the
United States there's a reason that the
title ends with fall so the techno
pessimists believe that the trends that
we currently see are the trends that are
going to be with us and that underlies
the slowdown and productivity growth
since the mid-1980s so this has been
going for a long time there's another
version of this which are people who
believe that and this is in terms of
evidence there was one period in the
late 1990s in the United States when
productivity went up during the height
of really when the technologies were
beginning to permeate through from the
computer age maturing that was the only
period when productivity growth was
rising and it's because technologies
were embedded in the way we work
so most technologies are technologies oh
wow look at this is cool innovation but
does it really change your workplace
does it really get used in a productive
way so that's the kind of device I'll
give you another example I was in Japan
recently and they have they have really
advanced AI and robotics so I met a
robot called pepper
have you ever seen pepper peppers a
humanoid robot pepper function is as a
companion to the old people in Japan so
peppers only function is to read your
emotion so I said on a panel like this
one one day I don't really peppers
incredibly impressive but I don't see
how pepper really raises productivity
here's other functions you know I don't
see how he raises productivity across
the economy and my fellow panelists now
Danny said I don't know how pepper can
raise productivity but if I had a pepper
robot in my house that read emotions it
would help my marriage
I'm so but I use that as an example
because maybe we don't quite know how to
use pepper yet you know that tech is
sophisticated so yes finally I also and
I write about this in my book I actually
think the reason why productivity growth
is slowing in advanced economies which
by the way are the cutting edge of
technology more than emerging markets
which can to follow us in terms of
trends the vast economies are on average
70% services output is designed to
measure manufacturing services and yeah
so this is the first chapter in my book
which is all about measuring the
intangible you Cana me actually two
chapters on it so the first chapter is
on how do you measure services second
chapter is should we worry about trade
deficits if you're also unable to
measure services trade so that's called
the invisible balance so basically these
are first two chapters of my latest book
and I essentially to give you the very
short version services output is very
difficult to measure services exports
almost impossible so it's like it's like
95% of the universe is comprised of dark
energy we have no idea what it is but we
know it's there and so to me
maybe we just miss measure services and
we're not as unproductive as we think so
for one final example just to give you a
sense of what I mean how many of you
have been in meetings which have been a
total waste of time how many of you have
been to meetings where you had a
breakthrough
decision may move forward this is you
know this is gonna propel you to go and
do great things in the world oh my god
okay so my point is a great meeting and
a useless meeting in services output
terms are the same because all you're
measuring is revenue wages so and the
what you sell so this is not at all well
measured it could be it could be if we
embed technologies better
and we appreciate that services
economies are differently measured we
may not face such a dire future well my
role is now to play the bad guy because
our time is
and but I guess we had a good meeting in
the post positive positive sense a sense
of the world even the topic wasn't the
most optimistic but at least we had some
we had some fun so thank you as Italian
da and professor Scheele escape for for
being here thank the audience for their
further questions and for being being
with us enjoy the rest of the group sex
today
[Applause]