brilliant okay now we have our waters
open thank you ladies and gentlemen for
joining us I know there's an awful lot
of competing panels at them in it so
really do appreciate you joining us for
a discussion about AI and humanity and I
guess how we can keep humanity as a I
slowly encroaches on us
my name is crystal Walker I'm a
technology journalist for a number of
publications in the UK including Wired
The Economist BBC Bloomberg and I'm
joined by some really really interesting
contributors to our panel so immediately
to my left I have Tracy Chu who is the
founder and CEO of Bloc Party which is a
london-based start-up working on kind of
rethinking social platforms so Tracy was
an engineer at kora and Pinterest she's
believed consulted with the US
government as well trying to keep them
honest which is always very very nice in
the middle we have Bridget Bridget
hyacinth who is the founder and director
of the MBA Caribbean organization so
that basically is trying to give leaders
around the world a bit of a conscience
and some provoking some critical
thinking I think she's also the author
of a number of books on leadership so
very very interesting contributor to our
debate on the human side and then on
your right we have Oren Etzioni who is
the CEO of the Allen Institute for
artificial intelligence in Seattle that
was set up by Paul Allen who is the
co-founder of Microsoft in 2014 and it's
basically developing AI for public good
so we are already biased I think
probably in that we want AI to be
developed sustainably and well but
perhaps the best place to start and I
mean Tracy what is it that separates AI
from humanity do you think in this sort
of thing when you're developing
intelligent platforms and using AI what
is it that's different from just humans
involved in that
that's a big question to start with one
thing to clarify up front might be what
we actually mean by the term artificial
intelligence or AI and in some contexts
it is actually people are talking about
AI it is a very intelligent super super
intelligent form of technology and in
many cases the way it's used now in the
industry is actually not so
sophisticated and so a lot of the AI
that we're talking about in technology
companies is if you actually look at it
really basic mathematical models that
take inputs like clicks and view time
and then tries to get people to click
more and view more on these platforms
and so some of these AI models that are
being used right now are not very
intelligent they're just trading off of
existing data that is not very smart and
what then happens is when we try to
deploy this at scale it is much faster
than having humans look at say cranking
what people should look at when they're
logging into Facebook or Twitter or what
moderation decisions should be so the AI
is faster but it's not actually more
intelligent and so what then ends up
happening is that we have dumber
decisions being made much more quickly
at a global scale and the Orang I mean I
know that you will see you're helping
try and develop AI for the public good
but is that fear amongst tech companies
is that they just want to throw AI at
any problem without thinking about the
long-term impact of it well first of all
I really like Tracy's characterization
because people do and it comes I think
largely from Hollywood people do get an
overinflated notion of what AI is it's
very much the next generation of
computer technology I like to say you
have to separate science from science
fiction and reality from Hollywood and
hype right we've all seen movies like
her and Terminator and so on great
movies
if you like that sort of thing but it's
not really what's happening now Christy
your question I don't think we can paint
everything with the same brush so
certainly the companies like Facebook
and Google are using this algorithm to
target advertising to collect a large
amount of data they're doing that very
effectively a number of authorities like
the Chinese but also various forces
inside the United States use AI for
facial recognition and we're finding
more and more that while Tracy is right
that the algorithms are not particularly
smart in any sense when you have massive
amounts of labeled data millions of
examples and you have a lot of
computational power increasingly you can
be accurate at least some of the time
and that leads to achievements at least
in these narrow arenas so then we get to
the question ok what do we do with this
and I think all of us think that's a
fascinating question I've probably
talked for too long all right I don't
want to turn this into a soliloquy let
me just say that my answer to that it's
not going to be one thing different
players are going to be doing very very
different things with AI and and
Bridgette I mean you spend your life
trying to make company founders think
sort of critically and intelligently and
nicely almost I mean are you waking up
in cold sweats at the idea of the AI
dawn coming upon us here I would say no
um the reality is here just like you
know electricity and I know as Orrin was
seeing that you know sometimes people
focus on just in negatives but there are
a lot of positives you know in in the
development of artificial intelligence
so you know we can focus on that I what
I really try to work with leaders is to
bring back that human touch that
elements I was raised by my mother
single parents and six children and
because of people giving back you know
in the community I'm able to be where I
am today so this is my stress
not even in this you know technological
age we still have to remain that have to
keep that human touch that that caring
aspect that ability to give back how do
you leave a like legacy it's true
inspiring it's true helping others is
true giving back so we still have to
balance yes
you know the profits and the balance
sheet but also to make a lasting impact
and when you look um also when you look
at how take for example right if you
look at sometimes on social media when
someone does a kind act it was
immediately viral when someone crosses
an LED street it goes viral why because
it's not in norm so things like kindness
and empathy and compassion and
generosity it is not in normal it should
be and this is what is gonna
differentiate us from AI that's really
interesting I should also say we do have
slider working for our panel so if you
want to ask us any questions I have a
the joys of Technology it's not AI but I
have a little iPad that will feed in
some of those questions and that's
that's really fascinating Bridgette so I
mean Tracy you you work with these
companies and try and advocate for them
I mean do you find it difficult to
convince some of what Bridget says in
terms of like making sure that they do
keep humanity at the core that they are
over reliant on this sort of stuff
I think these companies use big tech
companies they do have good people who
work at them and want to do good and
they are human and understand humanity
in that that sense I think one of the
risks right now is that a lot of the
people who work at these companies
belong to pretty homogenous cohorts and
despite trying to do good often have
pretty big blind spots and that can be
because many people are not trained in
humanities thinking or thinking beyond
the media technology they're working on
and some of it is a lack of demographic
diversity so really understanding what
is meaningful to their demographics but
not understanding what the implications
might be for others and so these
blind-spot
can end up being painful when there are
examples of things like Facebook sending
reminders of here
your most liked photograph in the last
year and it might be of a child that
passed away and that's very painful it
was meant to be here our happy memories
in the last year but sometimes they just
miss out on what the use case might end
up being and in other cases it can be
very insidious when there are impacts
that spiral out of control so you can
see like the spread of misinformation or
the weaponization of social media to
spread misinformation disinformation so
despite good intentions I think we still
have a lot of blind spots that need to
be addressed and I think sometimes
people who think that they're doing good
but don't understand
what they're missing can get very
defensive and feel like well technology
is always progress and we're not going
to stand against progress and that leads
to sometimes destructive effects on
community like if you look at uber or
the these like car services that now
employ millions of drivers but are also
working very hard to get to self-driving
cars so that they can actually be
profitable when they are able to make
that transition there will be many
drivers will be out of jobs and they're
not thinking about what that impact is
going to be because they're very
narrowly focused on let's try to achieve
self-driving cars and that's the
interesting thing because these even any
2ai development still requires human
input so I mean or on how do we how does
the human interface with the AI at the
minute and how does that relationship
work is today sort of back and forth or
is it that human and humanity is
essentially populating and creating this
AI so a great question and a complex
topic let me just highlight a couple of
points the first one is I like to think
of AI as augmented intelligence because
when we have the positive outcomes it's
when we have the tool being used by
people in a good way so one example of
course is just the Google search engine
which most of us use and it has
a number of AI systems in it if you're
using the Google Translation tool so
again you're using it the same way that
you use a calculator and when we have
for example what's called autonomous
vehicles and those will arrive gradually
over time we have the potential to write
another rung of Technology which is in
the United States over 40,000 people die
each year in car accidents on the
highways over a million people are
injured and the estimates are that as
much as 80 percent of that could be
prevented with with this kind of AI
technology so again we will have that be
good it's still going to be the case of
course that the people tell the cars
were to go right it's not like the cars
take over and you know all the cars say
okay we're going to do brexit we're
going to leave the EU or something like
that so in all these situations I think
when the system works well is is when
it's augmented intelligence of course
there are also plenty of situations some
of the Tracy alluded to and in the
criminal justice system and other ones
where that connection between people and
the AI isn't done right people are over
overly subservient to the technology
they listen it to it too much and then
it works quite quite badly so so I like
to advocate that we think of AI as
Augmented intelligence and we think
about how to use it to to build a better
society and do you think that it can be
used there for Bridgette - AI to build a
better leadership model as well can can
a I be used to help decision-makers be a
bit more human perversely it can help
decision makers definitely but it
depends on if you look at City what is
happening with with the many masses in
terms of information and manipulation of
data and things like that so it depends
upon accountability transparency and
having the right purpose what I do I
want to do what do I want to achieve and
it's things like that I mean we also I
mean you touched a bit Tracy on the
delay
the market aspect we do have a question
from me and on slide Oh which is you do
we need to think more carefully before
sort of running headlong into adopting
AI of the potential impact on employment
and society and things like that do we
need a sort of overarching AI strategy
and if so what would that look like do
you think it gave me another big
question sorry 25 words or less yeah
Tori we sorry we have until 5:15 we can
talk ideally we would have an AI
strategy that considers what the
implications might be but I think very
realistically the technology development
is just running so quickly ahead of
where we can be in terms of even like
discussion but definitely very far ahead
of regulation and policy and I don't
think it's realistic to say we need to
craft our whole strategy before we start
implementing more AI I think the other
thing that makes it impossible is that
we don't actually know what AI will be
capable of even I think let's see seven
or eight years ago the deep learning was
not yet working and I saw a member
actually when I studied AI machine
learning in my master's program we just
skipped over the whole neural net
section because my professor Andrew
eating said oh we tried this a few
decades ago and it didn't work so we're
just skipping over it we're just not
going to cover it and then in 2012 they
actually didn't manage to make neural
Nets work and now that's the the whole
craze around deep learning and it's
really propelled computer vision to new
levels and some of that was because of
the increase of compute power and data
and so things that we thought even 10
years ago are not going to work actually
have completely transformed AI now and
so just because it's so difficult to
predict where we're going to go it also
makes it impossible to design strategy
around it I very much agree yeah it's
there's so many races military and
economic we can't stop I just wanted to
highlight one piece with a metaphor of
an old professor of mine herb Simon who
won the Nobel Prize in Economics and the
Turing Award in computer science I think
one of the most Illustrated
intellectuals of all time and there's a
parable called simon's ant ant not as an
family member but is in the little
critter and if you were to draw the
graph of an ant walking on a beach
you'll see an extremely complex and
convoluted path it's difficult to
predict or or to model yet the ant is a
very very simple creature so how is that
possible and the answer is well the ant
is responding to local stimuli right
going up the little sand dunes and
responding to where the Sun is and so on
now how is this relevant here it's
relevant because as Tracy said earlier
right these algorithms are in some sense
dumb or in some sense you know simple
there they've been around for certainly
since the 50s and 60s in various
variations so how is this possible well
again what's happened in around 2012
with some successes this really
crystallized a combination of tremendous
compute power and tremendous data fed
into these relatively simple algorithms
resulted in in success so so this is
what we're seeing today and at the same
time I just want to reiterate these are
narrow successes right we still don't
have an AI system that's nearly as
capable as my my eight-year-old boy for
example or you know really any child
five or six years old is still a lot
more sophisticated as a generalist
compared to any AI system you're good I
think um that companies should be
rescaling and upskilling whicker's but
you know right now there's not no
massive you know um strategy with this
when change happens you know it's it's
difficult for people nobody likes change
so right now
employers should be preparing employees
for change your job is not permanent
change is coming and when that change
comes you know go about it in a humane
way for example John comes to work after
two eighteen years working a company
and they told him he no longer has a job
security escorts him out the building
what could he have done differently they
have been more humane in the process we
understand we can't understand what
you're going through but we are here to
help we can offer counseling we can help
you but resume writing interviewing do
you need a recommendation what can we do
to help this is happening we cannot
change because job descript disruption
is gonna happen but how do we handle it
to prepare people for it and it doesn't
take much you know to be human human
it's not like a hard thing is these
simple things that we do that County
Moose the kind would the thoughtful
gesture
that impacts people I will mean with
them so how do we keep that in cold hard
computer logic and how do we make sure
we don't lose that that moral grounding
well when I did that I wrote a little
while ago in Wired magazine if you want
to look it up we're specifically related
to the labor markets and these ideas and
I pointed out that the place that
computers and AI systems will get to
last in some sense is is human empathy
very much the sort of thing you were
saying Bridgette and so if we were
willing to invest in a society more
resources in you know delivering food to
the elderly and in a care for you know
autistic children and just care for the
weakest members in society we could
actually employ people people who are
displaced by the rapid change in the
technology in that capacity and it's
actually the the weakest members of
society or at people who say didn't
finish high school didn't finish college
may struggle with you know upscaling
programs people talked about you know
coal miners to data miners right but
that's not realistic how many of our
coal miners are going to become data
miners but perhaps they can be there to
care for four members of society and
this is not a simple thing but if we
could do that I think that would be a
powerful transition and Tracy I think
you worked with the
labor statistics in the US at some
points city I didn't work with them but
I have looked at the data they all like
but more generally in terms of I guess
preparing us for these changes what can
we do to kind of as Orrin says to get
people prepared for a world where AI and
humans really do coexist this is an area
where I don't have any answers I do have
some questions and one big space of
questions is around capitalism and what
we value and so this question around
upskilling workers that are going to be
displaced I'm not sure who has that
responsibility ideally we are all human
and humane and want to take care of each
other but in a capitalist society where
the overarching motive is the profit
motive it doesn't necessarily make sense
for corporations to be upskilling people
just make sense profit wise to switch
over to the robots when they're
available and there are a lot of jobs
that rely more on empathy and humanity
but these are ones that our society
right now does not value very much if
you look at how much caretakers are paid
it's pretty much the bottom so this is
maybe not so much capitalism as it is
potentially misogyny since a lot of
these jobs are coded as more feminine
and jobs that are more feminine are
usually valued less and there's a lot of
research on this over many different
industries like one more men move into a
field and it becomes viewed as more
masculine and lucrative yeah the one we
get pushed out so there's a lot of
things swirling around this I don't
actually have any good answers I do
think we should be looking at these jobs
that will be difficult for machines to
do and figure out how to support people
in those jobs yes I agree with you there
but also governments you know
institutions but also it comes back to
the individual you can't beat and say
well you know it depends upon them this
is your life so I tell individuals take
charge keep abreast of the information
what is going on there are free courses
you can
online that Microsoft on these companies
at least has some basic knowledge and
look at your skills what skills cannot
be cannot be easily automated in this
digital age what the reference kills do
you have what are your strengths what
are your passions what do you like to do
and also network network network network
is about connecting and building
relationships and Tracy touched on a
really interesting point there which is
kind of the implicit biases and how I
reflects human biases I mean orang how
do we iron out basically perpetuating
things like gender bias I mean we saw in
relatively recent months Amazon's
automatic filtering of job applicants
that just completely blanked out women
right so let me start by just explaining
this issue because it is a very serious
issue so these programs that we've been
talking about whether they're deep
learning neural network models or other
ones all have this characteristic that
they take data from the past they
collected and build models in the
present and use these to make
predictions or future decisions now the
problem with this story is if the data
from the past capture biases that we had
in the past whether they're sexist or
racist or what-have-you and we no longer
find those acceptable they're going to
be carried over by the technology into
the future what's worse is the
technology seeks to find patterns in the
data and so they can generalize and
amplify the biases so at the end of this
process the bias is even worse than it
was before the good news about this is
that we do first of all there's very
strong awareness now in the technical
community about this issue and I think
most things do not have technical
solutions but here at least part of this
does so we are increasingly aware of
tools that we can use to to mitigate
that whether by augmenting the data
changing the data or whether by changing
what's called the loss function
basically changing the the algorithm to
at least mitigate that to some extent
at the end of the day though the key is
to have people be aware don't accept you
know caveat emptor if i'm pronouncing
that correctly don't expect what they
don't accept with the machine spits out
at face value right you have to very
carefully audit and try to understand is
this reliable is this high-quality does
this contain biases I mean has this how
does the AI revolution actually oddly
highlighted some of the wider issues in
society do you think Tracy like when
it's in black and white that robots that
are designed to mimic human behavior
perpetuate biases do we then sort of
have more of a stark be honest yeah I do
think it is easier to quantify some of
that now and you can actually test out
an algorithm by putting an image in
front of it and asking it to classify it
so it'll be easier to test but yeah I
would also say there's there's been bias
for a long time people have talked about
it for a long time so it's not as if we
didn't know that these things existed I
do think there's a general shift in
conversation very broadly it's not
necessarily specifically just from AI
highlighting some of these issues now
and in terms of shifts of conversation I
mean I think probably the majority of
this debate has been relatively negative
and bashing AI for a bit I mean how do
we you know because it is potentially
something that is an enormous public
good how do we shift the conversation
about this and make it more about a eyes
powerful abilities to change the world
well Chris I'm glad you asked that
question
since we did have some exchange before
so so our mission is the eye for the
common good and I do see enormous
potential benefits and I think one of
the biggest ways that we can shift the
conversation is to deliver some of those
benefits whether they're as I mentioned
in cars and fewer accidents which will
is already starting to happen with
safety devices and cars that are based
on AI whether it's in the medical
systems where in the United States at
least
the third leading cause of death in
American hospitals is physician error
and again information systems and AI
systems can help reduce that at the
Allen Institute for artificial
intelligence we're building search
engines for free search engines for
scientists and researchers that
hopefully make them more efficient in
doing their science and that will
hopefully help us whether we're trying
to deal with climate change or superbugs
or whatever the intellectual and
technical challenges of the day so I
think as we deliver these high quality
beneficial applications they'll make a
difference I do want to make one point
about bias before in there generally so
far right it has been negative but again
as Tracy pointed out bias is part of the
human condition and one interesting
thing about bias when we see it in
people is they tend to lie about it
right whereas REI systems at least
unless they're designed to lie won't
they're more able to stick to a set of
rules in a set of constraints so the
potential in AI systems if we design
them in the right way is to reduce bias
to note when bias exists in human
behavior for example say black you know
defendants of color are treated
differently than defendants of the white
race and so on so I think the potential
is there for a lot of good we just have
to build the systems the right way I
want to add on to that just a little bit
bit on what Oren was saying there there
are people who are looking at how to
correct for biases that we don't want to
see in these systems that we're building
so in one example they're looking at
correlations of words where male was
more often associated with doctor and
female with nurse but knowing that this
bias exists it meant that the people
developing the models could actually go
in and zero out those correlations which
is very promising so if you tell
somebody or even if somebody
acknowledges that they are biased
yes I am sexist because I live in
society and I have picked up cues from
society it's very difficult to correct
for that and so even when humans are
very aware in trying to address it it's
very difficult to fix whereas in the
machine learning models you can actually
go server out those biases let me give
just a really concrete example of a
trace who's saying that we've we've
thought of it we haven't built this but
I hope that we will so again
unconscious bias in job applications is
well known we currently do not have a
way of stripping a gender
characteristics from resumes you can
take out the names you can take out the
pictures but then you know president of
the women's rowing club or whatever it
is it's pretty easy to tell a person's
gender from a standard resume well we
can build models right where the models
would strip away that information
automatically and when the resume is
presented to the recruiter it can be
very difficult to tell the gender or the
race of the person and that would
actually be a learning problem right
build something that makes it as
difficult as possible or impossible to
tell the person's characteristics that
you want to obscure and then give the
resume to people so that's a great
example of what you were saying in a
very concrete context there would make a
difference I want to respond to that
very quickly which is that that is very
powerful that we could strip those
identifying characteristics the next
question I would have is does that
actually improve the screening process
because actually in some cases when I've
reviewed resumes if I see that someone
let's say someone is a black woman and
they are still in tech I feel like they
must have faced much more obstacles and
the fact that they're still around is
probably a positive signal on their
tenacity and ability to stick it out in
an unfriendly environment so I may
actually want to know some of those
details in some cases because it
contextualizes and you know the prestige
of university there's bias and who has
access to certain universities we can't
afford to pay for them and so if
somebody has stuck it out through
State College a man should still become
very successful that sort of distance
traveled metric is very powerful and so
even if we could remove all the
information I'm not sure that I always
would but there are actually still
interesting ways of doing I'm a
candidate screening that could address
some of these issues in a different way
so I I know some people were working on
predictors of job performance at our
base on more psychometric fingerprint
type of details so if you play a game
you can start to assess if in
characteristics of how somebody
approaches problem solving and that can
be very independent of gender race or a
lot of these other superficial
characteristics but can be correlated to
success metrics in an in a specific
workplace and so then you could have
people who are candidates play those
games it doesn't really matter what
their resume says but if they have the
sort of psychometric fingerprint that
matches to high performers in this
specific job then they are better
candidates to hire I presume Bridget is
the one trying to improve the quality of
our leadership that gets you very
excited
it does hopefully does it use of AI
brillkids we are in our last sort of 10
minutes or so so I just wanted to see if
anybody from our audience has any
questions oh we do brilliant fantastic
we've got three there you go
okay thank you so my question addresses
something could be different it's about
the future of warfare we discussed that
yesterday essentially AI will be a very
important component of a future warfare
especially when you think about a
possible conflict with a dictatorship
authoritarian regime how much human
decision-making or power do you think
will be left in in the future on the
military level or even the political
level is there any hope well this is
something that I've written about and of
course I don't have a crystal ball but
I'd like to make a conceptual
distinction that I do think is important
here and that's the distinction between
intelligence and autonomy and we're used
to people who are of course are both and
so it's easy to conflate those but I
would argue that we can have
increasingly intelligent weapons in the
sense that they're more targeted
potentially more powerful and that has
its own mixed dynamic right more
targeted might reduce civilian
casualties more powerful is always a
scary thing if you think of incredibly
powerful cyber weapons but I do think
that's somewhat inevitable simply
because of the dynamics of the arms race
but the autonomy question which is the
second part of which you raised is a
completely separate thing so as we have
increasingly intelligent weapons we can
retain the control of these weapons in
the hands of humans and I personally
even though humans have their own
weaknesses certainly feel more
comfortable that way that people are
still the ones making the decisions so I
just want to draw that distinction and
at least argue that it's possible to
separate those two dimensions
yes so just as an example in a defensive
context right if the Israel has deployed
weapons to defend against you know the
indiscriminate shelling of civilian
population centers by Palestinians and
others and in that context right there
is no human-in-the-loop it's a purely
defensive measure in other situations
you do lose some speed but on the other
end you can gain an accuracy right so I
it is a choice but I think we can draw
the line there we'll leave some speed
but we will still have the authority for
taking human life rest with a person I
think we have one question in the back
there as well so what do you tell people
you know when they look at systems I
mean the current crop of systems in the
current wave they produce systems which
are basically totally opaque actually
have no way to look inside the current
type of systems not like in old days we
had ruled these systems you could look
inside I mean there was fine so these
systems are totally unexplainable
they're totally opaque and there's
actually no really couldn't you know
convincing way to do you know
verification validation test and
evaluation of a system when you can't
actually ever look inside I mean you can
make a guess but that's about it so what
do you tell people when they say okay
well I'm gonna put it in a critical
situation what about that so two points
one is actually three points very
quickly one is even in the old days of
rule-based systems right when you had a
large set of rules there was a bunch of
opacity there particularly the
interactions between them so we were
younger in the past but it wasn't always
so much better point one point two
people are working on more explainable
systems you're absolutely right it's
extremely difficult with these nonlinear
neural networks but the third piece
which is actually where I have the most
hope is externally auditing them so what
you can do even if the system is
relatively a black box you can fire at
it
literally hundreds of thousands if not
millions of cases and see how its loan
processing or criminal justice or
weapons behavior and this external
auditing can give you a model of how the
system will behave so I believe that
we're gonna have increasingly
sophisticated auditing system and that
will help one thing I had as a flipside
to being able to peer into some of these
systems is that if they are being used
in context that may become adversarial
having too much visibility is dangerous
so there are some of these computer
vision systems now that can be very
easily tricked just by adding in a few
pixels in the right places which is kind
of fun for now you could put on one of
these like stickers and then confuse the
computer vision algorithms but if you
wanted to use these it's a kick in
defense applications you don't
necessarily want the adversary to be
able to trick your system so I'm not
saying that we shouldn't have
interpretable systems and we definitely
should try to understand more what is
going to be the output with certain
inputs but that's another consideration
which is like how can they be weaponized
you can see this in more I guess like
the civilian or commercial context with
a Google search so Google is very
protective of what inputs are being used
and how they're being combined to do
search result because you always have
people trying to rise to the top that's
like the whole domain of SEO so people
are they used to do really simplistic
things like keyword stuffing to get the
results that rise to the top but then
you have these spammers and fraudsters
who are trying to rise the top so Google
has to be very protective there so it's
just a very difficult thing to advocate
for true transparency if you don't
really if you don't really know what's
happening in a system the attack may not
be adversarial or intention it may be if
you're running a system in a natural
environment you're subject to you have
no idea what exactly so it's not only
adversarial attacks it's also just
natural occurrences couldn't screw up
just as badly I mean we've seen Facebook
and Twitter get weaponized and they I
don't think they even fully understood
what they were getting used for we had a
chance at the fur
student at the frontier and then we'll
go to the back so these two people here
first thank you could we have a woman
ask a question yeah I was gonna I was
hoping that we could make maybe a lady's
voice and if that would I'm Victor soot
from the Coptic boys Institute I really
like the examples of the benefits if I
may go back to that question but all but
they sort of make me feel they are a
little bit more statistical when we come
when we talked about reducing number of
incidents whether there are car
incidents or incidents that happen in
surgeries because they're basically also
non events are on day if something
doesn't happen to you you might not
register it on a on a personal level so
I was just wondering if the trick to
make the conversation you know shift
towards the benefits of the AI also in
argumentum maybe the the experience for
instance in cars it would be the luxury
of not having to pay attention you can
it's more comfortable you can be
focusing on other things or would there
be other examples of benefits that would
register more on individual or more
personal level individually for the
first question there what's the what is
the best way of how can we reduce
friction I guess here I like your
suggestion of making it more personal I
don't have much to add ok bro we have we
have an ir developer there I think
basically yes hello thank you for for
your insight so far so my name is David
and I work for Google in protecting
elections actually so it's a bit maybe
not relevant in this discussion however
my question is connected to I think what
Tracy mentioned when we speak about a I
think AI will increase the these
discrepancies between between the you
know the haves and the have-nots and for
the have-nots what do you think will be
a solution way when when AI will
potentially displace them for their jobs
do you believe in a universal basic
income is this an option or taxing
robots how do you first see a future in
which there will be for sure people that
will be let's say not benefit
from AI as some of the other groups of
people how will we help them that's my
question thank you
I mean I'm personally an advocate for
the universal basic income but that's
just as a human rather than necessarily
as anything connected to AI
I mean how yeah how do we we have talked
about those people do get left behind in
this in these technological revolution
so how do you prevent that it is a
complex issue I would just make a couple
of points one is a universal basic
income at least in the United States is
not practical
we haven't even even though we're a very
rich society we haven't even been able
to deliver universal health care so I
think just as a practical matter we may
need a different solution I also think
that the problem with taxing robots on
the one hand it seems sensible right
then we could use that income to deliver
social programs you tend to tax things
that you want less of right like a sin
tax right you know we tax cigarettes we
tax alcohol it's unclear whether we want
fewer robots or not because again that
puts us somewhat at a disadvantage
internationally some I'm just concerned
about those two solutions for different
reasons the one thing that I do like is
if we were to provide tax credits to
people for or other benefits for
improving their education for for
working and so if we can provide
incentives for positive behaviors that
strikes me as something that would be
perhaps more practical than universal
basic income and perhaps promote
positive things rather than tax robots
but I don't have an answer and the
problem is absolutely a big one the last
point I want to make real quick is that
this is part of a trend that's been
taking place over some decades right so
where did all these uber drivers come
from right there were a displace from
other positions Amazon and e-commerce
even without a eyes already creating
you know loss of jobs in the retail
sector so we've had some decades of
these trends and they're going to
continue we need to do something about
it that's broader than just dealing with
AI it's really about digitization and
autom automation great back yes since
we're in the overarching theme is
navigating through disruptions can we
sort of talk about the global political
implications in terms of the disruptions
across countries like China India
Estonia as a one-element in Pakistan and
the implications of how those
disruptions will be managed and your
sense of the scale and impact of the
disruptions as it affects countries
differently and democracies versus
authoritarian regimes and the ability to
respond to those disruptions so this is
the AI arms race I guess right who's
gonna win out of this China okay then
say Estonia versus India and China and
so if you have a lot of people and
they're out of work because of the
disruptions of of Technology
they're greater political and social
implications may or may not be true so
the question is is anyone thinking about
that how do you manage it and those
disruptions is Traci said policy is not
going to be ahead of it it's going to be
behind it so the disruptions and
dislocations are going to be here and
the implications are going to be here
and are going to be not evenly felt
across countries what are you guys
thinking about that again very sweeping
question and a good one let me offer a
partial answer just
in the hopes of giving my co-panelists a
chance to think I don't know that
anybody has an adequate answer but two
points something that's working well and
I hope we continue to preserve it is the
open dissemination of information across
universities open source archive and so
on so even as tensions between the US
and China and other tensions are
inflamed so far there hasn't been there
has not been an attempt to curtail the
exchange of information in academic
forums and I hope that continues and
that of course gives smaller players
equal access to this sort of you know
the papers the the open source code the
open source data etc so I think that's a
good thing something that I think is a
huge negative both because of lack of
cross fertilization and also simply
weakens the United States I do think we
have increasingly adversarial
relationship with China is the
restraints on immigration so we have
fewer and fewer people applying to our
undergrad programs to our graduate
programs from outside of the United
States we have fewer people being
allowed to stay due to a variety of
measures that the Trump administration
has taken and the result of that is a
real negative for artificial
intelligence in the United States and
that's something I hope that we we
reverse put in plain terms we need more
visas for people to study AI and to be
part of the ecosystem in the United
States we need more visas rather than
less I was little bit hesitant to answer
because I don't feel like I'm a good
enough student of geopolitics and
society to give a good answer but I'll
also offer some thoughts on where
technology and AI are potentially going
to cause disruption in bad ways so with
technology in independent of AI if we're
looking at some of the big companies
like Google
uber they're starting to provide
services across the world but all the
wealth concentration all that power
concentration is still primarily in
those companies in Silicon Valley or in
the United States so they control the
the algorithms that determine who sees
what who can connect with whom the
economic so for uber the economics of
providing the service across the world
have primarily concentrated in San
Francisco so when we look at an AI it
gets even more powerful it's no longer
just the technology the data the
computer or the compute but all right
the data part of it becomes an even
bigger concentrator of that power and
we're seeing it primarily in the US and
in China and there are not any other
very compelling players so now we have a
little bit this arms between the US and
China as Orrin mentioned you know the
u.s. is doing some really dumb things
around immigration that it's going to
hurt it at a very high level right now
China is getting much better at
execution on AI the u.s. is still very
good at rnd but potentially is going to
lose out going forward
so then if we end up in a world where
China holds most of the power around AI
and these technology products are used
around the world they can then control
the technology that's used by all these
other countries so now we're not even
just looking at disruptions within
individual countries but at a global
scale we have a change of power where
China may be even more influential it's
already been very influential in terms
of like the trade and economics but if
it can control the technology as well
then other countries around the world
may just have to be beholden to what
China wants to do then we also have the
issues like within each country if
they're not able to control their own
destiny with technology what happens I
don't have real answers around what we
do about a growing income inequality or
wealth inequality but I think the
questions we were grappling with earlier
around like how do we rescale people or
put them into positions where they can
still live
in the absence of the job that they had
previously we still need to figure out
all of those questions mmm and speaking
of questions we are basically out of
time startlingly so will and a little
late and one very very very brief answer
from each of you what is the development
you're most excited for the use case of
AI in the future so we'll start with or
will go down line autonomous vehicles
because they have the potential to save
just so many lives richer um health care
because I think as humans the basic
thing we all want is health and better
health and Tracey I think better
understanding of people so we're
starting to clock more data on people
and workforce and how they interact and
I think if we have a better
understanding of the the humans that are
involved hopefully we can make better
decisions around how to treat people as
well I think that's a good manifesto for
life thank you very much for all of
their inputs and thank you very much for
joining us hope let you enjoy your
coffee break and thank you Chris for
being great
you