good morning ladies and gentlemen and
thank you for attending welcome to this
session on on Russia piling up the bones
as they call it which is a very sort of
aggressive way of looking at it but
that's fine I I'll just introduce myself
I'm Tom Clark I'm the chairman of a
company called global public affairs
were based in Canada and Washington and
the United States and fortunately I must
say we also have somebody who attended
the University of Toronto so I'll get to
that in a minute but I just want to very
briefly introduce you to the people who
are here tell you a little bit about
them
Brian Whitmore is to my left he's a
senior fellow and director of the
Russian program at the Center for
European policy analysis and in a much
previous life he tells me he worked for
the Boston Globe in both Moscow and
Prague so he's got deep understanding of
the situation
Sophie Katz Arava is the head of the
door George and delegation to the OSCE
as she spent 11 years at the British
Embassy in Tbilisi and for her work in
terms of helping relationships between
Georgia and the United Kingdom she is a
member of the the Order of the British
Empire personally bestowed upon her by
the Queen we have from Estonia the
foreign minister Edgard ricca vich
Latvia Lithuania I tell you I was more
concerned and how I pronounced his last
name and I got his country wrong as
opposed anyway it sounds to me as if
you're all we more familiar with that
girl than I am
anyway nice to heavier Minister sorry
about that name thing i we have toyou
klar who is the EU Special
Representative for the southern caucuses
and the crisis in Georgia in 2013 he was
the head of the EU monitoring mission
for Georgia
he spent many years in the Estonian
civil service at very senior levels he
graduated from Harvard the jf Kennedy
School for international studies and
attended two years at the Arundale
campus of the University of Toronto
which is really the main accomplishment
of his academic life and then Jim
Townsend I think everybody knows Jim
senior fellow at the center of the new
American security for eight years he was
President Obama's deputy assistant
secretary for defense for Europe and
NATO and he served in his time at both
the Pentagon and at NATO so welcome to
you all I wanted to start with a very
simple question and one that you may
have received once or twice before but
before we start talking about how we
deal with Russia let's talk about what
Russia wants and just let me throw that
out if it's a short answer that's fine
but Brian let me start with you what do
you think Russia wants yeah thanks um I
mean I think what Russia wants is clear
and it's also clear that Russia wants
things we can't give to it Russia wants
its neighbours sovereignty to be
conditional Russia has a problem with
Georgia's sovereignty it's a problem
with Latvia sovereignty has a problem
with the stoniest sovereignty and to say
the needless to mention it has a problem
with Ukraine's sovereignty that's that's
something Russia wants and when I think
we have to ask ourselves are we prepared
to give that I'm not Russia wants to
expand the kind of a corrupt
kleptocratic system that exists inside
of Russia what the emigrate political
scientist Elena Lydon you have a call
sistema it wants to spread this into the
former Soviet Union into the former
Warsaw Pact and farther two points
farther west if we're okay with that we
can have a discussion with mr. Putin if
we're not okay with that we really can't
have a discussion about this the Russia
wants to destroy NATO it has a problem
with NATO and it wants it wants NATO to
be dissolved and destroyed and Russia
wants to destroy the European Union
Russia wants the end to a rules-based
international system based on
institutions and wants one based on
great power politics and/or
or might makes right so I think this is
what Russia wants this is clear I mean I
think this has been clear for some time
and I think we have to stop asking what
Russia wants and start thinking about
what we want so I think that's how I
would I would kind of reframe the
question that way so do you see it that
way
thank you very much I think reframing
the question is exactly what I also
thought would be the right point because
I think everybody understands recognizes
what Russia wants and Georgia is a
perfect example of that alongside with
Ukraine infringement of sovereignty and
territorial integrity which goes on for
decades and we find ourselves exactly in
the same situation now in the 21st
century we're raised the why offences
through razor wire fences European
countries are being divided that is what
we see I think the the question that
will be will be posed later on how this
should be dealt with that is more
relevant for us for countries like
Georgia to think how to move forward I
think that that's that's the principal
question okay
Minister I can't imagine another country
that has more stake in this than Latvia
does how do you view from your position
from where you said as Minister of
Foreign Affairs when you look across
that border what do you think they want
from you well I think that it is going
to be a very boring panel because we are
going to agree on everything is
everything on everything and no kind of
discussion so I'm quite sorry for those
people who are here expecting some kind
of entertainment but at least from my
perspective I would say first Russia
really wants to restore its status of
great superpower in order to do that it
needs Ukraine it needs to some of those
countries that is in the neighborhood
from my perspective from latias
perspective I would say that we are not
any more so concerned about what's a
direct kind of possible influence on
material because we are part of NATO
part of EU and we jumped the Train
almost at the last moment of historic
opportunity so no military threats
thanks also to our allies but what we
see and there is increasing
attempt to influence societies from
Estonia to Latvia to Germany to Spain to
Italy to destroy the core of society
democratic system rule of law and to
some extent also to spread the new type
of ideology it's not anymore communism
now it's a kind of social conservative
approach they are talking about
traditional values but they are also
trying to affect the way how the system
works through money through corruption
through what we call also propaganda
warfare information warfare so those are
three things to restore the greatness as
they perceive it - let's say influence
the neighbors but also I agree with my
previous colleagues who spoke here also
to undermine institutions that we are
part of NATO EU and also the core system
of our own liberal democracies
let me go to you but let me slightly
change the question a little bit because
I'm sure you probably agree with our
other panelists unless you don't
in which case jump in but you've got a
unique perspective only not because of
all the work and service that you've
given to the Georgia situation in the
South Caucasus but also because you
served for a long time in Estonia so and
in a way you've served on both fronts if
I could put it that way are we doing
today a better job of figuring this out
than we were five years ago well I think
first of all I would agree with the with
the Minister that this there's not a lot
of daylight between us here but but I
would I would actually like to refer
back to I was sitting in in Baku one on
Monday evening with a friend in a
restaurant and and we were talking about
that this topic more or less as well and
basically thinking that well if if
Russia if Russia wants to restore its
power and influence actually what it's
doing is is not really very sensible
because I have also my my previous job I
was dealing with Central Asia that
actually there is such a thing as this
ruski Mir and you from bishkek to Minsk
there is a common cultural sort of
emotional space which the Russians could
make use of as huge amounts of potential
soft power which they're not making use
of instead all of these countries are
around Russia are wary of Russia and so
the the the what what Russia is making
use of is making use of its hard power
whereas with much less effort with much
everybody feeling much more comfortable
about it it could achieve perhaps even
much more in terms of influence by by
building on this soft power and having
the countries around it feel actually
comfortable with with this big beer
sitting in Moscow and that's that's
that's really a problem that how can we
how is there a way for us to to get the
Russians to change track and Jim let me
finish off this round with you and again
you've got a very unique perspective on
the Russian situation considering your
background you know it used to be that
when you thought of that struggle
between the United States and the Soviet
Union and then with Russia that it was
really one of arms now particularly in
the United States and other countries
too I might add
it is more of an insidious attack than
anything else when you take a look at
that relationship particularly between
the United States and Russia I and put
it in a five-year context is getting
worse than it was five years ago
well yes I think it is but let me start
off though and say that we've been
talking about what does Russia want and
I think it's really
in a lot of ways what does Putin want so
much of this is being driven by his own
personality I think one of the
differences with the Soviet Union and
the Cold War that struggle as we know
had a lot much more of an ideological
tent to it and a ideological system in
Moscow that kind of ran it and we went
through a lot of definite personalities
running the Soviet Union but today it's
different in the sense that we're
dealing with Putin and and and his own
views on what he wants and number one
what he wants us to stay in power and so
he's doing whatever it takes to pump
himself up among the Russian people
whether it's taking off his shirt and
riding bareback on a horse or its
invading Georgia and and Ukraine he's
he's got this tough-guy image and that's
part of what he's trying to do to make
sure he stays in power and that his
influence and his money and this type of
thing stays there to the oleg Arkell
system that he has set up there's a lot
there for him that he wants and that's
number one number two is I do feel he
has this sense almost like Adolf Hitler
had a sense within himself on what his
mission was his mission is to restore
Russia to what it was not necessarily
even the Soviet Union but a Russian
greatness whatever he has in his mind of
what Russian greatness looks like he
wants to restore that and and that
manifests itself in many different ways
but one of the tools that he likes to
use to bring about this Russian
greatness or an image of Russian
greatness or Putin's greatness is chaos
he loves chaos and he does that through
means whether it's interfering and
democracy whether it's intimidating
nations whether it's invading nations
whether it is it is with them on a
friendly way whether it's with Trump or
whether it's with with some political
parties in Europe that have an affinity
for him whether it's Syria whether it's
Venezuela if he can see if he can
instill chaos in this Western system
that we've created that helps him stay
in power and so for me as I look at that
question and again and and as well as
well as this way of warfare that you're
talking about to which is much more
insidious that is another tool
but he is used that is much more
effective than something kinetic you
know his misinformation campaign just in
the u.s. presidential campaign that we
just went through a few years ago that
is worth much more than five batteries
of of howitzers or tank divisions he was
able to come across the Atlantic and
screw with our democracy and we haven't
been able to respond to it so in this
day and age is what does Putin wants and
the tools that he uses to get what he
wants is different than what we've seen
in the past I want to go to Brian but
just before I do Brian
I just want to as you all know that
these things please go to slide oh let
me get the questions because we're in a
fairly informal environment here and I'd
like to make this as much of a
conversation with all of us as as we can
right over first I wanted to agree with
Jim that that Putin is effectively
trying to create a situation where the
side that best copes with chaos is the
site that's gonna be victorious my
colleague Asifa Donnell Jenson's
recently wrote an excellent report on
this I do want to kind of gently push
back a little bit about that we just
have a Putin problem because I don't
think we just have a Putin problem I
think Putin is the current manifestation
of our Russia problem because I think
this conflict promises to be a very long
term conflict unfortunately because I
believe it's systemic I believe it's
systemic we're not in a kind of Cold War
situation where you're having to kind of
fully formed ideologies facing off
against each other but we get to a kind
of struggle between two normative
systems and we have a struggle between
Western liberalism with all of its
faults that we recognize but we
recognizes it's probably the worst
system in the world except all the
others as Winston Churchill once said
and on the other hand you have again
what I alluded to in my introductory
comments this Sistema right with the
russian émigré political scientist elena
LED and yet a call sistiana and what is
this well it's this kind of it's what
the russians called Pangea and blackness
Piazzi right the the kind of the the
system of understanding of informal
rules of getting things done of corrupt
and kleptocratic networks and this is
how russia is truly ruled and we've
allowed ourselves to be kind of fooled
by the forms because Russia has been
ruled this way whether it was ruled by
czars and boyars in general
Terri's and polyp euros or so-called
presidents and Parliament's it's always
been ruled by sistema now sistema during
the Cold War was hermetically sealed it
was hermetically sealed behind the Iron
Curtain it really wasn't our problem
it was the problem of the other three
the other three of co-panelists but Jim
it wasn't your in my problem well guess
what after after the end of the Cold War
in the advent of globalization you and I
were probably pretty naive in thinking
that our Western values were going to
basically spread throughout the entire
world
what's happened instead is that Russia
has been able to spread the values of
Systema into our systems and to corrupt
and corrode and in undermine our systems
that's what we're seeing right now what
Putin has done and I think every Russian
leader basically is a product of Systema
and to a degree is shaped by Systema and
shape Systema to a little and Putin
shaped Systema in his image to a degree
and what he's done is basically
externalize it and weaponize it against
the West he's basically taken these
domestic arrangements of using kind of
corruption as a tool of statecraft
effectively in informal networks as a
tool of statecraft and turned it into
something to undermine Western
institutions so well we have a kinetic
war in the former Soviet space in an
effort to read to re-establish the
Empire in Ukraine and Georgia
specifically but it could end up in
other places as well I'd keep my eye on
Belarus and when does thereby of passes
from the scene I'd keep my eye on
Kazakhstan to be quite honest but well
then we have a non kinetic war against
the West under minor institutions and I
think this is going to continue after
Putin I don't think it I think Putin is
just one manifestation of that so it's a
slight nuance in our Brian you're led
neatly to the the obvious next question
which is now that we've defined what the
problem is how are we dealing with it
and are we dealing with it today Andy
differently than we dealt with it five
years ago are we having any greater
success than we did five years ago to
choose an arbitrary timeline and you
know I want to deal with Georgia for a
second but obviously this applies to the
Baltic states as well and there are
thank you there is one person in the
room who's sending a lot of questions
name is anonymous I thank you thank you
for that but let's deal with the
question of how we're dealing with it
and when you're talking about Russian
soft power law not kinetic so we know
how to deal with kinetic stuff when they
shoot at us we shoot at them and then
somebody wins and somebody loses but the
soft power is far more difficult to
figure out how is Georgia dealing with
that and toivo you would obviously have
a say in this as well as Sophie but and
what lessons are there being learned
right now in Georgia and other places to
deal with this soft power the more we
talk about Russia and relations with the
West the more we realize here that
that's one of the hardest questions that
this panel is posing but most relevant
and we should be talking about that
particularly for countries like Georgia
it's extremely important that's the
audience that we are here and more
broadly the international community
fully understands the challenges that we
are facing Georgia Ukraine and any other
country the country's sovereignty and
territorial integrity are being
infringed by Russia
so here everybody here knows the context
well I just since we are comparing where
we stand now what was five years ago or
what was ten years ago
the context is there Russia continues to
violate the principles of international
law Russia continues to occupy 20% of
Georgia's territories Ukraine's Crimea
annexation and the situation is to
Ukraine it simply demonstrates the
magnitude of security challenges that we
are facing in the Black Sea region I
know that everybody in this room
understands this I know that as I said
broadly more broadly everybody
understand that this should be
highlighted and they should be
recognized more and more the challenges
that we are facing in the Black Sea
region and conventional and
unconventional threats and hybrid
threats that undermines Western values
how we're dealing with that
it's not an easy pass but being an
immediate neighbor of Russia and facing
this challenge is almost on a daily
basis obviously conventional are threats
and the occupation is there and the
security challenge but I think what
makes us frontline state and here I
would like to both perhaps a little bit
because Georgia is a frontline state in
many ways and what makes us frontline is
perhaps the values that we share and our
commitments to share the values of
freedom and democracy that is our
biggest instrument and to to counter the
threats that we are facing and our
commitment perhaps that we want to
become a member of the European Union
and member of NATO and perhaps the
resilience that we keep talking about it
and I I was in Lithuania a week ago at
the Baltic assembly where the Minister
was also there and we had a very
interesting discussion about the unity
and the strengths and more strategic
vision of Europe and NATO towards
countries like Georgia like Ukraine I
mean strategic vision practicality
technical assistance it's all there it's
all very important and it's all very it
is vital for countries like Georgia but
at the same time it's important that
we've got more strategic vision and
yesterday the president of this country
made very good remarks about about
strong foreign policy and also the
remark that I remembered and I want to
reiterate here that while we argue and
it's not about what it's not Georgia we
are not a member of the EU hope but
hopefully we will be a member of you at
some point and NATO while we argue some
someone else takes the lead so I think
that is the issue that we need to talk
through the resilience of transatlantic
security and where it lies and why this
is important for countries like Georgia
it's about open-door policy it's about
in
large amount of the you and this has
been always at the heart of
transatlantic security and our
democratic values and our commitment and
determination to be the front-runner so
that this is also an example to other
countries in the region which obviously
does not play into Russia sense so I
want to get you involved in this briefly
if I could and then I've got a question
for the menisci yeah I think resilience
is really a key word generally speaking
and it's not only resilience so if we
was mentioning here the transatlantic
institutions European institutions but
it's the resilience of countries and
resilience of countries institutions and
and and here I would say that for
example in in in the Georgian case the
Russia exploited weaknesses that existed
in in Georgia made use of the of the
fact that there was death neck tension
in the beginning of the 90s and and
jumped right in and and so the the
paradigm of course changed fundamentally
in 2008 because that was when when there
was a real war between Russia and
Georgia up to now you had had Russian
troops in Georgia but but under the
under the heading of peacekeepers but
but so the the question again coming
back is is that the the fact that the
Russians came in in the first place that
they had an opening to come in in first
place was the fact that there was there
were these conflicts and if these
conflicts had not been there it would
have been more difficult much more
difficult for the Russians to find a
foothold they might still have tried but
it would have been more difficult and so
the question is in in this context what
can we do what can any country do and it
depends of course on the situation of
the country and Georgia's is a
particularly difficult one with the
Russian troops
being in south ossetia and abkhazia but
nevertheless what can even in those
circumstances the Georgian government do
to strengthen its own situation visa vie
the population in in south ossetia and
abkhazia in terms of reaching out to
those two those two territories to an
and Georgian government is doing quite a
bit but I think there's more that can be
done precisely in order not to play
along with the Russian PlayBook but to
write your own playbook and I think that
is that is where we are perhaps I think
they've mentioned we was mentioned here
before that that the question is one
question is what are the Russians doing
but the question is also what are we
doing what is our with our our plans how
can we strengthen our institutions our
countries in order to counteract any
kind of initiatives let me just pick up
on that point and I'll throw it out to
anybody and I really their microphones
going around but just a me let me take
my position to pose this question to you
and it was suggested I think by Peter I
don't know where Peter is in the room
he's a friend with anonymous by the way
so but you bring up the question of what
we can do and it's it's it begs the
question then do we have the will to do
it do we have the will to make the
sacrifices necessary to have a robust
policy and by that I mean when soft
power is used in insidious ways and
perhaps I'm talking about oil pipelines
or natural gas pipelines and this sort
of thing how let me get your sense and
especially from a Baltic point of view
Minister how far are you prepared to go
to stop this and how much do you think
that your sovereignty right now is at
risk well I just want to come back a
little bit to the previous discussion
because I think it is very important
look we have been able to formulate some
kind of basic policies back in 2014 to
2016 two levels
you and NATO EU has this kind of two way
approach and five principles meaning
contain and engage put sanctions by the
way strange enough but the European
Union has quite coherent policy when it
comes to dealing with Russia but they
are still struggling to find the same
kind of policy to deal with China or to
deal with the United States or the rest
of the world that's also a really
interesting my country would always hope
to have more robust more strict policy
with a V Russia but then I understand
that in order to get whatever kind of
united and more or less efficient policy
we have to compromise all the time and
that's what we did back in 2014-2015 not
much has changed frankly but it's also a
good news with all those let's say
attacks against democracies in many of
you nations we still hold remarkably
well NATO has the same kind of policy
developed from 2014 to 2016 we started
with US deployments in the Baltic States
April 2014 when we really were scared
and if you compare five years ago the
situation on the streets of Riga tallest
darling and Venus people were
remembering 1940 not anymore
all the opinion polls are showing that
there is quite a trust in European Union
in the Alliance and people are starting
kind of feel that Russia is not anymore
so a big threat that's a public
perception that is growing back back
home we also were able to work out
sensible strategy on resilience what we
are lacking we are lacking resources we
are sometimes lacking understanding in
all capitals in European Union but I do
believe that from that point of view we
are trying to at least do what is
necessary and to find a common
denominator is there a will to do more
no actually there is a very mixed
feeling we have this kind of North
Stream project developing despite the
objections of many countries including
my own we are now struggling and we are
quite a minority
when it comes to the restoration of the
voting rights of Russia in the Council
of Europe the what is coming in couple
of weeks we do believe this is not the
right thing because we see that there
are moves from Russia that are just
opposite to what we were expecting like
hospitalization of Donbass like seizure
of 24 sailors of Ukraine and then
refusing to implement ruling of the
International Tribunal of for the law of
the sea so this is a very mixed feeling
however I would say that one of our
major kind of efforts right now is to
keep what we have achieved at the
European level and it's not less I would
hope that we would get kind of more
let's say steam more real to do more but
then we need to deal with things that we
were not dealing five years ago we have
a lot of issues with the United States
now from Iran and trade to climate
change and also transatlantic bond and
defense spending we have now growing
debate never have seen that before in
China and we still need to keep our
Eastern partners on the agenda for EU
foreign policy so this is a very complex
very mixed feeling and we are not
talking about breaks it here we are not
talking about some other things that I
don't want to mention because then I
would have lecture for a couple of hours
and I wouldn't stop mentioning all those
troubles EU or or NATO all of us need to
do so this is not good thing to say that
we are not doing enough but I also
understand the limits that we all are in
Jim you've been sitting here listening
to a lot of different topics and I want
to bring you in just to respond to some
of it but and there was a question from
Reinhart but it was also on my mind as
well and that is that we are dealing
with a Russia that may be outsized in
terms of its reputation and what it has
done let's not kid ourselves but its
economy is puny compared to many other
countries it has vast Natural Resources
has never been able to
turn itself into an economic superpower
is being constrained or should be
constrained somewhat by its own economy
and therefore what you know how it can
meet its own ambitions on that front is
that a significant deterrent in itself
that Russia just doesn't have the money
to do what they want to do well you know
I think it's a very important question
and I think about that all the time and
when I was in the Pentagon dealing
particularly after the Crimea invasion
and trying to figure out what are we
dealing with here
I kept what I kept thinking over and
over again we have to look at the facts
as they are and not get lulled into this
idea that that Putin was pumping out
that he's actually 10 feet tall and we
can't allow ourselves to make decisions
based on the wrong data and a
misunderstanding of what he really is
and what his capabilities really are on
a regional basis he can cause a lot of
problems and I think our friends here
whether it's in Georgia or Ukraine
Latvia Estonia having the Russians on
right there on the border that's that's
a superpower situation right they're not
even taking into consideration nuclear
capabilities so so it depends on the
perspective that you have in terms of
what he's able to do and so um so I but
but I think the the most important thing
though in looking at Putin and in the
right context is that while we have to
keep in mind he's not ten feet tall they
have these problems within Russian
society whether its funding whether its
military capability I mean the aircraft
we see flying or the old bears and you
know it's not like we're seeing a lot of
new things but that but that's the point
just because right now you're looking at
Russia using these metrics like DeMott
demographics or GDP or this type of
thing that doesn't mean number one that
it will always stay that way and number
two it doesn't mean that he can't take
even the little of what he has and make
it into something very large and that's
what we're seeing going back to your
earlier point about his ability to use
on these
new technologies to go in and have quite
a big effect at a very low cost so um so
I think we fool ourselves if we look at
him the way we might have 50 years ago
or 100 years ago or 150 years ago as we
looked at a at an opponent and you
looked at these metrics like GDP in to
demographics and say well they're really
not that big a threat
you've lull yourself into a
misunderstanding of what you're dealing
with and so we have to on the one hand
not fool ourselves that this guy is ten
feet tall and that the Russians are
behind every tree and we're going to be
doing all kinds of things to defeat an
enemy that is not as as big as we we we
fear and all bad things that that brings
to your own planning if you're doing
much more than you have to do but at the
same time don't be fooled that these
weaknesses that we see in fact are not
weaknesses when it comes to a regional
problem like Georgia and Ukraine have
come into or the fact that they can't
use technology such as the Internet and
what we've been seeing in the past as
well as new things like artificial
intelligence hypersonics to achieve a
capability that you would not expect
from a country that you might
underestimate just because of democritus
and GDP
I just need all of you to help me out
here for a minute we have a restricted
time in fact very short period of time
and I want to get this conversation
going so if you could do me a favor and
if you ask a question or want to make a
point can you do it as briefly as you
possibly can and I will apologize in
advance if you're going on a little bit
too long I'll probably intervene and ask
you to wrap it up sir if we got a
microphone we could give I see a couple
of hands going up and I'm also keeping
an eye on slide oh so we're not ignoring
that Jonathan Adler from the Royal
United Services Institute in London I
wonder if I could push you forward with
James Townsend this point looking to the
future one of the areas which we see now
is the sort of disintegration of most of
the arms control agreements that we have
the nuclear ones the conventional ones
in Europe so it's a very complex area
just a simple question to the panel as a
whole
do you think we can engage now in a new
disarmament or arms control discussions
with Moscow while avoiding a discussion
about the division into spheres of
influence who would like to take that
Minister okay yes we must do whatever we
can to try to get a new round of the
negotiations not only with Moscow for
instance INF treaty was obsolete already
as the United States pulled out we all
understand that we need also China we
need anyone having said that I have no
illusion that we are not going to start
it tomorrow or the day after tomorrow I
think that at some point we need to push
for some kind of new
maybe decades-long but still let's say
discussion on on ours control and also
you remember that back in 2007 Russia
was the one to pull out from the
conventional forces Europe agreement
that also leaves us in a kind of way
where probably we need to discuss this
issue we have always see format but I
have seen it for many years it's not
very efficient it's not going to be
efficient but still I believe that at
least we need to try to find the way how
we can engage in the new round of the
talks on this one so I began my career
working on salt - a lot of you weren't
alive when salt - was being negotiated
and I was a very young man but I say
that because I'm no stranger to arms
control and I'm no strangers to its
flaws and how long it takes but I do
know from Cold War days all the way up
through CFE and into the modern day
there is a place for arms control in the
package of things that nations have to
do to deter and to defend themselves
there's a role for it there it's not
it's something that is hard to do it
takes a long time and it's a boutique
point it's it's there is conventional
there's nuclear and but there's elements
of nuclear elements of conventional that
you can tackle through arms control that
gives you more stew
ability at the end of the day you want
deterrence you want stability you want
transparency transparency helps provide
for deterrence you want these things
arms control can help bring that about
it is not a silver bullet you will never
have peace if you only rely on arms
control but it's something that's part
of the package and it's something that
we cannot do away with arms control also
calls for experts you cannot do an arms
control negotiation as a journalist
walking in there and sitting down with
the Russians and expect to get anywhere
so what we cannot do is lose the people
who know how to do this myself included
not you're just kidding
but but we need to keep it it's got to
be part of it
but it but it cannot be the only leg of
that stool it's got to be part of a
broader package including strong
military strong deterrence and a modern
nuclear capability but you've got to
have the guidelines and the cushions
that come with arms control I'm gonna go
to this gentleman in a minute I just
before I do I'm receiving a number of
slider questions here which also was on
my question sheet and that is the
elephant in the room which is China
and we're talking about this emerging
love affair between Putin and XI I how
much of that is going to affect how we
deal with the Russian situation can we
control or contain or deal with China
without controlling containing and
dealing with Russia first are the two
connected Sophie you want to deal with
that
well I should say before answering that
question that the my answers to those
questions would have to bear the context
from my from the perspective of my
country and in the best interest of my
country there's a lot of Chinese
investment in Tbilisi well Georgia
Georgia's ambition is to is to become a
hub and there is a lot that we are doing
obviously we have a very strong and
straightforward and clear
foreign policy and this is clearly
clearly European integration and data
integration and this is not just a glyph
declared go we are consistently
delivering to get closer to these
institutions and that's a fact
cooperation with China and our relations
with China again given the context of my
country we are diversifying our markets
we are turning Georgia into a hub and we
we do have the relations with China that
that that is but that's being balanced
and in the best interest and in the best
interest of our country Brian first of
all I wouldn't characterize it as a love
affair a characterize it more as a
shotgun wedding that's quickly turning
into a dysfunctional marriage I mean
let's face facts I mean Moscow's pivot
to China came as a result of the falling
out of its relations with the West and
in that relationship
Moscow is clearly the junior partner to
China although they are very loath to
admit it
but China's viewing Russia as a source
of cheap raw materials and this is begun
coming back to haunt Moscow now with you
we're seeing protests in the Baikal
region over Chinese investment there
there was even a webpage encouraging
locals to throw garbage into Lake Baikal
because they were conspiracy theories
the Chinese were gonna steal all of
Russia's water so the policy of a
Kremlin is increasingly at odds with the
populations of the Far East in Russia
there's a reason that no sino-russian
relationship has ever lasted and that is
because neither one of those two
countries wants to be a junior partner
in this case Russia is clearly junior
partner I don't I don't see this as a
long-term as a long-term a marriage it's
a dysfunctional marriage that's been a
sooner or later coming to an end I think
Moscow's hope is that at some point the
West is going to sue for peace with
Moscow in the in the interest of
confronting China I think that's what
they're hoping for and that's what
gambling on but I don't think it's gonna
happen thanks Brian microphone to this
channel oh you are Michael sent
Alexandra jitter to come from European
secret research initiative foundation
from Ukraine key and that one question
about some point I think you and miss
key in this difficult discussion this is
a Russian civil society how he should
influence is this entries because
without having support from civil
society from I mean whole Russian
society it will be impossible just to
execute any kind of policy towards
Ukraine towards no Georgia don't Crimean
and all other things do you have any
kind of ideas how to increase Russian
society to make the changes then to push
some kind of pressure on the ruling
elites to destroy this system a
so-called thank you Umberto I would be
model well I I would I would first of
all civil society is indeed very
important I think from from a new
perspective actually the European Union
has been trying and he is continuing to
try to engage with Russian civil society
and to serve and to to work with Russian
civil society to what extent it is it
has become also more more difficult to
engage with Russian civil society
because of greater restrictions but but
I mean but in general I agree with you I
think I think it is important to
strengthen civil society whatever
whatever we can do that that ultimately
again I think the ultimate hope and goal
for any neighbor of Russia is that that
Russia at one point maybe not tomorrow
maybe not next year but at one point
turns around and and becomes a big
country but a country that its neighbors
actually feel reasonably comfortable to
live with and I think that's there a
civil society will be extremely
important no III agree with that
completely we've seen during the Soviet
Union days the importance of civil
society and I wasn't very very evident
during those days in Moscow where those
folks were they were underground and
this type of thing but but now there
there's still some civil society that we
can work with but you're right it's
they're getting much
or much smaller they've harder to find
and under a lot of pressure because
Putin knows that too and it goes back to
this point about Putin he's not gonna
sit there and allow the United States
for example for us to go in and to
create this opposition to him and he's
already been battling that we all we all
know that so how can we figure out a way
to support civil society to support all
the things that civil civil society can
do in Moscow without causing a blowback
and and wrecking what's left there and
that's a that's a that's a hard task for
an open society to do there's a lot of
things you can do quietly behind the
scenes but but but that one that's
discovered and found out can cause
massive problems so your question is a
very good one is there important one and
I just don't think there's any really
good answers except to continue to be
persistent and try try try try do you
want to say something bright I think we
have to come I kind of come to terms
with the fact that our ability to affect
events inside of Russia is extremely
limited and that the west engaging with
civil society as laudable as that is
puts that civil society in danger and I
think the business of changing Russia is
up to the Russians and after Russian
civil society I would disagree with you
that we can't help Ukraine without
engaging Russian civil society I think
well you crane is an area where we
certainly can happen and have an impact
I think we should be focusing our
efforts on the countries like Ukraine
and Georgia and to a lesser degree
Moldova that have chosen to go west to
break free of this sistema and I think
we this is where we should be placing
our efforts and I'm more of the mind
that we need to contain Russia right now
and leave the business of changing
Russia up to the Russians Mark Kelly Adi
I don't know where you are mark you're
right there let me read your question
and then ask you can the West do
anything positively to make Russian
policy less hostile or is our only
option to deter and outlast can you give
me 30 seconds more on that
oh are you mark i I don't know why I
thought he looks just like you okay sure
thanks very much mark guarantee also
racing um yeah I'm just just to sort of
anyway riff off this this this last
point I mean the question is civil
society is only one part of that overall
equation do we just simply accept that
Russia is going through its own
post-imperial
crisis I say this is coming from brexit
land and therefore we just have to start
to make sure it can we minimize the
damage it can do to the rest of us or is
there anything we can do positively to
address it because the thing that
strikes me is when I'm in Moscow time
and time again I talk to people within
the system and as far as they're
concerned they are at war with the West
and the West started it now that's wrong
but nonetheless it is genuinely believed
do we just have to live with that or can
we do anything about it sure briefly and
then maybe to Sophie
thanks for setting up what I've been
wanting to say through the entire panel
I mean I think we do have to I would say
that we can only contain the damage
right now basically I don't I don't
think there's anything we do to to
positively change Russia's behavior and
I think we have to come up with a kind
of 21st century policy of containment
for lack of a better word I mean I call
it hybrid containment because it's not
your grandfather's containment it's not
putting some tanks in the folded gap it
starts with resilience the minister was
talking about her and I would concur
that laffy has done a great job along
with the other Baltic states in
constructing kind of resilient societies
and I think this is something we can all
learn from there's a direct correlation
between levels of corruption and the
levant and in levels of resilience visa
vie Russia's Russia Russia's active
measures and I think countries that have
done a great job on corruption like
Estonia light laughing in like Georgia
have been much more resilient against
against Russian active measures so kind
of the battle begins at home but you
also have to be able to deter Russia
there has to be an honor or else right
there has to be an or else and I've I
mean my colleague Edward Lucas has
proposed snap financial exercises where
we basically kind of run through
financial exercises of what assets we'd
freeze and when what what what bank
accounts we'd seize
in the event of Russian aggression
hybrid kinetic non kinetic or otherwise
again again against our ally so I think
we have to start thinking in these terms
I think we have to start thinking in
terms of early warning systems we have
early warning systems for nuclear
weapons and for terrorism we need kind
of early warning systems for weaponized
corruption so I think we have to start
thinking through what containing
something like this means in the 21st
century and Jim I want to go to you but
you know an interesting part of what
you're saying though and this applies to
the Baltic States in particular where
the electrical grid is still controlled
by Russia and how easily it would be for
them to cause mischief back if we cause
mischief going forward and Minister I
want to get your reaction to that and
then Jim I want to go to you well I I
and I don't want to get political here
in terms of US politics talking about
brexit land we've got our got our own
land back in the US but I but I think
there's there's going to your question
about looking what can we do there's a
player we really haven't talked much
about and I think we have to and that is
I think one of the things that we can do
belong squarely on the lap of the United
States and we've got to have a clearer
policy about dealing with Russia it's
it's a bit muddled you've got the
pentagon studies and the NSC studies and
the Supercat the competition between the
US and Russia but there is a leadership
part that the United States has is weak
on right now in terms of helping to
propel unity with a NATO or within
within Europe as we try to deal with the
various aspects of Russia we're not as
strong as we have been in the past in
terms of a solid agreed-upon strategy
and policy and leadership dealing with
Russia we need to return to that and
that's one of the things that we can do
is to try to have a stronger policy
dealing with Russia and to lead Minister
briefly on the grid well still coming
back also to the civil society let's not
forget that Russia civil society is also
very different and when we speak about
Russia civil society for instance the
view on Crimea would be totally
different depending on whom you speak so
if you speak about Ukraine and
assistance Ukraine don't assume that
everyone in the Russia's
shishun or civil society would say that
you should return Crimea to Ukraine in
two weeks time we take take over or
second on this kind of engagement with
civil society I would say two things and
I very much agree with those who are
saying that the system can change itself
only with promising like in all good
days of the Soviet Union but if we meet
with representatives of civil society if
we show that they are important to us
that we want to speak with them that
actually also gives some moral boost to
them and also to work with them but
let's not go into financing them because
in that case you will find that there
will be accusations of taking foreign
money spying and being the agent of
influence an electrical grid and the
energy look I think that if you look at
the Baltic states we have done
remarkable work already to a model from
the gas supply so we are now able to get
more gas supplies from not only Russia
but from different parts of the world we
have allergies we have inter characters
building and now the second issue that
we are now working with the European
Union and I hope that by 2025 or so
you'll be able also to connect with the
European Union our grid and to let's I
say goodbye to Russian Belarus but then
again I was myself part of Latvian
delegation back in 2010 visiting Moscow
which then president and one thing that
Russian leadership said back then and it
hasn't changed if you pay your bills you
will get electricity and gas and by the
way with all our back political
relations economic part and while you
are paying bills that part has always
worked with Russia so it's always about
money at the end of the day can I just
and I I apologize I know that there's
other people who want to ask questions
and and we are mere moments away from
coming to an end on here but I did want
to bring up a question that I think
might be on a lot of people's minds
especially those who
don't come from the United States which
is basically all of us except for J Jim
and Brian I
Jim you brought it up and the question
is that in in foreign policy especially
dealing with Europe and and and now
dealing with Russia
the u.s. is giving us a confused picture
the u.s. is being belligerent to their
to their trade allies let alone to their
military allies and I'm wondering and I
take this because the president the
outgoing President of Slovakia said this
yesterday in his speech and that is that
it is time for a more European response
to this as opposed to and I think and I
don't want to put words in his mouth or
even thoughts that may not have been
there but it does beg the question
should the rest of the world
particularly Europe and its extensions
develop a new type of leadership for
dealing with this or should we double
down on a highly unpredictable US
administration where do you go would be
a disaster if Europe developed its own
way to go as a hedge against the United
States because of the events over the
past couple of years but number one
thing we need is unity transatlantic
unity as hard as that is and it's been
hard in the past too this isn't
something new we the transatlantic unity
has had its ups and downs since 1945
this is this isn't new I would say that
there's new elements and there is a a
louder megaphone from the White House
saying things are you know you're not
used to hearing but but but and I will
also say too there is a need for Europe
a strong Europe a strong European Union
a strong European defense industry there
is a need for a strong European sense of
self too but not not up not not in
opposition or in counterbalance to the
United States or or as a result of
politics in the United States which is
transient like all politics are so I
think as terms of what the European
Union is doing what some European
capitals are talking about in terms of a
European identity you mean see us a
above and beyond CSDP a strong Europe is
helpful to the transatlantic
relationship we don't want that but what
we don't want is two separate entities
going about dealing with adversaries or
competitors in two separate ways we've
got to have unity that's got to be the
case we're going through a rough patch
now we will see where politics go but
for for gosh sakes what we don't want to
do is its make decisions in Europe based
on politics in the United States that is
transitory and the same thing in Europe
Tube politics politics in Europe are
transitory and we don't want to do
things in the United States based on
that so we've got to stay unified that's
the key the context to the question from
a Canadian perspective was that until a
week ago we had tariffs slapped on steel
and aluminum because on a 2/3 - we posed
a threat to the national security of the
United States Canada we don't even pose
a threat to ourselves let alone to the
United States but a toy oh and Sophia I
know everybody want to get in on this so
we'll do this the final round no I just
take her what he said what Jim said and
the fact that that in today's world
neither the United States nor Europe can
in the end just do it alone because we
have a huge and rising China we it's a
question of who is going to set the
rules of the world that we live in and
and if we if we have this rift that we
in this these disagreements that we have
between the US and Europe right now if
that deepens if we if we drift apart
then we are only serving others neither
of us is going to win from that and so
in the end it's a question of just
sticking it out and and counting on on
getting back together again because
because this is the only way we can
ensure that those values that we share
actually across the Atlantic that these
that we can push these values forward
also in in the future
yeah because that was the point that I
wanted to make as soon as the panel is
almost over
it's the power of unity and that's how I
started my remarks and it's the
resilience but there are certain caveats
of building resilience and I want to go
back to the point that I made earlier
that transatlantic unity and resilience
lies in open door policy and enlargement
of the European Union and NATO and this
has been always at the heart of Hewitt
wanting security and this is from the
perspective of Georgia from countries
like Georgia which are again maybe I
repeating myself but I think that's a
very important point that I'm making
that particularly for countries like
Georgia who have chosen the paths and
are determined to continue this path
it's extremely important that these
messages this unity is maintained and
this is an encouragement for us for us
for Ukrainians to have the light at the
end of the tunnel thank you just before
I go to the minister because I and and
and Brian should just picking up a
Sophie's point as the time come for us
just to bring Georgia into NATO anybody
disagree with that okay
Minister over to you well indeed it was
time to bring Georgia to NATO in 2008
and we didn't do that in Bucharest and
we got the August of 2008 but that
that's the history and we still think
that it's a hard time to keep our
promise however this panel sounds like
the ordinary European Union Foreign
Affairs Council or NATO foreign
ministerial we always talk about unity
and solidarity and we agree always that
we need unity and solidarity and by the
way things are actually much better on
the ground and they are in the virtual
reality if you look of what's a NATO I
would say that I'm very happy to see
that all the decisions of Warsaw summit
of 2016 have been implement
and also the decisions at very famous
Brussels summit where the Pres got it
wrong and actually the reality was
totally different in the closed room we
see that this is a very mixed picture
and I'm not going to be very original we
are living in a very strange world where
we sometimes get something happening in
those small gadgets and we comment as
diplomats on tweets and Facebook posts
and then when we speak about real things
then sinks again out a bit bit better
but from my perspective I just want to
leave with three short points first of
all for us for the small European
countries it is very very important not
to be put in the position where we are
asked the question are we better
Europeans or are we better transatlantic
cysts because we all understand that
u.s. role in Europe's security is the
same like it was thirty forty or ten
years ago or five years ago it's very
important
second I do believe that sometimes we
are lacking a dialogue between Europe
and the United States for instance when
we are talking about new ideas on the
common security and defence policy it's
not that they are kind of contradictory
to NATO but when Europe is ready to
spend more money as Europe on mobility
or our infrastructure that is also
useful for defense then I think it's the
right thing to do and sometimes our
American friends are looking at with
some suspicion that we are creating
something that is parallel or
contradictory no it's actually
complementary even the biggest skeptics
of the United States in Europe are
understanding that the United States and
NATO is important and final point where
I believe Europe is getting it wrong
this is defense spending and this is
where I would agree with all the
American administrations I remember from
President Clinton President Bush Obama
and now president Trump all of them are
asking and begging European allies to
spend at least two percent and only six
or seven countries by the last count of
NATO are doing that out of 30 almost 30
members of the Alliance so this is a
very mixed feeling so to make a blame
game that the current administration is
worse than the
in the United States or Europe based
fragmented it's not the case but we have
our problems to solve and many problems
to support okay
Thank You minister and and just unless
there's any confusion at all edgar is
the Minister of Foreign Affairs of
Latvia I know somebody thank you for for
mixing up me with Estonia normally I get
mixed up with Lee Swain here so this was
something no all right I'll get the last
word to you I'm not gonna say anything
terribly original here I want to give a
ringing endorsement to Jim's passionate
call for transatlantic ISM going back to
the question you began this panel with
if we go down that path of splitting the
transatlantic alliance we're giving
Putin one of those main things that he
wants it's a big gift to Putin and we
can't do that but beyond that I mean the
like the canadian-american relationship
and I say that as a proud American of
Canadian descent and a proud North
American this relationship is deeper
than any one u.s. president and the
transatlantic relationship is deeper
than any one u.s. president so I think
we we've been through rough patches
before we'll get through this rough
patch and I think they basically keep
calm and carry on us as mark would say I
that brings us to the end so Jim toivo
Edgar Sophie and Brian thank you all
very much and thank you for
participating
[Applause]