so good morning is this on
yes good morning everyone and and thank
you for joining us my name is kathleen
koch and I will be your moderator today
and we're here to talk about cities
right now it's more than half of the
world's population lives in cities and
the prediction is that by 2050 we'll be
68 percent so the question we're going
to be exploring here today is really how
do we handle this massive urban
expansion in a controlled and
sustainable way can can technology help
and and how will these new urban centers
how will they evolve will they become
hubs smart hubs of innovation so I have
as you can see a fabulous panel here to
discuss it so immediately on my left um
is andreas glucoside and he's BMW
group's vice president of governmental
affairs you may recognize the gentleman
next to him the good mayor of the lovely
city of Frances lava Mata Chuvalo
next is Vaz o Hudak vice-president of
the European Investment Bank and then
finally young partner at McKinsey Global
Institute so welcome my panel and mr.
mayor I would like to or shall I call
you Matus is that fine
matter suspect I would love to start
with you so first of all thank you again
for hosting globe SEC here in Bratislava
this is my sixth year to moderate so I
enjoy coming here and my first question
to you is I understand your election was
rather extraordinary because you you
were campaigning with a plan and this
was not a short plan a 300-page
Bratislava plan put together by 30
experts laying out your vision your
future vision for this city how to
improve it and I I am only a visitor
here but it seems perfect to me so what
what is your vision how do you want to
make Bratislava different as it moves
forward
you very much firstly let me say that
I'm so proud that we have glob psyche in
Bratislava and we will cooperate more
with the object to have a every year
better conference and but better
environment for this fabulous meeting of
whole world and of course we we made a
plan Bratislava as you said was made by
76 in the end and the professionals from
different levels of city government and
there was there was maybe there was
something different because everybody
told me before I I start my campaign you
need to be a face who knows like every
very well-known face and you need to be
in television and I said no I would like
to try to go with program and in this
kind of Central Europe in election the
program is is for somebody's maybe to
old school or just everybody said the
famous spin-doctors from different
agencies we always say nobody listened
to the program but anyway we tried it
and we in the end there was a in the end
the property saw is a huge six hundred
page document on internet on internet
movie and we published the book which is
three hundred page big and is more
accessible for for common public let's
say now so how is it going what I
realize you've only been in office how
many months now actually after tomorrow
is six months six months right and I
know it's you can't expect a lot I'm
sorry today actually today Sigma happy
anniversary
so can you tell us about just briefly
the progress you're making on any of the
points in the plan concrete progress at
this point I need to say that I have
decided it is if I want to do something
in very good way I need to have a good
plan and the team but after six months I
need to say that I'm so happy I have
this book I have this menu because in
the end is a manual for better
Bratislava and I'm just following
everyday the steps of it brought in so
it's a road map it's a road map and it's
it's my only help I have because there
are so many problems in the city
everybody knows it and to talk about the
future the strategy
the vision there is no real time during
this month so so I'm so glad to have it
and we are with Almighty we follow it we
following it very closely
Jana I'd like to ask you to help for us
to define the concept of smart cities
we're going to be talking about that a
lot today so what is a smart city what
does that actually entail and how do you
retrofit an existing municipality to
make it smart yes we we refer to smart
cities in terms of adding digital
intelligence to achieve better quality
of life outcomes that's that's really
what it is about and that has three
layers it has the most commonly referred
to traditional technology layer which is
about networked sensors and devices
which is also then a good part of the
retrofitting say cameras along the
streets to give an example but it is
also very importantly two more layers so
one is or the second one is the data
analytics and applications without which
the sensors and networks don't do much
good so to give an example from from
crime incidence if you had use the
cameras for instance for gunshot
detection that would be an application
and data analytics but then thirdly and
as importantly it's about usage and
changing behavior so to stay with that
example if you then deployed for
instance predictive policing where you
know from the big data analysis there is
going to be some incidents or high
likelihood of a some incident in an area
you actually massively change their
crime outcomes in the city on that point
your organization becomes a global
Institute last year studied how dozens
of Smart City applications if they put
them to use how they would impact three
sample cities and I have to share these
numbers because they're fabulous
they found the tools would reduce
fatalities by eight to ten percent
accelerate emergency
times in those cities by 20 to 35%
shorten the average commute by 15 to 20%
lower the disease burden by 8 to 15
percent and cut greenhouse gas emissions
by 10 to 15 percent and those are just
some of the positive outcomes that they
found Volvo I know that the European
Investment Bank has created a smart
cities and regions initiatives you're a
real leader in financing projects like
this I mean with numbers like those that
I just cited you must have cities
banging down the door saying make us
smart we want to be the next smart city
so how do you choose how do you select
the cities that you take on and are they
always the largest cities are we talking
second-tier cities where do you see the
highest degree of success maybe just
taking a step one step back I think I
like the phrase think globally act
locally and I think this very much
applies to to cities and to local
regional development what we see when we
look at the cities is a kind of two
dimension issue on one hand cities
represent as you mentioned a big part of
the global population according to the
OECD forecast by to some 100 it should
be 85 percent of global population
cities generate approximately 82 percent
of global GDP but on the other hand
since these also generate sixty five
percent of co2 emissions so you can on
one hand see the challenges in terms of
environment in terms of transport I
think the mayor experienced the
transport in Bratislava this morning and
some of us as well
he made a good experience and of course
we have issues related to related to
migration to social cohesion etc but on
the other hand also you see cities as
real sources and hubs of innovation hubs
of dynamics for economy and this is
something which you're going to utilize
also through financing and supporting
so-called smart cities concept the way
how we define is the best we don't
differentiate too much between the big
small cities and actually when we did an
analysis of cities in Central Eastern
Europe we came is the conclusion that
the market gap which exists in terms of
financing in terms of potential are
so-called second-tier cities so there is
if you were you were to fill the gaps
because we are public Development Bank
so our role is not to replace commercial
banking and the private sources of
financing which are available but to
really focus on those gaps because it's
the end market for us small city second
30 cities it doesn't mean that we
exclude rata Slovak sure we have very
strong as man knows very strong
cooperation with Bratislava and the
capital cities but we believe that there
is a huge potential in the second-tier
cities area and for those we are trying
to create so-called innocent platforms
basically a way how we pour resources
and how we work especially with the
National Development Bank's to provide
bigger pools of money which can be then
translated into financing for specific
smart solutions for for cities and
regions interesting so andreas I
understand that BMW back in 2010 started
a very interesting project you started
dialoguing with cities around the world
about their problems and looking at how
BMW could perhaps help them with those
and so over that time you visited some
three dozen cities and you most recently
been looking at the issue of mobility
what were you hearing as you went around
the world and talked to these cities
about their struggles what did the BMW
Group learn from that yeah I think you
could thing and thanks for for being
here thanks for making the drive drove
down last night
yeah Berlin I had to because my flight
was canceled and before I answer your
question just one anecdotal observation
that I had yesterday also in Berlin just
to show where we are currently you know
everybody talks about smart cities but I
drove yesterday through one of the
longer
streets of roads of Berlin probably six
seven kilometres long
I drove Volkswagen when I was a teenager
since then I've changed my habits now
Quinn's coincidentally I felt the
comfort and beauty of the BMW I was
sitting in but just to be serious here
so everybody talks about smart cities
when I drove down that long stretch of
road in Berlin probably every 800 meters
to 1 kilometer there was a traffic light
and yes you can guess I had to stop at
pretty everyone every of these traffic
lights so the status quo is not that
these cities are smart right the status
quo is actually that many of the
possibilities and potentials that we
have already today and not actually
utilized for whatever reason you know I
don't want to judge here there are
cities that do a better job there are
cities that do a less good job but you
know the basics at times are not yet
there and was nobility one of the issues
that cities were struggling with the
most when you talk to them well you know
we we did we did these stakeholder
dialogues in the with the attitude of
listening so it was not like you know
here comes BMW have all the solutions
don't worry anymore but we rather want
to understand what is happening in the
cities because cities are important for
us because of them reasons mentioned but
also and very much so because that our
customers actually in these cities so
it's about GDP it's about innovation but
it's also about customers so we want to
understand what they think but we also
took senior experts from city
governments we asked students we asked
the general population and clearly the
top priority for everyone as seamless
mobility so it's not about the actual
means of transportation anymore it's not
about - I want to have a car do I prefer
the bus or whatever I just want to have
the most convenient
probably the best priced and at times
also the least a mission-driven way to
move from A to B and that's the task
that we see coming really is to to let's
say to match different modes of
transportation in order to give the
customer the best way to move from A to
B what that means for a car company is a
is a question certainly for us right now
fascinating much I'm going to give you
the opportunity because andreas brought
up the the the issue that you had
getting here so how is Bratislava
addressing that the challenge of
mobility getting in and out of the city
in a speedy non emitting way firstly I
want to say that even if I very
appreciate it this new level of
technology which which city must be work
with I'm always very very careful with
expression smart cities it's always is
always and if we are talking about the
smart cities always ended somebody want
to sell me some software you know so so
in a way I prefer or in our environment
or group of people who are who are we
are talking on a European level about
the cities I prefer like thinking cities
or something like the cities who are
able to judge the best way or to find
the best solution sometimes is the old
school way many times these are the new
technologies involved and and of course
I'm glad you said that we are not
talking we are talking we are using
expression mobility as well that's the
main way also in problem but at least
our plan we are always using this
because in the end it's about how we are
moving from A to B in our city and
people want to do that
maybe with not so many money and in very
quick and safe wave and in Bratislava
the the aim is clear I'm the big fan and
there was also in my campaign that the
public transport is the is the way it's
funny that we are only like 40 50
kilometers from Vienna which is in many
many levels the best in the world and I
actually this week had official meeting
with
the mayor of Vienna so I spent the whole
day in Vienna and we talked we asked
them for three different workshops with
my team and and there their problem is
they have very good infrastructure for
cycling segregated bike lines but they
are not able to really get people on
bikes because the public transport it's
so good that people just use using
public transfer so this is the level I
would like to go it's not a bad that's
fantastic problem and I'm very happy
that we can learn from the best but in
terms of mobility cars sorry for that
but cars are just not not very in good
place right now in some cities are
looking at things like congestion
pricing charging you if you want to
drive around in your vehicle during busy
times is that something you're seeing
more cities look at your city might look
at I was actually living in London 2004
when they start it was the first city
new Europe congestion charge the time
was five pounds I think today is 1150 so
it's crazy how this regulation are how
strong are this regulation we of course
we are talking now on two topics in
Bratislava first one is congestion
charge but we prefer and we are doing it
are the just normal parking policies
regulations so everybody making parking
more expenses yeah American parking
that's it that's it I died I will never
use this but the realities I would like
to talk about the fair way have to use
the public space for example okay all
right let's give the mayor a break one
of the issues that so many cities
grapple with as they grow is is housing
give us your thoughts on how cities can
move forward in in that area because
that's that's difficult especially
cities that are already very congested
and don't have extra space yeah and I
very much like the idea of rather like
thinking than only say smart cities
because of course it's great to have
lots of sensors but
people if people don't have a decent
place to live and participate in society
and work life
there's no good so we do need cities to
plan for future growth we have the
stunning numbers on how many future
additional urban residents there will be
if the status quo is that already today
330 million urban households in the
world cannot afford decent places to
live and the gap between what they can
afford and what it would cost to house
them decently is 650 billion dollars a
year now for too long particularly and
say the Western world we have been
thinking about this problem as a
financial problem we've been trying to
throw finance at the problem and then
what comes out is what you see also a
London is a good example or say bad
example in that regard you throw a lot
of financing at the problem and at
people you see house prices rise
fivefold over too many years and supply
doesn't move at all there's no supply
response because the issue is a supply
issue much more than a finance or demand
issue and this is I think where where
cities need to plan forward to how to
accommodate growth that's kind of what
our thinking the city needs to do and
where to find the space for additional
housing and how to deliver productively
and quite often it's actually not as
impossible as it may seem we we didn't
analyze in in California which is as
everyone knows a pretty dense place
where people would say well it's also
difficult to find all that additional
housing and we all know it's a very
unaffordable place as well but just with
geospatial analysis to give it some
smartness again we found space for three
and a half million homes within existing
urban boundaries so so what our city's
missing what are they not looking at
that you saw yeah if effectively there's
a lot of unused or underused urban land
plots for all kinds of reasons there's
sometimes it's related to to speculation
and just
on the plates to wait for prices to
appreciate it sometimes because of
zoning or building code requirements
that made it make it too expensive to
redevelop and so on so there's a lot of
things that can be changed and then
there's the more say fundamental shifts
particularly moving towards dense
transit oriented development where if
you want to add a lot of housing to
cities of course you need the transport
to bring people in and out there is not
easy you cannot build massive new
highways in existing cities at least not
so it at good expenses but most cities
do have good transit hubs already so if
you increase the density around those
and increase it actually massively like
five to ten X rather than 1.5 X as most
people see this think about when this
thing densification then you find those
numbers of additional home supply
fascinating his puzzle on this issue
because I think obviously housing is
important where we see and as I
mentioned we are focusing very much on
market gaps where we see the need for a
public Development Bank to be engaged
and in terms of housing in cities we see
three particular areas one is exactly
the development of housing in the areas
which are difficult for the real-estate
development for example brownfields
there are many brownfields especially in
central Eastern Europe where in the past
you had industrial plants in the cities
themselves and they obviously have to be
dealt with from the environmental point
of view but on the other hand they
represent quite an interesting area for
real estate development see cleaners
happen develop so basically but it's
quite a risky operation obviously for
any developer because you also have to
take on your shoulders the environmental
aspects and cetera so there is a role
and do countries here they'll cover that
cost if you are developing the area I
mean we have several projects the most
recent one I remember is in Warsaw where
there was a brownfield basically old
industrial plant in this bicycle center
of Warsaw and the real estate developer
was trying to get commercial financing
for from the project for residential
housing and it was impossible because
there was just too much risk for
commercial banks in terms of the
environmental liability so so we had to
step in and take kind of fruitless peace
aspect and then private sector came in
so that's one area the other area is
so-called near near near zero emission
buildings this is very important for
cities especially in moving towards
clean cities decreasing the energy
consumption etc and I think this is
something where many cities are now
moving towards and the third area is
so-called social housing what were
dimension is really the fact in many
cities I think in Germany in their
demonstrations recently in Berlin and
other places because what you see is
that the cost of housing and of rent
Falls is going up
also things like Airbnb people are
basically renting their apartments for
for tourists and so on and all these
basically leads to the increase of the
cost of housing and rentals so there is
a big pressure and very simply supported
for example social housing development
in Austria in Vienna but we see more and
more of this happening actually the
municipalities and the local governments
have to take the lead in providing
social housing for especially for young
families all the families who cannot
afford to pay the current market prices
andreas I'd like to go back to talking
about transportation with you so as we
look at these thinking or smart cities
of the future etc and and as the mayor
mentioned what will be the future of the
vehicle are we looking at electric are
we looking at autonomous they just going
away as he suggested and if so if BMW is
working toward that last goal when
aren't you working ourselves out of
business so what we are doing right now
in terms of a strategy we are grouping
our R&D investments around what we call
the four aces
so that is autonomous connected
electrified and shared and that implies
what what the mobility will look like
you know it will be to a to large degree
or anonymous in in in cities and we are
talking here not a future dream i
anything like that but we are talking
basically you know when in the case of
BMW autonomous vehicles being available
as early as 2021 right so that is two
years from now I guess and electrified
is a is a is a no question topic anyway
you know that is no longer something
that people and cities do really think
about it is a given to a large degree
when it comes to their strategic
approaches but again you know look at at
the realities
how much charging infrastructure is
already available it's it's a big topic
it's a big topic in Germany I'm not sure
about what is love I have to say but
it's it's in many cities through Europe
and and certainly in other places in the
world it is a big topic and I can tell
you for example that for the time being
we fleet in into our car sharing fleet
we have Drive now it is called some
people will know it probably worldwide
car sharing operation we get more and
more electric vehicles into these fleets
and in in which and we arrange those
cities where we have this fleet running
that they built up the charging
infrastructure so it is a it is
basically a contract you know the more
electric vehicles we bring into the
fleet the more the cities are supporting
that with charging infrastructure not
only for our cars obviously but for for
all the cars often then trying to
utilize a public-private partnership
model in order to make that happen
and yes the future of mobility in cities
is probably not characterized in 2030 or
2040 by an endless number of spots you
till eternity vehicles SUVs that was
probably the point that you were making
you know that kind of an of a picture is
probably not the one that everyone
strives for also not we right we
understand that this is not
not sustainable but there's going to be
a place for the individual car no
question but it will be integrated in a
multi-modal traffic system that is you
know including sharing let it be bikes
or car sharing in general that the
obviously include public transportation
and so on I just give you one one
example from copying one of the leaders
obviously in that field where we have a
project running with Areva
we gave them they bought actually 400
BMW i3 so 400 full electric vehicles and
got them into a car sharing fleet and
the whole traffic system in Copenhagen
is is utilized by customers through the
so-called riser card which is a travel
card a way you can do everything you can
do back share and with that card you can
do back pick transportation you can do
car sharing you can do light rail you
can actually choose but you always have
the convenience of using that car to
open that world of mobility so those are
opens all doors yeah and that's you know
that's a data-driven approach obviously
you know here comes smart where those
thinking data that doesn't make sense
ultimately and it's it's not rocket
science as you can see in the case of
cop making it's feasible and we hope to
seem all that and we are going to be
part of that no question Matus annie i
be a survey and 2018 found that 70% of
municipalities consider fiscal
constraints to be a major obstacle as
they try to move forward with their
their future visions whether it involves
major infrastructure etc how are you
financing your bratislava plan that's a
difficult one
it always is I mean on the political
level of course it's very difficult to
talk about more density because people
are in Bratislava with with a very huge
developer development boom from 2000
after 2010 and so on as a very hot topic
but we are lucky because
we don't have big density in British
Isles so we still have a possibility to
grow in the inner city without before us
to do to build satellite cities or
outskirts which are in economical and in
a sociological way very bad solution for
for the city so imagine again I know
it's Vienna but if we are making
comparison with Vienna the size of the
two cities are nearly similar but in
Vienna they have two millions and we are
600,000 so so we still have a lot of
space which is important and Bratislava
owns still some of the space in own City
which is important as well of course and
we what we are looking now with my new
team is to have a smaller depth with 50
our depth like cities for 50% which is
we don't want to have have it more and
if we will be able to make it smaller we
definitely go with some smart financing
and you raise taxes to get to achieve
some of your goals or no that's that's
very tough one
of course we starting with parking
policies the parking regulation and we
we hope we will have we have some money
from it every year we need to see how it
goes and we have we have possibility to
to raise local taxes some local taxes
it's a possibility they are very small
in European level they're very small and
if I will be forced to do that because
of better development of City I will do
that and maybe just just as an addition
also we see clearly that ultimately a
smart sorry for using that term again a
smart way to do pricing also for
mobility for example is going to be also
a given it is totally needed and you
know there might be some revenues out of
that but even more important is the
signal to organize the city in order to
to make sure that the sustainability
goals and the development goals are
achieved so we will see very soon
and much more road pricing much more
City pricing excess pricing and we need
to do that in a way so that makes
ecologically sense and also delivers
what is needed and that there is a good
mobility performance because mobility oh
absolutely relates also to the economic
activities of the city it is a total
necessary t-too to have a good mobility
infrastructure in cities but it's
changing right now tripping on the
financing a question I think one one
tool that in my sense is under deployed
for financing city grows and smartness
and improvement this forms of land value
capture and I mean you may agree or
disagree I have no idea what the
situation and Vladislav is but the the
situation is that cities invest in
better infrastructure and better quality
of life outcomes and better amenities
for cities security all those things
that make the city and of course all the
real estate in the city much more
valuable and in most situations that
means someone who is sitting on a plot
of land for of urban and just waits
waits waits waits for the actor the city
to do its drop and then reaps a huge
profit when he sells or develops that
profit and my sense of a market economy
belongs to the city and good share and
that is big value and a big lever for
financing talk about financing I have to
say something now obviously what matters
mention mention is a big issue not only
in Slovakia but throughout the region
because you have this so-called debt
caps for on the municipal and regional
levels so the mayor's or heads of
municipalities and regions they have to
be very careful how much they invest how
much money they spent so that they don't
breach this debt cap that level and also
I think is something which is very
closely monitored by the citizens by the
opposition and so on so the question is
how do you finance especially larger
projects in this kind of constrained
situation one possibility is to look for
different so-called off-balance-sheet
operations where the financing is not
aggregated into the internal budget of
the municipality or the region we are
quite often working as the bank for
example with the different municipal
companies and transport company waste
management company etc which in many
cases is of balance sheet so basically
the financing does not go into the debt
structure of the municipality or there
are interesting structures for example
for the energy efficiency so-called
energy performance contracting where a
private provider of energy efficiency
when you improve the energy efficiency
especially in public buildings because
municipality cities they have many
schools hospitals local different
offices etc which consume a lot of
energy and you by decreasing the energy
consumption by improving the quality of
the buildings you save when a lot of
energy and also of course improve the
environment and so on so if you have a
private company which does it for the
municipality and invest into this and
then the companies paid by the savings
on the energy then basically this
operation is also not aggregated into
the internet so there are structures of
this type which can be I think in a
creative way utilized by by mayor's by
municipalities to to deal with the issue
of the limitations of the all the dead
break fascinating no we're gonna be
going to questions shortly and you can
either ask them in person I think we
have someone who will have a microphone
already to come to and you can also
submit them on slide oh and then they'll
pop up on the screen and I'll share them
with the audience with my panel and with
all of you I'd like to go to the mayor
for one final question mr. mayor I've
heard you talk about Vienna a little bit
of
and some of the things they have that
you might want to emulate II is that the
the city that that is the model that
you'd like to followers there another
one somewhere else in the globe that you
someday you know Bratislava wants to be
the fill in the blank of Slovakia what
is what is your ideal city I spent a lot
of times on different conferences I
spend a lot of time difficult organized
by Bloomberg or or Atlanta even oh and
and there are so many good examples in
the world and what is very good at Lima
feudin I mean I guess there was New York
it was a big inspiration of course
different scale different frame low
frame or legislative frame but there are
so many bright ideas of court coming
from there and I was glad that I
interview for Slovak magazine Janet said
he can for example she was a she was a
director of transportation director so
she was a director of Department of
Transportation of city of New York under
the Bloomberg and and what is good on
these different meetings of the mayors
that every every mayor is always happy
to share success you know if they are
successful in something they always
share so the ideas are are pretty much
always on the table and I always use
this expression that in art you you
cannot use copying you cannot do that
because but in doing the cities we we we
inspiration and sometimes also copying
some stuff is very very good it's it's
very necessary to do that and mainly in
any situation where Bratislava is now we
I feel bad so is quite a lot behind
other cities on European levels for
example also there are so many issues
for example we we didn't have open data
we didn't work with open data our data
which are every day we aggregating
thousands of data as a variant
they are not available for public there
so did this just start we can talk about
how many flats bratislava owns rights la
owns 945 flights which is absolutely
tragic tragic fact so we don't have
housing we don't have we don't have this
important instrument which is so so
important so this is one of my biggest
challenges to build new houses new
houses so there are so so many we can
talk about security we can talk about
the using of technologies for example
yeah also using technology for security
in the street and so I just as I said I
know this Vienna is on very different
levels at the top of the world but I
always like to learn from the best and
we are the actual Vienna Bratislava is
two closest capital cities in world or I
think so
so and we have a good relationship so
this is the where I want to go you have
New York but you have Brno
which is the second biggest city of
Czech Republic and they agreed they made
you in the last four years great work
with homelessness there was a working
the program called housing first where
you you finishing you stopping
homelessness giving the houses to the
homeless people not not not work now but
housing that there's always the team so
a lot of inspiration and and I'm always
continuing to see what's happening
outside of Slovakia and different cities
thank you well let's go to questions and
if you would identify yourself please
good morning thank you my name is Peter
Schneider I'm from the Slovak foreign
ministry where I am coordinator for
migration so that indicates where my
question is going to you've been talking
about challenges such as housing
mobility economic activity but only mr.
Hudak so far mentioned migration briefly
we know that big city is a large cities
are to a large extent formed also by
migrants the Bratislava is full of
migrants from all the corners of
Slovakia including myself but don't
worry mr. wallow I'm paying my taxes
here ammaji
the resident but the economic activity
and the possibilities of the cities are
of course attracting migrants when I say
migrants or migration I have in mind a
regular migration of the workforce
mainly how do you see and also taking
into account the name of this panel
cities driving for change how do you see
the role of the cities of the
municipalities in influencing the
national policies on migration regulated
migration of the workforce because there
are examples including Munich that
cities can actually achieve a lot and
they can make a change when the
politicians on national level are
failing or not delivering on the
migration thank you thank you I'll try
and certainly a big issue especially in
Slovakia for example where as we know
the regional differences are very very
high and many people migrate from the
less developed parts of Slovakia to
obviously Bratislava or the parts of the
country which are more developed and it
creates obviously a challenge for the
country itself how to deal with the
regional differences and secondly
obviously for the recipient
municipalities or regions how to deal
with this new group of people one thing
which we are addressing is as a bank
because one of the issues obviously for
this so-called migrants or new new
people in the community is the issue of
housing and and rental housing
availability of rental housing is
something which is very important it's
also very important for the labor force
mobility within within the country
itself so we have joint programs with
with different municipalities throughout
Europe European Union where we actually
support construction development of
rental housing which is in many cases
used is especially to target the the
commuting or the migrant population of
course then you have a different type of
migrants who are migrants from outside
of the country the issue is probably a
little more complex and challenging
obviously in our policies as the bank
being a public development bank we make
sure that any solutions we provide do
not lead to any ghettoization creating
ghettos for some groups of population
and and here I think cities can be very
very important drivers also for the
national policy because we do have you
know many discussions also in the v4
countries and our region how to deal
with migration migration not internal
but external and I think cities can
provide a good example how how such
migration actually can benefit the
countries and have can contribute in a
positive way to the to the international
economy thank you for so we have a
question here on slide oh and I'll go to
that of the question or Alexander asks
after decades of continued urbanization
is there any hope left for rural areas
what are the political consequences of
cities moving faster than the rest would
like to take that one Matus if you are
talking about the rural areas around the
Bratislava for example it's it's a big
challenge because we of course practices
growing very fast we have there is
Slovaks like to own own housing the Dell
like to be owners of place where they
are living and and what's happening that
that there is these satellites villages
or cities are built around the brightest
law but without good infrastructure
without good public transportation of
course so so it it means more cars
coming every day is to Bratislava and
and actually the consumer consumption
confirmation of the of the land is it's
just too big and which is losing this
kind of countryside and branches
becoming just one big urban sprawl so
against the density is the key word in
this in this case and we will try to
explain to citizen that the dense city
can be also good city doesn't really
mean that
they they will not have a green space or
they will no have a public space and and
use this land anyone else wanna chime in
yep let's see do we have any other
questions from the room let's go back to
any other ideas I can continue with
slide oh let's see well I think I
already sort of asked the example of the
second question regarding examples hmm
interesting
anonymous asks who benefits from smart
cities the most is there one segment of
the population that benefits more than
another thought I believe that
eventually the citizens benefit among
the citizens of the city or at the end
of the day it should be it should be for
the citizens and improving the
environment improving the the way how
the city functions whether it's about
transport about energy about waste
management but I think what I agree I
think that issue of smart cities and
calling everything smart is probably too
much and we like to use it because it
brings something a flavour of new and
being modern but for us what is
important is that value that for us
smart means that there is a strategic
thinking in the city itself you know
that we don't do ad hoc decisions and
solutions quick fixes just because it
has to be done but there is a strategy a
way how the leadership of the city by
also engaging citizens and this is very
important this goes in and shweet who
benefits because some time I think there
is a view and feeling that actually who
benefits are those IT companies and the
providers of different solutions maybe
some car companies who provide the car
sharing pooling and so on but I think
it's very important that behind the
strategy long term strategy there is
also engagement of people and for SAP I
always like one example from Krakow
is a city in in Poland beautiful city
and what they do to promote innovation
internally in in the city itself they
organize I don't know every year of
every second year but they organize a
competition for the most innovative
ideas for the city and it's targeting
especially younger people yeah basically
up to 35 and then they select the best
ideas and those best ideas which
actually voted by the population my
website a portal then those ideas the
top three also have to be implemented by
the leadership of the city so I think
innovation smartness is also about
communicating with people getting them
energized getting the ideas from them
implementing those ideas in in such way
and obviously engaging private sector I
think it's very important private sector
has to be a part in this process and and
it has to be part of the overall
strategy for the city itself yon how do
cities make sure they move forward into
the future that they don't leave one
segment of the population behind they're
developing these thinking smart cities
yeah I think the the more narrow scope
of smartness there is this is to an
extent probably than even either easier
to achieve because you have such a
magnitude of dozens and dozens of
different applications and use cases and
one benefits one segment more one
benefits another segment more thing in
the end everyone when benefits the the
bigger challenge are saying are they are
the big topics of urban development
integration with the more rural areas
around providing housing providing
infrastructure providing public services
at quality and I think we could we can
open up a huge discussion around all of
this but and in the end it's actually
it's mostly about good planning and and
of course also having the financing
behind the plans and I can offer allow
me that that one other comment on on the
financing and in that regard I
I'm really kind of applauding a lot of
those efforts on on finding ways to
off-balanced read and so on find all
kinds of financing cities cities it
still escapes me why that is actually
necessary why do not public cities
governments national governments have
balance sheets like every corporation on
this planet where assets are on the
balance sheet and if you have added a
liability next to it it's a wash it's
fine you can do it interesting I'm gonna
go to one more question here from slide
Oh from anonymous what role are upcoming
demographic trends in other words aging
generation on one side the ability to
work from anywhere on the other side
what role are those changing trends
these upcoming trends playing in the
strategies of smart cities and I know
Matus that in writing Slava you have an
issue with the population aging and will
soon be become one of the oldest in
Europe correct correct
of course aging is a big topic around
the Europe and European cities for many
years and again it's it's let's talk we
can talk about the on two levels
the first one is policy level so how are
we going to to make make are we going to
spend our money for what what what a
group of citizen in which many we are
going to use money and who needs help
and who needs our support and also in
Bratislava planned the aging and seniors
were big big big topic and and and after
you have a very very another level very
simple level and you can you can and you
can easily do it you can very easily
talk about what how to make a better day
for our more senior for all this
Bratislava has different cultural
programs for example during the day
which can be used we are now we're going
to make we're going to do a competition
for our own bench so we're going to own
design for a new purchase
Benj and the talk is that we are going
to of course do the size we're seating
is on on high of 45 centimeters but also
the seating is high on 65 centimeters
which is maybe looks strange but it's
much easier for seniors to step from it
of - so these are different levels and I
would like to embrace both levels
the high level of the policies but of
also the very simple changes in public
space on this topic because I think it's
very interesting aging is mostly viewed
as a dangerous threat yes because
obviously you have less population which
is interactive age which can produce
economic products etc but on the other
hand one of the fastest-growing parts of
global economy so-called gray economy
you have huge new segments of economy
which have to cater cater to the to the
aging population because most of these
people are and they live longer they
want to be active post 60 and you have
huge segments of services stories new
things which can be cently health care
which can be developed for this segment
of population so it is an opportunity
it's an opportunity opportunity also for
cities to actually utilize this new
trend phenomenon as a way to be those
hubs of innovation and generation of the
new economic developments and new
economic services address I'd like to
give you the last word before we wrap
sit very kind as I'm reaching now 50 I
like the idea of aging not being a
problem but actually an opportunity I
speak for many in the room I guess but
now I just wanted to add that in in
terms of mobility just to give you one
example autonomous driving and and aging
is again also an indication of how we
regenerate actually social participation
through technology right so
in the very near future you can take
that as a potential you can take it as a
threat as well older people will be much
more mobile just for the simple fact
that they don't need to drive themselves
but they are basically you know
passenger in an autonomous car or
vehicle let's put it the more general
and and with that they have the
capabilities to do more than they used
to and you know when you come from an
humanistic point of view that is
certainly the big advantage it has to be
dealt with because it potentially means
also more vehicle miles traveled in
cities so more more traffic but there
again innovation and technology used in
a smart way and can provide here the
ability to combine the social factor and
the intelligence but please join me in
thanking this wonderful panel I'm
andreas Matus Fuzzle yarn you were
fabulous and thank you for your
wonderful questions whoever submitted
them on slide oh they were terrific
we are wrapped and please know that
there are other sessions in other rooms
make sure and go in