yeah discern
forty-five minutes it's everything about
to fear uncertainty and banking
credentials
why I have chosen that title a willow
quickly learn or see and
if I put it on it will in were or not
I just replace it by your other one
and it installs to drivers device driver
software until 10 lichen
use tomorrow's okay my name's a generous
man
I'm working for a Swiss financial
institute and
I'm working their son I to security
officer so I'm
to pester to annoy at two to help make
them to the system or securities
just my a.m. normal day work just as a
disclaimer at the beginning
a.m. as a set I work for a financial
institute
so everything I say here is my own
opinion
does not necessarily reflect the opinion
of me employees here
a.m. all the credential type same
talking about the only man
asa example some no specific to
products so yes term
about the motivation I started Torre why
AM
wanted to give to talk there was a a TV
show in the swiss TV the some time ago
Boat of the Year something and they
thought that would be probably a good
idea to just talk about
credentials what our day way our day
like they are
have there are two the problems we have
if those
and them I thought it would be good to
do some kind of taxonomy to just raised
the bar to
so that 3 a.m. have to say McAbee Larry
to talk about term
credentials I didn't know
put like that agenda and them
I was halfway through and they recognize
step to making that exxon army isn't
good enough
so I am I thought about
doing as some kind of taxonomy but then
talk about TT credentials themselves but
you will I notice when you're there
just as a starter
why we're we in the mess today are in
this mess today where
are we talking about credentials or yeah
it said probably just a quick reminder
for you it's probably nothing you
but the main thing is but or two main
point is
we have that the problem for our I
between bank owned it
hardware or software and privately or a
customer own
harder softer in a beginning their word
is a ATM's
or someone in the beginning there were
dis- ATM's and
most %uh firm or anything of this
awesome
bank owned bank decided which software
is used which hardware issues
usually the the space to rent it was
banked by
rented by the bank so perhaps that the
whole spectrum offer security in their
own hands
physical and IT security a.m.
someday the customer-owned computers
came into the story
so there was two beginning of the I'm
online banking
and there was some some part of the
whole
firm system which was ten customer-owned
and so to cost them at the site it
what top date went well update to what
are going to use a sitter
now with a city in getting worse early
her for some other devices which we
don't really are you still
the we lose them here take them with us
them it's not getting any better but
lets a set the stage so what are we
talking about what this into solar
banking or online banking part what kind
of objects are dear
I a mate on my abstraction
and you see from right to left there are
two
banking service like the web server to
credential server or something
then the fireball the internet SSM
as a clout and
computer owned by the customer then some
kind of credential whatever type there
is
and the user itself and for this talk
I am focusing on
leftmost part mostly because
I just said okay the serve parted banks
usually know what they do so they know
what they have on the service they
hartnett 25 almost the same its bank
owned so they usually know what they do
internet that just said okay we use SSL
if it's correctly used a.m. should work
a.m.
on the computer didn't want to focus
because they're all the talks a
focusing only on that one as so I said
okay we go to the
credentialing to use our only so I try
to make some a credential group just two
to have fair am to go to have some
logical groups of these different
credentials and a start to twittershare
grouping by connection first I really
tried to do some
and some grouping or some some taxonomy
which is so
which could term have every
every aspect of his credentials in it
and then you could to just make some
remarks and
and have fewer for for one special type
of credential
to have fewer a profile this stuff
unfortunately work
am so Mitt much this grouping a.m.
drooping by connection means the you do
you have that
credential plucked into your computer
that would be the rightmost so you have
it
directly connected a.m. you have it
indirectly connected like a a flickering
solution
they do have some some kind of
communication between the computer and
that device and then you have thats
disconnected state
where am here you have for the
some kind of a calculator valued do
something with it
animator the next grouping by user
interface
there are some components with half
which half no screen
I like USB sticks or something and you
have some small correct output
like 50 a.m. term
calculator kind of things and there are
even
a.m. credentials which half a screen
like a
mobile devices something
and the last grouping inmate is Sam
by secret sewer with what internal stuff
this credential work
the said okay we have a shared secret
like term
and some kind of an itan
list which you share it with the bank
you have for cert fickt
certificates based the credential
or mechanism and to have for one time
pat
pace the a.m. mechanism
until you cum if he is there generate
Lisa
one-time Pat or one type also hurt
yourself
or half it to preaching to rate it for
you
beta by the bank
so I then them took his
different credentials we have to add on
to market and tried to place them to
tease
different term a group site just made
and again decide just examples so we
have
some kind of I 10 I tried to two groups
pieced together
Mayfair what kind of connection does it
have it is disconnected what kind of you
I does it have
some kind of table a.m. on what kind of
Secrets does it work
and them what that it's Dennis what kind
of attack surface
does it have so them
how could it be exploited how could it
be misused by an attacker
therefore TEDA turn it says quite clear
you could copy it
there were some cases where an attack is
just asked for am
just send me your next 10 a chance and
their uses a truly
a.m. pocket their I 10 number 2
next 10 to arm to that Web interface
so it's it's an for social engineering
it's not foolproof as well
I took to ask next example I took that
USB stick
it said directly connected it has no UI
its certificate based
and the attack here is Sam
I guess some of you hurts that talk by
Max
last year you could either do a remote
USB
so it just kinda from a remote computer
can access that USB stick
you can that connects a.m. the
the smart card to be a peak it KcsA 11
as an attack yourself so there some way
off firm
exploiting that the swell
then it took the DM ten use the
sometimes a by two banks its indirectly
connected to have a normal screen
it's the one-time Pat based
and it's not foolproof against social NC
engineering
same swapping the which mean SEM
somebody goes to Swisscom or whichever
am I'm
service provider and asks them to
replace his SIM card which Justin
basically
basically you worse and you have 10 his
SIM cards
the the attacker has your SIM card
and Canton receive fewer SMS's so
that again isn't foolproof as well
terrorists
again the somatic lecture and the
the last one I at it is a certificate
spaced
challenge response so that this a.m
indirectly connected as well you have a
normal screen
a.m. it has a certificate that's the
secret
ante at Tech surface here again is says
social engineering
or can be social engineering
and them this is nothing really new I
guess
so I am a took another step analyzed
this the different situations
and quickly noticed all of this
half either direct communication which
means
an its it uses the same communication
channels
that that the normal banking session
takes
are you have an indirect communication
like
TDM 10 but again you have tats
communication somehow
aunt a.m. that best %uh Fallis
the banks usually don't have to direct
connection
to decrease central and if they have
its usually not mutual so
did the endpoint of the SSL usually is
not
that trust device after of the bank it's
the computer
and so I am just another quick reminder
a.m. the computer is not bank account
to use other computers customer-owned so
there's no chance for the bank
to enforce any policies to to make sure
it's patched
it s their hardware you want to order
bank wants to have et cetera
so a.m. this means Altes systems
half her definition to say mattox
surface or
a similar attack surface and
a.m. at least on a higher level
and which means if if you have no trust
dense point
you have no 100 percent security
protection you can't have to
which probably comes quite a surprise
for all of you
a.m. but the best offer
of of Fallis a.m.
there's hope aunt this is actually at
that them
to basic short bass part of of to talk
am what this the hope what what actually
should be talk about what actually is
that that the part we should talk about
its an risk
the risks can be a chance term at least
at this what that that the business
a.m. some to business always talks about
but what's this this what does this mean
what this
what's what kind to firm
what what does this mean for US to
customer for 42 bank
at the first part that like to talk
about this numbers
let's let's take a very simple um
calculation
you have certain you are banks you half
a million customers
or million online banking customers
and that this means you have a
credential you have to release
these or you have to and to send his
credentials out
to your customers a.m. just a wild guess
the if you take some kind of
hardware Tamagotchi dingy
it will cost you 30 dollar store Swiss
francs
what which only like which means if you
have a a million customers this means
30 million your chest have for
delivering that hardware
for having it the air and for some when
replacing it
because this heifer if their pop that
tree the run
and turn to don't put them into USB part
a.m. some went back she will be empty
which means you have to replace this
hardware
so 30 million every few years
and there can be quite a few fraud cases
to
2 a.m. to to have two similar
expenses you have so actually when
talking about the about credentials to
you not only talking about security
you're talking about
the risk country talking about money
ultimately so
30 million is quite big number then
them
of course nobody will ever
that talk about fraud cases but a guest
is set
the thirty frankfurter hardware isn't
that far away or far-fetched probably
with some hardware it even more and
them probably if you only
the talk about hardware costs you don't
have to help this calls
cost them a switch callin to ask our
it's not working
at the replacements you have to have two
processes you have to have internally
so am as a set
we talk about a number so in talking
about banking credentials
the second term
point I'd like to talk about to say
reputation
have you ever heard about the company
going tits up bankrupt because of
whatever happened to them
except the task now
I i'm really talking about a company
which went it up because stay a
at a huge fuckup of deadlock in
or or whatever I don't know of any
probably there are some but they're
quite if there are
term they can't be that peak so
all that talk about who your reputation
et cetera is
in my personal opinion overrated if
there's really something happening
is that you won't ever hear about that
or
from perhaps it hurts the the company
but after year to 34 don't know
that's probably a over and nobody will
ever remember it
when I'm 80 slight I thought about ito
ay anti-choice
you probably heard that story early
nineties I guess
that was a Tory them which is that
them Drupal firm to know how to call
themselves
just 'em artists something and that
there was the company toys
and that's that they want to sell at
their toys sent there was that pick a
fight
between each other Andy twice isn't
living anymore so am
that's the only company I remember it
which really went it up because stay a
Mehta a brown decision but it had
nothing to do with
anything security the third part this
well i i written their am transaction
180 ring but it goes
much for them the when talking about to
banking system our online banking the
authentication is
up authentication is not the only party
so
we're talking about we're talking about
term
transaction monitoring as on back-end
processing some
what not am so only because
the transaction RTT deadlock in
a.m. was cracked doesn't mean to money
is going out
to the to the attackers it might but
it's not does not necessarily have to do
you probably were phoned up by your
credit card company someone in your life
they asked you are you really sure that
you want to buy now this
whatever and term they actually to
exactly the same
as to banks are some of the banks don't
know T
the others and to it's just a.m.
having a backend process which does try
to to find out the
if they're attacked or not so
and in to talk about I was able to
execute
that at that location or take over that
looking for you
that doesn't necessarily mean to monies
away
and a.m. what's also appoint this a.m.
we need to 2 a.m. differentiates between
the authentication and to all dressed so
I am
if your authentication fails probably
have some
transaction signing in in the front
entry really have to sign
all of your transactions so it really
have to say
okay I wants to do with this transaction
I will come back to that in
a little late
now that on fails as well I could change
again
until it works again to go to this link
am
also II sets now these three points
about term
yet there are other systems or other
mechanisms to arm
to make a system secure and my personal
opinion is that
every Frank for every dollar whatever
day get
is set is wrong so and my personal
opinion is
also we do this calculation I'm also we
have to do that calculation
what's to do and what this a what has
the better return on your investment
Asian if they have get that one frank
day a day arm supported so today I am
can move on and be davilla compaq
when it worked once they will come back
for second time
and so on so I am don't let them win
well to points to consider
there is some
will this actually that's pointy
usability and one is
a.m. what actually do the USACE know
what they do
in
yes you have that their credential where
you are logged in we firm
graphic art you place it in some kind of
card reader
as you enter pin and then you get the
china's response
kind of the communication wish to thank
you lookin and everything's fine am if
you use the same deweiss
for transaction signature and the usual
use it actually has no idea what he
signs he can't see it
he has stepped Adams he will get some
kind of number
anything but his signs that but s no
idea what he signs
even if you have the
better or a.m. another um
credential an say you have for them some
kind to firm
display something an where you cannot
display it
the amount whom to pay to the
mmm whether use this
today really know what they do do they
really know
what they are sign to to really read it
a.m. if they have to do it every time
they probably just click
through because said they knew it from
the last three hundred times that it was
correct
why shouldn't it be correct this time
a.m.
there you don't have for the
the TV to proceed under your control it
could be
anything on there Miko at hats
disservice
example this morning probably there is
some a notice which service
behalf that contest send us your money
and you will win a Wii
and the use it then wants to submit
that money he really wants it thank you
will make everything
that the transaction will go through he
will even phone up
to say you stopped my transaction
transaction white
so even that you have transaction
signing
it does not necessarily have to work
because of the use is the heat
he isn't able to to it he cites on
on the information if im or his tricked
into accepted anyway
a.m.
so there's the them this seemed a
question
a.m. some banks to whitelisting which
means you have
you first transaction to account a and
the second time you you sent to account
you don't have to a transcendent sign
transactions anymore
am this is only because the
date don't want to to make its too
common for use it to
sign their transactions otherwise it's
it's too common
and they don't look at it any more but
them
yet again this isn't foolproof
so that there could be some them some
fraud cases as well
another another point is dis here
portability is for canales actually has
some guy at Microsoft at that
but that because of their development
thing but they're I found to
sentences saying nice what it's like
an on Monday summer financial Institute
will release a
complete mobile banking client so you
can a
to all your banking stuff if to mobile
phone
which means the you need some kind of
firm credential you can take review you
can take fifty
that solution you can use if that
solution
them now firm USB stick
definitely won't work the in
you could have some keyboard on
I'm on a credit card that could work but
then you have to take the credit card if
you want
them this SEM this kind offer
move they don't like so if
if if ever you are at the conference
something's day show you
a credit card to be fair keyboard on it
just a to like this
a little bit and they will hate you
there
am you could have a efforts device
unlike term Tamagotchi like TM
calculator stuff something then you
always have to carry
a new device with you an an access card
like that the i-ten I shows before you
can have in your am
first that will probably work but then
again you're back
at that the i-ten which we actually want
to move away from
so talking about portability is really
problem what kind of credentials are
dear
you can take with you what kind of
credentials our date which still are you
support for the user
and still portable so
there are many credentials on the market
but
when talking about all of his points
many will fall out of your shortlist
or will not even trying there was
actually a talk before not sure how many
of you
were listening to it from Suisse com
twenty other am
just the room just before to stalk you
but it talked about
amo by Lady an again the you
you take it with you which is called but
them you have to same communication
channels like when in you do mobile
banking you have to same communication
channels for the banking
as you have for authentication assigning
which isn't ideal
it could work if everything works but
and it's not ideal so
really there is a is a problem what kind
of credential really works
and if you want to do a kickoff and you
have a good idea I guess this quite
much money to make do
them so
actually a.m. he could talk about
trusted devices
or we should talk about trusted devices
but then what is a trust
device am it should end
yes all session so it really is cleared
at everything you see
is a is legit make this is really art
I or itching from TD Bank and which
would be portable it should be a
user-friendly a.m. yet what is the
trusted device
probably you will will needs to update
that from
from afar as a you so you you need some
kind of firm
updating mechanism remote
access kind of thing which means there
is another attack surface
or at least a potential attack surface
if you don't make it updatable
a.m. probably will have to replace it
somewhere in its lifetime because he
found a buck
which you didn't find prior to the
rollout the
there were many ideas like a CD rom's
your you entered a CD-rom to your CD
Drive
and then you booted from that one the
at least you have to softer part assault
but term I'm not sure how many users
will use that you have to
shutdown your machine and two CD
booted again do your banking stuff shut
it down again
put it again if you owe us not very sure
if it's that usable
a.m. what they've seen is set this
that's twenty five dollar
or six British Pound now i guess its
dollar
a.m. computer a.m. could be a
possibility that
bank customers get the complete laptop
from their bank
just for doing am online banking
again you would have to to update that
one
so again another epic surface am
you see where this is heading to
so I am 2022 n that
a CNAME little bit or later now plant am
so you can have more questions than p.m.
this is really talking about credentials
is actually always because said it again
this morning
cat-and-mouse well there is rolled out
some when it's cracked
and cracking it isn't really wary much a
program
it's just a question of time and mostly
resources
and to probably knowing something about
it
so I'm at the end it's all this
calculating the risk
having a look at term at what this
possible
with what risks can you live what how
big will
the Los a speed and then the
you will decide which credentials the
rollout but every
credential I've seen so far is hackable
or the
at the end the user can be a can be
hacked
what social engineered into a submitting
to the TM
payment anyway so questions
this place
that the microphone
to post on the usability
and security office at bay City then
it's a business decision on how much
risk you want to take
as I want secure you tried to put into
the cost to an hour security due in the
back construction sucks monitoring
now if you look at the a lot of US
banking website still me ask for
username password don't have to stomach
which is top as you mentioned them
so Swiss banks most to make extremely
hard to login
for user he takes a lot of time but just
login because have all these additional
security settings need to wait for an
SMS into
you have ever types on challenge
response of which is extremely tedious
for users
so why is it that Swiss banks overalls
additional security
sings almost on that all sanitation side
if it in the end
so pretty I guess the same businesses
most US banks to
were apparently using password is good
enough for Citibank and
many others asked decision makes I
don't will you know I'm what I can say
is there was that term
yep actually it was some kind of
research for a day I looked at them
at companies being attacked and
that usually you just want to be a
little bit better than the others
its its usually an arms race if you have
your house
you have or are a few houses in the
street a.m.
you have an alarm and some kind of all
our machinery
stuff and other stone you probably won't
get attacked but the others 1 Pittsburgh
licked
usually so at the end it's just an arms
race it's
I'm a little bit better than the other
so the others are getting attacked
and this is of course
a.m. one of the points as well to
consider
what have the others house TTT
the landscape of the attacks how many
attacks to be half
at at all and then it's just a calm you
to take that into consideration and this
user name password
suffers are too we have to have
something else thanks
so in the end it seems the good old
paper i-ten
isn't so bad after all are wyatt bank so
keen to get away from that
the of again my personal opinion
one is a.m. transaction signing
won't be possible if that one so
and the other one is them you don't
really know
who you state so you have to to them
paper copy something and you put
actually copy it
and your life but use it to Sun a.m.
wherever
and you don't really know who used it
sites that
attack to sell asked for all the numbers
anti-u_s_ has entered all of his number
still uses which status
and mmm yet if they have some kind of
time ago today
at least can only login once so I
it really isn't that foolproof I saw
their
credential types are how many attacks do
you see
the
asks which but on a comp sculptor
talk about numbers sort with yes some
comment for the first question in
america
as far as i know im kinda you only can
transfer money
money to the to account of the same bank
or two
bridges to it companies so you cannot
a transfer money to some bank account or
some other banks
its restricted as far as I know this is
actually a good point
the that's also a risk or some kind of
risk management
you say okay if you login with username
password you only have T's features
are you have that limit on money order
whatever
and if you look in with the with the
stronger authentication you have a
higher limit or you can
we have no limit at all but that surely
something which will I'm
income over here or or even more
that there are some some kind of a
mechanisms like post Finance has stepped
onto handy payment
only don't know a few hundred francs you
can submit
from two handy without any strong
authentication
am I guess this will calm with
that the online banking as well but
that's only a wild guess
to follow
on what you just said i've seen a Swiss
bank
have different type accounts there were
people
our account with read-only their
accounts with
limited at privilege to send money
endeavor accounts to to n3 transaction
but not able to actually executed and
endeavor accounts
buried you need it to loggins by two
different people into the same account
to execute transactions so if you think
a bit out of the box
there is a lot of more variance would
you can actually do
so you the problem is not solved so
maybe there
other solutions week which could help in
your situation
I'm are you allowed to wear comment on
the protection of your new model and
solution
sorry are you allowed to comment on the
protection of can you move on. solution
you're
rolling out you may also be in line
what are interesting in most how do you
protect it
with these mechanisms we talk about this
later coffee or fear other accepted
but
place thank you the former
from a German bank account i've Eisinger
they have a very smart
a chance to sponsor meant to message
because
say that shares a in the input I have to
give to the external devices
a part of it is in receive your receive
a bank account number
and in -ism challenge and those bonds I
enter then
is based on that in Port so even if that
would be a man in the middle take
he could as it will not work because
people cause if you would in the
background change the recipient
bank account number the response I enter
would not to mention
but then it would fit right dusty using
know what he signs
yes it displays it it it to them
proms me to really check that what I am
entering is
his system what what system prompts you
it's the computer it's a computer I did
display I have to enter in the
external device a bank account number
sorus IP and a part of it
yeah but a.m. you know that does every
user of that bank no
that he enters the last few parts or
whatever of that
accounting number no as as example a.m.
you could have some kind of a screen
popping up after locking
which says a.m. this is some kind of
test police entities numbers
user angst is numbers makes
challenge response and your money is
away so I'll the problem again this
the user order/banker's no control over
to display of the usage so
anything could be written there and some
users
are believing it and RS sending their
money
because of that and the don't even
recognize house would think okay I agree
you had a slight for you
announced hope the new talked about to
risk management
I could you explain please what they
wanted to say if that is actually
a.m. most of the discussions were only
about
credentials and only credentials and
their will to want
safe that this SEM the whole
store it's not only about credentials
credentials we can't really makes
secure or I haven't seen one credential
which Kant
be attacked in one or the other way so I
am
di hope must be coming from somewhere
else or to hope for is a solution
and the only a solution I currently see
is risk much so at the end it's just a
numbers against numbers just
just the second until to Mikes coming
but this is to a risk management this
sucks for me s
end-user because if my bank I Singh said
we take the risk but personally I get
the tech today
it sucks or my pay not not since a.m.
to do you know for offer customer
which has to pay because of the
offer for cup of the system or an attack
na and a successful
as she I know one person she had to
had to earn yeah mentions that she will
go to
cousins towards if if they don't pay it
back so only if gaza
when cousins towards came in C they pay
to take
but it was was a pin code on its a.m.
teller machines
okay hit you
I want to say a similar thing your
bottom line seems to be a
nothing really works because much are
two users are
early anyway just to interrupt you to T
did thing I want to say is it can't work
because there's always an attack
yep but a message from the other side
from
client-side so I think there are big
differences between
the system's because
love I'm not so much interested in what
the other customers to
I might be interested in securing my
transactions
because maybe I got the money back maybe
not
any case I'll have a lot of trouble to
get it back so I want to avoid this
so I have a system but get me some
information on
on a display I can say okay I want those
key and some sumpin not into the
computer but I'm too
class 3 card reader or whatever device
so I gets something out of that system
even if u from Mar risk
find a few may say okay this works for
ten percent of the user's
and ninety percent on other so i i think
there are a lot of differences
I'll which are kind of your
if you've just say at the end the usable
always
are break it up because he doesn't pay
attention
but let's talk about alternatives that
there aren't really
at least for me a.m. the owner told
alternative I know it's you take your
money if you you go to the next
bank or post the bureau and to half your
am
suitcase with for your thousands of
francs and to pay it like that
for me it this isn't really alternative
to electronic payment
if I have a system but dismay
good security as long as I pay attention
to what I do
that's a good alternative for me and
it's much better than a system
I say okay of like like though
credit card system so they say well we
don't put in any security or they used
to say that
I'm be just reimburse you if something
happens so I don't like that
so much as a system I say if
II pay attention look after my money
I won't lose the money souls I think
that makes a difference
and also the the other thing with the
there
of course after update any divisive
we have to be able to update it so don't
think that's
kinda for on arguments to
to roll out security out everything
because I think the big difference was
after update a PC
every day in all the applications and
stuff or other half
kind of card reader which might have to
update
once in a while and I think there should
be a pretty good solutions to
to handle us I'll that's it's much
easier to
to keep your or your card reader clean
trying to keep a
PC clean but then your card region needs
to be the end point of two that
to secure channel of course of us can be
done yeah I guess there was some
question too packed somewhere
or not anymore
no more questions then a
thank you thank you Adrian