all rights you started
so I'm Dave Kennedy I'm I'm a chief
security officer at a fortune 1000
company I wrote the social engineering
toolkit
fast track and a new talk of artillery
arm
6 was the work ago there's
emina backtracked on Team that's where
the development team
and miss gonna penetration tester expert
writer much but other things
and so when I came over the stalk
I Y I i was looking at were and security
in a lot of things I see in the industry
and the penetration testing executions
and you said and that talk was
a lot about it by I get to see a lot of
unique things
in my position in life unique things
when I do assessments for other
companies
and so a pose a question to everybody in
the audience here
who here feels that they can withstand a
targeted attack against our company
so yes
this generation I get so not a lot
people
and so why is that why can't we were
standing targeted attack as
infrastructure as a as a national
industry and so the first thing is we
are secure
right we aren't able to protect against
attacks
or scared of guys like this
running around and we're worrying
during all that right
and reset their in the San hoping that
we were going to be the next ones to be
attacked
because we knew that our security wasn't
any better whatsoever
and so instead of being indicted in a
front of security
we prayed please don't let this be the
next ones to get preacher hacked
and I've noticed the security community
during the time love
loss after anonymous but everybody was
silent no one's at anything negative
about sign about him no one wins spoke
against them
it's really just a really I don't wanna
touch there because I don't want to be
act right
and sorry washing we waitin and we saw
different companies get breached right
saw more more MORE which
ironically was bicycle injection are and
more
and more and more and sorry a lot this
year
rain so we have a lot of bridges this
year we had a significant number
as a risk aired and so we hire
consultants
clickers really well to hire some
consultants Ryan
the fixer challenges industry and we get
the certs
do you give us more knowledge to expand
our knowledge
and we invest in compliance to protect
us
to secure organization right and we are
free we
prioritize what we're doing so we can
incorporate mismanagement
week re complexity with risk formulas
and we spend right
it's kinda industry right now so why do
we suck
well in order to answer the question and
I'll answer that question and I'll give
an answer I'm fixin
really need to understand the past
present future of where we came from and
security
as a security kinda started off a little
bit like this
you know maybe ten years ago or so
formerly and so before we had hackers we
hadn't
you know their national security
community would hackers come out and do
different types of things which can
respond the industry as we know it today
you start off with hackers and how to
protect against hackers and so
we came out to and so technology
progressed sorted hackers
and where is born in the security
industry
as you flash forward to today
this is what I've you today s right
it's a complete trainwreck if you look
at statistics from 2009 to 2010 if you
look at the industry as a whole
security conferences record a record
number of attendees
you guys here is a prime example yes
we're in here 10 years ago next
some remind me to get to the point tell
store but I wasn't here
and if you look at how the industry
started to
groan groan grow we had a record number
but any security staff
decrease during the recession is United
States and when up
when I spent an estimated one billion
just on security in Windows Vista and 7
which okay
on in 2008
sure looking at how we're doing for
bridge this prospective
the screen senator Carr privacy rights
that or and he does in a terse 354
reported public data breaches RBS
WorldPay is one of them has a bazillion
amount of social security numbers into
in 2009
there's only two nitee to so we got
better I
unfortunately there are literally the
largest bridges we've ever seen in the
history of like bridges ever
the largest amount a PCI data paji paji
everything else just got destroyed a
year
and say look at 2010 we spent over 34
percent more on security from 2009 to
34 percent more as an industry it
doesn't end there's five or ninety four
reportable within regions
over double that of last year it's a
good coverage statistics that's kinda
how it looks
right pretty graphs look at security
spanned
kinda how looks rain
and so we buy products protect us
we're the only industry that I know of
the King keep increasing
are expenditure expenditures and
continue to get worse
the second issue sorry weatherman other
first but
as in her head I mean I I was told it
was going to rain my entire way here and
a
has won the most obvious flights have
ever had in my life but you buy these
products right they're gonna fix it
by intrusion prevention hereby quicker
hospice jus intervention web application
firewalls voluntary my firewalls
anti-virus while listening blacklisted
magic solutions body scanners network
access control
and after a banner data loss prevention
anomaly detection her istics
shiny stuff right this is what we're
told to buy to fix
the crap that we have right now in
security
and all those a failed us because they
don't work
as anybody read the OP implemented
where one is why anybody here have it
working
as anybody do anything other than
looking for social security numbers and
credit cards
okay checking as anybody stop taps
even know if anybody is really had after
are
what that really is the gala getting the
cloud with the first 15 minutes use
playing with the cloud is
so we have consultants right and
consultants are designed to come in and
fix our problems because they know a
better than us
to hire these guys to come in and do our
security assessments in our penetration
tests n
our risk assessments in you know I it
not to pick on the Big Five
because we're they're all guilty of it
but they come in they give you this this
model of how you need architecture
enterprise security
arm program missus five-year plan about
how you can spend
a million this year maybe three million
next year minutes in a decrease after
year after year right
and I have not seen a company fully
implemented as anybody implemented a
five year plan a security before that
actually works
pigan on the same page is not unique
to somehow they know the business better
than we do inside our own company
and so can we spend and /span and span
dance band
because that's what we're told is gonna
fix our problems we keep throwing money
at it
we're gonna be good right
this stuff doesn't stop us it doesn't
it barely stopped her
that's where we're at right now it
barely stopped her
she's a mean hacker
so why
if you look at how our balance right now
there's is an influx of
crap that's going on between compliance
vendors and products versus actual real
security in fixing things
you know we have all these terms like
GRC an wrist the ferment in risk manager
programs in
and all these things that are supposed
to build our programs up mature it
and haven't seen one that's been
decently mature and yes true did that
today
when asked you how many have you can
stop a targeted attack
the answer was no and I haven't in
audience that would raise their hand to
that
never secure an hour and are closer now
and see this big influx a compliance and
risk management
and really were securities is tiny
little thing
we're not actually secure organizations
but people say we're in tune with the
business right
the May heard that before we know the
business when you know the business with
the business says you know it's just
like
hypothetical monster that no one ever
knows no one can own security
and that brings me to my next point
which is a very favorite topic of mine
which is the CISO MCSO
for hats I mean for for CIS owes in CSS
today
there purely focused on business
let me ask a question does anybody here
have a technical CS own place
couple to that's great it's going to be
the the way for the future trust me
think about this you have business guys
running a security program rain
don't be like me saying hey the have
legal
you don't need any law experience
whatsoever to run the legal shop
you can just talk all business Ian when
court cases
or hey head of HR you probably don't
need an HR experience
or hear general you know you to do need
to be a troop
you need to know how to fire a gun you
mean I do a estar because you know
you disfigured on talk all business in
and so this year so since yesterday our
business folks not security folks
they do not know how to secure an
organization now again
%uh explain how this works in the second
but they buy in the binder binder binder
by any wonder why they have a breach
they do not fix things they buy things
they sell risk management programs and
GRC
in deal PN and APT
you know all these different bus times
whatever happened to be going on at the
arce conference at everybody else's song
that that year
is a terms that we use in order to you
build our programs up
and so we'll see about tech our business
savvy CISO since you're so does is we've
needed them for a while because we have
no idea how to talk
as security people we've never known how
to communicate to the organization s
explain what we're doing
what I can tell you is we don't need
them anymore
ross is your the next year so
mark my words you have to be the next
year so
if you are at risk route seriously
and think about it I mean where we at
right now in security
me were very immature industry
10 years we needed the business folks to
help us out nationally establishments or
security
now we can blow everything they did it
up and start from scratch initiative
right
and why say that is in on us when this
but
you look at the business and help
businesses make decisions
it is make decisions on what they know
I says hackers have a very tough time
communicating
anytime information about security to
where they feel comfortable love what
they know
and that's what the business guys can
make a minister in all these different
formulas and risk equations in
are GRC and all these are things to you
hopefully
changer for them rain when they were you
making decisions on security anymore
that point
risk the ferment seriously
I'm gonna transfer the rest to the
business really
is there going to secure organization in
any way shape or form
whole we need to do is communicate the
right now the easiest thing
is did the word the business just
communication
talking in the labor to the game
understand that's about it
and he may be saying hey how my
qualified say this
so here's how you guys know me right the
social engineer talk it
or the 10 the device order the $10,000
spots customized
you know or on some code that I rode or
me giving hugs the people or you know
me talking in front of people so I'm
hacker
right Chur we don't see
is that mean issue doing stuff like
meaning in biz in a meeting I actually
holding meetings and having meanings
within the organization
I'm you their CEO Garcia for every
single week I'm you there see on a
monthly basis
a report to the Board or sitting in
but really important news reaction make
decisions and stuff
I'm CSL a fortune 1000 company
I a budget with capital expenditures and
expenses
I'm you to see if only get three
stitches the board I can I can talk
about that
we actually have a working security
program I can say they're
I miss you we actually fix things in the
organization
it's not perfect but we actually tackle
issues that are important to the
organization
you don't have this risk acceptance
model we don't have come a little risk
management processes
we are viewed as a business in Hanson in
the company
competition look at this is like wow
these guys are awesome
we need incorporate them into what we're
doing Ross we're screwed
we don't buy billions of dollars of
products we don't need 'em
we rely on people rely on the people in
the business
to help us we are our motto in in our
segment our company is a
securities a.m. an individual ever but a
team responsibility
and it's true holster within our entire
company we have funding
we have funding by ask 4 I get it
me but I said that kinda
songs going so here has agreed budget
staff
one imminent to many of us
so for those either don't have a great
budget and staff and wanna be next year
so sorry
like that I can help you with an in
Issaquah topical bridges
we are terrified of a breach and
security rain you look at breaches as
the most horrendous thing that can
happen
water is bridges can actually be a good
thing for your
it almost takes a breach any company for
something that actually move
actually inject security into the
culture most people I could care less
about security within the company
it takes it actually takes a culture
change or something like that the work
and so come to the realization in your
security for no matter how good you are
you'll never be on a per cent secure
period
in most cases a breach will not destroy
your company
there's been too that averages that
went down in under data data nor and
like 19 2006 was only two companies have
ever
proper bankruptcy you specifically
because a breach so most cases nine and
out on you not me breach at TJ Maxx is
reporting record number of
a profit right now if you look at their
their stock options like dip
will Rebecca recovered easy
so sometimes lol I also do you sometimes
a bridge isn't as bad as it sounds
you can help us so
you guys can get security budget
experience breach
I'm serious on a and socially two
options and experiencing a bridge
option 1 as you get popped yet Sox
can't really control it we use that
opportunity
to change the culture and the company
use that opportunity to make sure the
business understands how bad it hurts
when these type of things happen
because it's gonna be inevitable you're
never going to be a hundred percent
secure all time
and 98.9 percent you've already
experienced a breach just don't know yet
so experience that in use that for your
benefit don't be scared don't be like
man I'm so sorry I can protect
organization listen debit 103 F in years
to do this and this is what happens when
you don't
use it action to
which is probably most preferable a
similar to bridge
does it actually experiencing a bad one
you can also simulate for to penetration
testing
zulu years had a penetration test them
before
get us a question again in about three
minutes
a penetration test today annual about
about this and NP testers
not what is designed to be today's
penetration testers essentially a
vulnerability scan with validation
testing on top
which means that Iran scanners to deploy
to look at any type of
me are passing might have added eight er
a misconfiguration or something that
they've developed in their scanners
to detect a possible exposure and from
there
the penetration tester will go into next
with the Spurs reportedly that scanner
found
how is that a simulated breach
not thank you you that's awesome
participation
a penetration test is always been
designed and should have been always
design
to simulate a national Thacker simulate
a breach
and only thing that your company cares
about period
is its ability to generate revenue and
some penetration test should mimic that
how can I actually attacking
organization exploit them and hurt them
so that there they can no longer
generate revenue alright
impact the revenue so much that age is
really jacked up their company
that's what up and test designed to do
they're designed a seemly a bridge
period penetration test equals bridge
simulation
thats it similarly to breach you need a
jacket company up
bad macomb hurt you need to make her
she lost be able to show how you guys
should destroy their company and
in Chris nickerson seasonality in a on
he the specter believing arm he is the
the
the rationality of you know break into
GM does it was a better explanation I
can ever give but
no break in a GM you hack into a
manufacturing plant instead of them
making
GM products they start making for
products so
I mean that will check their company up
beyond you hit any type of
you know comparison you ever canvas art
trying to sell for products and from
from a GM made are manufacturing plant
because
millions have a different as an example
zedi my company you know future
projections
I'm schematic summer our product lines
are things like that are in were big
services company
so if you target any three of those
different types and
avenues you're gonna make us her and
that's what we do we target those
business units
to making show pain so again who hears
had a penetration test number four
hands went down quite a bit
and so let's look at
packing today if you look at the
evolution hacking Wii's
me someone start off with social
engineering we can I went to you
the network layer doing what operating
systems in with the web applications and
we serve a client side which Adobe still
getting hit and then
arm from there you know who knows if
it's any copying or whatever but it's
kinda back at the the social engineering
mom part right now and i wanna touch
briefly on the cloud every time
every time I see I have two drinks at
one right now as to you
so the cloud for me
is like taking a big chance and it's
like
going out there and throwing your data
somewhere we have no idea that have
controls in Iran and
and you just basically taking our data
moving out and this is the terms and
services
are taken from a cloud service provider
and why it is important because this is
pretty much identical in every saber and
form to any time a cloud service
provider the provider you go with
and saw misread a om the
read parts here that the service is free
of viruses or other harmful components
any content downloaded or otherwise
obtained through the use of the Service
download is
or at your own risk will be solely
responsible for any damage to your
computer system
and loss of data to result from such
down their own arm is also a part of it
here that I like is our
I unwrapped it or secure that any
defects or errors will be
be tracked in I mean it just it
basically dissolves the company any type
of legal liability whatsoever
for putting information officer from
in his clout in a swerving all over data
should have gone back about 10 years and
security with the cloud so what now
you look at
the future security we have a long ways
to go
when it comes to actually protecting
ourselves against
attacks against targeted attacks from
not anywhere near to be able to handle
even the most simplistic any sequence
action
is 13 years old with a teenager in your
if you go to any OS meeting or you go to
any web application security won the
first then they're talking about a
sequence action
thirteen-years-old buffer overflows are
before I was even born
no personal happiness
so we have a long ways to go
when it comes to actually
securitizations and it's gonna take a
real big fundamental shift
and how we're doing it and it's gonna
take technical people like us
to run it in my opinion there's there's
to roll type serve
love CISO czar CSR's you could have one
that's business Sep jerker focus that
can actually communicate
but he understands the technical
abilities are the people to actually
secure their organization
and so his only purpose is to be the
chief sales officer
all that guy does is forms of out to the
executives to get more funding
any less technical people build the
program to do what they need to do more
secure the organization
the second is the hybrid which is %uh us
the guys that are technical that
understand and agree to the ropes of
security
again as you start to secure
organizations but can also communicate
the same time it for you guys we need to
start talking to people
mara and talking their language
Sefo or CEO doesn't care about security
all they care about is a rest towards
the company
if you can shown in here interest to the
company they all
98.9 percent but I'm fixin because they
don't want to go down bernier
is all about communication so the future
it's really up to us could be this
quicker Sox it could be this
or you can step up and be the next year
so
thing that we need to do is we need
invest in our people and do some hard
work because technology is not going to
do for us
your magic product that is that box that
shiny in the closet that is your apt
preventer or your DLP Prevenar or
whatever it is that you're buying
is not gonna Fisher problems as
announcing that you don't need to buy
technology sometimes I mean
there's some really good technology out
there like a semi casual corley
essentially if what you do but where you
build on top of that as we start again
the meat and potatoes
things technology should use as an
enhancement to
a national program its miniature they
already have in their
you can automate some function on that
portion love
something that makes it even better in
most cases we cite a product and that's
our program right
orphanages impact change secure critical
assets the company
remove any type complexities you have
other throw away your risk for muscles
are bullshit
their bullshit risk formulas are
absolutely bullshit
they do nothing your company about one
attacker at three o'clock in the morning
is going to come in ACW
in or the fear-mongering what am i doing
well musher moderate seen
through a or five-year plans do you have
for security
and a secure stuff its
these thing that's a member for me is is
find out what your company does to make
money
just protect that as it the hairdo
think it's like I could I could mean by
five hundred thousand dollars for
from a big 5 to tell you that right
there is that other do in
invest in people guys and and technology
and get back to reality
has every day in my life
so that concludes my high level stuff
because as a caso I'm not a
just a CSM a technical person so I was
gonna she is breaking and shit so
arm so I want to show your
is it all their road which is new
version are now actually
called little thing called the social in
here talkin
and actually need to find mine well
tended to pressure a quick
but as anybody here use the social and
you're talking before the past it's good
to hear
maybe not firmly within reach and please
anyone know me know her so she undertook
a
great ca so
the social engineer talking for me is
probably the easiest way to break into
an infrastructure organisation
and why is that because humans are the
weakest link when it comes to you
penetration testing are now wifi a
million dollars in security that you
invested in your Sims right PS your
ideas your new hampshire whatever the
heck
ap Prevenar walser provider
all the stuff you guys bought when
I can just call somebody up impersonate
them first and somebody in the company
and having to come whenever I want to
and so I wrote this about two and a half
years ago or so
and it really has become a standard and
penetration testing as far as social
engineering gives
you guys aren't doing social engineering
as part of a penetration testing you're
really missing out
you're really missing a large Avenue
exposure that
probably is one the most significant
threats you have to face today I mean I
don't really even go for like
segal injection and I anymore I'd and
think about it like at Britain's your
days
before the guy user days in similar
stuff in
I don't wanna my computer and I'm
working on it but on you know
it'll take me about two weeks or so of
heavy fighting in reversing
and crafting an exploit up in bypassing
the witness protection mechanisms are
like that
Financial are in whatever I need to do
in order to you right that exploration
is too we saw frustration export running
a frustration for me
the pain in the butt and so two weeks
of doing this to an environment that I
hope
the other company has or that maybe I
just profiling and maybe a certain
subset the company has
in the hope that goes off they don't
have any others have a protection
mechanisms in place sucks
how long it takes to compromise in
organizational social engineering
a day and it's just me during my
dole you know diligence are trying to
understand your organization
how to make money a development pre-tax
income in assume
arm for social engineer so generally a
lot times lightning tens our favor one
for every like everybody uses it
and select elegant like the helpdesk for
example because urgently rotating door
with an accompanying their
you like to stay and help us for a
longer time people hate dealing with
customers in
and I raid you know people within the
company and so
you have new people coming in and out
helpdesk and so what i'll do is i'll go
on LinkedIn a look for the specific
company name
and others look at all the new employees
manager look for people that had
elevated privileges within the company
and all specific target them and so I'll
call them up auspey
main my phone number to appear like I'm
coming from inside the company
public am zone summer VP of Sales I'm
really trying to get this
website to work i've a two million
dollar you know polls online I really
need your help here we know can you help
me
and is a common technique with and
social engineers on anchoring which is
probably gonna uses once understand
India
but you know if i call someone essay hey
I'm vice president of sales I'm Sonso
I have a really big problem I just
planted in a car dude said Oh
hey these guys have for one isn't
importance but to you
this guy is in need of help I haven't
asked them yet for anything like that
but soon as I do is gonna do it Nepal
anchor
and is gonna help ya no matter what it's
very hard to get his democrats attacks
and so was set it couples technology
with the process of social engineering
and so well C back to you is
exports are great the fun there sexy
either awesome right
when you're targeting accompanied you
know they have a6
for ie7 or ie8 or Windows 7 64 bit or
Windows 7 32 bit or Windows XP or
Windows Vista
all these different variations that can
cause that's what not not to work
because there's rarely Universal exports
that work across the board because
they're very specific to memory address
spaces
within those individual operators
something even service packs
so why target those with exports anymore
I don't use 'em
don't use experts anymore haven't used
exploiting the penetration test when I
don't social engineering
in the longest time and reasoning is so
easy to use
things that are exploits that are
legitimate nature to do it
and so here set command line is also a
web GUI interface into a
and also to those few that that used
fast track in the past
IOM reported fast-track over into the
sand satins
class early so has all the attack
vectors with inset
now wanna do some slack the social
engineer attack everything okay
to as a budget different types of attack
occurs in here there's the
adrenal based actors website act like a
spear phishing wireless access point at
factors SMS moving
on a talented London Times attack
vectors in my favor won by default as
the website attack vector
and what was attacked by two dozen im
any use my favorite
portion would you have to read gradual
harvester which kresa harvester you can
go on klone anyone so you want to
it automatically read the post premise
for you and reject them back to your
site for sin and redirect them back to
legitimate site
so they never knew they were there so
you'd still our credentials from other
one is a job applicant ac
because everybody has job install and a
job Apple isn't
an exploit I can write whatever
malicious Java applet I want to you
and deployed on to become senior full
access person she wants a quick run
and a lot of stuff but I don't know that
really pisses people off a date would we
have to hit run
Ross they had like task ill II x4
hermosillo whatever because it doesn't
let them
so it's goin' slut that and since I
don't have internet access right now
on issues or is what template but you
could use the cyclone which you can
spawn any web so you want to make a
difference
and ago in New web templates and others
use Gmail's an example
and shipping it you're gonna
C
and giving it some to do all this icon
one second
to go into what's attacks java app works
like Warner
at school gym so on ago
read Gmail pullback reread everything
they possibly can
and then set you up a fake web server
that everything's are working there
now this is the corp are the new the new
version
senator is a new version of our Senate's
version 2.2 and I have a bugfix
so it's been about two months trying to
figure out this blog and I happen to
have an idea as I was writing the train
system over coming here and I end up
facing it some really happy about that
and what this new attack for to does
does does a much different as a payload
you can use
the one that a bill for Sat it's a
completely arm
custom our river shell basically even
has a lot of features like bypass you
see keystroke logging
arm as s is reversed tunneling are
in RTP all those two types of things are
already built into it
ready is one arm that thomas was born is
a developer on the the talk at
and this purely communicate over HDPE
natively
so thin it should be based protocol that
communicate over TCP in HDPE
Bass Pro cause hearing in ATP inspection
to get around that
on then you also have on the ability to
use any of the
Metasploit payloads now was the problem
with most were payloads
especially gave you guys know is it
gently Africa banners regards what
happened in coding using stuff like that
and a city bus different Rick sturckow
grab a mess by payload I do P accident
obviously UP actually
iran denies it quite a bit and then I
would on news on dr Stevens technique of
importing any
microsoft digital certificate into that
execute a ball
making it look like it was a Microsoft
signed: execute a ble
and that guy of around for a longer time
than a surgeon's more on that
and the latest version I put in our show
code exactly as I me from their shock at
exec
com people's skin arm shoko tech is a
small secure both like 5k
and all does it takes an argument and
you can inject
of America show coach a into memory
however haven't touched desk
such a smart a cute about that that
create basically uses red process memory
to you load a bunch of Neosho Kercher
into memory in it
creature major for Shell so that's also
in here but the cost for now the job
happened I'm shows you know user
show called execuse an example but with
the newest version upset
it does something really unique as again
in Matthew
Graber who figure out a way to
inject show kosher into memory for
PowerShell and so I rewrote the job ap
lit
to automatically detect on power shows
install and so soon as a quick run on a
job applicant effective partials their
it drops a completely custom on
PowerShell commands
onto the system that shoots mentor
percent memory never touches desi don't
have to worry bout
antivirus ever again ever no its cool
about this
as Regatta is image from a partial and
execution restriction policies
right so and Afghan 16
the guy I Josh Kelley myself we present
on how to bypass execution restriction
policies
in are you doing this document is like
now it's on a hacker anything
but we do is you take bomb your scripts
make shirts in one line so we can be
multiple lines can actually be
you know a pic script it on one line
unico to
you basically for encoder and the past
the encoded command parameter PowerShell
that allows you to sensual execute
gossip what I profess his research and
policy in place
so even if you're using the most
restrictive execution restriction policy
it bypasses and largest to execute
whatever you want to and the Machine
I'll give an example that nanosecond in
just to show you what it looks like
Apple attack does the system right here
right up there this is the encoded
string
%uh the PowerShot ac and so what happens
is
the index additional whatever website
you tryna
trying to you on klone katherine ann ads
primers on to the next page
and in a job app hold on Paul's
Preminger so it's unique every time
and it's good for Mac is he Asian
perspective to and Solapur those
parameters
and then at a lecture on the partials
the Tekken here's can with the code
looks like a little bit as far as the
partial stuff goes from Matt
is me so
here he just Tom you know basically is
an add-on that libros was
arm leveraging power shelter enumerate
kernel32.dll an atmosphere TR
CRT a DLL and then he goes in polls
arm shuttle premise here and there's two
best offer 64-bit 32-bit
it then interesa page sizes to that and
then injected into memory
and create a process for so never
touches desk not change is ron so that's
one line verses
many
some to go to website
you can see here that a look in feel
ever wish you perform as
gmail pops up change my appearance
obverse
a still process should yeah
issue to kill this bill process which
began that's the listener
out
are 29 at Madras as well I gotta
excess I so
we get gmail a pop so no one thing and
it's kinda funny is om
know if you cancel and they got an
amazing pestering
pops back up again
began even in a group in the game cause
a browser it's really f'ing annoying
and Om and so the driver Peter so
they're gonna click on the matter what
but but maybe more believable
about a year and a half ago when I came
out as a tack
you get signed the publisher name with
whatever you want to
using cell site ourself sign coaching
search right and so
after they get kinda popular people like
holy crap you can sound like Microsoft
and Google mean a real believable
Java like you know got really taken
basically than update
about six months ago that shows a big
unknown in the publisher feel
so what I did was I just went in
registered an LLC in the state of Ohio
Calder
my publisher and I bought a code signing
certificates
Go Daddy so you know the applications as
a singer has been verified the one on
the application
yeah sure of course any notice defaults
to always trust country from the
publisher
thrill trusting so soon as a hit-run
and as a lot a mathematical equations is
going on right now to calculate the show
code
arm in a sizable you see here now I'm
get my payload
offer partial you see here that I camera
chopper show and as migrating from
process partial to know that now
for a compromise version about every in
touch this through the job app with
am
now the second attack on Sharia let me
get my a handler of
as the 10 the attack as a visionary tens
is a mean after the 10 Z
good that's good rehashing mucho all
tough
miss get the Center for a bit
alright source
here
type a slow and
with the tens years says the computer
chip here to differ miles it in the post
close-knit into smaller size
that's the thing we're you can buy a
frumpy RJC dot com
and thereabouts are now 13 bucks or so
and what's unique about this is it's it
you can leave whenever you want to she's
using ordering a programming language so
it's got small processor in your number
memory
what's cool about it is it emulates a
mouse and a keyboard
that's why it's important is the
bypasses Arun
you plug it in at MIT keyboard has a
more stores I think about things that
you can do
with that thing you downloader and stuff
like that which is gonna call
all we did is we are we took our went to
Best Buy me about a hundred our keyboard
but to 'em
miss keywords like the best keyboard
ever seen lighting is god-like
iTunes hook in with the much like really
nice liza back and you know it's got me
on my stuff
we senator to that guys and I T and we
did is we modified first we open up the
keyboard
we started the citizen in mind device
and so the key word goes through this
first and then out to
national symbol sending and what happens
is every time he goes through here
reset the counter right here okay so
some Press third letter D
de coser he repeated the back to its
original keyboard
and reset the counter all we did is
we if we detected about five minutes
been activity
in move the mouse up one pixel to left
so this means there is a kick on you'll
notice that
must moving and we waited about are
eight to nine hours have an activity so
when they're at home or away from the
other key word right
and what we found is we can deploy
payload at that point andropov a binary
at the system to this guy
and fully customize it without them ever
knowing about another funny part about
as a senator to itis
mean I'm getting four shells back in
four different people
so my guess is like that artery I see
guys going to cause they're jealous
about the new keyboards
which is what we do nineteen we still
good stuff and
so there he know surprise on our mission
at the gay stuff
no mystery a although the demo this
and this is using other new version a
set has the on PowerShell
mechanism on its you can drop this
interpreter into memory now there's also
no technical used to you
on the show got executive shocker exec
on over its hexadecimal
an alright its operating system and I
recovered it back to binaries impartial
so I just read a small parcel stop that
reason robberies in binary mister reason
hacks in rates are a binary it's really
easy
and Zara lighter disk drive a minor at
the system's much you want you
and the problem with only 10 zzzz art
has arm
yes storage capability our stores
limitations %um 64k stored on a
so we saw turn SD card to your own
native as the drivers into it so that
attendee native leary's the SD card and
doesn't mounted as an SD card storage
device
you can have as much room as you want to
you unattended device itself
another thing we did too is said
actually I copy it over just
reading I'm tired binary special art one
takes for ever we wrote a small stage
for that opens up a comp or entrance
through treachery initialize itself back
as a
as a comment after in transit or be
accom- so dry it drops of a multi
seconds
now here's this poppin
watch the match now you can make this
black guy I'm working on the the black
ok own
I gotta from garland on my good buddies
and a
has run a partial commanding code in
tonight I've been
I have a cairo is open if the wireless
and it's almost done
so it'll go and execute so executes
now overshadowing over here we can
interpret Shaw
but I ran the first disc Jamaica
so
good with all this and a lot more than
what I can show you but running out I'm
unfortunate luck will serve on a ship
fast track
on but nasa say this article stop other
you can do
if you look at my presentation one train
explain is
is not all bad we have a lot to get
things coming out love industry
it's just we have a lot of work to do
because we're such an immature industry
we have so much work to do in order to
fix our our companies and actually
protect against 'em
that it's gonna require a major change
in how we're currently doing things
cause major change who are in charge of
things in order to actually meet the
demands of what we're doing today and
security
the many questions so how did you
um addressed the issue of
security or just general quality from
like developers or the like
companies that use to you know program
store for you
and the question yep so it's question
was how did you address the
our mission is a concern drown things
that you program either internally or
you have outside
enemies our program for you as well
correct run application security
rate race level eso
what we did is arm for my company we
have developed shops or a place we are
places in India we have places
on in I am r-ohio facilities where
places in
arm Florida and what we end up doing is
we got injected so you look at who does
a soft lawn company
usually fall follows up to some BP and
then down to some
multiple are people on it kinda spread
out from there and so we had to BP up
first
and what we did is we injected ourselves
from the very early conceive men
other suffered on the life cycle so soon
as a new application a new version a new
something comes alive
were involved from the very beginning a
bit and then throughout the entire
suffered on the life cycle we're very
much involved
and so if you look at the National
developers we work very close to them on
a regular basis and ensuring that the
QoS quality
now in addition have to go through
yearly mandatory you education awareness
training right
we did ours differently we show our
developers how to hack
and so the headers testing by returning
don't penetrate things amish on 101st
code shown how you know how to actually
letter segal Jackson cover nice things
that's our user awareness because we
figured average good how about a much
more security stuff and I can really
care
the cash hack your own stuff we actually
use our life are hurled applications
have sought to do it arm
so you know it it's been kinda a
two-fold approach to that
but then before it ever listen
production we work family of source code
analysis and dynamic testing and we do
before to release in a daze a production
what we've seen is
we rarely have on any type of large
exposures usually minor things that
they've missed
I'm so we've seen a significant
reduction paper of it and almost
non-existent so sequence action
army Crossett scripting the things that
we start run into a little bit here and
there are more permission at I
attributes in
and things that affect so it's been
pretty pretty good just from that part
when it comes to actually outsourcing
their code we don't do it
we have in moved to the model of
outsourcing code development outside in
specific because it's a rest their
organization
are we find out if we move our code
outside to someone India or China or
things like deja
rate per much just echoed by exits
religious guy in your daughter property
and gone
and so is a decision a while back not to
do that I'll this
it was this is between us and the VP
that handles that the bomb inside a bit
and so we've been pretty successful in
mom
at least application security and
maturing as opera life cycle tours
premature
very question no questions
well they said
time figure much