good morning everybody for
for my part as well
it's good to be here saw been an
interesting trip for me but I'll wanna
I'll just skip all the details let's get
in today real meat of the matter
I think I finally made it
professionally after working twenty
years
in this business yesterday we were
looking at
some botnet command-and-control servers
and
I was not depart fire fellow researcher
to one of the
hostname study but that was connecting
to us
in kazakhstan sold top-level domain case
said
make got it but it sucks operational
right not to
at the IP address right right there so
good we haven't taken it down it's
idea how could I be angry about that
right to know
its most likely will a date raised the
same gang was operating Prado lap
earlier but and of course if you're
interested on who registered the domain
you can go and I'm check it out from the
Hui sits by Don Kodansha
from games will I didn't know
dung co lives in games will but so I
must have been doing something right I
guess
after working 10 years at f-secure I
gotta watch
Swiss watch Amiga nice after wrecking
twenty years at f-secure I get an extra
week of summer holiday my summer holiday
stuff I weeks which is nice
and of course the the logic for why I
gotta Amiga
is that the very first virus we ever
analyzed at f-secure
was called Amiga I know because I named
it
I analyzed it in 1991 and I've named it
amigo because it displayed to the Amiga
sign on-screen
and then we started a tradition that
when you've been 10 years with the
company you get an Amiga watch
so I know your thinking what I'm
thinking I
should up name the virus fair re: right
next time
but we all work
in one way or another with security
or computer security when we work
in security what we are ultimately doing
is that we are helping people people
obviously cannot hope to cope
with today's computer security problems
by themselves
I mean normal human beings can't do it
anymore it's way beyond that
if you look at just just viruses I made
up something that people used to know
that they were infected with viruses
would do something
no at the very least they would be
destructive people know that there's
something going on
because they are going to lose all the
files on their computers or the computer
keeps crashing or rebooting
or a virus plays music or shows funny
animations something like that well
today
nothing like that happens today smile
where world slow down your PC
won't crash your PC won't delete
anything will play music won't do
anything that you would actually
know it's happening you get infected by
something like the deal for
you won't be able to tell and even if
you somehow
learned during affected you will not be
able to get rid of it by yourself
so the end users need us that's
basically our job to help
the ones who called help themselves and
the best way for us to help the ones who
can't help themselves is to understand
who we are fighting
if we want to stick your computer's
sure we can run all the firewalls and do
all the backups and and do the patching
and
minnow whatever you you can think of but
thats actually
not going to make the problem smaller
that's like a band-aid
Mike it helps with the immediate pain
but dust nothing to read used
future attacks the only way to read use
future attacks is to understand where
the attacks are coming from
and try to do something to minimize to
the attackers
keep changing during the twenty years I
worked in this business they've changed
several times when I started
almost all the attackers were doing the
attacks for fun
for for fun for challenge for fame maybe
that's what they were teenagers hacking
servers for excitement
of course they are still at attackers
like that as well
but overall today I would group
all the attacks in 23 main group
we have first the wall the organized
criminal gangs who do the attacks to
make money
second a ball the hacktivists
and third attacks launched by countries
and nation-states that's where the main
attacks are coming from and I decided to
give you examples
of of each of these so
organized criminal gangs hootie
scarface right I do is cough is
are you are you there
good
this is not the kind of criminal were
fighting when we're fighting organized
crime
on the net we're not talking about
real-world of it we're talking about
completely new kind
organized crime in fact let's think
about organized crime
what is organized crime was organized
crime ten years ago
ten years ago organized crime loss drug
trafficking
money laundering smuggling stuff like
that
since that
over the last 10 years in addition of
that type of
international organized crime we have
suddenly
we're not only facing all this internet
organized crime which didn't really
exist in the sense ten years ago I mean
nobody was writing by rosies to make
money
ten years ago it started pretty much
around 2002 2003
and that means that the
overall a mild of international crime
house
just exploded over the last 10 years but
of the resources to fight
international crime have those resources
also exploded
not have in fact that pretty much
exactly the same resources we have ten
years ago
things like Europol and Interpol and so
we're actually doing a lousy job
infighting international crime when it
comes to online crime that's one of the
main
main challenges we have we pretty well
know what we're supposed to do was
supposed to use international law
enforcement to catch International
Criminal to put them behind bars
but we're doing a lousy job in actually
doing that although these guys aren't
real gangsters be like to look like
gangsters for tell these guys the box
website operating in some Petersburg run
by russians
specializing in buying infected
computers or buying access to infected
computers if you are a virus writer but
you don't know how
don't know how to monetize the computers
were infected can simply sell
the computers are infected to these guys
they'll pay you money
the money depends on which country the
infected computer is in
yet another one this is sad iframe based
called used to run in saint petersburg
its
it's been down now for a year or so but
it sort of gives you a good impression
of the kinda file
lifestyle these guys would like to try
to impose
virus writers you know right by receipts
make money buy a BMW
impress girls in of that kinda flushed
but is it really
like that is that really how virus
writers live
do they really make money with viruses
well here's a photo
which was found during for into
extermination of a drop site
a server which was used in operation
related to banking Trojans
while doing forensic examination that
this deleted folder just found
and that folder hat budget images taken
with a digital camera
one of the images this we try to
estimate how much money there isn't a
photo it around
one and a half million dollars yes that
looks like a lot of money but we have to
remember
but the value of dollar has been going
down so if the lifestyle of
online criminal tomorrow's writers
really like this well actually yes
it pretty much piece/pieces Albert
Gonzalez photographed
at the penthouse suites
of I believe the W Hotel
which is one of the most expensive
hotels in New York arm
this is his partner in crime mister
Stephen what
known online us a UNIX terrorist if you
actually go online you'll find
video of his Def Con talk from def good
Las Vegas from nineteen
I don't know 2.2 maybe something like
that he was the Aries photographed
partying
at the private pool of our
another expensive New York Hotel
of these guys of Fort a lifestyle like
this
of course they're not paying these bills
with their credit cards they're babying
them
with our credit cards to these guys are
america's
but majority of the attackers actually
are not in fact if you look at the
hotspots globally
of course russians all Russia Ukraine
Kazakhstan
bill Irish here in Europe maybe Romania
are moldova produces much more moderate
and that they should for country of that
size
arm China Brazil so on
curious to meet a callable from Ukraine
Rex next to being
Ludhiana chechen from the city of Botox
in Estonia
examples of the kind of guys who are
behind the attacks and of course the
mechanisms vary
but they are basically typically in the
range of
Roque under fire is ease rogue registry
cleaners which are
push to end users keyloggers to steal
credit card numbers
banking Trojans to move money around
from online backs
here sa the Swedish yards and Dean
together with his partner in crime
much article by jane from United States
these guys were behind
the IM you operation so the actual
coder school were writing the model
where these guys were using to become
rich we're all ukrainians
but these guys were not great news they
were running an international crime gang
where the actual code River ukraine by
themselves were
mostly in USA these guys are still on
the run
this picture is from Interpol pages from
the 13 pages
nobody knows where they are but the
secret service from United States froze
a Swiss bank accounts belonging to
Charlotte by Jane
around two months ago that bank account
had 14 docked nine million US dollars on
it
so the amount of money these guys are
making is significant
last statistics from Brazil
say that the Brazilian banks
lost 480 million US dollars
to banking Trojan attacks during the
first half of this year
for the somebody walking around on the
streets of Sao Paulo
width 480 million US dollars in their
pockets
think about that that's a lot of money
especially in Brazil that is a lot of
money
in fact quite surprisingly brazil is the
number one country in the world in
producing banking Trojans
Brazilian banks have pro the best
security mechanisms i've seen anywhere
else because the attacks are so bad
uneven
those mechanisms are great they are
still broken all the time
regardless of what kind of mechanisms
they've tried and they've tried pretty
much everything including
of course want i poss birch challenge
response bearish
arm up custom-made
job I interfaces for the online bank Jul
they've also tried secure ID chips
they've tried SMS old authorization
older and everything has been broke in
fact we saw last
spring one really really clever attack
against that Brazilian band called quake
struck
and that attack is so clever that
I actually cannot figure out a way on
how to stop
I can't imagine any authorization
mechanism
which would fix the problem and the way
that particle or
banking Trojan worked is dat first to
get infected
as usual you get infected by surfing the
web with your Windows computer you get
hit by a drive-by download because you
have
but on Patch I do get PDF Reader plugin
inside your browser or you haven't
touched Java or on patch to QuickTime or
something like that
but Munster infected the only thing that
the Trojan das
is that it waits for you to look into
this bank's website
once you login the bank's website it
doesn't modify your payments
it doesn't change anything it just
displays extra one extra page
between the login before you actually
enter
the back and that page what advertisment
advertisment which look like internet
British but from the back
it had the bank logos different
animations very well done was likely
done with
some at ages at the add
told the user that we have now launched
a new investment product the new
investment account and if you
put money to this account with it gives
you five to two percent annual
return on your investment and now during
this week
if you start investing in you invest
more done 2000 Riaz on this
investment account you get a free
Nintendo Wii
now there's an image of intend oh and
Mario animations
and that it continues to start investing
into your investment account please move
at least 2,000 Riaz
to your investment account number keys
and this
to people rate this and they see that a
great deal
as a good return that's not too much
money absolutely I want a Nintendo Wii
so now the user himself really watched a
movie
his money that is a cup
for the new owners click OK to continue
now they are in the real bank and they
really believe
it's a real thing and now day will be
themselves
going through all the hoops table be
using their secure ID chips are
answering text messages whatever to bank
is trying to do
to prevent back intro to need all goes
through
how do you fix that I don't know I don't
know
how do you fix credit card theft
I'll first we have to look who's
actually paying
for the credit card fraud in most cases
it's not
the credit card companies in most cases
it's the online Americans
who get get food with the bill once
keylogger steal people's credit card
numbers and a card numbers are used by
stolen car but buy goods like iPhone to
sell them further or used as credit card
numbers in online games like poker games
to move money away from the
accounts
one more example of banking Trojans post
bank in germany
introduced text message a all the
of the cation around a year ago and the
reason why danger dues dist
SMS text message on occasion is very
clear banking Trojans
seeing on the computer can change the a
college you think you are sending money
to
so you go to an online banking you think
you are sending 100 euros to your
electricity company to
debate your electricity bill at the
Trojan on your computer changes the
account the different number and
of of your goes of the money goes the
way they
decided to fix that is that every time
you send money it sent you a text
message to your phone
and that of course on your text message
you will see the real account number and
you'll figure out that you know
there's something wrong because the
account numbers don't match that's a
great idea
exxon foolproof can't be hacked right
wrong this is what the real page looks
like when you go there from a
claim computer when you go there from an
infected computer to page
Changi turnout explains the you that the
bank has introduced
another new security feature which is a
mobile security app
please give your mobile phone number
here so we can send you say hi to
control a
a security control program running on
your phone and they have a version for
Android for Symbian and BlackBerry
and then when you install this on your
phone and continue
doing banking from the infected Windows
computer when it triggers
a text message to your phone this to hit
Heights controller will intercept a text
message and reply back at yes
please move the money and the user never
even sees the message
so the game of cat and mouse whatever
obstacles we can throw in the way of
these guys take a bigger a way around it
just like I mean lockpicking exactly the
same problem even the best
mines in the world whatever locked they
can imagine
of course it can be picked everything
can be broken if it it can be hard but
it can be done
right
so what about
group number two online
social activists groups like an animal
scripts like LulzSec
I'm in charge at
f-secure for what we call trap a threat
assessment
program which is where we tried for a
custom future try to try to see where
we're going to come up with
to plans on how to how do how do be
ready for future changes
and this was one thing that I missed
overall
we were trying to think what could
happen in the future we didn't really
see this happening this has been a
fairly rapid change
a year ago of course anonymous existed
but they were not know where nearly as
active
and visible as they are today a big part
of this of course is related to
WikiLeaks and just like other than us
Weekly has been around for years and
years five years or so
but they'd word really very visible
under un until they started leaking
information related to US government
including the Iraq war files and the
embassy cables which we made them a
high-profile
operation which of course cost: into
problems after Visa and MasterCard stop
money traffic
in donations to WikiLeaks as we know
very quickly and in a must took offense
in that and started to large-scale
denial of service attacks against
Visa and MasterCard and quite
surprisingly shutting down
at least briefly but really dumb anyway
both with a dot com
a Moscato by the way was I dot com runs
and above aka by
so it's it's actually pretty interesting
that these guys were able to china doll
with fairly simple attacks
there's also one lesson to be learnt
their
at the same time when the develop
service attacks were
targeting is a common MasterCard com arm
the same attackers also try china doll
papal papal dot com
this paper had also shut down donations
to WikiLeaks
a papal the comp didn't go to their
system for good enough
no problem so what did the beat the
attackers to
well they look for alternative targets
and they found papeles
block which is running at Pay Pal block
dot com when Pay Pal
had been securing their systems they had
made
the conscious decision that the crucial
resources Pay Pal to pub
that's what we have to protect our block
is not crucial
and of course it went to and of course
that's not too bad but that's not the
way
the media sort if you go back
and repaired lines for February what the
media was writing that
be sup boss to cart and Pay Pal were all
down
because papal block was to and there's a
lesson to be learned here like when you
are securing your systems
you have to secure even the even the
business which
art actually important or otherwise
the public and the media will assume but
you were taken down even though you
weren't really taken down but was taken
down in this case
wasn't crucial in any way so this is
arab are
who used to be the CEO of HB Gary
federal
security company which was specializing
in producing consulting and
products for US government and
one thing they were specializing in Los
intelligence-gathering
from social networks soul
me to bar got interested
animals and infiltrated Adam Walsh
which wasn't really that hard when you
just find the discussion boards and the
IRC's a new goal there is one of them he
had multiple different personas and he
was there for several weeks collecting
information and
intelligence nicknames IP address the
stuff like that that he goes
a given interview about the topic to
forbes where he explained that he's done
all the senate gonna
give a talk about this at the b-side San
Francisco
in at the same time with the RS a
conference in March bad idea
he gave the interview Friday he was
supposed to give a talk on Tuesday
he never gave the talk because during
the weekend between these two events
his Home Server was hacked
his Facebook but act his Twitter was
hacked
is gmail was hacked HB Gary Federals
website
was defaced HB carry Federals I
file server was hacked and their email
server was hacked and the attackers
published the whole five-year history of
the email
server in fact they published on a
server here in Switzerland on I don't
leak stop ch
it still online today right now anybody
can go and search
the whole five-year history of this
company for anything to interested in
including
all the private emails all the
confidential emails
all declassified emails all the email
exchange between the US government
and HB Gary Farrell is right there and
that's a pretty devastating attack
that's good example how ruthless
a group like this can be when they feel
threatened when the attack against
somebody day perceive on
as a threat
his photo I took at the RC conference
for HB Gary were supposed to have a both
they didn't they canceled their both and
he do in fact here it says that to
they are gonna have both because in
addition to the day the theft aid
its bigger individuals have received
numerous threats of while its
so they had to cancel double
so who r these people
well there's been quite a few arrests in
I think six or seven countries I think
the total count is low 160
people arrested arm this is from Spain
was spanish police arrest date:
like 16 Adams activists and they
basically get a press conference that
you know
an animal has been arrested no problem
is now over
and the next day for some mysterious
reason police ya
dot ES was crashed with denial of
service attack so
wasn't that simple
but if you look beyond just the fact
that there's been a rest and have a look
at the okay what do these guys look like
so here's some of the people have been
arrested in United States and it sort of
the kind of guys
arm or USA and UK and it sort of the
guys you
you're expecting like you know angry
young men right
but that's not the whole story here's to
more much upstate is such a crazy and
Valenzuela and its Mercedes rene hofer
she's 42 she's 20 not the traditional
angry and Matt at all
select a seven day is like this they
themselves sa we are all
and so we roll members about animals
anonymous
are members of an animal and this is
it is the next generation that's growing
up and it is D
this is the way it is protest thing has
changed
and it's not going to go away
for the last group we are criminals
we have hacktivists been we have
countries launching these attacks
when will
talk about attacks launched by countries
a nation states there's
a range of things like espionage spying
spying has completely
almost completely moved but the online
world because but what is buying
spying is collecting information what
information information is data
of course it is data now spying used to
be
something where you had to physically
enter a building to poppy papers because
information what on paper
now it is not on paper now it stayed at
which means you can reach it
at least in theory from anywhere in the
world so espionage
is one thing then we have a tax like a
government attacking their own citizens
examples from Iran examples from Germany
buddhist trojan or starch trojan or
whatever you call it r2 d2 and then we
have
for the lack of better word things like
cyberwar or or lime warfare
of which we haven't really had the ring
very good examples yet but we will
military has changed
at a great weapon
like troll tanks at your enemy that's
gonna do
I can't explain day which I just found
it online but I your
I'm fascinated by the mechanisms of this
so
espionage is both a dumb but targeted
attacks and targeted tax means that you
receive an e-mail
which is commencing you receive an
e-mail from your friend from your
colleague from your customer and it
contains
attachment which is relevant like this
example that a PDF file which were sent
to a
a technical engineer at a defense
contractor
and the PDF contents are about
high-efficiency dc-dc converters
which is what the guy was working with
but its Trojan eyes by the time you have
it on your screen you've already
been infected by a back door which
connects from your computer to an
outside address
whose whoever is at that address has
full access to a PC
a full access to everything you can
access in your local area network
and we've seen a lot of these have
another PDF Converter Pro John
in another PDF contains a Trojan yet
another PDF
called it a Trojan yet another PDF
contains a Trojan
another one well he's actually a word
for us not all of them are PDF
believes are the most common one still
this talked about some units have
meetings
contains a Trojan here's an excel file
contains
fairly realistic looking content but it
contains a Trojan
another one here's another PDF file
is another one sent to an Air Force I'll
general this is a Word file we found
this
like five days ago that we have these as
well like this
this cont was not all of them are like
business content
I don't know who she is but it was one
of the files we found but two weeks ago
contains a Trojan and so on and so on
and so on
to PowerPoint for and we do see the
whole different languages
fears Russian this is German spike in a
system
lies to smack Mar toward a star of
my German is rusty but look fairly
convincing to me
I don't speak Arabic but I'm convinced
that's
fairly convincing as well so who's hit
for this is Alfred noble
of a noble d-nev the guy we have a date
dynamite and
because dynamite ended up being used in
wars he
got a bad conscience out a bit when you
get older so we created this Noble Peace
Prize
so who won Noble Peace price
a year ago last year must
a guy called lucia both this guy right
here
a Chinese dissident who were not able to
pick up the best price
in person because he is under house
arrest in China this here
is Noble Peace Prize to orc which is a
website running or slow
at pretty much exactly a week after
is peace prize was announced this
website was hacked
was hacked as somebody inserted a
drive-by downloads
with one lot of JavaScript to every
single page Noble Peace Prize dork and
that
one might have JavaScript launched a
attack with a zero-day against Firefox
so if you with the Noble Peace Prize
with Firefox
you get hit by a back door which get
access to a computer
one of the administrators of this
website
investigated the case found out about
what happened
cleaned the site did for a sec
examination analyzed how they were
breached
fixed everything unless the exploit he
did a great job overall
in fixing in fact he did such a great
job
on fixing the problem that he got
invited the Noble Peace Prize ceremony
he received an email
an email sent by Alex Gladstein from
Oslo Freedom Forum in New York which is
a real organization and Alex Gladstein
really
exists in fact my I called up mister
black but I spoke
about this with him and he confirmed
that yes that is his email address
yes that is signature nope he did not
sent his email
and the attachment an invitation and
Noble Peace Prize ceremony
doc pdf if you open up the attachment it
is a real
invitation to the real Noble Peace Prize
ceremony
and mister class then confronted yes
that's a real invitation and
yes it has an exploit and it has a
Trojan so weird that the attackers get
this file
great question I mean these files don't
exactly flowed around you get that
Google for an invitation to the Noble
Peace Prize ceremony
we don't know where they got it from and
even better question who's behind this
attack who launched his attack which
country
launched his attack I dunno
Denmark maybe because China has
always denied any involvement in any
ESPN Arsch
or in are online attacks on my wall for
any of that
but they did run into a slight problem
earlier this year
this AM TV channel called CCT 7
in China which is TV channel run by the
government
for topics related to agriculture and
military they published
a documentary about online warfare
earlier this year and it's like a 20
minute propaganda documentary where
too general to explain the concepts of
cyber warfare and and how to defend and
how to attack and all that
fairly normal document but there's one
interesting part of the documentary most
likely by accident
they ended up leaving this one snippet
like a bee roast me but in there
which very briefly show someone opening
up
a Chinese application choosing some
settings and clicking a button
is lasts like five seconds but we have
that translated what does the
application actually say the
applications says at the top
it says Papa right people Liberation
Army choose a target
here start at least he too was one which
has an IP address and click the button
which is
attack and the IP address is in United
States of America and that this is
my friends what I call the smoking gun a
know better what they say the fact is
they have written a program like this
and it is copyright pela and a show
is themselves on and propaganda
documentary they make themselves which
was paired on a government channel
when we found out about this
be we put it put it in our block we've
be
guess that it's gonna disappear if the
document is gonna go away from the
website
I did disappeared from the Chinese
website two days later
hasn't returned so most likely these was
some sort of a goof they weren't really
supposed to make this public
but they did so what's happening right
now
well last year was the year of Stuxnet
which is the most complicated milder be
ever seen and as you've read from the
news two weeks ago
and you Trojan called ducal must follow
a ducal shares a lot woodstock
chairs code but even more importantly I
think it shares
techniques including the fact that it
has
speed uses signed kernel drivers which
have been signed
with real certificates which have been
stolen
from companies in Taiwan Stuxnet
it this do go dust is in fact one of the
drivers used by Dougal
arm is
to has been published by company called
Jamie crown which is a real
company in Taiwan and Jamie Kerr was one
of the drivers
signatures Houston started as well I
believe
80s connected if not done by the same
party well one theory we
we do have is that if stocks it was done
by US government
it's like that they didn't write
themselves the out started to a defense
contractor of some sort
maybe it is that company or maybe these
individuals from the company who
participated in stocks the devil open
doing something on their own
maybe its debt we don't really know but
it
isn't shredding duco is not a word
stocks it was
were made for spreading around the world
to go isn't spreading
be found only a handful of infections
one of them in Hungary arm one of them
are in a country icon name 67 of them in
Iran
which is interesting one of them in
this country that Iran this is
shugart in Africa
so we have and you Trojan with links to
stocks met which has infected
servers or computers in Iran and should
I
what is the connection between Iran as
to dock
well if you go to the US Department of
State of list of countries that support
terrorism
this four countries on this list cuba
Suria Iran answered on
now this is probably a coincidence right
so that's the enemy we're fighting
we have big organized crime
we have activists then we have
nation-states
and while it's fairly clear that you
know to fight crime you use police
it also has clear that to fight attacks
launched by other countries you don't
used to police that's not the task of
police if you look at the real world and
one country goes into a war against
another country it's not the police
but handle step right it's not a crime
its war so we probably shouldn't be
expecting these nation-state attacks to
be handled by traditional law
enforcement either
that's not their job
but one thing is clear: we've probably
seen
only the very beginning all of these
problems
and it's highly likely the situation is
gonna get much worse before it gets
better
and that means for us working in
security
well there's job security in securing
thank you