on my name is properly Polski
as though
Renault he sets virus live in Bratislava
today will be speaking about
banking Trojans are
now as we as we all know armoured today
is about
stealing money that's that's a well
known fact
and they're actually as Lisa different
ways are
how the attackers can steal the money
from the victims from
are less obvious ways such as various
shady advertising campaigns
collecting the user's so browsing habits
stark
delivering targeted ops and making money
like this
indirectly or or the range
berries anna & example for banking
Trojans
its morse much more straightforward
approach where they would directly
rob the user all and target his or
online banking
system or payment system whatever so
world is it today's agenda these are the
our families that all mainly focusing on
you
and all I'll be showing our technical
analysis
or boss up for some other features some
of the more interesting features
all that I that I would like to point
out or
there the car our our interest hopefully
hopefully not too boring
I'll that'll add though are some
statistical
India but the prep prevalence
and about the distribution no the
malware
and during the course of the
presentation I think it'll become
obvious
are why it's important to deal with the
stuff and why these Mauer families
are significant so I'll
without further ado let's get to it and
as an introduction I think II
but this is why do about the zoo since
by I know
I will be focusing on these two there's
is so much said about these
and they've been around offer some quite
so for quite some time
are so only for the sake of completeness
some well known facts
are these from our families were rivals
at first our vendors use
all source codes were
or sold probably dole author stop
development
there's been some something like a
merger between these two families
and/or these now we're
these backing Trojans that use the
common are common techniques over many
the browser attacks
then when backs added second factor
authentication like more oh and towns
all SMS messages or they reacted with
using many mobile techniques
where which software mobile malware will
be forwarding
the security messages to the attackers
and I'll
variance of these were targeting or
Symbian Blackberry and Android platform
as well
also this is this is a screenshot from
an old
or spy eye boat builder over here you
can even see
the option to uninstall Tucson and on an
effective machine
and though even though even a zoo since
by I am
aren't that hot anymore I'll
there certainly still active they're
still active there
prevalent this is a screenshot from not
not such a long time ago
and it reads it we found this in a
packer
in a custom Packer for Zeus and it has
had he not
nod32 guys are less work was very good I
was really surprised has been over four
hours trying to fix the detections
but the better man still stands come
along little doggy cum a lot more
hahahaha
I mean come on the better man still
stands okay whatever
it was quite funny buying this message
into in the malware
but as I was saying up this this power
though is still out there or it's the
oats the Robin users
and I'll be 4i before I continue
I added some some statistics serve the
distribution
ok because do since by I another big big
girl all purple
our sector that's rest of the world
and these ones are turkey Spain Italy
Argentina up for spy it's quite similar
to Zeus and as you can see the
distribution is always pretty global its
Aubrey spread
all over the world which a lot will not
be the case in though
know in the main in the example that
I'll be focusing on later
well as those will be targeting mostly
Russian speaking countries
and also originating or from Russian
speaking countries
so let's talk about or RDP door be
RTP door an interesting piece of malware
our first samples were detected in 2010
and the way it works is that
%uh it uses our remote desktop 22
or enable the attacker to log into the
victim's machine
and the attack is pretty pretty manual
so
this service back to our winning able
the attacker to or connect to the victim
and they will that he will literally
have to watch over his shoulder
and awaits offer him to connect send
to enter some credentials and then or
misuse those
up for for that though this malware uses
so components a legitimate software co
pensive
thin soft between and also uses some
pretty pretty neat interesting
techniques
for bypassing some security mechanisms a
that has some techniques for
avoiding AB detection and for the Casa
two thousand dollars he would basically
be getting
but builder and the
access to an administrative our panel
and/or basically that's that's the price
you keep you can pretty much by this
malware
on under underground black forums and
that's that's that's the way the modem
our work today dub
criminals using it for stealing aren't
necessarily the same ones behind
behind programming and it supports the
whole scheme or
for organized crime
now statistics as I was mentioning are
the big blue part is russia followed by
ukraine and Kazakhstan and the in this
grab will be similar
or with so I'll all the other examples
and the reason why
these so these bad guys are targeting
these countries with this malware
is that they actually our book quite
similar banking system so they're able
or targets all these regions
at the same time with the same same
software
okay let's take a little look cool under
the hood how this works
up the installation of RTP doors pretty
simple %uh
when the droppers run on the affected
computer will send some or system and
information to the a command-and-control
center
and then the command in control server
will authenticate
are the infection and provide the
between all software for insulation
so this is what it looks like that's the
URL up there there are some but I D
that's being sent
%uh information about the system Windows
version Service Pack whether it's all
standard user account over
administrator account then the response
or
there's a standardized or protocol which
RTP doors using starting with this web
tag and then there is an our command are
which is basically sending
I'll sending though components of the
beat when software
are to the infected computer and then
or India then though a client will
respond with status information with the
installation was successful or not
and right there it is that every
everything went okay
okay I have a little demo showing you
how
are the attackers actually steal the
login information
offer the computer and
this is this is how it works it's
installing an extension
upward gino raffle left graphical
are authentication
so infected though machine on a virtual
replicator
that's the sample that was run Rd
petered out a
now we're were checking in record it or
where the appropriate
all registry entry was made for the
Gina extension
and there it is Gina D lol is showing
two XT gino
dodi level which is the extension or
drop by the malware
was that ends what's months that
installed will
re start the system wills
fire up poor Wireshark
on the host so we can see what its
sending out what's what is communicating
enter
the password username is is
administrator password is password
switch back to Wireshark and
wait for it
moment surprise
and there it is user name administrator
and the password
followed by the computer name and the
fact that it's an administrator account
so using this
simple yet effective technique though
attackers are able to get the log in
correct credentials of the victim
and then using the between are
components
they will remotely connect or to the
computer and/or the advantage of using
this between
between software is that so is that so
that user will not actually be logged
out every session
so he they will literally be watching
over his shoulder
and waiting for him all to Axis Bank
obvious that these are some of the
commands of from the protocol
RTP doors using or the Morse
more interesting ones remember are that
was from the installation
are used over there up twenty
r is for between back in action knows
initialization
are with their function one already
enables RDP door
or to deal with an 80 and then the you
command
or is used for updating the modules of
the malware
so without the you command or
a new dropper with the new configuration
in bed inside
will be provided very simple nowhere but
so quite effective actually are showed
or
is something similar or the price on the
black market
is is also quite similar %uh its the
emo or Bush shoulder and dole RTP door
are quite is or pretty much the same the
attacker
will be all trying
trying to or connects to the victim or
through
with remote access but doesn't use
between or software this time it uses
TeamViewer
which is again a legitimate application
and the
and the the advantage of using a legend
application that is signed
all one advantage is that so
it is able to avoid suspicion it is so
sign components
so with up at first glance appears
pretty legitimate and the second up
second advantage is that so using
TeamViewer adds another level
and enemies into the club beat service
statistics
again quite similar
before Russia Ukraine Kazakhstan this
illustration actually shows
on how the TeamViewer or connections
work
so first or the affected so host
the affected by what would cut contact
the team York router squiggle press the
cloud ID
up the crowd though would reply are then
this so I D
will be set on the client and then
all due to the infected though by the
infected binary will or the militias
binary will connect to the shoulder CNC
and send or the TeamViewer credentials
to the attacker and once he has that or
there's nothing standing in his way to
connect
to the computer by a the TeamViewer
infrastructure
articulate taken little loco under the
hood
up these are the components of a
legitimate ones
that's the team your eggs in TeamViewer
or DLL
are with them our put in place is a it's
our TV DLL
which X as a proxy deal all basically it
does some simple
ordeal hooking and all this is what it's
all looks like inside the deal
are these are the functions of the deal
there be poked this is where the
original TS dealers loaded
are the function hooks are installed
down here you can even see
are the command control URL are
these are the BOC BOC manse that's all
shoulder is using there's there's the
though ability to download and execute
additional modules thus greatly
expanding
all the functionality the capabilities
of the malware
or there's a cool feature to delete all
the files
to hide his tracks and stuff like that
and though as I said
I'll well this malware is not only
for all technically skilled people
up any anyone any criminal basically is
able to buy this
and/or you crime using these tools
so this is a screenshot from moreover
user perspective
on this malware this was taken after
or a takedown of one of them wanna the C
and C's
and what you can see here are the
different banks or which
though which the malware is targeting
these a Russian banks I bank
BSS be as bees bear cetera et cetera
okay car burping car burp on like
the previous two examples is slightly
more sophisticated
and the price tag also or confirms that
sits
it's more expensive and
to for this price what will what will
the law client the criminal be getting
are is he's again getting an access to a
boat builder
to an administrative panel and/or
this this malware unlike the previous
two examples
works differently this is a much more
sophisticated and advanced malware
are it's not your eyes there are plugins
for its plug-ins which are targeted
directly at specific banks and depending
on the model on the modules the plugins
that you're buying
on the price will depend on that and
also
or the amount and the level of support
that's right these or
people are are also providing support or
for this malware
our technical support and also stuff
like they will provide you a new variant
once or these so but is being detected
by a bee engines
and stuff like that so we're in another
another important of fact about Harbor
is that is not its
also sold on about four hours but is not
thought to ever also it somewhere close
circle
well as I was that it's our customizable
to target specific banks
and the way it works similarly like call
Zeus and
spy I is that using man in the browser
techniques or
its installs or the dll's
injects the OAS into Internet Explorer
and Firefox and
its it is really a grant of Trojan there
are real world incidents
are where usage of harbor porpoise
proven
and these are cases where millions of
dollars were stolen
so statistics other two pie charts
or this time the last time I did a
presentation on Harbor
office at the chart used in again Russia
is the in the first place followed by
Ukraine
but the point I was making is that this
time our car burp
attackers are expanding and
attacking more globally there's Ukraine
is followed by Spain
and the United States so it's not only
focusing on
on the russian-speaking region and
then when I updated this crap
with his presentation from April 2011 to
present it's still the same graph as
we've seen with for
Russia Ukraine as it's done there in
fourth place
so previously I was saying that okay
there
globalizing their broadening their
horizons now what they
they're going back well the reason for
this is an actually that's
all they're pulling up pulling away
from the global markets but they were
actually
the reason for that is not that there's
less the texan's
are in the US safe harbor but there's
much much more detections
in Russia for example missus though are
these are time statistics
up for russia as as you can see at this
period of time
May and June love this year it has
increased rapidly in the reasons for
this
is that several cyber criminal groups
are behind
our car burp so basically more people
have been working on this more people
have been
using it there were changes are in
though
in the people behind that and these
changes are quite visible during our
analysis of the code as well and on the
bright side though
or other there have been also of you are
successful takedowns a command control
all servers of for car burp which were
coordinated by
or group IB which is the main company
are doing the investigations of a cyber
crime in Russia
are assisted by the Russian police and
about the
most visible or impact that it had on
the on the
sections %uh is between November and
December where there was quite a
dramatic or
or decline thanks to the takedown of a
couple for C&C servers
okay these are the book a man's that
corporate is using to put out
point out or sum up the more more
interesting ones
are theirs the kill user option which so
is there to better cover or their tracks
for the attackers where the the whole
winder
Windows user account would be deleted
and thus making forensic analysis is a
bit harder
Kerber as I said it is it is much more
sophisticated than the previous two
examples
it has some more pretty nice or self
protection mechanisms are it has
techniques were backed by passing a BME
laters
all such as doing many calls over gaya
PI's
and no code injection method has changed
between these two versions
of Carver before he was using the EE
reason thread
I'll the later version was using the BBQ
ABC thread
are the later version also I was using
an encryption algorithm
for encrypting its commands and the
strings inside the binary
are it would do better a better job of
authenticating
all on the CNC so what will be much
harder
to infiltrate the botnet and carry out
an investigation
and a couple a couple of other or other
tricks import as well some basic
coverage good techniques for hiding in
the system
detecting the hoops all installed by a
bee engines and
on installing them on hooking and stuff
like that
now as for the distribution all the bad
guys either 100 handle
it themselves so that it should be
directly were
the basically there would only be paying
for the traffic or they were distributed
by partners
all the typical paper install schemes
or partner for the programs and a
typical takings for disturbing my were
used by Harris
SEO infected blogs try Bart drive-by
downloads
and up and instances where up the impact
exploit pack was used
were quite numerous as well
okay so here's here's again a user
user's perspective
all of the malware know this is a
car burp control panel as you can see
wouldn't come we didn't come up with the
name ourselves
are the bad guys named its and though
to put out the more the interesting
parts here this prefix column that's the
affiliate ID
so the attacker will actually know who
to pay
in their paper install scheme as you can
see here
its they're a bunch of zeros in the
right column so this
sea creature was taken after a takedown
above the C&C server and are here
there's there's the bar the controls
for controlling the individual pots all
there's an option to execute commands
and
a remote shell stuff like that
here's the back settings up the control
panel
the interesting fact here is that so
some limits for the train to
transactions can be made so was so ok
banks
aren't suspicious if large amount of
money
is withdrawn at at at a single in a
single transaction
and I over here you can see the
different back to the car Berbice
targetting as
targeting as you can see these are only
Russian banks there's a jazz BC Uruk
their net or banks in the Netherlands
Israel
germans park %uh sir all latvian banks
so pretty global pretty global targeting
the harbor
and also after after those takedowns
that I was mentioning
are we we've seen all the stolen data
that was so
that the attackers lay their hands on
that was a lot of stolen data
this is this is a screenshot of over
7,000 cab archives with sensitive user
information
inside them all it contain all the
information that
that the attackers were interested in
asking charts loading zone banking
credentials key logs
and stuff like that for different
different payment systems cyber plots
I back internet banking client used by
different banks
another one this is a Ukrainian bank
okay so let's go in let's compare
up the difference stealing tools as a
said these are these are basically
weapons in the hands of criminals
for stealing the victim's money and I'll
as against as as I said before carb is
the most technically advanced
I'll add it all up these and is also
its horizon that and the its
the scope that it's targeting the
country's it so much wider
up the functionality that is using for
remote access is different in all of
these three
a coverup is almost twice targeting
specific banks
and over here all the information doing
has to be done manually
the complexity above the cold or when a
reverse engineering
obviously is the most is the highest
with Carver
and the similarity between all these is
that they all form but let's
got obviously these aren't the only on
our families
all designated for this purpose apart
from all those that have been mentioning
there's
she's there which is our one of the
first
sophisticated though banking Trojans
targeting
banks in Russia perspire NBS but cyber
which as the name suggest
targets though cyber plaid payment
system and I week
which is starting the Kiwi payment
system
okay and lets let's not move something a
little bit different gets
very closely connected to all these
and that's hot pot
statistics again pretty similar
now hotpot is a downloader so it's
it's it's a tool which which cooperates
with all these
Mauer families that I was just
mentioning there were instances found
were hot pot would be
downloading RTP door shelter or plot
cyber car burp
and others and though it isn't it isn't
up
simple Trojan downloader either it
features some pretty interesting
our techniques or summat I forensic
so methods and basically
techniques which are or doing mosier
making our jobs
more difficult and it's been associated
with real-world incidents
where a lot of money was stolen but
let's let's take a closer look at the
technical details
a pop-rock so or the insulation its
it starts becoming interesting from the
very start
unlike the simpler are backing trojans
which would after installation
first directly contact are the CNC
not on the witness download updates of
it cetera hotpot
first penetrates the system better we
settles in
before it before it starts doing its all
its dirty work are
it consists of several modules all
I'll describe each of them %uh in
greater detail
yes and techniques for bypassing AB's an
intrusion prevention systems
are its using the at print processor
trick during the installation
now for those of you that our are
following our analysis
all probably know that so this isn't
unique and this was inspired by some
malware before so who knows which power
that was
check if you're not asleep yet
that's TDL the famous or all Murray
kriti deal rootkit
are which or which is well known for
using this trick
up the driver it uses it undocumented
way
aren't in on common way overboard
loading the driver
by using this at all he says is him
information all
native API with the system a driver
%uh parameter unlike though common way
installing drivers as registering them
as a service
and the mall most interesting probably
is that it's stored as program called in
the registry instead of
files as on the disk so
clearly it's obvious that all the hot
product creators are following the
trends of modern Mauer
rootkits because as you all know are
rootkits in the past what they would do
is that they would try to hide the
processes on this is the malicious
processes on the system
they would hide the malicious files in
the file system
whereas modern Ricketts they would try
to avoid this
suspicious behavior this hooking that
could give it up give it away
and try try to bypass files altogether
suggested you know stories they tend to
run in raw sectors
in Iraq as raw bytes so on at at the end
of the hard drive
a piece of bacon let's take a look at so
the installation steps
are better done better taken by heart
problem so first
a setup API DLL is dropped in the did
in the directory of the browsers on the
system all the malware
or support center next for Opera and
Firefox
and following that are the ad print
processor technique is used
are to load the module and if that fails
due to some are problems with admin
rights
all the malware no escalate the
privileges by using the MS 10-15
vulnerability
if it succeeds it will disable the
Windows file protection service
and after that it will replace the SFC
files DLL
and store the original file in the
registry
I'll explain what the purpose of this is
in just a second
then it drops unloads the most driver
using that
on common technique that I just mention
then it's than activates the whole pill
deference installed
by opening up a default browser
and navigating to google.com
okay so the code in the registry the
main main binaries the main cold
or the malware is stored in the registry
like this it's
encrypted using are some custom Saurer
and irritation and stuff like that
and though these are the five five
richest ricky's
that the mauer is using Core settings is
used to store
the main module the main but module all
or the Trojan in this key
the original a subsea files de lo is
stored
this one or is the binary the kernel
driver image
over here is some loader cold which is
used to load the main what you
and then in the last 1/2 seed is where
the malware stored it in cryptid
are CNC URL's
so to get to get the whole picture as
you see there's some different
components to the Maori might get a be
confusing
I'll so so this is this is because this
is the code stored
are inside inside the registry there's
lotta code is the main bar module
their the C&C URL's and plus there are
these two API setup API DLL
and SSE files the A level and also the
kernel driver
so what is obvious for what's what's the
purpose were what
what's the all infrastructure or
implemented
by this power to set up API DLL as I
said that's the
thats though deal well that's dropped
into the
installation directories of the browsers
on the system
%uh interesting interesting technique
that it's using
to inject this deal well into the
browser's after space
is called the little hijacking so
when when this so browser process will
be started the windows loader what it
would do
is due to first check wet the D the what
the weather the deal is located in the
present correct directory
where the all process image
is starting is yeah is located
and if it's not there it will search the
path or environment variable
and Woodford directors directories
listed there so that
but the legitimate it a bigger deal is
in the system directory
so when the malware drops its its audio
into these
directories the militias the law will be
loading is that a bill
legitimate one the purpose of the DLL
is to get into the browser's address
space into injects
are inject the main bookmark your from
the registry that I was just showing
before
SFC files de lo all that has to do with
Windows file protection that I was
mentioning during the installation phase
that's been disabled and of this
gets onto the infected system by
overwriting
up a legitimate so DLL and the original
is stored in the registry
and/or its purpose is so wanna
to be started are one so was the
operation
operating system is started have to
reboot
and/or to load the driver if it's not
running
and it also also has the capability to
update
the software know the advantage of that
is that
it's loaded by win log on XD which is a
trusted system process
and the driver SFC sis now
what that is doing its purpose
is the same as with setup API DLL to
load the main bar mod your
into the browser now as you can see
there is some duplicity
in the functionality of these different
models
which I'll show was how all
how much work the authors of hot pot had
put into their creation
and basically they're creating backup
mechanisms in case one
one of them fails and a making making
the malware
much more difficult to remove from the
infected system
so what what the driver drivers doing is
that into registers the low-dimensional
if I
routine or call back function
which gets triggered by the by the
windows loader or whenever an image
whenever module is loaded and any checks
whether
wanna be loaded modules is wannabes when
in a deal and so on
used by browsers and if it if it is
the browser injection takes place
okay so so there's are quite a lot of
are quite a lot of module so let's see
how
how this is interconnected as a said the
heart up though Trojan
are the main components are stored
Norris Pyles but in the registry that's
over here
and the SFC files DLL well which is
residing in the wing of an outer space
loaded by when look on during the
start-up of the system
is able to update this payload and also
make sure
that the driver the kernel driver is
loaded
and that the purpose of the driver then
is
to make sure that's the payload
the main bought module will be injected
into the browser
address space and the same or same
functionality is implemented by that
setup API DLL
which was dropped injured or browser out
browser or directory so this publicity
back a mechanism implemented by the
malware
you know and while ripe for describe
this architecture
all around around Mauer the installation
and the self-protection
techniques that is using I'll the main
thing obviously that's using instance it
so
or since it's a bot is of the main
module
and though here here though techniques
are a pretty obvious it
contact the remote server requests some
additional
now where to download and execute and
I'll
just to highlight so a quite a quite an
interesting technique that this so
or model is using is that the request
that it's so
using that it's building up to contact
the C and C's
up there they're building up with some
junk values
so there will be the the target URL
either from the URL
list encrypt it in the registry horse it
has alternatives
embedded inside the binary and then
there will be some
parameters and about the Standard
limited and
the number of these parameters is not
fixed actually it's it's a random
or random amount from five to nine
and one thing that it sends in each case
is the bar ID
so so the attacker %uh is able to
identify
or the infection but then then
additional junk is is adage to this HTTP
request
are such as the promise you wanna be
strings
and others as well and the value is one
of these are these
these have no specific purpose and why
is the malware using these well thats
to avoid recognizable patterns in the
network communication
so this is what it looks like in no in
it was traded
form are the client will will send a
request
to the C&C server which will reply are
with
though with the law execute a bull with
the other
malware such a Scarborough or shoulder
or RDP door for example
it's compressed with AP lip and that
will be
executed on the infected machine and
then a status information will be said
whether the installation
was successful or not okay quite a lot
of statistics are included in my
presentation
here's another one which shows or the
relative ratio I just wanted to show how
much
up each of these families that have just
described or
is out there all so as you can see
over here in the top the barely visible
red and blue colors belong to shell door
and RDP door now that is not to say
that saw these families are
insignificant
these detections are still in the
numbers of thousands and
people are getting or are having two
parts
or with their money or thanks to these
Trojans
but that is to show are how much how
much
all for hop prod Inc Arbor is actually
out there
so hot pot as it's as if the downloader
all
downloading in infecting other computers
and delivering other malware other
markings
banking Trojans onto the system has the
greatest share are all these
for families and I already mentioned
though similarity in the installation
with 30 DL
and if you think about it though
functionality
reminds me of tedious work as well since
TDR would
or infect the system use pretty advanced
or repeat techniques and then allow are
other third-party Mauer to be loaded on
the infected system
so I think the question of why we need
to pay attention to what this Maori all
these families has been answered
during the presentation I mean this is
this is these are tools
which the attackers the criminals are
using to steal
money from the victim to steal a lot of
money and just to give you an example
of how much they're stealing these are
these are some numbers from the
investigations carried out by group IB
your separates or group which this one
was stealing
over 24 million dollars over a period of
time this these
these bad guys we're seeing or $26
million dollars
and according to the group IB reports
the global cybercrime TRO over
4 2010 was seven billion dollars that's
quite quite an astonishing number
and bill share of Russia speaking
countries
I love this horrific figure is over
one-third
now these numbers are for 2010 this
report was
all was published this year
and it's already already known that so
in the second half of 2010
are there has been no no tips or
noticeable increase
in or cyber crime related to banking
Trojans
so were expecting or
the numbers for 2011 to be even higher
and report will be
out or in the first quarter of next year
so to finish up my presentation are as I
said
these backing Trojans are used as
weapons and
they're targeting targeting no victims
globally but though share
russian-speaking countries is are quite
quite remarkable and these countries are
both the red
origin up for of these Trojans as well
as
targets of the criminals and you say
that
the solutions so would be cooperation
and is probably a few
cliche are but its it's not only
necessary to compete to communicate to
our between
all peers in in in the industry
different maybe companies
do this do this so our communication all
the time also different sectors of the
security industry
all such as a AB companies or law
enforcement
banks et cetera et cetera so
while while and a good anti virus can be
thought about as a bulletproof vest the
real solution
will be to stop the person shooting
and hopefully if we do it well we'll be
seeing more headlines like this
these these people or were arrested by
the Russian police
and this group was actually using the
shoulder or all
banking Trojan and among other
instances of theft
are these guys also stole
over six hundred thousand dollars in a
single transaction
that's probably not a very good idea
and also this headline up this guy is
are pretty famous our bill group lipsky
a major player
in though or a Russian cybercrime
business are where mainly mainly
focusing on our row cabey's
where his or company crime pays the
largest processor of the payment
up the online payments and basically
enabling
the criminals to cash out are from the
dirty business
he was arrested this summer
so a big thank you to my colleagues have
a great
upgrades or sharp work on this
presentation knowledge in a month or so
and Eugene audio from he said and
imagery volkov from group I B
and thanks to you all for attention