how about now am I on yet of getting on
there we go excellent I have a brief
announcement and sort of self
introduction as well I I'm just really
pleased yesterday to see how successful
everything seemed to go because I didn't
have to organize this but I am one of
the people that helps organize besides
Vancouver so I didn't want to announce
that we've we've chosen our dates and we
believe we have our venue all secured
now so we invite all of you that are
able to join us on March 12th and 13th
in downtown Vancouver to come out for
our b-sides and have kind of the the
other half of the calendar maybe we'll
just keep going back and forth with
besides Calgary so you don't have more
than six months between some hacker fun
and would really enjoy that my name is
Chester Wisniewski I'm a principal
research scientist at Sophos but what
that really translates to for me is that
I'm not tied to revenue and products and
stuff and I just get to do research
whatever I think's interesting is gonna
help and then I get to fly around the
world and tell everybody about it so
it's like kind of dream job and my I
guess I might explain the outfit
slightly as well in that I've been
hearing rumors that all of us that
besides Vancouver some kind of hipsters
that might be related to Alex Dahl I
suspect because of course he's at
besides Portland as hipsters do whereas
Farshad and I are here in Calgary where
we really know the important things are
happening and so I wanted to dispel any
myths that we're all hipsters that
besides Vancouver so that's why I
decided to try to blend in with some of
the locals so for the next hour so I
hope to show you some disclaimers about
my presentation I hope to show you a
demo for 90% of the next hour and not
show you slides but I have slides
because working with malware and online
things that can't be staged is like
working with children and animals and so
you're not really sure that I can you
know not all of it always works
I tested stuff this morning everything
was looking really good although I just
remembered that I forgot to reset my VM
snapshot but I'll do that for the for
the VM part of the demo the other
disclaimer warning is most of this is
going to be on the dark web
and I've gone out of my way once again
to avoid random pornography coming up on
the screen but it's incredibly difficult
and many of the places that I'm going to
show you today in the last three or four
times I've done some other presentations
three of the four I've managed to avoid
any incidents that that are
unintentional I promise you they're
unintentional but one time in the one
place where I didn't want it to happen
Singapore is in fact where it happened
so well that is a warning if that will
bother you I apologize if I think um ZUP
I will try to switch away from it as
quickly as I can
but I would like to show you kind of the
real experience of what this stuff is
and be be aware if you decide to do this
on your own that you are likely to run
into a lot of very let's not say does it
say not softcore pornography so let's
let me get started here I do have a
couple slides to kind of set things up a
little bit this this started it based on
a lot of conversations I've been having
with mid-sized companies around the
world trying to understand why they seem
to be suddenly targeted in getting
hacked like ten times more than they
ever were before and it's it's simply
economics but I don't think everyone
realizes that that the reality is in
2005 if you wanted to buy an exploit kit
or all the malicious document hmm build
a malicious document to dilute and
deploy some malware that kind of thing
you were gonna have to make friends in
some underground Russian forums it
wasn't particularly easy to get access
to them many of them were only Russian
language
there wasn't a uh there certainly wasn't
an open marketplace for any idiot to
decide to be a cyber criminal many
idiots tried but they weren't all that
successful and sadly some of the you
know those of us that are privacy
advocates and things like that are
pretty excited about things like Tor and
Bitcoin when they're used properly
they're amazing tools but obviously the
criminals that has enabled the criminals
to kind of have an open marketplace as
we all know and in what's changed is you
know we've gone from a few hundred
people trying to you know keep a low
profile and target some high profile
targets to make a lot of money with
their skills
and we've transformed that into 25,000
idiots buying tools on the dark markets
and just slamming this stuff into any
network they can find and that's
increasing the quantity of attacks and
sadly after leaks from the NSA and other
things we've seen an increase in the
sophistication of these attacks because
we've kind of got nation-state ideals
now about how we might go about
attacking people and that's being sold
as kits and so that's what I'm gonna
trying to talk about and show you today
and and I kind of in marketing didn't
want me to call it so you want to be a
cyber criminal but I put in a second
slide because kind of that thing like if
you woke up tomorrow morning and you
weren't one of us and passionate about
security and had some ethics and you'd
gone hey I've heard what this ransomware
thing on TV that sounds really
profitable how might you go about it
right like how hard would it be to go
from just random computer idiot that
doesn't have any skills to someone
attacking you and taking your money so
I'm gonna kind of walk through that
process and you know starting on the
left you'll see a bit of you probably
gonna do some Google searches or look in
some forums and go like hey I want to be
a hacker how do I do this
right and then the very first thing
you're gonna discover is well if you
don't have any bitcoins you're not
getting anything like every you know
it's it's the it's the lingua franca of
currencies for the dark markets so
you're gonna have to get some bitcoins
and we'll kind of walk through some of
some of the ways you might steal money
to get some bitcoins and then once you
have those bitcoins you need some
delivery vehicle to find your victims so
you're probably either gonna need to
hire a spanner spammer to you know send
out some kind of malicious attachments
or links or you're gonna need to hack
some kind of web servers somebody's
wordpress blog or whatever to booby-trap
it to try to get people to download the
malware or exploit them once you do that
of course you'll end up delivering some
kind of a virus or a malicious document
which will downloading in the end the
ransomware the skull and then of course
the ransomware is fully cloud enabled as
all things are now goes to the cloud and
gets keys and talks to the criminals and
all that kind of stuff and ultimately
locks up your files and demands the
money so that's what we're gonna walk
through in the next 60 minutes or
probably about 40 minutes now and I
don't get started here so take it blimps
behind the curtain and you're probably
gonna start out as I said if you don't
really know anything you're gonna start
out with search so this is a screenshot
I'm just gonna jump to the real thing
here and see how this goes so I've got a
few things open I've got my Graham
search open this is today's parent
sometimes they have a Graham's doodle
not
saying that they're copying a certain
company in California what their search
but their logo looks more remarkably
similar to a large company that starts
with a G and and actually on 4/20 day I
wish I'd had that screen shot in the
slide I forgot I took it out for
Singapore on 4/20 day they had this
phenomenal marijuana graphic of the
Grahams logo that was just it was it was
pretty incredibly amusing I don't
recommend ever clicking I'm feeling
lucky
when when you're doing this but you
might go you know I don't really know
what I'm doing but I might realize that
fishing is important so I'm gonna go how
to fit how to fish see what we get
Internet's don't fail me now
oh no the internet has failed me I have
a question mark this was happening to me
yesterday of how many problems with my
own company's Wi-Fi at your event we
supplied the Wi-Fi for B sites Vancouver
besides Calgary and ant and besides Las
Vegas for that matter and my computers
they don't think one that seems to not
be able to stay connected let's try that
again this is why I have slides
meanwhile point is while that's loading
or not loading the you know you can just
basically search for how to fish how to
hack how to how do I get you know how to
get into ransomware all these things and
they literally are selling ebooks for
between usually three and five US
dollars that'll show up on these markets
oh wait looks there we go oh there we go
how to fish credit card information is
the top result today it's a little
different every day and you know you
might go how to fish or you might go you
know how to hack and then what are they
selling these so by default it shows you
the price in and BTC and bitcoins it's
point zero zero zero for the ultimate
guide to travel hacking that one's
actually probably a real book that's
just stolen on this particular market
how to hack a credit card let's see so
we can go over here and well they don't
list Canadian dollars son the other
market will show you in a minute they
actually do like allow you to display
the prices in Canadian which is rather
convenient for us but the we can see in
US dollars what are we have two dollars
and four
five cents for this how to hack a credit
card guide how to hack almost any MSN
account now I would assume how do you
hack in MSN account is like download any
password dump and then log in to MSN but
you know this stuff literally people are
selling these handbooks now of course
none of this is illegal right telling
people how to do these things I mean
we've had the you know the Jolly Roger
and the Anarchist Cookbook and all kinds
of things for years right it's not like
a particular revelation but if you were
getting started that's that might be how
you might you might get going but what
we really know is that we're gonna need
some cash and it's probably easiest to
use someone else's cash so we'll
probably want to buy some stolen credit
cards so let's I pulled up this
particular site is very popular with the
for for stolen Canadian cards now as a
good security researcher I don't know my
password so one second
red spider now I'm gonna have to change
all these passwords because this video
is going out no I have to actually have
to refresh this first because the
CAPTCHAs are only valid for 30 seconds
and I always forget that and then I
can't login I'd like to do this stuff
ahead but a lot of these things time out
very quickly so I have to do it live
here we go red spiders so this is a a
live credit card form they specialize in
u.s. Canadian and British stolen credit
cards and we can say if you follow on
the left hand side of the screen you'll
see sort of their newsfeed
in fact the 20th is that today yeah
there you go servers some fresh cards
posted today 41 new UK cards were posted
this morning they you know kind of have
a news and announcements on the site
what's what's more interesting as sort
of how these markets function like real
markets and on the right side of the
screen here you'll see you get a 50%
discount if the credit card expires this
month if it's more than four weeks old
if it was stolen more than a month ago
you get a 66% discount right because the
banks catch on to where these cards are
being stolen and often pre proactively
cancelled them and the one that isn't on
the screen oh they took it off see these
things literally change every day
yesterday when I did this when I was
setting up in the my hotel room last
night they had a discount for cards that
were
for people under born after 1995 you got
a 20% discount because if you're 21
years old or younger you don't have much
credit so those cards aren't as valuable
and so there's they're literally you
know that's how they apply these
discounts and things and you can get
very specific because a lot of these
people buying these why is that this
screen resolution is killing me because
none of my things are clickable we'll
look at the Canadian cards that are here
in the in the market and you can see you
can you can search by province by bank
by postal code there are lots of
different types of criteria and that's
mostly for the physical carters people
that are gonna literally make a card and
go into Shoppers Drug Mart and try to
make an illicit purchase because you
don't want to trigger fraud alerts so if
you're gonna do that here in Calgary you
want to bike you know Albertans stolen
cards you're less likely to trigger a
fraud alert than if you use one from
Newfoundland the same day as the victim
also use their card in New Finland and
the bank goes well you can't have a
purchase in the two places of the same
card in the same day sometimes they even
identify Oh a Discover card you don't
see those stolen very often that's true
I mean I do this a lot and I don't
usually see discover there's usually a
lot more Amex and a lot less a lot less
Discover but you can see they give you
partial card numbers expiration dates
you know a lot of information about the
victims including the postal code and if
I were the banks I would be sitting on
this site every day looking at it and
just taking all those because it's not
hard to correlate then amount of
information they provide with who the
victim would be so you could cancel
these cards I don't know if the banks do
that or not but I certainly would if I
were in risk management at the banks we
also see this chart of what other
information they have from the victim
phone mother's maiden name Social
Insurance number driver's license etc
that information is used for social
engineering purposes if this is a chip
and pin card I may need to reset the pin
or I may choose to reset the online
banking login or the online credit card
login in order to do that I need to be
able to impersonate you in which case of
course knowing your mother's maiden name
is the golden key that will unlock all
financial institutions and allow that to
happen so that's kind of how that worked
now while I was doing this research I
have a tendency to like to search for
the word Trump on anything I'm doing
just to see what happens and I found
this
Trump dumps making dumps great again so
this is a competitor to red spider and
another stolen credit card market that's
the Trump dump store in the tea the
trumpet on the store looks remarkably
like a TD Canada big I'm not sure if
that's intentional if they took the TD
Bank logo and modified that a little bit
there but I have to give him credit for
much better branding than any of the
other credit card markets that I've
logged into so now that we've got some
money we can buy some bitcoins like
there's my emergency backup slides now
you might say well how did they get all
the credit card data and actually
accidentally while doing this research
got fished by these same guys that were
that's how that they were putting the
cards in there so I got this email while
I was traveling you can see my screen
shots are from my android and asking
saying my my car my credit card had been
charged $6.95 from the Apple Store for
clash of clans and if it wasn't my
purchase I should click the link and of
course I clicked the link and this is
what I got and and as you do I logged in
as Donald J Trump at whitehouse.gov/live
as word was orange monkey so I did that
but the URL which you can't really see
because of the the lighting here but the
the URL was app Apple ID - Apple - comm
and then a long hexadecimal string and
then ultimately on the second screenshot
i went looked at what you know where it
really went and in the end it was
connection AC com so some hacked website
that they were using to host this
fishing kit and so once I logged in as
Donald I was told that my Apple ID had
been locked for security reasons and
that I needed to unlock my account fair
enough and then you might notice a while
you probably can't because the prints
really tiny but if you could read that
you would notice that every one of those
blanks lines up exactly with the things
on red spider and in fact the
information I input fake about Donald J
Trump showed up on red spider within
minutes
so that's one of the ways these credit
card marketplaces are populating these
things it's not just about mag stripes
at Burger King anymore right it's a
mostly phishing oriented where they they
convince you somehow
they're your financial institution or
their PayPal or their Apple and places
your custom to getting your account
locked sadly and then lastly at the very
end they they they ask you to reset your
security question ask for your mother's
maiden name and your passport
conveniently enough and then once it's
complete they actually redirect you to
the real Apple site so you can log in
and of course it works so it's a it's a
very convincing social engineering scam
and in ruse in order to collect credit
card data so this is some marketing for
some other things so now that I've got
money I probably know right I also need
to to build some sort of malicious
payload to send out to my victims I need
to exploit them in some way there's a
lot of kits available this is particular
ones called offensive where you can see
they've got a budget version for $49
where what the budget version is this is
one that builds these Excel spreadsheets
and Word docs that have the enable macro
right you have to run the macro there's
no actual exploit right it's just a
malicious macro that doesn't run until
you allow it to and then it goes and
retrieves a payload where it's the 290
dollar premium version you get the what
they call silent exploit which is an
actual exploit and the silent exploits
are where you're literally attacking
vulnerabilities in office and silently
delivering a payload
without the user clicking anything right
just simply open the document as no if
it's not always office although it's
usually office you can see the silent
exploits there in the red box at the
bottom silent dark silent dark silent
dock and auto refund big output I don't
even know what that is
keep in mind Fudd doesn't mean what you
probably think it means fund usually in
our business means fear uncertainty and
doubt when we're looking at the dark
markets FUD means fully undetectable so
they're talking about your malware not
being able to be detected by anty anty
any antivirus and that's what FUD means
and then you can see at the top the non
silent exploits include things like PDFs
and other types of documents where
you're actively choosing to run
JavaScript or acting of chuza actively
choosing to run macros so I've got a
malicious document I can build with
those and we'll actually do that in a
minute my VM I'll show you have got a
few of these document builders so we'll
walk through and build a few malicious
documents during how they work but not
all I got my malicious document
I probably need somebody to spam it out
because I'm an idiot I don't have a
botnet and I don't know how to build one
so I'll just go searching on the forums
for somebody who does have one and wants
to sell it and my phone say what he was
selling his spamming services features
random text in subject and letter
attachments good inbox rate my service
is 100% in box depending on your leads
letter attachment and header you need 80
to 90 percent so he's promising it
basically an 80 to 90 percent in box
delivery rate past spam filters his
price is $2 per 1000 leads so effort
every two dollars he'll send a thousand
mails but he minimum order is a hundred
thousand emails he's not going to mess
around for less than 200 bucks coolyback
bitcoin is accepted and he's got a few
rules he doesn't have a lot of rules
he's got a few rules the main rule is no
child abuse content and that in the last
rule there is if your attachment is a
malware it should be 100% FUD won't be
responsible for inbox delivery rate so
if you're gonna deliver malware he
doesn't give you a promise about
delivering the mail because antivirus
might block it that's not his fault so
that that's that that's how we'll get
our spam messages out so let's let's see
here let me launch my my forgotten VM
there was always something that you
forget to do I'm gonna do that really
quickly and hopefully by the time I
present the next slide or I'll do a live
demo know while it's loading we'll be in
good shape
oh right this so now we need a
ransomware right we've got a malicious
document that's gonna go download
something from a URL we got a spammer to
deliver our malicious document we need
something for the malicious document to
retrieve to infect the machines so
ransomware seems like the thing and like
everything else why not ransomware as a
service go to the cloud when you have no
skills you don't need to set up the
infrastructure the criminals will manage
it for you they'll give you the payload
all you need to do is deliver the
payload and in fact that's exactly this
is one of them called Satan I found this
one on January 16th this year and what
is Satan apart from a mythological
creature Satan is a ransomware a
malicious software for once open under
windows systems encrypts all files I do
like they explain at the bottom
basically that it's a it's a fully
contained cloud-based criminal service
and they charge a 30 percent commission
is their revenue models so in essence if
you charge your victims one Bitcoin for
ransom which is a pretty hefty ransom
one bitcoins about seven thousand
Canadian dollars right now so you
wouldn't probably do that but if you did
charge him a Bitcoin for ransom the
criminals would would take point three
bitcoins and you would get point seven
bitcoins per victim and there's a volume
discount for victims so if you have lots
of the more victims you have the the
cheaper price or lower their Commission
from 30% they don't really promise what
they're gonna lower it to but they tell
you that they will so let's login I'm a
customer so we'll log in here now so let
me get my password
another password burned Thank You
YouTube come on
no it's being very slow oh my internet
wont wonky again
sorry that's genuinely my fault I did
some sort of update the other day and it
started making my Wi-Fi funny and and
there's no wired connection so on and
since the slack message just popped up
feel free to join the b-sides Vancouver
slack channel has somebody just sent a
message from okay come on oh good good
so here we go Jane yes and there's
always a CAPTCHA because they seem to be
really nervous about BOTS but I'm not
terribly surprised considering most of
them write bots so and this one has two
factor authentication of course because
you don't want somebody logging into
your ransomware as a service control
panel it's stealing all your bitcoins
from your victims so what they do is
they make you give them a GPG key so
they and then they encrypt a blob sort
of a poor man's Google Authenticator so
I have to decrypt this you have to do I
have to decrypt this blob with my PGP
key to login so there we go there's like
our arson our authentication code
[Music]
there we go so we can see the malware's
tab may not be in English for a first
language speaker but we don't get to
specify a lot in this one right you get
to put in how much ransom do you want to
charge what is the multiplier if you
don't pay right away so we can say okay
charge them double if they don't pay
right away and give them seven days and
it will double the ransom I can make a
note besides why do I see so I know
which Malware this is you can specify a
proxy to route the traffic through if
you choose to and of course you have to
solve a CAPTCHA they say do not upload
your malware to virustotal
any healthcare on line scanner which of
course every time I do this is the first
thing I do the malware was created so we
can see down here now this is my malware
I just created this is the token to
identify that malware the version number
the amount of ransom and you can see the
version numbers do increment if I go to
the second page here from when I started
doing this earlier in the year like I
said I logged in to this the first time
in January we can see in January it was
version 1.0.0 dot one and then I got
preoccupied with other work and I didn't
come back for a few months until July
27th as you can see in which case they
were up to version 1.0.0 about 1/6 and I
think that's still the current version
but it's as simple as that and they
don't just provide the malware they also
provide you some assistance even by
giving you some droppers so you can go
in and configure like the URL of the
ransom notes and different things like
this and then it will build you little
PowerShell and Python scripts to to
assist with dropping the malware onto
the system that you could use in
conjunction with your malicious Word
document you see your PowerShell
execution policy bypass file run run the
script in order to install the malware
on the machine and and run it as an
administrator and then conveniently they
don't just give you in Python the house
they give it to you in Impala show they
also go team Python so it's that easy
now another thing that I found in this
one that was interesting is they're
crowdsourcing the translation of the
malware so when I first went to the site
it was only in English and Portuguese in
January which might be some kind of a
hint as to the origin and yet now we can
see that they've added a whole bunch of
language is basically targeting
everybody around the world
from arabic to mandarin too to most
Western in European languages so it's
kind of equal opportunities scams but if
you contribute a new translation they
give you 10% off your Commission so you
know it's another way to why pay more so
you know we can see all the strings from
the malware there and you can contribute
translations it's kind of interesting
how that all works so let's go over here
and oops why is it off I told it to run
oh no it's gonna run so go back to the
slides for a second while that boots up
or will I so we have the Satan there
there's a few other ones there out there
you this is kind of the progression of
the languages every time I login I take
a screenshot as they're adding new
languages you can see the the list keeps
expanding as criminals contribute more
and more languages another business
model for some of these guys this one's
no longer available but this was nemesis
this was popular back in about March and
April of this year nemesis
their business model was you get a trial
version you get 20 free infections and
then after that you have to subscribe on
a subscription model so they also you'll
see they have support tickets they
believe they use OTRS the open source
ticketing system in order to provide
their their support their tech support
I contacted their tech support on behalf
of a journalist at the New York Times
earlier this year whose mother was
infected with ransomware and she wanted
to like she's like can I can I interview
these criminals I'm like well they have
a tendency to hang out on jabber chat
like yeah we probably can try to get
ahold of them so I messaged and I'm like
yeah I've got this journalist from New
York Times she's interested in
interviewing you
Alina Simone she's a great journalist
and would you be willing to do a
anonymous private interview with her and
cut back the response no f off
this is another model this is dot
ransomware I'll actually show you dot
ransomware I have it in my VM if it ever
loads and dot ransomware was just you
know one time by right 500 bucks you get
the source code it's up to you to figure
out how to evade antivirus and you know
you might need a few more skills but
easy setup low requirements infects
Windows XP with no problem so you know
the lot lots of different choices out
there so let's go back
okay good this is loaded
oh I should have hooked up the sound so
we could hear the Windows 7 Start noise
so we have some builders right so let's
look at the malicious document builders
this one's actually Python and we can
see there's a there for files that come
in the kit there's a malware XE which of
course is just a dummy file that's where
you would put your file you downloaded
from satan where you know you created
your ransomware on the ransomware as a
service you'd plop that down in this
folder and call it Malory XE there's a
Python script which is the actual
builder tool fpy there's an exploit
sample so this is actually the the
exploit sample is the word doc with the
malicious code attacking the word
vulnerability in it but without the
mount we're injected into it so it's
like a word shell waiting for the
payload to get inserted into it and then
there's a decoy document dot docx which
I don't know why extension so I guess
this is too narrow a resolution that
doesn't show it but the decoy document
because what happens when you exploit an
application typically as it crashes and
so users gonna notice like oh I got an
email I opened a thing that said it was
an invoice and it crashed I better call
IT you don't want them doing that right
if they're the persons in finance let's
say so they include a decoy document so
what it does is it exploits word injects
the malware crashes word and then
instantly relaunches word with another
document that's not malicious so the
user thinks everything was just fine
most of our computers are so fast these
days you don't even notice the crash and
relaunch because even when I'm testing
these things I don't see it often and so
that's that's kind of what this decoy
documents about so if we open up the
decoy document I think in this case it
was a C here I always do this wrong I'm
terrible at windows why is it there we
go that's what I'm looking for thank you
builder decoy document I've got a couple
different ones in here so I think this
one is a invoice it pretends to be an
invoice for some furniture being drop
shipped from Chennai India or something
yeah you can see here this is the decoy
document
fortunately opened and protected view
I'm very well / - of course the exploit
it uses
it's protected view but this yeah so
they're your M&R furniture or M&R
furnishings is the decoy document there
so if we run this fpy I did install
Python of course in this Windows machine
in order to do this most criminals are
to probably you know may be too stupid
to run Python I don't know but we can
see they they give you the usage and if
this was wide enough you could actually
see and because it's not wide enough I
have to try to remember but I think you
go f2f py and then you specify the first
parameter is the malware and the second
parameter I think is the decoy document
oh wait can scroll sideways how do I do
that I usually have a much higher
resolution screen yeah it is the decoy
document right yeah and then the exploit
sample so I run that and basically it
takes the malware and Jux it into the
next point sample takes the decoy
document injects it into the exploit
sample and packages all up into one file
and then if I do a directory we can now
see that that's that exploit sample now
is dated October 20 today so that's the
one we just created no I don't want to
infect the system yet so I'm going to
hide that now that was too hard for a
lot of crooks to use so when we saw the
you know how they're kind of had their
advertising too they had the simple
version and then $249 version so these
these a.k people later came up with one
called Anka log and Anka log has a GUI
so we have the ankle but of course you
always want to grant administrative
permission to your tools you buy from
criminals and here we go so this is the
the kind of next version of that same
tool so it's basically the same builder
that fpy it's just got a GUI around it
you don't need to install python o know
how to add python to your path and all
that kind of stuff right and so you can
see here regular exploit method which is
not exploits at all that's the macros
and then you have silent exploit method
which is a true exploit against a either
Microsoft help vulnerability internet
explorer vulnerability or doc word doc
of ulnar ability and you see there's a
blank for a license key but fortunately
I got the pirated version of the hack
tool it's you see cracked bio X 22 so I
don't need to actually end
a license no honor among thieves use
this software only for educational
purposes no illegal activities so that
of course means you won't go to jail if
you use it because you of course you
breach the EULA I'm sure they'll come
after you I would love for them to sue
me for the EULA breach I would meet them
at the courthouse with glee but
nonetheless you can see how you know how
easy this has become and this has
continued to evolve no wonder there's
been a really recent development
interesting development a couple weeks
ago I believe Palo Alto it published a
paper about two weeks ago talking about
how they had detected a Chinese apt
campaign that was using malicious
documents
docx documents and they shared some of
those samples with us and one of our
researchers zappy looked at it and went
oh my god that's that's ANCA log like
the Chinese government attackers are
using the fpy script I just showed you
to actually build their malicious
documents for these apt campaigns and we
can tell there's some markers in there
that allow us to see that it's being
generated by that same script they're
not using the exploits because these are
old they're typically old exploits in a
lot of these kits this particular one I
think the exploits from 2015 so if
you're you know if you've patched in the
last two years arguably you shouldn't
fall victim to that document but that
you know the Chinese were using a
zero-day in word but they used the same
script to build the documents just
because apparently why reinvent the
wheel right the criminals did pretty
good work with the script just stick
your new zero-day exploit into it and go
and and that looks exactly like what may
have happened so let's continue on here
let's Blue Dot ransomware
oh no that's a screenshot of the ad
that's not what I meant
that's what I meant so we can see that
ransomware if you bought it for the 500
bucks I showed you they add there you
got three things you got a set-up guide
will show the setup cut is quite
entertaining you get a set-up guide you
get the ransomware builder and then you
get what's called a dot wrasse core the
core is again a shell it's basically the
entire ransomware without a
configuration file in it so it's not
armed yet it won't do anything and then
what what the configuration tool does is
it asks you a bunch of questions about
you know how much ransom all this kind
of stuff and then it stuffs the config
into the core
that arms it makes it a a live malware
and here's the setup guide we recommend
you build your ransomware size virtual
machine it's just you know probably a
smart idea just don't run build a deck
see file on your PC good advice you
should want to run with the recommended
decryption price they give you even
prices per country so they tell you no
but richer countries can afford more
ransom clearly so they give you advice
on how much ransom to charge in
different countries so you maximize your
your payload and then also recommended
extensions these are things that are
likely represent documents that are
valuable to people and you can see
things like Adobe Illustrator or AutoCAD
you know not just office and in PNG s
and videos which of course for a home
user those are the things we care about
right it's our photos of our children
and our families and the videos of the
summer vacation but at work of course
it's the AutoCAD and the adobe
illustrator and the Photoshop and you
know all these types of assets because
those are the things you're gonna want
to pay ransom to get back so we'll run
that now this always give it admin
privileges this may look like a DOS
application but it is not a DOS
application it's just somebody who has
very little skill and coding and you can
see there's a menu so we'll go in here
and go set up first we have to give it
the Bitcoin wallet or where we want the
victims to pay or our bitcoins to I'm
obviously not gonna put in a real wallet
encryption mode do I want to encrypt
only the first four megabytes well turns
out three terabyte hard drives take a
really long time to encrypt and people
kind of notice that when you in fact
they're machines so you really just want
to screw up every file so that they
don't work you don't really need to
encrypt the whole file right because
it's not like you're actually trying to
protect the data you're just trying to
prevent access to it so if you only
encrypt the first four megabytes you can
very quickly blitz through the entire
system but you still pose all the files
so the victim still has to pay to get
them back I kind of look at this funny
cuz I a lot of these high resolution
photos I was playing with this and I
wish I had saved one of the samples but
if you take a jpg file from like a
high-end nikon camera you'll get like a
45 megabyte JPEG right so when it equips
just the form first for megabytes if you
stuff that into an image for you
it just like cuts the person's head off
the rest of the the rest of the JPEG is
still there it's just the top is like
noise you know you just have to fix the
headers so it thinks it's a JPEG it's
quite amusing which kind of is a tip to
be honest most ransomware does this if
you have a machine that's completely
hosed and you can't pay the ransom or
don't want to or forget don't have
backups or whatever the circumstances
are if there's a giant spreadsheet
that's got a bunch of valuable data in
it you might just lose the first four
megabytes not all of its gone right not
all of that data is gone you may be able
to forensic Li at least put something
back together and not lose everything
and it's not always four megabytes
either it just happens to be this one
but very few of them encrypt the full
file anymore it doesn't make any sense
to do the full file so you there are
some forensic opportunities there to
recover some partial data depending on
the file type and you may want to
consider that attacked extensions of
course we have the the list they
recommended in the setup guide but for
my purposes I'm just gonna go PDF I
probably should do lower case PDF text
and docx and then we got the default
decryption price so we'll say 0.5
bitcoins but we've been having some
issues with the Russians so we'll go to
bitcoins for them all right and so then
we can print out our config so we can
see our settings there's my Bitcoin
wallet my fast encryption and is enabled
my default Bitcoin price is 0.5 which is
a bit steep that's thirty five hundred
thirty six hundred Canadian dollars and
of course in Russia it's fourteen
thousand Canadian dollars and my
attacked extensions okay great that
looks good to me so now I have to load
that shell right load ransomware core so
that's the the unarmed malware and then
built success okay good because this
fails about one in five times so that's
good we've got a tracking ID for this
particular malware so we know which one
it is if we were building multiples of
these and sending them out to different
victims in two different places or maybe
four different criminals and now we'll
close that up let's go do that and let's
open up my document folder
so there's my documents these are dummy
documents obviously I have a press
release announcing how amazing I am and
some quarterly sales results to make
sure I make quota and we'll run the
newly armed core we can see the date
stamp is today that's the one we just
built 836 am which is Pacific Daylight
Time run the malware and you should see
the extensions changed on the file types
there you go - one pipe easy and then in
the second the ransom note will pop up
strangely didn't pop to the front but
there you go your data was locked and
it's as simple as that so I mean these
tools are incredibly easy to use they
have gooeys menus everything included
including a set-up guide that you can
read if you're not quite sure how to
operate it I didn't realize there was a
set-up guide until I'd done this ten
times so it's a it's you know kind of
self-explanatory how to infect people
with these things but that's how it
works and you can see the files if we
open them up documents these are pretty
well jumbled oh do you not use the web
what why would I ever trust microsoft to
tell me what file to use to open a
malicious file but yeah you can see it's
been it's clearly not a PDF so alright
let's go back here so now that we've got
some victims we've in fact that you know
we've got our spammer to send on
religious document with our ransomware
payload now we've got the money rolling
in but we probably don't want to go to
prison so we want to be careful with
those bitcoins because it turns out you
know bitcoin is the most trackable
currency ever people seem to think it's
anonymous when if they even have a
concept of what the blockchain is they
would understand it's the exact opposite
of anonymous so the there's Bitcoin
tumblers and these are just a few of the
ones that that I found in doing my
research I quite like the mr. clean
Bitcoin tumble is some nice imagery
there we also have the bit launderers
the and the Bitcoin Fogg company now I'm
a pretty paranoid guy I'm probably more
paranoid than most of criminals because
they seem to be going to jail more
frequently
I suspect law enforcement is running
these tumblers
and I and I certainly would be if I were
a federal agent being asked to
investigate these crimes I think the
first thing I do it would do would be
try to set up the most popular Bitcoin
tumbler because once they're tumbled
they are incredibly difficult to track
and tumbling in essence is just
literally taking a whole bunch of
different people's bitcoins putting them
into like the thing where they do the
lotto draw and mixing them all together
and then giving you somebody else's
bitcoins back out the other side right
and that's basically you know I have a
very basic form of Bitcoin money
laundering and there's a lot of these
services but just doing brief looks when
I was putting this presentation together
I found 40 or 50 of them in a few hours
so there's a lotta different people
doing it then there's a lot of faith in
using a Bitcoin tumbler because you're
literally giving someone your money and
you don't know that they're ever gonna
give it back
like there's no escrow there's no way to
know right you're giving them your
bitcoins on a hope and a promise that
they're gonna give you somebody else's
bitcoins back and that they're not the
FBI so that's a pretty big leap of faith
for me but obviously the dark market
people that have been arrested over the
last couple years clearly we're more
trusting than I am so you probably would
want to launder your bitcoins if you
were doing this and then I'm paranoid
like even after laundering them like
what if it was the FBI running the
mr.clean Bitcoin laundering service this
is a very common tactic as well which is
that this looks terrible let's show you
live this is called the Tor warehouse
and this is another way a lot of these
guys are laundering their money and if
in fact this is better than my
screenshot because of course the iPhone
8 is here now in the screenshots about a
month old and I didn't have the iPhone 8
in the Tor warehouse yet but the Tor
warehouse is a marketplace where you can
buy stolen goods and sell them on eBay
or Craigslist or Kijiji or this kind of
thing right and and that's another step
in the laundering process right use the
bitcoins buy stolen goods that are
high-value like Apple stuff and Samsung
notes and while let's see what they have
a pretty good deal right I mean iPhone a
256 gig at only 399 yeah and the new
Apple TV 4k 99 bucks the watch you get
the they cater to Bitcoin miners there's
a lot of GPUs in these marketplaces
selling these things for the Bitcoin
mining crowd
and you know anything that's gone a high
value sale limited time only on the iMac
5k $6.99 so you might say well how does
this all work well let's look at the FAQ
or actually is it the about I forget
which there this this site is a treasure
trove of humor oh it's just it there's a
part of the FAQ is a little wire you're
good so cheap oh it's because we only
buy the finest merchandise from thieves
and you know that well I mean this is
the thing that you know Tor and Bitcoin
is embolden these people to be able to
stand out in the public site and and and
and behave this way which obviously in
normal society would never be acceptable
my internet broke again off I wonder is
this the crack vulnerability is somebody
trying to this just started when I
literally the day I left Vancouver to
come out here on Wednesday this problem
and so let's try that again oh wait I
still don't there we go the problem is
every time that Wi-Fi goes down that
breaks all my tour circuits and so then
the tor browser has to re-establish
circuits into into the dark web and that
often takes a few seconds but they have
they also have customer testimonials you
know things like you know I I bought
stuff on other dark web map and web
markets and got ripped off and and I was
skeptical but I tried it and Wow
time for some unboxing therapy I wish it
was show up but a wait day there we go
why are your products so cheap our
pricing structure becomes easy to
understand once you're aware of the ways
these products are obtained by buying
them from thieves and then they explain
why they don't sell them on eBay and how
can you how can we trust you and so I
guess it's the illegal to use your store
what if I get caught it's like dwelve
don't rat on us
do you provide tracking numbers who do
you ship with
if you join the members circle you can
get discounts and yeah so but that's
another step in the process of the the
money laundering chain I'm doing ok on
time because I'm almost done now this
has been a lot of work and I've been
pretty stressed out about all this so I
really could use a holiday after all
this but of course why pay for a holiday
when you can do it the easy way so let's
let's go to dream market oops let me log
in the dream market real quick cement
cement you're always interesting things
on dream market what do I need to do
here go pass and dream
always gotta solve a CAPTCHA I've never
seen a CAPTCHA like this I quite like
these there they show you a whole thing
and then they put a box around the parts
you have to type now this one also
offers PGP two-factor I don't have it
enabled because it just makes it too
hard to demo we'll see if it is actually
working this site has been down up and
down lately the rumors on reddit are the
FBI is running the site I don't really
care cuz I'm not a criminal we can do a
Trump search if it comes up it's always
good looks looks sketchy try one other
URL it's been changing URLs a lot lately
and there's been some fissures targeting
them as well with fake ones trying to
harvest other people's credentials so
there's been a lot of the you know alpha
bay went down Hansen market when alpha
Bay was run by a Canadian guy and
Thailand and he committed suicide after
he was arrested so we won't probably
ever find out really what was going on
down there
honson market was shut down by the Dutch
police so it these demos have been
getting harder and harder as the years
been going on because a lot of the dark
markets are getting shut down
which is fantastic for society that's
terrible for my demo and you know this
morning you can see the dream market
clearly loaded this morning because this
was the this literally you know I loaded
this when I was setting up my laptop
here on the lectern this morning and
it's wait that one of the mirrors might
be up they've been getting ddosed is the
problem they've been putting up all
these extra CAPTCHAs and stuff because
the the crooks have been getting DDoS
and no honor among thieves it's not
oh good thank you so glad somebody's
paying attention let's try that again
all right wrap up in just a second if I
can not make copy and paste errors good
okay the mirror is working excellent so
we'll set our currency to Canadian in
there is seven thousand four hundred and
seventeen dollars to the Bitcoin right
now and I don't know who names the
marijuana strains but they've got a lot
of creativity see here well do our Trump
this is one of my favorites Trump shaped
ecstasy
that's bright orange bright orange Trump
shaped XC it's it's you can't make this
stuff up and it turns out I did a little
research on other ecstasy on this market
and you pay about a thirty percent
premium for the orange Trump shaped ones
but you know as you do ships from the
Netherlands where else would you get
Trump shaped ecstasy that wasn't what I
meant to show but nonetheless you know
in the you know all this stuff is
available to buy on these things right
there's the one of the more popular
ransomware kits out there that we wrote
a white paper on recently is called
Philadelphia here's somebody selling a
pirated version of the Philadelphia kit
on dream market for $18 and 54 cents
Canadian see his screenshots fully GUI
enabled and includes a whole bunch of
proxy automatically setup proxies and
somebody I heard had hacked it to even
set up like an automated Amazon AWS
proxies where it'll create a bunch of
Amazon AWS instances and route traffic
through it to to try to disguise your
origin so you know you can really search
for almost anything on here I mean you
do have to be careful like I say
sometimes there's some undesirable
things show up in the search results but
if we want to get out of town though we
probably might take uber to the airport
so let's do a quick search for uber
there we go hack uber and become a fake
driver this one one way to do it so some
of some ways to convince uber that
you're actually a driver when you're not
I was hoping for more like a free ride
from
were unlimited uber and lift rides 2017
2.46 canady now there we go
so that'll get us to the airport or
apparently another strain of marijuana
that has over in it or mushrooms or
something I don't know what is it so
yeah so we could get you know we could
become a fake uber driver and probably
get a Anubha ride to the airport that
might be good we're probably gonna need
a passport once we get there so we'll
have them acquire some passports to see
what we can get here we have Spanish one
for $43 these cheap ones aren't really
good for much I like having I bought one
because I wanted to see how good they
are and they're not that great the under
$50 ones are pretty low quality but
they're great for like when you're
checking into that foreign hotel they
insist on having your passport and
you're like yeah yeah my passport here
you go take this one they don't care
that you were just told we're supposed
to take your passport so I you know make
them happy it's always good to have a
few extra passports around this is you
know you're gonna pay more money for the
good quality ones you can see this one's
twelve hundred and thirty-seven dollars
Canadian for one of the high-grade
American ones in addition to that you
search for passports and things like
that you'll also find people selling
high-quality Photoshop documents of all
different types of documentation from
around the world driver's license ID
cards passports etc so that you can have
them printed locally by your friendly
neighborhood printer if you don't want
to purchase the the real goods directly
we can see here you go ten gig of PS DS
fake bills scans passports DL s another
thing you'll see is people selling scans
of passports so those same people at the
hotel that you think I'm picking on for
giving them my fake passport when they
put your passport on the scanner when
you're checking in they're selling those
scans on the dark market to anybody that
wants to buy them so who's paranoid now
and well I don't really want to spend my
hard-earned bitcoins on airline tickets
so let's see if I can get a hacked
aeroplane account there we go
for a dollar twenty three I can have
somebody's stolen Aeroplan Miles now of
course I don't need them I have over a
million airplane miles for my job I
travel constantly but again right I mean
everything is available at your
fingertips if you desire it and
uh you know if you're gonna buy things
like Rolexes and stuff I recommend very
carefully checking the spelling I did
find a lot of Rolexes with two L's maybe
not genuine merchandise but it you know
to kind of conclude this is incredibly
easy sadly I mean in an hour I kind of
explained how I could conduct an entire
attack and if I didn't have to explain
it to you and if I hadn't forgot to
reset my VM I probably could have done
the whole attack in about five or six
minutes and now granted I'm skilled so
this idiot might take a day to do it but
that's the thing it's not a lot of
effort it's not a lot of energy and
there's there's step by step ebooks that
you can put on your Kindle to tell you
how to do it and that's what we're
seeing so much of this and why we have
to stay vigilant even if we're small
companies there are literally you know
tens of thousands of people out there
doing this stuff and know they're
leaving no stone unturned no company's
too small to have them come after them
sadly and we really have to bolster our
defenses and remind ourselves that this
has become you know weaponized toolkits
that are available in the open market
and sadly in most countries in the world
it's legal to sell these tools right
including Canada in the United States
there's nothing it's illegal to use them
but it's not illegal to make them
because you could argue oh if you are if
you wanted to argue it was illegal to
make them you would have to put
Metasploit in jail because that's all
they're saying right well we're just
building a kit like what's the
difference between Metasploit in an
exploit builder I mean tech support so
that's a challenge right that's why a
lot of these people do it they don't
want the risk of going to jail and
they'd rather sell the tool to some
other idiot and let them take the risk
and then in a lot of them are going to
jail we're having more far more success
put than putting people away than we
ever have there's been more arrests in
2017 than I recall cumulative ly ever in
this space and specifically in the
criminal space not you know not the
controversial things like malware hunter
at DEFCON but like genuine criminals
that we should be quite pleased are
behind bars or off the streets and and
and it's been increasing lately there's
been you know we're finally getting a
rhythm between Europol and Interpol and
the FBI and the RCMP and and the
Australian Federal Police etc where when
we know somebody is truly bad we're able
to take action and we're starting to
have a lot more success so don't be
discouraged but I also encourage you not
to become a
somewhere entrepreneur tomorrow and on
that I will conclude my talk I hope you
found that entertaining and informative
and thank you for being generous about
my mistakes and my glitches and my
problems but I think I was able to
provide all the content and I hope you
enjoyed it thank you
[Applause]
you