okay you can probably kill the lights
whoever's leaning on that light switch
you guys hear me okay all right
all right so this this talks called
Microsoft just gave the blue team's
tactical newts and how red teams need to
adapt so I'm Chris Thompson I'm the red
teaming or ops lead at IBM x-force red
my job involves conducting red team
operations against really large banks
and defense contractors and more mature
targets I actually graduated from state
about a dozen years ago and I I teach
the network and mobile pen testing class
at night here I probably hold the you
know probably some unofficial record for
the most f-bombs dropped by an
instructor here but but we do have a lot
of fun in the class
my main goal from teaching at night at
say is just to help to grow calgary's
local technical security community so if
that's if you're kind of offensive
minded or defensive minded please come
on out we meet every month second
Thursday ish of the month at the bank
and Baron down in the basement most of
the time but check our Twitter feed for
the right right info so why this talk on
Microsoft advanced threat analytics and
threat threat protection you know Andrew
had that quadrant up about different
research you know why why people are
driven by different research his
quadrant kind of lacked the beer driven
research I was just kind of saw that
something was coming out from Microsoft
and I thought nobody was taking a look
at it so I wanted to spend some time on
it I've come up against some really good
distraction when I've been testing some
large fortune 50 s lately I've come up
some really good against some really
good detection strategies
they've got tools like sis Mon and
AppLocker and II met in place
they've got event lock forwarding they
were using products like CrowdStrike and
silence for host behavior analytics and
tools like rapid7 and user insights for
domain behavior analytics so when I saw
that Microsoft is coming out with both
host and domain based analytic tools and
that advanced threat protection was
going to be built directly in the
Windows 10 I knew this was an area that
needed some more focus especially when
these products are further integrated
this fall like we just saw with this
Tuesday's fall creator update in Windows
10 so I gave the original version of
this talk at Def Con which was the first
talk on evading and bypassing ATP and
was only the second on ata Nicole Nikhil
sorry had just presented on ata two days
before my DEFCON talk so there was a bit
of similarities in a research but we we
also found quite a lot of different
things so that was great to get some
different perspectives on the product
and because we're so early in the
history of these products I've withheld
a few techniques that I'm presenting
later at blackhat Europe in a month
Phish so check my Twitter feed and I'll
put a few more out there so to kind of
set the stage when I developed our TTP
or tactics techniques and procedures for
the IBM x-force Red Team I put a really
distinct emphasis between host and
internal recon so those are very
distinct phases and you'll see why when
we start to deal with products like ATP
and ata in a minute and really to become
better red teamers and operate against
more mature blue teams we need to gain a
solid understanding of what indicators
are compromised our tools and techniques
are leading by leaving behind you know
what commands might be caught by
different script logging what's Flag
double by sis Mon and and more
importantly how we can learn to use
techniques that can avoid user behavior
analytics so my lab set up real quick
it's not running on an old compact force
area it's running a couple dozen boxes
sabirah from alberta is actually giving
me all that space so if anyone from
there is here thanks a lot I tried to
run the commands against his you know
multiple different forests and domains
and hosts just to verify the accuracy
but that being said it is a test
environment so it's hard to replicate
real-world corporate domain traffic
especially when we're bringing in
behavior analytics because you know
we're we can simulate regular user
behavior as much as we want a lab but it
might different obviously from what's in
in the real world so to give an overview
of ATP this was the original dashboard
no you can see alerts on the left talks
about the status of different machines
it's active on more than two million
devices right now they get almost a
billion security events a day that they
go through this is the cloud dashboard
of ATP that everything reports into an
ATP provides host behavior sensors
similar to products like CrowdStrike the
difference that is that these sensors
are built and embedded directly into
Windows 10 Pro and enterprise and the
second release came out 1703 in the
spring and released three was just
bundled with two days ago as fall update
or Windows 10 1709 these sensors collect
and process behavior signals from the
box for example they process the
registry file and network communications
and they send all this sensor data or
telemetry data to the cloud for further
processing you know sometimes these
alerts can happen is as soon as five
minutes sometimes because they're
chugging all the data in the cloud it
might take a few hours attackers could
use that to their advantage if they're
going
quick smash and grab but because we're
talking about more mature target so that
it's going to be hard to do that type of
smash and grab we got to go low and slow
and we need to go with a more mature
methodology so this is the you know if
you're investigating alert there's
PowerShell Empire being launched we can
see that even though it was a encrypted
or uh uh skated
sorry payload it D office gates it on
the fly and shows exactly how it was
launched if there's lateral movement
from that box it talks about where it
moved to and what processes or
techniques were used to perform lateral
movement as a blue team you can see you
know the hash associated with that
initial payload and you can see it hit
two machines you got the option to
quarantine those machines and then
you'll see that pop up if you were one
of the infected users released three
that again just came out on Tuesday it
was expanded to include Windows Defender
antivirus the new advanced threat
protection or ATP it also came out as
Windows Defender exploit guard so if
anyone's used Amit this is the new Amit
it's now Windows Defender application
guard device guard firewall and
credential guard the third version that
just came out also provided expanded
support for operating systems so some
initial support for 2012 and 2016
I'm sorry 2012 r2 and 2016 and a bit of
Linux support as well and and really the
focus of this released 3 was to
consolidate the entire Windows 10
security stack into a single pane of
glass you if you have some binoculars up
there you can see that we have device
guard firewall cred guard all those
technologies I talked about reporting in
for all the devices we see by OS we see
which ones are missing patches we see
you know
and exploits being launched or certain
payloads being caught up in the top-left
corner and now in release for Microsoft
bought a company called hexa date and a
lot of hexa Deitz
IP was around auto or mediating some of
these things so if an initial infection
is is found it's gonna automatically
analyze you know all the files and
processes and services and drivers on
that infected device it's then going to
look for certain i/o sees it's going to
look at different end points across the
network that might have had the similar
IOC s and then it's going to auto
quarantine or mediate them so it might
use windows firewall to block command
and control traffic to the attackers box
it might you know remove a file if
there's more Advanced Options that need
to be taken it'll wait for the operators
approval but you know pretty interesting
stuff that's coming out the pipe from
from Microsoft so far from automating
defenders out of a job I think
especially for smaller shops this type
of product will really help them to
augment their in-house capabilities and
allow them to free up some time to
really start to focus on more advanced
threat hunting so if we actually look at
advanced threat protection in play you
know here's launching a novice gated
PowerShell band it's caught
here's launching a much more heavily
obfuscated command still caught this is
you know when we talk about PowerShell
Empire a lot of cobalt strike payloads a
lot of them are based in PowerShell so
when you take things like the obfuscated
Empire project and whatnot this is still
gonna catch them and we'll see why in a
minute
so with PowerShell Microsoft gave us
this amazing framework attackers have
been favoring using PowerShell the
executable powershell the core or the
windows management framework for several
years because it's so flexible and
because it's so easy to use we've seen
some awesome tools as attackers come out
you know frameworks like empire tools
like powerup
unmanage powershell powersploit nishang
power view user hunter and bloodhound
and all of these you know a lot of these
are deeply connected with with
powershell but now that microsoft you
know got us all developing tools and
attack frameworks on top of powershell
they started to implement heavy logging
and heavy d obfuscation technologies
into powershell so they're trying to
take those shiny new tools that we've
all come to rely on away so if if you're
not familiar with with all the new
improvements around windows management
framework 5 here's some are so you know
we're doing powershell script prop
logging trans transaction and
transcription logging it's looking for
suspicious strings
it's enforcing a constrain language low
mode it's got the anti-malware scanning
interface which can put all the office
gated PowerShell commands through to the
antivirus engine and check those for
malicious signatures but you know I
won't spend too much time on these but
if you are you know an offense or
defense you really should be familiar
with these especially as they're
becoming more core to the the security
stack and because PowerShell are sorry
Windows 10 and 80 P are enforcing
Windows management framework 5
you can't even downgrade to PowerShell
version 2 anymore because they've
removed it all together in the latest
creators update so that was a free bic
technique to downgrade to to get around
all those new technologies I just talked
about Oh we'll just go back to an
earlier version of PowerShell get around
all that you can't do that anymore
because they've removed support
PowerShell version 2 in the latest
update so common techniques that also
leverage like w script shell or also
caught you can't use not not powershell
and just call the windows management
framework directly because you know it's
all forced to use the the version 5
which has all those technologies so you
know we we start to see that attackers
common techniques are being caught
across the board
you know and it's pretty good at
detecting a lot of these signed binaries
that are used to launch malware
executables it's pretty good at
detecting abnormal behavior that you
know maybe you're connecting out to a
newly registered domain or to a tour
service and so a lot of the initial
execution or attack vectors that that
we're performing are getting caught but
you know there are some options for
gaining initial foothold we can use
obvious gated Java or VB script payloads
that don't have kernel32 API
declarations so just like cactus torch
we can use signed execs to load cobalt
stages payloads or we can you know
continue with either encrypted or
obfuscated techniques that are used by
veil or shelter to get around some of
these but the the challenge doesn't stop
about on getting on the box initially
that's the easy part we can all you know
fish somebody and get on the box
initially and maybe that payloads caught
maybe it's not maybe we've used some
crazy technique that just came off a
twitter that morning and an ATP hasn't
been updated yet the challenge is not
getting on the box initially the
challenge is the commands and tools that
you need to run after you get on the box
so how do you perform new process
creation without getting caught how do
you check for privilege escalation how
you check for vulnerabilities on the box
to actually escalate your privileges on
the box and take over it how do you get
around preventive controls like UAC and
AppLocker and emit against drain
language mode and PowerShell logging
when it's all going through the
PowerShell and or sorry the ATP sensor
so you know as an attacker some of these
commands might look familiar to you for
doing hosts recon so understanding
what's on the box
understanding what antivirus is in place
seeing what programs might be vulnerable
on the box who the users are more info
well the system
but these are all pretty much caught if
run in the same time period so instead
of you know using these typical commands
we need to move towards different
opportunities like using WMI so we can
we can get around detection by just
using WMI either through the wi command
line W Mik or calling the W my schema
directly
I spoke to Microsoft and they're looking
to really improve W my detection in the
upcoming spring release apparently
they've put some detection into just
Tuesday's update but I haven't had a
chance to test it out yet also not
detected is if we kind of go back to
living off the land and using host only
information gathering techniques that
directly call window AP windows api is
through raw sockets like meterpreter has
got the railgun post module but before
you use those you want to make sure that
those Metasploit modules are only using
local api calls when you use stuff like
local min search that's going across the
network and that that could be flagged
they also use a lot of non host only API
is in those scripts so you want to
review them first Kobalt strike has a
number of modules that are also API only
and we also want to make sure that again
we're sticking to focusing on host recon
and not going out against the network
because we might get caught by ata so if
we look more at common any virus or
bypass techniques a lot of these won't
work as an in menu might be able to read
modify the registry but that won't take
effect until their next reboot you could
also modify file permissions maybe but
it's super noisy and easy to detect and
unlike other next-gen AV products like
CrowdStrike you can't just uninstall
them from an elevated command line
because it actually requires a signed
off-boarding script you uninstall ATP
and the reason you can't stop these
evenness system is is do to protect
process light or ppl it's a mechanism
that was introduced in Windows 8.1 that
transfers many of the security
restrictions applied to the system
process to user mode processes but it
hasn't been widely implemented until
just now the binary is signed by a
Windows cert with the windows ppl
verification cert the extended key use
property there and after the process is
launched as protected Windows uses code
integrity to only allow trusted signed
Microsoft code to load into that
protected process
17:03 or Windows 10 1703 also added the
binary signature policy which helps
mitigate some process injection
techniques as well if you want to know
more about ppl Alex ion ask you has
extend extensively covered ppl and older
blog posts of his but until now again we
haven't seen PBL's widely implemented so
james Forshaw had a from project zero
came out with a ppl bypass specifically
for Windows Defender ppl and you could
basically modify the trusted installer
path to say when I launch trusted
installer I'm stopping Windows Defender
and deleting Windows Defender service
and then I started and so that was a
great bypass it doesn't work in since
the spring release for ATP because ATP
now runs at the windows ppl level
instead of anti-malware ppl which
defender does and the process is
configured as not stoppable which is key
which we'll show you in a minute and
when you try to modify that you are
getting flagged by ATP as we see at the
bottom there so the ATP sensor
communicates using the
windows telemetry service the the same
thing that everyone is complaining about
on the internet you know three years ago
when Windows 10 came out how there's so
much telemetry data being sent well this
is how they're implementing it telemetry
uses the when HTTP services and that in
API is independent of your proxy browser
settings but however it will follow a
proxy settings within the user registry
that any user can add things to so we
can simply just add a registry key that
says use my sync Holling proxy script
and what that script says is anything
that is going to the Microsoft domains
they're 480p put them sinkhole them all
to the local box otherwise return them
directly to the internet so you're not
impacting regular traffic now this
technique apparently might have been
fixed just now I haven't had a chance to
properly test it yet I do have another
unprivileged technique but I'm saving it
for your blackhat once I've had more
time to disclose it to Microsoft but
when we talk about privileged techniques
this is one of my favorite quotes
recently from from Matt Graber and it
can apply to a lot of different
technologies along the kill or a lot of
activities along the kill chain a lot of
bypass techniques rely on having
privileges on the box
and while defenders can do their best to
reduce the number of users with local
admin and harden their box it's
inevitable that some point in the future
an attacker is gonna fish one of your
users with an exploit or technique that
your org didn't patch in time or maybe
some configuration abuse to become local
admin once they get on the box it's
extremely important that defenders
implement redundant detection controls
on a box so that if an attacker does
manage to initially get on that box as
local admin or quickly upgrade their
privileges and disable a TP your crowd
straight for example you also have
redundant logging controls in place that
use things like sis Mon and WMI logging
and are sending those all through
his event forwarding and with windows
event forwarding it's all free you can
pick it up on a network share that's
protected and analyze that data in your
sim so you really want to make sure you
have these these redundant logging in
place in case somebody has privileges on
the box but with that said here's some
privileged techniques for disabling a TP
so even though a TP was a ppl in release
to the diagonal entry service was not so
you could just stop it
in tuesday's release they did apply a
ppl not only to diag track but to
Windows Firewall in another couple of
other services but they didn't flag them
as not stoppable so we can still kill
the telemetry service by using James's
technique to both stop direct track but
more importantly to stop the service
from ever running again so we can stop
it but ATP is gonna start it right back
up in five minutes so importantly we
need to change the executable to diet
track to just some blah
so that way when ATP goes to start
dyeing track so it can send out all its
alerts to the Internet we just say now
the diet tracks we've we've killed it
another favorite technique the line this
is script I wrote basically similar to
the the proxy settings we take all the
destination URLs for Microsoft we search
the IPS and then we add a block on the
Windows Firewall so we're actually using
Windows Firewall Microsoft's product to
block Microsoft's other product you know
and and this technique works really well
to also block win RM sis mons alerts
being sent by windows event forwarding
scum you can use the same technique
about against other cloud-based next-gen
antivirus like CrowdStrike
where if you know their destination IPS
you can block them and and system on or
sorry windows event forwarding is even
easier because instead of
having to know the destination advance
you just set the the process the origin
originating process the reason I didn't
set the originating process is ATP or
its its various executables is because
Microsoft keeps putting out new
redundant methods in place like release
three I just found a new dll called Mir
which looks to do some other background
communications so instead of trying to
play cat and mouse and keep blocking all
those different new ATP processes I'm
just blocking the destination James also
put out an awesome technique to become
trusted installer itself you know if you
had a Metasploit shell and you became
system you could take over trusted
installer but I think that whole process
is a lot noisier than this this is
basically just saying debug the
privilege and start a new process as
trusted installer and once we trusted
installer as we can find here we've
added ourselves to that privilege we can
just rename ATP executables that aren't
currently in use so one of those is the
sense CNC proxy which uses dog track to
communicate out to the internet and
because it's only called every five
minutes it's not currently in use a week
we can modify the the executable we can
just say well we'll rename it to blah
and that way the next time ATP goes to
communicate out and send an alert it
can't launch that process and can't
connect out to the Internet
another thing we can do I found in there
is not very well-documented ppl removal
function in me me cats which allowed you
to remove ppl protection it was
originally intended so you could inject
into L SAS and steal all the credentials
but it uses a kernel mode driver to
target down those PBL's so we do have to
launch a run at kernel mode driver but
because sense is listed as not stoppable
we can first remove the ppl protection
and then we can you know basically do a
kill - 9 or at a skill and and just kill
the process outright and for that point
on we can disable the service or what
else we want to do to it
so out of all those different kind of
techniques I think Windows Firewall is
the easiest best approach it's very fast
it doesn't require escalating the system
to become trusted installer it doesn't
require some Mimi Katz kernel-mode
module and once we've blocked ATP and
event log forwarding and system on and
scam or whatever is running on that box
we can do whatever we want to the box
and and the blue team's not going to be
none the wiser the problem with using
Windows Firewall and why you might want
to use those other techniques is because
when organizations have implemented
other third-party firewall products like
say McAfee hips it takes the place over
windows firewall rules and you can set
you know passwords to protect McAfee
hips and by the time you've removed all
that from McAfee hips you've created
enough noise and alerts gone out you've
been caught so you might want to look at
some of these other techniques instead
but you know we're not worried about
creating noise on the the box itself
we're more worried about alerts going
out to the internet or ATP flagging
network traffic so now we can actually
you know we're at the point where we
have control we have an initial foothold
in the organization we can run whatever
we want against the box we can run
whatever we want from the box we need to
start looking at being stealthy against
or stealthy for what we're running from
the box against the rest of the internal
network so Microsoft put out a product
called advanced threat analytics
captures traffic to domain controllers
it runs as a service on the domain
controller and basically it's intended
to to catch a lot of the techniques that
you see there I won't go into detail on
that slide but basically it's
the current version runs in your
organization the future version which
they just announced and I don't have
access to it yet
because it's in a beta trial is they've
actually taken a TA and moved it to a
zero and now they're calling it as or a
TP not it not a t I don't know why they
chose that naming convention but it will
be living in the cloud and on-premise a
screenshot for the people in the first
row basically you have the console you
you start to see alerts so if somebody
created a new account that had two admin
rights
somebody tried passed the hash if
somebody tried to create a golden ticket
or modify a sensitive group all of
that's you know gonna be flagged by it
by a TA might seen a little alert pop-up
if you're the administrator of the
attack and dive deeper into details so
you can see the history of the user the
time where they moved against what
resource is by what domain controller
pretty detailed in order to do this some
of it is based on just reg acts like hey
we expected to see stronger encryption
and use and we didn't so we're gonna
flag it but some of ata is based on
learning behavior so it needs to know
that Bob and accounting shouldn't be
connected to these DevOps servers and
over the last six months Bob never
connected to them and now he is we're
gonna set off an alert based on some
other you know machine learning as well
so whenever possible when you are on an
internal network and you want to be
moving laterally around the network you
want to be leveraging RDP history and
PowerShell command history and whatnot
so you can simulate
you know legit traffic as much as
possible and avoid these user behavior
alerts so now that we're at the point we
can run those commands without getting
flagged let's look at the next
activity's an attacker would perform so
that's you know identifying
infrastructure interest doing some
Active Directory recon trying to find
password vaults and sensitive sequel
servers and file shares and and
different intellectual property you're
trying to avoid IPS and whatnot
so often when you get on the internal
network you're you're trying to do some
DNS queries to find out you know where
the DNS servers are what can they tell
us about the layout of Active Directory
we're more sensitive boxes are a lot of
that's gonna get caught if you're using
brute force tools like like fierce or a
lot of nslookup queries singh goes when
you try to use a command like net user
slash domain it's gonna see that you're
you're not blending in with active
regular Active Directory traffic very
well and you're doing using Samer and
doing some reconnaissance against held
up and and the reason that gets flagged
is because you're looking for so many
random account properties like the full
account properties which which no user
should be doing so we need to look at a
lot stealthier techniques to get around
that
so not detected is if we initially use
PowerShell to grab a list of computers
which is pretty normal traffic on the on
the domain and then remove any domain
controllers from that list
oh sorry step ahead so you know grabbing
the the different group members grabbing
the the different infrastructure all of
this is pretty regular traffic also not
detecting and this is my morph a more
preferred technique is enumerated all
this against
local W my namespace so believe it or
not on the windows box that we got a
foothold on all of this information or
most of it it's copy that is stored in
the local W my local namespace so we can
query all the group memberships who the
domain admins are who the you know
sequel mins are all that directly
against the Windows 10 computer and none
of that traffic actually goes out on the
local network so there's no chance for a
TP 2 or sorry ata to catch it you know
and we can even since a TP 1.8 they add
a different Active Directory user roles
for ATA admins so we can even query for
the existence of this group against the
local box and know if a TAS and use in
the environment or not so that's pretty
handy before we start sending traffic
around the network so if we use the
default user hunter or bloodhound
scripts and we we query all the servers
on the the network and we try to find
out who's got a session on that file
server or that terminal server or that
workstation and we use that to plot out
an attack path by default that's going
to get caught you know it's a super
valuable technique and a lot of
attackers are using it right now because
it takes the guessing game out of trying
to know what box to attack next or what
workstation or what user I have to go
after to get the privileges I need to
get to my target so by default options a
lot of that's going to get flagged right
now same with you know using tools like
user hunter and net sesh that's gonna
get flagged as well but we can get
around being flagged if we just remove
the domain controllers from the list of
hosts that we're careering so if we feed
it a host file that we've we've removed
all the the domain controllers out of we
can gather all of that information about
every other box on the network but just
not the DC's and because it's not shut
no traffic's hitting the DC's to find
out who's logged into that box you as a
session ATP or ata can't flag on it
because it never sees that traffic and
then just earlier this month the
Bloodhound guys actually just added a
flag and that says exclude DC so that
that takes makes my technique a lot
easier because they just added it right
into bloodhound so now that we've found
out where our target users are where our
target boxes are who we need to go after
to get the prints that we need we can
start to look at lateral movement we can
leverage all that information so hey is
pretty decent at detecting PS exacting
wi exact against the DC itself and it
may detect different lateral movement
techniques just based on abnormal user
behavior so again that's when we want to
try to replicate normal traffic as much
as possible
SBN her service principle named
enumeration and kerb roasting is not
Kerberos ting is not detected it blends
in with regular traffic - well they
maybe they'll they'll improve this in
the next release but right now I can say
tell me where all your your s be ends
for your sequel servers are and then
give me the SPN ticket or the Kerberos
ticket for that service once I have it
you know my team has 16 GT GT X 1080
GPUs that we can crack that that
Kerberos ticket with it within a couple
of minutes so we can get the credentials
for any SPN service account across the
network and crack them within a couple
of minutes so now we have those
privileged accounts that we wanted and
we even know where they're used so if I
have sequel admins and they're logged
into sequel servers I now know I'm safe
to log into any sequel server because
I've a TAS gonna know that that's
regular traffic
and I can also avoid any authentication
events to the domain controller at all
by just generating a silver ticket with
that service account that I just created
and so you know I won't go into detail
and silver tickets because we don't have
too much time but you know this prevents
us from having any authentication event
against the domain controller this is
strictly against the local sequel box or
a local IAS box and all of those logs
are strictly on that box also not
detected is abusing 80 object access
control entries so with the bloodhound
1.3 attack path update we can enumerate
80 object access control entry entries
and visualize those attack paths with
bloodhound so not just the sessions that
are on the box but now we're enumerated
some random user through 20 different
delegated control groups has access to
this box and instead of having a huge
guessing game we can now visualize that
in a couple of minutes so we can say you
know invoke bloodhound give me all the
vehicles and bloodhound well that will
tell me that Abbie Abbie Edward is a
member of the help desk who has
delegated rights to the sequel box and
they can reset the password of web
service who is then added men to Apple
one my target and I can get all that
information in a couple of minutes where
if you were trying to figure out this
information before as an attacker this
would take like days or weeks of
guessing and creating a crapload of
noise on the internal network and this
is this is minutes now so we can abuse
those permissions and out ourselves
you know to the sequel admin group and
now once we're in the sequel of Ming
Group we can temporarily reset the
password of the web service and then log
into the app and again we can avoid a TA
alerts because that web service is
supposed to be a be allowed to log into
Apple one
now in you know it's Forest Active
Directory forest 2012 versions you can
set protected groups but nobody does but
if sequel admins was was flagged as a
protected group ata would flag on that
because you've modified a sensitive
group but but nobody has that in place
and Rohan Andy and will from the Spector
ops crew recently covered how to reset
that users password back to their old
password based on their password history
so you know if we perform this attack it
at midnight and by 8:00 a.m.
we've sent their password back to
whatever it was before nobody's the
wiser that that we actually perform this
attack I check that link if you want to
know more about their research so
passing the that the ticket or over
passing the hash that's caught you'll
see that you know we're passing just the
ntlm value but if we go down we look
that we look and see that that no way no
AES keys are being passed and that's how
it's flagging on that because it's
expecting AES keys to accompany the ntlm
hash so we can get around that and not
be flagged for passing the ticket over
passing the hash to move laterally
around the organisation by simply just
including the AES key along with the
ntlm hash and I found it was really hard
to find out how to get the AES 128 key
so I I found out that you could just put
all zeros in there and it would still
not flag on it so as long as something
is in that setting you're you're fine
and a TA won't flag you also not
detected Nick Hale covers covered in his
talk a lot of movement around sequel and
it makes sense because just like silver
tickets are the authentication against
sequel is to the local sequel server
it's not via Active Directory especially
those accounts aren't tied to Active
Directory they're all sequel off so you
can target essay accounts and compromise
sequel boxes and then use that and use
any trust relationships between
different sequel servers to move around
the network and never be seen by a TA
and never create an authentication event
[Music]
it's also a TAS not very good at look at
monitoring between different child
domains and especially child forests has
no visibility between forest so you have
multiple forests trusted forests in your
organization you're gonna need an ata
instance in both forests and I believe
in both your major subdomains for it to
detect accurately but I won't repeat
Nick Hills research in that area but you
should check out his link for that so
once you have access to these privileged
users it's now time to move towards
achieving the primary goals of our red
team engagement so these may include
dominance over the network and you may
or may not need to become a domain
administrator I was just testing a huge
bank last about two weeks ago and we got
on the box
Kerberos stood got service account was
able to gain access to their SVN via the
service account so their whole code repo
and demonstrated that we could gain
access to this all the bank's trading
algorithms all without ever doing you
know any lateral movement or remote code
execution all of it was just be a
Kerberos thing so you might not need to
get domain admin to achieve your
objectives right but it certainly helps
but it comes with its own challenges you
know your other other objectives might
be gaining access to that sense of
information or code repos like I talked
about or just you know specific
financial data or sensitive file shares
so DC sync is a common technique to grab
80 the Active Directory database which
effectively you're just saying hey
I'm a domain controller send me a copy
of the Active Directory database and the
other domain controller says here you go
we're obviously a TA could flag that
pretty easily as suspicious because my
workstation is not a domain controller
why am i doing that request right so
it's pretty easy to flag DC sync so even
though it was the fastest you know and
easiest technique to use in the past I
wouldn't recommend it anymore
partially detected in the loss it wasn't
detected all in 1.7 and 1.8 it partially
detected it when we used the WMI Shadow
Copy so we're basically just doing a
shadow copy like a backup event on the
domain controller to dump the NTDs bit
and we can do that without having to
call the Shadow Copy admin direct
executable directly by using WMI but
this is now flagged as a low severity
event in ata not because we got a copy
of the act directory database but
because an attempt was made to connect
via WMI to the Active Directory Mercer
to the domain controller so you know if
you saw this you you might this is a low
severity event you might just ignore it
where in reality we got a full copy of
the Active Directory database with all
the admittances or and all the user
creds and everything like that not
detecting another technique if we
execute Mimi cats directly or remotely
on on a domain controller in memory via
win RM or PS remoting that's not
detected well you might be able to
reproduce it user behavior Analects
might spot it but I couldn't reproduce
that as a blue Timur this is pretty easy
to detect if you're running sis Mon on
the domain controller as well as as
hardening who can actually remotely log
into the box over win RM or PS remoting
you can just block that attack path all
together
same goes with raw disk access so if we
just directly connect to the raw disk to
copy the NTDs study date and system file
without starting any services or
processes or injecting into anything or
elevating the system that's not detected
either but again you can detect that
else s injection arad this access with
system on just like past the hash golden
tickets are going to be detected because
we're only supplying the rc4 not the AES
so if we supply the AES key we're able
to grab a golden ticket it's not flagged
by ata so some takeaways we're doing for
time oh pretty much up so you can grab
these slides they're on the internet but
really what you want to do from a blue
teaming perspective is implement that
second line of defense don't just rely
on that shiny tool that some sales guy
pushed down your throat to to be that
you know Silver Bullet you want to put
in a lot of these backup detection
methods you know CrowdStrike and ATP and
all that are good products but there's
always going to be a way around them
because people like me are motivated to
get around them and whether the
techniques public or not people are
still gonna be motivated so you want to
make sure that you're forcing the
attacker to create as much noise as
possible so you can grab those events
somewhere and flag on them you really
want to integrate I know you know in the
past a lot of it men's or like our on
Windows 7 and now we're on Service Pack
one we're gonna skip Windows a we'll
skip 8.1 yeah I will probably skip
Windows 10 until you know we have to
move Windows 7 over just because it's
under life I highly recommend you look
at how your what's it called foresting
green something I don't know how you're
ever
ever evergreening there you go
environmentally-conscious term yeah so
however you're getting rid of those
windows seven boxes and moving to
Windows 10 you instead want to look at
your your release cycle a lot better and
say ok there is a security benefit to
moving to you know release 3 that just
came out not just a hey we'll plan for
it in 3 years from now you know
Microsoft's got this new release cycle
that you should really investigate
sometime into and see that some of the
security benefits from doing that as
well from a red teaming perspective we
really got a return to living off the
land and only leveraging these awesome
PowerShell tools after we're confident
we can run them against the box and not
get caught by PowerShell logging in all
that crap so we want to make sure we're
disabling ATP and event log forwarding
before we start to use those fancy tools
we really want to review RDP in session
history and whatnot so we can emulate
real traffic and real users connecting
to a certain box as much as possible so
it's not flagging somebody from
marketing connecting to the dev ops box
we want to focus on a lot of information
gathering techniques and lateral
movement techniques that don't connect
communicate with the domain controller
and don't authenticate to the domain
controller so looking at the local WMI
namespace queries looking at Kerberos
sting and SPNs and creating silver
tickets and and evading or avoiding any
authentication events due to me to the
domain controller whenever possible so
big thanks to all those Turner hashes
take a picture of that and follow those
people they're amazing they really
helped me along with my research this
was actually the first formal research
project that I did and at times I
definitely regretted it because it was
so much work but at the same time it was
super interesting because it forced me
to learn a lot of techniques and you
know the amount of side paths I went on
and new techniques I learned just by
picking a product
trying to attack it was was awesome so
even if you just start doing research
against some random new security product
that's out there with no goal and doing
a talk or putting a paper out and just
do it for your own benefit I highly
recommend it so thanks everyone for your
time and come on out to Cal sec