deaveon say na deter and security
professional he's done a lot of work
around lock picking and is on a bit on
the board sorry for for tool the US lost
my note the u.s. organization for lock
Pickers he's here today like I said to
talk about the elevator hacking and I've
seen this talk a couple times myself
it's very entertaining very
informational so please big hand for up
for deviant alright I kind of wander
around a little bit I'll stand this way
so you can see past my wall of elevator
locks and such if i'm still on camera is
that good okay so yeah who are the
people who put this crazy talk together
well you heard a little bit about me my
name is deviant i do physical
penetration work i do physical
pentesting physical evaluation my buddy
on this one was howard payne Howard's
not here with us today but he is an
elevator consultant and way more
responsible and knowledgeable in this
field than I ever could have been if I
hadn't met him so I'm really grateful
that he reached out to me he saw me
giving a talk about big buildings once
hotels and the like and I mentioned a
little bit about elevators and do just
got in touch he was like man you have no
idea this industry does it take security
seriously at all so we started to have a
good time with it speaking of not taking
things seriously hackers sometimes don't
take things seriously now elevators are
generally safe elevators actually are
not responsible for injuries all that
often when they are their minor there
you know trip and fall of something miss
levels at a landing the few times in a
given year that people are injured by
elevators grievously they're usually
proper elevator techs who are working on
them at the time so that said there are
numerous failure modes that can occur
with elevators that will involve
grievous bodily harm if you screw around
with elevators because you think this
was a funny talk or cool or like I can
totally do that I am not responsible if
you like you know trap your leg between
the door sill and a landing sale or
something like that alright downer stuff
aside most of you are not that stupid
most of you are just mischievous
it's possible to break or damage or foul
up an elevator by messing around with it
in ways you shouldn't be now just
because you're smart enough to not rip
an arm off it doesn't mean you're not
facing like a felony criminal something
as simple as that if you don't know what
you're doing can cause tens of thousands
of dollars in damage this person wound
up with a felony charge just for trying
to you know helicopter himself on this
and snapping the entire like Saturday if
you don't know what you're doing you
probably shouldn't be doing it unless
it's in a controlled and safe
environment so we are we are security
professionals or at least Howard is I
just you know kind of tag along and
axially as long as you follow that rule
just you know don't be a jackwagon
you're probably fine with this and most
other kinds of hacking right so really
quick we're not going to break down the
every possible type of elevator system
that's out there if you saw the very
first time we talked about this at the
hope conference in New York how many
people get to hackers on planet earth
the New York City one hand render man
all right you should come it's coming up
this summer it's a really good time it's
an interesting time it's where we first
deal like a two-hour long talk and we
got weighed in the nitty-gritty of every
elevator system i'm going to give you
just some basics so you understand what
we're talking about here there are
essentially two types of elevator
propulsion systems there's overhead
traction where you have a machine room
up on the penthouse way above the
elevator using cables to hoist and
there's beneath threat there's beneath
pressure from a piston from a hydraulic
system usually the motor room will be in
the basement on a lot of those those
fundamentally are your two methods of
driving and elevator around a building
and you notice there's a penthouse motor
room or like a basement motor room the
motor itself the power of the elevator
is not like in the cab there's an
external machine Oh machine driving this
the cab itself is really just floating
along in the hoistway on some guide
rails and some rollers just letting
itself be centered and aligned as
another machine somewhere else in the
building drives it up and down now how
are you interacting with the elevator
well industry terminology you need to
know is fixtures there are all kinds of
fixtures there's travelling lanterns
there's hall lanterns there's of course
the car operating panel which is where
you input all of your cab calls there's
the you know the hall buttons there's
all of these fixtures most of which are
just push buttons also incorporating
some key switches talk about them that
is how you send commands to the motor
room in the motor room obviously we said
earlier we got some big winding hoist
motors up here you can have pumps in a
hydraulic room not as sexy but in either
case you are interacting with you are
sending commands to the controller the
controller is the brains of the system
that is what takes all the input logic
from you as well as from a number of
other sensors puts it all together and
makes decisions about how to drive that
elevator up and down in the hoistway
what other positions you know what other
sensors can you have while there's
positioning sensors right the elevator
needs to know where it is these are
roller switches known as limit switches
so as the elevator is getting close to
the end of its run it's going to just
trip these switches their simple dry
contacts and the controller is getting
input saying okay we're hitting slow
down one we're hitting slow down two
okay we're level with that platform or
you notice there's a fourth one there
it's like oh god you completely shot
past the final landing you're on the
final limit stop motor now like that's
an error condition that you can you know
have happen in an elevator the elevator
itself has what's known as a selector
when you are traveling up and down the
hoistway this device on the car itself
is taking input usually from a magnetic
style tape there are older magnetic
veins there's newer ones that use QR
code which is dumb but in general the
selector is telling the elevator system
where it is in the hoistway and we'll
talk about what happens if that input
gets a little goofy if something goes
very very wrong there are other machines
other devices up in the motor room that
would be the governors and the braking
systems here we see an old-time gut ball
governor we see a rope gripper
unintended movement elevators are really
good at arresting that movement upward
or downward travel so elevators
generally keep you very safe if anything
goes super wrong there's even the buffer
down in the pit and that giant spring
that giant piston that's not like where
the elevator sits and rests when it's
not in use at the bottom of its travel
that normally the elevator shouldn't
contact that but it is rated to to
withstand the
entire weight of the elevator loaded
fully at full travel speed so if you
overshoot the last landing you will not
die like normally elevators are actually
really good at keeping you alive just
believe me if you are not doing anything
weird if the elevators on automatic mode
elevators are exceedingly safe now there
are other modes of service maybe you've
been in a building somebody just tweeted
at us the other day they said hey why is
this elevator SE non stop am I you know
they had they tweeted a photo well
that's something called attendant mode
there are different levels of permission
you can get in an elevators cab if you
know how to unlock certain modes mostly
it involves just flipping switches key
switches or manual switches so attendant
service if you have someone in an
elevator operating it for like a hotel
they can decide boy this elevator is
full of people we probably shouldn't be
collecting more calls further up this
let me just let me reverse direction go
down to the lobby get these people out
of here non-stop or bypass as you see in
this photo similar function that's going
to zoom past any floor landings that
have registered calls it's not going to
dump those calls out it's just going to
ignore them for now also if you want to
ignore other like landing calls so I'm
not advocating you do this right I'm on
hey this elevator is really crowded
let's get down to the lobby hey check it
out a switch let's flip it I mean yeah
this is what happens on attendant
service mode it's also what happens if
you have a special key some buildings
are designed to not need an attendant in
the cab but to give Big Shot people this
kind of power to just run the elevator
without collecting other other demand in
the building that's called executive
service or sometimes VIP service the
idea of I want this cab just for where I
want it to go and I don't want to stop
anywhere else that can be pretty useful
mostly in a convenience way we'll talk
about some security implications of that
in other ways something you can do with
let's say independent service we'll get
to in a minute an interesting one
Sabbath service I don't know how much
you have that up here in Canada down in
certain cities like Miami Beach Florida
New York City there's a lot of people
who for their religious reasons don't
want to interact with switches and
toggles and electronics on the holidays
like an arrow in their holy days so what
sabbath mode well no not like black
sabbath mode it's it's literally it's
like
sabbath mode shabbat mode an elevator if
you've never seen this if you didn't see
Bill Maher's film religulous where they
talk about it what does it do well a
person can get in an elevator the
elevator will on a time cycle it'll just
go all the way up to the very top floor
of a building and without any user input
it'll just platform its way on every
floor all the way down letting people
egress at their leisure and therefore
they haven't actually like pushed a
button so I mean if you know anything
about elevator systems you're totally
registering all kind of inputs with the
controller by breaking the beam on the
doors so it's if you think you're
hacking God like I don't know how well
that's actually working out for you but
the thing is like if you can flip an
elevator into Sabbath service suddenly
every floor just becomes not only
accessible but like open door accessible
the elevator is going to go to every
floor and this might be a mode embedded
in your controller that you didn't even
know about something you should know
about and this is not even for
Security's sake but please talk to your
elevator service techs there are
optimization algorithms you can use like
peak service load bypass service if
you've ever been in an elevator that's
so full you know like they get angry
they start beeping on you like be uh
we're overweight somebody get out fat
ass like I used to be really heavy and
like that was usually my fault in
elevators right elevators know how heavy
they are you can use that input to your
advantage in the controller if the load
sensor says boy this elevator is really
full and I'm trying to collect more of
these Hall calls that are registered on
eight other floors I should probably not
do that I should just go wherever it's
going usually the lobby and get everyone
the hell out so you don't have to be
that elevator that platforms are like
every floor and the door is open and
you're standing there with a bunch of
other people you're like oh sorry like
you can enable this kind of stuff to get
your building moving around faster you
can enable anti nuisance modes where if
somebody presses all the buttons too
quickly or if it detects no passenger
has broken the beam on the door sensor
so that like boy why did we just get
eighth floor calls when no one got on
the elevator you can totally have that
sorry to prevention
to get people keep going around a
building brands das this is an anti
nuisance elevator where we just tried
that's amazing press all the buttons and
the elevator was like lull nope and it
would just dump the calls all out 23 and
boom out I said it's like over here
tells you where you are I'm going a
little fast by the way because we you
know we waited for some people to get in
so I hope you're bearing with me on this
stuff I want to get to the good stuff
later I said the selector tells you
where tells the elevator where it is in
its travel there's something called a
correction run again this is not so much
a security implementation but it's
really interesting if you've never
experienced this if the elevator gets
mixed up on its inputs if the motor says
all right I've wound this far and my
motor generator my encoder says I've
gone this far but the selector says no
I've actually gone three floors if the
elevator kind of panics this is well why
is this not matching up the elevator can
sometimes run at slow speed usually
inspection speed so it's like one
quarter normal speed and it'll park all
the way at the bottom it'll travel the
whole hoistway until it basically re
learns the hoistway and then it says
okay I'm satisfied my inputs are
matching again and all of a sudden poof
it just works normally and if you've
ever been in an elevator that suddenly
didn't go where you wanted it and then
when really slowly like what has
happened you start freaking out if
you're claustrophobic it's probably just
a correction run you should report that
to the building management if that
happens there's something went wrong but
the elevator tried to self-soothe and
there you go what about like these kind
of buttons Oh what's halfway in between
floors or something what's well no
there's all kind of odd quirks in the
elevator industry if you add floors if
you have rear doors if a split-level
building is platforming at half floors
there's a lot of strange stuff you'll
see especially on the badges on the car
operating panel totally tweet photos it
like me or Howard Payne we love that
stuff and we will usually how it'll
explain it instantly he's like oh yeah
it's totally a Dover impulse system you
can see it was modernized in 2007
because the nature of the fire keys you
got there and he i bet you there's a
rear door turn around show me those rear
doors on the door buck like he'll just
spew on twitter and your end the person
replies like wow how'd you know that it
was one blurry photo totally the kind of
stuff we love talking about we talked
about peak mode obviously why is your
elevator
forming and parking itself at like the
top floor if it's the morning when
everyone's trying to go up you can set
the floors where the elevator will idle
and wait for people at different times
of the day stuff that's a little more
interesting not so much up here you
don't have a lot of earthquakes up here
right there are modes in an elevator
where it will detect seismic unrest it
will detect if a building is swaying or
shaking or vibrating maybe up here you'd
set it off with like blasting and stuff
that you do to extract minerals but if
the elevator can detect problem
conditions again elevators are really
good at keeping you alive they will go
to the lobby they'll sit there with
their doors open and they'll wait what
if you have a different kind of unrest
though because we got a lot of irate
hockey fans sometimes what if you have
civil unrest there are error modes and
emergency modes that elevators can have
to not go to the lobby there's literally
a mode called riot mode and it's enabled
in some big like museums and other
places of culture where they want to
protect much of the resource and
whatever's in the building during unrest
outside in the streets the elevator will
literally run at normal operation around
a building on the upper floors will not
platform at the lobby will not open its
doors for the lobby it will not like let
people storming in from the lobby get
into the building it's kind of neat
don't rely on that however this is the
first of our many points about don't
rely on your elevator exclusively as a
security protocol because there are
certain overrides in elevator systems
there are certain special modes not in
every elevator some are more prevalent
than others that throw a lot of this
security out the window so for instance
in medical centers in the US we call it
code blue operation or medical emergency
operation i'm pretty sure it's called
that up here to the idea of if you have
a key turn this key switch you now have
priority to control that elevator as if
you were a mini supervisor in that
moment if you just need an out or if you
need an elevator that's not there right
now let's say you are at the lobby I'd
let's say all the other elevators are
somewhere else in the building servicing
other demand but you're a doctor you got
a patient there coding out there on a
gurney throw in your code blue key it
will take the closest elevator to you in
any of the elevators in the bank reverse
its direction if necessary platform at
the
Bobby or wherever you used your key and
literally sometimes there's a voice
announced like this elevator is needed
for other purposes exit now and just
kick everyone out of the elevator and
then it's your elevator now imagine if
there's a building with riot mode
enabled because something happened and
the people are you know running through
the lobby tearing up what if somebody
has a priority service key does it a lot
which they're not super restricted right
does it allow somebody to suddenly call
your elevator that you thought couldn't
go to the lobby I don't know I don't
know how your elevator controller is
configured it's however somebody set it
up stacking those priority requests
there are interesting security blockages
that some buildings try to use for
instance baby theft mode if the little
baby LoJack that most hospitals use now
sets off an alarm because somebody moved
a baby without authorization it's
supposed to lock certain doors it's
supposed to set off an alarm is supposed
to lock the elevators I don't know if
you can override your elevator if it's
in baby theft mode if somebody has let's
say an independent key which we'll talk
about in a minute security recall is
another very similar feature this is
manually activated not by a little
sensor like an RFID but somebody can
literally say click this elevator
stopped it from going to this floor or
hey I think there's somebody suspicious
who just got on elevator 6 bring it to
this floor immediately and sit there
with the doors open so we can like
arrest them is your security recall
going to behave like a man trap or is it
going to get overwritten if somebody
else has these two other special modes
what do we use as pen testers what do we
do on jobs to override and throw a lot
of security out the window well two or
three things basically one of them I
strongly recommend you look into if
you're checking your security in your
own building independent service it is
far and away one of the most common
special modes it's built into most
elevators even if you don't see a key
switch or a toggle switch it might be
there behind a hidden panel independent
service here we see just manual toggle
switches for independent service it
basically gives you local admin rights
on that elevator now if there are card
readers enabled if there are security
lockouts and certain floors any number
of conditions that are supposed to
prevent you from moving around the
building most of the time I've flipped
independent service on an elevator
sure it has thrown those out the other
fun thing it also ignores all the hall
demand so if I'm in an elevator and I
flip it to independent not only can I
usually go to any floor even ones I
wasn't supposed to but it'll sit there
with its door shut until I tell it open
the doors I've hidden in elevators for
hours in like jobs where we kind of you
know saunter our way in during the day
nobody notices nobody's checking badges
I've just taken an elevator turned it to
independent sat there for four hours
like texting my friends and catching up
on Twitter waiting till the team outside
is like hey looks like everyone's gone
home for the day deve so I'll Drive the
elevator down to the lobby i'll just
walk open the door and let everyone in
and it's the perfect hiding place
because you know if you have a building
and the bank of elevators is like 8 wide
no one is ever like going to lunch and
be like oh yeah i wanna get some timber
all right man hey have you noticed
elevator 5 hasn't been responding all
day suspicious like nobody says that
nobody's you get on the first elevator
that gets there and I'm like snickering
away just some one time I rolled a chair
into the elevator to have somewhere to
sit there's like oh it's jaron gonna
take it downstairs and yeah like it's a
perfect hidey hole that most buildings
have and you might not realize that what
is more powerful than independent
service though because I say it it
varies how the commands are stacked up
maybe a certain floor cutout is still
enabled even if you flip independent
because it has usually not usually
independent throws all that out
guaranteed to almost always throw out
all your security is fire service mode
fire service mode emergency responder
mode is by code part of almost every
elevator at least here in North America
by code you might have someone who says
I demand that floor seven is the data
center and no one you need a badge and
you this and that the boss can have all
the demands he or she wants in the
elevator tech can try to program the
elevator all the way you want all that
gets thrown out the window if an
emergency responder needs to get
somewhere and this goes for old and new
systems so you can even see elevators
that they'll get retrofit they'll get
modernized it's called and all of a
sudden if you like look to the side view
here you can see this elevator on this
side didn't used to have all the same
fire controls
now they've got an extra panel that was
put in to come up to compliance this is
code compliance stuff the idea that in
an emergency if the elevator thinks the
building has a fire condition a smoker
heat condition which you can totally
fake either by exploiting what's called
the back net we won't have to get into
that or by manually throwing an elevator
into fire service mode which you can do
and usually it does not result in alarms
going off you can absolutely gain the
powers that an emergency responder would
have in an emergency situation which
means no security stops for you all
floors accessible go where you want by
the way there is one more powerful mode
than fire service mode it's kind of
crazy like who could possibly be more
important than a thin like a fire crew
and emergency responder crew any any
ideas yeah yeah the elevator text of
cells there's elevator technician
service mode there is it's called
hoistway mode also sometimes called
inspection service mode and it is
exactly that it is for getting into the
hoistway and moving around in the
hoistway to either inspect things
service things adjust things you name it
if you are in the hoistway if you are
running on inspection service running an
inspection speed is slow but it throws
everything out the window every possible
lockout every possible preventive
measure measure in every elevator I've
ever heard of outside of maybe some
crazy spooky federal buildings other
than that like everything is yours to do
whatever you want with if you're in the
hoistway hoist ways are effing dangerous
you and i'm looking to like all of you
probably don't belong in the hoistway
you can find little panels and access
shoots and things if you do a lot of
urban exploring I do not recommend you
ever go near this stuff now that said if
someone does there are run controls in
the hoistway there on the car top you're
going to see that later you should not
be screwing around with this if you
don't know the industry because this
industry again like if you're not from
this industry these key switch right
here this is the motor generator shut
down key switch that's if you need to
take one of the motors just out of
service if you need to turn it off how
do you think you turn shutdown
mode on in this elevator will you turn
shut down to on like that's the kind of
thinking that you need to know and if
there's a really bizarre as industry on
some of its controls if you don't know
how things are working you shouldn't be
messing around with them let me instead
show you us messing around with them and
then you can take this knowledge know
there are various kinds of elevator
securities that have been implemented
trying to prevent people from moving
around a building they can usually all
be subverted so disabling your ability
to just call an elevator is common it's
common in a lot of schools and other
environments where like the teachers can
use the elevator but the kids can't I
see it in airports a lot of the time so
either there's just no hall call buttons
or they're disabled by a switch now you
might have like a maybe even in a hotel
where like this was a little holiday and
I stayed at it looks like that's a
button but it's not this is just a light
an indicator light the only way to get
the elevator is to throw my key card for
my room into it it latches a call the
elevator arrives now you notice there
was another key switch right near that
button that wasn't a button right what
key switch was it it was red yeah that's
the fire control switch you can manually
throw the elevator that exact elevator
into fire service mode and it would
platform right away for you to here is a
little pin pad based system again the
floor call won't be registered the hall
call won't be registered unless you have
the pin this is in an airport what is
right below it a regular key switch that
either turns on or turns off that
functionality you might have seen key
switches in the cab these are called
floor cutouts so the idea of floor three
floor for you can manually toggle them
on or off these are not series circuit
like you're breaking the circuit that
operates that push button remember if a
fire responder gets in the elevator they
don't have time to figure out which
floors are unlocked and locked and like
mess with 18 keys this is all logic
gates and just because the logic gate is
closed by one switch the button still
works the controller is either ignoring
it or allowing it based on what you are
doing and what's special mode you're in
independent mode usually throws all
these out the window fire service mode
always throws all these out the window
the most typical elevator restriction
you'll usually see involves key card
systems right
so like big hotels posh hotels where you
can't get up to sir I think the hotel
i'm staying at Jack you and I are Thea
where the Fairfield and we need our
little khabar RFID key to get up to the
our floors there's absolutely ways
around that if the elevator is running
in special modes of operation think of
physically securing your elevator as
literally something you would have to do
like this like this is from a
corrections environment and this is the
only thing I would consider a very
secured elevator the idea of caging off
the elevator why am I like that's a
goofy-looking photo and it's a photo in
our slide deck because Howard was there
investigating an accident somebody
actually stepped off the elevator and I
think the hoistway door is closed like
and then they were pinned in like this
one foot space and they couldn't go
anywhere because they forgot that you
know that I don't know what the hell
they were doing they were maybe they
were trying to escape but anyway you can
sue anybody in my freaking country so
there they were taking photos of this
but why am I saying this is like
securing your elevator well think of
your elevators as just a giant open
stairway in your building and not
lockable and what you're about to see in
the next few slides should hopefully
reinforce that the idea of my elevator
is providing these security is something
that you really want to wipe out of your
brain and while you don't need to make
like a cage around your elevator that
stairwell analogy is valid and if you
want a really secure environment like
vestibule Ling off the elevator landing
area the elevator lobby landing like
that's your best course of action for
really secure floors so how can we
subvert just about everything we just
talked about their well when there's no
Hulk all buttons this is a funny little
video from a school
we see what happened there let's watch
the video
what the hell person anybody see what
they did shout it out yeah they stuck an
envelope or a paper through the door
they tripped the door sensor the door
sensor which will not work all the time
right but the elevator happened to be
platform dat that floor and they just
tripped the door sensor into popping
open because it's like oh so there's an
obstruction in the doorway let me open
my doors that completely works in a lot
of environments is this me recommending
that you just stick stuff randomly
through closed hoistway doors no no you
misinterpreted me sir no no don't do
that the key cards that the key cards
are super common in a lot of buildings
right so key card systems allowing you
access never discount the possibility
that there might be a little locked
panel and let's see here we've got it i
can write i can register a call to
senators shovin but i think the top
floor in this building for more locked
out so let's try like let's say 33 yeah
can't get up there I need that's a badge
reader right there but what's below the
barrier well there's a little panel and
literally a switch that says card reader
off
yay good moon card reader no longer
necessary and you can even flip the
switch back and reenable that load
already latched the call you can tell
this is an Otis Elevator it's actually
noticed series seven elevator is it all
be a p.m. 30 key that's on that lok pal
why do I know this kind of stuff well
because most elevators in default keying
on all of their fixtures they come from
the factory you need a certain way
that's name brands off brands third
market Brandt their party market brands
like an aftermarket brands if you've
never checked this stuff out and a lot
of people in the industry don't even
realize that completely possible that
you might have default keys for your
building it's like it's not changing
your passwords on router that you
installed in your building so yeah we're
just you know riding all the way up to
the top for getting some free whatever
snacks or liquor was at this crazy bar
something so yeah like literally card
reader on/off totally exists as a thing
in a lot of card reader based elevators
here it is in another elevator this is
in Las Vegas like what you think
security is a serious thing here's more
toggle switches in other elevators these
little switches which are sometimes
behind locked panels sometimes behind
hidden panels if you can get to them
there are a lot of ways of triggering
other modes of operation interestingly
enough and you'll start to see this in
some of the pictures people in the
elevator industry often don't realize
that these keys are repeating themselves
you'll sometimes even see like Howard
calls this elevator graffiti when
elevator text will be like oh the run
stop is khone one and the independent is
khone for it looks like fire service
mode phase one and two is that's an
innovations key switch cx-5 15 so people
are like scratching down notes to
themselves which keys work where well
Howard when he's worked in this industry
for year after year after year and the
way his brain is kind of funny like some
of ours is he just started logging all
these keys and then collecting all these
keys and now like Murdock monkeys
holding a little you know one of our key
sets up here not nearly as big as
Howard's right but we have the default
keys for basically every brand of
fixture and elevator system that exists
out there there's not there's like a lot
of names this industry there's not
at many names and if you're on it like a
pen test job like me or you know uh
novella for any of our team we will send
photos to Howard like we're debt we're
texting and we're like dude tell me what
this is he's like you know what it is
it's a slightly concave button it has
the indicator on top of it it's a
Schindler like I didn't know that he's
like yes you did you should listen to me
more so yeah like we there's a lot of
fixtures right but you can start
identifying them recognizing them and
knowing exactly what key you need what
can you need to test if you're testing
your own building out just because
something all looks oh this is all so
unique and every elevator looks
different no man no appt go like this
one right here super huge vendor of
aftermarket parts if you see that super
thick black halo with that Helvetica
font like epco all day long if you ever
doubts when I my job sometimes I like
text Howard a photo I'll be like hey man
I just emailed you something I'm texting
you I need to know what kita is he's
like to probably up go I'm like dude my
email didn't even send yet he's like yet
try it try F go it's probably up go you
know this and sure enough usually I'm
like damn it sup co one you're right
thanks even futuristic systems or what's
a futuristic cutting-edge like
destination dispatch elevators if you've
ever seen these where there's no
controls in the cab you register your
destination in the lobby and it directs
you to a different elevator says okay go
to elevator a go to elevator be some
hotels have that it just gets people
moving around the building more
efficiently every one of those has to be
able to operate in an emergency
condition for fire responders every
destination dispatch elevator has a
hidden panel with all of the floor call
floor buttons there that you can
register calls on sometimes they're not
even locked out sometimes if you pop
that panel you can just start ret like I
can go to 42 right there just it just
latches a call like it's a conventional
elevator controller but forget about you
know cutting-edge stuff this is an
industry that's still really in the past
with most of its controls so for example
these are all screenshots of elevator
controller software does this look like
super ultra modern to you it looks just
modern enough to be throwing it on like
an XP box on the network so you can
remote control it that's about it
they're running in dosbox environments
they're running in really old windows
environments there this is the nature of
the industry though the idea
oh wow we could we could totally put a
little Ethernet chip on our controller
board and I we can get that thing hooked
up to the network do some remote
management remote monitoring sounds
great remember this is not an industry
that focuses on security security to the
elevator industry means you not dying it
doesn't mean you not going to the wrong
floor so like here we go you know put in
your password right let's look at the
let's go ahead and look at the lift net
user manual for the default passwords
right this is every lift net install
unless you use the default administrator
controls to change the default user
passwords and hopefully like change your
administrator creds to do you think the
average elevator texts are doing that no
they're really not MCE another huge
supplier of elevator parts this is MCE
and jen and this is one of their
controller systems this is in their
manual they say hey if you have an MC e
system you want your remote support be
sure to create a user on your router and
for remote access call it MCE support
and be sure to set the password to MC e
support while you're at it go ahead and
set the router password to MC e support
just set everything to MC e support so
that we can always get in you know
whenever we need to do something to your
elevator for like that's in the manual
that's what they're telling customers to
do yeah you get that from vendors all
the time right how about from like your
government like the government itself
them the regulatory bodies the elevator
industry in working with the government
developed something called the fe ok one
the fe ok one was designed to be like
the supreme godfather fire key because
again every brand a fixture kind of had
their own fire keys you know Otis was
UTF and innovation was the x5 15 and on
down the line so they say there's too
many keys as if there's like a big
problem with this like you know you show
up at the job site you get the I guess
if a fire truck is driving around town
and there's this building that building
and the other building they want one key
ok I get it feo k 1 and if it's going to
be this powerful key shall only be
possessed it says in the code my
elevator personnel responders etc no one
else should have this key so like any
good government operation in bureaucracy
they put the direct bidding code in the
freaking code when they put like that's
in the published code document been
there since 2007
yes up here you use the fe okay one on a
ton of your systems if you see a tubular
key in an elevator like you got some
elevators in this country right there's
some big ones it's probably feo que one
if you're not sure of it you know I'm
going to give you a better than fifty
percent chance it all the ones that I've
allegedly heard somebody test totally
we're feo que one but just bear in mind
it's again it's all naked on the inside
to right so the car panel you're just
you know you're just clicking dry
contacts together if you can interact
with the rear side of that panel which
no one should ever do including whoever
this person which is totally not me in
this video should ever do because you're
talking like you know those are live
mains back there there's some serious
voltage on the other side of this panel
you shouldn't be touching but let's say
you have a situation like this where the
swing panel was not really secured
somebody may have just popped that with
a knife blade now you can't register a
floor call to like I think the top floor
of the building here to a floor 12 we
want to see floor 12 well there's
independent service mode and if you
don't have the key for that key switch
well again it's just contacts you can
pull those apart and bare hand it like
an assface drunk somebody might just
push those two contacts together now
independent service mode is enabled now
you can go ahead and register and latch
a call on two floor 12 and because
you're an independent mode you have to
manually like drive the door shut or
open and whatever you want to do
completely janky and hokey right
absolutely valid on a pen test you want
to get somewhere you don't want to be in
a building why look for stairwells that
are unlocked or weird back like I've
seen up the fire exits somebody once
said to me I was like yeah I'm gonna
look for the elevators the first thing I
always look for because half the time
it's going to take me where I want to go
and I don't even have to use my legs all
that much so there we are now we're just
you know reconnecting everything back up
that's completely what we do is pen
testers and buildings inside of a target
facility if I can find an elevator I can
usually leverage that elevator how do we
do it most of the time it's way cleaner
than that ugly video most of the time
it's you know key switches if we give
the keys which most of the time we can
find the keys correctly because they're
not change their default keys we can do
stuff like this here is an example tar
yep where we use fire service the front
of the building had a security lobby it
had a guard it had you know please sign
in are you on the list and we thought we
might be able to bluff by them if you
ever seen a good social engineering talk
like good stuff right we said all right
well they seem to be we're looking at
him through the lobby like glass for
like yeah they're looking pretty tight
in there I don't know if we can just
breeze our way in let's walk around the
building a little bit around the back of
the building though there was an
entrance it was on the parking deck
which already they thought no one could
get to because you needed a badge for
the company to get the gate arm to like
let you up the ramp yeah we walked up
the ramp completely blew the clients
mind they're like how did you get to
that backdoor I was like I I have legs I
went up the ramp I walked up the ramp so
from the back parking deck we went in
the back door which you'll see was like
locked but it wasn't like locked and
then there was an elevator and this
elevator we could call it at the lobby
but we couldn't go anywhere because we
needed a badge or not and as you'll see
we shot a little bit of footage and the
client was so effing stunned that they
pulled security camera footage they said
you didn't there's I know that you can't
take that elevator with us not you got
in the building a different way pull
that footage they'll order the client
thought we were lying here's here's some
footage of us so we're on the back
parking
the door's locked but like it's not like
much well that's a whole other talk so
now we can call you and now things are
going to happen very quickly with
multiple sets of communities that are
kind of out of spec on day one place too
now that elevator jewel is Rick this
elevator is running on fire for us right
now with no keys in the ground floor
plan he's not but we can drive it up to
whatever floor we want to go to
and then if we manually drive those
doors open you can hop out on whatever
floor we want to and the culture of this
building is such that once you were
upstairs like no be blessed you must
have come from that security desk so you
were just presumed good we just want
this all that for a couple of keys that
almost anybody can get you shouldn't be
able to get these keys this was in New
York City however so in New York City
there's this infamous key right this
like 2642 key which everybody freaked
out when a newspaper like printed
pictures of it i'll print a giant ass
picture right here for you it's not like
i'm breaking you know some crazy
security literally it's a unrestricted
blank cut 2 to 6 for 20 that's every
elevator in New York City that's the
fire service key you can do that in any
building you shouldn't I'm not telling
you to somebody could or if you want to
do the whole greater new york region
this is for effing states including my
original home of New Jersey 3502 key
unrestricted key anybody can cut this
there are many many statewide keys that
if you know how to find them or maybe if
you can't order them maybe you can order
like the key box like this is in the
state of Indiana down in the US every
building can have its own fire key but
you have to use the Indiana key box well
you can order it you just can't order it
with the key what can you do however if
you've never tried tubular picking we
will totally show you tubular picking
later if you pick a tubular lock not
only does the lock open but then you can
decode it and you can cut your own key
ma'am there's the Indiana key and we
then like could return the box if we
wanted to back to the vendor we did that
in Minnesota we did that in kentucky
kentucky uses medico systems medicos a
nicer key system right they ship you the
box unlocked because you have to mount
it on the wall you can't buy the key you
can buy the box you can then take the
lock apart very carefully and if you've
never done any physical like eval
hardware it's not that hard to inspect
pins inside of a lock and get the
bidding including the sidebar bidding
for this medico lock oh and we did it in
Florida which is split up into all
different zones and we did it in
Louisiana and we did it in Virginia and
there's other states where if you look
at their state codes they just have
state keys the
keys are not as restricted as people say
we have built our own pen testers key
rings and they are always with us on
jobs leveraging the elevators to go
where you want them to go is not hard
for an attacker to do many times it's
stupid easy when like for some reason
one of your maintenance staff or your
elevator contractor they want a keybox
on-site look around near your machine
spaces look for little key boxes many
times they are very simple locks they
are either wafer locks or tubular locks
their pickable or you know that that
telling you man that fe ok one is a
bitch for security let me show you a
little feo que one story that we added
into our our little stick here right
this is a key box up above an elevator
right in the lobby landing of a big
building we could walk in from the
outside act like we're just going
upstairs in the process use an FeO k-12
pop that key box it contains the master
maintenance and override keys for the
building it contains the emerg the stuff
that an emergency responder needs to get
anywhere in a building is in that box
here's maintenance space keys this
maintenance space which of course is
also where like the camera system is for
the building all the security hardware
was in here all the routers switches
everything was in here then the next key
on the keyring was the key box it was
another key for the maintenance room the
motor room that has a key box in here
that we were able to pick open what does
that have well it has a hoist way drop
the hoistway door drop key like will
show you what that can do to but the
idea of one little box with one little
key that let me into everything an
entire building including like this is
the fire service key for the building
this is the alarm panel key for the
building these are the sprinkler
controls the sprinkler valves for the
building like I could run amok for this
one key one fe ok one did all of that
and it's all over the internet like the
fe ok one really needs to die if you
have any poll with anybody in a
regulatory sense please help them
understand the people especially really
unscrupulous people are selling these
keys without a care in the world there
are like this this is somebody who
actually works in the elevator industry
and that's they operate multiple
companies under other names selling
parts kind of out the front door and
then selling other keys out the back
door and that is that is not cool bro
like the idea that any boner can just
get an Fe okay one walk around a
building yeah render yeah
yeah render saying that if you have the
if you know the spec you don't even have
to buy something off that you know ebay
you can walk to a locksmith who can code
cut keys yeah is this even looking like
he does he has walked into locksmiths
and say I need a 7 pin key 7-pin tubular
key and I need to cut to this bidding
you know and they're gonna charge you
right they're gonna charge you out like
40 50 bucks maybe at the high end 20
bucks in the low end four or five you
can get to mickey's up here for four or
five bucks damn exchange rate or
something man shit I gotta get my keys
up here yes so Renner does point out
that because the standard never
specified clockwise or counterclockwise
people have sometimes mate like some
injury switches have made them wrong so
technically it's supposed to be cut
clockwise that is the standard for all
tubular keys if you're looking at the
you know anyway it's funny that you
sometimes you know fire text now carry
two of them but the idea that you can
just get this key for very little money
and do everything that I'm talking about
very easily that's kind of creepy in my
mind way creepier especially when my mom
so this presentation is that hoistway
stuff though right we had another job we
had a medical facility where we could be
on a low floor we were like on two or
three and we wanted to get up to the
fourth floor which had this radiation
lab and all the drug storage and stuff
and we said well we can't seem to move
around the building easily and it was an
older elevator it hadn't been modernized
with fire you know fire mode that we
could access which is not always
required in some parts of the US we
could use the hoistway though how did we
use the hoistway well we did this
completely out of spec this is not how
you're supposed to do us we let the cab
kind of drip drop down let it rafal
itself to the lobby checking this is
with a drop key this is what you can get
in that other little black box you saw
look the elevators drop down a little
bit to the almost to the next floor pop
the hoistway door we should stop to the
worse the older we can then get on the
car top and I said car top has run
controls right so here's all of us
getting in on one floor and we're going
to just ride the car top up the hoistway
which you're not supposed to be able to
pop open when you're like in the Hall
like we were do you think there's any
kind of long or key or anything you need
on inside of those doors to pop them
open no there is not that door good
elevator in 91 melco is going up going
up we can drive it from run control box
that was pardoned let me show you can
drive yeah or we can drive it up or down
kick Oh
injured on to is this smart or safe no
on their legs in a three-stop but sure
enough work really well there is no
protection in the hoistway from the
Union just send it down if you are in
the hoistway especially on the car top
for safety of life reasons you have
absolute control you are the God of that
elevator in that moment from the motor
room from the machine room you can
literally remake the universe though you
can change variables and inputs you can
change conditions on the motor if you
saw like Barnaby Jack stalk the late
Barnaby Jack anybody remember him before
he passed so he talked about Jack
potting ATMs where he would literally
say this bill hopper it doesn't contain
twenty-dollar bills it contains five
dollar bills spit out for more at a time
like he would change variable you can do
that you can do that from the controller
if you know how to interact with the
controller software you can do that
right from the dry contacts you can
click and connect just jumper wires to
various contacts and jump out certain
sensor conditions these are part of the
tests that elevate our Tech's run on a
routine basis so you're about to see
what looks like this is not an overnight
this is it
the elevators full travel ski
but it's going to blow by a bunch
jumped out those sanctions
that happens regularly you know it has
to be tested well they can absorb error
conditions that's something an elevator
Tex get to just do with like test
weights if they have to lug and put in
the cabs really cause if you don't know
what you're doing hey baby messing
around to go to room terminal these her
daughter those kind of cramped in there
you don't know what I did the shopping
fair warned shock surprise but like an
took three are like this is my spare
wire but you can see just be careful you
should this is more than you shouldn't
be doing this evidence side of things
there was an elevator accident that was
investigated by Howard and his team and
what you're seeing here is a clip from a
video like you'll see when an elevator
was jumpered incorrectly when the
safeties were not interlocked
incorrectly the elevator was running
without the door being fully closed yet
and this ultimately whoop that ain't no
good and that caused a pretty grievous
injury thank God it was in a hospital
the woman was saved but she was it was
bad dude it was bad it was ugly so if
you don't know what's going on in your
motor room if your people are getting
into your motor room they shouldn't be
up there we'll show you a little bit
about that later really quick and I want
to go too far over on time we've got
some more slides but any leg old school
phone freak hackers there's phones in a
lot of elevators usually by code these
phones have regular phone lines pulled
through the motor room through the
traveling cable into the elevator car if
you can get to that phone line there's a
lot you can do like we always travel
with some little you know we used to
have lineman's but packs but they were
big little little handset like the the
tiny this little like tiny it's like
it's a phone that fits in the palm of
your hand keep one of these around
getting to that phone line you could do
interesting stuff making calls from
within the building making calls out of
the building if you call the phone
itself like if you can figure out the
elevator phone number which maybe it's
just written inside the panel like this
you can the phones are usually
configured to automatically pick up
silently on one ring then you're just on
the call with the elevator now
what do you do with this information
well you could be mischievous and be
like I'm watching you I'm the elevator I
know what you did like you could try to
make people think they're crazy I guess
that's fun in its own right or you could
just call up an elevator and not say
anything at all just listen people use
elevators like refuge secluded spaces
where they have very private
conversations and in very big cities
when government officials are in town
for like you know g8 summits and stuff
you are not going to be too surprised I
bet if I tell you that the phone company
has specialists come in and they're like
all right why is there activity on this
line all right what's that line doing
that's that's not an elevator why is
what's happened trace that call like
there are people who will try to listen
to elevator calls and like listen to the
elevator phones there are sometimes just
intercoms in the elevator again usually
based around the machine room in the
machine room to turn that elevator in a
come on listen to what's going on in
there your elevator is not a secure
environment both for restricting
movement or for having private
conversations really quick just on the
building owner sort of supervisory side
if you have authority in your building
especially if problems in your building
fall into your head please be aware that
you should have a little more active
oversight than a lot of people do over
their maintenance like this is a this is
a maintenance control program this is an
MCP just freaking blank and it's not
like this is a default one that came out
like this was an accident site and
Howard and the guys showed up like wow
you guys even fake it you didn't fill
anything out at all you just you had no
maintenance for years okay that sounds
good guys they're all kind of weird
hacks in the industry they once looked
at these circuit breakers for one
elevator that was you know having some
problems they flipped open the panel
those aren't fuses those are just busbar
they're just there's bar connected like
yeah we kept blowin fuses we don't know
what to do so you like that was your
solution like yeah well kept running
like that is the kind of stuff that
elevator texts will sometimes do to get
because when the elevators down everyone
is hopping mad everyone's saying fix it
now fix it fix it fix it fix it you get
tired of going out there elevator text
will do something like this look at the
second fuse from the left see anything
odd about it is a little bit
here a little bit of wire wrapped around
that fuse it's taking just enough of the
resistance load off that fuse to prevent
it from blowing and that's totally what
they did old-style relay logic systems
where there's contacts clacking on and
off this is carbon dust blowing all over
the inside of a you know controller box
which is conductive because that's what
you want inside among all your contacts
right that's just great conditions there
they were on one job and they were like
why are there so many oil pads and like
bags of oil dry in the corner of this
hydraulic motor room so they looked at
the tank they popped open the controller
you know the pump system there was like
a dishpan oil pad saturated there's so
much oil spewing out of this thing the
hydro fluid was soaking the test tag
which was illegible and they're like how
long has this been like this and the
building owner was like mmm and yet it
falls on to that building owner it falls
on to plant ops and maintenance if
there's an incident this is something
that could be going on and if most
people don't have keys to their own
motor room most of the time you can't
easily get into your motor room that's
something your elevator you know
contractor is doing stick your head in
there once in a while ask what's going
on find out if there's any kind of
conflicts of interest or collusion going
on there are situations where inspection
says this needs to be replaced but does
it need to be replaced like this is a
test tag this was an inspection on an
otis elevator system and you can see the
inspection was done by otis like unless
the inspection techs name was Otis this
is bullshit there was a job that Howard
was on where they kept tree roping the
cables tens of thousands of dollars
every time they were run oh your cables
they're getting pretty tired cables
going bad we got to restring it Howard
crawled into a maintenance space found
the original install cable from the 70s
was still tagged they had never changed
the cables they were just charging the
client over and over and over and this
is the kind of I'm not saying this is
common elevator industry's no more
corrupts are less corrupt than any other
industry really but if you're getting
like red-tagged if you're not taking an
interest in your elevator systems this
can happen in the
motor generator like ripped off the one
of its you know install plates that was
a final acceptance test for final
readiness it was not ready but more than
that like you're not that's not your
main stick right security is and follow
your building procedures badge people in
and out we've breezed into buildings
just say oh we're here for your
semiannual were the elevator folk you
know people just oh yeah I guess so you
need the keys or something like oh thank
you yes if your security guard is an
elevator you need to fire that security
guard it's not doing what you think it's
doing and when people say oh what's the
worst that can happen like this is an
elevator security system this is you
need a badge and it's a biometric and
you need pin gets three factor
authentication why this is in an airport
but what does it have this is fire
service mode and that jewel is lit this
is us able to drive an elevator from the
sterile zone or start from down in the
parking zone to the sterile zone of an
airport now you can do that on just a
test and simulate what could happen or
somebody can buy a four dollar feo que
one and actually get to the sterile zone
from the output of open areas own very
easily and the more you know about
elevators and elevator controls and
elevator key boxes you're going to start
seeing them places that you maybe
weren't noticing them before I hope and
start thinking about them and start
thinking what this means for your
building there are regular elevator
Tech's doing your parts oil and grease
and there are elevators security
consultant text and there are two very
different animals just because your
installer or your tech says oh yeah just
an elevator can never go up without a
badge that's what they might think
that's probably not reality talk to
someone who knows and if you're in that
crowd we're like I really don't want my
elevator on the internet but I love the
idea of remote monitoring there are ways
to do that like you don't need to set
default passwords like manager and
technician and just call it good and
kick it down the road there are
third-party ad on systems that will give
you not excuse me non ethernet-based
connectivity to your dry contacts for
monitoring things like what mode is my
elevator and why is it running in this
condition you can do that talking to the
right people final tips and i'm going to
get out of the way will get us back on
schedule if you are ever stuck in an
elevator or someone you know is
in an elevator first of all don't panic
remember elevators are very safe they
are not likely to cause you harm you're
not going to run out of air you're just
gonna have a story to tell there's some
things you can try if the main lights
are off if only the emergency light is
on you got bigger problems you're pretty
much not getting out of that elevator
until it gets power maybe even emergency
power which a lot of elevators have if
the main lights are on though try to
press door open a lot of people if the
elevator errored out or didn't latch a
call or doesn't know where it's going
the door operator might work just fine
press door open or press door close and
then press door open to recycle the door
operator reset it try it out maybe it
opens place calls to other floors place
Lobby calls there may be a condition
where it's expecting a badge input of
some kind or you don't know you don't
know what could have gone wrong but try
all the other floors just because one
floor isn't working others might make
sure you are badged in if you have any
kind of credential keep trying it for
every single floor if you're authorized
start trying those key switches man if
I'm in an elevator and it's not working
after 5 10 minutes I'm not waiting
around for someone to maybe answer that
phone I'm going hey let's see what these
switches to independent get there's get
us moving get us out of here and lastly
verify the cab doors are closed you
don't ever reach through the cab doors
but if you can just put the flat of your
hand on the door see if it has any
movement try to make sure it's fully
closed and interlocked that will
sometimes be causing the error in a
really badly maintained elevator now if
nothing else works yeah go ahead call
for help with your phone with the e
phone whatever you need to do things to
never do never go through the top hatch
it's very popular in TV and film it
doesn't get you anywhere you need to be
now you're just on top of a dark filthy
elevator and if the power is out you're
still not getting it anywhere I would
not recommend this never exit a Miss
leveled car a badly miss leveled car if
you have to jump that is too far if you
can step out of Miss leveled car you're
fine unintended movement is how people
get pinched this is how really bad
things happen this like this is a
maintenance janitor or something letting
people out of a stuck elevator
he's wedged the doors open with like a
bench I I'm these people whatever maybe
they were in there for a while looks
like a lot of them were in there and
they got tired and they get hot they
want to get out I would look right at
this guy I'd be like wow fuck a bunch of
you buddy i'm waiting for proper people
proper people emergency responders
elevator tex those are who you were
speaking to when you were getting out of
a badly miss leveled car keep all that
in mind stay safe the safest place is
usually in the elevator itself thank you
for listening I hope you learned
something and I appreciate being here
thank you very much you be available for
question here we're going to sign it
real outside and have all this stuff out
there if you want