hello everyone as as mentioned my name
is Julian Pileggi I am here to talk to
you about how to make use of your sim
and before I get into that I'll talk to
you a bit about who I am and will also
talk about maybe a bit of best practices
on how to use a sim I think though the
meet of the content will be probably
near the end when we talk about some sim
rules that I think are pretty valuable
and that you should consider
implementing if you have a sim and
you're trying to get some value out of
it and you're getting flooded with a lot
of noisy alerts I think what we're gonna
talk about near the end is going to be
maybe some higher accuracy hopefully
less noisy events that will give you
some value so like I said before that my
name is Julian Pileggi I'm a senior
consultant with mandiant in the Toronto
office I've been with Mandy it for about
two and a half years now prior to that I
worked in a large Bank in Canada doing
security operations investigations and
Incident Response
so obviously working with the sim in a
sock is kind of part of your day-to-day
I've got experience with ArcSight q
radar Splunk a bunch of other types of
sims so I've got a pretty varied breadth
of experience with different
technologies and this talk is not really
gonna be about a specific technology
it's more just about sim in general I
also talked at besides charm this year
and I trained or presented a training at
blackhat and Amir Khan or fire icds as
it's known now and if you guys will be
at sector you might see me again or at
blackhat Europe fun fact about me I can
type on average 120 words per minute I
probably won't speak that faster at
least I hope I won't but yeah I can
probably also type as fast as 165 words
per minute actually it's recorded not
probably so if anyone wants to challenge
me feel free to do that after the calf
tur the presentation disclaimer though
everything that I will be talking about
today is coming from me it's not really
represented of representative of maybe
fireEye or mandiant I mean a lot of it
will be very similar but keep that in
mind
take everything with a grain of salt and
also understand that everyone's
organizations are unique situations are
different
what I suggest or might say is good
or as best practice may not really be
suitable for your organization or for
your situations you have to take that
into consideration of course so like I
said we're gonna start off with some
best practices and we're first going to
talk about logging I'm not going to get
into this that in any depth really this
is very high-level but the idea here is
the kinds of logs you need to make sure
you have in your sim this is a laundry
list of things I put together based on
the kinds of things I think are useful
from my investigations or the experience
that I've had right when I see these
kinds of logs there's a lot of value
that you can get from them certain
things you can look for in them probably
one that I'll point out to you is
PowerShell times 3 the reason I say
times 3 is because of course if you have
upgraded to at least version 5 of
PowerShell you can enable all 3 logging
script block logging transcription
logging and module logging highly
recommend that you make sure you have
all those 3 very useful of course with
all the various PowerShell frameworks
for post exploitation activities that
are used by attackers and red team's
alike on the right side I've got some
things that are nice to have system on
top logs this is a shout-out to Kenneth
who did a pretty sweet training this
week on how to deploy this montt your
environment and monitor and look in
those logs using Splunk which is pretty
sweet
so that problem a bit of attention to my
mind in that in that sense but I think a
lot of these are arguable right some of
these you might say yeah we think these
are very valuable in some you might
disagree with that's totally fine
this is just my opinion and a couple of
other things I think that are very
valuable that people don't always
consider metering data here I've put
SCCM that's one capability or one tool
that you can use for metering data
people don't think of metering data as a
security tool or like security
information because it's not really but
it keeps track of information about
what's happening in your environment you
can get some really good stuff out of it
like for example applications that have
been used if the meter is just
monitoring how long the application was
running the fact that it was running
maybe that will give you an indicator of
compromise for a backdoor or something
damas logging we're gonna talk a bit
about tech specs the specifications you
should strive to ensure that you have in
your sim or the platform that you're
using as a sim and I've only got
a one slide on it which is not too bad
again I said it's very high-level but I
think there's one thing on this slide
that's gonna make most people's head
explode but most of it I think is what
you would expect right you ideally want
to have some kind of backup situation so
primary and secondary if you can
redundancy a lot of organizations they
don't consider a sim or a lot of
security tools as high availability miss
tier one right and depending on the size
of your organization maybe that's
reasonable but realistically if your
monitoring team or your ops team is
unable to monitor the environment
because your sim is down it can be
pretty pretty serious the second thing I
want to point out here is at your test
environment you should have a test
environment to test your code test rules
test changes to the sim you should
actually have a full copy of your
production data in your test environment
and a lot of people say that's not right
right because normally test environments
should not have production data however
in the case of a sim if you don't have
real production data you're not actually
testing anything right you maybe are
testing your ability to type the keys
into the computer and see if you can do
it in a test environment but it's not
gonna really validate whether there's a
performance impact it's not going to
tell you if you actually will catch what
you're expecting to catch so you really
need to make sure you have a copy of
your Prada in that test environment
specifically for the sim role based
access control that's a basic feature I
think that everything's got automated
aggregation by distinguishers this I
think is probably pretty standard but
the idea here is you want to be able to
aggregate alerts coming from the sim
based on specific distinguishers by
alert
so each alert might have a different
distinguisher right of course if you
have a sim rule that triggers on
suspicious emails the distinguisher
might be the sending email address
versus an IP address from a network kind
of correlation rule geolocation
enrichment is huge if you don't have
this in your sim it's actually very very
important that you have this geolocation
enrichment can be as simple as getting
like a max mind or IP to location
database hooking it up to your sim so
anytime there's you know a publicly
routable IP address the information
associated with that address can be kind
of added to the metadata for that event
and then you can use that to actually
create correlation roles and we'll see a
couple of examples of that later on now
here at the bottom is where I think a
lot of people sometimes have a hard time
you know swallowing this pill and that's
30 days retention is what you should
strive for across all of the logs that
you centralize near Sim can be very
difficult it can take a lot of storage
but of course it's very necessary and
I'll explain why in just a second but
before we get to that the second point
is that you should have you should be
able to query at least the last two
weeks of your data for a specific atomic
indicator within 60 seconds and you'll
notice I'm not telling you you need 256
gigs of ram or five terabytes of storage
I'm not telling you that because that
doesn't really matter it depends on your
environment and the kind of logs are
storing well you need to strive for is
the actual usability right and so that's
a measurement that I think a lot of
people can sometimes get to sometimes
they don't you know I've had this
reaction a lot of times where people say
what I should be able to do this in 60
seconds it's not possible right but the
reality is if you aren't able to get
access to the information in your sim
it's gonna make it much more difficult
to actually perform effective monitoring
and investigation and perhaps incident
response if you ever need to do that and
it is doable I mean this is an example
of a query I pulled for the last two
weeks I had to make sure it was doable
before I said this publicly but you know
it is doable in this case the query took
16 seconds other times I've tried it
takes 3040 seconds but the idea is if
you're looking for a specific indicator
atomic indicator not a complex
expression you should be able to get the
information relatively quickly in one
organization that I saw this you know
issue they had Intel that said that they
were being targeted and they needed to
validate whether the specific threat
group had actually made any
communication with their network very
straightforward here's five IP addresses
used by the threat actor we know they're
targeting you check your logs and see if
you've had any connections they said
yeah we've got a sim we've got 30 days
no problem except when they went to
query it for 30 days they realize that
the sim was under scoped and it was
actually gonna take about seven days to
pull the data and see if they could
actually query all the firewall logs
right so obviously not gonna be very
useful in that time frame and this is
the point I was referring to earlier is
that that dwell time the amount of time
that an attacker is inside an
environment before they're typically
identified by an external party or by
the team at the organization is a median
of 99 days
this informations pulled from the
mandiant m trends report that they
release every year based on all the
cases they worked on in the previous
year so 99 days was the median number
last year in 2016 and it's been going
down which is good but again if an
attackers in your environment for 99
days you probably need at least 30 days
of data right a couple weeks it's not
gonna cut it the longest case that I've
heard about where an attacker was an
environment was actually over 2000 days
right so that's 5 plus years then the
attacker was in an environment so in
that case I don't think the sim was
gonna help them too much now we're gonna
talk about staffing again very high
level the reason I talk about staffing
is because you need to know how to
appropriately staff one the sim and the
management of the sim but also the staff
that actually will use the sim right
because if you don't have users of a sim
tool you know there's no value to it
because you can't just plug it in and
turn it on it's not like a detective or
rather it is a detective it's not a
preventative measure right it's not
gonna just prevent attacks so this is my
kind of thought process on amateur Blue
Team whatever you want to call it I'm
gonna call it a blue team all right
you'll see three tiers within amateur
blue team you have a tier one right or
an l1 those are the folks who are doing
the day-to-day monitoring the initial
alert assessment triage
contextualization and the idea here is
at the l1 level someone should be able
to look at an alert coming from the sim
and within 15 minutes make a decision
about whether this is a false positive
or it needs to be escalated for further
investigation right potential incident
at that point of course then you have
your l2 or level 2 tier those are the
folks who will be typically doing that
investigation that analysis you'll
notice I put threat intelligence there
that typically is a separate group of
folks who are probably providing input
into the tier 2 and tier 3 teams as well
as your on team if you get to that level
of maturity and then of course the tier
3 you can see tier 3 is got your l3 team
those are typically like very skilled
folks right maybe your forensics guy
your
reverse engineer if you have that it not
a lot of organizations end up getting to
tier 3 again the hunt team also that
tier 3 level that's very mature level of
an organization not everyone gets to
that and that's something you'll
probably want to strive for but the key
star or the key player for us today is
this group over here right that I've
pointed out the automation and content
development group and you'll see I put
them kind of somewhere between two and
three because they're working really
with that tier 2 and tier 3 folks to
ensure that the content is being
developed for the sim as effectively as
possible now you see it a little number
beside each of these teams that little
number is a proportion it's not hard and
fast but it's a recommendation so if
your team was comprised of you know this
number of people you should have four at
the level 1 and the ratio is at 3 at
level 2 2 at level 3 etc if you have a
smaller team that can go down to two and
one and one and so forth but as I
mentioned the lowest maturity or kind of
you know where everyone kind of starts
from he probably are just gonna start
off with level ones and twos that makes
sense that's probably where we are for
most people you then expand and the key
here is after you've got your initial
monitoring capabilities down you then
expand immediately into automation and
content development right so a lot of
times folks leave automation and content
development so that's the sim
development that's the people who are
tuning and creating rules for a sim and
possibly other capabilities or
technologies as well that's where you
want to fit them in in this kind of
second stage of course after that you
probably want to expand out to get a
threat intelligence team or a couple of
thread Intel analysts again depending on
the size of your organization and the
needs that you have and lastly you then
get to threat hunting which is a great
topic that we won't discuss today
unfortunately so recap on a full mature
blue team and again the reason we I talk
about this is because the technology
itself is not sufficient I'm gonna tell
you about some sim rules that are super
cool but if you don't have anyone who
can actually implement these properly
and if you don't have anyone who can
actually investigate them properly
doesn't matter so a lot of times it's
important to understand that you need
the right resources and you need to use
them correctly in order to you know
effectively leverage what you're doing
with your security program now when
you're trying to staff the security
content development team or security
automation team of course you probably
want dedicated resources if you can one
or two is probably sufficient three is
ideal typically they need to have a
little bit of software dev background
and some IR or security operations
background red team is also perfectly
acceptable the idea here is I need to
understand what attackers do what
attackers might try to do what attacks
look like attacker TTP's techniques
tactics and procedures they're probably
gonna get this information from the
threat Intel feeds or group anyways but
they still need to have a good
understanding of what it is if you want
to make effective detection for it
because a lot of times people try to
develop sim content and if they don't
really understand the attack or why the
attack works or you know the details of
it they might tune it in a way that it
won't won't be effective any longer
without realizing it
so programming skills of course and
maybe some signature skills signature
writing skills like regex is a very
basic way of writing patterns snort cigs
PR i-- OCS there's a number of different
capabilities as long as you have a
little bit of an understanding of how to
do that you should be fine now we're
gonna get into content management how
you manage and develop this content this
will be a bit more interesting I think
and then we're gonna get into the sim
roles here's what I expect most people
are mostly interested in today of course
the use case development cycle looks
pretty much like any development cycle
right you need to have an idea starting
off with the plan and what you're trying
to detect what are you trying to detect
or correlate upon and that's typically
like I said maybe going to be some input
coming from your Intel team it could be
input from the hunt team if you have a
threat hunting team and they've
identified something that your controls
do not currently detect that would be a
great input alternatively it could also
be from you know anyone in the security
organization who's got a good idea of
something to detect you then develop
some pseudo code or logic try to
identify
by which tools and log sources you'll
need and then you need to implement that
of course in probably tests first than
production talk a bit about more that
and once it's implemented and you know
that it's tuned effectively that's when
you can operationalize it and actually
have people start monitoring it and the
biggest mistake a lot of people make is
they implement and they don't tune
before they operationalize and so what
you end up having is of course a
security monitoring team or you know
security analysts who are basically
overloaded and they're flooded with
alerts and it's impossible for them to
really assess and evaluate all the
alerts and then they end up missing
something that was really obvious and
the organization might get breached and
then later they go back and say well you
had you know an alert that told you but
if there's an a thousand alerts a day
it's not really reasonable for anyone to
actually expect them to catch everything
now when you're developing use cases or
use cases as a kind of a that kind of
term for correlation rules in a sim
that's the term that folks use so when
you're developing use cases when you're
making a library of use cases these are
the kinds of things you probably want to
track right you need to have of course a
unique name and number so you can
reference that specific use case of
correlation rule you probably want to
assign it some kind of category
personally I like to assign categories
that are associated with the attack
lifecycle or the kill chain right Mandy
and fireEye has our own attack lifecycle
there's a Lockheed Martin kill chain
whichever you use you know I think it's
good that's a good way to approach the
categorization severity of course is
subjective a description should be
enough to explain to someone who's
reading what this use case should detect
or this rule should detect so they don't
actually need to read you know the logic
behind it they should be able to get a
good understanding from your description
you of course do want to have some
pseudo code involved right so you've got
to think about that a little bit and the
stuff we're gonna see today I have 22
correlation rules we're gonna go through
and I've written pseudocode for each of
those and you can take that pseudocode
and then try to implement it and the
reason we use pseudocode is because it's
technology agnostic right you then have
to adapt it for your technology and also
for your environment depending on what
logs you have log sources you might be
using etc log source requirements I
mentioned before very straightforward
what do we need to make this accomplish
this associated reference lists
this is data that you need to populate
when you're first creating your sim or
when you're trying to make correlation
rules effective this might be something
like a list of all the server host names
a list of all the workstation host names
a list of all of the user names
associated with your IT administrators
etc these types of Lists that you may
want a reference in correlation rows
later on and lastly something that a lot
of people leave out of their library or
use case database is test scripts that's
just a step by step of how you actually
trigger this alert for real not in a
theory and then you will actually
execute that test script and this is how
you make sure that the sim is doing what
is expected to do so for the actual
development portion as I mentioned you
probably want to start off with user
acceptance testing right UAT that's the
test environment here after you've gone
from UAT
goes into the tuning phase and that's a
back-and-forth process between tuning
and production implementation so when we
get into that UAT implementation of
course you're just testing to make sure
whether the logic works and preferably
you've got your production data in there
so you can actually see the kind of
performance impact that's going to
happen on your sim once you start this
rule it could be very could be very high
impact depending on what you've written
at the thresholds you set
but once you're feeling comfortable with
that you need to tune it a little right
every organization will have false
positives the pseudocode I'm going to
show you a guarantee if you just try to
copy paste this into your own
organization there's gonna be some false
positive that I've never heard of that
nobody even considered was even possible
and it's going to be in your
organization so tuning is very very
important and then of course the
production about the implementation
should be the easiest part that's
basically just taking the content you
developed in your uit
you've already tested and tuned and you
just plop that into prod and that can be
of course done through change management
easily this is the hard part that can't
be done through change management easily
that's daily tuning again another thing
that a lot of people say not possible
and in some places it's really hard to
do that but that is what you should
strive for that is the ideal situation
is that you should be tuning rules and
events on a daily basis in your sim
which is of course why you need
dedicated staff and resources to do that
it's not really reasonable to expect a
team that's party got a number of other
things on their plate to be doing daily
tuning of the same as
now I mentioned that test script this is
an example of one of the test scripts
you might use for a use case or a
correlation rule that detects malware
detected on a domain controller very
simple not very cool but you know
obviously how do you test this well
let's create an AI car file if you're
not familiar with an AI car file this is
a file that will be detected by all
antivirus solutions however it is not
malicious it's just a plain text string
I believe with 68 characters is the
minimum you need for the AI car and it's
a specific set of characters written
right here you can find this online save
the file on your domain controller
validate yes we saw the alert validate
yes the antivirus clean this off very
straightforward but you actually need to
create scripts for everything in your
use case database now that use case
database or the library itself is one
building block from many and these
building blocks all connect in this way
they're all correlated I'm gonna show
you actually how you could fit these
together and how they should be fit
together but the idea here is that you
have your use case library or database
as the center of what you're doing for
security monitoring right these are the
things you're looking for this is how
you're monitoring and what you're
monitoring for that ties into an
investigations tracker some central
database where you can track the
investigations and lurtz that are coming
out of your tools whether they're coming
from your sim or somewhere else but
probably from your sim so your alert
right feeds into that Investigations
tracker the tracker references the use
case database or the use case library so
if an alert fires your analyst should be
able to click on the alert name and read
the use case library entry with all of
the details that we discussed previously
all those fields so that they can get
context on what's going on that use case
libraries then tied into the alert
playbooks or alert tasks this is the
actual steps you should take so having a
sim and having monitoring is great but
then you need to know what to do want
something triggers so that's what we
call alert playbooks this is different
than an incident playbook right this is
more what you do before you know there's
an incident you just have an alert you
have to validate is this alert actually
representative of an incident or
something we need to investigate further
or is it a false positive that we're
gonna queue up for daily tuning and the
last piece is your threat intelligence
database whether this is simply just
feeds coming from you know some sticks
and taxi feeds or it's an actual team
that's kind of preparing briefs for you
you also want to have that tied in so
that you can have that connection with
your use cases in your alerts again the
context is there in one place the
purpose of a sim is that central pane of
glass so you don't want to have people
having to go to different resources if
you can avoid it or at least make it as
easy as possible this is an example of
what you might have at a very high level
of the used case library names these may
not be that valuable I've made these up
you know based on things that we've seen
before or correlation rows we've used
before but the idea is more on the right
side here those tasks the alert tasks
should be defined and these will be
procedural tasks that your organization
would do in a regular basis these are
things you can document to a tee every
single time someone needs to get you
know information about a specific source
IP address it's gonna be the same every
time in your organization the goal here
is you can standardize what you're doing
you can make it more efficient and you
potentially could actually automate a
lot of this in the future right using
security orchestration tools that's the
new buzzword for automation right here's
an example of what you might see for the
alert playbook for an exe being
downloaded from an on categorize website
very straightforward there are six tasks
that need to be done these tasks can be
done within 10 minutes they could even
be automated and then all it takes is
someone to review the information that
they've collected from the collection
tasks and then make a decision about
whether this is a false positive or true
positive and we're going to give you an
example of an actual use case library
this is one of many that you could have
in this particular case there are a
couple of thousand use cases in this
library which is pretty extensive but
the idea again being that you have you
know a rule name some other information
associated with you I'm going to show
you details of those informations that
you could collect but the way that this
interlocks with the other components
right so here you can see we've got a
rule database I can go in and I can read
about
rulz I can understand what they are if I
so choose however as I mentioned before
that investigations tracker is where the
alerts will come into so an alert should
spawn in your sim that should
automatically generate a case for
investigation so when that generates a
case in your investigations tracker you
come with something like this right a
series of alerts the case that's been
generated and you'll notice the name is
correlated with something from the use
case database that we just saw are those
rules that we saw in the previous slides
maybe I was doom in any bit here yeah so
you can see alert generated this isn't
my investigation tracking database now I
can actually go in and I can action
these alerts and I can immediately see a
summary from that use case database
entry this is pretty small maybe y'all
zoom it in a little more here that
easier okay so you can see that that
summary information is right there
available that's what your need to
strive for you need to strive for having
this integrated with your sim so that as
soon as the alert fires a case is
created the case references the
information in the u.s. case database so
that the analyst or investigator can
immediately read the description and in
this particular case the actual query
that's being used to trigger the alert
now this is a big problem with a lot of
mm-maybe proprietary IDs is for example
they never want to tell you why they
detected something and that makes it
really difficult to understand how to
investigate it we don't have those
limitations with a sim because there are
tools we own them so it's very valuable
to make sure that your analysts can
actually read the contents of your rules
so they know how and why it triggered
this is a rule that detects 1 to 2
character executables being downloaded
not really very high fidelity probably
lots of false positives but it catches
some malicious things every so often as
well so as I mentioned before you want
to make sure you have that summary
available immediately and once somebody
accesses that they can read the full
details right so here you can see
there's more details inside for example
the confidence level severity any notes
the specific distinguishers it's very
difficult to see I know I think I have a
blown-up version in a couple slides but
here's another one for example dry
dextro j'en tried X is a malware family
that has a specific SSL certificate that
uses and there's a pattern
that you can detect may not be relevant
anymore these kinds of things change all
the time but the idea here is again you
have this information easily accessible
and when clicking on the alert because
these are tied together right you get
that same information automatically
populated in the alert details from the
use case database and you can see here
that the threat intelligence database is
also correlated as well here's a link to
whatever threat intelligence is related
to this specific alert I'll show this
for a second okay now the threat
intelligence database as I mentioned
ideally you want to have that integrated
so that you can see how all these
components are all in one we haven't
gone anywhere else this is the goal that
you need to strive for not always doable
but that's what you want so let's see
how this looks if I click on this use
case alert the alert brings me to my
description the description has a link
to my threat intelligence the threat
intelligence that allows me to read
about this specific threat and say ok
what is this what are the kind of things
I should be looking for are there any
other relevant materials on this threat
intelligence portal that you know I
might be interested in the last piece as
I mentioned before are the alert tasks
the alert tasks are what you need to do
when alert fires now in this particular
tool I've been showing you which I
haven't even mentioned what it is it
doesn't matter in this tool they call it
guided investigation the point is you
need to have a definition of specific
things someone should do when an alert
fires here is an example of what this
specific rule is customized for right
this rule says these are the things you
should check when this alert fires the
analyst goes in evaluates these things
and that makes their determination do I
escalate this or do I suppress this do I
close this now we're gonna get into the
actual sim rules as I mentioned there
are 22 rules we're gonna discuss these
are mostly high-fidelity some of them
I'll talk about maybe have a little bit
of a lower level of confidence but it'll
explain why I included them and we'll
have pseudocode as well I've made a bit
of my own syntax highlighting and again
the pseudocode is just something that I
came up with it's not gonna be something
you can implement immediately but should
be fairly easy to understand for most
folks who have a bit of background with
computers or boolean logic so the first
we're gonna start off with very
straightforward and some of these
actually might seem like they're really
obvious to you there are some people who
haven't heard of these before but this
one is very straightforward this is
successful remote authentication via a
tor exit node now a lot of people say
why do I care about tor well they're
thinking about probes from Tour Pros
from tor I agree if someone's just
scanning me from a tour as a node I
probably don't care that much I be a
little interested but I'm really
interested if someone who successfully
logs in from a tor exit node so you can
see the pseudocode here my event source
is specified in this particular case as
VPN or citrix right so my remote access
utilities if there's an authentication
success event and the IP address is in a
list that I'm pulling on the our for tor
exit nodes then I want to alert and
you'll see the dependency here is of
course we need some kind of tool or
ability to actually pull the Tor exit
node list which is public here I
recommend hourly and I've put a little
bit of a legend here all of the field
names will be in blue values in red if
there's a function or some kind of
operation that's gonna be in green and
if there's a list that we're referencing
so kind of reference list I mentioned
before those will be in yellow now the
second one we're going to talk about
again this might be something you think
is a no-brainer very straightforward but
some folks don't really pay attention to
antivirus alerts because the antivirus
is meant to automatically detect and
clean things right and that's its job
and that's what it does and folks don't
really read or look at the antivirus
alerts and that totally makes sense
however they I think there are some
situations where you probably do care
for example if there's malware detected
on a critical server like your domain
controller if there is ever a malware
detected your domain controller even if
it's adware it's still worth
investigating how did that end up on
your domain controller there's zero
reason for you to not investigate
regardless of what it is here you also
notice I've actually excluded something
from a specific list of servers the
Citrix XenApp servers right because
users have profiles on those and they
might be
browsing using Citrix XenApp if you're
familiar with that kind of gives them
like a remote access portal and they can
use virtualized I guess not virtualized
but segregated applications on the
Citrix server so of course that might be
a server you're not really caring about
malware being detected from the
application data folder because that's
very common you'll probably get a lot of
adware false positives as users are
browsing or maybe some JavaScript files
are detected the next one we're going to
talk about is common credential theft
file names this is super easy for an
attacker to avoid all thing to do is
rename their malware or the credential
theft utility to something else but the
reality of the situation is in that
probably about 30 to 40 percent of the
cases I've worked on we see the
credential theft Malheur simply renamed
one of these file names I mean that's my
personal experience may not be yours but
the situation of or the the fact of the
matter is that the attackers are kind of
lazy and so if this is the tool name
they're probably gonna just drop it like
that so the ability to actually look for
that this is a fairly comprehensive list
of course is gonna be very useful like I
said though attacker all they have to do
is rename their tool it's not gonna be
triggered on or not detected and
actually there's something we're gonna
detect for that later on as well now
this one's a little bit more of a
behavioral rule rule number four this is
a webserver acting a little unusually
and what I mean by that and maybe I
could have named this a little better is
that the actual web server process so if
you're using iis web server application
which is a web server application for
Windows the webserver process is
typically either w3w PXE that program
that is the iis web server application
and on older versions I think prior to
iOS version six which hopefully nobody's
still running right okay you might also
see this as the application name asp net
underscore WP so those two executables
are not an hour
those are your IAS servers but if those
processes are the parent or they spawn
another process it's not maybe that
common or that usual unless there's
evidence of attacker activity for
example if an attacker has found a
vulnerability in your website they may
leveraging a web shell that they've
uploaded into your website or on your
web server to perform some other
operations and those operations might
include some of these commands so very
straightforward one to look for again
you might have to check to see if this
is actually happening your web server
may have custom code that your
developers have made and they may be
running these some of these commands as
part of the web server application so
validate that check that with all of
these rules again as I mentioned
everyone's environments different you
need to take these with a grain of salt
you're not gonna be able to copy/paste
these directly into your environment
there's probably gonna be something that
happens and that's unique for you that
other people don't see now this next one
is the suspicious service installation
and I'm gonna actually show you an event
a service installation event right after
this so you can see why I picked some of
these keywords but the idea here is
you're looking for service installation
events which is the 70 45 a ID right so
in the Windows Event log 70 45 and
you'll notice here I've put service name
matches in this weird expression right
if you're not familiar with that that's
called reg regular expressions or reg X
and that expression or that series of
symbols essentially represents a 16
character string that is composed
entirely of eh-2-zed characters of
either case no spaces no special
characters no numbers okay I'll explain
why that is that in a second and then of
course also we're looking for whether it
contains some of these key words like
powershell CMD basic c for IX and comm
spec and the reason is because the
default service installation done in by
Metasploit looks like this
so you can see that the name or service
name that Metasploit will use in a
default installation and i don't think
most people are changing this is a
randomized 16 character string I don't
believe I've seen one that has numbers
or spaces which is why I wrote the
expression to look for upper or
lowercase characters it's always exactly
16 characters long straightforward very
low hanging fruit if you can't detect it
or you're not looking for it you should
be able to and then you'll notice some
of these other keywords that I also
highlighted those are the
specific strings that I looked for in
this rule because of course if a service
is installed on my system but that
service is responsible for simply
running PowerShell that doesn't sound
like a service that I've probably
installed on purpose same with command
prompt cmd.exe if you're not familiar
with this I X I X ie X is how power cell
can be used to execute specific things
invoke execution I believe so that's
used to execute things I've added that
in as well
because if a service again is being
installed in your system and it's
executing something using PowerShell it
doesn't really sound like an actual
system service that you would know ly be
installing next we're gonna talk about
is the download function from PowerShell
PowerShell has I think 10 15 maybe more
ways to download things from the
internet and at the bottom you'll notice
I put actually this name and this talk
that I saw der beek on Daniel Bohannon
actually another Mandy consultant he can
explain to you why this rule is not
gonna be the greatest because he's
created this thing that is called invoke
cradle crafter and he's basically made a
way to obvious gate PowerShell in a way
that it's almost impossible to detect
but this will catch low-hanging fruit
PowerShell scripts running in your
environment that are downloading files
should be very rare with the exception
of specific scripts that are being
around by your sis admin's and that's
something that you can easily observe
identifying a whitelist but otherwise
pretty much all of those functions start
with the keywords dot download or open
read and you'll notice here I've
actually have a green function I
mentioned these functions earlier this
function is meant to split or strip
special characters because when
attackers try to obfuscate their
commands they'll put in things like tick
marks or quotation marks and funnily
enough PowerShell will actually allow
you to write the word PowerShell if you
want to execute power shell with a bunch
of tick marks separating each character
right so that might destroy your
detection if you're simply looking for
the word powershell or vice-versa if
they want to put those tick marks
between every letter of the word down
if you're simply looking for dot
download and you're not stripping out
the special characters you're gonna fail
to catch that so it's very important to
try and strip out special characters if
you're doing this kind of detection
otherwise your likelihood of catching
more advanced attackers is gonna be very
low at this one but it will probably
catch a lot of commodity stuff or some
of the more basic frameworks the next
we're gonna talk about is attempted
exploitation detected this requires your
vulnerability scan data is everyone
doing vulnerability scans every so often
yeah hopefully you should be you should
be doing it probably quarterly or maybe
more frequently if you can but the idea
here is once you've got that scan data I
mean a lot of people use that scan data
for patching you go you patched your
systems and you say that's great
or sometimes you say well you know what
we're gonna prioritize only the critical
ones we're gonna leave all these other
ones unpatched it happens a lot right
has anyone heard of that before
yeah not ideal but it definitely happens
so the idea here is if you have this
data and you know your systems are
unpatched to specific CVS you can
actually correlate that with IDs alerts
because your IDs alerts will should also
have a CV so again you're looking for an
IDs alert correlated with a specific
host that you know to be vulnerable with
that CV and that could and likely does
indicate that someone has done some
reconnaissance they've already
identified what application is running
on that server or system that they're
trying to exploit and they're actually
running an exploit that has a very high
likelihood of being successful right and
that means that someone is specifically
interacting with your environment and
the likelihood of that being a random
scan is a little bit lower
that being said of course it's entirely
likely if you're running unpatched
software expose the internet you're
probably gonna get people trying to
exploit you with everything all the time
this is probably better to limit to your
internal network your internal servers
that are not internet facing the next
row we're gonna talk about I actually
hate this kind of rule and I only
included it so I could specifically tell
you one thing about it a lot of
organizations they like to say let's
detect brute force and usually the
threshold I see is like three failed
logins in five minutes or something
something really low like I said I'm not
a huge fan of this because I really
don't see a lot of value coming out of
it but if you have to implement this
and for whatever reason you think it's
really great up here threshold as much
as you can right we had in one
organization you know we had this three
failed logins in five minutes it
basically just detected every Monday
morning everyone forgetting their
password on Monday morning that's all it
was really good for and I think we did
about 1,000 investigations and zero of
them were ever actual evidence of
activity that was malicious or even
someone doing something bad right so
that's a lot of spent effort on
something that wasn't really great we up
the threshold and if we if we up it to
200 in 24 hours all of those you know
just user error things go away what
you're left with is two things
you're left with possible brute force
that's gonna be probably one in ten nine
times out of ten you're gonna find that
a sysadmin has written a script and he's
hard-coded credentials and you know the
credentials have changed now his script
is hammering some server trying to use
the old credentials not really a
security issue from the perspective of
someone breaching your organization but
it kind of is a security issue from the
perspective of you now have identified
assistive minutes are good hard coded
plaintext credentials into a script and
that has some value to you know finding
and fixing of course now this one is
good and actually you know I've
considered even just making this service
installation in general but if you have
services being installed just at all on
your critical servers you probably
should be detecting that again 70 45 VI
D like we saw before very
straightforward all you really need is a
reference list of your critical servers
and your event looks pretty easy to
check and compare the reality is once
your servers are set up domain
controller is deployed you're probably
not installing new services to it very
often the only people doing that are
likely going to be attackers except of
course if you have you know an approve
change window where you're actually
deploying new applications then that
makes sense that you might have that now
earlier I showed you a bunch of file
names that were related to credential
dumping malware but of course as I said
attacker can simply change the file name
and your detection is now moot so the
alternative I mean it's really not a
great alternative
but I'll explain why I put this in here
is going with antivirus signatures and
in this particular case the AV solution
that I looked at it names all of the
credential theft malware with the prefix
hack tool dot so rather than trying to
figure out all the credential theft
malware names I simply use that
expression or that pattern substring to
look for detection of these hacked tools
and that catchers hack tools credential
theft malware and the reason I included
this because this is kind of lame right
antivirus detected it why do I care so I
can see why you might think this is kind
of lame but if someone is already in
your environment and dropping hack tools
even if it's cleaned what happens
immediately and I've seen this with real
attackers here's what happens they drop
the hack tool it gets cleaned off
antivirus wipes it away everyone ignores
it the attacker changes one bite in the
file brings it back in antivirus doesn't
detect it continues on his way that has
basically slowed him down for about 30
seconds but for us it's a great
indicator right and they're not like so
many cases that I've worked on where we
come in and we see the antivirus
actually had detected the attack tool
but it was cleaned and so no one really
paid attention to it but that was a
great early warning now this one is a
cool one we saw an apt threat actor
actually doing this and folks were
talking anything about ho 365 earlier
right so webmail or accessible email
from the internet especially in cloud
hosting providers we actually saw an apt
organization or a group who gained
access to the cloud or a 365 mail system
for a specific organization and what
they did was they had access to a couple
of users and they basically gave those
users delegation rights to the entire IT
security team's mailboxes so it's about
26 or 27 if I recall correctly users
that they got access to and what that
means is then the attackers had full
access to read modify and send mail on
behalf of the security team so as the
security team was actually investigating
in this case they didn't have an
investigations tracker this particular
organization the security team well they
just communicated by email the attackers
were actually reading the emails and
watching the investig--
into them as it proceeded in real-time
but again basically to detect this take
a look for the access rights equal full
access delegation being set on a
specific mailbox and this happens right
an EA has delegation rights to an
executives mailbox for example so it
happens once in a while here I
recommended a threshold of three in 24
hours is where you should trigger on
because one or two kind of makes sense
right a new employee being set up who
has to do some work for other folks will
have delegation rights assigned to them
and you don't to bother yourself with
false positives like that okay we're
about halfway through we've got about I
think 10 or loving more I think
numbering is messed up let's see bypass
code being used this is cool again
another case where we saw a PT thread
actor's collect the paper bypass codes
so what that means is if you have a
two-factor authentication
deployment and you've got that token
code that changes every 30 or 60 seconds
when that is registered or enrolled the
user is given 8 typically bypass codes
that are called paper codes this is like
a file that they might download and
these codes can be used in place of a
rolling token or a one-time password
most users click on the file it
automatically downloads it to your
machine if you're using something like
Google Authenticator for example and
then they forget about it right so if an
attacker gets access to that system they
can collect that file now they've got 8
token codes they can use to remotely
access your environment they don't need
a soft token so if you're looking in
your multi-factor authentication logs
there's typically a specific signature
or some indicator that a bypass code was
used for this particular authentication
and here I thought ok it's possible that
someone will use a bypass code right
you've lost your phone you got a new
phone you might want to use a bypass
code to login so in this case I limited
this to outside of the home region of
this organization this organization
fictional exists only in Canada and the
US so if someone uses a bypass code from
anywhere outside of that I want to know
about it why again because we saw an apt
thread actor do this from a country that
was outside of the home organization
this also links in with that if a too
after authentication token is registered
outside of your home region you might
also be interested in that because why
when a new employee joins your company
and you give them their two-factor
authentication where are they doing that
from they're setting that up in the
office maybe at home and if your
organization is based in Calgary for
example you don't have any employees
outside of Calgary someone is
registering a new two-factor
authentication token in China you might
be interested in why that's happening
again
that's what hackers are doing now so
what we see is that advanced attackers
like to use your own existing remote
access utilities right because they can
blend in the traffic blends right in and
we have seen where they will actually
generate their own token codes to get
access to you know the administration
server they'll simply create a new token
and now they can log in the same way
that all your users can so this is
something that I think should be very
easy to implement and you know fairly
good accuracy now this one is related to
scheduled tasks and scheduled tasks of
course are part of the Windows operating
system that allows specific commands or
applications to be run on a regular
basis or one time they can be used on
local or remote systems so attackers
like to use this for what we call remote
command execution or they might use it
for persistence but of course if someone
is using a scheduled task in a normal
environment you might not see some of
these things for example how often you
have scheduled tasks running batch files
you might have it in your environment
actually but if you do it probably
happens on a regular basis and that's
something that you can easily observe
and - now that being said it's probably
not likely you have any scheduled tasks
that are using register of 32 or have
this keyword in here ser obj dll does
anyone know what that is I've written it
here in the description that's actually
called squiggly-doo which is an attack
that uses this Windows signed binary to
deploy whatever kind of malicious code
on a system I believe Casey Smith subti
on Twitter developed or
you know was the first researcher
identified that any named scribbly do
and but the idea being if someone is
doing this in your environment you
should be able to detect it and I would
actually go as far as to say you should
probably be able to detect scribbly do
beyond scheduled tasks but you know if
the fact if someone is using these
keywords and you know any command-line
argument if you have the visibility into
command-line arguments if you have like
an EDR tool Enterprise the detection and
response tool that would be great or you
can probably get that out of system on
as well now this one yeah this one I can
take or leave but I thought I'd include
it because it points out a couple of
interesting things that I think not a
lot of people are aware of does anybody
know what an HT a file is or an MHT file
this so some folks do some folks don't
right these are file types I can
actually can actually contain you know
executable code HTA is like an HTML
application so it might look like a web
page but it actually couldn't contain
code MHT is a Microsoft document file
and actually can be renamed as dot docx
if an attacker wants to it would be
opened by word but it actually can
launch code as well so these are a
couple of things you might check for
piff and scr files SCR files being
screen savers again another file type
that can actually contain Windows
executable code right so like I said I
could take or leave this one it's not
bad but kind of interesting at least for
folks who don't know that these file
extensions can actually contain
executable content got only a few more
here so hopefully we'll get through
these pretty quickly this one is very
straightforward
I think the relevance of this one has
decreased over the last few years but
it's everyone's familiar with right
WordPress sites that are not kept up to
date they might have a specific plugin
it's not you know it's got a
vulnerability in it and then all of a
sudden someone pops 30,000 WordPress
sites or has I never heard that before
we're seeing like a news article or X
number of thousand WordPress sites has
been compromised over the last X Day
yeah so if you start seeing downloads of
executables from specifically these two
directories that might indicate that
this has been compromised and is being
used to deliver malware a third director
you might see is WP dash content but the
WP dash content directory is the content
directory for the WordPress site where
all of its content will reside
so if the author of that WordPress site
is actually just you know delivering
software because there's security blog
or you know an IT developer blog it
probably would be in that folder and
you'll get false positives sixteen local
account created in a server this is
straightforward right if someone is
creating a local account on a domain
join server in your environment again
it's probably not that common probably
isn't shouldn't be happening in your
environment likely you have policies in
place that say this shouldn't happen
because most of your domain joint
servers should be administered by domain
accounts so if someone is creating a
local account again this could be an
indicator of malicious activity I'd say
this one is probably like a 30/70 more
often than not like seventy percent of
the time it's like a sysadmin is just
doing something that you shouldn't be
doing now I'm purposely just for
whatever reason interactive use of a
service account this one is great
attackers love to leverage service
accounts because service accounts have
access to a lot of stuff right they have
access to a lot of systems as well but
their service accounts and they should
be performing specific operations in the
windows logon types you'll see here a
specified event type two and ten event
type two is an interactive logon as if I
sat down at a computer and type two my
password event type ten is a remote
interactive logon and that's the event
type that you would generate if you log
on using let's say Remote Desktop
Network logons which is what a service
account normally uses that would be an
event type three so you could write this
rule in two ways right you can either
say look for two and ten or you can say
just tell me any event type that doesn't
match three either way again you need to
check your environment I mean you
shouldn't have service accounts take
interactive logons
unless you have some strange apps that
have been deployed but a really good one
if you've if you've got the confirmation
that your organization uses service
accounts appropriately this one is a
great one for detecting to make dns
command control so covert channels that
attackers might use for commanding
control using dns they like to use DNS
requests and text records can contain
blobs of data so that actually allows
them to transmit information more
quickly so a high volume of DNS text
records from a specific system can be a
great indicator that someone is deployed
malware that is using DNS work
mattie control now this one is an
example of a cobalt strike detection and
I put this here because I think this is
very valuable so the cobalt strike
cupola strike for those of you who don't
know is an attack framework similar to
Metasploit right it's a commercial tool
however the profiles that it uses to
hide its traffic the technology uses or
the technique it uses is called
malleable c2 so the command and control
traffic of cobalt strike beacon can be
changed very easily and there are a
number of profiles that the author of
cobalt strike has published on github
this is an example of Amazon's
profile and there are a number of other
ones and what the profile does is it
tells the attack tool or the payload to
communicate in such and such a way well
there are specific strings that are
hard-coded in there and actually you'll
see I have two rules on this slide the
first rule being detect any post request
that has this specific string or any get
request that has this specific string in
the URI this will only work if someone
uses the Amazon profile out-of-the-box
but like I said how often are people
really fiddling with these things and
not that often and the reality is we
should at least be able to detect the
ones we know about it's kind of shooting
ourselves in the foot if we don't even
go for those ones that are public this
one is another one that's good in the
header host so the requests will
actually be generated by the beacon
payload and it will actually specify the
host as wwm comm but of course the IP
address associated with it it's probably
not gonna be the organisation of Amazon
unless they're using Amazon AWS for
commanding control but that's something
that you have to consider like I said
this is one example there's at least a
dozen I think there might be two or
three dozen profiles on the github that
will tell you you know how those
specific profiles are used for beacon to
communicate back and forth and you can
look for those kinds of keywords now
this one okay we're getting to the last
two or three I know we're going a bit
over time my apologies but the next one
we're talking about is volume Shadow
Copy deletion this one is good for
detecting ransomware if you didn't
already know because everything's
encrypted and you know you're in trouble
but if you if you're in that situation
what happens is ransomware will like to
delete your volume Shadow Copy so you
cannot restore from backup
there is a flip side to this and I've
mentioned it in the description but I
didn't specify this as a different rule
but attackers will also like to create
volume shadow copies especially in your
domain controller so if you detect a
volume Shadow Copy creation on your
domain controller there's a very high
likelihood the reason that copy was made
is what the attacker can extract the
NTDs it file which is the file that
contains the password hashes for all of
the accounts in your domain and that
file is normally locked right that's
normally a locked file that an attacker
cannot access so they create a new
volume shadow backup or volume Shadow
Copy so that they can then extract the
file and they get the most up-to-date
hashes rather rather than using an
existing Shadow Copy all right this one
is again some folks think it's a little
bit lame but the point here that I'm
trying to get at is that it's important
to be able to detect when a virus has
been cleaned in real time versus on a
scheduled scan which means that it's
been there for some time right you might
want to know how long it's been there
for especially depending on the kind of
malware so here I've specified specific
prefixes for types of malware I would be
interested in knowing how long they were
in my environment for example if someone
had a you know spyware on one of my
servers for five seconds that's a very
different story than if it was there for
six months and we talked about the dull
time earlier so of course that's very
valuable to understand and the last
we're going to talk about actually I
just got inspired in the last talk
because someone mentioned about those
golden ticket attacks or something I
think they mentioned that but the idea
here is that the me me cats attack tool
or the credential theft tool me me cats
when it dumps tickets to a file by
default
it creates a file with the dot Kirby
extension as far as I know there are no
other uses for the dot Kirby file
extension so just being able to detect
the creation of those files again it's a
baseline to be able to possibly detect
the activity of ticket dumping I don't
know why I wrote token dumping it should
be ticket and anyways so this is to
detect that past the ticket attack
because of course an attacker will try
to dump the ticket or create a forge
ticket on your domain controller and
then they will use that in your
environment to move throughout the
organization that comes to the
conclusion of the content I wanted to
talk to you
today thanks everyone for your attention
if you have any questions feel free to
come and find me after
[Applause]