alright so without further ado we're
going to introduce muhlenberg ova and
he's going to talk about the communion
financial darknet here so see my hand hi
my name is million bhargav and i will be
talking about lighting of the Kandyan
doctor and financially so this is a true
story at Alice a little about me I'm
working as a security consultant with
telus security solutions based out of
Calgary I'm also a part-time professor
with George Brown College in Toronto
where at each Network auditing forensics
cryptography and so on to the students
of network and system security analysis
program mouthful I've been involved on
and off with the doctoral research over
the past five years and not really the
only expert on this topic I am sure
there are plenty of people including
some speakers were spoken earlier for me
all of this started back end 2009 when I
first came to know about bitcoins so I
was working as a part-time web designer
trying to make websites apart from
studying in colleges to make some extra
money a client of mine who later became
a good friend tried to pay me with
bitcoins I was actually hoping to get
actual currency that I can use in the
market back then about one dollar you
could get something like 40 bitcoins so
I got offered 800 bitcoins for twenty
dollars worth of work and her twenty
dollars is little cheap for a website
but I was in India and at that time with
the exchange rate it was about a
thousand rupees and that's the best you
could get for HTML site at that time so
I started looking more into the problem
I got now bitcoins okay what do I do
next tried googling found out about or
found out about darknet started going in
and out check out the how to's seem
pretty easy it was fun initially so what
is dark net
I am NOT talking about the TV show or
what exactly like show like mr. robot
yes the things that are shown in there
are completely true for me darkness more
of a you can say untapped source of
thread and tells an amusement amazement
because I feel people ever learn one
example is how to fail like a doctor
drug lord that I spoke about that one
very well so news that you see mostly on
the darknet is all about Russians their
drugs and so on well those are the most
sought-after topics that people are
trying to find I am going to talk about
the financial side especially what's in
canada because not many people talk
about what is there for canada doctorate
threat Intel is like penis sex everyone
talks about it everyone thinks that the
other person is doing it even though
they don't really know how to do it so
just claim that they are doing it so how
do you connect to dark net simple terms
google it if you still too lazy go to
youtube plenty of videos by all kinds of
people on how to access dark net this is
an image taken from BBC's website
talking about how to connect to dark net
a very rooted inventory method you
download something like a tor browser on
your PC which is based off Mozilla
Firefox you connect to it like you
connect over a proxy chain and it
finally takes you to where you can
access all the Union addresses so based
on Sarah's talk and other people in the
past how many of you have checked out
dark net or tour in the past okay most
of you anyone still curious about it
right now not a few so congratulations
you're all terrorists
NSA tags everyone who's your curious as
a terrorist or even if you used a tail
service that was used by Edward Snowden
you're still a terrorist NSA just like
the DHS has a very long list of keywords
that it finds terrorizing if you search
for things like snow you're a terrorist
in Canada everybody is a terrorist so
you've heard the terms a deeper dark web
surface web what is the difference
surface web is anything you can access
via say Google Bing and Yahoo kind of
search engines that they can index so it
can be any site even like Wikipedia Deep
Web is a part where you need credence to
login like social media sites like
Facebook when you actually you know
security settings the one that actually
secure like moving things from public
and other size that you need to login to
say government sites or your banking
sites and so on dark web is a part that
you need a special browser to access
it's not available on the normal com dot
dot CA and so on they're all da Tony
analysis and you need the special
browser tor browser for PC or if you are
using an android phone tor board and
then the browser that comes with it so
an infographic from deep web tech
talking about the same thing the sites
at the top that you can see cerise web
baying Google Wikipedia Deep Web
multilingual databases financial records
government records and so on and finally
the dark web where you find all the tour
encrypted information illegal access
data journalist for other people trying
to hide so few days after i got paid
with the bitcoins my dad told me that
his bank called him and asked him
something very funny that he had
authorized a two-thousand-dollar
transaction over a email ecommerce site
which he never does over 20 so he
obviously told him no he did not and the
bank put a hold on it later the bank
told him that they came to know that his
credit card details were stolen of an
e-commerce site and sold on the darknet
after i came to know that I got curious
okay so I've already learned a few
things about dark net why don't I try
and find out where my dad's card was I
did not find his card anywhere but I did
find a lot of places where the cell
credit cards like there was a side with
more than a million credit cards on it
sure most of them would be burnt or fake
I mean how can people have a million
credit cards and sell them you know why
not use them on their own make money so
what kind of things can you find on the
darknet interact plug-ins for electronic
file transfer these are listings about
three banks in Canada where they're
giving you the username and password for
you to login and the three secret
questions and their answer for all the
help that you will need and you know
when you send money by interact you get
a email afterwards saying that the money
has been received by the person you send
it to what if you want to cover those
tracks you also get the email username
it password so that you can log in and
cover your tracks so just since the
password didn't do whatever else you
want with them one way to protect with
this would be to use software tokens or
one-time password sent over email one
bank recently started doing that in
Canada after they came to know that they
were briefs in 2012 and they that they
found out I think very recently about
that for end of 2015 that's why I'm
using people they would learn now I did
not log in to the bank account to
actually test if there was a valid
credential this is part of a list of
samples that a vendor was showing off
that he actually knows his stuff in one
case i was able to talk to a vendor and
tell him that no I don't trust you
you're lying this is never true and so
on this is all photoshop so he sent me a
teamviewer connection ID I was able to
see his screen and then he logged into
the accounts will show me I took a lot
of screenshots so back in 2012 I came
across a lot of sites that was selling
banking data like things like this
username password and so on and in the
list of samples I found they had last
four digits
a phone number first name of the person
selling it sorry the person of the
account holder and the balances in them
so I got curious and my part of Pharaohs
my dad again part of it I went to the
list from whatever I could find and we
were not on it but i found a
familiar-looking name it was of a friend
and the french phone numbers match so I
thought maybe give him a call and find
out I give him a call I tell him what I
found lots of swear words a while later
lot more spell words is a lot of yelling
once he calmed down he hung up came over
to my house to the back I was a cricket
bat I don't know how many of you know
cricket it's like baseball but bigger
stronger and heavier back he thought I
had into his account because most of my
friends know I dabble in these things
for a lot so I explained to him what I
have I showed him my screen show him how
things are and so on and he relax and he
decided to leave the bat separately so
we went through all of his data and
decided okay let's just update the
listing that he has in the bank and see
how things are going is their claims of
this is life data and the fact that they
are showing it with regular updates true
or not so he updates his phone number to
a fake number immediately we check it
nothing check in a few days later no the
weekend offer and nothing I just assume
fine they're just making it up it might
be old data they got from somewhere else
one week exactly to the date he updated
his phone number the new number was
there in the new list of samples and I
was a Canadian bank and yes he hates me
a lot and we're not friends anymore
either
so they're more examples of what else
you can find like this listing talks
about a username password the mailing
address the last date you signed on to
it checking information sayings
information and just like you visit any
site where there's a lot of helpful
information like frequently asked
questions FAQ what can you do with the
money how can you take it out of that
account and spend it anywhere else do
you want more help you can just visit
the links that are listed here at the
bottom all the help that you want now
you're wondering how do people get
access to these like all the login
information same way as they used to do
always phishing pages you are aware of
phishing pages of gmail hotmail yahoo
and so on paypal it's not odious now the
bad guys have become very effective at
making typos free phishing pages for
banks and so on these phishing pages not
only capture the standard user name
password but they also have secret
quotients where you have to type the
coefficients in that way you will not
assume that this is say a fake banking
site you'll probably go along with it
except for the URL that where people
will generally skip over viewing there's
no other way you can tell that this is a
fake site so their vendors that are
actually providing phishing pages with
hosting so gone are the days when it'll
be just one person doing all the bad
stuff now we have a full scale industry
one guy will make the phishing pages and
sell it on the dark web and that person
might try to buy it from this one and
sell it for a cheaper price just to make
more money somebody will sell it with
hosting that they will host it on their
own gateway all you have to do is send a
spear phishing email get the victims
yourself and you can either share the
money of the loot or you can just get
the logs from that person another
example of the same kind of phishing
pages these are available everywhere for
every kind of bank every kind of even
websites a company side gets hard the
lots of people who
request somebody can make a phishing
page for them now what kind of a talk
will be complete without PayPal PayPal
accounts linked to Canadian banks or
Kennedy credit cards all available for a
very low price of two US dollars so if
you want to buy something by paypal you
don't have the money if you have to use
dollars you can now buy it for cheap
they're willing to replace your account
if it's wrong password or there's
something wrong with the account right
before you ordered but in case you run
out of money bad luck you have to buy
another one you can use this to do a lot
of things like most of you know what is
the drop location or dropping service ok
so our drop is somewhere where you buy
something say from a bad place and you
don't want to have a ship to your home
address so you get caught you instead
send it to a drop location where the
person for a fee will take that package
out of the orders and packaging
repackage it and send it to a new
address so it can be there a new drop
location or to your address that way if
somebody is tracking the shipment it
will not necessarily come back to you
just like earlier somebody i think it
was our again who suggested don't go to
customs to pick up your cocaine box
here's a vendor who claims that they had
the government now it may be it may not
be there's no way to actually check this
without buying the product and that's
illegal but based on the data that you
can see it has a social insurance number
first name last name address with zip
code the birth today and valid email and
driver's license can be a government
database can be taken from any other
source and just showing a few columns to
make it look like a government database
another vendor claiming to have a
records database so this is a listing in
one of the markets that was saying the
website was hacked using SQL injection
the records talk about plain text admin
password as well as some personal later
that was on it recently there have been
a lower
of bank breaches in the Middle East and
so on I will talk about one of those
very soon in the next few slides I was
personally impacted and that one was
also hat using SQL map you will assume a
bank will be protected from SQL
injection and finally credit cards a
what kind of financial talk will skip
red cards well this is more towards a
debit card maestro from an Indian based
bank in Canada now as a vendor says
Indians love to save there will be a lot
of money in that account as an Indian I
can vouch for that if you saw my dad's
bank account you can definitely agree to
that and the one who's broke bread cards
so this is one of the major market
places that you find credit cards on
sale the first column the bin number
talks about the first six digits of your
credit card or debit card if you take
out your credit card right now without
showing it to me look at the first six
digits and just google been followed by
the first six digits it will tell you
all about what your credit card is from
like which bank it is from what kind of
car it is is it a corporate card of feed
card debit card and so on the second
column talking word mastercard visa
american express debit third column
debit or credit or ATM card fourth one
gold ATM cards classic standard platinum
all the kinds that you have expired
talks about the expiry date and the
country which country your state the
card is from and bank finally in the end
if you are very choosy was the kind of
back you want to defraud or you have
favorites or you don't really like a
bank for some reason so the big question
how do process actually cash out like
okay fine you have got stolen credit
cards how do you make money order it one
ways you can sell it on a doctor and
somebody else who do all the fraud part
and you just make money from the sale of
it
and now the scratch guard cause
something between three dollars to $45
three dollars if it is expiring very
soon we'll save within the same month or
it's very old and most likely burnt that
is caught by the bank and if it's high
current limit or from somewhere that has
a long expiry date plenty of users fresh
data it's going to cost a little more
now Admiral support cutting and the
following explanation should only be
taken as an education message so the
most common that I have seen is a fraud
sir sets up an account say on sites like
eBay trying to sell a product that is
very much in demand but with a very low
value say in iphone 6s how much will it
cause in the open market quite a lot of
money say you see it available for sale
for two hundred dollars will you buy it
at least you'll be tempted to because
you'd be well it's cheap a lot of people
who will actually go and buy it so the
scheme works like this the frosted has
set up an ebay listing with the product
that he doesn't get on a normal
customers say any one of us goes and
buys it from him because there's cheaper
right so they got a really good deal
after the purchasing is done the money
is then transferred to the process
paypal account or bank account however
it is set up the bad guy then goes back
to ebay and searches for any other
vendor who's selling the exact same
product then using a stolen credit card
he buys that item so again no money
spent from his side after the item is
bored you can send it to any shipping
address so you send it back to the good
customer in the end the guy who actually
paid for the original product from the
faster gases product no complaints there
the Orson foster is obviously not going
to complain about anything and the only
person who is left in the end to
complain
about a fraud is the original credit
card holder whose credit card got stolen
and most people don't really check their
credit cards for any small things can
limit it like say forty dollars fifty
dollars people will not really think
about five hundred dollars people will
be concerned more than that yes
definitely another place where this
keeps happening is gift cards now we
have seen sites like Groupon you can
just go and buy something for
ridiculously cheap with ninety percent
of ninety-five percent off so get used
to those kind of things and you assume
it happens all the time so you go to say
ebay you see an amazon gift card or
starbucks gift card but the thousand
bucks for ten dollars or one hundred
dollars your thing is like a Groupon
like deal you can buy in bulk you're
getting away with it most likely that's
a stolen card like last year we heard
about starbucks getting hacked and then
we saw a lot of news about people using
his points you know illegally loading up
lots of points in their cards same way
you can sell those cards after you've
loaded points so in the end you're not
the person who's getting caught it's the
poor hapless greedy man who went to get
all those starbucks points to get free
coffee so how do else can you go about
it the vendors who claim to do the
carding for you so this is a listing
about someone claiming to be a loyal and
professional paypal cash short service
saying that they can draw up to seven
thousand dollars in under two hours now
they have work with people in the past
and they're people that they've been
working with have become inconsistent
due to other projects or maybe they got
arrested that happen they're looking for
someone who can help with them time to
time and understand how the market works
and basically make the frauding more
efficient there's always people like
these guys so if you go to Facebook
we're actually groups of Carters so just
go to facebook and search for Carter's
you will come across groups of people or
actual groups where people are asking
how is carding done they are sharing
their carding skills so things have
and in the past to both so they can get
more customers who will who they can do
carding on behalf of their literally
telling law enforcement come and arrest
me it's like a shopping list for the
cops this fine man here uses actual
profile like clicked on it and I check
yes that's his actual profile and he
asks can anyone do calling for me if yes
then message me for details I'm sure any
cough you like to contact him for
details and then it can get worse the
people who can offer to help on facebook
so here's a listing on facebook by a
friend saying of gaia teaching carding
from basics to end and he escapes escrow
for payment so if you don't know how to
do guarding you can learn from this guy
another wonderful way to go to the cops
so why don't companies buying back all
the stuff all the data that's available
for sale on the darknet by buying you're
just going to encourage the behavior the
mood say a bank cease all of their
credit cards eighteen twenty thousand
credit cards on sale in the dark net
they buy it all up the vendors will see
there's a big demand for this they try
to hack it more so it's not really
helping legal ramifications buying any
kind of stolen property by anyone
whether cooperation or individual is
illegal and then there's a ransomware
issue one place very have to pay money
to get your stuff back and in some cases
of badly designed done somewhere that
never happens you pay money and still
bye-bye some people deserve it who have
never set of backups just my personal
opinion another one called fools so this
is full p IA identity information that
you can find they claim to be having
hundred thousand records and they're
selling it for 475 dollars seems pretty
cheap right i mean poor record and the
format is very nice i don't know if you
can read it from for title given name
surname
read address city state zip code country
mother's maiden name for today L phone
number elfin country code pounds
kilograms feed inches centimeters
national ID color occupation company
vehicle blood type gender I don't think
there's any field left pant size maybe
so there are always people like this guy
so this guy is looking for Canadians
although people found you can you say we
will also do but preferably Canadians to
work with and he claims to have access
to millions of first profile and about
300,000 currently in front of him so he
already has connections of contacts in
eastern Canada cubic in Ontario
especially looking for people in bc or
Alberta so if anybody is looking for a
job right now you know cyber crime does
pay to a while looking for people to
work with who can either make fake IDs
or know someone who can make fake IDs
photoshop skills are considered an asset
sorry you see so example so what can you
get once you have faxes to phils
information and somebody who could those
photoshop and can print this stuff you
know you can get a printer for this for
like 150 dollars and you can get 30 or
40 blank cards that come with it on ebay
it's not difficult so you had can get
citizenship cards diver licenses for
medicinal card and this is very badly
obscured idea of the guy selling it so
you can look it up now so there are many
places where of course IDs like these
will get caught say at border crossings
if you go to a bank and so on a places
where they are validated then their
place is where they're not validated
like say if you're traveling in a
foreign country you can put it in as ID
proof anywhere to get a train ticket
plane ticket and so on it's not going to
be checked
and say if you go ice skating and you
want free ice skates what better idea
then to take this fake ID present it
there let the guy keep it at ice skating
rink while you take the ice skates and
then you go home with them you can't get
cheaper right well you know ice skating
shoes that way so now that you have fake
credit cards fake IDs how bad can life
get I mean for other people being in
Calgary most of you would have seen this
in the news hyatt regency Calgary 1 of 2
50 hotels hit by hackers you would have
also seen this in the news from hotels
and Hilton Hotel acknowledged breach now
every time such a breach occurs
everybody says no credit card
information was stolen just some user
information was stolen now what kind of
user information gets stolen from a
hotel now every time you sign up for any
hotel say Best Western hilton and so on
you also get a point system with it a
loyalty program kind of so when a user
information is stolen every user ID has
a loyalty account associated with it and
then you get things like this our
vendors selling 300,000 points account
for $90 just saying how long will it
take for you to achieve 300,000 points
that's in this seemed easier of course
only a royal idiot will go and stay in a
hotel for free on a stolen account with
a sort of fake ID there have been cases
apparently in Europe but there are the
things you can get from it all hotel
chains offer gift cards so you can buy a
gift card for next to nothing you can
get services or you can resell those
services to somebody else some hotels
also have tie-ups with other hotel
chains and you can buy it from say hotel
chain a of this card for hotel chain be
lots of fun now you have already you
have seen how well the life of
cybercrime can be how much fun you can
have from this there are things that can
wrong like this one this is a screenshot
from warrant issued by Calgary Police
Services taken with their permission
about two people caught having credit
card data ID theft information doing for
spread card counterfeiting mark of
Government of Canada vital documents and
so on so remember earlier I mentioned
something about a bank getting hacked
and Middle East so there was a bank put
125th I came to know that I used to bank
within my parents still have an account
there that got priests and all the
account data and everything is available
online not only on the darknet but
everywhere and people have already
torrented and is everywhere I came to
know that not only the fact that they
kept my account details which was closed
in december twenty ten till 2016 they
still had all the fields intact in the
country it was in qatar the normal said
not only will this store your teachers
like name address phone number and those
kind of things at any bank stores there
was a stole your passport number expiry
date the city of bird city of issue and
so on all of those details including
your visa number pure ID document blah
blah blah all of that is currently out
and i came to know of this on the night
of 26 that all of this data came out and
in the morning of 27 that is yesterday
morning i got a social engineering call
i did not initially assume that it is
going to be a fishing pole they claimed
they were from the High Commission of
India based out of alpha and they kept
on repeating you can check our phone
number you can check our phone number I
know how to spoof phone numbers to not
difficult so they go on explaining how
I'm going to be deported from Canada
because I did fraud in my imitation
documents by Miss entering my date of
birth three years ago in a forum in
India and for that reason indian
government has cancelled my passport
so according to the caller I had two
hours until the cost will show up and
deport me oh yes and advance warning i
can pack my bags they went on insisting
that i don't tell anyone so I played
along yes yes please go ahead tell me
everything what can I do to save myself
first option fly home back to India meet
their contact there and pay him the fees
and we'll take a few days second option
stay in Canada pay the fees right now so
i said okay i'll have my credit card
ready you can just go ahead and charge
me is this not a we insist on cash
because it's faster they wanted me to
pay about two thousand dollars canadian
to take it out from the bank go to
safeway in downtown calgary and hand it
over to a canadian border service agent
who's waiting for me there I mean I know
it's ironical that happens to a guy in
security so I played along he explained
everything then he says okay go to the
bank right now I'll stay on the call and
if you hang up or if you talk in your
native language you will be deported I
just hung up he called me about 10 times
more after that it was fun but I did let
the bank know just in case something
happens you never know they have
everything now so why should enterprises
care they can identify criminals who are
targeting you so this is a life cycle
that generally occurs in the exultation
of information from private groups
traded reaches the public Internet you
see a small group or individual like
this wonderful person talks about it on
dark net until it comes out as a plan
and they put it as a listing so this
person talks about they need a custom
basic phishing page it has to be just
one page for a company that they have
and have access to I'll be taking credit
cards and some other things it doesn't
have to be flashy but if you look nice
very thoughtful
how can enter prices benefit you can
find out who's targeting you like this
person they need email hat at a
particular website and will pay five
hundred dollars for the email they need
the username and password will only pay
after accessing and then there's another
person who claims they can provide a
specialized keylogger service via word
documents for word 2010 so it's pretty
easy also PDF and screensaver because we
all know how much people like
screensavers they can give all three for
the price include a keylogger and they
will host it for you too and it can be
overt or if you like that it will cost
the same so with this you can find out
the latest tactics techniques and
procedures at TTP's and through this we
learn that there is a special exploit
either they got from somebody else or
they develop great plenty of options and
they're willing to sell it and that can
lead us to things like this of what
macro for download or execution and as
of March 21st they claimed it was fully
undetected for a very cheap price of ten
dollars which in Canadians 13 maybe
still cheap so things for enterprises to
keep in mind this requires time effort
dedication commitment and lots of hooves
are required for jumping through legal
processes I've worked in tell us we do
this there and yes it took a long time
the strangest incident that I had there
was a lady from the privacy office asked
me have you been tested the darknet is
it secure I still haven't answered that
email I don't know what to say the
plenty of risks involved legal lots of
PII available buying selling trading
using even looking at P is considered
illegal so more of the story the lot of
things to talk about with regards to
dark net financial drugs and others i
have only covered the financial one as
the whole topic will take hours the
final objective
light of the Canadian dark net for you
financially and why we should not ignore
it
thank you so we're getting back on track
here we've got about 15 minutes for
questions if anybody has them
sorry what is that
yeah lot of people are even say Carnegie
Mellon University I think they got paid
for something Princeton's working on at
MIT is working on it even RCMP's working
on it I don't think anybody's left