okay great for a next presentation we
have Steve masses er from ion United and
he's gonna walk us through a security
Enterprise Active Directory thank you
guys hear me sounds like it all right I
don't know if I can follow up chest talk
but I'll I'll do my best here all I'm
gonna go right into this a little bit
and catch up as we go along so some of
you might remember I did a talk last
year which was basically all the things
you need to do in your environment that
you're not doing and that don't cost you
any money that was that's kind of my
summary of what I talked about last year
so this is step two so still trying not
to spend too much your money
how can you mitigate the risk to your
biggest attack surface which is Active
Directory and where most of the
attackers have their focus where most of
your stuff is or the access to your
stuff so that's what I'm gonna be
talking to you about today I've done for
the obligatory intro I don't have an
intro slide I've done lots of stuff I
was a software developer I let a
security team I've done a lot of pen
testing I'm I teach for sans
and I'm starting to focus a little bit
more on the blue team or at least purple
teaming and so this is kind of come from
a lot of those engagements that I've
done in those areas just a quick review
of what I talked about last year so the
first thing is knowing what the hell
you're doing what are you trying to
protect what what does your business
care about all of those things turn
stuff on and more than turn stuff on
don't just turn stuff on and plug it in
you know actually configure it use the
features that you're paying all that
money for egress filtering is always a
big one multi-factor is talking to a
friend of mine who deals with a lot of
Incident Response and and threat Intel
and he says the one thing that is
actually somewhat effective today for
whether we're talking enterprise or the
the average user is multi-factor
authentication
I mean yeah fishing there's there's all
kinds of ways around everything I'm
going to talk about but it's probably
the one thing that is somewhat effective
across the board you know control your
management access passwords passwords
passwords passwords mean anyone who does
any sort of red teaming will can tell
you about those your administrative
access your monitoring and patching we
still see people with challenges and on
that front so as far as what I'm going
to talk about today it's one thing I've
noticed over the last few years is we
have Windows teams that are really good
at doing Windows II stuff but generally
speaking they're not getting a lot of
security training and we have security
teams that most often come from a
networking background they don't know a
whole lot about Windows or Active
Directory who are the ones that are
actually tasked with managing and
securing Windows though most companies
I've seen that's the windows team
security team kind of sits over here and
and lobs grenades every now and then but
it's really your windows team that's
responsible for your enterprise Active
Directory which is essentially the keys
to the kingdom right and as a side note
though that same windows team is the one
moving everything you've got to the
cloud but that's a that's a different
topic we won't talk about that too much
today so we end up with a bit of a push
me pull you here as I was sliding should
have found that image anyways
so we've got security going one way
windows going the other way because the
windows team it's their job they're all
about operations its uptime it's making
applications available keeping the
business going security team has a
different perspective and different
motivation but like I said they don't
have that deep knowledge of the Windows
environment so that's that's really what
I'm going to talk to you about today I I
haven't tied this in too much to the
miter attack matrix but really what this
is is you know we do a lot everything we
do from an offensive side is based on
patterns right we've started with
antivirus it's all about
the malware The MITRE attack matrix is
more about figuring out what tactics
tools techniques the attackers are using
and building our defenses around those
so loosely speaking that's that's how I
kind of came up with my laundry list for
today it's it's not about specific
attacks although I mentioned a bunch of
them it's about how an attacker is going
to get into your environment and move
around your environment
so I I recommend definitely taking a
look at the attack matrix if you haven't
already and and starting to change that
mindset so it's not about you know me me
cats it's about how someone's going to
steal credentials and reuse credentials
and how do I detect that not me me cats
and prevent it too so the other caveat
to this is you're not gonna do this all
at once it's just not gonna happen
it's a journey it's cliche but there's a
lot of work here I'm gonna give you a
laundry list of things you can and
probably should do I would say that's
probably for the average organization
it'll take years at least to get through
this but you got to stop somewhere I've
you know data exfiltration is just as an
example company I said I've worked for
it's like well people can burn stuff to
DVDs they can print it out they can plug
in USB they can go to Dropbox they can
use office 365 if the list goes on and
on and on so well why bother I can't
stop data exfil I'm not gonna try right
that's not gonna get anybody anywhere so
don't take that approach this stuff is
hard
there can be business impact you have to
sell the business on it that's probably
the most important thing is is selling
the powers-that-be that this is worth
doing but again everything hinges on
Active Directory you can have all the
firewalls in the world it's it doesn't
matter someone's gonna get fished
someone's gonna be on the inside of your
network and they're going to be able to
do whatever they want because they're
gonna own your Active Directory so let's
start
you know if you come out with nothing
else come up with a roadmap right let's
here's where we want to be so that you
know when inevitably we decide to
replace windows 2003 sometime in the
next decade at least you have a
direction where you want to go with
whatever it is you're implementing next
right hopefully that's not Windows 2028
or something like that but you know come
out with a roadmap with an idea that
maybe you can't change things today
maybe you've got that thing that's still
running on Windows NT but someday it's
gonna die and someday you know you're
going to be forced into an upgrade
because your business is changing your
data center is moving your whatever's
happening
so be ready know what you want to do
when when those things happen get
yourself tacked on to the Windows 10
project or the Windows 2016 project or
whatever and start to influence at least
moving forward and over time hopefully
you can make a difference and I said
that was the last cavity last caveat is
there is absolutely nothing original in
this presentation it is all amalgamated
borrowed stolen if you will from a
number of sources in particular if you
haven't had a chance to check out Sean
Metcalfe's presentations I strongly
suggest you do his site ad Security org
was pretty much a one-stop shop for a
lot of what went into this presentation
and I've got a whole bunch of links in
the slides at the end to everything that
I stole so there are just come coming
back to the the attack matrix in this
presentation anyways I've come up with
seven ways that Acme comm is going to
lose just general classes of attacks
that Acme comm is going to fall victim
to and what we can do about it
number one as I said we could talk about
passwords till the cows come home
passwords are a problem we need to have
them we haven't solved that part of the
problem yet although we're getting
closer I suppose
I can tell you from my experience 90 to
95% of passwords start with an uppercase
letter followed by lowercase and out
letters followed by numbers ending in a
special character 1 to 2% of users have
season in year as their password
password spraying if multi-factor is not
in place it's the easiest way to get
into any environment and we have service
accounts that are sitting around there
with passwords that don't change hashes
that we can potentially get out whether
that's in memory on the wire what have
you and of course we have the the good
old human password synchronization tools
as Michael's presentation Illustrated
very very well yesterday right humans
are really good at keeping their
passwords synchronized so what can we do
about that first off 15 plus character
passwords so you could do this in 2008
certainly in 2012 there is native
support now for passwords longer than 14
characters because if you go into the
regular group policy editor you're
limited 14 characters there is a thing
called a password setting object I've
got a link to that that allows you to
set passwords however you want in your
active directory 15-plus is just a nice
number because a it takes longer to
crack and be because you can't store
land manager hashes for that managed
service accounts again I'll talk about
this bit more later Windows has made it
easier to have the operating system deal
with your service account so you don't
need to worry about their passwords you
don't need to know their passwords they
get managed for you by the operating
system
sam'l and single sign-on double-edged
sword always but the fewer passwords
people have the less likely an adversary
is going to be able to steal them it's
it's as simple as that and the fewer
ones they'll have to write down and
stick to keyboards and all of that I'm
you know length before everything else
I've said it over and over again when
when it comes to passwords honestly I
don't care about complexity if you if
you start doing math
a 12 character all lowercase password is
hard to track maybe that's on the low
end but it's not trivial
anyways so 15 go higher encourage
complexity there certainly I would
encourage it but at least for the
average user and and admin passwords we
can have a different conversation but
for the average user encourage them to
use complexity but the more you require
it the more you end up with winter 2017
is your password so I've got a couple
kids 8 and 11 or almost 8 and 11 years
old now I've been doing this for a while
so I take my kids to whatever beavers
guides hockey whatever activities and
they know I'm probably sitting out in
the car because wherever we are was too
far for me to go home and I've got my
VPN up and I'm doing a pen test of some
sort so it got to the point where my
kids were coming out saying hey Dad what
was it this time winter 2017 so that was
the best education for my kids about
passwords honestly I didn't have to work
too hard on that but naturally I have a
few computers at home and they've had
computers for a long time so we've we've
talked about passwords I didn't make a
big deal out of it for a long time my
daughter's password was pink but you
know over time we've worked on that and
proved that a little bit and it does
depend a little bit on how your brain
works but the advice that I give them
and the advice now my go-to advice for
anyone for choosing a password is just
pick two things you like one thing you
don't so sticking with the theme of my
presentation we have rocket roadrunner
and cliff so you know if you if you
don't want to type that much it could be
rocket bird cliff but you know I
couldn't decide for Road Runner was
really a bird or not so I left that in
there you know stick a space in there
stick and purse ants commas whatever I
got complexity is not a big deal if
there's the possibility of complexity as
an attacker I've got to take that into
account right but that's easy to
remember it's easy to type and it's hard
to crack or guess simple as that
and if hopefully you know by taking the
two things you like one thing you don't
it's not coming off your facebook at
least not all at one time you know might
so my daughter's password for the
longest time we dog sat for some friends
she loves the dog so his the name of the
dog she likes to ride her bike so it was
bike and it started out as her brother's
name being the the thing she didn't like
we switched that to clean because she
doesn't like to clean her room either
point being she has no problem
remembering me her password she has no
problem typing it she's been doing it
since she was about four or five years
old so if anyone tells you they can't
deal with long passwords that's what I'm
leading up to ask to see their text
message history they can type they can
remember long passwords are not a big
deal and don't change them as often the
biggest thing with changing passwords
today is breaches you don't want to be
using passwords have been exposed in a
breach or again back to Michael's
presentation from yesterday that have
been sent in plain text over who knows
what networks but again the the 90-day
change policy is what gets us into this
winter 2017 cycle so enough about
passwords local admitting that can go
wrong so I still see group policy
preferences that contain passwords long
story short it was microsoft's old way
of allowing you to manage the local
admin passwords on all your devices the
only bad thing about that is the
password was in decrypt able form on
publicly accessible login chairs so
that's not good just check and don't do
that but local amendments are the path
the easiest path anyways to getting full
control of your environment there the
there's still lots of organizations out
there they have the same local admin
password across all devices everybody
knows what they are or not but if you
get one if you get a hash your local min
on everything which then leads to more
administrative access domain admin and
so on we have admin's adding immense saw
this a lot I have a server it's an
application server so IT doesn't really
know what goes on on that server so they
need a
location stewards and business analysts
and project managers for some reason to
log in to that server so therefore they
they need to be admins of course and
manage that application and what happens
well I'm going on vacation or I'm not
gonna be here tomorrow where I'm sick so
I'm just gonna go into that local
administrators group I can google that
part and and add my project manager or
my my other BA and and soon it's it's
like Sesame Street right everyone adds
two friends and they add two friends and
they add two more and two more and and
then it's we have a huge mess and the
last thing is there are lots of
relatively trivial ways to get privilege
escalation I mean just check out your
monthly patch releases but also there's
lots of common missed configurations
that lead to privilege escalation of
court as well so what do we do about
some of that easy easy one is laps local
administrator password solution
long story short windows will manage the
local admin passwords across all your
devices keep them random change them as
often as you like you as an
administrator can pull them out of
active directory if you need to you need
to be doing and min to do that so you've
got other problems if people are
stealing your local administrators out
of your Active Directory so turn it on
this is a no-brainer it has zero
business impact it's very easy to
implement it supports Windows 2003 so
just configure laps on servers and
workstations because someone's gonna get
people log into both I guess it's the
point I've seen companies where they're
like our servers are the most valuable
we better do it there or well no one
logs into servers we're gonna do it on
workstations just do it across the board
and and allow it to change passwords as
often as you want I know people that
change them more than once a day it
doesn't matter as long as they're set
you have access to them you're good
privileged access over the network I
don't know how this is gonna work within
presentation mode yeah I can't zoom in
on that well now I can no just on my
screen sorry probably gonna end my
presentation now fixing that there we go
alright so
user rights assignment there are user
rights for things like deny access over
the network right deny login via remote
desktop protocol it took me the first
time I tried to actually do this I
couldn't figure out what the heck you
were supposed to do here
turns out you actually need to type the
string local account and member of
administrators group in there and then
you can prevent people who have local
accounts that are members of the
administrators group from logging into
the or using that right so or or you can
enforce that right for that account
which is in this case didn't I login
over the network so you can't you know
connect with with SMB you can't connect
with WMI with a local account you should
hopefully have some sort of out-of-band
management solution whether that's
VMware or I lowered rack or whatever and
hopefully you're dealing with
authentication and validation on that
side as well you don't need a local
account for over the network if you're
in front of the machine fine login on
the console but you don't need it over
the network
but yeah you can't select that you can't
browse and select that just type it in
and there's another one for guests and
there's another one for I think just
local account but not member of the
administrator group if you want to do
that local admin controls so protected
users again use protected users so I'm
my brain is full of all of the different
controls so I guarantee you today I am
going to mix some of them up but
protected users have a number of
characteristics enforced by the domain
you can prevent them or sorry you can't
prevent them I mean you can from logging
in remotely but when they log in
remotely their passwords are not cached
or the tokens are not cached basically
if you are DP into one system and then
try to RDP or map a drive in particular
from there to another system your
credentials are not passed through if
you're a member of the protected users
group so at least so for jump boxes for
example you are not carrying your
credentials forward for the bad guys to
take local admin there's the Sesame
Street thing right like there's there's
no one solution to that policy is one
part of it auditing that on a regular
basis is another one right just it's not
hard query Active Directory or query
every system you know bloodhound does a
great job of it in your environment to
see who's a member of local
administration and knock people off or
make the local administrators group a
restricted group which essentially means
now you get to use a group policy
preference for good instead of evil you
can create a group policy preference
that enforces that only these users are
members are the local administrators
group such as your workstation it means
that's the only thing that can be in
that local admins group and that local
admins group cannot be changed even by
those people you have to be able to
change that your policy preference run
the tools see what again back to the
audit get GPP password I mean Google
these things it'll tell you what GPP
passwords are out there for for all to
see even if you're not using that
password as your local admin today
because Microsoft's essentially broken
that functionality that password may
still be valid or give me clues as to
what I can do to get admin access get
system or and variations that's the
power sploit command to basically try
all the different ways of privilege
escalation on a box you know improperly
quoted service paths
service executables running from
directories where you have write or
anybody has write privileges there's
there's a number of different ways to
get system well see if you can
especially in Calgary with all that
wonderful oil and gas based software
there there are some there's some
software out there that doesn't do
things very well that doesn't install
itself very well we'll put it that way
invoke all checks I can't remember I
think maybe that once the power sploit
one it's the same idea for seeing how
you can escalate privileges
institutional inertia I was watching a
football game on the weekend and the
commentator
said something along the lines of oh
well maybe now they'll get some inertia
from that play I don't think you
understand what that word means I mean
there's XP Windows 7 2003 2008 or worse
out there in our environment
I blame inertia for most of it nobody is
willing to actually stand up and do
something about it so do something about
it and there's other out-of-date
software which is usually the reason
that you're running Windows 2003 right
so have that conversation
sorry that's on the next slide I'll get
to the fixes in a second domain
functional level again people's may the
domain works right I can login well I
change it it's it's another one of those
things that that a lot of people aren't
aware is there but potentially and they
certainly aren't aware of the benefits
they get from changing their functional
level and there are many stale accounts
again well you can't change that
password or disable that account because
nobody's using it
we'll find out and older protocols
there's three examples they are roundly
abused by malware but again something
might be using that I don't know well
you know what what what do IT people do
better than anything else they firefight
so you know what you break something so
what we're really good at putting out
fires so find out if those things are
used and fix them so and this applies to
patching as well yes you need to
validate you need to test and so on and
so forth but it's got to end at some
point
yes follow change management do your
tests and do your validation but again
we have virtualization it's this awesome
technology that allows you to say go
back now or clone try it over here let's
use some of this stuff and stop screwing
around trying to make sure that we've
reduced our risk to zero because we
never will
have the business discussions right
whatever that is it's a piece of crap is
anyone actually using it do they care
has anyone asked them if they have
alternatives for for conducting business
can we just get rid of it
failing that can we isolate it so
there's good old Network segregation
sometimes is easier than other times I'm
not saying that's a an easy one to
accomplish in all cases none of this is
really but it's an option remove from
the domain and when I sorry when I say
network segregation that could be just a
single host-based firewall rule to
protect the the most broken parts
removed from the domain double-edged
sword you're protecting your domain
you're crippling your ability to manage
that machine I mean so have that go
through that thought process or you know
what I've got this box because it's the
thing that prints the checks
well printing the checks is obviously
very important but it is a very clear
finite distinct process so whitelist the
hell out of it and all I need to be able
to do is print so block whatever network
access me you can block because on doing
is printing whitelist or a blacklist I
guess or whichever use whitelisting so
that you're only white listing the
pieces of the OS that are needed to
print don't don't allow anything else
and virtualize because it gives you more
flexibility to you can apply some
stronger security tools at the
hypervisor level you can move things
around you can segregate them and you're
one step closer to being able to get rid
of that thing because you can clone it
you can roll things back and so on so
talking about domain functional level
these are the key security features that
were added as you raise your level 2012
is a major change in my book I had them
all highlighted at one point and then I
decided that looked stupid but in 2008
you get better auditing so you've got
finer grained control over your auditing
we'll talk about that towards the end
the the logging visibility piece
fine-grained password policies so that's
where you could actually get to your 15
character password and you could apply
it to you know you can apply different
policy to your administrators versus
your marketing team what have you got
better in 2012 now there's a GUI for it
read only domain controllers that's
where managed service accounts first
came in is 2008
functional level there's even a best
practices analyzer to tell you what
you're doing wrong and then 2012 is we
got to group managed service accounts so
you could have a managed service account
used on multiple systems that was
managed by the operating system so you
never needed to worry about the password
there's the UI like I said for for
managing your password policy but 2012
is where we get the good stuff like
protected users like I was saying don't
carry your credentials along with you
you can't authenticate with ntlm you
have to use Kerberos or ntlm v2 I'd have
to look that one up again restricted in
min mode and I'm probably getting those
two mixed up right now but restricted in
min I yeah same idea let's just go with
that before I get it wrong again
let's say protection is you know LSA the
local security authority subsystem
service is where all the passwords are
so again with 2012 functional level you
can turn on LSA protection so that it's
harder to actually get at the memory of
the the LSS process and get those
credentials out authentication policies
you can set policies that say the this
group of users must use Kerberos or
can't use DES for their Kerberos tickets
and so on and then in 2016 we get
privileged access management which I'll
talk about a little bit later which has
just in time and just enough access but
Pam itself is a whole umbrella of stuff
so let's do some basics
I can't zoom in on this so I will have
to read it to you but yes land managers
still out there go to long passwords
disable it really like mine even XP in
2003 supported ntlm v2 and SMB v1 is
only required for XP in 2003 and only
for the things that they need to talk to
you so there are some opportunities
there for example to create subdomains
too or maybe they're not a member of the
domain if they're not mapping drives who
cares about SMB v1 turn it off on
everything else
Ned pile he's nerd pile on Twitter he's
the owner of SMB at Microsoft and he
says these are a couple of his Twitter
posts at Microsoft I cannot emphasize
enough how much I want everyone to stop
using Samba version 1 that was in April
of last year and then is his other tweet
which is more interesting day 700
without SMB one installed nothing
happened
just like the last 699 days so again
back to that inertia just turn it off
and and put out the there might be a
fire honestly but you've got two choices
when there's a fire turn it back on
because you did it during your change
window and you had change management and
all of those wonderful things that we're
all beholding to or it broke that one
little thing in the corner and you fixed
it like so turn it off and and if you
need the leverage any more leverage just
point back to want to cry not Pecha and
all all of that recent SMB v1 goodness
badness other stuff things to turn off
session enumeration windows proxy auto
detection local LAN multicast name
resolution winders browser protocol net
by a scripting host w digest
authentication untrusted fonts macros in
Oh Ellie I know but we'll talk about
that smarty there are all things you
know if you are rolling out Windows 10
for example at least get them turned off
in your Windows 10 builds again moving
forward these ones some of these are
getting tougher or to implement
universally although Microsoft is slowly
building them into Windows 10 with every
release but device guard exploit guard
credential guard so device guard is
basically controlling what code can run
in kernel mode what device drivers you
can load and so on so it really
restricts what privileged code you can
get to execute it also adds PowerShell
constrained language mode which
basically says you can only use these
types in PowerShell and I'll talk about
that I think on another slide exploit
guard so
just this week there were some posts
about attack surface reduction I've got
that on another slide you can actually
if you enable exploit guard you can say
things like don't let some don't let
PowerShell code that looks obfuscated
run again back to attack techniques
it's not about detecting the PowerShell
Empire it's about don't don't allow
obviously skated code or don't allow
office to inject the DLL an office
executable means simple things and
credential guard is the piece that
protects else ass so these are all
things to turn on app Locker application
whitelisting
do it to the degree that you can again
these things this is as I said a process
it's multiple years it's it's work
doesn't cost you anything except work
blood sweat and tears but you got to
start doing it so yeah there you go
there's the attack surface reduction in
the this was like this week these are
some of the exploit guard SR rules you
can block executable content from email
client and webmail so if the OS figures
out that's an email client then it can't
run an executable office applications
can't spawn processes or can't create
executable content or can't inject code
scripts can't download executables
obfuscated scripts can't call a Windows
32 API from an office macro like these
are all huge like that's the laundry
list of the most common attack vectors
so stay on top of these things you have
to be able to take advantage as they
come again you've got the windows people
over here figuring out how they're gonna
migrate stuff to the cloud you've got
the security people over here dealing
with everything else
no one's dealing with the actual
security in the area where it can make
the biggest difference another way you
can go wrong subdomains they are not a
security boundary domain admin in a
subdomain equals domain admin in the
forest it's just as simple as that
they as Microsoft says the forest is a
security boundary for the information
that is
and in that instance of Active Directory
so I don't really have much to say about
that except that everything is in your
Active Directory and it is replicated to
everything at least the key parts of AD
are replicated to every domain in the
forest it is not a security boundary and
min proves at the domain level I did an
assessment of a white a3 400 person
company that had 85 domain admins that's
probably a little bit on the extreme
side there you know their their manager
of physical facilities was a domain
admin and his password was Gunnar yeah
regular accounts as admins whether
that's you know added it to the local
admins are to the workstations admin
group or whatever you know regular
accounts not not doing that separation
of duties service principal names so
service accounts that are registered
with the domain but of course anything
that needs a service account that
service account has to be domain admin
isn't that the way it works if you're
creating a service account your virtual
admins right if I if I run if I have
access to your VMware environment or or
sometimes fun your VMware backups I am
essentially a domain admin if your
domain controllers are virtual write
those people are just as important as
your domain admins delegated permissions
in ACLs it's awesome when the help desk
can do password resets or join computers
to the domain but it is also amazing how
far that those permissions spread within
the domain there are ACLs on everything
and they get changed and people with
regular accounts I don't know how but
they end up with control over OU's that
contain accounts that then have
privileges or systems that have
privileges and so on you have to so and
this is I'll show you on the next slide
this is some of the new the newer attack
tools are really starting to take
advantage of delegated permissions and
Active Directory ACLs even to maintain
persistence so I'm a regular user in in
the
and I update an ACL that says I have
update access to your domain admins
group for simple example I don't have to
I don't show up as privileged like you
have to go looking to find that I have
right access to your domain and men's
group and I just need to tweak something
every now and then or reset password
access to key accounts right I you may
not be compromised now other than that
little ACL but I can use it to do
everything I want your directory
services Recovery Manager you know when
you install a domain controller to ask
you for some password for something you
have no idea what it's really going to
do with it that's so that if you
completely blow up your domain you can
do kind of an offline recovery of it
well you can also use that online and
its domain admin access do you know what
that password is was it created when
your domain was created back in 1997 was
it your company name or password because
I'm trying to get a domain up and
running here I don't have time to think
up a good password well that's that's
domain admin
same with your out-of-band management
you know your ILO's your dracs your
virtual consoles all that kind of stuff
and just frankly users with too much
privilege again we we are terrible and
and I don't have a good solution for
this one but we are terrible at
provisioning the appropriate amount of
access for people we always give them
too much so
bloodhound if you've never seen
bloodhound download it and run it and
then you know go see your shrink and
come back to work a little bit later it
it bloodhound will draw you a directed
line graph of your environment with
typically domain admin over here as the
goal and those nodes along the way are
our relationships between objects in
your environment so this user has an
active session here this and this user
is an administrator there so therefore
you can use that to steal that users
credentials and then that users an
administrator here and you can steal
their credentials that's those
bloodhounds first version then they
added in stuff like delegated access so
this account has delegated access to
this group of which this user is a
member and they're an administrator here
and and on down the road and ACLs as
well so I think some of the edges in
here are forced password reset
this user has the ability to reset this
users password who's an administrator
here who can get in here who can go in
there
I mean bloodhounds noisy hopefully you
can detect it as if you are on the
defensive side of this equation but run
it run these tools regularly because the
attackers are so why shouldn't you know
what they are going to find and this is
one of the easiest ways to audit these
kinds of hidden delegations and ACL
permissions in your environment and yes
you get the directed graph but
bloodhound also creates CSV files of the
output so those are our potentials to
import into your sim and your other
tools to do a lot more automated
remediation for this kind of thing and
as a bonus by running it yourself learn
to detect bloodhound activity right or
and then try to be more stealthy and
then learn to detect that more auditing
and validation kerberos another tool I
was talking about service principle
names
services register with Active Directory
so that you can request a Kerberos
ticket from Active Directory so you can
authenticate yourself to that service
more or less in so doing that allows you
to query act the ticket you get from
Active Directory is based on that
accounts password which can be cracked
quickly depending on your hardware not
as quickly as NT password it's like it's
many orders of magnitude slower but they
can be cracked
so again run Kerberos did learn how to
detect that and certainly remove the
unnecessary SPNs
or well and make sure how often do you
type in your service account passwords
hopefully not very often because you
shouldn't be logging in with a service
account therefore it follows that
service account passwords can be
incredibly long because you never have
to type them they're in a password safe
somewhere that has multi-factor enabled
hopefully and isn't doesn't have the
human synchronization of passwords going
on for access to the password safe
that's all another good one
so passwords on service accounts there's
no reason it can't be 20 25 characters
more doesn't you're just copying and
pasting them once in a blue moon or use
a managed service account
I think I must have said this a few
times virtual access to domain
controllers unbanned management DRM
protected accounts so again with with
Kerberos when you connect to a web
server and then access a back-end
database for example that web server is
proxying your access to the database
right it's it's impersonating you to
talk to the back-end database and gain
access to stuff that is required for a
lot of applications to work don't get me
wrong but that doesn't mean it should be
a complete free-for-all that web server
shouldn't be able to impersonate you to
everything in the environment this is a
relatively complex and involved topic
check out Shawn's
spark con presentation for for many many
slides on that one I'm not gonna go into
big massive detail but basically
protected accounts allow you to control
how that account can be used for
delegation so your service accounts are
prime basically your service accounts
and your min accounts are the prime
candidates for being protected accounts
you've probably seen some variation on
this slide if you've done any digging
into Active Directory this is
Microsoft's utopia worried about the
yellow right now so you probably can't
read that but we've got three tiers tier
0 tier 1 tier 2 tier 0 think ring 0 if
you if if you know how to say Bela
Padula la petula and you know what the
Bela padula module is I think your your
most privileged stuff so your domain
controllers go at tier 0 tier 1 is your
servers tier 2 as your workstations so
there are two things
can you hear me there we go there's
there is your ability to manage and your
ability to authenticate so you should
only be able to manage across and down
in special cases that's what this slide
is basically saying you can manage at
your level
and down if you need to and you can
authenticate up or at your level but you
can't authenticate down this is again
this is one of those roadmap things to
start thinking about tier zero right get
your domain controllers in a state where
you have you control the access to them
and the management of them and you get
that nailed down we've got some
customers working on tier 1 which is the
server level and that's a challenge
workstation levels a much bigger
challenge after after that so you know
take it again
this is roadmap stuff along with it
come privileged access workstations and
enhance security administrative
environment so short version is a
privileged access workstation is what it
sounds like you use that thing only for
administration you don't use it to do
day-to-day stuff and it is secured so in
in some organizations that is actually a
laptop that is a member of another
domain that has nothing installed on it
other than 80 administrative tools that
you patch out a band or basically
doesn't allow inbound connections so it
goes out to fetch its updates from wsus
or something similar has no other tools
on an isolated network that you may not
allow inbound connectivity to that
network at all you may have to walk over
there to that workstation and login and
the only thing that can login in there
is certain accounts and so on and so
forth right it's an isolate excuse me
it's an isolated workstation Microsoft
also does support or recommend this
concept of making your primary
workstation that workstation and then
running your your day-to-day PC as a VM
inside that workstation not the other
way around but because you don't want to
have something that's not privileged
having access to your virtual memory but
that is a way to do it if you don't want
to go to the full extreme of isolating
it but but honestly you really don't
need to use domain admin privileges very
often you don't need to log into domain
you should know every time anybody logs
into a domain controller period because
you shouldn't have to do it very often
so have those workstations make them
physical and make somebody walk over and
log into it better yet make somebody
else unlock the account that allows them
to log in there's no reason for it to be
unlocked at all or enabled I guess it's
a better term all the time enhanced
security administrative environment so
short version is dedicated to
administrative forests so put all your
admin stuff into a completely separate
domain that looks kind of something like
this the idea being you some people call
it a read domain you have and in this
case there's two of them you have a read
domain all it does is holds the accounts
that allow you to manage your domain
controller so that would be well period
so you have a one-way trust and then no
matter what happens to your domain
nobody's going to get administrative
credentials because there are zero
administrators in your production domain
they're all in this other domain over
here that is locked down and so on and
so forth and then optionally you can add
a second other domain which is the one
that holds all of your privileges and
users that manage or that work in your
production domain right this stuff
doesn't happen overnight
I am had time to dig into it 2016
facilitates this a little bit allowing
you to kind of manage it all under one
umbrella while still keeping it separate
I'm not sure quite how that goes but I'm
had time to look into it in depth but
these are all things you need to be
working towards especially the tiering
starting with tier 0 so there's another
tool called privileged access management
Pam in 2016 and it has two goals one is
to re-establish control over a
compromised Active Directory environment
by maintaining a separate Bastion
environment that is known to be
unaffected by malicious attacks so this
is what I'm talking about in 2016 and
then isolate the use of privileged
accounts to reduce the risk of those
credentials being stolen so Pam is is
basically creating that that red domain
but virtually within 2016 like within
your 2016 domain and it leverages just
in time and just enough access which are
tools to limit
the scope of any administrative access
that you have that's another deep dive
that we don't really have time for so
I'm gonna come back or move on to end
points end points are where it's at
right that's where all the bad stuff
lives that's what it takes advantage of
it's what it's attacking PowerShell we
all know about the PowerShell frameworks
phishing you end up on an end point
after you fish someone drive-by
downloads are still a thing and
attackers generally want to get on to an
end point and pivot macros are a great
way to do a lot of this as is other
executable content so again I'm not
trying to sell you any any utopia here
any silver bullets but all of these
things do contribute to raising the bar
for an attacker so gets powershell 5.1
remove to zero I don't know if it's this
creators update 2.0 will soon be gone
from Windows 10 it you won't have that
choice in PowerShell 6 I think is coming
out very very soon as well
constrained language mode like I said so
limits allowed types it basically stops
powerful shell from talking to the
windows API and yes you have parallel
our shell in your environment you should
it is the most valuable administrative
tool that you have you can't and
shouldn't ever turn it off but you can
restrict who can run PowerShell and you
can restrict what you can do with it and
yes you can bypass that stuff too but
again we're just trying to raise the bar
a MSI I didn't know where to put that in
here but I wanted to throw it out there
there is an anti-malware scan interface
in Windows 10 I believe that basically
allows antivirus products to hook into
the scripting engine and get fed the
PowerShell scripts that or any power
shell and other scripts that the
operating system is running there are I
believe three or four out of what 50 to
100 antivirus vendors who actually
support MSI again it's not a silver
bullet but beat up your vendor because
they should there's no reason not to
support it
they don't otherwise they don't get
see they may have other techniques and
ways of doing it but why wouldn't you
subscribe to the monster that it's
Microsoft and get all of the stuff that
it's gonna feed you write enable
transcription module and script block
logging for PowerShell and we'll talk
about logging and visibility as the last
section here runs this Mon there's been
lots of talk about sis monde whatever it
is it doesn't have to be sis Mon but get
endpoint visibility but first I'm gonna
talk about network the network's side of
endpoints restrict the amount
communication to endpoint who needs to
initiate a connection to your endpoint
yes there are exceptions there's stuff
like Skype although most of that is
outbound now you know voice kinds of
things you sometimes there's a
requirement Remote Desktop but beyond
that who needs to initiate a connection
to an endpoint why do you allow it or
why should you allow it and certainly
why do endpoints need to talk to each
other ever this is probably one of the
single most effective controls you can
put in place to stop a bad guy from
wandering around your network you just
don't let endpoints talk to each other
there is no reason so because usually I
mean sometimes it's possible to get
everything you want off of the endpoint
that you landed on as an attacker but
usually you're trying to find another
endpoint where there's somebody with
privilege or some other piece of
information that you can use to elevate
your access so don't let that
communication happen so doing it at the
network or firewall level is good
because you have centralized control and
it's not an endpoint technology that is
implementing that control but you have
intra VLAN issues which is where private
VLANs come in and it is actually harder
to manage because you have to manage it
at all of those different intersection
points of your various networks so turn
on an endpoint firewall again Chris will
probably turn it off but try to try to
notice that that is happening so you at
least you know make him turn it off so
that you have that opportunity to see
that he's there right so use simplest
case use a GPO apply a Windows Firewall
that basically says block all inbound
connections except
from my server Network and my assistant
minute allow RDP block everything else
like throwing that out there it's
something simple you can do that with a
GPO push it out to everything all of a
sudden when I land on a workstation yeah
I can I can change those rules if I can
elevate my privileges on that
workstation but you can detect me making
those changes you can hopefully detect
me elevating my privileges without being
able to wander around the rest of your
network right it is incredibly effective
means of at least slowing down in making
attackers visible so I started come back
to macros yeah yeah I know we use macros
not as much as you'd think there are
definitely people who use macros but I
can tell you you know the average
computer user doesn't know I don't know
I'm just trying to think of something
really obvious that the average person
uses the computer doesn't know how to do
but you get where I'm going with that
you really think they know how to use
macros like yes there are teams
accounting being by far the biggest
culprits they need to have macros
enabled does your HR department need to
have macros enabled with all of those
Word documents that they're opening like
they're theirs case in point if you
disable it for anybody disable macros
for HR because they love to open
documents so if you do just that it's
progress right who really needs them
though yeah accountants production
accounting those kinds of things
turn them off everywhere else you can
use a GPO to target that appropriately
and with office 2016 now you are
actually able to do that in a targeted
fashion for downloaded content only so
again maybe that inertia is rearing its
head again and you can't make this kind
of change globally but you can for
office 2016 or sorry you can for content
downloaded from the internet
run macros all you want internally it's
it's progress I'd rather you didn't but
that's a step do something with all of
the different kinds of potentially
malicious files the one easy thing to do
is change the file Association so that
if I double-click on a dot bat file
I get notepad again target that your
administrators probably would find that
in
but you know all of these these file
associations I should not be able to
open them
I should who uses HTF Isles
really especially attached to emails
does a I'm curious anyone know of a
legitimate use yeah I didn't think so I
use them all the time
but again don't let people use these
types of files there's there's lots of
ways to turn them off like I said
changing the file Association is a
simple one hop waitlisting the other
Bugaboo that inertia kind of puts a
crimp on am i doing here
so start slow turn the application
whitelisting in log on on in log only
mode and start to build your your
exception list your whitelist
right and and then start it at a high
level of granularity like I'm gonna just
whitelist see Windows c program files
see Program Files x86
I'm also going to check to see if
there's any world writable directories
in there before I do that but that's but
you know open it up that wide or just
lock down the users profile folders
permit signed executables or at least
don't alert on signed executables and
yes there are there's a lot of talk
lately about how to bypass that but
again we're just raising the bar empower
your sock or whoever that is right turn
on the logging with with app Locker and
if you start to actually block with app
Locker then just empower your your sock
oh I got an alert because something was
blocked I'm gonna check that with
virustotal
if it says hey then you probably don't
make a change if it says yes that is
probably good which is virustotal code
for we don't know of anything wrong with
that we've never seen any problems with
that file then your saw could
proactively add it to the whitelist and
maybe by the time the user clicks it
again it works right like you can make
this stuff easier on yourself and again
start start building that that corpus of
data start learning what you need to
allow run in your environment and then
you know just as an example
Citrix or remote access servers those
are the best defined servers in terms of
what applications can run because you
just had to
them all to make them available in that
that platform so why can't you whitelist
what they need to do because you
shouldn't be doing anything else on a
citrix server and that's also a nice
target for attack so real quick this is
the one piece that you may need some
outside tools for particularly sim but
visibility we there's been a lot to talk
about this so I won't go into it massive
depth but command lines ports and
sessions processes parent-child
relationship of processes the accessing
and changing of privileged things
there's one thing I want to point out
there the use of privileged access
PowerShell logging as I said new or
novel behavior now we're getting into
into machine learning and all those fun
buzzwords but Taylor some use cases if
you saw Julian's presentation yesterday
he had what 21 22 of them a lot of them
were really really good most of them
were check out his presentation if you
didn't see it the big one for me in
terms of the simplicity versus
effectiveness you know the 80/20 rule
here turn on object auditing for your
administrator groups for local admins
and domain admins and when I say what I
mean by object auditing is every time
someone queries that object you can get
Windows to generate an alert who needs
to to do to see who's a member of the
administrators group on a daily basis or
the domain admins group who's querying
those things on a on a regular basis
there may be some stuff and you'll have
to exclude that from your alerting but
once you figure out what the stuff is
that does normally query those things
then then you're set because the first
thing an attacker is gonna do when they
land on your network is figure out who's
in the local administrators group and
who's in the domain administrators group
and they might use WMI they might use
PowerShell they they might use net local
group administrators so and yes you can
watch for all those command lines too
with system on or what have you but why
not just create an event when someone
reads the group hopefully you get bad
event before they get enough access well
you should before they get enough access
to disable system on right that I've
seen multiple environments where they're
catching adversaries or red teamers
within a few minutes based soley
not other stuff else ass access lock it
down
turn on protection that's credential
guard command line length character set
profiling so long command lines I mean
long DNS names long URLs all that stuff
there's a tool called freak py FR e q
dot p why does frequency analysis based
on a dictionary that you give it so you
feed it what is normal service names
what is normal file names executable
names whatever and it will then be build
a dictionary that allows it to or a
database that allows it to tell you when
something doesn't match that so use that
against executables command line scripts
all that stuff look for office or
browser as a parent process changes to
privileged groups or GPOs anyone
querying ACLs again we don't go asking
Active Directory what are the ACL is on
the domain admins group very often
monitor your privileged access
workstations and your your
administrative domains and the use of
your privileges how about credential
manager so I mentioned sam'l earlier
I've had this I bring this up because
I've had this happen multiple times I
land on a box they've got a good
password policy or you know I'm kind of
stranded for a little bit I haven't
figured out how I'm gonna elevate
privileges then I realized they use
office 365 but they don't use sam'l so
the passwords are stored in credential
manager which are readable by the user
that I am logged in as so I just dump
everything out a credential manager so
but again who sequentially reads through
everything in credential manager you
might ask for a credential but not this
one this one this one this one this one
and then I reuse those passwords of
course usually they work for domain
admin I've had that happen poor-man's
you be a so PowerShell module logging
and just throwing these out there's
ideas so PowerShell will log every
module that is run so run that for 30
days log them all hopefully in a normal
environment remember what that list is
every time a module that you have never
seen before it gets run that's something
to investigate because PowerShell
doesn't normally do DLL injection
so whatever the modules are that malware
is running they're not normal
there it will hit some that are not
normally run same thing with sis Mon you
could baseline the normal executables
for your environment and logon activity
right build a running list of where the
users log in again the you can do that
on an ongoing basis this user has logged
into these ten machines when they log in
somewhere new generate an alert it takes
some maturity and some ability to
respond to these things but they're
they're hugely valuable and I want to
throw out there yeah as Julian said
yesterday don't log fail I mean not
don't log don't alert on failed logins
but alert on an unusual number or change
in the number of login attempts because
I'm gonna password spray everybody's
gonna do that but that's gonna generate
more login attempts for Monday morning
at 8 o'clock or you know overnight then
is normal so alert when there's a
standard deviation change in the number
of attempts right so it's poor-man's UVA
but they're there all those are some of
my favorites in terms of effectiveness
other stuff clean out your cas control
your SSL TLS sam'l as I talked about
patch patch patch and build that
mindshare have a plan figure out you
know build your roadmap talk to some of
this stuff and get those two teams you
know get one of them to turn around in
the canoe alright get going in the same
direction focused on your ad security so
I left you what zero minutes for
questions but are there any questions
alright I'll be around if you want to
talk further and these slides I'm sure
will be available I've got lots of links
for you to look at as well
you