hey folks thanks for checking out this
short video just wanted to share one of
the targets for this year's
capture-the-flag event we've got going
on at Calgary besides the CTF course
this year is an engineering company that
is building a missile launcher
controlled by TCP Modbus we had a couple
of industrial control Flags last year
but this flag shoots missiles which is
pretty cool
now we have t-shirt going on up in this
top terminal session and that's kind of
like mixing TCP dump and Wireshark
together so that you can see the
protocol communications a little more
clearly now over here we've got the HMI
which for the CTF event will be behind a
couple of firewalls just like you'd find
in a normal industrial shop but let's
connect to that controller and you can
see here up in the tea shark window that
we've got a three-way handshake followed
by some Modbus connections in this case
Reed coil
let's move this missile launcher a
little bit using our really amazing GUI
okay it's not that amazing but it does
get the job done we're going to move it
left 950 milliseconds now there's a loop
going on in the Raspberry Pi and what
that does is it reads the coils and
registers about every 30 45 seconds
something like that and once they see a
change they make actions so this logic
is very much like what we'd see in a PLC
so in this case the motors moving left
and the safety is enabled now it's great
moving a missile around but it would be
much more fun to shoot one I think so
let's exit this menu and go to number
four launch the missile have to disable
the safety to actually launch the
missile and we have to put in a launch
code so let's take a guess one two three
four no it turns out it's not one two
three four
not too surprised let's hope they don't
arm missiles as one-two-three-four we
can bypass that all together if we want
by using a direct connection to the
Modbus controller and setting the coil
and register values manually there isn't
any authentication built into TCP Modbus
so let's try this with any luck all
right we see we've got another three-way
handshake and some more data that's
going across between the two of them and
this is a little timing sensitive
because as I mentioned there's a logic
loop that's going on in there and with
any luck it says it's disabled to safety
and it wants to launch the missile and
there we go thanks very much for
checking this out we really hope we see
out at B sides on October 19th and 20th