foreign
welcome to my talk on adversary
emulation in OT environments
so about six years ago
this pop-up appeared on a couple hundred
thousand different devices all over the
world
and what was striking about this was not
necessarily that you know ransomware was
a thing but just how broad and how much
of the imagination of executive
leadership it actually captured
because the very next day many of us
were asked this question
are we secure
so the the problem is is that Executives
don't really want to have that nuanced
conversation of culture process and
tools because ultimately like that is
what is required to answer that question
around are we secure
what they want is that yes or no are we
secure that thing I read about in the
Wall Street Journal can that happen to
us
well
some of the realities of answering that
question
and getting to that yes or no is our
people are strained
us on the defense side we have an
operations group that is struggling to
keep up at times
there's a lot going on
process is not necessarily guaranteed
and the tools including some of our very
fine vendors their tools may not do
specifically what you expect them to do
in your time of need
but that doesn't help us answer that
question
the question is are we secure because
the executives are still needing that
answer
so at OG e
about four years ago five years ago we
started down our path on adversary
emulation
there's a couple of reasons that we took
we went down this path
one we wanted to introduce some realism
and we wanted to be able to control that
realism and realism for us is we wanted
to be able to test the low-hinging fruit
we wanted to be more specific and
intentional with the things that we were
going to test we weren't we could not
worry about those zero days and those
fancy things that we read on dark
reading and stuff like that we knew that
there's a lot of block and tackling to
get to before we got to this point
we we knew we needed to be iterative in
our improvements there was not some
silver bullet like Dale talked about
there is not you know this big gigantic
Quantum Leap Forward for us it was going
to be a grind to improvements iterate
iterate iterate over and over and over
again learn our environment get better
and we felt like we could do this as
long as we manage the three things that
we could control around scope frequency
and complexity
lastly we viewed adversary emulation as
an opportunity to develop our talent and
develop our culture
because I think we all will send people
off to some really expensive training
class and may not get everything out of
it that we're expecting because those
individuals come back to your
environment with your tools with this
with your own nuances and have to then
adjust to that environment so we figured
why why not just skip that part and get
straight to training in our own
environment
so that's why we went there now how did
we get there
so our goal
was to develop a process around it
and so it starts for us like midi threat
hunting programs
around you know some sort of
intelligence or a hypothesis of what
could go wrong in your environment
we take that information we develop our
threat we emulate that threat and then
we measure our tool response We Gather
that telemetry
we review that Telemetry we adjust our
tooling update our cmf update our
processes and then we the last step is
around automation of our response
this is the critical piece is we're
trying again to scale our people and to
drive those iterative improvements and
if we could just reduce one step of that
workload on our people we can begin to
address some of the concerns that we
have around are our people taxed
so what does this look like in real time
so it starts with some sort of CTI
trigger
and in this case
we're going to use the ecans ransomware
and ecans was interesting because it it
was specifically targeting electric
industry companies
and for us specifically it had a couple
of processes that we were kind of
interested in
and so we said this is a great
opportunity for us to take this this
threat intelligence convert it into an
emulation test our processes develop our
people
but we couldn't just say take take this
CTI report that we got from one of our
trusted vendors and do emulation we had
to translate that somehow and the method
that we chose is miter because it makes
a lot of sense
our goal on our operations front is to
move up that pyramid of pain away from
hashes away from IPS we wanted to go to
detect those ttps we wanted to push up
and so
the way we got there is we started doing
these translations
and so now members of our operations
team when they receive these Intel
reports they'll actually convert it into
miter tactics we'll then build them into
the emulations and that's how we go and
spin those up
and in this case specifically
the the tip offer us was around some
specific processes in the report that we
received we wanted to go see if we can
identify if a service is looking for
those processes and then trying to stop
those processes
we also looked at this Mass grading and
so this is one of the very first
simulations that we ran in our
Enterprise environment because we wanted
to be able to answer this specific
question are we secure when our
executive teams were asking
so we run the emulation you know we get
our feedback out of our tools you know
some tools you know responded admirably
you know we got everything that we were
hoping for some some tools miss the mark
and that's again okay because this is
probably where you want to fail this is
where you can make improvements this is
where you can iterate
so we made those adjustments and we
created those automations
so everything's going great here
we're into the we're into the I.T
but that's not really where we're
ultimately trying to get
because most of us
are crown jewels are in our OT
environments
so how do we go from this Enterprise I.T
environment towards OT for adversary
emulation
so much like on the Enterprise side
where we try to put some structure and
some governance and some guard rails
around our activities we wanted to do
kind of the same thing but more specific
to our OT environment and so for us it
began with how are we viewing our OT
environment now as Defenders pretty much
all of us here have seen the image here
on the left around the Purdue model
the Purdue model is fantastic because
it's a great tool that can be used to
communicate defense and depth and what
we're trying to do from a defensive
perspective
but the adversary doesn't necessarily
see it that way
the adversary sees it in areas of
opportunity
and so what we try to do is create a
translation between the two and say all
right if I take Purdue but I try to view
it through the adversary's mind or eyes
and say like how how are they going to
go and approach these problems we are
able to break the Purdue model down into
three larger groups I.T makes sense
beachhead and OT
and upon you know really looking at this
and thinking through this problem with
some of our partners we recognize that
beachhead
that's really where we're out to defend
or at least that's where our efforts
should be until we're able to
successfully defend the beachhead and
then we can probably move down into more
into the OT space
so
that's all well and good how do we get
there
so the path OT starts with just an
evaluation of maybe our DMZ
I'm guessing most of us in this room
have some level of DMZ a space between
your I.T and your OT space that's most
likely where the adversary is going to
try to communicate outbound from so our
first goal was can we establish C2 in
that environment
and so we took some miter tactics
we targeted some specific areas in our
environment
and we tried to establish C2
and we were successful because
ultimately you give it enough time you
can be successful but we learned some
really great stuff along the ways namely
we were able to test the efficacy of our
av EDR and firewall on specific threats
and that's hard to do especially in this
environment so we now know that that
first entry into our beachhead What
specifically those tools are are going
to look like and how they're going to
respond to threats
and then we started learning other cool
stuff about our environment namely when
we try to execute some C2 using HTTP
versus https we saw different behaviors
now I don't know how many people in this
room have read the ICS cyber kill chain
written by Rob and Mike Asante
but there's a section in that paper
where they talk about the importance of
leveraging some of the complexities of
your OT environment as a mechanism to
defend right you have home field
advantage and so this is what we're
building here
we think about that home field advantage
thing a lot and how can we leverage that
home field advantage to be able to shake
out the adversary faster or to perform
those disruption activities that we need
to
so we are identifying what makes our
environment unique how to leverage and
take advantage of that and in the
meantime we're developing Talent
which is not you cannot send anyone to a
you know a ten thousand dollar a week
class and have them learn about how your
environment is going to respond to
threats
so once we've established C2
we want to begin to turn our lasers
inward because if we're the adversary
beachhead is just the first step now
we're wanting to get closer into that OT
we want to actually start to get to a
spot where we can impact operations
so this is the area we're targeting
and uh you know we're running pretty
standard techniques
we're looking for connections we're
looking for system discoveries
information discoveries you know real
high level generic access operations
because we're new to this
we're developing this muscle we're
trying to grow our organization's
capability
but word of the wise
once you start facing inward you you are
going to run a risk of impact
depending on how far down you go
depending upon the systems that you hit
and so this is where we pivot back to
say these relationships
the control of scope the control of
complexity these are the things that are
going to enable you to successfully test
these environments rather than just
hauling off and running an automated
emulation campaign where you're going to
test all the things and you're going to
beat up all your systems and then get a
report and go work from that everything
we're doing in this environment is very
targeted tightly scoped uh you know
reduced complexity as we as we grow and
develop our own internal capabilities
so other emulation campaigns that we
focused on was around our low Bass
because that's what the Intel says
Intel tells us that adversaries don't
need fancy malware because we're
providing them all the capabilities that
they need and it's signed and it's it's
part of the Baseline and everything just
works it's all hunky-dory
so what we're looking for here
through these low bass activities is if
we if we are able to say
I'm performing this activity that I know
is malicious I'm able to detect that
activity we now know the adversary has
established some level of persistence
and that they have command and control
and our shift then moves into a
reduction of dwell time and A disruption
of any stage two activity
because in our opinion if you're here if
you're already that far down in the
environment and you're performing these
types of activities
you're likely an advanced adversary that
is seeking to move into some sort of
stage to you know moving towards impact
operations or reading impact operations
and so even our response our process May
adjust based upon the types of threats
that we discover and where but again
like these are not things that you just
like wake up and do these are things
that you iterate towards it takes a lot
of discipline it takes a lot of
intentional effort to get to these types
of capabilities
and so
the big observation for us too is around
just the the data collection the
Telemetry that we gathered
and uh we uh we like to think that we
have our own pyramid of pain on the
defense side
because we're really good at logging all
the things yeah storage is cheap send
that syslog stream over we'll just dump
it all we'll do analytics maybe later
um but what we see is we collect all the
things we alert on some of the things we
block a couple of things
and so how are we now moving up that t
those ttps
or up that pyramid of pain similar to on
the uh on uh with the other
pyramid of pain where we're moving from
hashes and and IPS up to the up to the
ttps
again none of it is accidental it's all
intentional as we're driving towards
that
and you guys are going to hear me beat
up on this one it's all manageable as
long as you are taking care of the scope
frequency and the complexity of uh
of your emulations
but we're at S4 and no one really wants
to hear about access operations we want
to talk about impact operations and so
we we've done a fair bit of thinking on
this uh and I hope I don't disappoint
too many people with the ultimate result
but uh you know there are some impact
operations worth pursuing and I'll tell
you why
probably one of the most important
things we're doing right now is we're
building a new lab
and we're doing a new lab specifically
to do impact operations but not for the
reason you're thinking we're doing this
fancy lab so we can start to develop the
security culture of our security or ICS
capability with our security people
because like much of you we have I.T
security people that we're trying to
transform into OT security people
we have OT secure or OT professionals
that we're trying to grow their security
capability
and we're trying to develop the
relationships that will ultimately pull
us out of the fire in case one were to
occur because going back to the you know
one of my first slides the process will
break down the tools will fail you
ultimately it's the relationships that
are going to help you recover from
whatever you're dealing with
so
let's just say we're going to go ahead
and uh and and continue forward with uh
our uh
our impact
so this is kind of what we would you
know still consider to be an access
operation where at this this time though
we're directly going after level one
level zero we're doing kind of same
miter tactics we're reporting out
um
and uh you know here in our lab
environment
uh you know we would actually have the
adversary attacking the the units and
stuff and so
I just wanted to take a pause on this
one and and say like we have struggled
to identify that specific value that
doing the adversary emulation on a level
one or level zero truly provides when
you think about it in the context of all
the other stuff that's going on so when
you think about the uh
you know
I'm sorry I just lost my train of
thought uh when you think about all the
the different opportunities to improve
across the the various miter framework
elements uh just in levels two through
four uh that that is going to chew up
all of your time
so
so in closing
and uh well I really burned through this
one uh so in closing our adversary
emulation activities have truly been
focused on levels two through the DMZ
um our goal is to prevent access into
that beachhead our goal is to reduce
that dwell time to disrupt any stage two
activities and we do aspire to one day
get further down into level one and zero
but we think that there's so much runway
here in the beachhead area that that's
where our main focus has been
so in our wrap up
the people the process the tools those
are the things that are going to that
that we're trying to to develop and
measure and grow through our adversary
emulation practices
um we really focus on what managing what
we can control and everything we do is
around iteration uh you know continuous
improvements and continuous iteration
for our processes
so
questions
so you uh you mentioned scope frequency
and complexity several times but what
did you really mean by that
can you what do you mean
so three times in the slides you you had
scope frequency and complexity and you
just sort of noted it as an emulation
but what exactly did you mean for those
three variables okay uh yeah so thanks
Bryson I uh I did just kind of cruise
right by that one uh scope for us is
defining uh the attack service or
attacking the uh
What specifically we're going to be
testing so are we testing a specific
system are we testing a specific
collection of systems what specific
tactics techniques or procedures
um you know that's that's generally what
scope is uh for us frequency
um you know there's some stuff that we
try and do you know quarterly with
Partners there's some stuff that we try
and do monthly just with amongst teams
and then we even have some uh some some
processes where our security operations
Personnel run these emulations on
individual virtual machines and so their
frequency is actually hourly that they
will go and run these like kind of mini
campaigns against you know antivirus
tools or EDR tools just to kind of see
what the different variations look like
and so as we change our change our
frequency that actually also adjusts
complexity
so with a lot of adversary emulation
tools you can build kind of a sequence
of events and so you can get a really
thorough and robust campaign but the
different measurements and the different
things you're going to have to look at
afterwards is going to be a lot for your
teams to kind of digest and decompose
and so what we try to do is we try to
you know limit the scope and limit the
complexity so that way we're testing
specific capabilities and specific
functions of our security stack is that
answer okay
so I'm going to ask a question it's
going to sound a little cynical and it's
not meant to be uh sounds like the
program that you've put together is
really cool and you're building out the
next generation of professionals with
this process you're giving them the
opportunity to really get their hands
dirty and see how to protect things by
seeing how to protect attack things my
question to you is
have you found as you've built this out
that people are poaching your resources
and what are you doing about retention
to ensure as you're making this
investment that you're not just becoming
the the feeder for
um you know other other spaces in the
industry that well candidly pay more
than utilities
yeah that's a that's a great question so
I think the The General
perspective of my team and I I that I
don't necessarily want to speak for them
but I have an idea of kind of how how
they position themselves
um they see this as continuous
involvement with them
right and that's not necessarily
something you get everywhere
and so we I look I'm blessed to have the
quality of people working for me that I
do yeah we're it's a really special
group and uh it's an intentional culture
right so like we talk you know I talk
about Talent Development because for us
we hire really we really try to focus on
the cultural fits and the people that
want to come and grow and look man we're
an electric utility or excuse me
electric company and uh so you're you
know the likelihood of people come in
and getting rich working at the electric
company's pretty low so the kind of
people that we tend to recruit
is kind of a different sort anyway
um and at the same time we're going to
continue to pour into our people and if
they end up going and making somewhere
else better hey that's great good for
them you know we we can't be afraid to
develop people for fear that they're
going to leave
so
but that's easy for us to say because
the again like the quality of people
that we've somehow managed to find and
maintain is exceptional and uh and so
I'm very lucky but yeah I I I totally
understand that perspective
thank you
um just to kind of add on to his
question I'm an Oklahoman so to answer
your question differently he's building
a culture
in a team as an Oklahoman that there's a
lot of there's there's a lot of jobs in
Oklahoma but he's building an
environment where people may want to
work and he's helping keep that
retention I know I've known Ian for
years but I now live in Houston Texas
and thank you for keeping my Oklahoma
power on that culture is so good that he
left yeah exactly
um so the people that do work for him
are working and staying and helping
drive a mission focused uh culture my
question to Ian obviously you're not
doing level zero level one monitoring to
the degree that you I mean I'm sorry
adversarial emulation to the degree that
you can share if you were a company
looking to do level zero adversarial
emulation where would you start
where would I start if I wanted to get
all the way down
uh I mean like functionally like uh you
know low-hanging fruit where would you
start if you wanted to test something in
level zero ah I mean I'd probably it
depends on what the the Intel says right
so I would probably probably start in
you know most likely are substations
that's probably be an area where I would
I would go look at
um you know generation facilities
probably as well like I think that those
are those are going to be kind of those
are the big ones right I would start
where I think that I could uh have the
most value
but again like each of these processes
are so different right and so like this
one sensor I attack it in one way it's
going to respond differently than if
it's in another environment or at least
it will that it will show up differently
right and so then I have to figure out
that Nuance between the the two
environments but I mean it would it
would be a I would look at what the
Intel says and then I would look at the
impact of the business and try and find
kind of that happy medium and I probably
the other one that I would think about
is where do I have relationships that
will help me get into those environments
and and in a way like take care of us if
you know something goes sideways because
you know that could happen right if
you're not careful
so I don't know if this is going to be a
longer question but at a high level are
you using commercial tools are you guys
doing uh build your own
so I was promised to not talk about
specific I had a promise to not talk
about specific tools uh uh I will meet
anyone out in the hallway that wants to
talk tooling but what I'll say is we've
gone through multiple tools we've gone
through multiple vendors and it took us
a while to find something that works for
us and we've looked at different stuff
um
the tooling question really is about the
uptake of your people right so what are
like what do they like to use
you know
um you know we were lucky enough to find
a tool that our team has actually taken
up on right I think a lot of us have
been through situations where we bought
something got it installed and then it
just withered on the vine right it just
it never got used
um but to answer the deeper part of your
question is you know it's a homegrowner
or vendor-led uh it's vendor and and the
reasoning is is that we talked a little
bit about the perspective of Defense
versus adversary
we don't have that adversary perspective
I don't think that we understand it the
way we think a third party vendor May
understand it they're probably going to
get it at a deeper level than than how
we get it and so having that
relationship to like help kind of Sanity
check us and it's like okay here let me
tell you how adversaries are really
working right that's valuable to us
um and we're also you know we got a lot
of other stuff to do so homegrown sounds
great and there's a lot of cool
opportunities and if I had the funding
to do my own red team like that would be
really neat but a lot of us don't have
that and so we got to find that kind of
happy middle ground so where we're at
now is we've got this nice partnership
uh but it's led by my teams they build
out the emulations they they they figure
out what they want to test and then they
can go confer come back and run it
through and that's where we're getting a
ton of value okay I'm definitely going
to talk to you because we built it
ourselves and it's a pain in the ass to
maintain okay yeah so if you've got a
special solution yeah man you just
totally validated my answer I appreciate
that
thank you
it's great
um you talked a lot about training and
using
which is an end product along that
process are there are certain parts of
the process where you see the lights
come on where you see people actually
get the risk and the challenge that
you're trying to teach them to to be
alert to and to be motivated to do
something about are there certain points
in that process where you really see it
happen
could you repeat that question one more
time for me please so as you're as
you're running your people through this
process are there certain points in that
process where you see the lights come on
where they actually get the risk and you
see that cultural shift yeah and how
they approach what's going on yeah uh
uh I think it's
so what part of that cycle do they do
they really seem to jump on so I think
it's the it's measuring the response of
the tools
because I think we all go in and we say
wow I'm spending a whole lot of money on
X tool and it's going to do all these
things and then you run this emulation
and you know that this process is Rand
and you see it go through and like you
know their firewalls logged it but it
didn't actually kick you know kick off
an alert it didn't block anything you
just see go right through like swiss
cheese and you start to have that
realization and it's I think this is for
my new folks like you have that
realization like oh my God
these vendors aren't blocking all the
stuff they should be by default shocker
I know
and so that's typically where we see
that first kind of voila moment
for my senior uh uh analysts for them I
think it's seeing that repetition
right because we you know all of us can
do something once but when they see it
baked into a process and they see that
continuous Improvement and like they've
been around long enough to know it is
the iterative step by step by step
improvements that actually will help you
you know create that defensible
environment like that's where their
voila moment is
so it's it's high touch it's that kind
of continuous nature of the of the
process that they seem to gravitate
towards
thank you that's a good question
okay thanks everyone
foreign