foreign
thank you
for the audience
let's start and learn about deception
oops yep so
people may tend to think the deception
is Honeypot and basically as is rely on
the basic idea behind honey pots it's
around 35 years old technology but
deception is basically took this
approach and make it to a platform
so let's start from the basic about
deception what is the meaning of
deception how deception is equal to our
real life
I guess everybody here took his kids to
a mirror maze and you know what's funny
about me or maze if you look on mirror
is from
above you can see a line of 25 meters
that you need to pass
if you go walking in the street 25
meters will take you half a minute
but if you take your kids into the
mirror message try to navigate
will take you at least 20 minutes and at
least two times you get your head in the
mirror
this is the idea behind deception
it's basically to take a real Network
Place fake asset fake device fake
application
the whole mission of the fake blanket
it's to get attacked by attacker
why because deception rely on a very
basic idea that nobody should touch
something fake
unless he had good reason to do it and
if you think about it
you will never open it though that
you're not aware they don't exist but if
you open this door
you do something that
against the policy so the idea behind
deception is to create illusion on the
network and basically
deceive the attacker to touch the wrong
asset versus the real asset
so let's try to understand what we try
to slow solve with deception
first
time to detect
and the mathematic here is very simple
if we spend more time on your network
the damage will be much bigger if you
detect it early in the kill chain
we reduce the damage so one of the
biggest problem of the industry and we
see it in the threat landscape for the
last 10 years that we try to reduce the
time to detect attacker there is many
analysts reports speaking about 200 days
100 Days end of the day we wake up in
the morning hearing about data breach
three weeks after the investigation we
discovered that these guys spend more
time on the network if we're willing to
detect attacker early we need to deceive
them early and this is what we try to do
with deception platform
and on this session we will learn how to
do it
the second time is the false positive
alert
this is one of the biggest problem of
the industry and I always describe it in
a mathematical way if you have five
analysts
in your soak and each one of them spent
two hours on a false alarm
meaning you pay for five Engineers you
get four because they spend 10 hours on
false alarm
with deception there is no chance
to spend
time on false alarm why because
go back again nobody should touch
something fake
if you think about it attackers that get
inside your network assuming assume that
you have 10 web servers but what if you
have 50 web servers
five FTP Service but what if you have 60
FTP Service the whole idea is to mimic
your environment
and make it 10x for the attacker so once
you get an alert you know that is a
relay because nobody should touch your
legit user contractor customer will
never touch fake asset because they're
not aware there is a fake asset
and the last one in the Otis space we
are dealing with networks that become
from airgap to Connected we are dealing
with devices that cannot protect
themselves cannot generate their own
Telemetry we're dealing with unpatched
devices and yes everybody here know that
you're still finding windows xp7 and Etc
inside your network
and you always have asset that I call
them problem of somebody else why
because you get devices from the vendors
of the OT but somebody else maintained
them and operate them so it's a problem
of somebody else but it's become your
problem
so as I mentioned deception is not
Honeypot Honeypot is a model inside the
platform Deception come from the idea of
let's take the network and split it to
four elements four silos
infrastructure endpoint and server data
and application
why because when threat act or penetrate
your network he always engage with one
of these silos he tried to move
laterally to keep engaging with more
so from deception perspective if we want
to detect the attacker early in the kill
chain
we will place deception on each one of
these silos we start with the decoy yes
it's a Honeypot by I call it Honeypot on
steroid not next gen why because it's
more scalable you get a long list of
inventory of decoys everything that you
have on iot iot and ID exist in
deception platform you can also build
your own decoy it's a new technology
that's coming
so if you look on the decoy today it's
not the Honeypot for 30 years ago it's
different it's more scalable place in
the cloud
OT iot and Etc the second layer is the
loo the services if you want to expand
the attack surface maximize your chance
to detect the attacker
take the services and make it 10x if you
have
five file server let's have 20. if you
have one sap system let's have three sap
or Erp system
this is basically try to deceive the
attacker the moment he land on the
network
the third element is the network
deception if you want to deal with
sophisticated attacker
this attacker always listen to the
traffic this attacker try to reroute the
traffic
try to pass traffic through the infected
machine in order to collect data you
want to attract them send them the
signal it's like a radio station
you get into your car you put the radio
station you're willing to hear the songs
this is exactly the purpose of network
deception sending to the wire single few
limited packets attacker willing to hear
and the last one
this is the last Innovation from
deception platform what we call
deception token breadcrumbs remember
attacker always land on a real asset
attacker Never Land from the internet on
a fake asset so the moment he land on
the real estate this is the moment we're
willing to deceive him so deception
token took the Honeypot technology to
deception platform into the prime time
by taking your real endpoint and server
the real one and convert them logically
to a hand to a decoy we basically Place
bread crumbs on the real endpoint and
server it's a fake keys to the Vault
fake credentials file application it's
an agentless technology it's not an
agent and basically when attack a
compromiser machine start collecting and
extracting data on the surface he will
get fake data it's always be attractive
he always get the direction go there and
if you go there he interact with a fake
asset
so how we do it
first
the deception when you plug it into your
network we need to interact with all the
network segments the idea is to cover
all your network villain and basically
the decoy just taking IP addresses that
nobody use think about it resource that
nobody use resource does not cost you
money basically you plug the software we
start Gathering addresses that nobody
use and we attach it to a decoys so on
every villain that you have X amount of
real asset you have y amount of fake
asset
once we finish to deploy the decoys we
get the topology of a fake Network the
system will start generating the keys
why because each fake Keys need fake
dough
so the system ensure that we create the
keys while the door are exist you cannot
do it before
once you deploy the deception token you
get one blanket on the endpoint and
server Network deception Services decoy
application and data think about it the
attacker get in
he never know what is the real what is
the fake we only need one time to touch
the fake
people tend to think the decoys and
deception need AI technology and Etc
machine learning nothing why because you
touch the decoy you shouldn't touch game
over it doesn't matter if it's a
malicious connection it's a legit
connection from attacker like Ping for
ETC for ETC for the decoy there is one
and zero you touch me alert you don't
touch me nothing happened
so once you engage with the decoy the
platform capture the whole engagement
analyze the engagement and generate
threat intelligence the idea behind
trade intelligence it's one to enrich
your threat analytics platform seems so
threat hunting and second
take the threat intelligence convert it
into mitigation response
deception platform utilize your
ecosystem in order to isolated or
quarantine the attacker out of the
network automatically
it's not just deceive and detect it's
not just forensics and analyze the data
we also mitigate it meaning we're
telling you that you have a problem but
we take care of the problem
so why to his deception in iot in OT
when I mentioned iot in terms of medical
iot many Healthcare adopt deception and
Audi critical infrastructure
and why people tend to use this
technology three main reasons there is
many of them behind me about three main
first it's non-intrusive zero impact on
your network second easy to install and
not require any network topology changes
nothing not inline configuration
shutdown plug the software start using
free address free IP address that nobody
use system is up and running and the
third one
there is no false alarm and false alarm
for all the team
that not all the time they are cyber
expert or not on the time they have the
time to deal with alerts to have a tool
that they know once they get an alert
Houston will have a problem
is a great Roi for them because they
know that they need to stop the
day-to-day operation and dealing with
the alert
and also it's not expensive
and if you look on Audi networks and you
want to understand how to detect
attackers with devices that you cannot
protect
think about attacker that get in and try
to find a PLC on a regular network with
20 plcs what happen if you have 200 plcs
from the attacker perspective it's
Heaven everything can be penetrated
everything is vulnerable he can have fun
and control everything but nobody tell
him that the moment he touched the wrong
asset this is the moment he go out
and how we do it with deception
it sounds like complicated maybe I'm not
mature maybe I'm not ready for deception
yes it was through six seven years ago
not today with all the virtualization
Automation in place
a good deception tool
basically automate 85 from your
deployment first he profile the network
he running as a discovery he can do it
actively scanning in all it is a
Forbidden World and also do it by
passive
we know how to take the traffic and
build your asset Discovery the system
build your asset discovery
the system analyze your network and the
system by algorithm proposing what kind
of decoy to deploy you get a nice visual
map with all your network and all the
decoys any element to deploy
you can customize it you can agree
disagree you can manually fix the map
the deployment once you click the button
go grab a coffee cup of coffee 20 25
minutes system is up and running
you have the decoys we have the token
you integrate it with your platform
you just wait for the attacker to make
one mistake
you know
one of the things that's unique for
deception
it's the ability to detect the attacker
on the first mistake if you think about
attacker that move literally he can
touch your firewall your AV other
security but if it's not reaching the
anomaly signature or the threshold that
these devices will not send an alert
with deception it's different
you need to touch one time to get
detected there is no place for mistakes
with deception attacker without
deception can understand what AV what
firewall what proxy what other system
you have with deception
it's kind of a game over he touched the
wrong door get an alert getting out
and deception while adopting the ulti
market
and by the way 40 41 of our business in
deception is in the outer space just to
understand the value of the platform
let's look on the Purdue model and we
basically build the platform to support
the whole Purdue model on the control
Zone we will deploy decoy PLC Legacy
system
PLC should support all the biggest
vendor in in the industry plus the
protocols on the on the operation one we
will see scada HMI management platform
I.T because OT always have ID desktop in
the OT people need to work with the
headquarter even though that they are
placing on the OT side
then we go to the Enterprise deception
support ID not just OT you can deploy
servers application data camera switches
printers anything that you have on the
network in terms of ID iot and OT you
can find with deception solution you can
also build your own you can upload your
gold image and build your own decode
that will mimic your environment exactly
deception can be part of your domain can
be part of your tools
and the last one is the DMZ where you
can place deception in the DMZ however I
always recommend customer to place it in
the DMZ close to an asset that already
get exposed but don't expose the
Honeypot people get excited for exposing
Honeypot to the internet but once you do
it 90 90 of the alert is a white noise
because everybody scan everybody it's
not will not help you but if somebody
compromise the web server and around the
web server we have a lot of decoys guess
what once you compromise the web server
and try to look inside the segment
because you know in the DMZ he will walk
very slow and sensitive
once he touched the decoy it's a game
over for him he get out
now
let's see of the success of the
technology because take time I'm with
deception almost 12 feet I start in 2012
for Gardner was
hard to explain them and convince them
there is a technology for the Enterprise
so we was the first company in the
market so I saw the market from day one
and today when it's a bigger Market
let's look on a couple of case study
first this is by the way one of them
that I was personally involved as the
product it's a gas station company and
when I asked the ciso why gas station
need deception technology
he had a nice answer
he said look I was a ciso
of a different company
on my previous company the way to
penetrate me was between five to seven
entries to my network
now in the gas station business when I
have 335 gas station
I have 335 points to attack me
and gas station in covid-19 was the
business that was opened so this
business was grow because it was the one
of the few business that the government
allowed them to be open
so the business was grow
more application more data they start
collecting a lot of information
he was feel exposed
so the idea was to place deception
and detect the attacker on the gas
station itself why because if I detect
it early in the kitchen I just closed
the line for this gas station and he may
keep running there and when I contain it
or isolated but it will not affect my
the rest of my network because for one
gas station penetrate the data center
data center connect to 335 gas station
it's heaven for the attacker but if you
isolate the detect it on the gas station
level this is basically what you try to
achieve with deception so we place
deception on the gas station gas tank
camera printers Point of Sales
everything that gas station have we
place with deception
and the second one
it's a us-based customer is a water
company and the problem for the water
company
is a problem that we speak but we are
not aware that is exists if you are
manager water company and you are
dealing with the I.T and OT
where you spend your day protecting the
active directory or protecting the water
systems
the team every day have the challenge
what to do and they are stretching with
a lot of alerts false alarm system to
manage so they hear about deception and
the reason they go after deception was
not the decoyote and Etc it was nice
they want a tool for early Bridge
detection with zero Force positive they
don't have time to deal with everything
but they want to get a tool that one is
signaling an alert they now stop working
on the I.T go to the OT because it's a
problem
this was the reason for them to buy
deception
for use case for many use cases first
otiot and ID second ransomware we do
ransomware
without agent without machine learning
we are not EDR system why we just let
the ransomware encrypt fake files user
not encrypted fake files ransomware
encrypt when he encrypt the fake files
that placed on a decoy that act as a
file server we detect is a ransomware
so we detect 100 of the time ransomware
y because we're letting the ransomware
to do his mission to encrypt fire if he
encrypt fake we know that he's a
ransomware it cannot be a user
lateral movement is the classical one
and of course thread hunting
so why deception
if you want to know if there is somebody
in your network
already in the network use deception if
you have i t iot OT that cannot protect
themselves use deception it's not an
agent it's around them and protect them
and provide visibility and the last one
reducing false positive it's very
important false positive cost you money
buying deception reducing your false
positive save you money
q a
thank you
so you mentioned that like most likely
if an attacker gains access to the
environment will be on a real system
so you guys have an agent on the real
system correct no
there is two elements for deception
there is the decoys they are running
inside the software just taking IP
address from the network everything run
in the software but the IPS from the
segment when you scan the segment the
decoy answer like a real system this is
one level the second level is the
deception token we take the breadcrumbs
the agent list it's a script that we run
on the real endpoint and server and we
are placing secret that the attacker
wants a compromise and get exposed he
just follow it we just inject like fake
credentials fake shortcut to application
we hide it from the user the user don't
see it you need hacking tools to see it
we inject it into the operating system
so once you get exposed to effect
credentials with a destination for
example we inject user password for RDP
session to a server you run a mimikat
Store password you extract the user
password with the IP he accessed the
server login fine it's a decoy he keep
playing with the asset not aware that is
a fake we keep capturing the data
alerting and mitigate it out from the
network so so you're assuming that he's
going that the attacker is going to
focus on what the red bread crumbs you
leave like to me an attacker first thing
they're going to do is they're going to
do some enumeration they might try to
figure out what systems maybe they want
to go after domain controllers or
specific systems but your product's not
going to give them because there's
multiple products out there for
deception so your product's not going to
give them misleading names for systems
it's just going to leave breadcrumbs
um with uh
in the hopes or the design that the
attacker will find those breadcrumbs
first before they find other legitimate
systems
making a motion on an endpoint he will
expose real data from the user and fake
data fake data will always be more
attractive for him he may not use it in
the beginning and in a later phase but
he know that he has credentials access
interesting application to go after
think about it one of the breadcrumbs
very simple very brilliant we place fake
network drive share that map to a decoy
but we hide the network drive from the
user when the user click my computer
they will not see the network drive just
on command line when attacker compromise
your desktop running in the background
you go after local Drive network drive
the moment you touch the fake you get an
alert without do nothing just you know
enamorate the desktop we will get the
First Alert this is how we detect by the
way around somewhere so there is
deception token you just need to touch
get alert or you need to execute the
data that you get so two different but
all of them in one package it's a script
running and disappear it's not an agent
okay so then your your system needs
credentials to be able to get into that
system over the network to drop the it's
a script that you put in the logon
script it utilize the user it's a user
space not admin we're running insert it
in the user level so once the attacker
can run it you see it from the user and
also can place in the admin it's depend
on the permission but the default and
the user level you don't need admin
access and you just place this place it
in active directory logon script is the
best way to do it there is many way but
this is the most reliable one okay thank
you
thank you so much for the presentation
how do you differentiate between the
decoy and the real one I mean if you
have an asset information asset
inventory system or a health monitoring
system or something how do you
differentiate on the two yeah it's a
good question we have we have a
mechanism in the platform that's called
safe list during that installation you
discover tools that monitor the network
monitoring tool vulnerability scanner
and Etc you take their behavior and put
it in the safe list meaning you let the
system know that if you get engagement
from this AP on this service ignore it
not alert and you also can block from
him the answer so if not map you in
their Network so you don't see that you
don't want to see the decoy on the
monitoring tool and you don't want to
see the decoy vulnerable on your
reporting on the vulnerability scanner
so we know how to ignore it and not even
be visible on their side that means
there's a kind of a master where you
know if it's a decoy or no I configured
in my side so if the monitoring tool
touch it I am not alerting I ignore it
and I also can block this connection and
say even not fingerprint it in your
system so you don't want to have like a
hpov and see your real network with many
many other assets at your networking
like what's happened like we get like
500 more assets today so it's working
both Direction
thank you
all right as Security Professionals I
think it's easy to say we get the value
proposition of this but I'm going to
tell you in real life we have to deal
with operations managers who don't want
us dropping anything in an environment
that they don't understand
so how do you
um recommend those of us who are trying
to educate our Business Leaders
especially our operations Business
Leaders that it's safe to put something
like this in their environment and it's
not going to cause
I can give you many many recommendations
but I will choose the one that always
work wait for the annual penetration
test that you need to do every year ask
them to put deception as a proof of
concept before the penetration test and
let us see the value how we detect the
penetration tester team early in the
kitchen it's always work we always sell
deception if the customer have a annual
penetration test several weeks before
deployed and let it run this is the best
proof you can have
I I think we have time for one more
question so go ahead so one of the
issues in OT honeypots is creating a
degree of realism so you can set up some
scada software or PLC or whatever and
emulate it but if it's not filled with
the right kind of points and the right
kind of connections you don't get that
prolonged attack or dwell time that you
might need to observe them deploy their
ttps to a later stage how do you guys
take care of that yes so
we have two kind of OT decoys there is
the emulation engine and soon we are
going to come with a full operating
system engine it's too different so on
the emulation part we basically create
an asset the look and feel it's like a
real PLC but it's not running the actual
OS the next gen of it this year we will
allow you to upload like a Rockwell
firmware and run it as a real asset we
take control of the networking that the
PLC should send we take control on the
Mac address we take control on the web
UI we teach the emulation to answer like
the attacker expect and and again I
always tell people you don't want to
have your OT as a cyber range only
things you need the moment you touch
jump and take it out you don't want to
let attacker 20 30 10 one hour in an old
environment to play because okay he will
play nice not nice he will move on you
don't want to let him move laterally you
want him one time touch take out so it
shouldn't be like 100 you need one
mistake remember even a ping or even
layer 2 attacks we know how to detect we
have an IPS engine in the platform so
even if you run many in the middle
respond there all these attacks that
under the hood we know how to detect it
because we're looking on the network
stack
right thank you
and remember if you cannot beat them at
least deceive them thank you
foreign