foreign
good morning everybody and and push
thanks for push I'm sorry about that
push thanks for coming down to Miami
thanks for having me well we've got 30
minutes and I've got a long long list of
questions so we're just going to dive in
but
um we had Bill Furman up on stage and I
talked to him about one of the more
successful programs I wanted to start
there with you as well we've seen in the
last couple of years a lot of work
between Department of energy and the
utilities in Sharing data and then
analyzing and sharing intelligence from
that data I saw
I guess it was in 2021 you had
150 Electric utilities serving almost 90
million American Electric customers that
were part of this program
has that grown much since 21 do you have
any current numbers
so first and foremost thanks for having
me here this is just a great space and
it's an incredible space because you're
bringing together
subject matter experts on OT systems
which is just a huge gap that we
continue to have and so building this
community is amazing um now
uh before I jump into the specifics of
information sharing yeah and the work
we're doing it might help to set the
stage in terms of where we are as an
office if that's okay
um just broadly speaking my office the
office of cyber security energy security
and emergency response or the shorthand
is Caesar Caesar's really focused on
understanding all threats and Hazards to
the U.S energy sector that's part of our
mission it's to how do you buy down
these risks you do policies you do to
tools and Technologies like information
sharing and then when a really bad day
happens you respond so the colonial
pipeline ransomware attack my team led
the response for that on behalf of the
US government in partnership with
Colonial in partnership with our
interagency partners at DHS and other
agencies now to do that work we first
need to understand what is happening
what is what are the threats that are
actually targeting Energy Systems
we've had a program along those lines
for over 10 years in our cyber security
risk information sharing program for the
Chris program that you were alluding to
the reality is that program was started
10 years ago
threats have evolved that program has
also focused on I.T threats we know we
know that threats are in the OT
environment so
it's it's still a really important
really important program because it
still gives us visibility of what's
happening on all of these electricity
sector and some oil and natural gas
sector networks but we recognize that we
have to evolve as well and so where
we're headed in terms of we're moving
beyond just threat information sharing
it no longer has to be one way where we
believe we need to be is that joint
collaboration we need to have industry
experts sitting down with government
experts it needs to be Engineers working
with cyber experts to really understand
threats otherwise we're going to miss
stuff and that's something that is
really important to me as my background
is a Power Systems engineer working in
electric utility industry what I would
often see is you would hear about cyber
threats and then my engineering brain
would come on and I'd be like well that
that seems like a big deal but
um I don't think it's going to take down
the grid that's not that big of a deal
now the reverse would also happen where
I would hear about a cyber threat and
someone would be like oh it's not a big
deal for electricity systems and I'd
think about it and say no that specific
software or Hardware is so widely
deployed across the sector that if
impacted could have a significant
disruptive impact on Energy Systems
across the country so where would that
as a backup where are we today so we are
actually morphing the program in
expanding it to look at Cyber threats in
the OT environment so what we're doing
is last year we really focused on
encouraging the utilities to not only
have the I.T side of the house which is
great rate but we also need to look at
the operational side so go deploy
OT sensor Technologies let's start to
infuse it and OT data together with
engineering information
and so where we are right now is we're
building a new environment that's going
to take the data from this from the I.T
side marry it up with the OT side we're
still in the beginning phases because
that's incredibly difficult to do as
this community knows OT data is very
complex and it's different than it data
and so what we're starting with right
now is developing an OT data taxonomy
how do we look at OT data and then
correlate it with it data just look for
anomalous activities so we're still
building that platform but there's going
to be a lot more to come in this space
as we start to expand things like sensor
technology detection
methodologies going forward so you said
it's been going for 10 years
I've heard from Bill and a lot of other
people that seem to you know is going
going and then really activity level
ramped up in the last couple of years
probably a little bit as a result of
colonial that you mentioned
has this effort
stopped attacks on the grid you know
broadly speaking the generate if this
program did not exist would we have had
outages in the generation or
transmission of power
you know much like with any cyber
detection tool or technology you know
you're you're looking at a lot of
different
events that are happening you know any
one tool is you really have to take a
look at it more broadly
um can you say any one tool has stopped
anything big we're stopping things
constantly all of our tools and
Technologies are stopping things
constantly including the Chris program
it is observing activity it is
correlating information with our
intelligence Holdings and we're getting
information out to the sector in a
timely and actionable manner now that is
one tool in the toolbox so I would say
it has had an impact
um a fairly significant impact on the
sector but I think the biggest thing
it's been able to do that other Tools 10
years ago were not doing was if let's
say one utility on the west coast was
seeing some type of cyber activity it
was able to immediately say entire
Electric utilities that are
participating in the program
you need to be observing what this other
utility is doing so we were able to
build a a network of data across the
country so we're not just individually
all looking at different pieces of
events that are happening we were able
to look at it all in the distribute it
broadly now the data got distributed not
to the utilities just participating but
to all energy sector companies across
the country through our partnership with
the electricity ISAC so one of our goals
in doing this work is certainly it
benefits us seeing what's happening but
the ultimate benefit need to go off to
the entire community so it has done that
we have seen threats fairly significant
ones that we've been able to get out to
the community and say you need to be
looking out for these ttps these
indicators and so
um I would say it has had an impact
downward early on I could see
some of your measurement would be
are we getting information are we
passing information for back and forth
how many people are participating how
many even if they're not sending us
information how many people are
receiving information kind of an
activity metric but now that it's it's
much more broadly spread how is you know
as director Caesar how are you going to
measure success what is the metric that
says
this program because you're investing a
lot in this and you're talking about it
growing this program is worthy of
continued resources how are you going to
measure that you know uh the metrics
question is always a hard one you know
how do you define metrics is that
something that you're
um what have you avoided you know what
incident could have connected conducted
an operational impact is it a
theoretical number is it an academic
number so metrics in the cyberspace
are hard they're not easy and
particularly on the OT space even harder
you know there's a lot of metrics that a
lot of companies will use at a high
level in terms of how had an adversary
or intrusion gotten through your trust
levels what your bit site score is
there's measures that we still are using
on the I.T side to say how good did we
do I think that's an actual area that is
right for more discussion to really get
into better metrics of what's the cost
avoided by having a system or a tool
like this and I would say that for all
cyber tools it's not just for our tool
right I think that's a gap we have in
the community and I think that's an
important Gap we need to fill and the
reason I say this is because when you
actually talk to senior Executives at
utilities or oil and natural gas
companies a lot of what they're thinking
about is cost right so they're thinking
about what technology do I need to
invest in and will it actually buy down
risk and I don't think we've done enough
work in this space to really start to
quantify value of programs like this but
also quantify the impact of cyber events
so how do we quantify cyber so that we
can make a better case to Executives
across the country to say you got to buy
down this cyber risk much like we buy
down Wildfire risk at West Hurricane
risk in the Southeast I think this is an
area that's right for this community to
come together and say let's quantify and
develop better metrics so that we can
make the business case to use tools like
this and and others that are out there
okay now that that program was one that
I think is
got a bit of a glow seems to be a
success
the theme of this conference here this
year is explore and when you explore you
don't always succeed sometimes you you
know you fall short you fail
what has the your group
tried and said we thought this would be
a really good idea we went at it with
you know the best of intentions and we
just decided it didn't work or we needed
to do it differently
do you have an example of that
oh geez um
uh that that's a good question in terms
of what is work what you know what what
Pro what hasn't worked yeah because I I
would hope some things didn't work or
we're probably not trying hard enough
right wasn't I I couldn't agree more so
again as an engineer you want to test
things you want to break things and you
want to see what works and sometimes
things don't work and that's okay
because then you get to think about the
next thing and you've learned from what
you've done and that's that's it's very
important
um you know you know on the government
side
we don't always do it that well and you
know and the thing is it's okay because
we're actually trying to invest in new
technologies right so so
I'll talk about a specific example that
where I think we we learned a lot
um in the sector and then I I'd like to
share a potential
um failure that we could have in the on
the horizon if you're okay with that um
so it's for the first one specifically
we have this this amazing program called
our cyber testing for resilient
industrial Control Systems side tricks
Citrix the goal of Citrix is to bring
together
manufacturers with cyber researchers to
really identify software Hardware
vulnerabilities before adversaries
exploit them right that's that makes
sense now we have amazing capabilities
at the National Laboratories to help us
with the testing let me step back so
there's three pieces there's governance
of a program like this there's the
testing and then there's the analytics
of all the data that you get
the National Laboratories Davies
National Laboratory some of which are in
the room today and I'd encourage you to
talk to them are doing amazing work on
testing they're doing amazing work on
the data analytics piece of correlating
this information how the governance
piece which you would think would be
something we could solve fairly easily
we've struggled in terms of the legal
contracts because this we're we're
charting new ground of industry and
government working together on testing
critical components on software that is
used across the energy sector and while
we have all the expertise on the
technical side what we realized was the
legal pieces of doing this testing and
who owns the risk of the testing when do
you disclose vulnerabilities so that an
adversary doesn't necessarily exploit
them but at the same time you need to
get it out to the community as quickly
as possible those are very hairy issues
and the reality with the program was it
took us a long time to figure out the
legal pieces to even get the program off
the ground so it took us a long time now
it took a lot of really smart lawyers
both from industry and government coming
together to really think through listen
we have to at some point agree that we
have risk even on the government side we
have risk with a program like this we're
going to be breaking things we're going
to be really testing things in a way
that maybe the manufacturer never
thought they would be tested before but
we got to do it in the in the National
interest in the company's interest
so why I actually I had some question on
Citrix why does the company need the
government to do the testing they have
very strong teams they have Deep Pockets
I was looking some of the two of the
first ones are GE and Hitachi they're
certainly big enough to be able to hire
people to do this testing themselves
that's a great question so one of the
things with scitrix says we started this
program when there wasn't as much
testing going on in in the sector both
hardware and software down to the chip
level down to the firmware level
um what we hope to do with this program
is the reality is we on the government
side we'll never be able to test all of
it but what we'd like to do is a couple
things one we want to develop a culture
of OT vulnerability disclosure and I
think we're getting there so we've
actually disclosed vulnerabilities
through cisa on cis's vulnerability site
to disclose testing now a lot of our
testing where we are focused on is its
intelligence informed so if we learn
about something from intelligence and it
directs us to say we need to prioritize
testing this component versus that it
will help us prioritize now where we
want to head with the program is we have
to get tools out to the industry we want
other folks to be able to do the testing
we want to publish things like
methodology to do this testing on your
own and for my advantage point I think
we have three tiers for testing in the
future potentially I'd love to get your
thoughts give it given your background
now one is some of the utilities are
doing their own testing whether it's
vulnerability scanning or some other
work that's tier one tier two is
possibly bringing in a third party
company much like you would bring in a
pen tester to do testing because it's
higher risk now the third tier is maybe
National Security threats that's the
piece that I think where we live but the
work we do at Citrix the goal is to get
it out to the community the testing
procedures the tools that we develop so
you all can do it yourselves as well
I I'm just wondering and maybe this is
part of the legal issues because I I did
look
like the the initial testing on geur
family of relays they found old versions
of SSH HTTP for management
unauthenticated firmware upload Hardware
coded credentials uh insecure Factory
support mode and Hitachi hard car plane
tax on the device and then the backup
files and things like that I mean that's
that's really basic stuff that's you
know that's that's the kind of thing
that probably half the audience could do
in in a couple of days on one of these
devices is there is a real juicy stuff
is that still hidden behind all these
lawyers and it's like yeah you can put
that stuff out but I'm hoping there's a
big treasure cache that we don't know
about yet so we're constantly disclosing
vulnerabilities I won't get into any
specific vulnerabilities but I will say
um I think this has created a cultural
shift even with the manufacturers
because I mean these These are companies
that are really large they've been doing
their work in terms of engineering these
types of devices and components for a
lot of years and a lot of the Cyber
Folks at some of these big companies
also have to get the engineers to
rethink how they engineer some of these
devices with cyber in mind and so that
actually leads me me to something that
we're really focused on is a concept
called cyber informed engineering
perfect transition that was where I was
going oh perfect okay so so cyber
informed engineering the idea is how do
we get the engineering side of the house
to really design these things with cyber
and mind I think that's important as a
former engineer and working on designing
grid equipment and and systems because
we have to think about how we think
about the grid you know from a utility
perspective is we want it to be reliable
we want to be safe
super important but what I'd offer is
you cannot be reliable or safe if you're
not also secure and so we have to
include that in the equation that is not
a an option it is a requirement for
these systems to operate safely I mean
where we're seeing a lot of cyber
threats is no longer just getting data
and being able to you know use data by
cyber adversaries we're seeing
capabilities out there that are that
could have destructive capabilities
safety impacts you think Triton tries
this you think pipe dream these are real
threats that could actually have
operational impacts so I think we're
seeing a shift we're seeing a shift in
the in the community to say we got to
make sure that these things are designed
with security in mind and and so to to
the comments in terms of the
manufacturers we've had agreements in
place for side tricks with Hitachi
energy Schweitzer and Schneider and I'm
really excited that we just signed a
brand new agreement with GE gas power
and it was really exciting to get GE gas
power on board as well and what I'd say
about these vendors is they're coming to
the table because they recognize they
want to ensure the security of their
products they want to make sure that
they're applying the best techniques to
secure them in the future and I had
applaud them for being partners with us
so um you know again I think cyber
informed engineering is where we need to
be and would be happy to talk more about
that if you had any specifics on it I
don't know I don't know that I'm on the
same page with you on side tricks but I
think the Cyber informed engineering is
is interesting and how is that different
[Music]
would you say that's different by than
secure by Design or is that are they
kind of just different names for the
same thing
I think there's there's certainly
um uh similar Concepts I mean even cyber
informed engineering secure by Design is
one of those those terms that have been
around yeah for a very long time
um where what we've done now is we've
built a strategy around it to say here
are specific things that we need to do
as a community and so one of the next
steps is the strategies on our website I
encourage you to look at it is we want
to work with the community to say what
are specific activities that we can do
together to buy down that cyber risk in
our engineering designs going forward
for for example one of the things we've
been thinking about is how do we better
work with the IEEE community in terms of
their standards so if you control F
substation standard out there you don't
see cyber in that substation standard
it's all design standards so how do we
better work with engineering communities
and standards organizations to ensure
that we can look at their standards and
say you can change this by doing this
this and this to build in some of the
security requirements that's just one
example of what we need to be doing but
there's a lot more we can do with
Academia engineering schools out there
to embed cyber into the curriculum going
forward and
I think it's acknowledged in the
document which is quite a good document
I'd encourage people to look at it this
is a long process
and we got to start it sometime right
and it probably should have started 10
15 20 years ago but we have to start
sometime so that's good you can you can
only do what you can do today right
but what does some of the early winds
look like like sometimes in these 10 15
year projects
you just don't know if you're making any
progress for the first couple years but
like two years from now how would we
know if we have started down that path
in our succeeding
you know there's a lot to work on when
it comes to the concept like cyber
informed engineering
we've been talking about that a lot with
my team in terms of where can we
actually have an impact and so one of
the first areas we'd like to focus on is
standards
again as someone who is designing this
equipment I'd be pulling up IEEE Sanders
design it why don't we as a cyber
community go to them and go into their
space to say instead of trying to create
a whole new standard you have to follow
can we partner with you and help update
your standard with some of these I think
we can do that I think it's low hanging
fruit
we can do that
ASAP it will take two different
communities coming together the
engineers and the Cyber folks unlike
ever before I think this conference is
where you're actually seeing those
communities come together but we need
this to we need to take this back to
some of the organizations out there but
I think that's an area that is right for
us to in two years if we haven't done
something in this space to change
standards I don't think we'll have
succeeded in the way I'd like to succeed
you know one thing I noticed I think it
was on page nine you had four bulleted
examples you said these are examples
where cyber informed engineering will
make a difference
and three of the examples were
maintaining a manual capability
manual operations capability and the
fourth example was having the safety
system
separated from the control system
so to me all those are saying you need
to be able to continue to operate
in a certain time period you know you
might have an RTO a recovery time
objective but you need to be able to
operate your critical infrastructure if
your ICS is hit
um why not I mean especially since there
were only four examples and all all four
were like that why not just say that
so those are just examples of things
that we should be thinking about
um certainly we need to do a lot more
than that okay um you know when we think
of the the cyber security framework of
identify protect detect yeah respond and
recover we have to have plans along all
of those areas they can't just be all
um
um protect we have to be doing more
detection we have to be prepared for a
day when you have to have some type of
manual operations the reality is with
the energy sector electricity sector
every other sector depends on it being
up we cannot function in terms of our
Economic Security our national security
without electricity it's one of those
critical sectors in fact a super
critical sector so we have to be
thinking about some of those manual
operations and other ways to ensure that
we have that but those are examples we
need to think more broadly than that as
well yeah I do think you're right I
think I think that that could be like a
short-term win
you know because someone can do that
pretty quickly but the idea of working
with maybe SEI or someone else on the
coding side and the engineering side I I
think that's really a worthy effort I'm
hoping
you know it's been taught as you said
it's been it's the concept has been
around but now you've got this great
paper out you've got some mind share
behind it we have uh inl here with their
CCE which is kind of related and I'm
really excited to see if we can move
that forward
well I I I'd love to do that would love
to partner with this community here so
we're going to be doing Outreach to the
OT cyber security Community to the
traditional engineers and we're going to
need all of you coming to the table to
actually put forth their ideas on how we
can move the ball forward so we would
look forward to doing that
and to me that it was going to Pivot to
this clean energy cyber security
accelerator that might be an excellent
project for your accelerator to try to
get some of the
OT vendors and maybe asset owners
because there's parts of it to both
involved in that
yeah so that's a that's a really
exciting um effort that we just launched
um it's called the clean energy cyber
accelerator
um so my office Caesar is certainly
focused on Cyber threats I would say
more than half of our budget is focused
on Cyber addressing cyber
um but we are in all hazards office I'm
looking at threats such as climate-based
risks physical security incidents like
the ones we saw in Moore County we're
looking at an electromagnetic pulse or
an EMP we're looking at geomagnetic
disturbances any risk or threat that can
impact the energy sector so in that vein
we are thinking of climate risks and so
we know that with these climate risks
that are upon us that are causing these
hundred year every 100 Year storms to be
every couple of years now
we have to address that risk we have to
address that by evolving Technologies by
integrating new sources of generation
wind solar batteries electric vehicles
all of this needs to come online as we
start to battle the climate-based risks
that are out there now as we do that
we're adding more connectivity more
sources of generation more comps
Pathways new architectures onto an
already very complex electric grid so we
need to ensure we're getting ahead of
this you know I like to say we have an
opportunity right now in the in the
energy sector globally to ensure that we
are building back to cyber cyber
informed Engineering in the past we had
a grid of the past that we were bolting
on security onto how do we re really
ensure that as we're designing the grid
of the future that is not just
theoretical anymore the the government
is spending trillions of dollars private
Equity is spending trillions of dollars
in the Grid in the next five to ten
years doe alone will be spending 62
billion dollars to advance the clean
energy
grid of the future just alone that
doesn't even include in the private
investment so we're seeing all this big
shift in change happening in the energy
sector and so we need to find novel ways
of getting together a cyber community
with the clean energy community and
again there's a very different community
so this accelerator is one such way we
get to do that we have a at our national
renewable energy laboratory and some of
those folks I believe are in the room we
have a a test ground we have a cyber
range where they've actually set up a
wind solar EVS batteries all in a
connected grid environment disconnected
from the live grid because it can
generate its own energy but the cool
thing we can do is bring in cyber
security technology vendors to come in
and test their tools and products in
that environment before it gets deployed
into the broader energy sector and so we
started with the First Technology the
first cohort was multi-factor
multi-factor authentication Technologies
there's a group of subject matter
experts that review Technologies they
picked a couple that they're going to
test in this environment to see do they
apply in this new grid of the future and
we're going to continue doing that type
of testing on different types of
security measures and Technologies using
the accelerator site I'd encourage you
to look at it we just closed cohort 2 of
a new of to Discovery in an OT
environment or in clean energy
environment we're going to be continuing
to do more cohorts and I encourage folks
to look at it yeah I had a question on
that but just to let people know and uh
nrel National National renewable energy
laboratory they are outside they're one
of the worthy causes today so if you
want to learn more they're they're right
outside the doors there
it's funny I had Marty Edwards up here
years ago and I had like a table and I
had like a spotlight on them like I was
interrogating him but one of the
questions I asked him back then and I've
asked a few government people is your
job is so hard you've got you talked at
the beginning about the scope of it so
I'm always a little bit surprised when
you do things that
the commercial world is already doing so
for like you mentioned cohort cohort 2
they said
they are seeking applicants with
solutions that actively identify all ICS
assets connected to a utilities
infrastructure well I mean dragons
Clarity no Zone mealtoria I mean skate
offense I mean that's that's
you know the largest number of our
sponsors do that that's that's kind of
proven
um why would you repeat something that
the industry has already shown
so when you have so much to do already
so the the different thing here is this
is a different evolving grid this isn't
the grid of the past that we've been
using these Technologies on these These
are newcom's Pathways these are new
connection points that we have not seen
before in a grid environment so you're
seeing different sensor requirements out
there you might see different sensor
apartments different places to put this
asset Discovery and in some cases some
of the Technologies you just mentioned
are great tools out there and they will
work fantastically in this new
environment in other cases they might
not but the energy Community you know
generally traditional utilities want to
play it safe for good reason right they
don't want to add latency they don't
want to break things right and so
there's always that concern of if I go
deploy this new technology will it
create an impact on my system and have
unnecessary consequences and so giving
the both the manufacturers and the
utility Community a space to something
and then deploy it broadly now we might
be able to test it quickly right yeah
and say cool this works but in other
cases if it does cause an impact we
might need to work with the manufacturer
to say how do you change it so that it
doesn't have that impact yeah that's
what I was thinking so are you actually
seeing sometimes where the vendors come
in with one product and then based on
what they learn change their products to
to better suit this environment that
they're testing so so we just went
through cohort one okay uh this is still
um this effort is in its infancy you
just launched cohort 2 and asked for
folks to apply to it and even with
cohort one there have been just great
conversations with the experts at the
National Lab and the Cyber technologies
that we're chosen to say how do we think
of this differently where could this be
placed instead of here versus there so
so there actually is fueling really
great conversations between experts both
at the technology developers so yes we
are seeing some of those great
conversations well it's as an incredibly
broad scope incredibly hard job I mean
these these are not easy problems and I
do appreciate you and your team for
working on them and it's good to see the
interaction with the community too so
thank you very much for coming down here
I appreciate being here thanks so much
and we're hiring
[Applause]
foreign