foreign
welcome everybody today I want to talk
about lateral movement at level one and
that's because there's quite a few
devices at level one that sit at the
intersection of different mixed networks
they might be connected to an RF modem
which talks to a wireless hard Network
or to a Tetra Network where you can have
scada communications or there might be
field bus networks nested behind this
device and even connections to
third-party packaged units maintained by
external parties and while there has
been some research in the past on
Upstream hacking from level one for
example from an rtu all the way up to a
scada there has been very little
attention to arbitrary East-West
movement at this level as well as deep
Downstream movement
so a question you might ask is why
bother with this this is all stuff
that's very deep down in the soft
underbelly of OT you know why why care
about this well because I might want to
cross certain security perimeters that
do exist at these levels after all if a
device is multi-homed between different
zones with different security profiles
it is a perimeter device and it should
be hardened accordingly in the same way
that you would harden a workstation that
sits between different security segments
one example of this is something you can
find in the interaction between the
basic process control system and safety
instrumented system architectures
obviously this can be generalized to any
set of distinct but interacting control
systems but we take the bpcs sis
interfacing as an example on the left of
the slide you can see an increasingly
common architecture where the bpcs and
the sis basically interact at a level
above level one and this segmentation is
typically drawn through regular
firewalling but another architecture you
sometimes encounter is the so-called
interfaced architecture where the
controller in the bpcs has a direct
point-to-point link to the safety
controller and this can be a Serial link
this can be an Ethernet link but what
matters is that it is a very restricted
point-to-point link
now why would an attacker want to cross
into these Safety Systems there are many
obvious reasons for this but one of the
reasons our so-called sis bypasses and
for the people unfamiliar with this
concept there's various good reasons why
you might want to bypass safety
functions for example as part of process
startup as part of process transitions
or regular scheduled maintenance and as
you can see Illustrated in the
simplified block on the slide a bypass
allows you to bypass a single actuator a
sensor or entire safety instrumented
function within the sis but before you
can activate a bypass it needs to be
explicitly enabled now historically all
of this stuff used to be hardwired but
increasingly activation of bypasses is
done through software signals including
software signals sent from the bpcs to
the sis however what you sometimes see
is that the enabling of a specific
bypass will require a Hardware switch to
be turned and this Hardware switch might
not be hooked up or reachable from the
bbcs at all and will require you to have
a sort of foothold within the sis in
addition these bypasses might have
certain constraints they might have
timeouts on how long they are active and
there might be limits on the numbers of
simultaneously active bypasses that an
attacker might want to disable
so these are all reasons why you might
want to move very deeply into the sis
another aspect of perimeters that exist
at level one are through so-called field
bus couplers and so for those unfamiliar
with the concept A field bus coupler is
essentially a sort of limited Gateway
that sits between different fieldbus
networks that might hook up a profibus
DP Network to a profinet network and
essentially what it does is it moves a
limited set of i o values between
different Masters on these buses now
this is not necessarily a perimeter but
what you see quite frequently is that
when you're dealing with packaged units
for example HVAC or for example entire
gas turbine some asset owners opt to put
a field bus coupler in between that
packaged unit where a vendor might have
remote maintenance access and their own
basic process control system and because
essentially only a few i o values are
moved up and down and these devices used
to be historically dumb there used to be
a reduced attack surface and these kind
of couplers are seen as sufficient
perimeter by themselves but as these
devices have gotten smart with all the
stuff that entails that is typically no
longer the case
the second reason why you might want to
bother with lateral movement at level
one is because you need a certain sort
of granular control over these systems
if you look for example at this slide
you have an attacker and he's able to
reach out to the top level Master PLC
and behind the PLC there are different
nested networks of other plcs and field
devices and they expose their own set
points process variables configuration
interfaces to this PLC but obviously not
all of that is exposed at the level of
the master PLC so if I want to
manipulate what is going on in that
system I cannot immediately influence
what is lying behind that Master PLC now
in some cases traffic might be routable
over sip or S7 to these plcs but in
other cases there might be non-routable
links behind it and even if the traffic
is routable that means that I often
cannot send malformed packets over those
routable links and I can also not reach
out all the interfaces that might
otherwise be exposed so that means that
I might need to in initially get code
execution on this master PLC before it
can move to this other plcs in order to
bypass any sort of functional or safety
limits within them
now this kind of thinking is very common
in automotive exploitation which you see
a lot there is that attackers they
initially get code execution on some
sort of a multimedia unit but it doesn't
Grant you deep access to the canvas you
need access to so initially they first
will need to bypass some sort of a cam
command filter that exists within the
can controller and then they will need
to Pivot to a Gateway in order to access
the exact kind of canbus to achieve the
kind of effects they want so that's
essentially what we're trying to do here
as well for OT Networks
so what do vendors and standards say
about this kind of lateral movement and
these kind of connections so it seems
that over the past years there has been
a general acceptance of the integrated
interfaced and common architecture for
bpcs and sys integration that comes with
the typical segmentation advice
however there does seem to be quite a
few pieces of guidance out there that
say that non-routeable or serial
point-to-point links are sufficiently
segmented of themselves and that is
something that is definitely not true in
my opinion not all the guidance says
this but there's some guidance out there
and to illustrate this a little bit in
more in more depth we built a little
proof of concept scenario to Showcase
how this looks like in practice
so we based our scenario on the scenario
of movable Bridges so as you can see on
the slide you have a bascule bridge and
the Basco Bridge Leaf opens as the
counterweight moves into the pit and as
the leaf closes it will hit a limit
switch that essentially says you're
about to close decelerate to creep speed
so you know you don't hit the bearings
too hard and once it's fully closed it
will allow the lock bar to unlock and
then essentially close and put you know
the leave in in a sturdy place now
there's many ways in which an attacker
can seek to attack a bridge structure
like this but one scenario obviously is
attempting to close the bridge Leaf at
full speed and hit the bearings possibly
with the log bar driven now this is not
something you you can do from the scada
interface you will need to bypass a lot
of functionality for this you'll need to
make sure that the deceleration to creep
speed doesn't happen you will need to
bypass the leave and the lock limit
switches and the second scenario has
similar constraints so for example if we
want to close at maximum velocity and
then trigger an emergency stop which is
not graceful and will cause the inertia
of the counterweight to have large
forces move throughout the bridge leaf
and we will need to bypass creep speed
as well as well as have an ability to
trigger this emergency stop from our
position Point as an attacker
now we sketched out this little
architecture to come with these
scenarios it's based on several real
world Bridge management systems that we
uh that we saw and what you essentially
have here is that each of the individual
bridges are delivered as packaged units
managed by a local municipality for
example well the overall Bridge
management system is maintained by a
regional or a central government agency
now what happens is that from the scada
interface they talk to a coupler device
and this has a very limited interface
that doesn't allow you to talk to the
bridges directly you just are able to
manipulate some values that are Exposed
on part of this coupler that say open or
close this particular bridge and the
coupler then talks to the individual
Bridges and each of these individual
Bridges is controlled by an object PLC
that exposes again a limited set of
values for example something that allows
you to initiate an opening or a closing
sequence but definitely nothing granular
that allows you to bypass this creep
speed or manipulate these these um limit
switches so an attacker who wishes to
achieve a scenario like we just sketched
we'll first need to get code execution
on the coupler and then from there hop
on to the object PLC and from the object
PLC maybe manipulate these detailed
Bridge systems over the field bus in
this case it can open field bus we
picked for this scenario and if they
want to bypass any sort of safety
constraints they will need to hop across
the restricted point-to-point link to
the safety controller and achieve their
effects there
so in our scenario we used as a coupler
device we use the Wago 750 series but
really could be any sort of coupler and
this talks to the object PLC controlling
the bridge which is a Snyder Electric
and 340. we can't talk directly to the
m340 so first we want to be able to
bypass that sort of limit by hopping
onto the the Wago and the way we do this
is we exploit a more formed FTP packet
so we get code execution
pre-authentication by exploiting one of
the nucleus 13 vulnerabilities that we
covered a couple of years ago in our
research once we have code execution on
the Wago coupler what we do is we hook
its modbus Handler to effectively become
a proxy Handler that allows me to speak
the UMass protocol which is a protocol
proprietary to Schneider Electric under
function
code065a to the m340 plc
oh
it's one too far so
um yeah once I can talk to the object
PLC um I can speak the Schneider UMass
protocol and this is one of the best
understood and reverse Engineers
proprietary protocols out there
historically it used to be
unauthenticated but Schneider introduced
an application password at a certain
point to restrict the ability to start
and stop the PLC and download the logic
and all that sort of stuff
vulnerability was discovered in this by
multiple independent parties because of
the way it works as outlined in this
slide so the first thing you you
effectively do is you read a memory
block that holds a hash over the salt
and password then you do a nuns exchange
with the PLC then you do a take
reservation request where you use this
secret and the nonsense and then you
send authenticated messages essentially
to this PLC with these nonsense now
obviously if I can read this memory
block with the secret then essentially
it's it's client based authentication so
Schneider to fix this this secret is no
longer in the memory block but there
were a few other ways to bypass this
authentication that we did not see
covered before in which we reported to
Schneider
um in the advisories that you can see on
the bottom of the slide so one of them
is the ability to do a reservation
replay what I can do as an attacker is I
can sniff a legitimate authentication
hash and then I can Replay that because
the nonsense are globals held by the PLC
in memory they're not tied to any
specific section session or any specific
IP and they don't refresh automatically
so if someone legitimately authenticates
to the PLC and I sniffed that particular
authentication hash and I don't do my
own non's exchange those old monsters
will still be valid and I can use those
as part of my replay authentication hash
a little bit of a more a convenient way
to bypass this for an attacker is to
forge authenticated requests I can sniff
nonsense and the reservation ID and
because essentially these reservation
IDs are not tied to any particular IP or
session and because as you can see in
the previous slide on the bottom there's
no actual secret in the authenticated
request as long as I know the nonsense I
can just forge arbitrary requests and
inject them in that section
so once I'm able to bypass the
authentication I want to get code
execution on the m340 PLC now there's
different approaches in Prior work some
of them include downloading logic to the
PLC um for example vulnerable messages
as part of UMass which have been
exploited vulnerable TCP stacks on some
of the modicon family plcs but what we
wanted was an approach that works on a
fully updated PLC and that allows for
hot batching so we don't want the logic
to restart which might cause process
upsets or alarms to go off we don't want
any of that disruption that comes with
the logic download we also want it to be
a little bit hostile to forensic so you
know no project Jacksons that chains and
so on and use an obscure protocol
feature that evades most IDs
and before we can delve into how we did
that you need a little bit of background
about the emoticon internal organization
so the emoticon family of plcs uses
something called the application binary
file format the apx format and that
format is a part of its project files
and that essentially organizes the PLC
memory into different areas and each of
these areas is organized into different
sections and each of these sections
holds a bunch of blocks and these can be
data blocks these can be code blocks
these can be Source blocks whatever and
each of these blocks is linked to an
entry in the relocation table we have an
RTE number that basically describes this
is where the block is located and these
are its attributes and permissions and
so on
and this is what the PLC essentially
loads and how it organizes all of the
project in its memory
so what we found is that there is a
previously unexplored sub-function
within UMass called the CSA request with
function code 0x50 that allows you to
make these virtual pages on the PLC and
you can read and write to them and
schedule them for execution and you can
fill these Pages up with a proprietary
command set that allows you to read
write and copy and so on from these
different blocks so you can directly
manipulate these blocks as they reside
in memory and this is from an attacker
point of view very interesting because
it happens live I don't need to restart
logic I don't change these typical
forensic indicators like the project
checksum and any modifications to
executable blocks don't show up in the
source code when I upload the project
again to my ews
now initially it seems a little bit hard
to exploit because you can't write
directly to these code blocks but we
found another issue which we reported to
Schneider and that essentially meant
that we could write to a data block and
then copy from the data block to an
executable block because that copy
operation did not have the permission
check that the right operation did have
so what we then can do is we can
essentially copy to that code block and
when it executes as part of the regular
logic our malicious payload will execute
and what we did with that is essentially
this our code is executed as part of the
regular scan cycle but we want to get
out of the runtime executive because we
have to deal with Watch Dogs and all
kinds of restrictions so initially
inject a Stager payload and that Stager
payload allows us to move to a different
area of the m340 firmware where we have
arbitrary access to talking to the
backplane device driver the can open
device driver the vxworks socket library
and so on and that allows us to have
this detailed manipulation of the field
devices that are connected to its can
open bus that otherwise would not have
been possible so we can now talk to the
m340 can open API and use these standard
functions that are part of can in
automation where you have different
service data objects that allow you to
get code execution on the field devices
themselves for example to indent code
downloads that allow you to download
application logic or firmware to these
field devices or in some cases just have
arbitrary read and write do the memory
of these field devices to debugger
functionality that's exposed to a
different sdl and we looked through
various can open device manuals and
found that if there was any
authentication for this at all what
typically happened is that you just had
a 32-bit value that was written to a
different SEO and that was typically a
static failure so to prevent engineering
errors rather than security
now the second objective after we have
code execution on the m340 was to
essentially move through the safety
system in our case in our little demo we
had a Allen Bradley guard Logics as the
safety PLC and that had an Ethernet
module that was hooked up to the m340
over a non-routable point-to-point link
so we can just send zip messages to it
we can just download logic we we have a
very restricted interface here so in
order to be able to cross this little
Bridge what we do is we use the vxworks
raw sockets API to send more formed IP
options to this ethernet module in order
to exploit one of the Urgent 11
pre-authentication remote code execution
vulnerabilities
on the um on the ethernet module now on
this ethernet module you have no need
for further privilege escalation because
you're already running in supervisor
mode and there's no task separation
there
now once I am on the ethernet module I'm
no longer bothered by the restrictions
of this point to point link and
everything that's there because it can
talk directly to the backplane device
driver of this ethernet module that
allows me to talk to an Asic which is
called the Apex 2 Asic which is the
backplane Asic for uh for the Logix uh
backplane bus and this is essentially a
sip based bus so now I can send
arbitrary sip messages to the remote
dios to the CPU module and manipulate
any of these tags that might be related
to the safety bypasses so to illustrate
this a little bit more I have a little
video that should start playing great
how to move laterally through OT systems
at level one in order to gain deep
access to nested control systems and
cross-restricted perimeters between
different security zones
the demo setup shown consists of a Wago
750 ethernet coupler offering a limited
Gateway interface to a nested Snyder
m340 plc
the m340 PLC is in turn connected to it
Allen Bradley guard logic safety PLC via
a restricted point-to-point link to its
ethernet module none of these plcs are
conventionally reachable from the
attacker's initial point of access the
attacker starts by exploiting a nucleus
13 vulnerability for remote code
execution on the Wago coupler Gateway
once the implant is in place the
attacker can move beyond the coupler's
restricted interface into the nested
networks behind it
in order to reach the nested Snyder m340
PLC the attacker will instruct the
implant to forward their Snyder UMass
traffic
in addition the attacker will instruct
the implant to sniff Snyder UMass
authentication traffic meanwhile an
unsuspecting engineer authenticates to
the m340 PLC as part of regular
operations
having sniffed the engineer's nonses the
attacker will now reuse them to send
forged but seemingly authenticated UMass
traffic to the nested m340 PLC the
attacker now forges requests containing
the undocumented CSA commands in order
to gain code execution on the PLC itself
without disrupting its logic meanwhile
the engineering workstation cannot tell
that anything's changed as the software
shows everything's still okay granting
the attacker a high degree of stealth
once their implant resides on the m340
PLC the attacker can Now launch
additional exploits on previously
unreachable interfaces such as the
restricted point-to-point link between
the m340 PLC and the guard logic safety
PLC in order to gain full control over
the safety PLC the attacker launches one
of the Urgent 11 exploits from its
implant on the m340 PLC once the
attacker has code execution on the
safety PLC ethernet module they can talk
directly to device drivers offering
access to the PLC backplane and module
peripherals as shown by manipulating the
module's display in wider controller
LEDs similarly the attacker's
unconstrained access to the m340 plc's
internals as shown by manipulating the
CPU modules LEDs allows them granular
access to local and remote field devices
connected to the can bus or backplane
demonstrating how lateral movement at
level 1 grants attackers deep access to
complex control systems
all right so a little bit about
disclosure we coordinated the disclosure
of this with Schneider Electric reported
these issues in April and July of last
year advisories were recently released
their mitigations for now but
remediation plans are forthcoming we
suggested a retrofittable authentication
fix by using the secure remote password
protocol together with hmax to
essentially tie these authenticated
messages to the initial Mutual
authentication session so that that is
something that could be radio fitted on
the protocol luckily
um in conclusion there's likely a lot of
network crawl space that's not on your
radar like at the level one uh there
might still be perimeters that you
haven't looked into to external systems
and even systems that are you know
remotely maintainable so look into that
if a level one device sits between
different segments it needs a perimeter
security profile
um stop treating certain links like
serial links point-to-point links
non-routable links as if they're immune
to all of these issues because they're
not the impact of a compromise is not
limited to the explicit capabilities of
that link or just its first order
connectivity just because I have a
vulnerability in an Ethernet module
doesn't mean the impact is limited to
Communications I might use that as a
Stager to get for example to the um the
actual CPU and with deep access Things
become possible which change potential
impact so you might have been relying on
functional and safety limits within the
field devices that could be bypassed
through an attacker taking this sort of
route
there's a full report with way more
detail than I could go into including
some some mitigation and detection and
forensics advice I urge you to check
that out and if there's any questions I
take them now so move up to the
microphone
question the problem you were talking
about now with attacks coming from L1
would you say it would be even worse if
it's not wired if it's wireless that you
actually expose your L1 L2 stuff over
wired Wireless
yeah definitely
um I've seen some environments where for
example you have wide area scada
networks over something like Tetra or
DMR and there you have your
Communications for level one all in in
the open I mean obviously you have way
other issues uh if that is your case but
yeah that makes it a lot easier to get
already to level one obviously if you
can just jump on there
there's I had a question about the
monitoring piece I know you had
mentioned that it's that's in the report
and I know that there's only a couple
minutes but I was wondering if you could
give any sort of tldr on the monitoring
strategy for for something like that
very briefly
um in the case of this specific attack
chain being able to spot these ride
messages that are part of UMass as well
as certain things like for example
Watchdog failures on top of the PLC if
the attacker's not careful you're going
to trip up the Watchdog with this and
you can monitor that
um and in case of for example the Allen
Bradley guard Logics you have a web page
that shows you what tasks are being run
by vxworks so you could put a monitor
there that says you know I did someone
spawn a malicious task what resources
are being consumed and we mentioned some
of that kind of stuff in the report so
is that modern capability something we
could do with I inspect
yeah so so for example this these these
attacks um and the protocol level
attacks that's definitely something that
I inspect is able to do excellent thank
you
my question is kind of similar to his
about detections and so one of the top
20 secure PLC cutting practices is
monitoring the scan cycle time could you
comment on how this kind of attack would
potentially affect scan cycle time
so initially the if you look at what we
did with the m340 that'll have some
impact on scan cycle time because for a
little bit you're in that particular
task but once you break out and you you
know you schedule a new rtos stock for
your militia task for your malicious
code then I don't think it it affects
that as much anymore so it's for a
little bit but there's other resources
you can monitor uh yeah on the side yeah
thanks so much
hi I'd like to know
um is it possible to implement something
like a SMB signing in this environment
that would have a the ability to block
that replay attack that you did to get
the Authentication
yeah I mean I
hard to retrofit in you know Security on
protocols that were originally insecured
by Design and you know even though this
is broken uh at least the modicon family
took the the the attempt to put
authentication on there which a lot of
level one devices still have to do so
that's good
um and one of the suggestions we
describe in the report is to use the
secure remote password protocol for
initial Mutual authentication derive a
key from that and then use an hmac to
sign all of these messages and tie that
to the initial Mutual authentication and
you could in my opinion retrofit fit
that on the UMass protocol but whether
you know that's going to happen or not
that's that's not up to me but I I think
there's possibilities there yeah
thank you
all right thank you
[Applause]
foreign