foreign
so today what we're going to ultimate
goal of this talk is going to be to
provide you some ideas on how to save
time right and I think all of us can
agree that's something you know we
definitely want to look at is saving
time and how we're going to do that is
looking at
um different things that other
departments have that we can leverage
and utilize over on the security side
last year the woman in ICS conference at
the first um for the S4 conference I met
my co-author Ann and we realized that
although we work in cyber security now
we have decades worth of experience from
engineering quality sourcing and safety
departments and as we were listening to
people talk about the challenges they're
facing in security we would look at each
other and be like well that information
is kind of compiled over here this team
grabs and you know this information is
over here so we wanted to be able to
share that with you guys today
so if we look at what the first step is
in almost every security framework or
set of security requirements were
typically asked to look at and identify
critical systems and assets and so in
I.T security that's you know based
around the CIA Triad right
confidentiality Integrity availability
and typically that's our domain
controllers servers databases you know
key endpoints and then a handful of
devices that are particular to the
business operations but as we start
talking about OT security what happens
is safety comes to the Forefront of that
and then we start having that category
of devices that were critical to the
business
um business purpose that grows greatly
right becomes more complex and involves
more teams so
um as we look at and see what the
different teams have available to us
that we can leverage upon then we can
save time and also identify you know
what is critical because to understand
what's critical and OT is to you know
understand the process the environment
where we can put typical cyber security
controls and in reality where we can't
right so making sure we understand
so the first tool I'm going to talk
about is um typically owned by the
engineering team it's a risk priority
tool and it's you know been around since
the 1940s you know it's one of those
oldie but goodies
and um so that one is typically owned by
the engineering team it's called the
FMEA or failure modes and effects
analysis so what this is um is a tool
that the team will go through and
they'll typically identify failure modes
and look at okay how can these failure
modes
um fail what impact does that have to
the organization how what is the
probability of that occurring and then
how can we detect that so they use those
factors to come up with the risk
priority number rpn number although some
Industries lately are calling that and
relabeling as Industries and companies
like to do action numbers
so they'll do that do that and they'll
create you know a priority list of risk
but where the true value of this comes
in is that it's created by a
collaborative team of subject matter
experts
so yeah that team okay
um so
um and so these subject matter experts
are most likely the people you're
waiting you know for an email back from
or you're you know trying to get to be
involved in your event or um and and you
know if you're doing like a cc
um e-e event you know trying to get them
engaged in that as well
um so they have already come together
and these are painful to create the fmas
right but once they're created they're
very effective
um so hopefully that team has been
bribed you know by lots of great meals
and unlimited caffeine and you know
snacks but what they do is they'll
typically if it's a process FMEA they'll
start with listing out all the steps of
the process there's also product fmas
where you'll start with the bill of
materials with the components the sub
assemblies and then functional fmeas as
well so they look at those and they say
okay how can this fail
and then they'll say how else can it
fail right so they'll go through and do
that but then they also list the
consequences of that failure mode and
that's something that's valuable to us
right because if that's that particular
item has something that has connectivity
and stuff if we can see what the
consequences are if we were to say
create that failure with by you know
stopping a process on the device or
quarantining you know a file on it or
you know isolating the device and we'll
be able to see what that affected that
failure and action would be as well but
they rank that with a severity score
and then they go through and say okay
what are the possible causes so that
would have you know created that failure
and they'll list all those out and then
they go back and rank and say well
what's the probability that that cause
um you know that that would actually
occur
and then they um go through and they say
how can we detect this like what
processes do we have control what
procedures you know what do we have
alarm set that would let us know that
this failure has occurred before we
realize the impact of the failure so
they do that and they calculate what is
the again the risk priority number
and that is all great information in
itself right like to have that you know
we can we can look upon that and see the
impacts that we have we can start asking
the teams to look at in those causes
because right now they're most probably
looking at what I'd consider the you
know children of product liability you
know misuse
um mistakes
acts of convenience you know but not
really the intentional piece right so
maybe intention in the effect of
employee sabotage or competitive
sabotage so being able to ask the teams
to start adding those in as they update
or create new fmeas you know will help
one buy-in right so as you're adding in
and you're saying okay what if the cause
of this failure mode was ransomware
which is the one we're all really
concerned about right so how does that
change that and then that will move that
risk up in that priority list so the
team doesn't stop here though right they
create the priority list and then they
go through and if there is a threshold
that they've set based on their risk
appetite of um we want to hit anything
that's above this threshold they'll go
through and they'll put mitigation plans
in place for that and then put any
actions um make actions to that and then
re-rank all the different scorings so as
you can imagine if you're adding
ransomware into that the occurrence of
that will be high right the severity
will be high detection probably pretty
high so that's going to put that higher
up on their risk so whereas you're
trying to maybe struggle with them to
see the impact that kind of helps get
that buy-in as well
um as we're going through
um and with the fmeas you know how else
can security teams use this you know
they can use it to understand the
process the mitigations and the risks
and what the teams that are currently
supporting it um are struggling with and
what they already have in place you can
use it to build out your risk assessment
so this tools typically meets the
requirements of any standards that ask
for a risk assessment tool so you can
use this and build upon it as opposed to
handing the team a blink slate and
saying please create this you know pay a
new portrait you're asking them to fill
in the blanks and then again building
out playbooks understanding what the
consequences is as you start having them
add in the cyber security aspects into
the fmeas helps you kind of build out
those IR playbooks and then just
providing context right you have your
asset list to your IPS
um your host names you know how how does
this fit into the process and
understanding that piece as well and
again the biggest I think impact it has
is building that relationship with those
teams so you know you're recognizing the
work they've already done and building
upon that as opposing to ask them to
start from scratch I think I see a
couple engineers in the the audience who
are kind of smiling and shaking their
heads on that
um so I've kind of talked about fmas I
personally think their gold you know is
at Value but what if you know if you ask
and they don't have an FMEA so some
Alternatives you can ask for are process
maps and value stream apps these aren't
going to give you the full picture but
they're going to at least give you the
view of that process so you can start to
understand the environment as well
um also as we all know people like to
relabel within companies so just ask for
risk priority you know Matrix and a tool
they use because they might call it
something else and then the sidepock
it's also a document that's going to
have the process and then talks about
the suppliers and inputs and then the
outputs and the consumers for each of
those and that would again give you at
least that Baseline often the sidebox
and the process maps are the first steps
in the FMA that they use to list the um
steps there
so that's talking about kind of a tool
from engineering again to me that's one
of you know the the top ones that um we
can use
um what about safety and quality
so with safety and quality unfortunately
right safety incidents occur and quality
spills happen I mean it's reality
um so these teams typically already have
response plans in place they
unfortunately have either been tested
from necessity or they probably have
some compliance or policy reasons that
they've been tested so again looking at
reviewing those and adding and seeing if
you can modify them to include the Cyber
you know security piece as opposed to
introducing a whole new process I would
definitely recommend that but at a very
minimum I would recommend reviewing
these and we call them sometimes eight
D's or pdca plan do checked act to see
where if you can add in the security
team as part of the communication plan
so again on saving time you know if
there's a safety incident going on we've
shut down something over here instead of
the sock over here like noticing logs
aren't coming in start asking questions
as this team's trying to you know work a
safety thing they're already in part of
that communication plan to know that has
occurred and then you can move on and
also I would have them look at if there
is any safety and quality stuff and
there's after action reports have them
look back at the logs and see it it can
rule out whether there was any cyber
security
impacts that could have affected that or
cause that
so that's what safety and quality
response plans another tool that I
debated whether to put as a FMEA
alternative but I decided to put here
was Hazard analysis this is very similar
to FMEA but whereas fmeas are looking at
outputs to the processes Hazard analysis
sometimes also called JJ's or job Hazard
analysis they're more looking at the
safety and internal right so how it
affects and it protects our the
employees
so these also can be used for CIS review
as well
so with safety and quality again using
Hazard analysis to gain an understanding
I'm adding a security teams to existing
existing response plans maybe
integrating in instead of building out a
new one for security response plans and
then um
making sure that we review any after
action things to see if there's any
cyber impact that might have played a
role into that
so you'll see that I use quality
throughout quality to me you know kind
of throughout the organization kind of
like eventually Security will be
um so the next one we're going to talk
about is quality and sourcing
so one of the things we definitely heard
you know before is you know third party
risk and how you know that plays a big
part into cyber risk so typically the
sourcing teams they're going to have
supplier score cards where they're
already touching base with and ranking
and providing metrics to the customer or
to the vendors with regards to typically
delivery quality metrics and then cost
savings because of course we're always
asking for you know just cost savings
there so this is a good place to go in
especially if you have roll down
requirements you can add those to the
purchase orders but you can also add
those metrics to the supplier scorecards
so that they're part of that already
it's the same touch point with the
vendor you're not confusing them with
additional requests coming from a
different team
um there's also vendor audits typically
the supplier Quality Group will do
um I know being in supplier quality you
know you would go in you'd review look
at the risk sometimes we'd do the fmeas
with them as well
um but these are a great place too to go
through understand as part of the audit
maybe add in the piece of what access to
these vendors have to our systems and do
the audit there is you know is this
still relevant are these still the
people that should have access
so the other piece that sourcing has and
this goes into the Integrity right data
Integrity is vendor documentation so if
you're doing a product review
um you know you can definitely go to the
engineers but you to know exactly what
they purchased
um the the purchasing team is going to
have data sheets and schematics
um there so just it's a good place to be
able to get that information as well
so equality and sourcing you know
understanding the supply chain layout
and by looking at those scorecards you
know how we're evaluating our suppliers
adding to that if there's stuff that we
need to add you know from the security
perspective I'm adding those cyber
metrics and then
um again adding the security team to the
response plans
that communication back I think
um would again hit that Saving Time a
lot and then tracking an auditing vendor
access through supplier quality and
sourcing tools
this last team we're gonna I'm gonna
wrap up and talk about
um is finance and I'll be honest with
you you know this is the one Department
I haven't worked in but it's definitely
the department I always Ally with
um to getting the buy-in I include them
on any of my first trainings like if I'm
pulling out a new initiative or program
they're the first group that I train so
that they understand and they can help
me as a stop Gap as other projects and
programs are coming through if those
that allowed aligned with what my
initiative is there so definitely
utilize them and then they have some
interesting insights they can provide as
well because if we use the concept of
follow the money they can provide
insight into existing assets that might
be out of sight out of mind right so we
always talk about remote locations you
know what's out there well they of
course know what was purchased you know
and what what should be out there
typically they'll have the teams go
through and do an inventory audit every
year so they probably have that list you
know that they're making can people
check only caveat there is if it's an
older subsystem that might have
depreciated so it might fall off that
list but at least you'll get a good
start there they'll also be able to tell
you what's on the Shelf like what have
we bought but not implemented yet you
know what's coming your way and then
also you know just things that are
forgotten about maybe they never got
implemented so they'll be able to tell
you upcoming changes and get the you
know what they've approved and what's
coming your way you know how you can
start preparing for that and again if
they don't align with some of the
initiatives you're having you can kind
of utilize them as a stop Gap as well
and then another area following the
money is looking at where we paid for
calibrations and high value maintenance
right if we're paying for calibration on
a piece of equipment that pretty much
means that the settings and that
equipment are pretty critical to the
business so definitely an area of risk
right for any studying manipulation and
then high value maintenance that if
we're paying high value and it's that's
a piece of equipment that you can't just
easily replace
so you know that's something that we're
going to need to look at and protect
um because obviously you know it's
costing a lot to maintain so those are
two areas that you know they can give
you insights on that you might not
um you know thought of or you know had
before
um so with Finance what can we you know
utilize them for again getting inside
some less valuable based assets some
based on what was purchased and
following the money
um also another thing I look for when
I'm looking at that Finance team in who
to Ally with and you know build that
relationship with I always look for the
person that typically looks like they
work in it you know multiple monitors
multiple you know devices on their desk
um and these are great also because
those those are the people that are
probably testing out any changes to the
Business Systems making sure they don't
impact because you know we have to close
the end of every month
um but also they're great to use those
in Pilot groups you know for your EDR
program for any beta testing or if
you're doing patching and you want to
test that out as well the other thing
they can do is they typically know what
other people roles and systems have
duplicate you know that they've approved
for duplicate assets right so again
being able to understand what other
teams like if there's a key engineer
that had you know they've they've
approved three laptops because you know
they need to make sure they do these
using that second device again in Pilot
groups for EDR or this type of things
you know you can get that a good input
on that of where those duplicate assets
are changes we talked about that I the
other person I'd like to make sure I
know and I'm allied with is whoever's
approving the capital expenditure
expenditures requests or any project
requests as well and again aligning with
them but also getting to understand so
um you know if you come across an old
device right most likely the request has
been submitted at some point to get that
updated or changed and there's usually
an Roi right that's involved in why it
hasn't been or some kind of cost
disparity so they getting that insight
and that understanding as to why that
changes and and what it would take to
make that change get in place
um
so that they'll be able to give you that
and then Roi again associated with
changes
the other piece there is if you have a
component right the the you can get this
from both finance and sourcing but a
component that has a vulnerability on it
and you're all excited because you're
like yes this is coming you know
becoming unavailable we're probably
going to switch this out soon
um there is a thing called Last Time by
and typically the ROI to do the
re-engineering retesting and you know
all that type of stuff to be able to put
the new component in place isn't really
you know cost effective so typically a
last time buy and I've seen it happen
many times
um purchasing will go by you know as
many as they can which could last five
years so whereas you from the security
team are thinking this component's about
to be switched out it's going to fall
off our list you know just realize that
probably isn't the case and there's a
reason for it so they'll be able to
provide that reason and in that case you
have to go look at that alternate
solution and then as I mentioned buy-in
you know including in trainings and
discussion for buy-in on initiatives and
alignment of projects to support those
so in summary these are kind of the
documents that you know I've suggested
that we look at I do recommend you know
obviously these help us and get a good
understanding more quickly right but at
the same time they would let any
malicious actor also get an
understanding so you know please make
sure that these are included you know
you have role best access controls file
sharing controls and they're probably
included on your DLP or data last
program as well
um just pulling it all together as I
mentioned you know looking at the ROI
maybe that that would change something
realizing that you know cyber budgets
and operation budgets are there's a big
disparity there so um maybe that change
hasn't been approved right with the
operations budget but going back through
and as I mentioned speaking the same
language in regards to risk by adding
um the causes of cyber security and to
the FMEA raising that up and then now
bringing the backing you know and the
budget of the security department to
that evaluate that change that might
actually make a difference and be able
to help the operations team and again
another way to align and build that
relationship
so I talked way too fast during that
but um
are there any questions because I went
quick and that means you guys got to
save time and we'll get a break
sure you can go to either of the
microphones here yep thanks very much
for the presentation and I I think it's
awesome to highlight how other other
teams can help the Allies
um there's some movement with the
security Exchange Commission right now
in having more kind of dollar-based risk
assessments and security
and I really like that like Richard
searson's books on like how to measure
anything in risk that kind of gets to
the like the economic part of it for
finance teams
um have you seen them be more
comfortable to like help engage to you
know to look at impact in the context of
like I loved your calibration example
for example you know but like an hour of
loss on this equipment would mean X are
you seeing that more right so again I've
typically gone through and just made
sure I understand how they're
calculating you know
what those changes and how you know how
what the ROI is right what they're
looking at the other thing the finance
team will do it usually has some
interaction with the insurance side of
things right so they've already had to
kind of explain that
um so I do find like if you find the
person that can explain you know like
how those are calculated so that you can
you know like then go back and say okay
and present those numbers to them then I
definitely do see more collaboration and
willingness there did they answer your
question
go ahead Maggie
yeah thank you and great talk thank you
for giving it uh one of the the things
that I really appreciated seeing you
speak on is the FMEA uh component all
this I know as a vendor it's a
conversation that we end up having to
have sometimes where a researcher will
come and say Hey you know we found this
in your product and you know therefore I
could cause you know XYZ to happen and
it's it's really an interesting uh
Dynamic to have to go back to the safety
team and say hey can you pull the fmeas
for this and how do you see us best
maybe raising awareness about that
dynamic in the community I mean it would
be it would be my dream to have
researchers come to us and say you know
hey we think we found this you know can
you pull your FMEA and see if you know
this would have been accounted so I
definitely think again you know these
are things security teams can ask for
but these are also things that you know
on the other side right we can realize
that they don't have the access to so
provide those I know when we would do FM
Mas I always provide them to our
preventive maintenance team and they
would build the PM programs on that I'd
provide them to our technical you know
writers they build the manuals based on
that so just disseminating that
information to those teams so that they
can start you know having that awareness
um you know and then maybe not and
that's kind of the point right instead
of them coming to you with hey we have
you know this is smoking you know we
always joke right you know you let the
smoke out you know it's it's not it's an
acceptable failure mode right we've
already evaluated that the other piece I
didn't mention was some of the safety
testing you know that's out there I was
trying to keep it to the things that
people could easily absorb but you know
safety testing we we do extensive
testing right you know like if it's
smoking that's acceptable like it's if
it catches fire right so so um I think
just providing you know that the overall
what the FMEA gives them acceptable
failure modes as well and the things
that we've you know done to mitigate
does that answer your question awesome
thank you thank you any other questions
well thank you all I appreciate it