foreign
I have good news for you today
there are two kinds of security
decisions
and probably you're only paying
attention to one of them
now why is this good news
this is good news because it means you
have a huge potential for improvement
if you start also paying attention
to making security by Design decisions
now before we start
I would like you to reflect for a moment
on your ICS security priorities for 2023
where are you going to spend your
security dollars on
what others tools and services you're
going to buy
well because unfortunately I can't get
the answers from each of you here today
Sans took care of that a couple of
months ago and they asked approximately
the same question
and here are the top three answers they
got
now if you look at those
what do they have in common
these are all things that help you
to see what you have
to monitor what's wrong to decide what
you do about that that could all be
summarized as security operations
decisions right so these are all things
that help you to defend your systems
and probably a lot of tools that you're
already using also fall into this
category
now I'm not saying security operations
decisions are unimportant to the
contrary I would even say they are so
important they could be called one half
of the yin and yang of security decision
making
but there's another half
and this other half is often neglected
security design decisions
so why security operations decisions are
about defending your system
security design decisions are about
building a system that is defensible in
the first place
and I will spend all this money we have
all these Advanced tools even to the
point of using AI for making informed
security operations decisions
for security design decisions we have
security controls checklists
so
in an ideal word these checklist would
be great right so you could just take
any of the checklist take each of the
lists off
tick off each of the
each of the controls on the checklist
and then you're good
but in reality of course
you have restrictions
your budget is limited your time is
limited not everything is technically
feasible
so you cannot take just every measure on
the list the real challenge is not to
have a big list of security measures
that you should could take but the real
challenge is
to decide which security measures not to
take
compare that to security operations
and real challenge is not to get a
million alerts for everything they could
potentially be relevant the real
challenge is to decide which incidents
not to react to
so this is what tells security control
checklists apart from True security
engineering
it is
security engineering helps you to decide
which security measures you should not
be taking
so you should invest into doing security
engineering
not although
but because you have a limited security
budget
now even if you now understand and you
say okay let's do some security
engineering you probably run into
different problems practical problems
we've been doing research on
security by design for the last two
years and we've got two industry
Partners in years and hemart which is an
asset owner and a control and components
manufacturer for functional safety
components
and
we've asked them why it is so hard for
them to consider security during the
design of the ICS systems
and what they said was
well it's simple
our icis Engineers don't have the time
and they don't have the security
expertise
and probably this applies to your
organization as well and also this is
something that we're not going to change
anytime soon because we won't turn on
ICS Engineers into full-blown Security
Experts and to be honest I'm not sure we
would even want that
so instead what we've done in the last
two years about what I want to share
with you today
is to create simplifiers for security
engineering so a way that enables your
ICS Engineers which have no time and no
security expertise
to make well-informed security design
decisions anyway
and the resulting decisions
should be such that managers with
limited security budgets are still kept
happy
right
so these are the four simplifiers
um and we Dive Right In
the first one is called filters
filters mean you they help you focus on
what's important and what's matters most
and when we asked our industry partners
what's most important or what what we
could do to help them in order to
make security engineering doing the
design of the ICS easier for them
what they said was
tell us what matters
tell us where we need to look at
because the problem is to understand
that need you need to understand that
the ICS Engineering Process even without
security is utterly complex and
interdisciplinary
so ICS Engineers tend to complain that
they're always late to the secure to the
engineering party right when they come
come in for the control system
Engineering in a plant
a lot of decisions have already been
made there was electrical engineering
mechanical engineering maybe functional
safety process engineering you name it
and all these disciplines created a huge
Haystack
of engineering information
and if ICS Engineers are late to the to
the engineering party security Engineers
are like super late so when we come in
the big Haystack of engineering
information that could potentially be
relevant has become even bigger
so to illustrate that I brought a simple
OT network with me today
don't need to understand the details but
if you consider that the problem is what
makes things worse is for security
potentially anything in there could be
relevant because anything could be
subject to an attack or be used by an
attacker
so it could be some remote printer in
the remote corner of your network it
could be some little configuration
detail so what we did is we said okay
we introduced a concept called security
parameters
yes other little wheels that you
see here so security parameters are a
little wheels that you can adjust
somewhere in your systems and every
adjustment has an impact on your
security posture
now these security parameters
make security decisions visible
and explicit
and then can be very different in nature
for example some of them
are clearly security so for
authentication I probably don't have to
tell anyone of you that authentication
is securely related but there are others
for example
the design of a safety shutdown
if that's electronic or mechanical may
not seem security relevant at First
Sight but of course it is because a
mechanical shutdown cannot be hacked
remotely at least not that easily
or not at all
and then there are also
insecure by design features
probably have heard of them so there's
legitimate features that are built into
your ICS
for legitimate reasons but they do have
a security impact anyway
and the third group of security
parameters makes features like that
explicit and visible for example the
fact that you can update your PSE logic
during operations of your systems that
may be needed from a functional
perspective but of course it does have a
security implication
so security parameters really are the
little Wheels in your big Haze deck
of engineering information
they help you focus on the security
decisions that matter
our second filter
it's probably not news to you
it's high consequence events and you may
know that for example from Iron Out CCE
method
it's explained really quickly as the
answer to the question but we'll make a
real good day in your plant
and your engineers are probably good at
answering that one and it's not always
but sometimes functional safety related
so I used to work for a
co-service mind company and a project
and they used to tell us our worst
nightmare is or would be if our call
excavator would fall over
because these things have about the size
of an Eiffel Tower and as you can
imagine no one has a spare Eiffel Tower
somewhere and it's closer so
this would make prime high consequence
event in this case or in our example in
a high consequence event could also be
the explosion of a reactor
you probably get the point but the
important Point here is
the definition of high consequence
events
should absolutely be a management
decision management should decide which
high consequence events Engineers should
focus on in security decision making
because they are the why behind your
security engineering you could imagine
them as kind of your North Stars right
they are shine shine bright and they
keep your engineers on track when making
their security design decisions
they also make security by Design
decision making easier
so let's try this out I just put the
North Star here and you've got the
security parameters all in your network
you see it's easy right
you're not seeing it's easy right
it's because it still isn't there's
still something missing we've got these
very high level high consequence events
up there and then we've got this tiny
little configuration options in the
security parameters and in between
there's a large gap
so we need something to fill that Gap
and that's something as our third filter
and that's functions
now
functions are magical
functions have the power to turn a big
pile of Technology into something
meaningful
they add humans interactions and a
purpose which is important so let's try
and do some magic that's our pile of
Technology we've looked at that before
and that's a function
and a function example for update of PSE
logic so even if you're not knee-deep
into ICS technology and by no means your
knee-deep into the example Network I've
shown here you can probably understand
pretty quickly that one of the things
that Engineers do with that pile of
technology is updating PRC logic and you
can also see how that works and you can
also see who does it
now apply that to our other filters that
we already have used
this was our overwhelming picture from
before
and this is it now
so now what the security design question
boils down to and that is way easier to
answer is the question
which of these security parameters that
you see here you need to adjust
in order to make sure the function that
you see here cannot cause that high
consequence event
so if you go through your entire system
high consequence event by high
consequence event and function by
function your security design decisions
become way less overwhelming
and then there's last one last cool fact
about functions
actually they are the only information
that you need in order to time your
decisions within your ICS Engineering
Process
you don't need any new any fancy new
security by Design workflow the only
thing that you need to know is and your
engineers do know that
when in your ICS Engineering Process do
you decide how updating of POC logic
works
because that's the time when you also
need to decide about the security
parameters attached to that one
so
to wrap things up
our first simplifier was filters
security parameters help you to focus on
decisions that matter
High consequence events help you to
focus on risks that matter
and functions help you to focus on
systems that matter and to help you to
time your security design decisions
within your Engineering Process
well
that may look easy now or at least
easier on my pretty slides but I've
cheated
because
I haven't told you where all these
colorful functions and security
parameters come from
and your security engineers
won't have the time to create them
obviously
so that's why our second simplifier
comes in
which is libraries
in our research we did create libraries
and they make all the difference because
having libraries for functions and
security parameters means your engineers
don't have to make up functions and
security parameters they simply have to
choose them from a library
so for example this is an example I
believe they can browse and say oh for
automatic control this is a function
that we also use and for engineering
this is a function that we also use
and that makes things easier and then
also to every function
the security parameters are attached
now
are there any ICS vendors in the room
here
one and a half
talk about the half one later
because this is where you need to sit up
straight and take notes so in case you
haven't remembered to put out your arm
doesn't matter but take notes now
these functions
and the parameters and the libraries
attached
other solution to one of your major
problems because you probably know the
situations like these here as a router
and use it around a table and you ask
them what do you want security Wise from
all components and the asset owners like
well what do you have what can you offer
that's a deadlock situation
the libraries can help you because they
can help you really efficiently
communicate your security philosophy
because you can imagine functions like
these
can have variance that can be different
depending on the ICS vendor so if you're
ABB for example
and also the security parameters they
can defer for different vendors so if
you're ABB you could say okay see if you
have an ABB system this is how we want
you to be engineering to updating POC
logic this is how it works look at that
function and if you want to do it
securely these are the parameters that
you need to pay attention to and also
these other values that we recommend
sending the parameters to setting the
parameters to
and soon you're going to need to do
something like this anyway because for
Conformity assessments regulation is
just around the corner at least in
Europe with the Cyber resilience Act
so
again here
to wrap things up for the libraries
libraries are really important because
they encapsulate knowledge
and notice that people or your engineers
sometimes will not have
and also they make that knowledge
available for reuse so they don't have
to reinvent the wheel all the time
now our first two simplifiers we're
focusing on how to identify security
design decisions
next
we're going to focus on how to make and
document these decisions
and remember your engineers are no
Security Experts and your managers
probably on your engine engineering
experts and there's one tool that's most
efficient for communicating information
to non-experts and that's diagrams
you've actually seen proof of that
before when you've been looking at the
function diagram
even if you were not knee-deep into the
technology that was behind this this
diagram you could pretty well understand
what was behind the function that I've
shown you
imagine this instead through reading a
text or through an exiled table
trust me we've tried doesn't work at all
so
we'd created four kinds of diagrams that
help your engineers make security design
decisions
by only showing them the information
they need in a certain decision making
step you've already seen two of them
but I want to spend a bit of time at the
security decision diagram down below
because we haven't looked at that one
yet
so let's imagine a few decisions have
been made for them
are here and three have been made that
these are the gray ones on the picture
here
and let's now imagine you want to
understand why they've been made that
way
let's start with that one in the middle
updating logic during operations
remember that was the security insecured
by Design feature
and that has been enabled
strange right because that sounds
detrimental to security
and if you click on it
you can see that you know what it is but
security simply had no say in this it
was a decision made based on a
functional requirement and we have so
many decisions made that way but there
are security relevant anyway so it's
important to know that and to document
it that way
next up
the one on the right Integrity
protection for PRC logic
now this has been set to Hash in our
example
and maybe there are some top 20 PSE
coding practices fans in here so you
know this is a hassle this may not be
technically feasible to implement
at least one fan
and
so you better have a damn good reason to
to require something like that so if you
click on that you can see what your
engineers have done they've said okay
this is a risk-based decision and this
is tied to one of your high consequence
events and luckily for them to one of
the high consequence events that you
deemed important in the first part and
your engineers have even attacked
attached an attack scenario detailing
how this security parameter could be
used in order to cause the directory
explosion and if you've been talking
about earlier
display with the details
last decision
whoa patching
we all know patching an ICS is a
nightmare so there was a decision made
to patch this vulnerability and you're
pretty sure I want to know why because
they better have a pretty good risk for
that one
clicking on that you see no risk
because that's what wasn't a risk-based
decision it was a compliance based
distribution so for example because you
are subject to critical infrastructure
regulation you have to patch full stop
if you look at these three decisions
that we've made in comparison
we can see two things here
first it's tremendously important to be
able to trace decisions to be able to
trace back why you made a certain
decision
it's important
because you have to explain them may
have to explain them to external
Auditors it's important because during
operations you're doing change
management you want to make changes and
you want to make want to know why you
made certain decisions and why you
didn't
and it's vitally important remember what
security engineering is all about not
taking certain security measures so if
you're not taking if you're deciding
against certain security measures
you want to know why and you want to
document why
the second point that you're seeing here
is that there are different legitimate
reasons for making security design
decisions
and risk is only one of them
we as a security bubble tend to
stress that all decisions should be
risk-based
and we see here that this may not always
be accurate
so
I would like to recommend that instead
of
requiring all decisions to be risk-based
we should maybe require that all
decisions are traceable instead
wrapping around the diagram portion
diagrams are important because
they guide your engineers in their
decision making by only showing them the
information relevant in a certain
decision-making step
they are very efficient for
communication of decisions for example
to management
and they are very efficient in
communicating the traceability of
decisions
a reason why decisions are made
so if you want precise
decision making and you want what you
want to have the decisions communicated
precisely you should request diagrams
from your engineers
now if you do if you do request diagrams
you're probably going to get strange
looks saying well
I don't have time for pretty pictures
that's right because I don't have time
for pretty pictures either right I
haven't drawn any of these pictures
myself
it's the 21st century right so we have
four socks for Security operation
centers no one would get to the idea to
put your people in there for making
security operations decisions in front
of a sock without any electronic tool
why do we do that for security
engineering
now I'm not saying
you should get any security engineering
tool or get any electronic tool support
for security engineering just because
but there are three purposes
where they are really important that
they can really make a difference the
first is a single source of Truth
you want to have a single source of
Truth where all your security design
decisions are documented you want to
have a single source of Truth where all
your high consequences and security
parameters the decisions that you made
and why you made them are documented you
want to have a possibility for your
libraries for example the ones that you
vendor provided to exchange them
digitally so you can put them to direct
use
and then the last one don't
underestimate the power of a tool if it
even if it's really simple to guide
Engineers through a workflow that are
not familiar with that's not there
Daily Business
Okay so
you've seen these four simplifiers now
and with that knowledge in mind
I'd like you to come back to this
science study we've looked at the
beginning and I'd like to reveal the
fourth item on the list that's yellow
here
now you can see here look
security design decisions
awesome
but
by Consultants
well
Ivy qualified to comment alert on that
one because I am a consultant myself I
know the pain right
I think twice about that one
because a consultant or any external
party for that matter who doesn't know
your filters who doesn't know your
security parameters who doesn't know
your high consequence events who doesn't
know your functions
can most likely only come up with the
security controls checklist
and you know by now what a waste of time
and money it would be so just try and
tick off any any measure on that
checklist
anyone really everyone
can come up with a large checklist of
security controls that you would need to
take
but only you
can decide which which security measures
you are not going to take
so
instead of this one
consider investing into your own
decision making
consider investing into deciding which
security measures you don't take
it can be done
find your filters
leverage your libraries draw some
diagrams maybe try out some two support
Empower your engineers to do some
serious engine security engineering
and to make these decisions
I know
we in the ICS security Community are a
strange Bunch right some people keep
talking about senders others keep
talking about data diodes and I keep
waiving my giant ball talking about
security engineering
and you know what
I hope that four years from now I don't
have to be that person anymore
because four years from now
doing serious security engineering
professionalizing your security design
decisions
will have become a total no-brainer
just as professionalizing your security
operations decisions already is
so I hope that if you return from S4 get
back into your offices review your
priorities for 2023
you sneak some serious security
Engineering in
thank you
[Applause]