foreign
before I begin just a note that this
presentation represents my personal
experiences and opinions and not
necessarily those of my employer Pastor
present I'm currently employed at Tesla
working on software systems for
renewable energy generation battery
storage electric vehicle charging and
energy Market participation
I'm going to talk today about
webassembly a technology that I think is
just maturing right now to the point
where we should start considering it
seriously in iot as well as ICS
giving us a cleaner separation between
firmware and software allowing us to
iterate faster respond faster and also
do so more securely
so I'm going to begin the presentation
by kind of motivating my interest in
webassembly through some of the problems
I'm facing at the iot edge as well as in
the cloud that'll provide an
introduction to webassembly
then through a motivating example I'll
describe what it would be like to be an
application developer using webassembly
and finally I'll conclude with some
challenges
so let's start by looking at some
challenges in Edge Computing
environments that I think webassembly
can help address
and what I mean about Edge what my
definition of edge Computing I guess I'm
going to talk throughout the
presentation about the edge or the iot
edge really what I mean is software or
firmware controlling Hardware performing
critical functions so I think what I'm
going to talk about here equally applies
to ICS to manufacturing or any kind of
software in critical infrastructure
okay so let's take a look first at what
it takes to get software deployed to an
iot edge device so first you need to
write that software compile it test it
do static analysis
then you need to package it for a
deployment including signing go through
component testing integration testing
you often have procedures for Regulatory
Compliance or customer acceptance
testing and then finally you get to the
stage where you can distribute it to
those iot Edge devices
and the distribution is often phased
around the world in order to monitor it
and protect against regressions and
often in these environments you need to
you need to um
you need to obey some kind of
maintenance schedule that's dictated by
the customer
and some of these Edge iot devices are
air gapped in some of their
functionality so they may be able to
send Telemetry to the cloud but you
can't actually update firmware or or do
control against them so they're they're
actually updated quite infrequently
and what this means is this whole
process can take weeks months or years
to deploy new code to Edge iot devices
and because this process is not executed
very frequently we don't get very good
at it as an industry and because we're
not good at it people sense risk and
they don't want to change
so I think webassembly is an opportunity
perhaps to to iterate more quickly here
but also do so more securely
okay there's three problems I'm facing
in the cloud that I think webassembly
may help address
the first is hosting untrusted code for
me that's usually empirical models that
are developed by other teams that I that
I need to host in my infrastructure so
there are some service providers that
are kind of on The Cutting Edge of
webassembly usage
cloudflare and fastly are both hosting
untrusted code from their customers and
then moving it around their Global
networks to operate closer to their
customers and red panda allows the
opportunity to host uh like data
Transformations and streaming
calculations using webassembly
the second problem that I'm facing in
the cloud
the the relationship between Edge iot
devices and cloud services
to date is a fairly simple one so Edge
iot devices send Telemetry and alerts to
the cloud and they fetch their
configuration and that's about it and
then really rich services for Asset
Management stream data processing
historian capabilities data Lake
security really only exists in the cloud
environment
so in order to build really
sophisticated Services I think we need
to start blurring the distinction
between Edge and cloud and having some
of those sophisticated Services move
closer to the edge there's a few
advantages in doing this There's an
opportunity to save a lot of money
because you can take advantage of this
Edge Computing environment that's
essentially free
The Edge usually has all of the context
that it needs we're in the cloud if you
try and recreate context you often have
to join data streams and when those are
eventually consistent data streams that
can lead to a lot of problems
and then the edge
if you can deliver these services on the
edge The Edge can operate autonomously
even without its connection to the cloud
and you can offer much richer Services
doing this
this problem for me also goes the other
way I want to take code that's running
on the iot edge and run it in the cloud
so that I can say run a state machine
representing you know a digital twin in
the cloud running the same code that's
on the edge or perhaps I want to back
test models like a pricing model against
historical data where the same code is
being used for that back testing and I
see webassembly is starting to blur the
distinction between Edge and Cloud
allowing us to move code from the cloud
to the edge or from the edge back to the
cloud
okay and the third problem that I'm
facing in the cloud that has motivated
my interest in webassembly
so this you know maybe 10 years ago or
so we're managing everything in the
stack all the way from Hardware to the
operating system up into the application
and then we virtualized the hardware
allowing us to run multiple operating
systems on top of it and then came
containers declarative deployments
orchestration and so on and this is
where most companies operating the cloud
are today
and it's a model that works quite well
but there are some problems if we look
inside those containers
so if we look at a container it's
probably pinned to some kind of Docker
image
you've probably installed some root CA
certificates along with some tooling
and then you finally get to the
application binary itself that's
embedded in this container
and let's say that that application has
an HTTP server
which also means it has a library for
parsing Json and serializing Json
perhaps the application also exposes a
grpc endpoint
this application May publish event data
to some kind of message bus like Kafka
so it's going to have a client for doing
that
of course you want to monitor the health
of this application so it's going to
have some kind of library and endpoint
or you can do that
if this application persists state it
may be deployed alongside another
container that has a database in it
which also means you then have a client
for interacting with the database
and once we've laid all of this
Foundation we finally get to the piece
of business logic that we wanted to
write called the application
now this isn't so bad when you have a
handful of applications
but it gets really difficult to manage
when you have hundreds of services like
this and these Services might some of
them might be inherited from from other
teams some of them might include Legacy
code they often have a mix of
programming languages a mix of libraries
and so if there's a security
vulnerability in a certain version of
the HTTP server used by some
applications you know which applications
need to be patched rebuilt redeployed
answering that question can be quite
difficult for most organizations this
was the problem many people faced with
the log for J vulnerability
so this is really a problem of
concordance where we want to provide
consistency but also allow diversity but
still understand what's where and have
teams operate in a decoupled manner
so in order to address this concordance
problem I expect this trend to continue
with more and more application code
moving down into the infrastructure so
what this would look like is say the
HTTP server or that Library that's
parsing Json moving down into the
infrastructure and being managed there
so that it can be consistent and so that
it can be patched without involving
application developers this is very
similar today if you if you operate a
kubernetes cluster you can you can patch
the machines underneath the kubernetes
cluster without involving application
development teams it's really kind of a
continuation of that this was kind of
the promise of server lists and
functions as a service
I don't think it quite got there yet and
we need to move more and more code
that's that's embedded in there down
into the infrastructure
and if you're I don't have time to go
into it here but if you're kind of
intrigued by this model This wasm Cloud
project is really leading the way here
in terms of the the model uh the
functionality and Security in this space
okay so I've kind of motivated why I'm
interested in webassembly at the edge
it's it's this problem of being able to
iterate quickly but also do so securely
and in the cloud hosting untrusted code
having more and more of the application
code moved down into the infrastructure
so that it's more manageable and then
this blurring of Edge and Cloud where I
can move Services between the two
so now that we've done that let's look
at what webassembly is
so webassembly is a portable binary
Intermediate Language that can be
targeted from various programming
languages and execute on different
platforms meaning it's portable in a
virtual machine
webassembly was first released in 2017
and it is supported by all of the
popular web browsers it was originally
developed to enable high performance
applications in the browser so that
meant you could write really efficient
code in C plus rather than in JavaScript
and still executed in the browser
there's also some
kind of famous examples of Legacy code
being ported to the browser like Google
Earth using webassembly now I am not
interested in web development at all
I've never written a line of code of
JavaScript my interest in webassembly
has come in the evolution of webassembly
to now be interesting in Cloud
environments as well as Edge iot
Computing environments
there's a number of systems programming
languages that can Target webassembly so
c c plus c sharp rust go Swift and
python can all can be compiled to
webassembly
and the way the way it works is you you
write code in the programming language
of your choice
you compile that to a webassembly binary
and then you host that webassembly
binary in your application binary and
the web assembly itself executes in a
sandbox
and the host application here is in full
control so it's a deny by default model
where the application has to Grant
access rather than restrict access and
the basic instruction set of webassembly
doesn't allow anything more than pure
functions so just math on memory that's
basically all you can do so that means
that the the web assembly that's running
in that sandbox it can't open ports it
can't read or write files it can't read
or write shared memory the application
can also budget the number of
instructions that the web assembly can
execute or limit the amount of memory
that can be used
and just before I move on there's been a
lot of work that many have done to to
sandbox applications already right like
secure boot app armor profiles c groups
your Docker environment all these kind
of things that remains complementary to
the webassembly sandbox webassembly is
really a Sandbox even further inside the
application that's you know right around
the web assembly itself
so VA is the web assembly execution
engine and sandbox that runs both in
node.js and in Chrome
there have been attempts to move V8 into
other environments although what's
become more popular recently are these
client runtimes that you can use as a
library and this there's been an
explosion of these there's probably
between 10 and 30 of them and there's a
lot of innovation happening here they're
evolving very quickly and I'll show an
example later in the presentation
there's two other things worth
mentioning about webassembly the first
is this webassembly systems interface or
Wazi so with such a limited instruction
set in in basic web assembly this is an
extension where you can do things like
open ports or do file i o I'm not
interested in Wazi at all I'm really
only interested in webassembly for Pure
functions as I'll show later
another thing I am interested in is this
component model so this is the idea of
declarity declaratively composing
webassembly modules in order to make
useful services or applications so an
application may need
um a key value store in order to spare
store state so it would just declare
that and that could be provided in the
infrastructure without the application
developer carrying how it's implemented
I think there's also some wins here
potentially for s-bombs so that we could
develop them around application
capabilities not just around the library
versions that they're using and it would
it would work well with machine
automation
okay changing gears a little bit I want
to demonstrate now through some source
code what it would be like to be an
application developer or service
provider using webassembly and some of
the advantages that come from it
so in order to do that I'm going to use
a motivating example of this point of
sale terminal where it calculates the
the total price for a number of items
displays that to the customer before
accepting payment and the example is a
little bit contrived but I wanted
something that's fairly easy to digest
as as part of this presentation
and I'm going to begin using a kind of
traditional approach to software
development and the programming language
I'm using here is rust
so here's the function that calculates
the price and it's quite simple it just
takes the count of items and multiplies
by the unit price
and then here's how it's used so here
the count and the unit price are
hard-coded but you know in the real
world those would be external inputs it
calls the price function to calculate
the total price
then it puts some restrictions around
nonsensical prices what I'm doing here
is kind of hinting it a firmware code
that would protect against Bad inputs
and this would be code that I would not
be iterating on
and then finally it Returns the price
okay so now that we've kind of laid the
foundation let's take a look at what it
would be like to make a code change
so let's say we want to introduce
off-peak pricing so from 11 at night to
11 in the morning we'll charge a
different price so we go back to the
price function
and we're going to modify it now to
charge the peak price during these hours
and then discount the price by half
outside of those hours
and then we need to pass in now that the
hour of the day into our price function
but otherwise calculating the price is
roughly unchanged
and now in order to deploy this to the
point of sale terminal we need to go
through this long process that could
take weeks months or years for this very
very tiny code change to reach our
customers
now let's take a look at this motivating
example if we were using webassembly
so the first step to use webassembly in
this motivating example is to extract
the price function into a library and
the way we do that is just adding this
no mangle and extern C around the
function and this just allows the the
library to be called from programming
languages other than rust
and once we've done that we compile that
rust code into a webassembly binary
and then we need to load that
webassembly binary into our firmware and
here I'm using the wasm time client
so that that's the webassembly binary
there in a file being loaded
and then we're creating an instance of a
Sandbox in which that webassembly code
will be hosted and executed
and then we're exporting from that
sandbox to price function and this is an
example of how the host application is
in full control of what is exported from
the webassembly module
then finally we need to to call that
webassembly price function so it program
looks pretty much the same as before
just with slightly different calling
conventions around the price function
because it's being executed in that
webassembly sandbox
and a bit easier to compare side by side
this is our program before and after so
we do need to load that web assembly
into the firmware but otherwise the only
difference is really just this slightly
different calling convention
okay now that we're using webassembly
let's take a look at what it would be
like to make a small code change
so in addition to that off-peak pricing
let's also do happy hour pricing between
2 and 5 PM
so we go back to our price function and
we modify it again to return the full
price during a more restricted set of
hours and then discount the price by
half outside of those hours
because we changed the price function we
need to rebuild that webassembly binary
but then when we go look at the firmware
we don't need to make any changes and
this is really the the kind of the key
point of the presentation is that I'm
able to iterate on my price function
and make changes to it without having to
make changes to Firmware and I can do so
safely and securely
that's the point no firmware changes
um okay so this rages raises some
questions how do we distribute that new
code to the that edge iot device now the
web assembly is only about 300 bytes
base64 encoded and it's pretty common
that edge iot devices are are managed
through some kind of desired State
configuration so why not just take
advantage of that so it's not uncommon
to have some kind of Json document
describing the desired state in this
case it might have the the language and
the tax rate and those kind of things
for the point of sale terminal so we can
just include the price function as sine
base64 encoded string in order to
distribute it
and we can take this process that used
to take weeks months or years for a very
small code change to reach our customers
and we can choose to Short Circuit it at
any point and I would make the argument
here that since the price function is a
pure function it can be entirely unit
tested that we could make that code
change repackage it and redeploy it
without going through component testing
integration testing and the rest
okay before I conclude some challenges
and a bit of caution
some people are going to object to
changing run you know code at runtime
the first objection I hear to that is
security but remember here we are using
webassembly so it's running first of all
the webassembly is signed it's running
in a sandbox with a very limited
instruction set and I'm also assuming
that the firmware is already protecting
against Bad input and bad output
the next objection is around
combinatorial testing if so if you can
change code at runtime how are you going
to test all these different combinations
I think this is a problem that already
exists that sometimes gets ignored often
Edge iot devices have a large number of
configuration parameters that change
behavior and you already have a
combinatorial testing problem so it
doesn't really make it any worse
and then the third objection is tracking
version so someone calls your customer
support line how are you even going to
know what kind of code they're running
if it can change again I think this is
really just back to the having a large
number of configuration parameters that
change Behavior you need to be able to
track that well over time and it's just
motivating doing a good job at these
things
okay picking a language can be
challenging
so in systems programming I really don't
think we should be using C or C plus
plus anymore those languages are just
too dangerous so if we're doing new
develop developing you know Greenfield
applications I think we should stay away
from those languages as an industry
python is kind of awkward with
webassembly because it's an interpreted
language The Interpreter itself needs to
go in the web assembly kind of awkward
go is a garbage collected language so
you need to deal with the garbage
collection inside the web assembly I
think the clear winner is is rust for
new development
um you know Russ is a great has really
really great tooling for web assembly
it's also you know functional
programming language has lots of other
benefits
um
if you're moving Legacy code into
webassembly especially if you're hosting
it in different environments it may make
sense to look at these other
applications targeting it but for new
development definitely look at rust of
course there's lots of reasons to use
rust in ICS in iot environments if
you're not familiar with those
motivations I would recommend watching
this talk from this conference from a
couple of years ago
okay picking a runtime is actually quite
challenging
as I mentioned there's these whole
number of client runtimes that you use
as a library the key here you want a
nice development experience for your
developers so nice interfaces good
documentation those kind of things but
really key is that this is what
implements the sandbox so the Integrity
of this approach really comes from the
Integrity of that sandbox
and you know the reason we trust V8 in
the browser is because of the scrutiny
it's had over the years and these
runtimes have not had that level of
scrutiny yet I think the leader here is
wasn't time
wasn't time is written in Rust rather
than C or C plus plus like some of the
other ones and they've also been very
very uh open about their vulnerability
disclosure policy their use of cargo vet
which is a in the rust tool chain for
um for securing their supply chain
limiting the use of insecure or unsafe
rust fuzz testing use of formal methods
and I think if these other run times are
going to remain relevant they're going
to need to follow suit and with this
kind of open approach
okay and the final uh kind of objection
or piece of caution I get is why not
just use Docker to solve this problem or
why not just you know distribute a
binary to the edge
so at this conference last year if you
didn't see the solar winds Sunburst
presentation I highly recommend watching
it very very interesting talk and and
really that's teaching us that you know
even trusted code can be vulnerable so
one of the real advantages with
webassembly is it's a very very limited
instruction set so it limits what you
can do it you can't do much of anything
I think that is reason alone to be
interested in webassembly for solving
these problems but even if even if
that's you know not your cup of tea if
you have to deal with multiple
environments you're going to have to
deal with portability you might end up
with pretty large containers or binaries
you need to deal with that problem when
the sub webassembly binaries are
extremely small they start really
quickly
um
and if you're if you're dealing with um
Docker updates and depending on how you
have your secure boot implemented it can
be really problematic to mix those two
things together so I think in the limit
if you're going to go and address these
problems on your own you're kind of
Reinventing webassembly and all the
problems it's solving so why not
investigate webassembly first I think
probably also doing these things on your
own rather than in a broader Community
you're probably not going to do a better
job
okay summing up
I think webassembly is really
interesting because of its sandboxed
deny by default security model that puts
the host application in full control as
well as its really limited instruction
set
um that's that's an advantage in terms
of its security
it also has portability so I can run the
same code in the cloud on the edge in
the browser in a mobile environment and
it can do all that at near native
execution
webassembly is really interesting in the
cloud in order to take more and more
application code and move it down into
the infrastructure to make that more
manageable easier to patch
and I think it's very very interesting
and blurring the distinction between
Edge and cloud and allowing us to
develop more sophistic sophisticated
applications
okay so this is a bit of a food for
thought presentation I'm not actually
using webassembly like this in any
production environments although I've
been doing a lot of prototyping and
proof of concept work around it lately
so if if you're interested in this
please come talk to me if you think the
idea is crazy please come talk to me
there's links in these two articles on
my blog to about everything I talked
about here today if you want some
references
so you were for Tesla and just wondering
where does webassembly fit within Tesla
or is this a side project
this is definitely a personal
presentation I'm not representing my
work here I mean Tesla clearly operates
a lot of edge iot devices that's what I
work on day to day that's motivating my
interest in webassembly not actually
using it in any of the systems I build
okay thank you
so uh
given given the limitations around Tesla
um what who is going to be the first
mover on these iot Edge use cases or who
is like where where can we see examples
of this being deployed
I would go look at those those run times
so you know wasm time wasmer
wasm Edge go look at the companies that
are using those
um there's wasn't times being used in a
lot of plays that's what's fastly is
using
um and also look at the wasm cloud
project that's very very interesting
um
yeah trying to I'm trying to think of
some examples that are in Edge iot Edge
iot is really yeah really really new
um there I think one of those runtimes
is coming out of IBM and they're the
plot The Edge platform that they
developed
um it I can't say that they're like a
canonical example of success there yet I
would say that this is very very new
very very promising but I wouldn't say
yeah there's not a canonical you know
here we did it
or at least a company being open about
that
I keep wondering if iot Edge is really
really going to be short-lived
as just Cloud adoption you know takes
you know the uptick is significant right
so I mean do you think this is something
that ultimately webassembly would move
us you know more toward the cloud and
just like iot Edge kind of dying off or
any thoughts on the trend around that no
I think the trends actually going the
other way or the iot edge is becoming
more iot when I think iot Edge I'm
really talking critical infrastructure
electric vehicle Chargers virtual power
plants I mean these are critical
infrastructure now those things need to
be able to operate autonomously so you
can you know charge your car without the
cloud so I think it's going the other
way the other thing driving it it's a
You Know Rich services at the edge
operating autonomously is is driving it
towards the edge
the other the other thing is cost the
Cloud's expensive so if you if you can
take advantage of even constrained
Computing environments to run some of
that code it's essentially free and you
can you could deliver even more
sophisticated services at very low cost
so looking at EVs and eventually we're
going to have to report a lot of data
out of them for the life cycle
management of the batteries right uh do
you see this web assembly helping with
that with iot devices you're talking
about any Edge because then it can
quickly pull that data once you get a
charge and tell you what type of charge
it was so you can figure out you know
how that the hard charging and things
yeah well they're commenting too much
about EVS or anything like that uh yeah
it's gonna what is webassembly would
allow us to do there is imagine you
could deliver richer services at the
edge to you know look through data do
anomaly detection those kind of things
and then only report what's of interest
to the cloud versus reporting all of the
data of the cloud which is quite
expensive
the problem there is is really the
iteration cycle so you can report all
the data to the cloud people can iterate
very very quickly with low friction but
if you want to do that at the edge how
are you going to do that if you have
these kind of long firmware release
cycles and with and with people that are
kind of risk adverse they don't want
change because you might have
malfunction so I think that's where
webassembly might allow this better
separation between firmware and software
better interfaces more security better
testability those kind of things so we
can be more sophisticated about running
those things at the edge
thank you
[Applause]