foreign
so the word critical is both clear
and confusing
it is clear because we know it means the
most important
it is confusing because it gives us no
help whatsoever to figure out how to
figure out what's most important
what I want to talk to you about today
is share with you my journey and
experience wrestling with this word
and thinking about defending the
critical infrastructure of the city of
New York
so to go back to before the pandemic
when I first started at the city I was
the director of cyber risk and one of
the ideas we were trying to figure out
is how do you evaluate the loss of a
service what does it mean if a service
is gone
how do you measure that
and we really struggled with this idea
because New York is pretty resilient and
can come back from a lot
so to ask people to imagine that a
service isn't there that you
can't go to a school that you can't get
a permit that the traffic lights aren't
working really stretch people's
imagination and then the pandemic
happens
you didn't have to stretch people's
imaginations
something else happened too
and I think I hope maybe you had this
experience as well
which is at the end of the beginning of
the pandemic when we knew we were in a
pandemic
we started to realize that this affected
everyone
people started to think about groups of
people
for whom if they got sick it was going
to be a real problem doctors nurses
Pilots teachers we knew that if that
group everyone started to realize that
if that group gets sick we are in a
downward spiral in terms of our capacity
to respond to this
that group critical
we all understood that
we still didn't know exactly how we got
there
the other thing that happened is
everyone experienced the pandemic
their experience of it was so local
people got to know their Mayors and
their local public health that's how a
lot of people experience the response
was local there was a wide scale
incident
everyone experienced
I think many of you have probably seen
this before
how many of you have seen this before
okay let me some of you haven't this is
Abraham Maslow's hierarchy of needs and
I'll give you just a few seconds to take
it in
it's pretty intuitive Abraham Maslow is
an American psychologist uh educated in
New York City product of a number of the
institutions
he had a fairly simple idea
there are certain needs that humans need
to address before others that's it and
then he ranked this hierarchy of needs
and this I think again should make
intuitive sense you need food and water
before you think about a job
pandemic tested a lot of this
now I'm presenting this to you not
because we had this really clear idea
we're going to use Maslow's hierarchy of
needs and apply that across the city I'm
giving it to you in Reverse at the end I
was like oh this is Maslow's hierarchy
of needs
and there's some debate about
this hierarchy by the way that it's
culturally specific that it only applies
in Western societies and you can see
that there's a question there but what's
not a question is that there is a
hierarchy
we are sometimes afraid to say that is
more important than that
and some of that can be technical that
depends on that
but otherwise you can't think about
that
other thing until you address this
so I want to tell you a quick story
about my first day at New York City
cyber command
um I was then like I am today under
prepared and overdressed
and I showed up and I was taking the
subway which you know you've been to New
York even once but even if you haven't
you know is the artery
so I was taking the subway I was
thinking about my first day
um I had already been to the government
office building so I had my expectations
managed about what I was walking into
but I was talking to someone on my first
day
and all these ideas were going around in
my mind and and this is a true story
um I'm mildly embarrassed but I have no
shame so it does not matter and and so I
got there and I was like wow the subway
like how do we think about cyber defense
of the subway
the person said we don't I was like what
do you mean and they were like the
subway is governed by the MTA which is
part of the state
that's not something that we the city
necessarily have purview over and they
went about their day and I stood there
be like uh oh
what do you mean like how does that work
I'll come back to that later
so we start to think about back to the
loss of services we started to think
about
different lenses that we could use to
prioritize
what would a New Yorker notice first
what would they make the biggest deal
out of
so if the power went out no immediately
right you know immediately
if you are on the subway or in an
elevator and that stopped working yes
you would notice immediately
and you wouldn't have many Alternatives
we think about contingency
there's immediacy visibility contingency
and then
let's say the trash stopped getting
picked up
would you notice immediately
nope
and they'd do their best esny New York's
strongest
you might not notice immediately but
when you notice
it would have a huge impact
how do we trade off against these
this brought to a larger question whoops
uh how does the city plan for outages
now I'm not going to spend too much time
talking about that here because that's a
whole separate talk that someone else
can and should give around Disaster
Response Emergency Management within the
city
the key point is that they had planned
to a certain extent for the idea of
responding to an outage
that response mechanism was there but
again the prioritization up front
there wasn't Clarity there surely wasn't
consensus and I tried to push and say
okay well this one is more important and
there was a rough tearing when it came
down to it we really needed to know so
now I want to talk to you about what are
the challenges that I faced in trying to
do this
uh and I'm talking now to people who are
maybe going to try and do this
or want to try and do this
or have tried and can maybe are stuck on
one of these
so the first was again just the the
foremost there's a consensus around the
criticality but no agreement on the
definition when I asked and I did many
people as I could
in the city
you know DHS has these 16 critical
infrastructure sectors how do those map
to the city where do those line up
what
I I don't we think about it this way
that's interesting that that's there no
one was dismissive of it per se
that's interesting that that's there but
this is how we think about it
so then I started to look at others
Canada Australia for other ideas and
there isn't even consensus there now I'm
not proposing that there be something
Universal but there needs to be
something Central if not similar
and I started to scratch on this a
little bit that cities share a lot more
in many ways than countries
the other key component is that services
are not delivered through sectors
that will either be patently obvious to
you or brand new
and it was both to me
working in the city and when I would
talk to my colleagues at agencies and
they would think about what they did as
part of their agency Mission and the
service that they provided that's how
they and when I worked there we thought
about what we do
but if you ask someone
in the city of New York what's your
experience with the chemical sector
right it doesn't really line up and even
the water sector they might know the
agency they wouldn't know much more than
that
I'll give you one example and and I the
example I'm going to give you all of
this comes from collective learning from
talking to other people so colleagues
who work in cyber defense in healthcare
and Hospital Systems particularly
I I asked as many people as I could
across the different sectors that were
represented in the city which sectors
line up with you and who do you depend
on those kinds of questions
but okay so tell me about Healthcare and
Public Health well the first thing you
need to know that it's not just
Healthcare and Public Health in a
hospital
a hospital includes and now going to 16
critical infrastructure sectors
Healthcare and Public Health
transportation
nuclear
chemical
commercial facilities
five sectors at least are subsumed in
that one
you can say okay well I see there's
complexity and across those but it's not
the right lens it was unhelpful
the kind of work that we were trying to
do
which involve prioritization and also
and you know this and appreciate this
communication I need to influence other
groups to focus on that so if I said
okay there's 16 sectors and these are
the five and now I'm talking numerators
and denominators what's 5 16 I don't
know like not not helpful not helpful
for for our purpose
then we had to come to an agreement
about
what was relatively important that
required some assumptions
and I'll talk about how we tested some
of those assumptions through scenarios
and incidents
did use Sis's
National critical functions how many of
you have seen the set National critical
functions a few nerds probably raised
their hand hello hello fellow nerds
55.
you thought 16 was Lot 15 is a lot but
there is an overarching logic there's
four big areas they line up under
connect distribute manage and Supply
they're things like manage Wastewater
Supply electricity connect electricity
provide law enforcement protect
sensitive information so it's much more
about the how it's getting closer to
services but it's not quite there
and this and I'll talk a little bit more
about this later the the sector-based
approach
really sets up blind spots
around interdependencies cascading
failure and other ideas it's not that
people don't think about them it just
doesn't naturally happen
so these are the challenges we had
coming in
what I proffer to you is that services
in this lens are a more effective way to
think about prioritization
the other challenge that I found
was that sectors vary widely
on maturity the type of OT that they use
the regulatory pressures that are there
the size the big players the number of
players the supply chain
but when we start to think about it
through services
they were more comparative they weren't
the same it didn't normalize everything
but it did give us something that was
comparative because of services Drew
from different sectors
so
that started to started to enable us to
more effectively allocate resources
and talk about it in a clear consistent
way
I say started because still started
one of the things we needed to do was
Define
to test some of our assumptions and
understanding of what's critical is
do our own version of what does it look
like when it's under duress under attack
and so we did some scenarios
where we looked at
incidents focused on critical
infrastructure and we had a grid it's a
two by two you can picture in your head
single vector
multi-vector
single sector multi-sector how many went
through each of those
so single Vector say yes cyber
multi-vector cyber and climate event
cyber and terrorism
uh we had ercot and Texas and Colonial
pipeline those two things happened they
didn't happen at the same time doesn't
require stretch and Imagination to
imagine them lining up
and then we looked at single sector
one of the things that became clear is
that wonderfully people are focused on
their institution their entity and then
the benchmarks the other entities around
it
and the sector writ large
so I can only speak in my experience
what it was in New York but those
sectors were pretty robust they were
lined up next to each other they're in
the same room they have those great
relationships but as soon as it flipped
over to another sector we don't talk to
them I don't know who to talk to
why would we
you know the answer
because you share the same operational
attack folks like if there's a problem
and it happens there you're going to be
in the same boat and we're not going to
know until we're all experiencing it
this is the thing that kept me up at
night it's also the thing that got me up
in the morning but New York is a city
that never sleeps so it's fine
and we so we've set that threshold of
okay it occurs simultaneously in
multiple sectors you know we did this
sort of incident and we saw where there
were gaps and it was really that
multi-sector that we wanted to focus on
so
just laying out I'll call it a framework
but it's really a an overlay of thinking
about
these four categories of Services Public
Safety and Emergency Services Public
Health and Welfare Community Services
Financial stability and economic health
now if you're familiar with the
conventional definition the DHS
definition at least of critical
infrastructure this sounds really
similar and in some ways it is but
there's a city lens on here
that I want to unpack with you
so we took all this agencies all the
city services and we looked at how the
city thinks about them and we map those
to the critical infrastructure sectors
and the national critical functions and
came up with
this lens of Service delivery and we're
going to look at this and go yeah
and I hope that's the case you look at
this and recognize that it doesn't look
strange
so first category Life Safety
unequivocally There's issues of life and
death
and back to Maslow's hierarchy of needs
that's going to be our first and
foremost
and it's it's not just because you need
to address that first it's because
that's what people think about first
if you try and put something ahead of
that you'll run into this confusion I
ran into that a lot
if we didn't overtly say yes this is how
we're dealing with public health or yes
this is how we're dealing with
sanitation someone say but what about
so there's a real need to prioritize
that in our communication so Emergency
Management law enforcement those ones
you know are clear Public Health
sanitation Water and Wastewater I know
you know these from the work that you do
but the services that are being provided
and how agencies line up
I believe
that if you started to if one started to
use this lens and talk to someone who
worked in a municipality they'd
recognize yes I know the agency does
that
I know where that fits for us
the second category is a really
interesting one it's very broad now
there are going to be some issues of
life and death in this category
but in all of these this is something
where a city is the provider there is no
alternative
there's no alternative to the Department
of homeless services to the fire
department
this annotation
there's no one else who's going to do
that
anyone who has that charge that mission
that responsibility that duty of care
and that's something that a long time
colleague of mine really introduced he
said
you know I think and he had been with
City for a long time he said you know
when you're we think about in the city
you're under the care of the city
stewards of that that's where the second
category comes in education elections
yes Healthcare
shelters Corrections and Technology
and shelters get to issues around Public
Health Corrections gets to issue of Life
Safety
but these are things that you know are
harder to put a frame around and then
the last is boring and yet so important
processing and management tax collection
fees payments payroll permits there's
two reasons that's really important one
the money collector from that funds all
the other stuff
and two pays the people that do all that
other stuff
payroll processing crucial
crucial
think back to the hierarchy of needs
right
like how am I going to get paid
so the other part is let me go back to
this for a second these are all things
that a city of New York but a city
municipality provides
public sector
it rests crucially
on other sectors that are
almost entirely private sector
telecommunications data electric and
power cargo when I talked to the folks
that work on those services and I said
what do you most need what are you most
going to need in a time of cyber crisis
or what do you want to make sure is
going to be steady and stable they
pointed to these great we have agreement
on those now what
we need those for our critical services
but they're not in our purview of
control this is where the partnership
aspect came in
but really identifying those
dependencies and calling that out
to me there is no
way to defend critical infrastructure
but collectively
I don't know how else to think about it
the other thing that came up for me and
this is a brief aside but I want to put
it in here is
you know the frame lots of times as
utilities so water and electricity but
the more I started to talk to people
the more I realize that data is also a
utility
has the same issues around jurisdiction
around generation distribution
transmission
doesn't really matter how it's used in
one sense in one sense it does matter we
think a lot about how the data is used
but in the other it's just about getting
the data there Cloud providers that kind
of framing came in there
the other thing that came up to me here
was concentration risk I would talk to
each of the sectors and some of the
different organizations and say who do
you most depend on
and everybody
named you know this one provider that I
was like right okay besides that I said
oh for our backup or whatever yeah we
depend here I talk to them
and what I realized is that a lot of
those organizations were dependent
on this one party
that no one was really paying attention
there's a concentration risk
what Dale was talking about earlier it
was known
it was there
people knew it you just need to draw the
pathway to it so this lens of services
and then sectors so I'm not saying a
shoe sectors it's just putting that
service lens first is really helpful
okay so I want to share some resources
here that were really helpful for me
that I hope are helpful for you
especially if you're trying to undertake
this journey in 2015 and 2016 MIT did a
series of workshops where they looked
specifically about sector dependency
and to no one's surprised they found
electricity at the core of it okay they
also found some other key dependencies
and how do we build those in so I
encourage you to look at the results of
that
another is an exercise from West Point
the Army called Jack voltaic those was
specifically focused on multi-sector
incidents and
municipalities now you might think oh
isn't that what you were looking for
yeah we built a lot of work on top of
that we also needed to customize it and
adjust but it was really great to have
that lens and build on top of that and
it's continued
uh the national critical functions I
talked about where they could be complex
or a little bit challenging but they are
also really close lens to how we are
providing what we're providing that's
critical and I I took those and sort of
mapped and lined them up and made my own
version of them and shared that back
with the folks at sisa and they were
very open to that great it's great for
us to see how people are using this set
and the last is the analysis and
resiliency center now they're focused
primarily on the financial sector
but they think a lot about systemic risk
this was a hard thing not just to think
about but to communicate about remember
those cascading failures and
interdependency
it can get kind of overwhelming think
back to Maslow's hierarchy of needs if
you say yeah what if this hits this it's
that people go no I'm just thinking
about this first I need to think about
this first
and so it helped put that scale in there
a few limitations caveat mtor here
um
Metropolitan right not all cities and
counties I think people say state and
local travel territories sltt it's all
encompassing no it's not uh the density
in population not just of New York but
of those metropolitan areas some of
these challenges around distribution of
services and application of those
Services really does vary widely we will
make different decisions on shelters and
education other things based on density
and population so that's a very
important factor governance I talked
about the subway so transportation in
the city of New York there's the
Department of Transportation the Port
Authority of New York and New Jersey and
the State Department of Transportation
and the MTA
if you ever fly into New York those
three airports that's controlled by the
Port Authority of New York and New
Jersey the Port Authority of New York
and New Jersey is co-governed by the
state of New York and the state of New
Jersey
what
so if we have a challenge in
transportation
how do we do this there is no answer but
together collectively
um I will underline again the point
about tax Taxation and Revenue
generation uh because you know different
cities set this up in different ways
there's different taxation but that was
a really important factor when we talked
about prioritization and then I will
just underline again this is just me
my experience
just the city of New York and it is
unique but it is not peerless
so back to this
I encourage you to think differently
I invite you to think differently about
scale and scope severity of that impact
the number of people how long it will
last when they will notice
not to lose the human side and the last
is some of the applications here I
talked a little bit about the
prioritization but what it allowed us to
do is more effectively allocate those
resources to think about Mutual Aid and
assistance in a time of cyber crisis
where would we get that support from who
would provide it who should we all go to
First
and did the resourcing line up there
answer no didn't and hasn't and then
most important in my mind
is as a communication tool
so I invite you to challenge this to
test it to try it talk to me about it
but I think we all can agree that one of
the biggest challenges
in security operational technology ICS
is around communication
coming back to this word and the power
of that one word
I hope you have a bit better
understanding of what that word means
how to think about it thank you
I have some time for questions
yes
go ahead yeah thanks very much for the
presentation I I did have a question so
given your adventure of dealing with a
lot of different stakeholders
um do you have any like Pro tips to
share in terms of
trying to bring people to like a common
understanding just even even the
language right yeah so interested in you
sharing about that yeah a few things the
first is
um I started with the least mature
sectors I didn't go to the most mature
sectors those mature sectors are used to
people coming to them and saying hey how
can you help what do you think
I started with the least mature sectors
that's number one number two I asked
everybody who do you most depend on
who do you need to be strong for you to
be strong that did two things one it
started to give me a short list of that
central element
and two it started to get them to think
about dependencies third parties other
things like that other questions I asked
them
um and I was with the government at the
time so I said
what are you not getting that you need
because I assume that if someone needs
something they're getting it what are
you not getting that you need
from us
there are two questions in there what
are you not getting that you need okay
and then from us
and then there was just general
consensus like do you have a clear way
in your sector of you to wait the way
you define criticality no would you be
open to that what is needed where is the
you know how do you influence that
thinking all of that I hope that answers
your question a bit
um I got another question in the app
that I'll answer real quick has this
been tested or tabletop no and I would
love it
I would love it uh we got to the point
where if you're familiar with the
tri-sector it's three sectors that have
come together
um we said here try your operational
exercise and incident response under
under this
let's let's see if this lens works
because you said you're working across
sector so let's try it through this lens
other questions
you just shout them out yeah
uh Finance electricity
Telecommunications
just gonna say I I love this
presentation and I think it's one of the
the very valuable ones that I wish that
this I know that the room was packed
that I mean even more so with people I
think what you're really talking about
and it's more of a comment than a
question but I will ask
a preview in a second
science I I do believe that we we've
we've aired in some ways and that yes
there needed to be an intense
concentration on Cyber because we're so
weak on capability but at the same time
we've lost some of the basics that
emergency managers
no no to be true 100 when I'm looking at
your presentation I'm like man this also
directly drives with continuity of
government Mission essential functions
versus business essential functions like
payroll delegations of authority who
actually has the power during an event
to make decisions if other people become
ill or otherwise income hesitated to
make the decision this all just ties in
so well and I just want to thank you
because I think that you're one of the
few thought leaders that is making these
connections between cyber and Emergency
Management and quite frankly it just
makes so much sense I I just I think
it's part of an Awakening so thank you
thank you Megan I appreciate that
um I will say I've built on some of the
work that that Megan's done so the the
feeling is mutual and it really is
um why are we rebuilding a thing that
already exists right the that capacity
that capability even the language
um it we shouldn't have to duplicate
that yeah question
one of the constraints I didn't see on
the slide but I'm sure is in your mind
and everyone's mind is resources right
it's not infinite right yeah so did you
ever have to tackle with how you uh
allocate resources so not only are the
most critical underlying things uh you
know more resilient but also you don't
lose the things that they are underlying
for right yeah if you you know secure
all the Power Systems but no hospitals
can work then what does it matter that
you've got the power so how have you
have you had to deal with that challenge
and if so have you do you have a way of
thinking about making sure you not only
um
strengthen the backbone but also the
things that require that backbone for
operation yeah that's a good question it
ties to a bit what Megan was talking
about one of the reasons and it wasn't
intentional but it worked out this way
and it was fantastic one of the reasons
we use critical infrastructure is
because there wasn't a question about
we're going to defend that that needs to
work
um so if we need to figure out how we're
gonna work with emerging Emergency
Management we know we got to figure it
out for this to your question about
resourcing and resource independency we
got into it a bit when we looked at
Mutual Aid and assistance how are we
going to support because I asked people
if you are having a bad day
who are you willing to support
if you are having a bad day who are you
willing to support that helped get to
that critical dependency and The crucial
paths there because yeah the
Telecommunications folks were like we
need the roads to be cleared and yes of
course we need power we need water for
cooling hospitals are like we can't do
it without 48 Hours of fresh water and
you can't just have water lying around
you have to truck it in right so these
all these interdependencies started to
to show up so I think it was really
highlighting those interdependencies
that was helpful that's all my time
thank you so much
foreign