[Music]
hi everyone
welcome to spotting the storm attack
detection in the cloud
um this is a repeat or an expansion of
um some talks i've done at a couple of
other conferences
and we've been working on cloud attack
detection for a while
it's a pretty interesting topic so
hopefully um you'll come away with some
useful knowledge you can take either
back into work or back into your own
um exploration and interest so
um what are we going to be talking about
today first up
um on-premises versus cloud detection
and i'm actually going to expand that a
little uh for this session into
um on premises versus cloud security in
general there's a fair bit to think
about there
um what attacker activity in the cloud
actually looks like
and that's still an area of open
research that a lot of people are
looking at
um so there's a fair bit to talk about
there and then bringing devops to
detection and we'll get into exactly
what that means later on
uh but as we've moved to the cloud in
the security space
uh catching up with the engineering
teams actually there's an awful lot of
lessons to learn there i think
and so we're going to dig into some of
that as well
but before we go much further um who am
i why am i sitting here talking
um i'm a senior security consultant
f-secure
um i'm the global cloud security lead i
run the the team globally
um that helps our clients out securing
their cloud estates
and we work with everything from small
startups right the way up to
some of the world's largest financial
organizations
and most of the work i do focuses in on
three areas really
attack detection hence the the talk here
and cloud security at scale and what i
mean by that is
um not just single projects or single
cloud accounts
but when we're looking at an enormous
estate full of loads of different
workloads how do we manage that
and the answer to that is security
automation so that the third area is
around
and dev secops and security automation
building security
into your development processes and
making it easy to scale that out as you
you have to these days and those themes
will come up quite a bit during the talk
and they all fit together quite nicely
and that's that's where i spend most of
my time
so first up on-premises versus the cloud
and
what what are the differences here one
of the key things we need to think about
there's actually quite a lot to to get
your head around and it's always
interesting talking to other security
people about this who perhaps aren't
quite as familiar with the cloud
and because from the pen testers or
security consultants perspective
people doing offensive security uh you
often hear the whole kind of there is no
cloud it's just someone else's computer
uh all of these kinds of things and one
of my bosses likes to wind me up with
that quite a lot
but actually uh this is a bit of a lie
really there's an awful lot to the cloud
and it changes a lot of things
fundamentally at the end of the day is
obviously still just a computer and a
data center somewhere
a network's still a network a lot of
these things work the way they used to
but there are a lot of changes that it
brings and that are really important to
how all this works
and from a detection perspective and one
of the things that we often see
with cloud migrations with our clients
is that
they migrate their existing detection
technologies into the cloud
so perhaps they've got i don't know um
silence
cyber reason one of these uh endpoint
detection and response products
they'll probably put that in any virtual
machines they're running they might look
to migrate some of their legacy
uh intrusion prevention systems things
like that into the cloud as well
um but it misses a lot of the point
really um and actually you will end up
missing a lot of attacks if that is all
that you do
and it's also really common to see
security operation centers try and
translate their
existing knowledge of what an attack
looks like uh into the cloud without
really doing any research or any
personal development and building cloud
skills in the team
and so we'll get on to on to that in a
while as well um
there's quite a lot more to it than
simply picking up your existing
detection stack
and putting it up in the cloud
fundamentally quite a lot has changed
actually when we moved to the cloud
you've no doubt heard of things like
kubernetes for instance
um aws lander or azure functions
and as we take on more of these cloud
native technologies as people refer to
them
um the further away we get really from
what we're used to dealing with
especially once you're looking at sort
of managed kubernetes clusters or
serverless functions like lambda we have
very little access to the underlying
operating systems if we have any at all
um our traditional detection products
edr
and syslog all these kinds of things may
not
function in these environments we may
not be able to use them um
it's really common to see a lot of uh
existing detection tooling that socks
uses having no support whatsoever for
any of this
um networking becomes a really
interesting one as well
from a on-premises perspective we know
how networks operate we can put in
network taps wherever we want
we can run snort bro whatever your
intrusion detection system of choices
and we have a fairly solid understanding
of how things work even at a really low
level
when we're looking at um layer one layer
two protocols things like art for
instance
um all of that goes away with the cloud
anything below the ip layer
just disappears completely because the
cloud providers have built their own
custom software-defined networks
uh that operate these things right so
arp spoofing to intercept traffic for
instance just doesn't work in the cloud
because there is no art to spoof
at least not at a level that you can
interact with and when you start looking
at
platform as a service things and so by
that we mean
managed databases and serverless
functions
things like s3 manage storage um we
don't have any network logging for that
at all
because we don't have any direct access
to those systems they're managed by the
cloud provider on our behalf
and so we lose all of that visibility we
have to get that visibility from
different log sources instead
and equally from an application
vulnerability perspective
there's a couple of really key things
that change when you move to the cloud
and server side request forgery
especially in aws is a really big
problem
because of what's known as the instance
metadata service if you've got
ssrf in an application and the right
defenses haven't been enabled in the
cloud
then actually you can often use that to
gather cloud credentials to then
authenticate yourself into aws and start
doing all kinds of nasty things from
there
um equally environment variable reading
if you get to a point where you can read
environment variables
inside a lambda function you can get
credentials that way too
um so actually there's a fair bit that's
shifted
and even when we look outside of the
cloud itself directly
uh devops you know this approach now of
um small deployments rapidly
cross-functional teams where you've got
the sysadmins and the
um developers working alongside each
other and
it produces a new model and a new
paradigm for doing these kinds of
um or building out a new software
development lifecycle sorry i should say
and what that brings with it is rapid
deployments usually
um netflix say they deploy hundreds or
thousands of times a day
into production amazon's safe for aws
there's new code in production
every 11.7 seconds on average um
so not only does that break all of our
old um
sort of penetration testing and
assurance techniques it also makes a lot
of things really difficult
for uh detection and response right
um even if you're not deploying
thousands of times a day
if you've got teams who are doing devops
properly they're probably still
deploying
i don't know somewhere between sort of
10 20 30 times a day maybe
um and so both from an attacker's
perspective persisting in that
environment
is quite hard in the traditional sense
you can't just drop interpreter
and have a shell because it will
probably go away quite quickly
if you're running a lambda functions for
instance each individual lambda function
typically only lives for about 10-15
minutes before it's killed
if there's no further requests coming in
for it so that persistence is quite
short-lived
what tends to happen is attackers move
into the control plane i'll get onto
what we mean by that in a second
and equally as i said before a lot of
your tooling probably doesn't work
uh with a lot of these new technologies
but actually
if you're doing these rapid deployment
cycles one of the most common things you
see is what they call
blue-green deployments where you you
bring new versions online and as you do
that you bring the old ones offline
and switch the dns records over to point
to the new ones once they're all there
um so systems might disappear long
before you realize there's been a breach
so how do you do a traditional sort of
forensics and incident response
on systems that don't exist anymore and
the answer to that is you have to gather
lots and lots of logs from outside of
them so that
what happens in an individual lambda
function or a container
matters less because you can infer
what's happened from from all the other
data you've gathered
and and to put some of what we're going
to talk about as we go through this into
context
um you see the traditional sort of a
attack um pyramid with script kiddies at
the bottom and nation states right the
way up the top somewhere
um i don't like to think of it like that
and the reason for that is
that um you can have very
specific individuals who are very
capable things like the phineas fisher
breaches at nasa are a great example
one very motivated individual um coming
up with some some relatively novel zero
days to break into nasa's network um
so instead i think about it this way we
have automated scanning and exploitation
at the bottom
think sort of spamming um meta sport
exploits or sql map against lots and
lots of sites
and then the next one up you have
opportunistic exploitation which is
where
there's some publicly available tooling
maybe and it needs a little bit more
human input but
people are essentially hunting around to
see what they can find and if there's
something there then they'll
they'll have a go at it and then at the
targeted attack level we're talking
sort of either oh days or bespoke
human-led
um exploitation attempts um
it's being driven and targeted by
humans it's probably more persistent you
know if they don't get in the first try
they're likely to try more often
and and when we're talking about that
from a detection perspective
and the automated scanning and
exploitation funnily enough you can
mostly detect in an automated fashion
quite frequently and that sort of
opportunistic exploitation piece there
and if you've got a security operation
center with a team of people who know
how to run it
they've got some decent detections and a
decent technology stack
and some processes as to how to deal
with whatever comes around that will
catch an awful lot of that
um you know so long as you keep up to
date with what's happening in the
industry
and what new uh techniques and things
are coming out then actually your
existing processes and things can can
handle that for the most part
and then at the top when we get into
that targeted attack space
we're talking more about proactive
threat hunting and investigations being
performed by
quite skilled individuals who really
know what they're doing and you know
human investigation
deliberately designed to catch things
the automated detections
and uh the standard run books and
processes won't
um and so the further up
that pyramid you get the greater the
attacker sophistication and likely the
the motivation and the persistence to
try and get in
is going to be but also the investment
required to defeat those attacks gets
higher the further up we go
now most this talks going to be aimed
more at um that bid in between
opportunistic exploitation and targeted
attack so the top end of opportunistic
and the bottom end are targeted
and because that to me is where it gets
interesting and where a lot of
organizations
stand a chance of having the resources
to do something about it um
so that's where i tend to work
so then when we dig into actually what
detection looks like um obviously
there's
people processes and technology involved
and when we're talking about
the technology side of things um
telemetry or log data or whatever you
want to call it is the
the key thing we need to gather enough
information that we can spot attacks
when they're
so sorry uh in the on-premises world we
have
typically three things that really are
the important
data together you have endpoint
telemetry so this is what's happening on
a user's laptop or on a server
and we're talking about endpoint
detection response syslog windows event
log these kinds of data sources
network telemetry what traffic is
traversing your network from where to
where
what does that look like an application
telemetry is
i'm going to include things like active
directory in there but also any
applications you're running
whatever data you can get out of those
in the cloud
you still have all of those to some
degree exactly what that looks like
varies depending on your cloud provider
and what services you're using obviously
most providers have
a very wide range of different services
that you can select from
but the the key thing really that is
more important in the cloud than
any of those really is what we've taken
calling control plane telemetry
so when i say control plane what i mean
is the apis that you interact with
to create and delete resources deploy
virtual machines reconfigure things
and you know when you're clicking around
in the aws console or the azure portal
and this is what you're interacting with
you're interacting with the control
plane
and each provider offers a log source
tied to that control plane
that you can get information out about
who did what where and when
and that really is the important thing
in the cloud if you've only got one data
source to work within the cloud
make it your control plane
but not only do we have that new
technology to grapple with
we also know roughly what attacks on
premises look like everyone's got
windows networks attackers have been
targeting them in
similar ways for a very long time now
new techniques come out all the time
but broadly speaking people are doing
the same kinds of stuff we're still
working out for the cloud really what
does an attacker do in aws
we have some good ideas you got things
like the capital one breach which
uh you know is a bit of a running joke
in security conference talks these days
because
everyone who talks about aws talks about
capital one the poor guys
but it gives us an idea as to what
happens and there's a few others that we
can we can reference as well
but broadly speaking the available
knowledge on what that looks like is
much thinner
i'll get on to how we deal with that um
a bit later on
that's then compounded by the fact that
actually when we look at
an enterprise and what they're doing in
the cloud they're probably not just
using aws or just using azure
i think every client i've ever worked
with says they're in
aws or they're in azure and you talk to
the engineers and someone at the back of
the room will stick their hand up and
say oh well
actually there's a little bit of this
other cloud provider living over there
uh the usual culprit for that is google
cloud because everyone likes their
kubernetes
but it's really common to see companies
working with at least two if not all
three of the big cloud providers
you then expand that with github for
your source code
with docker hub that you're pulling your
images down from
some manage continuous integration and
deployment your office 365
your slack your twitter your managed
services like mongodb for instance
mongodb atlas
you can pay them to run your databases
you end up with a
huge breadth of technology all of which
has its own types of log sources
its own things that an attacker is
likely to try and do with it so actually
covering all that is really hard and
prioritizing effectively
and is one of the critical things to
getting cloud detection right
and in terms of what we even look for
and
what logs do we look at and what do we
look for in them and
the closer you get to the software end
of the server the software is a service
end of things so
office 365 and slack these kinds of
things
the less information we have um and the
the more there is to think about in many
ways
and so at the infrastructure as a
service end of things this is running
virtual machines and networks in the
cloud
um ec2 for instance in aws uh
here we can still deploy our endpoint
detection and response products that we
used on premises
and we can get our vpc flow logs and
you've got the
control plane level logs cloud trail for
aws we've got some ideas to what to look
for there
platform as a service and there is still
some
some fairly uh open information about
what to look for there
what logs we can get and for aws um
you've got object level data events um
or lambda execution logs or various
service specific things which i'll get
onto again in a moment
um we have an idea as to what that
looked like less so than
the infrastructure as a service because
we're moving further away from
on-premises
but there's still some ideas there when
it comes to software as a service and
you're looking at your github logs or
circle ci or office 365 or
and we have a little bit of an idea but
we're mostly working it out as we go
along with our clients
and i think that's probably true for a
lot of organizations
the log sources themselves are
documented but what an attacker is
likely to do and what that looks like
and tends to be something that we have
to work out
and for each new software as a service
product as it comes along
and you then have to tweak that for each
client that's using it
there's also then a mindset shift to
deal with we're no longer thinking about
uh
exploits you know eternal blue doesn't
really have a cloud equivalent
it's rare that we find um remote code
execution at the control plane layer in
the cloud
and and we also then don't really have
a an obvious equivalent so things like
mimikats it's hard to
signature known bad cloud activity
because
most activity in the cloud 1995 of it
uh when you're looking at the control
plane layer is all about
using the aws or the azure provided
features to interact with things
so i make requests to the aws api to
backdoor a user or to change the network
configurations that i can get some
data exfiltrated i'm doing all of that
with legitimate functionality provided
by the
the cloud providers just in a way that
the user of the cloud didn't intend
so we can't just kind of rely on known
bad as we used to
it becomes more about what is
known good in an environment and
therefore what is likely to not be known
good
um and we that we might be able to infer
from and so context really is key here
so let's say we've got a user account
running in aws
and i am user and some new access keys
get generated for it
if that change was made by our
continuous integration deployment system
the way we usually make changes
then that's probably fine but equally if
that change was made by an
administrative user who's logged in from
an unusual location
let's say china for the sake of argument
that's probably not good
and we need to investigate that the
change buying of itself
or the action isn't obviously malicious
or not malicious
but we can infer from how it was done
whether or not it's likely to be
something that we need to investigate
so when it comes to all this log data
what do we need
how do we do it sensibly um you know
there's an awful lot to think about here
so i'm going to summarize at least at a
high level
um some key things to think about for
you and so first off
centralize everything you know as i say
most companies
operate with multiple cloud providers a
bunch of different software as a service
platforms
and the key thing here isn't necessarily
to dump everything into the
single pane of glass as well as the
industry buzzword goes
um but to make it so that the analysts
who are working on this data
are easily able to pivot between one
data source and another
and be able to cross-reference things
that happen because it's quite common
for instance for you to see
changes made into a set of source code
being deployed into the cloud um and
you might want to be able to follow
those logs all the way through from your
source code management system
to your ci cd and into the cloud or in
the case of solarwinds
um they had a breach that got to the
point where an attacker had the saml
signing certificates
which is how you certify who you are and
when you're using saml single sign-on
um they were able to sign their own
requests with those and authenticate
into the cloud
but you can then detect that that's
happened by looking at your
authentication logs
in active directory or whatever you're
using as your saml provider
and correlate that with successful
authentications into the cloud
and if someone hasn't authenticated to
the identity provider before they turn
up into the cloud
then you can detect that exploitation
has been done there by looking at those
two log sources
so being able to pivot back and forth is
really important
now data sources i've mentioned a few
already um the two key ones we're going
to talk about
are control plane audit logs um i
mentioned those already we'll go into
detail again in a second and
service specific logs there's a whole
bunch of other ones you can get
and cloud native detection services like
aws guard duty
and usually worth looking into turn them
on um
get the data out of them it's probably
not going to catch anything too
sophisticated though
and then the rest are log sources you'll
have seen equivalence of on-premises so
um your network flow logs your syslogs
out of your your virtual machines
uh all of these kinds of things have uh
equivalence on premise
that people are mostly used to working
with so control plane audit logs
you've got cloudtrail in aws audit log
in azure and gcp
kubernetes clusters also have an audit
log too well worth looking at that as
well
um and the key thing here why you should
have these and why i say these are the
most important log source to have
are that they are the key data source
for any activity in your cloud
that's happening at the administrative
layer where things are being created
destroyed modified
and this is what that log will give you
and i say they log almost every control
plane level event because over time
we've found various cases where
the providers have forgotten to to log a
specific api call or something
but they're fairly few and far between
and in many ways this gives you far
better visibility into your cloud than
we've ever had in on-premises networks
because you can deploy these for
instance cloud trail across an entire
aws organization at once
um and that's a level of visibility
that's pretty much unheard of on
premises
you always get a few systems that get
missed so this is
really awesome for me um and you can do
an awful lot just with that one data
source
then when i say service specific
telemetry this is things like um
who's using what cryptographic
encryption keys out of your key
management system
who's invoking what lambda functions
where and when who's accessing what
files in s3
you know if you've got a public s3
bucket by accident
this is the data source that will give
you uh those logs and that will tell you
who accessed what in your s3 buckets
and the thing here though is you can't
really just turn them on
everywhere all the time and you tend to
drown yourselves in logs doing that and
a lot of the time
the data you're getting won't be that
useful so what we typically recommend is
that you look at
what each type of service is doing for
you
or in the case of s3 for instance what
each individual bucket is doing
what data stored in it um and from there
dig into and investigate exactly
what the value in that data for you is
if you've got an s3 bucket that's full
of people's
uh bank statements for instance that's
probably worth having the service
specific logs turned on for
so that you can see who is reading what
logs
sorry what um statements out of it when
on the other hand if all it's doing
is serving uh static files javascript
images and things for your websites you
probably don't care about
read events because they're going to
happen all the time and that's
legitimate
what you probably do care about though
is keeping track of who's writing to it
and so that you can spot website
defacements and people trying like major
cart style
uh attacks where you're intercepting um
modifying the javascript rather to
intercept uh credit card details
um so you probably care about read event
sorry you probably care about right
events but you don't care about read
events
have a think about these individually
based on what your environment should do
now i've said a few times that we don't
really know what attacks in the cloud
look like
um and so a lot of this boils down to
the fact that the threat intel for cloud
right now isn't great you could argue
that the threat intel from premises
isn't great either
and but we know a lot less about what
attackers do in the cloud
than we do as to what they do on
premises and the best example of that
um you know to bring out another
stereotype from cloud detection
conference talks
uh the mitra attack framework if you're
not familiar with it um
it's a public framework for defining
attacking techniques ttps
tying them to threat groups all of these
kinds of things it's sort of a de facto
industry standard
for tracking uh who's doing what from an
attacker's perspective
and and to give you an idea of what
things look like
in terms of how much knowledge we have
of this the one on the left there
is the windows attack framework
um i can't remember how many techniques
there are there but you can see there's
quite a few
and you then you've got the cloud on the
right and as you can see there's a lot
less
and to mitre's credit uh they're putting
an awful lot of work into the cloud
they're working with all their partners
to get as much
into the the cloud version of the attack
framework as they can
but the data's just not there to work
with we don't really know a lot about
what attackers are doing
so what we have to do instead is work
out what an attacker is likely to do
in your environment so how do we
do that in my case i do an awful lot of
offensive security testing in the cloud
so i look at what i do to clients
environments how we break in
um and i use that to inform what an
attacker is likely to try
we can then mix that up with whatever we
can get out of mitre and out of
the um publicly available threat
intelligence to come up with something
that's
um reasonable to base our our detection
and our
uh our use cases on so
um the four key vectors i think that we
commonly see
uh exploited uh once you get past sort
of someone leaving their s3 bucket
out in the open um our identity
management
pivoting in from other environments and
the source code management continuous
delivery piece
and application vulnerabilities i'm
going to leave application
vulnerabilities to one side
um there's plenty of conference talks
talking about that already
and so we'll focus in on the other three
first off when i say
identity management exploitation what do
i actually mean so this is where an
attack has stolen some valid credentials
of some sort
either through access keys being posted
to github is the uh the really famous
one here for aws
and but also stolen credentials of some
sort through a breach or
fishing or whatever else um
the verizon 2020 data breach
investigation report
um suggests that about 70 or 80 of the
cases that they see
involving the cloud have some sort of
credential theft or identity management
exploitation involved
um so source code repositories
are really critical for this people hard
code secrets into their source code all
the time
um and occasionally they end up on
github but even if not if an attacker
gets a foothold on your on-premises
network
they're probably going to try digging
through your source code repositories to
find credentials for
for getting up into the cloud and and so
that's what i mean really by pivoting in
from other environments too
this is where we're talking about an
attacker phishing their way in
to an on-premises network and then
perhaps compromising active directory
getting domain admin and moving up into
the cloud from there or stealing
credentials from the internal network
and using that to jump into the cloud
we have also seen attackers start in the
cloud and move on premises
or start in one section of a company's
cloud estate
and use that to or leverage that access
to to break into another one
so there's a variety of different ways
that can happen
but pivoting and lateral movement
between environments like that is
becoming more and more common
especially that phishing on-premises
network and then moving into the cloud
now and source code and continuous
delivery what i mean by this
is that if we have source code
repositories
and deployment pipelines that are
building our cloud as is really common
these days
and we'll see things like terraform
deploying the cloud
and you know infrastructure is code that
defines what your cloud looks like
you deploy it automatically when you
make changes and that's great from an
operational perspective
because it reduces the the risk of
someone misclicking something and making
a mistake when they're deploying
but it also means that as an attacker if
i can get access to
your pipelines and manipulate what's
moving through it or i can change the
source code that defines what your cloud
looks like
then i have control over your your
production cloud environments
without ever actually having to touch
that particular aws account or azure
state
and so we've not seen a huge amount of
this done so far there have been a
couple of examples
and but i expect that we're going to see
more and more of this over time
as attackers get savvy to this and as a
lot of the more
basic attack vectors and start being
closed off as people become more aware
of them
and the defenses get better
so having talked through the three major
attack vectors into the cloud um how do
you then actually adapt
all of this to your environments how do
you know what to look for
[Music]
where do you start really um and so the
key thing here is to do it on an
environment by environment basis if
you're working for a large organization
with a lot of different workloads in the
cloud
pick a couple of the most important ones
as a starting point if you're working
for a smaller organization you've only
got perhaps
a software as a service product you're
monitoring or something a bit smaller
and then this is probably something you
only have to do once but
the overall process is the same and you
threat model a given environment or a
given workload
um and you work out how an attacker is
likely to to go for it
and you can use a combination of the
techniques in mitra attack and also
the usual sort of threat modelling if i
put my attacker hat on here
what is an attacker likely to try work
out what those attack parts look like
um and then prioritize those based on
what you think an attacker is most
likely to try
and also what's most likely to succeed
you know you know your environments you
know what's going to be weakest
this all works best really if you
involve the developers as well bring the
developers and your assist admins into
these conversations
and the knowledge they have is is
generally really invaluable
you can then prioritize those um as i
say
um then look at the exact individual
ttps
um work out what of those you can easily
detect which of those might be a bit
harder
and you know for instance anything
happening on the network on an
on-premise network is generally harder
than things happening on
the endpoint to spot um likewise there
will be some things that are easier to
pick out of the the background noise
than others so prioritize your
your individual detection cases based on
that next up
make sure that the telemetry is actually
turned on if you know you need your
control plane audit logs
are they making their way into your
scene can you actually access them
you know that that's the next important
thing to do um
then actually write your detection cases
um you know
write the the use cases that specify
what the scene should alert on or what
you should be
triggering on and what people should be
looking for um
then execute those individual attacker
actions
simulate what you expect an attacker to
do and make sure that the right alerts
go off or the right notifications come
through or
that the right data is available in the
right place for your analysts to react
to it in the right way
and in terms of where to start
on a prioritization perspective where do
we
first pick out as our first use cases i
generally recommend starting as close to
the objective as you can
because while obviously the attack is
closest to getting what they want at
that stage
actually it's also usually the the
highest fidelity the the lowest rate of
force positives
and so then there's also
a few key things that attackers likely
try and do and that you can also
signature on perhaps more easily than
you you can other things
and this is things like um attempts to
modify or change your
um detection tooling your log sources
things like an attacker trying to turn
off cloud trail is usually really loud
cloud trial doesn't change very often
once it's set up and so that's a nice
easy thing to monitor on
look for highly privileged activity
where people are trying to
grant new permissions or especially
unusual permissions
to im users or to roles in aws or to
particular entities in azure id um
people trying to turn off guard duty
again in aws that's that's usually
pretty obvious
um keep an eye on things that don't
happen very often and that you know have
a significant impact on the security of
the
the environment that's usually the best
place to start
now i mentioned earlier about bringing
devops to detection um
what i mean by that is learning from all
of our engineers who started working in
the cloud
in the it's always better to treat
things as code than to do things
manually
and so if you start defining your
detections as code it makes
knowledge sharing within your team
easier it makes it easier to pass rule
sets back and forth between partner
organizations
um you know if you're working with an
industry group
where you share threat intelligence
you're better off sharing that as
codified rules than you are as
individual sort of iocs like i don't
know hashes or
ip addresses what have you if you can
share the actual rules then then it's
even easier right
um one of the the key drivers we've seen
on that or the key projects in that area
is sigma uh by florian roth which is a
set of same agnostic rules he's got a
seam agnostic
definition format and then a compiler
that generates splunk rules
or q radar rules or as your sentinel
rules or whatever else it is that you're
using
from that set of agnostic rules so you
can write rules and easily trade them
back and forth between organizations
without digging too far into the
minutiae of how your individual
and scene works um makes it easier to
transfer these rules around
um another interesting one in this space
is jupiter notebooks
and so these were a data science tool
originally but it allows you to embed
python code in a document essentially in
a in a browser
um and so you can generate tables graphs
all kinds of things
off it but it's also just generally a
useful prototyping tool we've seen
people pass
um threat hunting uh ideas around those
jupiter notebooks for different people
to try
and spectrop's put some good stuff
together on that so worth checking that
blog post out
and the sort of the the granddaddy of
posts uh or conference talks on this is
an idea
was by john lambert from microsoft and
back at t2 in 2019
um on what he calls the githubification
of infosec
and well worth watching that and having
a read of his blog post i'd say
so um we took that idea we built an open
source tool around it
um and so what we have is leonidas which
is an automated attack simulation
framework
that also defines the detection rules
that allows you to catch
these individual attacker actions and we
link the whole thing back to mitre
attack
because that's what most socks like to
do these days um and the framework will
automatically generate based on a
yaml-based configuration file
and the serverless function that we run
in aws to actually trigger these
these test cases the sigma detection
rules based on
what this uh this particular ttp
generates
and some nice pretty documentation for
you to use to share the info around
um and it's all built in a way that's
designed to make it as easy as possible
for an analyst who doesn't really know
that much about the cloud yet uh to get
stuck in and get working with it quickly
and share these things around with the
team so that everyone can take advantage
of it
um so what is it and how does it
actually work um
[Music]
you have a set of analysts in your in
your sock and you define a new ttp
in a yaml-based rule format and you
check that into
a source code repository that lives in
the cloud and this is all built
out automatically with uh with
infrastructure's code for you and
and that then generates a lambda
function that lives in the cloud
with your ttps in and so you can just
hit these individual
web endpoints with the parameters that
you're interested in um
in order to trigger these test cases you
don't have to know
the exact aws cli incantations or
anything like that
and there's just web endpoints that you
can hit to execute these test cases
and so then generally what happens is
you go along you execute the attacks by
chaining a few of these ttps together
um and those logs get shipped into the
seam and you can verify whether your
uh your rule sets that you've built work
as expected um
by triggering these these attacks
through this web api as i say
so i mentioned the the definition format
what does that actually look like
um this is an example for enumerating
cloud trails your control plane audit
logs in aws
and you can see there we've just got a
single line of code that calls the aws
apis
leonidas itself behind the scenes
handles most of the the details around
exactly how that's
executed passing in all of the the right
um credentials or roles or whatever
other information we need to make that
happen
and the analysts only got to write a
line or two of code generally um
so that then is compiled as i say into
the the web api
and once you check it into the the repo
you got deployed
the detection cases then are also
written in a sigma-ish type format
but we can then generate sigma rules off
this with a single command from the to
the framework
um and so you can define alongside your
actual attacker ttps exactly how to
detect them
which makes it nice and easy to look at
what's happening when an attacker does
it
and then what that looks like in the
logs makes it nice and easy to compare
those which helps people understand them
better
and we can generate some nice pretty
documentation off the back of it
so in practice um why is this useful
um we can really use it to do continuous
testing
so you've seen things perhaps like mitre
caldera which allows you to simulate
individual attacker actions on an
automated basis across a corporate
network
and atomic red team's a similar thing if
you've seen that um
and so now instead of being locked down
to purely our on-premises estate
and we can actually simulate attack
chains that go
uh you know perhaps phishing land on
premise pivot up into the cloud pivot
back down again
and you know we can really simulate a
broad range of things now because we've
got that cloud integration
and we can simulate these whenever we
feel like it for very low effort
instead of having to run an entire
manual purple team which often consumes
a lot of man hours you know we can do
those less frequently to look for
particular new and interesting things
that require a more human level of
attacking to actually happen and test
the base level of
test cases the base level of detections
using
leonidas automatically and you know with
a just by running a script or with a few
button clicks
and then if you really want to get into
the weeds and we're talking a little bit
more about this
rsa next week and you can also use it
as part of your continuous integration
process
so you write some rules you deploy them
out to your scene
and as part of that we automatically
trigger leonidas against a test
environment
and essentially diff the leonidas logs
it produces some nice logs that tell you
what tests were run when
with what parameters you compare that to
what's turned up in your scene and what
alerts have been triggered
and what use cases have fired off and we
can then verify that
as you've improved your use cases a that
your improvements do what they're
supposed to
and b that in the process you've not
accidentally broken something
and one of the really powerful uses for
this in a slightly cynical way
is to take that data and that
improvement that you track over time
and take that up to your management team
and say look we're doing really well
give us more budget give us more
investment
uh you know we'll keep doing even better
it gives you that
hard data to show that you are working
in a positive fashion you're improving
and that you're helping the business out
which can be quite hard to do
in a sock depending on how things are
being measured
so and just to wrap things up and to
conclude um
detection really is a journey and you
don't start
finish in a couple of months with some
detections call it quits
and especially in the cloud new services
are coming out all the time
your environments change a lot faster
than on-premises because of how easy it
is to
to make improvements to make changes
from an engineering perspective so your
development teams tend to move faster
and so there's this constant cycle of
identifying new threats and risks as
new techniques come out and as your
environments change designing new use
cases
according to what you just identified
simulating those threats
seeing if your use cases trigger and you
know and verifying all of that in a in a
continuing cycle
um the easiest way to do that by far is
having all of this defined as code
so that you can track changes over time
uh you can share it more easily both
internally and with your partners um
and it just makes everything run much
more smoothly frankly
um and if you are doing this in aws at
least at the moment and give leonidas a
try it's up on our github
um and at the moment it's aws only we've
got
azure gcp on the roadmap i've been
saying that for a while but hopefully um
that shouldn't be too much longer
and we've got quite a few test cases in
there already um you know we're building
them out all the time
as we write new ones ourselves to use
both within f-secure
and with our clients um so it's up on
github like i say give it a try
um and feel free to ping me if you've
got any questions about that i'm always
happy to help
with that thank you for listening um i
think we might have some questions
potentially
yes we do thank you nick so right into
the questions
how often cloud provider is included in
dfr
ir process and do they perhaps have
additional
data they can provide for those purposes
with or without
warrant okay so
i understand that as um how do the
providers themselves
get involved in dfir when when incidents
happen
um and how can you take advantage of
that i think the
the question for that is the answer to
that rather is that it varies an awful
lot
and depends on the provider and some are
more willing to help than others
it also depends on your level of
agreement that you've got within the
support contracts you have
um generally it's in the providers
interests to help out
and if you've got a good level of
support contract with them they'll often
let you have access to their own
internal dfir specialists for the cloud
um but this is very much a case of
uh you know god helps those who help
themselves
if you don't have the right things
turned on yourself
and you don't have a bit of a process in
place for responding to incidents in the
cloud and for detecting that
and then the providers are going to be
able to do less for you
than if you were fairly well established
you had all your logs you had a good
process
uh set in place to uh get get that ball
rolling and to react to it
um you know so build these out
yourselves
it's worth talking to your account
managers at your cloud providers while
you're doing that
because they'll either be able to get
you some help internally as to to best
practices and how to do that
and they'll also be able to tell you how
best to engage them when you need to
and so talk to your your account reps on
that one i think
and they'll be able to provide more
tailored advice than i can on my
experience
okay so we can move to the next question
is identity is security so it's one of
the issues of things
in that cloud security how or
can organizations maximize their
identity
security posture uh what do you think
so that's a very broad question and i
could do an entire conference talk just
on that
um but some of the highlights i think um
one of the things that we often see
organizations fall down on when we're
talking about the cloud in particular
is they join their on-premises active
directory straight into the cloud
without necessarily assessing or
hardening their active directory first
um if you've got an organization who's
been around for a long time they've made
some acquisitions
their active directory might be a little
bit of a mess um
and so by far the easiest way to break
into the cloud in many cases is by
targeting the legacy on-premises active
directory estate
and using whatever link that is into the
cloud be it active directory federated
services
or maybe it's tied directly into azure
id whatever that is
and that's often a route that we take
that we exploit when we're doing
penetration testing
um so harden your active directory if
you're using that to authenticate to the
cloud
otherwise multi-factor authentication is
critical
get that turned on everywhere and where
you have
conditional access policies in azure id
make good use of them make it so that
people can
only authenticate from within your
corporate network or from
your corporate vpn or corporate devices
or
there's a number of features that you
can enable there to restrict where an
attack and connect them from
and that makes their life a lot harder
so turn all that on too i would
um takes a little bit of work often
because you've got to work out what you
can realistically do there
in your business context what you can
get away with and what's going to upset
people
but that's well worth looking at too i
think
okay so the next one we still have time
one way access to cloud resources uh
cloud accounts uh things like gh actions
uh is monetized is by mining
crypto this is probably a noisy thing
and alerting the legitimate owner quite
quickly
what might be the rough ratio with the
attack regarding
doing that kind of quick crap and runs
versus move covered long-term attacks
for example espionage and i twist my
tongue there
now i think i think we i get where we're
coming from at least um
so that's uh an interesting one and the
reason it's interesting is because
i don't think we have data to say for
the more sophisticated attacks
there's a little bit of a um a circular
sort of chicken and egg problem really
with cloud detection that
a lot of people base their detections on
what's in the attack framework
the attack framework only includes
techniques that we have threat
intelligence to show
happens and so if no one's looking for
them you don't get the threat
intelligence which means it doesn't make
its way into the mitre attack
and so a lot of people aren't looking
for it um
that said the broad majority of the
the cloud breaches that i see these days
are people doing stupid stuff
it's s3 buckets being left open or
elastic search databases
um it's credentials being stolen bitcoin
mining being done
um it's all these kinds of things and
you'd think that it would be nice and
easy to spot
people bitcoin mining um it actually
often takes people longer than you'd
expect
um one of my favorites is the the amount
of times i've seen people detect
crypto mining not by monitoring their
cloud trail logs in aws or their
um their actual telemetry sources uh but
by the finance department phoning up the
engineering team and saying you know why
is our cloud build 15 times as big as it
was last month
um so that's a little bit depressing aws
are getting better and i'm sure as urine
and google cloud are too i'm just less
familiar
at spotting that as it's happening and
they do that two ways
uh three ways actually aws guard duty
monitors for connections to known crypto
mining pool addresses
and so it alert based on that aws
themselves
keep a bit of an eye on how much compute
resource you're using
and if it looks like you're suddenly
using way more than you usually do
they might come for a chat about that um
and the
third approach is the most common way
that people do
bitcoin mining related breaches is by
stealing access keys off public github
repos as they're published
and aws themselves now monitor the
public
commit feed for github to look for
access keys that have been committed
and they revoke them as soon as they
spot them
and because the average time to
uh compromise on that between keys
hitting github
and attackers starting to cryptomine is
about
20 or 30 seconds these days because they
have automated deployment systems and
things
so aws monitor that feed and they revoke
keys and email you to say they have done
as soon as they see them hit the wild
and between all of that the situation is
getting better but i think there's
probably still more to be done
okay i think that was the last question
and
we can go for a break and then continue
with the next talk
thank you so much nick and it was
pleasure to have you here
well thank you for having me enjoy your
evening everyone