[Music]
hello everybody
i am tommy devos i go by the hacker
alias
doggie g and um i'm here
to give a talk uh titled hunted
uh wanted black cat to celebrated black
uh white hat
and uh this talk is going to be about uh
my journey from starting out as a black
hat hacker in the 90s
going through my life and all of the
things that happened as a result of that
and
to where i am now um basically yeah so
um i guess let's see this says
um yeah i live in richmond virginia um
it's in the u.s
um i'm currently a senior security
engineer
for a company based in new york city
called breeze
and i do bug bounties for a bunch of
different companies throughout the world
mainly verizon media various portions of
the us government
and military and things like that
all right let's see um so the beginning
um i started getting on computers for
the first time when i was
probably around 10 years old or so uh
that's when
um the my stepfather at the time
he brought home the first computer i
don't remember what kind it was but it
was one where
all of the games and stuff we had to
play were on those big floppy disks and
there was no internet connections or
anything like that
um but as soon as i started playing on
the computer the first time i just
absolutely fell in love with everything
about it um
i played around on games like wheel of
fortune and some baseball games and
stuff like that
uh while i had that computer and
i was introduced to the internet a
couple of years later
my little cousin his dad brought home a
computer and one of my cousin's
other cousins uh was a game developer
and
he knew how to get things on the
internet and all of that stuff
so um once my
uncle told him that he had just bought a
new computer and stuff
he came over one weekend and showed them
how to
get a dial up our first dial up was with
uh minespring i believe it was which was
a
guy life isp here in the us
during the 90s and um back then when you
got dial-ups and stuff like that they
would send you a little floppy disk
to uh install things and the floppy
disks that came with it happened to have
a program called
mirc on it and at the time i had
absolutely no idea what it was
but uh the person helping us set up the
computer knew what it was because he had
spent some time on irc
so he helped us get everything set up
and um
i was introduced to the f-net network
um f-net is an irc network that is still
around today
um it's the first network that i ever
started hanging out on
and um that's where basically everything
started for me when it comes to
packing uh computers and in general
um i started out on f net just
like any other young teenage boy looking
to talk to
people and talk to females and stuff
like that i
ended up spending a good
year or so on irc um just exploring
learning the different chat rooms and
everything and um
i got introduced to something called an
xdcc
bot which was a bot that would run on an
irc server
and you could download files from it it
could host
anything from um software which we
called wares at the time because it
would most likely be cracked software
um you could download uh pictures
um songs um like waves in the wave
format
and everything um when i first
got introduced to the xdcc bots it was
uh
really intriguing to me i really like
the idea that
you had a piece of software running on
another computer
that um was able to
always stay online and interact with
other people and
things like that i downloaded my own
software to
try to run my own xdcc bot but because
of being on a dial up
whenever i would disconnect from the
internet it would disconnect as well
um i started questioning people in
the the main wares channels and stuff
like that trying to figure out
how they got their compute their bots to
stay online all the time
and that was the first time i was
introduced to the word shell
uh shell is was referring to
an account on a remote system like a
remote linux or unix system
that you could use to run any type of
software that you wanted
a lot of the companies that offered you
shell accounts on their systems
would place limitations and stuff on
what you are allowed to use
their cisco score naturally um there
were others there were some
of course that they didn't care what you
ran on it as long as you paid
the appropriate monthly amount for
whatever the show
was back then they would charge you
based on
the number of background processes that
you would be running from within your
account
and your disk space so for like five
megabits
of disk space and um one or two
background processes that you were
allowed to run
you would look at maybe spending five to
ten dollars a month
um when i first started it ended up
getting a lot cheaper
later on because there were a lot more
companies
that were being set up to provide
services like this
um i didn't have i was too young to
really have money or have the ability to
pay people online to be able to buy
these shell accounts because i didn't
have a credit card
so i started um
trying to figure out ways to get my own
shell accounts
um while trying to do this i would join
various channels on f
net pound shell pound shells
shelves with a z and um just any other
kind of chat room where i thought there
would be
uh hackers and stuff like that to be
able to
get information about these shows um i
ended up joining the wrong chat room i
guess you could call it uh one day by
mistake
and it was a chat room that was run by a
gay guy
named uh lewis and he was a hacker from
san jose california um as soon as i went
into the
um chat room the first thing i noticed
was
he had hundreds of bots in the channel
that were all running on college uh
college servers and knowing that there
was no way that he went to all those
colleges
or had legitimate access to those they
knew right away that he
he was probably a hacker back then
everybody wanted uh shells on college
computers because they had
the absolute fastest internet and their
speeds were just
insane and any student that went to the
colleges
could plug in their own computers into
like the wall in their dorm room
and be on the college network and it
wasn't an always-on connection
and that opened the door to
tons of computers that were able to be
hacked because they were always online
and most of them were being run by
students that may not know
the uh ins and outs of the operating
system that they were running and know
how to properly secure it
and things so as soon as i saw that i
was just
basically obsessed with this guy in his
chatroom
i hung out in there for a little while
and
would be talking trying to get somebody
to respond back but at first
nobody ever responded because it was
just um
this guy's private room that was just
him a bunch of his bots
and occasionally he would have other
friends that would come in and out of
the chat room
like when he was online so um i
basically would join the chat room every
time that i ever got a line
after that point waiting and looking for
somebody to talk to because i wanted to
know
how lewis got all of those shells to be
running all of those bots
and um eventually after
i don't remember if it was a couple of
days or maybe a week or two of
constantly joining the chat room every
day after school
um i joined it and i actually saw people
talking for the first time
and i they got me really super excited
so i started basically butting into
their conversation
i was a kid at the time and i didn't
really have the concept of
or understand the concept of being
polite and didn't understand
anything about hackers where they were
distrustful of other people or anything
like that so
i was just some random kid in this guy's
chat room and
at first he banned me from the chatroom
and um
i admittedly was a little bit upset
about that
but thanks to the fact that i was on a
dial up internet connection
i just disconnected my internet
connection reconnected
and was able to join right back into it
um
i did this over the course of several
months
he would uh ban me
i would go back into the channel he
would ban me again and then
i would just keep on doing that and then
it would get to the point where
i would be back in the chat room and the
only time it wasn't banned when nobody
was online to ban me
so um after several months of basically
really annoying this guy that uh
was going in there um i don't know why
but he
finally decided one day that he was
gonna be nice to me
um i don't know if maybe he had a good
day that day or what but
instead of banning me he actually
started talking to me
um maybe he was just bored that day
because nobody else was online or
something but uh
he started talking to me and i
just started asking him everything that
i possibly could on
how he got the shelves how he was
running all those spots and everything
like that
and at first he was extremely skeptical
of me
because well here's this person he
didn't know that i was just a kid
he didn't know anything about me
whatsoever and for all he knew
i could have been an fbi agent or a
government agent period that was in
there
questioning him because of his hacking
activities and
everything uh so um
at first he didn't want to teach me
anything he didn't want to
like he would answer a couple of
questions but that was about it he
didn't want to actually
show me how to do it do anything but i
didn't give up and i just
kept on bugging him and it got to the
point where he started
opening up to me a little bit more and
started like uh
telling me okay i'll teach you some
stuff but you have to do
this this and this first and one of the
first things that he told me
was that he wanted me to go and find
everything on the internet
that i could and read it all and when i
was done
about hacking and when i was done that
he said that he would then teach me how
to be a hacker
so i was like okay great so that's what
i set out to do
i started using the search engines at
the time
which um i don't remember what they are
right now um i want to say somewhere on
like
geocities alta vista yahoo
this was before google event existed and
um
um i just read as much stuff as i can
and instead of just uh
going and skimming through it i would
try to
actually understand it and when i was
reading something that i didn't
understand
i would go to him and show him what i
was reading
and asked him if he could like help
explain it a little bit better or
um something along those lines just to
give me a little bit
more information i found out later on um
after me and him became
really good friends that this was a
method that he used
to kind of vet people that
wanted that would come in and start
talking to him about hacking
he said that most people that he ended
up telling okay
go to the internet and read everything
you can about hacking when you're done
come back to me and i'll
start teaching you how to hack he said
that most people especially young kids
like my age
would go and come back a couple of hours
later or the next day
and claim okay i read everything there
is on the internet so
now you can start teaching me and people
that would do that
you would never help them you would
continue to ban them and just basically
ignore them
um he ended up telling me that because
i actually showed the initiative and
spent the time going out and
trying to read anything that i could
find i came back to him with
um questions and showed him that i was
trying to put in the effort and
everything like that that
that's what ended up making him change
his mind to where
he agreed to want to start helping me
um it ended up getting to the point
where
he gave me my first shell account on
some
computer that was like uh from another
country
and um the reason he gave it to me i
didn't know at the time
was because it was a pretty much a
worthless shell it wasn't a root account
or anything like that it was very
limited privileges and it was missing
a lot of the different files that you
needed back then in order to
run the egg drop bots and stuff for the
um irc bots and everything like it was
missing compilers and all of that stuff
so
it was pretty much a useless show but it
was my first show i didn't realize it
was useless
and i set out trying to figure out how
to start using it
um i took that shell access
and i went back to the shells channels
where it was people that
were engaged in the trading of back and
forth of
shell accounts and um
um they they would trade shell accounts
people would hack into
servers get root on the servers and they
would go into the shell room
shelves rooms and they would advertise
like
willing to trade um shell accounts on
this server for
shell accounts on this type of server
whether it be a specific operating
system
or specific geographical location or
something somewhere along those lines a
lot of the people because they had
hacked
the servers and gotten root they were
able to create the accounts
that they were trading out so they
weren't really losing anything
um i had my one shell account
and i didn't really know how to use it
so i started
asking the active people in there like
hey can you
help me figure out why such and such
isn't working on my show and everything
like that
and um the very first person that i
trusted
and um gave them the login information
for my show
he stole my show from me and um i
i didn't really understand it
at first and then i realized after the
fact that he had gone into the account
um the shell account
changed the password on it and then he
just like
blocked me so that i couldn't even talk
to him anymore
um i went back to louis and told him i
was like hey
my shell account's not working anymore i
don't know what happened
because i didn't want to tell him that i
had given access to somebody else
because i thought he was going to be mad
at me
because he had given me this show you
know and um
he sat there and luckily uh
he he basically didn't get mad at me he
kind of explained he was like did you
give anybody access to it
and i was like well no i didn't um i was
trying to get somebody to help me but
i didn't tell them the passwords and
things like that
he had another account on the same box
so he was able to log into his account
and while it wasn't a root account he
was able to run like the w command and
see who was connected to it
and he saw that the account that he had
given me was logged into the system at
that time
and it showed the ip address of the
person that was connected to the account
and he knew right off that it wasn't my
wasn't my ip address
so then he came back to me and he was
like well
your your shell got ripped and i didn't
understand what he meant like i
thought that i had like physically
broken the shell or something and i was
like maybe i was wrong maybe the person
didn't steal it from me and maybe i just
broke it somehow and then he ended up
um explaining to me that a ripped shell
meant
that somebody ripped me off they had
stolen my shell
and um from that point on he pretty much
told me that i wasn't allowed to go
into the shells channels and
trade or anything with any shell access
that he had given me
and i i felt like that was a pretty
pretty reasonable request a
request from him and um he ended up
giving me another show
this time it was actually on what we
called an edu
it was a server that was being run at a
university so the host name of it
ended in dot edu and um this was a
server that he actually had root on so
he created me my own account and gave me
that one so that way
if i guess i was stupid enough to go and
get ripped again at least you would
be able to either take the account back
from me or from whoever ripped it or
just deleted so that way the person
wouldn't be able to
like try to steal access from him on
that server
because that was a big problem as well
you were worried about people
you creating an account on one of your
hacked boxes
for somebody and obviously if you were
able to hack it and get root then
somebody else could do the same thing so
he was worried about
that happening um he ended up
um helping me uh on this shell account
and showed me how to start downloading
exploits and various port scanners and
stuff like that so that way i could
start trying to make
um get my own shell accounts um because
he ran what was called an irc takeover
group and an irc takeover group was
basically just like it sounds on fnet in
the 90s
you were able to um dos
or ddos a any server that you wanted
that was connected to this network
and it would disconnect that server from
the rest of the network and this was
called a netsplit
and the purpose of a netsplit would be
you would find a server that none of the
operators
in a whatever room you are wanting to
take over you would find
a server on that network that not a
single one of the operators
were on that specific server and you did
this because when you would
dos the server and disconnect it from
the network
um you would still be able to connect to
the net to that irc server
it just wouldn't be connected to
anything so it would only be
the people that were connected to that
server so we would disconnect a
server from the network and we would go
into it we would join the chat room that
we were trying to
take over and if nobody else was in that
chat room
the server would think that we just
created the server
i mean the chat room and it would give
us what's called
operator status within that chat room
and
when that happened we would then stop um
dosing it so that way it would end up
being able to reconnect to the network
and when it reconnects to the network we
call this
writing the split so when it would
reconnect
you would stay on that server and as it
connected you would see
all kinds of stuff in the chat room like
scrolling where
it shows all the servers reconnecting or
it reconnecting to all the servers
and all of a sudden everybody that was
in the chat room
on the servers that were still connected
would be shown as
joining even though they were already on
it it looked like they were all
just joining because of the servers
coming back in
and when you would ride the split in as
an operator
the trick was to try to do what we
called
a mass dia and that means
we would try to remove the operator
status
of every other operator in that room
within like a second or two
of the the net split finishing
and you would do that so that way you
would be the only person
that was left as the operator and then
you basically own that room
once you de-opt everybody you would then
invite your um your your botnet
um i forgot what it was called but you
would have the
botnets that there would be one main bot
that acted as like the uh
um in today's terminology it would kind
of be like the command and control
server
um but that's not exactly what it was it
was a bot that all of the other bots
connected to and could receive commands
from and stuff like that
so we would have the botnets join the
channel
and we would set them as the operators
and then
it was ours and for as long as we could
uh
we could maintain the operator status
within that server
or within that room and um there was a
trick to prevent this from happening
so that people couldn't take your
channels and that was to make sure that
you had at least
one bot that was that had the operator
status
on every single server on the network
and it sounds like that would be pretty
easy to do but back then
in the 90s um some of these networks
like
fnet um undernet downnet
chat net they had a lot of servers that
were connected to it so in order to have
one at least one or two bots you would
ideally you would want more than one
because if you only had one bot
that was on a specific server while the
person that is trying to take your chat
room could
first dos or ddos that one bot
disconnect it and then do the net split
so that way it was
it wasn't protected on that server so um
i started i basically joined um lewis's
takeover crew we were called uh those
damn kids
tdk and um i
started helping them trying to um
basically expand our botnet
um i wasn't extremely good of course
because i was just starting so
i would always end up with uh really bad
bad shelves or bad servers like i would
find
shells that had really bad um connection
speeds or
shells that or servers that didn't have
all of the proper uh software that we
needed to
compile and run our bots and um
everything so we got to the point where
um he he's just started teaching me it
all basically
and once we had our actual
egg drop bots to the point where it was
a big enough net that we had
at least a couple of bots on every
single server that's when we started
transitioning to working on
our ddos net the first ddos software
that i ever used
um i think it was called trino
um trin00 and then there was another one
that was made by a german hacker i think
his name was mixer
and i don't know how to pronounce the
name of it but it translated from german
to english the translation was silent
night
and those were the two main
dos tools that we would use so i spent
all of my time after school uh just
helping expand our botnets and stuff
like that for all of these
i and i did this for a couple of years
um
i spent probably a good two or three
years just doing the
the irc war stuff and uh
it got to the point where my parents
were not my parents my mom and my
sisters
started to get online as well they had
gotten introduced to irc
and they were really enjoying talking uh
talking on irc and all of that stuff too
so
we uh we would hang out at times but
we kind of ran in completely different
circles but
um there was plenty of times where i
would be hanging out with my friends on
fnet
and my mom would be in a chat room on
ethnic called
cyber check and that was just like one
of the
main channels on this network so when
you connect to mrc
it pops up once you connect to the
server a little window would pop up
that would list all of the default
channels
that were available on that server and
cyber chat was one of them so
the channels that came up under the
default list are the ones that everybody
wanted to own
because those are the ones that got the
most users
the object was to own the rooms that had
the most users because
only gave you kind of like prestige and
stuff like that
well uh there were instances where
people would go into
cyber chat where my mom was and people
would just be disrespectful it would
probably be other kids that were about
my age and stuff
and um they would sit there and start
disrespecting my mom
like being rude to her cussing her out
and stuff
and she would always threaten him if you
don't leave me alone
i'm gonna tell my son and he's gonna
come and hack you and everything
and just like if anybody heard that from
anybody else
most people's reaction was basically
just to laugh at her and be like
whatever
i'm a hacker too i'm not scared of your
son blah blah blah
and um she would be like on the other
side of the house but she would yell
across the house like tommy i need you
to come into
the chat room we've got people that are
in here being mean or
whatever and uh me and louis and a
couple of other people would join the
chat room
and we would watch for a second we would
see the person being rude or
uh disrespectful and everything so we
would always be like all right well
you need to leave her alone that's my
mom and basically we gave him a shot we
told him if you leave her alone and just
leave
then that'll that'll be it you won't
hear from us again but if you don't
listen to us we would start threatening
i'm saying
we would hack his computer or we would
dawson or something like that
now back in the 90s there was a tool
that you could use
that was um called uh when nuke
any computer that was running like
windows 95 and windows 98
there was uh some little command
that you were able to send to their ip
address
that would instantly cause them to get a
blue screen of death
and on fnet they made no attempt to
hide the ip address of each individual
users
so all you had to do was type like slash
who is
the nickname and it would give you their
host name or their ip address and if it
gave you the host name you could just do
slash dns the host name and it would
give you the ip address
and we would at first we would nuke them
and
knock them offline and most of the time
they would come right back
and still talk crap and threaten us back
and stuff so
it got to the point where there were
some people that
were so disrespectful when we did this
that we instead of just nuking them
we would ddos their ip addresses and
there was a couple of times that
we we didn't really understand the power
of our botnets back then
so we didn't realize just how strong
they were
or it had become and we ddosed one
person
that was bothering my mom and we ended
up dropping
at the uh the isp that he was connected
to
every single person in his entire city
was knocked offline because we had
ddosed his ip address so hard
and the first time um i did that that
was kind of like
uh uh oh crap like i have this much
power online
and being 13 14 15 year old kid
having the power to take an entire city
off the internet
just kind of made my head blow up like
like crazy it made me think i was some
hot [ __ ] hacker that uh was much better
than
i actually was and um
yeah so we just we would go about doing
things like that
and um it got to be about
97 maybe 98 and i
was starting to get bored doing these
irc takeovers and stuff like that
i still did them but i was starting to
look for things that
would be more fun you know and um that's
when i got
introduced to the concept of defacing
websites
there was a website at the time and it's
still around now called
attrition.org and
they would mirror websites that um
had been hacked so if a website got
hacked
either the person that hacked it um or
somebody else could go to attrition
and submit the website and say okay this
website was defaced and this is the
person that did it
and then the people that ran attrition
would then go
verify that it was hacked and then they
would mirror the website to kind of keep
a log
or a record showing that it was hacked
and who did it
and um i got my first couple of sites
mirrored on attrition and like i said 97
or 98
and once i did that it kind of it got my
interest a whole lot more because
now i was able uh to deface websites and
it would be able to report it on here so
then it would kind of help me
like build up my uh credibility
or um something along those lines just
uh
like my elite skills or whatever because
i was able to have
proof that i was able to hack websites
instead of just
telling people that i was going to hack
them and stuff like that
um so i spent about uh
a year or so doing this by myself
um because uh lewis he didn't like
defacing websites he just wanted to do
the irc
wars and everything because he felt that
uh defacing the websites would
bring too much heat on him and when you
deface the website they know you're on
the system
so you have a much higher likelihood of
losing access to the server and he
didn't want to lose access to the
servers that he act
he act into so while i still was doing
the irc wars with them
here and there i started transitioning
to doing the website defacement thing
it got to be about 1999 and i joined
my first um defacement what we called a
defacement group
the name of this crew was the fear ph
33r hacksaw h4x0r
crew cr uh 3w stupid
stupid name of course but we were all a
bunch of kids
um i joined them and started defacing
websites with them
um most of the websites that we defaced
as part of this
uh this group were like
nothing websites they were random
peoples
like personal websites or like
uh a hardware store in indiana and stuff
like that
no meaningful website and people kind of
made fun of us
uh because of it because they were like
you're you're hacking into things that
like
my anybody could hack into so you're not
really showing that you have
good skills or anything like that um
once i got had gotten into that i
started every single day i would
go to attrition.org and i would look at
the mirror for every other website that
was hacked
and a lot of us that was were defacing
websites
we would put on there we would put our
message and then we would give our shout
outs to
other hacking groups or other people
that we liked
and then we would put a
link we would tell people what irc
server we were hanging out we were
hanging out on
and what chat room on that server well i
started joining other hacking groups uh
irc servers and their um chat rooms and
everything and that's how i
ended up stumbling across the um world
of hell hacking group in 2000
um at the time like i said fear hacksaw
crew was just hacking nothing but
really low-level websites and there was
a new
defacement mirror that came online that
was called
all das a-l-l-d-a-s-dot
d-e and this one showed a lot more
websites
from a lot more different hacking groups
than attrition did at the time
so i ended up coming across a
website that was hacked by the world of
health hackers
and it was what we called a high profile
website like it was a
it was a big company like a company that
everybody knew the name of
and um you had the ability to filter
the defaced websites by the
company the domain the hacking group
whether it was a high profile site or
just some random
crappy site and so i looked and saw that
every single website that world of hell
had hacked
was it was always a unix system
and they were all high-profile websites
it would be like
acer.com yahoo um hotmail
msn uh mercedes benz things like that
so to me that meant these guys were
really good
so i ended up joining their chat room
hanging out with them for a little while
and then we kind of like formed a little
bit of a bond between
the fear hacksaw crew and world of
health
and after a couple of months of being
separate groups
but still like kind of hacking together
um
one of the other like really active
members of the hacking group
um world of hell his name was rafa he uh
sent me a direct message and he was like
hey man would you be interested
in leaving fear hacks or crew and coming
over and joining world of hell with us
because um i had started trying to
basically mimic what they were doing
i stopped looking for just hacking any
website that i could
could and started trying to target
specific websites
or high profile websites and
i was like instantly i was like yes i'm
in
because back at this time um it was
all about your exploits on what you were
going to be able to
hack with the exploits and uh world of
hell
had uh some guys that were extremely
good at
finding vulnerabilities and then writing
the exploits to exploit those
vulnerabilities
and you didn't really share most of your
exploits with anybody if they weren't in
your group
so i saw joining world of hell as a
means to
get access to a lot more tools a lot
more exploits and
everything so it was a no-brainer um
the very first website that i hacked as
part of world of hell
was the uh virginia department of
informational technology
um server which housed the state of
virginia the state that i live in
it how housed our state website
and um that was my very first one that
was kind of like my inauguration
into the group and from there it just
it just blossomed past uh past that
within a couple of months
me and rafa every day all day
unless i was in school me and him were
talking to each other
in private messages we would talk in the
public chat room some and
in our private group chat room but me
and him were
always talking in um private together
and hacking together
and it got to a point where the two of
us were the
the most well two most well-known people
of the group
and we kind of took over the leadership
of the uh the group
and we set some new rules back then
windows was so easy to hack
that we actually told members of world
of help you're not allowed to hack
windows it's too easy
it doesn't take any uh any skill and
anybody can do it so
we wanted to build a name for ourselves
as being
the ones that went after the hard
targets uh so
that's what we did i ran the world of
health hacking group with rapa
up until um 2001.
so in 2001 i turned 18 in november of
and um being a kid and not really
understanding the law and everything
like that
i thought mistakenly that if
i um stopped hacking when i turned 18
that i couldn't get in trouble for
things that i did as a kid
i thought that as soon as i turned 18 it
would magically make it so all of the
stuff i had done
prior to that like they could never get
me in trouble for it
and uh so for the last month or so
before i turned 18
me and rafa went all in trying to hack
like as much stuff as we could we had
major pharmaceutical companies us
government
military computer systems um microsoft
websites and things like that
and um well up until my 18th birthday
the day before my 18th birthday i
did kind of like a last hurrah and uh
my planning was to hack that day and
then
stop after that well it didn't really
work out that way
and uh i still continue to hack a little
bit i didn't hack quite as much
because i had gotten into playing some
games like uh
team fortress and stuff like that so i
started playing
some more uh games a little bit more
instead of
focusing every bit of my waking hours uh
to hacking
uh that lasted for maybe maybe a month
or so
and then i got kind of bored and i was
no longer getting the
the rush of hacking these computers and
getting that
root shell uh prompt when you
successfully exploited the system
and um i've told people for a long time
that
to me hacking was always like a drug um
the rush the adrenaline rush and the
quote unquote high that we would get
after doing this
um was just like doing any other drugs
and it was just
tons of fun for us um i continued to do
this
until uh june 12th of 2002
i was working and um
i had downloaded the night before i had
downloaded the movie men in black 2
online and the plan was to go to work
the next day pretend that i was sick and
then
get sent home early so that i could
watch the movie
and then like just hang out for the rest
of the day so
i'm at work and pretending to be sick
and around noon that day
my uh boss agreed to let me go home
so i ran out jumped in my car and drove
home
when i pulled into my apartment complex
that i was living in at the time
the um at the time i didn't realize it
but the parking lot was completely empty
there wasn't a single car
anywhere around my building which in
hindsight it was really weird
because there was always some cars
parked there
but this time there weren't i walked up
the steps to my apartment
i put my key in the door i tried to
unlock it and i went to open the door
but it didn't open
my front door had two locks one dead
bolt that could be open from the outside
and the other deadbolt that could only
be open from the inside
so i started banging on the door and
yelling from my sister
my parents were at work so they weren't
home and i was banging on the door and i
yelled to my sister
you better not be in there smoking
without me referring to smoking weed
because i plan to go home smoke weed and
watch this movie well the next thing i
know i hear
the little click of the lock being
unlocked and i went to open it and the
door was ripped out of my hands because
it was ripped open
and standing in my house was the fbi i
don't know how many agents it was it was
at least like
15 or 20 agents they all had their
like m16s when they ripped the door open
in front of me
they had a gun pointed into my face they
pulled me into my apartment
put me up against the wall patted me
down and everything and led me into the
living room when i got into the living
room uh my sister was sitting on the
couch
and my dad was there i didn't know that
he was there but apparently when the fbi
showed up
my sister was a miner too and um they
forced her to
call her parents my mom was somewhere
off
working and couldn't be reached so my
sister had called my dad my dad got
there
as fast as he could and they were ready
in my house
and they ended up sitting me down and um
i i was beyond scared and
didn't really understand all of what was
going on and they started wanting to ask
me questions and everything and
i told them that i didn't want to answer
any questions without a warrior
and then they told me well if you're
forcing to be
um if you're gonna force to have a uh
con a lawyer then we're not gonna help
you uh when it comes time to giving a
good word for the judge and everything
like that so my dad
was all like you better answer all the
questions that they ask you
and everything so i sat there and i
admitted
that yes i was dog eg i was the leader
of world of hell the world of health
hacking group
and everything and um they
continued to ask me questions i would
answer some i would not answer some
pretending that i didn't didn't remember
the answer
or something along those lines and they
searched the house they took all the
computers every scrap piece of paper
that had handwritten notes
anything that they thought could
potentially help give them
evidence to convict me
and surprisingly enough they didn't
actually arrest me or to take me into
custody that day
they charged me and they put me on
something called pretrial services
that's basically probation before you go
to court
um i spent a year and a half on
pre-trial and during this time i was
banned from touching a computer
and for about the first six months or so
i i stayed off the computer like
completely i wasn't allowed to touch one
at all anyway
but i i actually listened and stayed off
the computer completely
but then after the six months i started
to get bored so
when my mom would go to sleep i would
sneak on the computer again
and it it just blossomed from getting on
for an hour to at night when everybody
was asleep to
staying online all the time again and i
joined another hacking group
called hackwiser hackwiser i joined them
under a different name i used the name
the unknown hacker
because i didn't want nobody to know who
i was the only two people
that knew who i really was in that group
was a guy named hackajack a hacker
in cincinnati ohio and his online
girlfriend fizz
um i started hacking together with them
and at the time i didn't know it but
they had been arrested too
and they were sitting with the fbi and
they were asking me to hack specific
websites
i would hack the website then give them
access
and then they basically used me to get
out of trouble
and help lower their sentence um
i originally was supposed to get six
months of what they call
shock incarceration or a boot camp and
then six months of probation
and then or six months of house arrest
and then five years of probation
um but because i didn't listen and
didn't stay off the computer and started
hacking again when i
um went to court on january 23
of 2004 they uh
they sentenced me and i went into court
that day thinking that i was gonna get
um sentenced but then have a month until
i had to self-report
they sentenced me to two and a half
years in federal prison
and banned me from touching a computer
for um
i think it was five years at first and
instead of giving me a month to turn
myself into the prison
they took me right away right that day
and they took me to federal prison
um i accidentally skipped the part about
my first arrest for
hacking and stuff in 2000 but because
of another charge that i got during that
first arrest in april of 2000
the u.s federal government considered me
a
violent criminal and instead of going to
a camp or a low-level
uh security prison to do my time they
classified me
as a high severity inmate
and put me in medium high and maximum
security federal prisons
i stayed in federal prison in that time
until 2006
i was released on january 6 2006
and i was on probation i wasn't allowed
to touch computers or anything like that
uh for the first month i stayed off
computers and then after a month it was
right back just like before
i started sneaking on a computer a
little bit here and there i would go to
the library and use it
and then it got to the point where i
didn't really care anymore and i just
always stayed on the computer when my
probation officer would show up at my
house
when i saw him pull into the driveway i
would rush and hide all my computers
like in closets under the bed and stuff
like that
and um in april of 2007
i forgot to hide um
one of the pieces when he showed up and
he walked into my bedroom and he saw a
keyboard and a mouse sitting on my bed
and to him that was enough proof that i
had a computer
so he violated my probation that time he
sent me back to federal prison for 10
months
i did those 10 months was released in
february of 2008.
um once again i was banned from
computers but i didn't listen again
i started getting on the computer again
right after my release
and uh a year after my release one of my
co-defendants from my original
hacking he started being a hacker a bad
hacker again
and uh a girl i broke up with called the
fbi and told them
because she was mad at me and knew i
wasn't allowed on the computer she
called the fbi and told them that i was
back on the computer and that i was
hacking
and everything again so they spent six
months watching my house
and monitoring my internet connection
and found out that i was
actually hacking again and they raided
my house again in october of 2009
and sent me back to federal prison for
another 14 months
i was released from federal prison the
last time in january
or november of 2010
um upon my release because they
killed my probation i was no longer on
probation they removed my
limitation of not being able to be on a
computer anymore
once they did that i started looking for
an ig job but
it was extremely difficult to find one
because i had been convicted of
the cfa cfaa which is the computer fraud
and abuse act
um that's the computer laws here in the
us
i finally found a company in june of
that agreed to hire me as their unix
system admin
i stayed with this company as a their
sys admin and developer from 2013
until 2016. 2016 i was introduced to the
world of
bug bounties i submitted my first
vulnerability to
the um yahoo program on hackerone
and it got accepted in march of 2016 and
they paid me 300
for it and at that point i knew what i
wanted to do for the rest of my life
now i was able to hack but instead of
them sending me to prison
they were gonna pay me so i stayed at my
job for about six months and was doing
bug bounties
in my free time and after six months i
realized that i'm making a lot more
money or i have the ability to make a
lot more money
doing the bug bounty stuff than i was as
a system admin
so in 2017 i
transitioned i quit my jobs and started
being a full-time bug bounty hunter
which i did is uh i
did full-time bug bounty hunting up
until
um actually december of last year i
got a job with a company called breeze
that i s
i'm still uh working with raise now but
uh
i did bug bounties full time from 2017
to the end of 2020.
in 2016 i only made about 30 thousand
dollars
doing bug bounties part time in 2017
i made right about a hundred thousand
dollars
uh for the first time and 2018 i really
started focusing on it
a lot more i changed up my approach to
how i was doing the hacking
and that was my first really good year i
made a couple of hundred thousand
dollars
in 2018 and then in 2019
um i had my best year i made roughly
900 000 in 2019
just from bug bounties and last year
i think i ended up doing about four or
five hundred thousand dollars
in um bounties um because of
cove and a lot of programs uh started
lowering their payments and everything
so
i didn't quite make as much and um
here's
some stuff currently i am the uh ranked
number 23
on hacker one out of hundreds of
thousands of different hackers
i'm ranked 280th on bug crowd since i
don't spend as much time on there
and i'm currently ranked 19th out of the
i think there's maybe a couple thousand
hackers on senec
and i've made roughly 2.5 million
dollars maybe a little bit more
across all the platforms and everything
when it comes
to bug bounties um let's see what's this
next class
um some of the achievements that i've
been able to get now
like in the bug bounties last year in
february of 2020 um
hacker one does these live hacking
events and um
the target during the last the h1 415
was verizon media which is the
program that i do most of my hacking for
they're responsible for
roughly 1.8 million dollars of my total
income
from bug bounties um and i won
the most valuable hacker which gave me a
little
wwe style wrestling belt
um i also won the exalted
which i don't remember what exactly that
um
achieved like that reward is for and
then the assassin
which i think was getting the most valid
bugs
or something along those lines and um
yeah uh i've that's pretty much what i
do now i now
am a senior security engineer for braze
i run the braised private bug bounty
program
and i'm getting to work with a bunch of
really good hackers helping secure
my company systems and learning a bunch
from them
um and yeah that's
uh that's pretty much it that's
basically my life story
this time went by a whole lot faster
than i was expecting so
i'm sure i left out a few things here
and there
um but yeah i didn't realize the time
was going to go by quite as fast as it
did
but uh yeah
i think there's going to be some
questions
that uh some people have submitted
or something hello
and hello again um i'm going to
um find them just a second
no problem at all okay and thank you for
your
talk it was really interesting and
fascinating in a way
that you can actually come back from the
black hat works so
what do you think you can learn from
being a black hat
that a white hat could never learn
um well when it comes to being a white
hat and following bug bounty programs
you have what's called a scope
and at times the scope can be extremely
limited
um telling you what you can and can't
hack but
being a black cat you don't care what
the scope is
so you're able to explore and hack a lot
of things that you would otherwise
not be able to legally hack and
i think that my experience as a black
cat
because of things like that and being
able to experience
um a lot more of different things that i
was hacking throughout all of my time
that it's contributed to help make me as
successful as i am today
okay so the next question is did you
have any run-ins
uh with ir irc
ops um sorry i'm used to talking
in finnish so um with the irc
ops um occasionally yeah um
so one of the members of tdk our hacking
group
was actually an offer from one of the
f-net
servers so he did his best a lot of
times to protect us and make sure we
didn't get in trouble
um at the time in the 90s most people
most of the operas on fnet didn't really
care what we were doing
as long as we didn't go after like
specific
rooms that were frequented or owned by
them or their friends
so as long as we were sticking to like
the shells channels the where's channels
and like team chat um cyber chat
uh chat zone things like that they
didn't
really care as long as we didn't go and
steal theirs
and we didn't like basically harass
everybody
okay so i think we have one more
time for one more question i think i
picked this one
how do your parents feel about your
career now
um now they're extremely happy um for a
long time
both them and i thought that i had
effectively ruined my life
um if things now were the same as they
were in the 90s then my life would have
been ruined but
luckily um over the last several years
we've been able to convince not the
entire world but a lot of people
that not all hackers are bad um
just because people made mistakes in the
past
doesn't mean that they haven't changed i
have changed a lot since i was
a black hat hacker i now have a
four-year-old daughter
that is one of my biggest motivating
factors to make sure
i never do anything illegal again
i make sure that i
don't violate to the best of my ability
i make sure i don't violate any rules
when it comes to bug bounties
because if i get caught illegally
hacking again it's life in prison
so my parents are extremely happy that
i've gone
from what we thought was a life
ruining event to being able to turn it
around
and become extremely successful doing
not only something that i love but
something that also
helps other people and helps secure
systems to protect people's data and
provide
a really good life for my daughter
okay thank you so much for your time it
i hope we would have more time for you
but i think
next we're going to have a little break
and then continue with our last talk
could i say
one more thing really quick is kind of
something to lose
um the biggest takeaway i want uh people
to get from this especially
young upcoming hackers is don't make the
mistakes that i did going
down the black cat route nowadays you
have so many opportunities to do this
legally and make a lot of money doing it
that the risk of doing it as a black
cat's not worth it
you have bug bounty programs you have
bone hub
and um try to hack various places that
let you legally hack them to learn and
explore your curiosity
without breaking the law and i highly
recommend people to take that route
versus
the blackout route because you don't
want to go to prison
for being a hacker especially when you
have so many opportunities in the world
to do this legally and to help people
yeah that's really good and sound advice
i'm
really up for that one and so
i think we can continue with the next
talk and
thank you very much for uh having me if
anybody has
any questions they can reach out to me
on twitter and i'll do my best to answer
any questions that people have that
i didn't get a chance to address or
answer during this
yeah are you actually in the server
which we have for
discord yes i am sure there are lots of
more questions
yeah yeah so we can actually continue
a couple of weeks to uh for anybody that
wants to feel free to reach out to me
on the city sex discord or
whatever and i'll do my best to answer
anything for anybody that
has questions yeah thank you so much
thank you very much