you
all right good morning everyone i'm ben
pick and this is Jack Menino we are
going through to discuss the cloud
native infrastructure and how things
have changed and some of the security
pitfalls that you can go through that
you need to address that warrant in
traditional pipelines so if you want to
move us along
um so I'm Jack Menino I've been working
at invision since 2009 sometime in
between the rest my work I get to write
a little bit of code do most things in
Scala and go these days any Scala
programmers in there okay good stuff I
do think a lot that things about scale
these days I worked for years doing
penetration testing it's not
particularly fun to find bugs anymore
I'm definitely more inch and as part of
my career in solving things and making
it damn near impossible for attackers to
get in Thanks and all right and I am Ben
pick I'm an application security
consultant with envision and my former
life I was also a agile and DevOps
consultant so I would go in assess
various teams and give them
recommendations for how they can improve
so some of the lessons learned from that
are that we're applying in this
presentation is you need to really just
take full advantage of the systems that
you're using and make sure that they
integrate properly within your pipeline
and more recently within the cloud so
this right here is your traditional
pipeline you can see in the lower left
your developer they are committing their
code and to get it moves in a very
linear fashion through each of the
various phases of your environment so
from dev to integration to staging to
production and you can see this very
very linear fashion of your developer
committing the code and it going
directly into production now at each
stage there are more more tests so say
within dev you'll look at the source
code and you will just really really try
and get fast feedback
the typical rule is you know five
minutes for the developer to go get a
cup of coffee before they can know
whether or not their code changes broke
the belt and then as you get further and
further towards production there are
much more in-depth tests that get run so
your performance tests your dynamic test
etc etc etc now this is your cloud
native pipeline again it is a flow from
left to right in production you can see
a lot of the same tool sort of carry
over so you have Jenkins you are working
within git and this is a much more
infrastructure aware environment so when
you are deploying into dev the the
pipeline itself is aware of your
container registry and it's updating as
needed or as you are designing within
your pipeline and this is using git UPS
which I'll go through in a couple of
slides but just wanted to address that
term here so it's using git apps to
manage your infrastructure and your code
and it's using declarative statements
throughout the process to define exactly
what is going on cool it's just a really
quick slide to highlight some of our key
summaries you have also on the left with
your traditional pipelines and then
new-school which is your cloud native
environments so some of my experience
with inconsistent environments excuse me
you will have your gold image that gets
produced by your systems admin or your
operations teams and over time that
developers tend to make changes to so
you'll have new new dependencies new
configuration settings within each of
the various development teams and what
ultimately happens is those sort of
cascade out until the goal the devoman
no longer looks like the gold Prada
Magette causes a lot of issues where you
are not necessarily finding bugs until
they are in production and looking at
some of the Robeck process for
those bugs well when you are in
production a lot of times you won't find
out about issues until your helpdesk
comes in with massive amounts of calls
and then in traditional pipelines there
is a large process that's needed which
costs a lot of money to then roll back
all those changes whereas in cloud cloud
native environments you have what's
called canary bills where you are able
to set up you with your load balancer
and say I want 10% of the people to our
site to be redirected to the updated
version whereas and then I percent will
be going to the known stable version and
then of those people that get redirected
through your load balancer they can say
well you know of those requests that
come through 5% of them are getting 500
errors so based on the declarative rules
that we have we set that to know that
the updated version is no longer stable
so then it redirects everyone back to
the original updated version the sorry
the original known good state and it
kills the containers for the updated
versions so cloud name can automatically
handle that based on the rules that you
have declared through canary builds all
right and then I sort of mentioned this
before but everything is defined within
your infrastructure within your source
code and get and so you need to manage
your environments and make sure that
that is well tracked well-documented and
you want to ensure that you are that you
are properly managing your branches so
where does security fall in well you
want to make sure that you're using
multi-factor authentication so you can
specifically tie an individual user to
sorry you want to is specifically tie an
individual to their identity then you
want to make sure that they aren't
committing anything without signing it
so you want to ensure that all the add
stations get signed for that for
it's and you want to enable branch
restrictions within the production so
that one single developer is not only
one single developer or a single team is
not able to commit or push changes into
the master branch which becomes your
production and that's cool
so one of the tools that you are using
within cloud native is spinnaker which
handles all of your communications now
this tool this tool is used for your for
your communication so it's very very
important that it is properly configured
and set up and much like your
applications using micro services this
follows the same process so you have
gate you have cloud driver
Igor Fiat and halyard now halyard is the
configuration management service which
configures all the other services Fiat
is the authorization service which
checks to make sure whether or not
something has say service level access
and queries it before running anything
important then you have a gate which is
the API manager it's sorry the API
gateway itself and I believe that's
everything that's not to Jack cool
so one of the things we have to think
about in our kind of updated workflows
is where do we actually derive any value
from the tests we run so before we push
and deploy things there's different
things we're gonna see after we push
things to in environments there's
different integration tests we're gonna
see different things that you know we
can't necessarily blame the developers
when somebody that runs cloud
infrastructure makes like an s3 bucket
public right so there's things we can
verify before we deploy but then there's
you know certain things that can happen
after deployment that we want to know
about right and those are unfortunately
things that we're not going to get out
of the way before we push so it is
important to get as much telemetry as we
possibly can out of all the tools we use
and all the different events we generate
so if we look at for example spinnaker
handles deployment not necessarily the
integration and build side so you'll
generally hook something like spinnaker
up to Jenkins I'm using web hooks and
stuff like that so all your systems are
definitely very active in talking to
each other and the feedback loop is
really important right because we can
use that feedback to help our systems
either recover in intelligent ways or
let us know what's going on so there's
the whole world of chaos testing right
which is what can go week what can go
wrong and ultimately you know how do we
break our applications in the worst way
possible the stuff I'm talking about
more today is verification right so
verifying that certain preconditions are
in place before you go in live with code
so more on the verification side on then
experimentation side so Jenkins X is
another pretty popular cloud native see
ICD tool so it builds on Jenkins pretty
significantly it's pretty much Jenkins
reimagined with an opinionated kind of
workflow on top of kubernetes so whose
work with kubernetes in here so two
curiosity who knows what a namespace is
great for anyone that doesn't know what
a kubernetes namespaces it's essentially
a logical isolation boundary where we
can divide up things like role based
access control networking access to
secrets so the better segmented your
architecture is via namespaces and doing
that intelligently the better off you're
going to be so once upon the time we
kind of ran Jenkins and we had these big
clusters and we had a few centralized
systems right and those were the kind of
keys to get into production for some
people we run these a lot more
decentralized now right so more teams
are gonna have their own instances so
I've seen environments where you know CI
CD is kind of the security and layer for
you know getting anything into
production and nobody touches you know
VMs and things like that and now we're
giving people access to the clusters so
we have to consider what can they do so
if we make the namespaces too muddy too
many teams you know different
applications kind of smashed into one
place and everybody has access to pull
secrets deploy applications read that
data so we find that our develop
workflows kind of follow us right into
production now because they're baked
right into the cluster itself kubernetes
Jenkins X uses um Tecton pipelines so
it's another way of essentially
everything is gonna be declarative right
so it's yeah mole based representation
for your pipelines the biggest
distinction between spinnaker and
jenkins x is that jenkins x is it's it's
deeper integrated into kubernetes the
CRD so we're a spinnaker introduce its
own api's jenkins actually actually uses
kubernetes to do a lot of its api back
stuff so building pipelines running
tasks and stuff like that there's all
kubernetes CR DS to represent those
things and you can also do things with
jenkins files as well so there's
essentially like the servo mush mode and
then there's static mode as well where
you can use jenkins files so but the big
difference here is that everything's
being driven i'm in a get apps fashion
right ideally we're not giving people
direct access the clusters but that
happens all the time
so we have security opportunities and
challenges so we have a lot more
telemetry that we generate we have a lot
more events and so we can use those
things for good right the downside is
that once we start missing things like
web hooks that means we're missing
builds we're missing events so we can
also have you know points of blindness
if we just start missing events with
regards that observability so we have
the development systems we use then we
have all the other tooling as well right
from our cloud to our containerized
orchestration systems to the things we
can get from the containers themselves
right and so there's certain things you
know you'll get at runtime right looking
at a container and figuring out you know
which syscalls it's actually using you
know granted you can get some of that
stuff through static analysis but you
can also run these things as well so
there's certain things that you
certainly want to see from different
stages and you really want to be careful
of the security opinionations that are
in place for you so one of the really
nice things about both Jenkins X and
spinnaker is that they abstract
developers away from a lot of detail so
you don't need to know as much about the
cloud you don't need to know as much
about kubernetes
the downside is that some of those
opinionations might not necessarily
match your tolerance for security and
risk great so the way you kind of
configure your cloud and do hardening
and governance it may be very different
than the opinionations or you know
minimal security built into these tools
right so the goal is to get people up
and running as fast as possible not to
make it as secure as possible and
impossible to use right so one makes
developer happy one makes everybody in
this room happy this is a developer tool
and failure is everywhere right so this
is an example of a kubernetes cluster
and there's a lot that can go wrong
there in terms of failure so first off
we have control plane I wish I have my
little pointer thing but you can see
right here this is pretty much the most
important part of the cluster so this is
where the API server is this is where
you know data representing the state of
the cluster is stored and all the
deployment resource management that all
happens from the control plane so if
you're using a managed service something
like e KS or a KS they'll handle the
control plane but then for example an
ECC e KS on AWS you'll actually spin up
you know essentially virtual machines
for each of the kubernetes nodes right
so there's a little bit that the cloud
handles and then there's a little bit
that you're still running instances at
the end of the day so depending on how
abstracted that aura is away from you
know if you have to manage it yourself
you have to harden the control plane if
a TBS is managing it you have maybe a
little bit less of that to do but some
considerations but things that can go
wrong there you can not do proper
isolation of containers so if you're
running containers super privileged or
you're not you know using what a
rule-based kind of security execution
around them containers aren't really
unlimited they're limited by namespaces
and control groups things like docker
for example they're not hypervisors is
not really a security boundary right so
there's a lot that can go wrong there
and you know with addition to you know
using our managed services rate how many
people think that kubernetes api is are
all over the internet if you look for
them right like they're everywhere
people make these public and as well
like 80s and others don't necessarily
make it hard feet or not do that so then
we also have code right because
everything runs inside of containers as
code so you know the thing we kind of
get lost in we think about all the new
pretty stuff is that at the end of the
day we're still running code right but
the difference is our code is maybe a
lot more abstracted from the things
around it than it was at one point so
things to consider right is that your
application just might not understand
what's happening outside of the
application itself so container
orchestration and runtime systems and
the container is important to get right
so when we're testing there's you know
things we can do locally right run
things like docker bench you know
there's a million tools I hate to kind
of get up here and be a tool evangelist
go on google and search them I guarantee
uses some good tools out there but
there's things you can kind of find
those things locally right but there's
also things you're not gonna see with
regards to contain a configuration I'm
told the point I'm right because there's
certain things that for example
kubernetes you know there's other
container orchestration technologies out
there they can also mutate that state as
well at a mission so you have emission
controllers that can do things and you
can also have different wrappers things
like security contexts and other things
that can potentially change what you see
inside if I could dock or farm openly so
if you want to have visibility of all
the different kind of states and then
you need to you know test as you move
through different environments right
from local to actually running it in a
cluster everything is declarative so
that's the good thing right so there's
really not a lot of kind of guesswork
the good thing is that everything
happens right away the bad thing is
everything happens right away so the
reconcile my pattern is essentially
always trying to reconcile towards the
correct state right so it's always
trying to move ahead and as soon it has
updates for different things it goes too
old and immediately apply those to your
resources with regards to ayahs and pass
integrations so if you are running your
own kind of bare metal cluster then
there's a lot more that you'd have to do
to get it to work with same like you
know eks right so eks aks
gke there they're integrated with things
like I am different
you know platform services and
everything like that so if you're gonna
do things yourself like that then you
have to you know consider key management
right credential management across your
system so I like to advocate for if you
can use the platform managed way of
doing things in some cases do that it
saves a lot of problems and things you
have to think about later the cloud is
is an interesting one right because your
applications now we're running on inside
of containers that are running on
orchestration systems and then the
orchestration systems are glued to your
cloud infrastructure right so
essentially your applications don't
really have any idea what happens there
so as you're building testing your
applications these are the kind of tests
you start to have to consider running
right when I go to deploy something is
the s3 bucket public can it be made
public is the EBS volume encrypted
that's going to be attached to this is
the I am role that's going to be
basically injected has like allow oil
across AWS like like there's certain
things from a security perspective that
you'd almost never want to happen right
so these end up becoming things that you
know happen inside of your integration
tests and other parts you have test
suite I am is where it really gets
interesting though because if you have
for example an I am role or user you
create for a platform rate and then you
give that to a service account that then
runs in container depending on what
you've privilege that at the cloud level
is going to dictate what happens when
that container gets compromised and
attacker starts to try to move laterally
and pivot into other systems so this is
a newer thing especially the AWS just
released recently the im2 eks I know
like as was done that for awhile gke but
these are things to consider right
because once you create these accounts
you create subjects you tie them to I am
sometimes your developers start reusing
them across applications and then we
have code that actually runs inside of
these things right so you know I've
heard this right it runs in the cloud so
you don't think about security and like
it runs in container so like they're
isolated at this
I know right like you're still writing
code and and in fact like the code you
write is more complex we have more
distributed systems right we have a lot
more that can kind of go wrong we have
you know a lot of interesting things
like seeing people that are migrated
existing systems to you know cloud
native architectures and you know from
fairly monolithic systems they start to
run into things like race conditions
kind of concurrency related issues where
they move from like a monolithic
workflow to using like simply Kafka and
passing messages around right where
there's just differences in terms of
like how that flows so that is really
important right as you migrate existing
systems to cloud native and then start
to use cloud native tooling you really
have to make sure your security controls
kind of follow with you the way you test
applications right so things like you
know I'm not gonna get into today and
like running your static analysis like
dynamic tools like I asked like
dependency stuff right those those
things don't change like you still have
places in the pipeline to run all that
stuff right so the way you test your
code arguably doesn't change there it's
on light of the other stuff that happens
around it an integration rate on things
you won't actually know in the code
until it's actually running in that
environment right so just certain things
they got harder our dorm on the IM side
of things depending on what you've
allowed people to do inside of your
cluster to potentially impact what they
can do inside of your cloud so from you
know things like permissioning access to
our container registries so I see people
do a couple different ways right one is
they put everything on the same cloud
provider right so their source code
management their container registries
cloud stuff like everything is under 100
they can use I am you know minimize the
credentials they pass around access keys
and stuff like that so if you can do it
all under one platform and that works
for you great I'm in reality most people
don't build like that so it gets really
important to figure out you know what
can that service account actually do in
the cost store and in the cloud by
default in kubernetes when you create a
new pod it'll use like a default service
account
so I'll show an example that like in
Tecton here right so you can use so this
is if you want to create a pipeline
using Tecton it follows the same pretty
much like you know it's essentially
running on kubernetes right so the way
you'd run you know other resources very
similar but as you run with service
accounts so if you using like default
accounts which is a common pattern right
so people will create a new pod create a
pod spec they won't assign an account
and by default it'll drop you into like
a namespace just a vault account which
is an issue because one each of those
accounts rooms with those same
privileges they have access to pull
secrets modify the containers kind of
lifecycle and everything like that so
it's really important to use separate
accounts for each of those things
essentially here this is like that same
thing kind of in a different place with
regards to namespace vs cluster level so
generally you don't need to give your
teams that are operating in different
namespaces cluster level privileges so
the whole goal nowadays is that if
you're doing it get apps properly then
you're not giving you developers access
to the cluster to do anything so they're
updating their applications that doing
all the deployments all their
modifications through get right so if
you're doing the get apps kind of thing
correctly then your your your developers
shouldn't be able to use cube control
and start doing stuff inside of
kubernetes api all right all right so
now we are going to focus back on the
network and how to make sure that that
is communicating properly without
spilling too much especially in the way
of secrets it's cool so everything can
go wrong a lot of these developers or
whomever have a lot of faith in the
tools that they're using there are still
very very very insecure defaults so it's
important and imperative that you set up
network isolation so that you are
controlling your blast radius
essentially you want to fail closed so
in the event that you are compromised
or you want to prepare yourself to
become compromised you are limiting what
might be exposed or what a compromised
account will have access to and you can
see there was a talk a month ago now in
blackhat where they revealed that the
eks was publicly accessible by default
so that was a very very very big concern
you need to ensure that you are changing
that and aware of it
likewise logging is disabled by default
which will help you clean up or identify
where an issue occurs or clean up after
an incident so you need to ensure that
you have that on and you're you're able
to connect to without authentication so
again a lot of very very surprising
insecure defaults that you need to be
aware of change and plug this holes so
in terms of Jenkins and s3 the s3
buckets that get automatically created
are unencrypted so that's again
something you want to change the the
default settings it's also kubernetes
your your humanizes setup to be publicly
accessible and publicly accessed so
those are some little tweaks here and
there that you need to ensure that you
are changing lastly you have helm and
tiller particularly which again you have
your your able to access it without
without authentication and it's a lot of
the same problems over and over and over
again so you are storing your secrets in
config maps which are again potentially
exposed and you want to encrypt them
there's a lot of different methods you
can use one of them is hashey corpse
vault so if you keep your secrets in
there then you can have your various
teams pass if they need to use those
secrets they can pass by reference
and your various teams can work together
within the same environment
without sharing secrets yeah and don't
do dumb stuff so even without all the
default settings which you will need to
go through and change there are things
that can sort of override the security
settings and they are named accordingly
there's the insecure flag that if you
use it turns off verification of your
yamo files which is a good way to get
malicious code introduced into those
configurations so don't do things like
use insecure Flags skip TLS checks etc
etc okay so secrets management inside of
a pipeline so secrets are one of those
things that either people handle those
out of the gate when they build the
system and they have a secrets
management solution in place or they get
to production everything works and then
they kind of get to clean up sprints and
cycles and they say like let's fix
secrets management at this point right
and then by that point you know if
secrets credentials have kind of
sprawled out between their different
environments so as you use different
tools right your CI CD Tools helm so
who's worked with Helmand here we talked
about helm a bit today helm is you know
first-class implementation inside of
Jenkins X you know most cloud native
tooling is using like helm and charts
and for stuff for deployments but you
have to think about right
secrets propagate to some of those
layers you have different tools with
regards to different management tools
different integrations so there's a lot
of different places where you can
inadvertently expose credentials so it's
one of those things like if you don't
get it right kind of out of the gate
then it gets harder ideally your
developers especially even at the gate
layer they're not handling secrets if
you're doing this stuff correctly then
the secrets are getting injected
somewhere beyond what is gonna happen at
the dockerfile right so this is you know
at your helmet art is a place where you
can kind of wire up secrets and stuff
like that
but ideally inside of kubernetes the
challenge is that you can use kubernetes
the secrets management API but then
secrets are still stored in plain text
inside of that CD so you can encrypt
those but it's it's kind of it's a
social implementation right a lot of
people use vaults right to kind of move
it out of there and Jenkins acts like
has integration with vault on spinnaker
I believe that some integrations with
vault and everything like that and the
vault integrations for kubernetes are
getting better and better right so if
that's one of the things I can recommend
kind of getting right out of the gate
its managing secrets and if you can
avoid developers ever having a reason to
manage those then then that's great
right and if it could be done
dynamically from day one then even
better
long live credentials are bad so people
any Azure people in here that use like
service principles and pins and like
they never rotate those things do people
use access keys on AWS like give them to
all their developers and then like they
have them for like two years and nobody
does anything with those right ideally
those were all really bad patterns
people shouldn't be using long with
credentials for things like that so if
you can use things like STS and you know
if you can use like platform integrated
you know stuff whether that's things
like Kerberos integration with I am
anything to avoid having to have
plaintext credentials get stored
anywhere so they're only you know when
you have developers you know handling
secrets they're on their local box right
any tests they run right depending on
you know whether it's local it's get
spit out somewhere you know each of
those interfaces is somewhere we're
potentially those things leak out
there's logs there's deployment logs so
on and so forth so the less places you
can expose secrets the better I really
can't stress that enough and these tools
are
extendable - so I started playing around
with just building a few extensions in
Jenkins X I worked at it's all might get
up if anybody wants to see some of this
code but there's if you basically run
like the JX scan commands you could put
anything after that right so there's one
there for running Hunter tool against
like coupon or rather but I built one
for Jenkins X and I'm gonna open-source
some stuff I wrote for our back but
there's there's different tests you can
run right so Jenkins X gives you things
like preview environments which is your
home environment spun up in a namespace
right ready to be tested so you can run
things through like you know commands
and comments on a pull request right
where you can literally run different
commands over and over against an
environment so it's nice to have as many
of these utilities on speed down as
possible and also to wire those up into
your Python as well
so in this example here it was a really
simple example of playing around with
dependency check basically what you end
up doing is anything you run is inside
of a container and then it gets the poit
on the way I have it set up is just like
an ephemeral namespace that gets thrown
away after the job runs but it's
creating itself as a batch job and then
it runs on kubernetes right so if
anyone's seen jobs run is nothing really
special about that but nonetheless I'm
it allows you to run you know any of
your security stuff in a containerized
environment in seconds and here's just
basically how you add those in so it's
Jenkins X I mean you're running on
locally so you I would be nice if they
build maybe a little bit on a better
plug-in interface for this at some point
but I mean it's like early days for the
tool right there's there are plugins but
not underneath like JX can this is
pretty much all that's available for now
under scan but pretty much you add you
command at that point and then you can
do them like J X can whatever tool you
want to run at that point and you know
one thing to note security management in
governance right especially in the cloud
it's nice to pick up the different tools
that they kind of give you them
harden things out of the gate what you
end up finding especially in the cloud
native world is that sometimes there's
not full support whether that's like you
know alerting and logs or integration
with some type of strong authentication
so as you're picking up the new cloud
native kind of hot in his tools you
really want to do your research to make
sure that the platform's you're using
them on have all the things you're
looking for for security right things
that you get out of the gate always are
like you know pod security policies and
some of that emission control based
stuff so there's a certain amount of
stuff that you want to just basically
opinionate out of the game right what
what developers can do can you run
containers is route right those are
things you should you know at a higher
level decide right and you should
implement policies so when you
developers go to push containers as
route and they can't do it like
everybody's happy at that point right
because nothing went wrong an asset
inventory gets incredibly hard right so
if you look at you know most of the
tools they do a good job at cloud-based
stuff or there's tools to get good
visibility inside of your clusters and
containers where it's getting maybe a
little bit better is you know
aggregating all that stuff so has
anybody gotten on the surface mesh
bandwagon
does anybody use this do like envoy has
anybody heard of those things so they're
really nice because they might inject
like sidecar containers that sit next to
your container and then you can proxy
traffic so you can do things like end to
end you know mutual TLS being Gettle and
logging metrics that you want out of
that so if you use in service meshes
then you actually do get a really good
extension of visibility other than that
I found that there's definitely a lot of
kind of Jimmy rigging tools together at
this point to kind of get a view because
you do want to know when people push
stuff right that's new things appear you
kind of want to know about that so in
conclusion there don't break the
feedback cycle and pile up security Det
kind of on the left-hand side there's a
lot of stuff we can do at our cluster
level things we can kind of opinionate
upfront for our developers a lot of it
has to do with how we layout
things like get-ups and how well we obey
kind of some of those rules right if we
are doing the get-ups thing and then
we're giving people like direct cluster
access we've broken a lot of the kind of
advantages right if we're having all of
our infrastructure and code in one place
where it's auditable right like I go
through sock to at my company every year
is anybody who sought to type do it's
the most miserable in the world and
they ask you dumb questions for two days
but it's great because like moving in
this model it's like here you guys go
here's literally argot right if you want
to know why we made a certain change to
our network it's it's all auditable in
one place so just as a business and
found that this is even how to benefit
from that perspective you want your
engineers to move as fast as possible
right like I'm I'm one of those security
people at this point in my career I'm
like just let everybody just write codes
business has to work right but we want
to put as much in place to make sure
that they don't just kind of shoot
themselves in the foot right and so
again how we based on ladies things out
from an IM perspective network
segmentation hiding secrets and just
enforcing good practices all around and
last but not least applying controls at
the levels they make the most sense
right there's certain things that if you
try to apply it to a docker file it's
it's a waste of time this is a better
place to do it at the container
orchestration level and then likewise
you know there's certain things that you
have to think about you know still at
the cloud level as well because if you
for example put all of your container
nodes or you know if you have multiple
clusters you put those in the same VP
sees like now they can all talk to each
other right so you can do good stuff
from a development perspective but if
the infrastructure is broken then
things aren't going to work well either
so that's our talk to everyone thank you
and happy to take any questions
[Applause]
and we got five minutes left for
questions and I've got a microphone if
you have one it remains silent do you
have any experiences you could share
with helm cause I'm curious like to know
more about I'm not really I just you
know if you had like any experiences
like things I should look at yeah you
could sure so his question was about
helm and anything we could share about
securing helm so I'm really looking
forward to helm three and the whole
Tillis approach right so a lot of the
security issues with helm came from the
tiller and just hi that was kind of set
up and so a lot of deployment issues
right for how people kind of over
privilege that tiller and then don't
leave like the you know they're G RPC
endpoints open and you can talk to that
thing right so from that perspective
I've seen just like a lot of deployment
based issues with how people do tiller
or helm right cuz it's always a major
component of it but in helm three
there's the whole tillis approach right
which solves a lot of that so you know
some of the things with like managing
helm service itself get better but then
it still gets down to like you know
managing your charts right you know cuz
that's a place a lot of people haven't
managed like charts right so they've
they've tooled around container
registries and code but they're like oh
well charts what how do I like control
access that how do I and like scan those
things right how do I do all that stuff
so that's that's the other place I see
people you know usually where they go
that model I have to build maturity
around how do you manage like the charts
and everything like that but is that a
good answer does that answer everything
you ask yeah that's helpful thanks cool
anything else are on that should be it
thank you everybody for you thank you
you