well good morning and welcome to the
presentation do certain types of
developers or teams write more secure
code the subtitle of this presentation
is human factors and application
security and the reason for that
subtitle will become obvious in a few
minutes first let me introduce myself my
name is Anita D'Amico and I am the CEO
of code DX I'm also the director of
secure decisions secure decisions is a
cybersecurity research organization that
does work primarily for the US
government we we do cybersecurity
research and develop new technologies
and then those technologies and
applications security which are the most
promising we bring over to code DX which
is a separate company that was spun out
of secure decisions and we mature those
OPSEC technologies and commercialize
them I'm here today with Chris Horne
from secure decisions he's a senior
researcher there and some of you may
have seen him present yesterday on the
topic of doing research in benchmarking
static code analyzers so he'll be doing
part of this talk today so there are
four parts to this talk part one is
going to talk about why it is that we do
research in human factors that affect
code quality and security part two we'll
discuss how we do that research part
three is the crux of this presentation
and it shows you some of the results of
what we have found to date and then part
four is where can we borrow some lessons
learned from other non software domains
about human factors that affect
performance so ready to go so let's talk
about why why should we be investigating
human factors that affect code quality
and code security
well software vulnerabilities are the
gateway to most major breaches in fact
the Verizon data breach report showed
that more than 90 percent
of breaches in the information industry
started with using web applications as
the attack vector so we know that we
have to find these software
vulnerabilities yet it still takes a
really long time despite the the state
of the art the heartbleed vulnerability
took about two years to discover the
Apache struts vulnerability took about
that was used in the Equifax breach took
about four years to discover and akkad
emissions have studied open source
repositories and found that despite the
fact that there are many eyes on the
code most vulnerabilities on average
take two years to to discover now
actually it's two years to be reported
right they very well may be discovered
long before that but they aren't
publicized for two years until after
they were originally introduced so
that's a long time for a vulnerability
to sit there and remain unknown to most
of the users of the open source software
now there are ways of course of finding
security weaknesses and vulnerabilities
most people here are familiar with
static application security testing
tools sass tools that can find security
weaknesses which may be indicative of
vulnerabilities but there have been
benchmarking tests of sass tools done by
the US government done by the National
Institute for Standards and Technology
and NSA and they took test Suites of
software with known vulnerabilities and
ran commercial and open source static
analyzers against them and found that on
average they found 14 percent of the
known vulnerabilities and each tool will
found almost a unique different 14
percent so you need to combine the
results to get the good vulnerability
coverage this is why a lot of people
still rely on manual code reviews and
the problem with manual code reviews is
that there's a lot of software to go
through where do you orient yourself as
to where to look
so that's where human factors comes in
what if you were looking for
vulnerabilities and code suppose you
were hunting for them perhaps you could
search on who the developer was or the
developer characteristics or maybe you
know something about the team and you
know that there's something about the
team characteristics that is more likely
to introduce security weaknesses or
maybe when when the code was written Tom
if day even time of year or where the
code was written if you could use that
to hunt for vulnerabilities then he
would have an advantage and where to
start looking so these factors that I
described are called human factors human
factors are properties of people and
their environment that affect human
performance so there are a number of
types there is psychological so for
example an individual's ability to focus
their attention is a human factor or
their memory or the way they make
decisions on a group level there are
human factors such as the way people
collaborate with each other or the way
they communicate with each other there's
also cultural norms that will affect the
way people perform their job as a group
there's also physiological factors for
example is the individual fatigue
this will this could affect their
performance or circadian rhythm a little
bit about circadian rhythm circadian
rhythm is the changes the diurnal cycles
that your body goes through during the
course of a day so there are certain
chemicals that are associated with your
alertness and arousal level and those
chemicals shift during the course of the
day and it's known that circadian rhythm
affects as things like the watch
standing attempt the attention of watch
standing officers on the bridge of a
ship so maybe that's relevant to to
software developers and then finally
environment so if the if the environment
is noisy if it's distracting if their
temperature changes or lighting these
are
factors now these human factors are
considered in almost all safety critical
systems in their design and also in the
analysis of failures so why not look at
them in software engineering so that's
what we're doing we're looking at human
factors in software engineering to see
if we can find correlations between
certain human factors and the resulting
quality of the code the quality and the
security of the code that software
developers are producing and I'll
describe a little bit about how this
research is done so the way most of this
research is done to date is first of all
it's done by mostly academia so one
example is Rochester Institute of
Technology that's their logo up there
and what they typically do is they work
with only open source projects fairly
medium to large-sized repos like linux
kernel or chromium apache Postgres
tomcat and they mine those repositories
for what they are consider indicators of
human factors now they can't actually
measure somebody's fatigue level but
they might look at what the local time
zone was that when the code was
committed if it's 11 o'clock at night
they might infer that the person may be
tired similarly they can't look at the
actual size of a team you know in terms
of the team dynamics but they might look
at the number of develop developers who
contribute to a file or look at the
comments on the commits to see how
people are communicating with each other
so they're looking at indirect
indicators of human factors and then
they look at the publicly disclosed
vulnerabilities in the open source and
they basically make two piles of results
they take let's say Apache server
they'll say here are all the files that
have vulnerabilities in them to have at
least one vulnerability and over here
are all the files that have no
vulnerabilities so they have two piles
and then what they do is they try to
maximally discriminate between
- what are the unique characteristics of
this pile that have ulnar abilities
versus this pile over here that doesn't
and they start making imprints it's
based on that now the other type of
study and they're very few of these are
done in proprietary environments and it
may be that the way you develop in a
proprietary environment is different
than contributing to open source so
there's studies by Microsoft and ATT and
Nortel Microsoft has a human factors
group that studies these types of things
and I'll be referencing one of their one
of their present one of their published
papers what we are doing is we are now
under contract to the Defense Advanced
Research Projects Agency DARPA it's a US
government R&D organization they have a
three billion dollar a year budget and
they did invent the Internet
it's called ARPANET after DARPA it was
called opera at the time and so what
they've asked us to do is expand on this
body of research to start looking at
proprietary environments and also to
study human factors more directly so let
me tell you a little bit about how that
work is going to be done and is being
done so there are three different types
of approaches that we're taking what I'm
going to be talking about today is
mostly this first approach was a
retrospective analysis that basically
means a historical analysis of existing
software repositories issued trackers
basically resources and we're looking at
both open-source as well as proprietary
code repositories and when we do that we
look for these human factors indicators
in the repositories and then we
correlate those two measures of security
now if it's an open source repository we
can use publicly disclosed
vulnerabilities but for both open source
and for proprietary code bases we're
also using the results of static code
analyzers so basically fast findings
those are indicators of both code
quality as well as code security the
advantage of using them is that you can
apply it though
to open source and proprietary code
bases even compare also since we know
that vulnerabilities remain unreported
in open source for updated for on
average two years these weaknesses that
are found in the SAS tools may be
indicators of problems even if at
vulnerability has not been disclosed now
the other thing that we do with these
proprietary code bases is that we're not
just looking at the code repositories
but we'll work with an organization and
see what other kind of data they have do
they have information about the level of
experience of the developers or their
education and what in one case we have
timecard information and that tells us
how many hours the developer worked that
week and we can correlate excessive work
hours to code quality or security it
also tells us on the time cards how many
different tasks they build so are they
focused on one thing all day long or are
they constantly context switching
between different tasks now the second
type of analysis that we're doing is
concurrent analysis and that is where we
study developers as they code and we
start at this part of the research
program already although I don't have
results to report I hope to report it
next year so what the concurrent
analysis does is we instrument the
developers environment and we measure of
various human factors directly so they
sign on in the morning and we say good
morning how many hours of sleep did you
get last night and during the course of
the day two other times we asked them
about their subjective fatigue level we
also asked about interruptions what
they're listening to on their earphones
and how much communication they've had
with other members of the team so you
advance debate okay or I did okay so the
third type of approach is vulnerability
history analysis there this is also
fairly new we're taking vulnerabilities
that have been disclosed in open source
and we know that it was discovered over
here in time
over here in time and we go back in time
to see when was it originated what was
the originating commit that caused that
vulnerability and what we're doing is
we're looking at what were the factors
in play in that repository at the time
where there a whole bunch of people
introducing new features where there are
a lot of people everything a lot more
people where there's only one person in
the repo we're trying to figure out what
are the indicators of what might be wet
what are indicators of a vulnerability
being introduced we also go to the time
of the discovery to see if we can
determine what are the factors in play
that help facilitate the discovery of a
vulnerability so we'll hopefully have
results of that next year as well so
what we're trying to do is answer the
question can human factors predict code
quality and security and today we're
going to be telling you some of the
results of not only our research but
other research that's been done by
academia as well as by large companies
so the predictors here's a list of the
predictors these are various human
factors that we'll talk about today and
they are trying to we're trying to
correlate those with outcome measures
those outcome measures could be known
vulnerabilities that could be security
quality and security weaknesses in the
code could be bug frequency failure rate
so this is what we're trying to do
predictors and outcomes so what did we
find
a dramatic pause so let's start with a
question does is does quote this code
quality vary with teen location in other
words is there a difference between
teams that are co-located and teams that
are remotely distributed so Microsoft
studied this specifically and they
looked at the post release failures a
failure rates in Windows Vista and
office
and what do you think do you think that
collocation versus just distributed
teams makes a difference or no
difference the answer is no counter
intuitively the answer is no they looked
at all different types of distributed
teams they looked at teams that were in
the same building teams that were in
different buildings but shared the same
cafeteria teams in the same campus in
the same region they looked at teams
that were across continents there was no
difference there was a difference though
that explain the different failure rates
and it wasn't location and I'll tell you
about that in a few minutes so you can't
leave how about time today all right
this is something a particular interest
to me because actually my doctoral
dissertation was on circadian rhythm and
time of day and sleep deprivation and so
I was very interested in this and our
own research results are not yet final
but I could tell you that it does though
there is other research that indicates
that late-night commits have more bugs
than morning commits now why is that
well I have one theory and it's just a
theory and it has to do with circadian
rhythm take a look at that chart you may
all relate to that there is a human
condition circadian rhythm it's fairly
universal that says that there are
certain certain chemicals in your body
that increase starting at about 7:00 in
the morning they increase fairly
significantly until about noon about
2:00 p.m. they drop that is your siesta
time right a lot of you get tired around
2 o'clock that's why because their
changes in your body chemistry they then
go back up at about 3:00 and they they
stay up and so you stay alert until
about 9 o'clock 10 o'clock at night at
which point they start dropping
precipitously
and you can go into aviation accidents
and accidents at sea and you could you
could look at all kinds of accidents and
you will see far more of them at those
times when you have a circadian trough
and so that may explain this I'll take
one question if yeah I don't I want to
make sure we have enough time but if we
do with very very similar that's very
similar that's different that's when
you're in a cave when you're in a cave
when you're in a cave you have no
sunlight and so you don't have your body
doesn't have the feedback mechanism and
the actual normal cycle of a human body
is twenty five hours not twenty-four so
if you're put into a cave and you think
that you've counted the days by the time
you get to the twenty-fifth day you you
actually you have an extra day in there
right all right do people synchronize
yes yes they are mm-hmm by and large
which is why it's so difficult for night
workers to adjust there are some people
who can actually change their circadian
rhythms but they are in the minority
that's that's more personality driven
but you're still going to if you measure
the urine catecholamines you're gonna
see that these cycles are fairly
universal I just want to hold those
questions cuz I want to make sure the
Chris it gets time so okay remember
talked about indicators of human factors
so when you're looking at a software
repository you can't actually measure
somebody's attention but what we can do
is infer it and so there's something
that we use in this line of research
called unfocused contribution and it is
an indicator of how much attention
developers are focusing on specific
files so unconscious contribution goes
up when developers who are working on a
file are all
so busy modifying other files working
here the work in here the work in here
or a file has a lot of high unfocused
contribution when many developers are
modifying it so basically a file has
unfocused a high unfocused contribution
when it's not getting the direct
attention of just a few developers so
you think it makes a difference it does
yep there's more the more unfocused
contribution the more insecure the code
so we looked at chromium and Apache web
server files and remember those piles
the pile with the vulnerabilities and
the pile without the vulnerabilities
while the pile with the vulnerabilities
had a lot more unfocused contribution
now we also looked at static analysis
findings and we did this across four
repos to open source and to proprietary
and we found that there is a correlation
a significant correlation such that as
unfocused contribution goes up so to do
the number of static analysis findings
in both code quality and security number
of developers a lot of people say many
eyes make good security so we we measure
number of developers by the number of
developers that contributed to a file
based on the commit data I think it
makes a difference yep it sure does
remember that Microsoft studies that I
said there was one factor that was
directly related to the failure rates it
was number of developers it didn't
matter whether you were in two entirely
different contents that the team was
smaller they had fewer failure rates if
the team was bigger they had more
failure rates now we're finding this
um you know that's a very good question
I don't know what they did in in
Microsoft I could tell you that because
of that question we we asked theirs
ourselves in our own research the same
question what we are now doing is not
just measuring the total number of
static analysis findings we're actually
looking at defect density so that we are
normalizing for both lines of code and
churn so when we report our results next
year you're going to see density
measures so the age of the file I'm not
sure what Microsoft did but we actually
when we did our analyses last year we
did two years worth of data we did six
months worth of data pretty much that's
a lot of findings hold up even when
you're only looking at six months worth
of data so age of a file might have a
difference but it's probably lines of
code and if we normalized four lines of
code and in turn we should control four
we should be able to capture age so
let's take a look at what we found or
what others found Linux remember those
two piles those pile those those files
that had nine or more developers on them
were 16 times more likely to have a
vulnerability what about chromium 9 or
more developers 68 times web
Apache web server 117 topics okay
now we also looked at static analysis
findings and we looked at the for
repositories and we found that there is
a significant correlation the more
developers that are on a project the
more static analysis findings so what
might we what might be to play here we
don't know but one idea is something
called the bystander effect
you have only three people in a
situation if something happens you see
something you say something right well
you have a lot more people that's like
everybody else thinks that somebody else
is taking care of it right so that maybe
it's a psychological thing that happens
is social social psychologists study
this and it's called the bystander
effect so it looks pretty clear-cut but
this has some alternative evidence
that's right thanks Anita so not all the
research agrees so there's other
research that's been done that has not
found that correlation and so this first
one here is a study of four different
open source projects I forgot which I
think Postgres is in there and then
these two proprietary studies of
telephone software so AT&T is a big
telephone monopoly in the States and in
both of those cases they found that
quality which is basically false right
so that's a little different than
security and in the end bugs which is
this this middle one here did not have a
correlation of this good number of
developers and so one of the things that
we think could explain this is that
quality and security are likely
different right and so there's actually
a some research that's been done to look
to see whether quality measures and and
faults right mistakes crashes things of
that nature are the same as security and
the they're similar but different they
don't always overlap another one is
developer experience so who here thinks
that developer
relates to quality popular opinion yep
so and just one of the things here so
people weren't able to survey developers
in this research so one of the things
they do to measure the developer
experiences look at how long they've
been active in the codebase or in the
number of commits they have made to a
codebase right and and the research as
the developer as developers gain
experience they actually are looking as
they go so it's not like you lump all of
the developers commits over their entire
history right so when they have six
months of experience you're looking at
six months and when it's a year it's
here and in fact they did so Microsoft
found that the components that have
these more contributors have more minor
contributors have more more problems and
the minor contributors are basically
people who are making relatively small
amounts of commits relative to the total
commits to a file right so if you've got
100 developers contributing to a file
and most of those commits are from like
two or three three people right all
everybody else is gonna be a minor
contributor same thing in the study here
of Linux and Postgres I think we've got
one more here so what's that
yep Oh day job yes so that's where I'm
trying to remember the details of the
study now they looked at the commit
patterns I think they were using time of
day here so you can tell the difference
in especially the like Linux and
Postgres you can see time and tell you
differences in two different people's
contributions right so some people
contribute primarily at night and some
people contribute during the day and so
the people who are during the day are
more like you know IBM errs or Google
whose full-time job it is to contribute
to the kernel and that's different than
what you know people think of as the
prototypical open source developer who's
working on their spare
time right and so they actually found
that these people whose job it is
they're actually making more mistakes
and that's just that's interesting to us
because that's one of the reasons we
want to study both open source and
proprietary software right because we
think there might be differences in the
sort of fault patterns and human factors
that are at play right so people who are
working on their own time and of their
own volition is very different than
somebody who's doing it for their job
and there's different social incentive
structures and companies as well so
another thing here is it is the way that
developers interact and so you know
there are a lot of interpersonal
interactions that are not captured by
most development systems right so your
version control systems not keeping
track of if you had a meeting that day
or who you talk to or who you're
slacking with or anything like that but
we can do is we can see the editing
behavior in the files right so if we
have the same code in the file that's
getting modified by one person then a
different person than a different person
that's something that we call this
interactive churn so churn in general is
the idea of in a commit it's the changes
right it's basically the change set so
it's the lines of code that have been
modified added remove deleted right and
so the interactive churn is in that
commit those lines of codes that you
added modified or deleted that were last
touched by somebody else so if you're
familiar with the git blame command
that's one of the ways you can figure
this out and so do you think that
basically when developers are editing
other people's code do you think that's
associated with more problems or not
yeah that's right so and so what we've
seen in we saw it in this chromium and
chromium browser and the Apache web
server this is the two stacks of files
the ones with vulnerabilities in their
history and the ones without and so we
see that there are more in there is more
interactive churn and files that have a
vulnerability right
okay and then this we just thought was
interesting it's not I don't have any
correlation with outcome measures here
but one of the common interaction
patterns so this this paper that's cited
here and just for the reference all
these references are in the bottom of
our presentation so if you'd like to go
read the original research ask us we'll
give you a copy we've got links
citations to all our work but this this
researcher actually studied the patterns
by which vulnerabilities get is it
vulnerabilities or bugs I can't remember
all these papers are different bugs get
introduced and then how they get fixed
and the most common pattern here is
we're basically personai fixes it and
somebody else comes or introduces a
problem and another person comes in and
fixes it and that's one of the most
common patterns versus you know two
people introducing the same thing or the
same person fixing your own problem
later basically takes the second set of
eyes to fix things usually and so this
final section of the presentation is
where we can draw lessons from non
software domains so that's all the
things that neither I just covered are
things that have been studied more in
the context of software engineering here
we've got some slides about human
factors and how they have been accounted
for in other fields right and so we're
gonna look at mostly transportation
medicine and occupational safe and
health and safety so that's like on the
workplace and things like that and the
first one here is fatigue and so this is
one of the most well known well studied
causes of human error right it's just
well known to degrade human performance
after about 17 hours of being awake
which is emitted Li a pretty long time
your performance on a number of tasks
and there's a battery of tests that
people run but your performance drops to
about the point where you're close to
being the legal limit for intoxicated
for alcohol in the United States right
you're basically drunk and basically
these two fields these there's a lot of
words here but in medicine and
transportation the take-home message
here is that both of those fields have
limited the amount of
hours you can work in a day to about 11
hours right they don't let you work more
than that you it is against the law to
drive a truck for more than 11 hours of
your commercial trucker if you're a grad
student in med school you're not allowed
to work more than 80 hours in a week
which works out to about 11 hours a day
right because after that point your
performance just plummets and it's
correlated with really bad outcomes in
medical contexts which looks like people
dying also experience oh and so what I
wanted to do was say here was that you
know in software engineering you know we
don't necessarily have caps on how how
much developers can work right but maybe
we should be thinking about that maybe
we should not be you know hero wising be
you know the long you know all-night
marathons right maybe that's not such a
good idea from a security standpoint and
experience in qualification so maybe we
need from a software engineering
standpoint we need to get a lot more
serious about looking at the
qualifications and certifications of
engineers right so professional
engineers is a is a proper title in the
states and you know in order to be
granted that title you have to go to a
bunch of school you have to apprentice
under somebody who's done something you
then have to take companies six teams
and you have to maintain continuing
education and it works very much the
same in a lot of sort of regulated and
violence right like medicines do the
same way it could have just as well been
like you know what it takes to become a
doctor and even no lawyer to some degree
and in the federal government there are
a lot of job qualifications and
requirements just to hold the job you
need to have a lot of certifications and
accreditation in order to be allowed to
perform the job so maybe we need to be
thinking about what is minimum education
for software engineering and security
and then this last one culture and so if
you were on the last session I think she
didn't Allison did from screen did a
really great job talking about this but
culture actually matters a lot and so
creating a safety or a security culture
is is often when you talk I talked to a
bunch of CEOs in my line of work I've
did a study where I talked to a large
number of security practitioners and you
find them basically working within their
to create with basically our security
cultures and they don't always talk
about it in those ways right but raising
awareness and creating shared values and
having everybody on the same page is a
culture and in medical contexts these
types of safety cultures have been
linked with the outcomes in the medical
field so the first is an intensive care
unit here and the second is at a
hospital and ten hospitals so in the
first one they looked across these
intensive care units and they have this
survey that's been you know deemed
reliable to measure the safety culture
of that ICU and when you look across all
the different eyes to use you can
correlate those safety culture scores
with patient outcomes
so complications and deaths and in the
hospitals basically they did this
intervention took two years but they
were able to shift the culture and that
was associated with improved outcomes
where the culture is shifted so cultural
change is slow right it's not something
that happens it's changing people's
opinions and beliefs takes basically at
least a year right but this is something
that we should probably be paying
attention to so with that I'm going to
turn it back to Anita thanks Chris so
let's wrap up we really believe that
there is a need for research into the
human factors that affect code quality
and security and we are looking for
teams especially proprietary teams that
would like to participate in this
research we're looking for code bases
proprietary code bases that we could
study ideally if you have information
about the developers or teams or the
environment that would be very helpful
or if you're interested in working with
us we can work with you to figure out
what are the human factors that your
organization is interested in and then
we could figure out a way of
instrumenting or collecting that data
and come up with with some actual
empirical evidence to determine whether
or not those human factors make a
difference and then if we do find
differences what do you do with it
so what we're really trying to do is
study things that are actionable that is
that if if we find something like number
of developers or number of hours worked
that you can actually do something and
change the work environment to
facilitate a more secure code
environment culture but you also can use
this information to look for
vulnerabilities in code so what have we
learned today where would you start
hunting for vulnerabilities based on
what I present it code committed after
midnight probably it very well may be
buggy if not have security weaknesses
files with unfocused contribution
attention these are where multiple
developers have contributed to many
other files right that's basically what
it is files with nine or more developers
files where contributors had little
experience in the codebase we sometimes
call these drive-by committers and also
files with high levels of interactive
churn so that's our presentation would
be happy to field questions
[Applause]
Richard I know you have a question well
done both of you um one of the the areas
that I believe strongly in that should
be studied and that can make a huge
impact or an you touched on it but the
culture you know what about what about
areas for example where mistakes are
frowned upon where creativity is stifled
what about cultures where the
application team and the security team
are interacting and working well
together
what about cultures where a company is
pushing get it out get it out I don't
care right these things are probably
more impactful than any of those but
they're harder to change because that's
from the top down and so I'd be curious
actually I'd love to see a study that we
can then take to the c-suite and say we
have a problem here but what can we do
to improve the culture mm-hmm I just I'd
want to get on my hobby horse so if
anybody would like to partner with us to
have you have us in your organization
and work with you to measure culture so
culture is a difficult thing to measure
because it's really know one thing it's
about a thousand of them but you know
there are survey instruments they've
been validated to measure security
safety culture we might be able to adapt
them for security and we're very
interested and we have the funding right
now to do that kind of work with
organizations and but yeah I think it's
got a lot of promise and it's difficult
to measure but I think it's be very good
to demonstrate you know scientifically
that it's correlated or causal one of
the things that we can do is look at
feature density like you could almost
see in a repository as you roll up to a
release as are there more features is
the rate at which features are being
added does that affect the quality and
post-security
so that that would be something that we
could look at in a repository but I'm
gonna live in myself to to to what
extent do you make this the distinction
between you know security bugs or
these versus real exploitable bugs yeah
so the everybody had heard the question
can you Mike
so I believe I mean the best of my
knowledge of vulnerability is
exploitable so CVE has been demonstrated
as an exploitable problem and that's how
that's part of the process of becoming
labeled as a CD mmm I would say that not
necessarily the case I mean you might
have a dependency for example that has a
CV attached to it but oh you're talking
about in your organization so if you're
using a library let's say that has a
published phoner ability or a security
bug that's not exploitable by saves so
for example if you have a security bug
in your website but that functionality
is not necessarily you know exploding I
know yeah so that that's a note that
that's true and I would say from a
research standpoint there's not the
manpower and time to go through and
manually verify every single
vulnerability and so what we're using
are some degree proxy measures right so
the number of static analysis findings
is not a perfect measure of security of
code right but it is a measure and it's
a repeatable measure and so it's
probably it's better than nothing is
what argument I understand the
challenges but yeah so and the second
question is so most of the samples like
code samples you use that is Postgres
chromium windows they are developed in
low-level memory unsafe languages I was
curious to what extent to take into
account also like kind of programming
language types of programming languages
we yeah there there has been research
done in to look at the effective
programming language on the security of
the code and they found some
correlations I would say they're not
super strong so they found generally
that the conclusion the paper reached
was that typed languages were stronger
but it wasn't always true fandom if I
went on my reading of the data so it's
it's a it's a bit of a mixed bag I don't
think it's a strong predictor thank you
very much very useful and great here
last question so I wanted to point out
that we have references if you wanted to
you want a copy of the presentation you
could do that and this is our contact
information
so if you want to copy the presentation
with the references or you want to
discuss possibly participating either by
offering a proprietary code repository
or by offering a development team please
contact either Kris horn or or me and we
would be happy to continue the
conversation I hope you found it useful
[Applause]