hello everyone and thank you very much
for coming to this session about the
composing security vulnerabilities a
show of hands how many of you implement
security in your company or no company
that implements security in order to
comply with regulations and this is the
current state at the moment the security
is perceived as a checkbox and it is
there primarily for compliance
regulations reasons we develop policies
that contains various vulnerabilities
each company is interested to comply
with most commonly use are the author's
top 10 which is the most most cited
document and it's a little bit both a
blessing and the curse especially since
it was picked by PCI DSS as a standard
which is not and then we develop these
policies that contain all the our top 10
because why not put them all and then we
run applications from very various tools
static analysis dynamic analysis to see
how those applications are against these
policies and then we get the reports and
the reports are sent to the applications
security teams and then the live
developers so how many of you are from
the application security team and how
many of you are developers so you both
have been on this side when you get now
you have large reports with lots of
flaws that needs to be resolved in order
to comply with the new policies and this
becomes a problem in particular in
companies where there is a security gate
and developers cannot develop deploy
their software
until those flows have been resolved and
this is the problem when the focus
shifts a little bit so instead of
actually focusing on the actual security
of the application the focus is on
making this flows disappears from the
report so developers can I can go and
release their selves here and this is
when I get questions like my application
is behind the firewall why do I have to
fix the SQL injection or sometimes I
have fixed the cross-site scripting I
have actually added a filter that looks
for the word for the tag script so it's
a shift now in actual in in order to get
rid of these vulnerabilities and have
the software release so they can focus
on their what they like the most
fixing the flaws and the problem is that
today we still develop a high large of
insecure applications and injection is
still king and this is the current state
in the law in the latest OS top 10 2017
injection is still in pole position at
number one and we have known about these
vulnerabilities for over 20 years the
SQL injection was first mentioned in
1998 in frag magazine the term of
cross-site scripting has been coined by
Microsoft in 1999 so we know about these
vulnerabilities for over 20 years so the
question is is there anything else that
we can do because if we continue on the
same route and we do the same thing like
we've done until now we are at the risk
of talking about injection for the next
20 years a little bit about myself Who
am I and why am I talking to you today
my name is Katie Anton I come from a
software development background and this
is when I got involved into the our top
10 proactive controls which is a project
for developer by developers which should
be included in every software
development project I currently work as
application security consultant at
Veracruz where I advise application
security teams and developers around the
world to secure their software in most
companies the security posture is
measured using the cwe's which stands
for common weakness enumeration in this
kind of a standard in most companies so
this is a formal list which is which is
a way to May which describes the
software security of weaknesses which
have been introduced in the software at
architecture and design stage and during
the code development and this is what
all of these are software security
weaknesses and they have been analyzed
for a long period of time
classified organized there is a very
nice classification on Nvidia website of
all of this and I will start my analysis
with the most common category of
vulnerabilities which is injection now
the injection is still the most common
vulnerability found in software
applications today as a Catterick
category it contains multiple types of
injections and you have command
injection cross-site scripting code
injection XML injection LDAP injection
SQL injection just to name a few
injections and if we go a little bit
further in details in all in each of
these then you can have a further
classification of all of these
injections for example this is a
classification of the SQL injection only
now you don't need to spend much time
looking on this graph but the point that
I'm trying to make is that and now we
are asking developers to think of all of
this type of injections when they write
the code and that's not possible for
there because their focus is on writing
the functionality
so no wonder that we are still talking
about injections today so the question
is is there anything else that we can do
can we look in another way at all of
these if we go back to the injection and
we just go to a very simple definition
of what the injection is just the basic
very basic one the injection occurs when
you have some type of data which is then
combined with a sort of a syntax that a
result is then sent through a parser and
that's when it ends up being executed as
code so the data which is not only from
get impose but also from a wide variety
of sources like HTTP headers file
uploads configuration files data from
the database so when taken from all
these variety of sources is combined
with the sort of a syntax that result is
sent to a parser and when we want to
store the data into the database we send
that result to the SQL person when
sending it when rendering a webpage we
send that result to an HTML parser or
the browser and that's when we end up
with that data being executed as part of
the code I would like to take this view
in order to focus more on the red part
the output where we end up with a curl
with that data executed as code and I'm
going to flip it so in the case of the
SQL injection we have the data which is
combined with the SQL query that is sent
to the SQL parser and that's when we end
up with the injection the best defense
for this is to promote rise the data
before sending it to the parser and this
is the primary control data prompt
ization but
defensing that we still have to validate
the input the input validation helps to
prevent a vulnerabilities that a
developer might not be aware of at the
time of writing the code a good example
for this is the second-order SQL
injection which is the injection where
the injection payload is recorded and
stays dormant in the database until it
finds the right environment to be
exploited so that's why we need both of
these controls the primary defense and
the defense in the input validation in
the case of the cross-site scripting we
need to contextually encode the output
to neutralize the characters that can
trigger the code injection but as in
fencing that we still have to validate
the input and similarly for XML
injection code injection LDAP injection
and command injection so rather than
focusing off on all type of injections
which can be overwhelming on develop for
developers and definitely I know from my
experience that it cannot be done when
they are writing their code what we can
do instead is to focus on these
techniques which are familiar to them
and as a primary defense we should
always parametrize the data if that's
not possible then contextual inker to
neutralise the characters that can
trigger the injection and thus defense
in that we still have to validate the
input the best point to family the input
is when your data entered the
application in order to effectively
reduce the attack surface for example in
the case of an MVC framework the best
point of all the data is in the
controller that's where the data enters
the application the next category of ICH
flows offending to tackle our intruder
or better said or better said the lack
of intrusion detection the problem today
in most applications is that
auditable events like logging fair
Logging's
high-level transactions are not logged
if there is any type of logging in place
then the format is not consistent enough
in order to allow the operations teams
do you centralize all these logs
automatically produces in order to get
some meaningful information intrusion
information within a reasonable amount
of time
so the problem boiled primarily to two
things one is the what is locked and the
second one is the content the format of
the logs to put it simply if a pen
tester is able to get into into a system
without being detected this is a good
indication that that application or API
does not have enough it's not it does
not have enough intrusion detection
mechanism so the question is can
developer do something about this
for this we have the security control
which is the security logging this is a
control that developers can use in order
to log security information during the
runtime operation of an application
according to the auspices of a very good
project it has two parts one is the
document a tool and another one is the
documentation and this is what I'm going
to focus on as part of this presentation
so according to the absences they're
considered six types of detection points
which are good attack identifiers and
these are authentication and
authorization failures client-side input
validation bypasses widely validation of
failures obviously code injection
attacks like for example when you have
obvious SQL injection payloads or
cross-site scripting payloads and a high
rate of function years when you have a
high number of page requests in a very
short period of time so let's go a
little bit through
more in detail in some of these to have
a better understanding of what exactly I
mean now in the case of the request if
an application expects to receive post
but instead is receives yet these are
very good indication that somebody has
intentionally intercepted that
communication and has intentionally
changed from post to get this is a type
of anomaly exception that should be
locked again if the application receives
extra or form or URL parameters a good
example of this and something that a pen
tester will all make almost every time
do is to add the buggy code equal true
if this extra form or URL parameters are
detected on the server side of the
validation this is another type of
exception that should be logged in the
case of authentication if the
application expects to receive for
example two parameters username and
password but instead it receives only
one of them the username because the
password has been removed that's another
type of exception that should be logged
again if the application expects to
receive if the application receives
extra parameters during authentication
and something that a Pentastar again
will try to do is admin equal true to
see if he can escalate privileges if
this is detected this is a another type
of exception that should be logged in
the case of input now if the validation
on the server side fails despite the
fact that there is a validation on the
client side a very simple example of
this you have a form
in one of the HTML forms it has an HTML
attribute of maximum length however when
that string reaches the server it is
greater than the length defined on the
client-side now this is a very good
indication that you have that since that
data has left the client where we had
the maximum length behind somebody has
intercepted that communication
intentionally changed that string when
it and then sent it to the server side
so this is a type of exception that the
gain should be logged or another one is
when the validation on the server side
fails for known editable user fields
like hidden field checkboxes radio
buttons a good example for this is your
honor ecommerce website and on the
shopping basket if there is a hidden
field there for the price that's a very
tempting for somebody to start playing
weight and if the value of that field is
when received on the server is not the
one that it is expected that's another
example of a high value transactions
where that anomaly should be logged so
these are just what we are actually
doing we are just ensuring that the
server it receives what it expects to
receive but by putting these exceptions
into place what we are actually doing
into the application we give the
software the mechanisms to respond to
this possible identified attacks
and reduce them or even stop them
depending of how it is respond to this
when we do the coding so if we are to
recap a basic workflow is that every
time we have data entering our
application which is validate it and
does not only from get in post but also
from configuration files database and
exceptions should be locked any output
should be contextually encoded and every
time we send data to the database we
should prompt rise the queries so this
is a basic workflow that not only that
will prevent a large portion of the
injections but also give the server
disability to respond in real-time to
this possible identified attacks the
ones that we have identified and we have
chosen to respond in a manner to them
another type of category that I will
tackle is the sensitive data exposure
and for this is about the data above the
at rest and in transit now when it comes
to date on anything ensure the
confidentiality the data cannot be spied
on integrity the data cannot be changed
and availability there are several types
of data depending of the type so when we
have data at rest then we have the type
of data where we need the initial value
like crackers this must be encrypted
then you have the data will still have
the storage but you don't need to note
the initial value like for example the
user password Disney this must be hashed
and then you have these entrances which
must be encrypted over a secure Channel
when it comes to encrypted data
oppressed a challenging powerful
developers is to actually store securely
the key that is used to encrypt data and
this is an example of from an
application and that we discovered
during a code review where in a folder
in the same folder we had to
files in one of them we had the
encrypted password which we kind of
guess what the encrypted password
contained and the other one always
contain was entities and when opened it
contain a seed assault and iteration
which turned out to be used in
conjunction with the password-based key
derivation function to to generate the
key that was used to encrypt the data so
to put it simply in the same folder we
had both the encrypted data and also
everything that you need to do in order
to generate that team happy days for
everyone getting access to that folder
and this was a new application where the
team has tried to come up with their own
homegrown solution of storing the case
which is definitely something that you
shouldn't do so when it comes to data at
rest when you need to encrypt it the
best cryptographic algorithm out there
is there a yes but it is important to
store the key away from the encrypted
data stay away from the homegrown
solutions because is so easy so easily
can go wrong and use dedicated key
management solutions but it's also
important to define a key life cycle and
we need to have in place a mechanism to
replace those keys because if the game
has been compromised then you need to do
that one anyway so it's better to have
in advance define the process so when
this happen you know exactly how to do
it and you have it to document it as
well when it comes to they then transit
we are getting pretty good at sending
the data encrypted over a secure channel
between the client and the application
server in particular thanks to let's
encrypt we are getting pretty good at
this one
these days but you still have a problem
between the communication behind the
firewall like for example between the
application servers and other non
browser components like the database and
this is where we have to improve as well
so ideally when you transfer the data it
should be over a secure Channel
throughout including behind the firewall
and the legs the next type of
vulnerabilities that I will tackle is
the third-party components or using
components with known vulnerabilities we
are getting pretty good and there are
lots of tools out there to check for
vulnerabilities in software components
and open source of their components but
the problem that I see from the
discussions with developers is actually
doing something about that list you end
up with a pretty long list of all type
of vulnerabilities and that's why it's
the problem are actually doing something
about it and the type of software that
has this problem problems is the type of
software that no developer wants to
touch because he's afraid that if he
touches in one part something will break
so it is it to break you might do one
change in one bit but you don't know
where it will break it's difficult to
test as a result of all of these
problems nobody wants to go there and do
any upgrades and all of these lead to
technical debt so the bottom line is
that all of these issues are because of
application that have a high level of
technical debt or design in some cases
legacy applications which there are
there are companies where they have
quite a large proportion of these so
what can we do about this before
answering this question I'm going to
introduce another concept and this is
the attack surface which the attack
surface as a simple definition is the
sum of the total points
through which a malicious actor can
enter data into or extract data from a
system and in security we have a very
simple principle which is whenever we do
we need to minimize this attack surface
so this is the entire purpose of this
and that's what you should do we should
achieve to do as well when in bringing
it's there no libraries so I'm going to
take three examples of the scenario of
these three components one of them is an
open source library like a locking
library which is something that
developer would almost never time do
their logging is something that they
were bringing another example is
offender API because again these are
external component and despite the fact
that is a partner we have to remember
that these days there is a trend where
rather than attacking the main target
the hackers choose to attack a vendor a
partner of the main target so we need to
treat this one as an external component
as well and now the next example is when
you're bringing another library from
another team within the same company and
this happens a lot in large companies
where you have one library that is then
used through multiple applications so
I'll start with the first example when
bringing in a logging library this
usually because it is ready-made it has
a large number a wealth of functionality
and highly likely that your application
is not going to need the entire
functional LT to be used in the case of
logging you move you are likely to use
only three levels like debug warning
info so for this scenario when you want
to exposing your software only a set of
the functionality and you want to hide
unwanted behavior a good design pattern
is a simple wrapper what this allows you
is so if there is data flowing through
that one having this wrapper this
interface it helps you
control the data that you expose and if
there is a vulnerability then you know
exactly what we expose into your
software and at that point at the
interface points you have that one point
where you can put extra controls if
needs be but also very importantly so
this is a way to reduce the attack
surface that's that's one of the
benefits also very importantly this is a
design pattern that helps you to easier
great or even replace obsolete libraries
without much penalty the other example
that I'm going to look into is a vendor
API and for this I'm going to consider
the case of a payment gateway which is
common with in e-commerce applications
and it's highly likely that in an
e-commerce application you're going to
have more than one payment gateway so
for this this this this scenario also it
is you have several partners and each of
them have their own endpoint highly
likely your application will have its
own transactional method so for this
scenario when you need to convert from
the provided interface to the required
interface a good software design pattern
is the adapter design pattern this helps
to convert from the provided interface
so whatever the corner endpoints are to
what your software needs also you can
have multiple oddities at the same time
so it's easy to switch between them so
if a partner becomes bridge then this
will allow you to you quickly get into
control of your software and remove that
problem and the third example that I
will give is the scenario when you you
use in your software a library that has
been developed by another company by
another thing within the same company a
good example for this is the single
sign-on which is quite commonly used in
many applications this day and it can be
quite complex so this package can get
quite
quite cumbersome and quite complex so
for this scenario when you actually need
to simplify the interaction between a
complex subsystem and your own one you
can use the facility design pattern now
what this this is a very good one as
well for legacy applications it
simplifies this interaction between your
own software and a complex subsystem so
you can use it as well for legacy
applications and it's again another type
of design pattern where the sate gives
it at one point where you can control
and you can see what's exactly exposing
to your software and it helps you out
with the upgrade so if we are to recap a
secure software starts from the design
from the point that you have to who's
and how you're going to bring assist a
library a package into your own software
from that point the security of the
software start so you can use a simple
wrapper when you want to expose into
your software a set of functionality and
you want to hide unwanted behavior then
you can use the adapter design pattern
when you want to change from the
provided interface to the required
interface and the facade for come up for
legacy applications I think it's worth
pointing as well that this work very
well on the server side which where you
can actually hide functionality they
would not apply on the client side the
last one that I would like to tackle is
the environment configuration and we see
more and more of these so we can as
developer tackle this one during
development during deployment and of the
release now during development ideally
you'd have a developer you use the same
users as in production for example the
database user that is used in the
development environment it should have
the same permissions as in the
production connection and the
application user used on the development
environment should have again the same
permission
and ideally should be a dedicated one so
if your application should access
certain folders using only for example
read permission which would apply to a
configuration files for example then
this should be in the development
environment as well as in production so
they should replicate as well in the
production during deployment we should
ensure that these permissions still
apply and for companies oh this can be
achieved today using infrastructure as
good but if this is not available
because it's not that modern application
we can still achieve the same thing
using a set of bash script for four
critical parts of the system that we
want to check the configuration for and
again after the release ideally you'd
adopt a configuration manager and ensure
that you provide the scanning and
continuous scanning across all the
servers to ensure that the configuration
is still preserved in place so rather
than what I'd like you to take away is
that rather than focusing on these cwe's
because at the end all of these cwe's
are software security weaknesses which
we can measure only after the software
has been developed let's focus instead
on the security controls that prevent
them are familiar to developers and they
can be used from the beginning and also
in order to be to be effective dish this
should be in place every single time so
we cannot say that we validate this data
but we con validate that one we're not
going to validate it ideally it should
be for every data that enters the
application and both of them should be
used like the primary controls our
defense in that in a consistent manner
because we have to remember that an
attacker needs one floor to bring down a
system as defenders we have to defend
everything and that's why it's important
to using consist
also I think we need to verify for them
that one they have been put in place but
they have been put in place in a correct
manner to be effective in preventing the
software security weaknesses so every
time the data enters the application we
should validate it and not only from
getting post but also from data from the
database configuration files and other
sources any exceptions that we get
during the validation should be locked
to give the software the mechanisms to
respond in real-time to the possible
identified attack is the ones that we
have identified any output should be
contextually encode it and any time we
store data into the database we should
price the queries if we need to access a
command on a system ideally you would
leave that one as a last resource
because sometimes you can achieve the
same thing using other methods like a
library but if you really really need to
access an operating system command then
you should prom tries the data every
time we bring in a new library not only
an open source library but also from a
vendor an API from a vendor partner or a
library from another team within the
same company we should choose a software
design pattern that helps to reduce the
attack surface and also it helps in the
long term to easy upgrade those
components to actually stay on top of
the technical debt any time we store the
data we store we in third data we need
to store the encryption key away from
the encrypt
data in dedicated key management
solutions and every time we transfer
data it should be done via list not only
on the public facing but also behind the
firewall and we should ensure that our
configuration is the same that we
intended in adopted configuration
management and have this continuous
scanning of the servers across the
network in order to detect any miss
configurations and remediate remediate
them now if you are if any of you is
looking to improve the security of their
own applications these are some security
controls that can help you with that and
because there are security techniques
that are familiar to developers it's
also easier to achieve compliance a
developer is highly likely to state that
that flow cannot be exploited it happens
to me all the time
but isn't likely to say that they cannot
validate or they cannot promote rise
once they have been shown how to do it
correctly even more you can actually
involve them and have them check between
themselves this can be done during the
cloud review peer code review to ensure
that these basic security controls are
in place and are okayed and are
implemented correctly this allows you as
an object person to free you up of time
so you can focus on on other more
complex security issues and this is just
a way to handle things you don't need to
stop here because for example if you
want your policy to to change it and you
want to have added to it a new
vulnerability for example the newly the
new entry of the OS obtained which
the a4 XML external entity or in other
words the CBE 611 now the security
control for that one is to harden the
XML parser so you can add that security
control to the list for developers of
what they need to do and you can have
that one added as well in your policy
and hopefully using these of focusing on
the security controls will help us and
not to have the injection still in poor
position in the next master thing thank
you very much and there is definitely
example questions I've got a microphone
for somebody who wants to ask a question
up front thank you I was trying to to
see the relevance of validating the
input that the data comes from the
database shouldn't the data beyond the
trust second base or DC be the database
is a device on your network private no
network in most of the cases but you
don't know who is on a private network
so I'm also a spirit a leader and we
have people from red team's their
feedback which do ethical high-tech
their feedback is once they get into a
company's network the security controls
are minimal and we have had breaches for
this the most famous one is the Marriott
data breach where the attacker has been
on the network for over four years you
don't want to be that company where the
attacker has been there for four years
and your software was not able to
respond to these type of things so that
would be that's why is not considered
usually trusted
yeah but but it's already on the
database you have greater problems right
I mean if it has data or he has asked
its to the database or can change the
data in the database you have bigger
problems than the input in the
application right so for example a good
example of actually validating the data
for the database when you actually use
the the data to create dynamic queries
SQL commands where you have that data in
two locations which cannot be premised
so that's why you need to find related
because if that happens then you don't
know how they that that data is used and
unless you actually do a risk analysis
what happens and you are no eyes the
entire software where that data from the
database is used because if it's used on
other connecting to other devices that's
when you are going to have the problem
so you my my that's one of the problems
you consider trusted don't trust
anything just put the security controls
every time because in this way we just
make it more difficult for the attackers
we are never going to get a 100% secure
system but it's just put them off of
hacking a system and another question
we've got time for one more I think and
if not then I'm gonna say thank you
thanks Katie