the content that's canary great the top
today unlikely allies how hey char
coming in how hey char can build help
you build a security first culture first
of all thank you so much for coming to
this I know that it's a bit of a hard
sell actually hey char at a security
conference so bear with me and I'll let
you decide at the end of the session
whether actually my discipline can bring
anything to yours okay and feel free to
vote publicly on the interwebs about
whether or not I have things to help to
start with Who am I you might have
realized this isn't your typical
security talk there's gonna be a lot of
audience participation
okay great my name is Alison I'm the
head of people at a company called
screen has anyone here heard of screen
fabulous that's very exciting
two out of 40 if that's great okay no
worries we'll get to that
um today I look after hiring and human
resources for a team of about sixty
people okay in parison in San Francisco
I am neither French nor American does
anyone know where I'm from oh yeah you
just show you gonna be quick yeah thank
you
pick the accent I've tried hard to get
rid of it but it just sticks okay come
on in so indeed I am Alison I am
Australian I am from a suburb called
cherry Brook who here has been to Terry
Brooke nobody of course nobody has been
to cherrybrook cherrybrook is a very
tiny suburb in the northwest of Sydney I
spent the first 15 years of my life
there how many convinced that nothing of
any consequence would ever happen to me
okay so that's Terry Brooke for you
gives you a lot of time to imagine
things okay
to basically work a curious mind I left
home at 18 I traveled the world I ended
up in France about eight years ago and
I've been working for screen for about a
year and a half so what is screen screen
is security without the hassle okay we
do application security management ok
app sick I don't think I need to go much
further given where we are if you're
curious about it however feel free to
ask me have a look on the internet
afterwards so why is the HR person
talking at a security conference any
ideas
because it's important this is it I like
this I like there's last-minute addition
with the right answers this is what we
like to see ok this is important HR is
important ok yeah why else ok people are
what ok ok absolutely the key part yeah
why else ok to enforce did use the word
enforce I will come back to that I like
it yeah in front that's that's why I got
into this gig to enforce things perfect
yeah also maybe just not enough speaker
applications this year right little bit
thin on the grounds or pen testers yeah
something like that something like that
so I wasn't sort of born to be an HR
person right I didn't so those you know
run out of high school saying you know
let me at those hills tennis homes and
payroll and you know hiring people all
the time that's going to be exciting
actually don't have a passion for HR as
such my friends and colleagues often say
to me hey house and well you're the head
of people you must really love people
right wrong I actually don't like people
very much at all but I am fascinated by
them ok what keeps me in my job is
trying to understand all of the small
tiny intricate combination of things
that motivate people to do the things
they do and they do a lot of things
right you've seen some things I imagine
the people have done right yeah why
whether that's to do with consequences
or the judgment of others coming in or
whether they do things for personal gain
or a moral obligation my life's work is
basically to understand why and
therefore to help predict and maybe
shape some of those behaviors for a very
young age I've been observing power
structures around me and trying to find
out where the boundaries are I mentioned
I grew up in chery chery Brook is a very
small suburb outside of Sydney and in
1989 my sister and I with my parents
moved into a house in a streets that was
just dirt okay
Australia compared to European countries
we went from dirt to bitumen we didn't
go through the cobblestones okay can
imagine my shock when I arrived in
Europe sort of eight years ago what are
these things okay so basically we let my
sister and I you grew up in this fairly
quiet street you were more likely to
cross a horse coming in without a rider
than you were to cross a car so my
sister and I were allowed to ride our
bikes out the front of our house while
mum was inside doing something else but
we had lines on our driveway three
segments Pebble Creek the second line
was the limit okay we're allowed to ride
our bikes as much as we liked as long as
we didn't go across that second line now
there are lots of different types of
people in this world my sister is a rule
follower okay succeeds very well in
traditional environments okay excellent
at academics does the right thing okay
very important to her that she does the
right thing so if the line was here my
sister would say I could have me two
back from it to make sure she didn't
accidentally touch the line with a bike
tyre me on the other hand at the age of
two I was always fairly convinced that
this line might have been a concert not
actually a boundary and so I would ride
my bike tricycle at the time up to it
and just kiss the line with my bike tire
and then I would wait I noticed that
nothing actually happened and so the
next time I would go just a centimetre
over the line same thing the earth went
on turning and so apparently I abandoned
this inch-by-inch iteration and one day
just abandoned the tricycle and went and
sat in the middle of the road my sister
ran inside to see my mom is hidden yeah
mommy mommy Ali's in the road
so quite reasonably - my older sister
why didn't you get her out for my sister
said well because I'm not allowed to
pass that line I was punished it was the
late 80s I was smacked which I
rightfully deserved sent to my room and
told that it was okay we didn't have to
tell my dad my sister had also been
breached bribed and told that I'd been
punished and we didn't have to tell my
dad dad gets home from his day of work
at the bank I started to understand
something I've understood that actually
maybe I'm not the one who risks to be in
the most trouble here but something else
is at play
so when dad walks in the door I
triumphantly scream from the top level
of our of our house I've been on the
road today daddy what Institute was a
fairly loud discussion between my
parents and from that day on I kind of
understood that maybe you know there are
different things that play than just the
rules that parents give their children
so so I got into HR basically if you
here already works closely like day to
day with their hate our team anyone okay
excellent on something other than
recruitment yeah okay excellent
what are you working with your HR teams
on security awareness excellent all
right you're gonna be able to teach us
some things I think okay okay great old
structures onboarding yeah what else
email attachment analysis so that's hey
char saying hey we got a thing can you
check it out yeah absolutely that's a
good good point okay perfect
I think things basically so actually
most of you didn't raise your hands
right do you know who your HR teams are
yeah do you know how to find them right
you're working security light you can
find anyone yeah okay perfect if you had
to write you could track them down
perfect by the end of the talk I hope
I've convinced you to go and like have a
conversation with them for me I think
there are three reasons why security and
HR teams can learn from each other and
probably should work more closely
together the first one is because we're
basically doing the same job
okay hear me out
HR and software engineering and HR and
security actually isn't all that
different
my main job today is to design systems
and processes and architect
organizations hoping for predictable
repeatable results that can scale ok not
unlike the job of a software engineer
except when your architecture
architecting backends of applications
you usually don't have to keep in mind
the hidden agendas of your AWS machines
for example ok when you're architecting
for people totally different ballgame
ok Everett youyou can predict about 10
percent of what people will do in a
system which is fun one of the things
that makes HR people really successful
is their ability to see around corners
to predict edge cases to anticipate and
mitigate risks and always always prepare
for the worst-case scenario
ok if that sounds familiar basically it
makes us good at our jobs and really
average to talk to our parties anything
more is just soar the same yet that DJ
plays that next so things are going
really terribly I'm out of here
the second reason I think that you
should speak to your HR team regularly
if you work in security is as you
mentioned security it's a people problem
right ok and hey char understands people
the weakest link in any system the human
factor who here has a good definition
for social engineering who has a
definition for social engineering let's
not set the bar too high it's early yeah
[Music]
ok all right I like it manipulating
people to do things potentially things
that are illegal or things that are not
allowed absolutely a nice definition I
like for social engineering is the at or
better yet the science it's still
skillfully maneuvering human beings to
take action in some area of their life
this is literally my job description ok
the next time I'm hiring for my team I'm
just literally going to put that
sentence and say who does this ok who's
good at this I spend my days convincing
candidates that actually working for a
series a startup in
is much better than working for any
other company anywhere in the world okay
I convinced my managers that maybe
changing the way they want to
communicate for a way that would be
effective to communicate is a great idea
I sometimes plant seeds of ideas in
leaders heads so that a couple of months
later when they come out with a great
new initiative it is the thing that we
should do another thing they maybe first
wanted to do and then I try and
understand how people in the team
respond to praise versus feedback versus
reward the skills required to be
effective in HR are very similar to the
skills required to be an effective
social engineer what's the difference
between HR and social engineers
oh nice the intention yeah that's a very
that's a very diplomatic way to put it
absolutely what I've written on my slide
here is one uses that power for good but
I won't tell you which okay nice we know
that social engineering by its very
nature encourages users to step outside
of a normal process or procedure okay so
it's not that we didn't have a process
or procedure it's that we manage to
circumvent it in listing hey try to help
you understand and predict specifically
what might motivate person a or person B
to deviate from that system can be
helpful does some of you may be familiar
with the phishing attack where basically
a woman calls up trying to change the
password on her husband's mobile phone
account and place crying sounds of
babies in the background okay
so understanding who would be
susceptible but which sort of
manipulation is something that HR is
pretty good at we will for example in my
daily life if I need to have a difficult
conversation with one of the engineers
and there is myself our director of
engineering our CTO and co-founder
available to do that conversation what
will choose who takes that conversation
will depend on the person in front of us
if it's somebody who needs to feel like
they're very very valued by the
organization in order to hear the hard
feedback will send the CTO and
co-founder if it's someone who needs to
feel like we're sort of all in this
together and they've got allies in this
and we might send me
okay because I'm a little bit less
organizational a little bit less top
leadership to talk in there so figuring
out who will respond best to what and
also what the risks are also in
interviews there are certain members of
the team who I wouldn't necessarily put
an interview alone with a candidate okay
because of the messages they give up
because of what their are susceptible
their influence and somebody the back
you mentioned that HR comes to you often
to check their email attachments
absolutely some uses by design of their
job role are just inherently more likely
to be exposed to certain attacks okay so
our job of HR and recruitment basically
is to receive emails and LinkedIn
messages from people we don't know with
attachments okay that are usually PDFs
and it's usually in our best interest to
open them okay so that's something
similarly finance teams so your support
teams you might traditionally think have
the least security knowledge and they're
the most at risk okay so it's important
to be having those conversations the
third reason I take HR and security
teams should work together is that HR
spends a lot of time trying to design
human systems that won't provoke
unwanted behavior so a few illustrations
here
does anyone fear use take the eyes yeah
knows what a KPI is okay okay Oz yeah
okay any other afternoon for trendy
things that came out of Google yeah okay
the idea behind KPIs or okay does
everyone know what I'm talking about
when I say it okay so like gold like
SMART goals if you will if we're still
in the early 2000s okay so basically a
way of designing objectives that we can
quantify and easily measure success
against it's not a bad idea in theory do
they work well in practice yeah yeah
yeah I mean it depends is about the most
positive answer you can get right when
you asked about our chaos and KPIs right
is it a good system if the answer is
always it depends probably not right so
does anybody know much about the
Australian Ambulance Association say are
there any other Australians in the room
all right that's fine totally fine
nobody's worried all right great
so the Australian Ambulance Association
what do you think the main job is why do
they exist what's the reason for being
yep so the basis they control all the
ambulances in Australia sorry trick
question
they're there to save lives hmm so no
the lobbyist group correct indeed they
are actually just doing the works yep
probably probably also you know a little
bit political but they're doing the work
so the Australian Ambulance Association
basically their one goal their reason
for being is you're basically to make it
so that less people die they decided to
borrow from the private sector and they
wanted to look at basically some
efficiency measures that they could put
in place they basically tracks their
stats and they noticed that when they
attended to an emergency call within
nine minutes that the outcomes were
drastically better okay outcomes in this
case meaning less people died okay we're
not talking about bottom line revenue
and I was talking about bugs in an
application if they were talking about
less people died better outcomes if you
respond to a call in under nine minutes
so they thought it would be better if we
respond to more calls in under nine
minutes okay and one of the ways they
thought it would do that was to
explicitly say that okay we can't
improve something that we haven't
changed towards so okay let's say well
the ambulance drivers that they are to
respond to calls from the moment it hits
them from dispatch in under nine minutes
okay in order to incentivize this they
said that basically the teams the
ambulance teams who respond to the most
calls in under nine minutes who have the
best stats on their KPIs get to choose
which shifts they work okay and will
it's working as you can imagine
accidents never stopped so they work
around the clock weekends nights okay
and basically it's very attractive to be
able to choose when you work after a
month of this system they measured the
results and they saw and that they had
indeed increased the number of accidents
that they attended to in under nine
minutes which was excellent that was the
goal they also noticed a spike around 18
minutes and around 27 minutes which they
previously never had before
and an overall spike in the death toll
now trying to figure out what was going
on does anyone have an idea of what
might have been happening there okay
yeah absolutely so they were focusing on
individual goals which is my truck
receives the call I have nine minutes to
respond ambulance drivers were arriving
close to the scene of an accident and
seeing on the clocks that they would
arrive at nine minutes and ten seconds
for example so they were rejecting the
call sending it back to dispatch sment
was going back out to another truck who
then had nine minutes back on the clock
who would do the same thing and so on it
sounded like a good idea right it
sounded like a good idea but because of
the human factor and because of the
motivations that they had and because of
the shortsightedness by design of the
system these ambulance drivers work they
do this work because they want to save
more lives right the system didn't put
them in a position where that wasn't in
conflict with their personal goals
thankfully most of us are not
necessarily doing work that has such
high stakes okay what we're doing is
important internet security is extremely
important and as we saw in the keynote
this morning can have real-life human
consequences that said most of the time
when we're setting KPIs for our security
teams for our engineering teams we have
a little bit more room for error which
thankfully okay thankfully what we try
and do in HR is make sure that we don't
have too many of those systems that
produce the wrong result okay it's one
reason why it's screen we don't have
variable salary for anyone in the team
okay Syria variable salary if you
achieve your goals you will be paid more
money I do recruitment as part of my job
if you say to me hey Alison at the end
of the month you'll have more money if
you work route 10 people this month who
thinks I'll recruit ten people this
month yeah the rest of you know that
convinced I can all right nice thanks
team they say on that ten people by the
time we're done yeah over
ten people the right people maybe not
will they still be here in six months
probably not doesn't matter I did the
thing it was very miserable okay so then
you say okay Alison let's get a bit
smarter
you're gonna recruit ten people this
month and after eighteen months
ninety percent of those ten people will
still be here alright so at which point
are you paying me this variable and
what's happening month over month and do
we have the predictability will we
always hire ten people per month what
happens if somebody leaves because of
something someone else controls or not
me okay at what point can i impact this
okay and then we kind of abandon it so
we don't pay anybody about a variable
salary at screen because we think that
it doesn't actually produce the right
results we think it can tend to be a
distraction what we do do however is
what I call backward-looking bonuses
okay you know when you sign up to work
for screen what you will be earning okay
you know that where I perform your
organization that you'll do your job
you'll be paid it okay that's the that's
the agreement that said if you have a
particularly exceptional border there's
nothing that stops us from saying hey
here's something you weren't expecting I
have a little extra and that becomes an
actual bonus as opposed to a you know
there's this room for maneuver and maybe
we'll give you eighty seven point five
percent of your variable is not not very
motivating if we agree that HR and
security teams should work together do
we agree are we starting to agree does
my turn imply that it's not a choice
yeah okay excellent
excellent okay so we agree we agree that
HR and SEC team should work together but
now let's concentrate on the house okay
so how should they work together you
mentioned earlier by raising awareness
okay one particularity about screen in
the security industry is that we refused
to market or to sell fear okay so we do
not capitalize on public breaches to
sell our SAS okay
just let that sink in for a minute
that's quite unusual in the industry we
don't market or sell fear which means
internally when we're raising awareness
about security we have a unique
challenge which is we will not spread
fear to our employees either how do you
educate people about security without
fear make it fun I like it
okay challenges and competitions I can
make it engaging make it educative make
it yeah make it fun okay absolutely
those are some of the things we do one
of the first things we do basically is
to give concrete real-world examples of
attacks so that individuals can
understand how they happen okay how and
why they work what that helps to do is
to distance people from the you'd have
to be stupid to click on a fishing line
okay what we basically do our CTO says
hey you know here is a spear phishing
attack that I once received you said and
I clicked on the link okay I'm the CTO
and co-founder of a security company and
absolutely happens to everybody here's
why okay and here's why it doesn't have
to be this big shameful event if it does
happen basically we give them awareness
common attacks how am I they work and
the most important which is an avenue
for recourse if something looks
suspicious or if you think you've done
something you know onboarding we have a
slide which is our CTO s personal phone
number and the words underneath it which
says if you have a doubt call me if it's
3:00 a.m. I would rather be woken up for
nothing then for you to hesitate and not
want to bother me okay and that's pretty
powerful you're on the first date
maybe when there's five of you on the
team okay logical when we start to be
fifty sixty two different time zones two
different continents that starts to be a
powerful message so we onboard a junior
sales development rep in San Francisco
they get this training they get JV use
personal phone number and they get the
call me if in doubt okay and a few of us
have done so so we also give guidelines
to our specific teams through our sales
team travel a lot okay so we're
basically very careful that's physical
security so things like ciphering their
laptop okay using privacy screens in the
Train custom host names not connecting
to public Wi-Fi things like that that
salespeople who are trying to close a
deal just want basically free anything
so that the paperwork can go through
keeping their browsers up-to-date one
effective awareness fun educative
challenge competition if you will that
we use at screen is the cookie method
okay this will not be new to a lot of
you basically if your laptop or another
device is left on
locked in the screen house which is our
offices screeners the people who work
there
stay with me it'll be easy screeners are
allowed to access that device and write
cookies on the general slack channels in
an email to the company okay you're told
about the cookie method on your first
day of screen okay
the two hours maybe that elapse before
that first meeting is the only time that
you're immune and otherwise up from that
day forward okay no device doesn't
matter if it's this telephone doesn't
matter if it's your hope you don't leave
it unlocked an unattended otherwise
somebody will purify you as we have made
it over which wasn't pretty creative
about the cookie method okay we're a
security company most people you know
they stand up to your the bathroom they
lops a computer right it's it's not that
hot so you have to get a bit creative
because we're a big fan of cookies feel
free coming in we're talking about
cookies of the eating client coming in
so one person in our San Francisco team
sustained a cookie attack because three
members of the team basically fired nerf
guns at him repeatedly he ducked below
his desk to take cover leaving his
laptop and somebody else came in and
worked quickest skateboard events that
we still refer to so if you have a Mac
new repaired Apple watch you can unlock
it you feel the vibration on your wrist
of course but when you're trying out a
brand new skateboard around the office
that your colleague is I said hey Dennis
want to take a tour you might not notice
okay so running behind picture this so
when running behind someone on a
skateboard trying to unlock a right
cookies at the same time the sales team
often take often like to walk around the
office while they're closing deals okay
so one team member was behind the screen
the glass door out to the patio on his
phone closing a customer with his laptop
outside but he left his Bluetooth
keyboard inside so no visual markers
this was quite an impressive one okay so
command space open spotlight on Mac
slack in top command okay general and
Intel to switch to the general channel
type cookies and enter with no visual
feedback whatsoever
and one screeners girlfriend actually
cook aside him when he went to the
bathroom at home while working from home
okay she doesn't actually doesn't work
for us but this culture has spread
beyond and where all of us went
Loic how did it get cook afraid you know
and his girlfriend's claims so we
started to go beyond the first circle
right the security is getting larger and
larger absolutely absolutely I mean
you're rewarded for your hard work
always boys and it's become quite the
competition now we're a big fan of
cookies sort of extent of food we like
to cook so each time somebody has cook a
fight the challenge is to raise the
level of what gets brought in okay so
it's started to get a little bit
ridiculous
I'll have it known that in 16 months
working at screen I have never once been
Kouga by challenge my laptop is here it
is not connected to the Wi-Fi fabulous
beyond that we also do security theme
nights at screen we're a member of the
team basically takes two days and
prepares a security type challenge for
all of us to work on for sort of three
hours at night one of them my favorite
one was learning how to execute a DDoS
attack I got into security very much by
accident I was teaching English to a lot
of people in business in France when I
first moved from Australia and I ended
up teaching English to an entire
Department of Engineers and I had the
head of infrastructure as one of my
first students and he came in and it was
explaining to me why he hadn't done any
Singlish oh boy he said well listen you
know I was up all night responding to an
incident we had a DDoS attack
listen okay no problem your your
homework was to explain something
specific about your drug so we're gonna
do that today
he said here I'm gonna ask me to explain
a DDoS attack in English I don't you
know I barely have the words so that's
exactly what we're gonna do so he spent
15 minutes in a mix of French and
English basically explaining to me that
if you have a lot of computers okay but
not actual computers okay they might not
be real computers and all at one place
there's a bunch of traffic to one server
that you could crash a website
I started to ask him questions I said
how many computers I said how much time
what sort of websites could we take down
and quite inadvertently he gave me a you
know sort of entry into the industry and
how things could work so when I join
screen one of the first things I said
was okay we agree if I join a security
company you'll teach me how to do some
cool things yeah and the CTO said well
listen I can't explicitly hand you the
tools to doing anything illegal of
course we wouldn't do that but if by
chance over time you know we taught you
enough that you then went and made a
decision on your own that would be fine
so my favorite hack night was DDoS
learning how to execute a DDoS attacks I
was very disappointed to learn that for
a very small sum I could actually just
pay somebody that I'd know it was it was
it was very sad I wanted to do it myself
but also not go to jail right which is
sort of the story of my life yeah
conflicting desires conflicting desires
so apart from the hack nights in the
cuckoo's vacation we have a great
onboarding for security and we use pedro
judy has a really great fishing training
if you've ever seen it very interactive
basically fishing or not fishing which
is good fun for teams everybody can play
and it came in handy actually last night
so every quarter at screen we do q3 of a
quarter release demo day okay so
whatever the teams have been working on
for three months we invite customers we
invite prospects we invite our investors
we invite the general public to come to
our offices and to basically see what
we've worked on for three months our
co-founders are formerly from Apple okay
so there's a little bit of that echo
there as well it's a big day it was last
night I was watching remotely from my
hotel room in Amsterdam and right after
we finished the demo I received an email
from Pia ICU
subject line urgent hey Alison do you
have time to do something really quickly
for me bye mate okay earlier that
morning Pierre had actually sent me an
email that was very similar to that okay
we're trying to close a vice president
of marketing in San Francisco who needed
to give notice by
ence T okay and we had all these things
moving around in San Francisco it wasn't
away couldn't call our lawyers couldn't
get board approval for shares and things
like that it came in handy but I'd had
this fishing training pretty recently it
also came in handy that one other piece
that I'll talk about which is emotional
intelligence okay say if I were a highly
strong type-a overachieving HR manager
there's a chance that seeing his urgent
email at 11:00 p.m. last night when I'm
traveling would have stopped something
okay I might have sparked my fear but
I'd done something wrong or it might
have triggered my impostor syndrome or
it might have triggered me into saying
okay whatever it is I need to drop
everything and do it now thankfully I am
none of those things or at least I'm
aware of those things okay and so the
first thing I did obviously was text him
and say hey Pierre and look closely and
so there was an extra in chair in his
name in another company without that
kind of fun memorable fishing training I
probably wouldn't have made the made the
link I also did that training 16 months
ago it turned out everybody in the
company had received some sort of a
phishing email right after our demo
which if you want to know if you're
doing interesting things that's a good
good validation that we were doing
interesting things and then our q3 demo
was quite a success I won't say anymore
if you're interested come and see me
later
we also offer in addition to this type
of training we also offer across the
device password manager as a perk
because we don't hire a lot of security
professionals 90% of the employees at
screen had never worked in security
before okay we have a very small team of
security engineers three people everyone
else basically is either a software
engineer sales team member products or
support we do that on purpose okay
because we're not building in the old
way of things we're building in the new
way things okay so everybody's starting
out in security which means we carry a
higher risk which means awareness and
training is big for us but the most
powerful thing security teams in HR can
do as a group benefit is to establish a
security first culture I might
like just a little parenthesis here what
is culture because people get really
confused about what it actually is and
isn't what is a company culture any
ideas
okay the norms the basics absolutely
the values okay okay internal motivation
okay it feels like the right thing to do
okay
attitudes yeah goals
yep yeah nice Netflix defines it pretty
well they say it's basically what gets
rewarded tolerated and punished okay
what are the things so the norms so what
just goes on all day every day and is
okay what sort of jokes can I make in
the open space without retribution who
gets promoted who gets fired and why who
gets hired who doesn't and why having a
security first culture sounds like maybe
we have like a multi door system at
screen was like retina scanners right
security first all right
everybody through here that we keep out
office address offline you know nobody
knows actually where we're hiding out
doing the security that we keep out all
about Apple accessories under lock and
key at all times
that we have a strong email filter on
that subject one of my very first I'm so
excited you got to use your sign 10
minutes 10 minutes team that's alright
one of my very first hecho jobs I worked
in an oil and gas company in Australia
IVA starts with implementing a new
parental leave policy including the
establishment of lactation rooms in our
headquarters every week I would have to
go to the IT department and ask them
very nicely they would release my very
safe for working house from the national
breastfeeding Association of Australia
that were being called me and I'll
filter every day this as just as a side
note this is why we need more diversity
and software engineering and security
teams because these types of filters
being set up by a certain population and
legitimate things get caught so my first
my first entry into the security world
was can you explain to me why
female containing potentially a
pornography it should be released into
your cat which was good fun here it's
free here at screen we have a security
first policy but an open-door policy as
well which means you can walk into
either of our offices in Paris or San
Francisco if you need a desk for the day
and I encourage you if you are in either
of their cities to come and see us we'll
give you Wi-Fi you'll be able to see our
dashboards in real time you can see our
revenue you can see our number of
customers you can see the bugs we're
currently fixing in which agent they
occur you can hear our conversations you
can see our springboard that's something
that we do very openly our CEO has been
known to meet direct competitors at
events not dissimilar to this and
explain our entire 18-month strategy
okay we are a very open company for a
security company for one reason we
believe in value okay and we don't think
that secrecy or fear is the way to a
more secure future we believe openness
okay sharing human vulnerability that
leads to less system vulnerability our
number one defense against attacks
actually probably our number two defense
and number one defense against the text
is our end product screen and over to
defense psychological safety okay who
ther knows what psychological safety is
yeah what is it it's tough to define
actually okay thinking that yeah okay
thinking you're secure it's the belief
that you can take a risk or make a
mistake without being punished okay it
doesn't mean that there aren't there
isn't a flow-on effects but that you
won't be punished for taking a risk or
making a mistake
who here in this room has already
personally fallen victim to a phishing
attack yeah okay he's not a difficult
thing to admit in a security conference
yeah it can be it can be right it can be
my feeling is the real number is
actually a little higher than hands that
were raised we haven't we haven't missed
Sara Lee I've tried but we haven't
necessarily established a culture of
psychological safety here today
give me another half a hour and maybe I
will but basically if we have a lot of
cultures in engineering and technology
and security that are very based on the
fact that our knowledge will protect us
okay we are good at our jobs we are
smart we are smarter than most okay
there's no way I would fall for
something like that I have such good
training I work with an excellent
security engineer Cedric who just built
an incredible POC but if you're
interested in I can tell you more about
but he basically works for Apple for
about 10 years and did some of the first
Dale breaks on the iPhones and he's the
first one to tell you that it would be
so easy to get him in a phishing attack
why you like to be like I would be able
to get him to clean you like concretely
I'd know exactly what I would do if I
want to Center it typically put on the
Lich's link and I've told him I said
this is how it would happen said er can
I share a passion for a hot metal and we
often go to concerts together okay super
easy hey Cedric I just took a ticket for
this concert if you're interested click
the link if I want to okay super easy
because why okay closeness vulnerability
also feeling of belonging things like
that he now only other vices own tickets
it tells me who made me that set of
that's a different story
psychological safety is required okay
you're fooling yourself if you think you
can have rules and punishment and also
have a secure technology company
anything like that the ability to say
hey JB el sitio I think I downloaded a
harmful file yesterday when I was
traveling yeah can you take my machine
and look I changed my password already
but can you just see what happened and
know that I won't be punished I won't be
ridiculed okay and that at the end of
the day it'll be used to teach other
people something beyond justice the
impacts on security a great company
culture is one we're speaking up is
routine okay there are a lot of
professions around the world where if
you can't speak up and say that you've
made a mistake people might die
okay the medical profession if you can't
speak up and say hey I have a bad
feeling about that so through yesterday
I think we should go back here okay you
need to be able to speak up
and the risk of looking dumb I think
this might be the hardest part in
technology and security companies the
ability to look dumb okay recently looks
dumb doing something yeah yeah it's not
a great feeling right when you're right
at all
you kind of hoped you might have less
suppose me or some of you like it
apparently like looking dumb I like it
this is great security first looking
done I love looking stupid unfortunately
life tends to lead me to a lot of
situations where that's the case I
recently learned how to ride a
motorcycle
now I hadn't ridden a bicycle in about
15 years and I don't have a driver's
license so this was possibly an
ill-advised ill-advised adventure but my
very first lesson the teacher was like I
knew you're being you know but like how
do you even just walk around you have no
sense of balance and I said okay look
excellent
great 30 years old you can't do what
most toddlers are doing doing very well
so that was humbling that was very
humbling looking dumb it's something
that we should cultivate it should
happen serve regularly you know
organizations we're in every meeting we
can say hey Jim our VP of Sales I'm
sorry I know you've told me 10,000 times
what a RR is but I still can't remember
okay which one is that
or conversion rates we use a lot of
acronyms and what tends to happen in
rooms full of smart people is we smile
an on dog I'll go and look that up later
okay I don't want to look I want to look
silly in front of all these small people
they hired me I think I'm positive I
encourage you to do the opposite I
encourage your particularly fear leaders
in meetings like that where there are a
bunch of different people one simple
thing we do is anytime an acronym is
used in a team meeting it screen one of
the leaders says oh sorry Jim when you
say ARR you mean annual recurring
revenue right and it stops maybe the
first year the most junior employee or
the most recently arrived from having to
do it
but because they've seen the leaders do
it okay it's fine it's normal so we do a
lot of things publicly to make sure that
that becomes our north
okay that book
the right behavior we share on our side
channel screenshots saying hey team be
careful I think this is a phishing email
okay we share that and everyone kind of
claps and everyone's like wow good
that's great okay we'll go and have a
look psychological safety is the ability
to be vulnerable okay if you want to
remember one thing about the talk
psychological safety the ability to be
vulnerable vulnerability in humans is
good for avoiding vulnerabilities in
your systems and technology okay
vulnerabilities okay OS top 10 bad human
vulnerability
good thank you very much
does anyone have any questions all right
HR department how is that something you
can bring to them okay I repeat the
question for the video correct yeah
fabulous okay so question was some
echoes of Britney Browns take on
vulnerability which by the way hugely
flatted a big fan of hers so loved that
that's coming through the question was
how can you scale this sort of thing or
how can you roll it out across a 10,000
person company as opposed to a 50 person
company yeah I think it comes back to
the same things it comes down to this
happened very quickly so we speak
English in the office despite the fact
that like 70 percent of the people are
French it takes one conversation in
French in the open space for that to
catch fire and all of a sudden never
have speaks French all day there are
certain things that have like an
exponential impact so it's things like
in that big organization it's obviously
leadership alignment it's saying hey
we're making vulnerability human
vulnerability a whole knock of how we
hire how we onboard our employer
branding this is where hay chopping kind
of go full employee cycle okay and roll
that out from hey the messaging we do
about screen is not we have the best
company in the world there is one
company who does that messaging its
Twitter I would not necessarily think
that Twitter actually has a great site
the psychological safety culture
somewhere I can see from the outside
it's very hard when you have claims like
we are the best okay
that screen would say hey we're doing a
bunch of things that we think are pretty
interesting but there's a chance those
things we're not doing come on in and
help us learn about them so I think it's
across that whole chain leadership
buy-in and the I come from a background
of change management it's always about
figuring out who the influences are and
if you find in a 10,000 person
organization that your main influences
are the opposite of the culture you're
trying to instill this
two options right one of them is clean
house and and and the other one is
except that your culture probably won't
change
[Applause]