you
hi guys my name is Dominic I'm a
security researcher and pen tester and
I'm mainly focused on blockchain
technology and smart contracts and last
year I was up SEC Europe in London I
gave a talk about vulnerabilities in
smart contracts and I did a small
showcase but this year I wanted to focus
on the whole process of development of
smart contracts and show you how to make
it know secure and well the first
question to you have you have have ever
created
I mean implemented or maybe used the
centralized applications or smart
contracts raise your hand that's just a
few people and I must tell you that this
is this topic is gonna be hot quite soon
because these are some of the companies
just a small list of the companies that
create platforms for smart contracts and
decentralized applications or just use
them and for example Facebook Libra have
you heard about Facebook Libra the
cryptocurrency of Facebook yes actually
this is not the cryptocurrency only it's
a smart contract platform so it is a
cryptocurrency but you can also create
smart contracts on on Libra so let's
start with a quick introduction because
the topic is not very familiar so what
are the decentralized applications and
I'm gonna call them the apps from now
and why why are they becoming so
important in your future
well decentralized applications are like
web applications but they have
decentralized storage and the governance
so if you we are looking for an example
of web applications we can go for
Facebook or already it and steam it is a
decentralized version of reality for
example and well why are they becoming
so important first there are many
projects that have proven its value also
the market is quite huge because there
billions of dollars in cryptocurrencies
of course on blockchain market and it
just it is also a great chance for new
technologies for for example for fin fin
text and as I mentioned before there are
big players behind the blockchain
technology the smart smart contracts and
decentralized applications but what is
so special about decentralized
applications why do we need them why
can't we stay with stick to their web
applications well the main thing is that
we gain trust worthiness thanks to the
blockchain technology which means that
there is no single point of authority no
no one person or institution can control
the application also it means that no
one can actually turn it off permanently
that's because anyone can keep the copy
locally of any decentralized
applications so if somebody turns of the
the application anyone else can just put
it back online and it's like well it's
like having a copy of whole Facebook's
including source code and its database
on your computer so that's that sounds
quite nice well what's the difference in
the architecture between their web
applications and the apps well the the
original idea behind the apps is that
they are kept on blockchain and I mean
both the front end application which is
usually written in JavaScript and the
API which is the back end of the
application of this decentralized
applications and these are smart
contracts and all of this is kept on
blockchain on decentralized network that
no one can modify and no one can control
so also there is a quite popular
architecture where the front end
application so the JavaScript is kept on
a web server like in web applications
and that's actually okay because still
you download the code the JavaScript
code and you can audit it you can see it
of course sometimes it's obfuscated but
there was a great talk about Luis
by lewis about how to automatically scan
for vulnerable for interesting stuff in
JavaScript applications so this hip
hybrid isn't the centralized
architecture is still okay because the
main logic the business logic the back
end is on blockchain still so are these
applications secure and comparing to web
applications well first of all they are
undestroyed like I said anyone can bring
it back to life because they using
terrorism blocking then they are
cryptographically secure I'm sure you've
seen that two words together many times
when you were you know reading some
descriptions of blockchain applications
so what does it mean it means that all
transactions which represent function
calls are digitally signed sounds nice
we have known repudiation we have
authentication that's cool and also
anyone can actually verify the code and
this current state of the application
because it's all public on public
blockchain so it's like you can read the
code but still we see many either Hux or
great submissions on bug bounty
platforms for for smart contracts and
decentralized applications so again it's
just about our expectations and the
reality so I'm sure that's not gonna be
a great discovery for you but what we
need we need a security for
decentralized applications the same as
we do for web applications and last
couple of months we've done some pen
tests and security audits for companies
related to blockchain and most of them
included of course web applications that
integrate with blockchain and some of
them also included the centralized
applications mainly the backend of
decentralized applications which are
smart contracts and well the case of web
applications is quite simple nowadays
because we have so many great projects
so many great materials and
standards that we can use to perform the
of it and let me ask you if you need to
know what are the most common web
application vulnerabilities
what would you go 400 ASP what I'll ask
top ten of course here the first answer
then if you need the knowledge knowledge
base for the common weaknesses that can
happen in web applications as w/e
exactly come on witness enumeration and
last but not least I guess the most
important where would you go what would
you go for if you need a security
checklist and to enlist to perform an
audit ASVs
exactly application security
verification standard and actually we
can ask we can ask the same questions
for the centralized applications because
this is obstacle ocation security so
what what are the most common naval
abilities for decentralized applications
there is a project which is very similar
to over top 10 which is called Dokdo 10
that enumerates those 10 most popular
vulnerabilities also we can look for a
knowledge base for the most for the
weaknesses that could happen in smart
contracts and here we have a smart
contract weakness falsification registry
which is very similar to CV again and
last do we have a security checklist
that covers whole smart contracts the
whole security of smart contracts
actually we couldn't find any so well
there are there is there are very many
publications materials about the
security of smart contracts but we
couldn't find a checklist that you can
you know just say that this is path this
path this is passed ok our contract is
secure for an hour first so that's why
we have created together with Pavlovic
from our company SES vs smart contracts
security verification standard
it has very similar form to ASVs because
we like ASVs and we use it every day for
web applications and we also have very
similar objectives we want to create a
checklist for developers for architects
and for security reviewers and also we
want to help to mitigate the common
vulnerabilities by design and to help to
create well secure code secure smart
contracts so we have created 13
different categories the last one is a
bit different I'm going to talk about
about it later and well they are they
have the same form so they have as as
ISVs so they have the security
requirements they call all of them
contain about 100 security requirements
and I'd like to present some of them on
example on the base of the SDLC software
development lifecycle and show you that
these requirements cover whole process
and I must say here this there is a
disclaimer this presentation is not
about how to introduce security into
your SDLC because that's a huge topic
and there are many approaches for that
I'm just using SDLC as the base for
examples so let's start with analysis
well of course we have some similarities
between web applications and the apps
and one of them is a threat model which
we should perform actually for any kind
of application so that's why we have
added security requirements with ABS
that makes sure that you first define
the boundaries the trust boundaries in
the documentation and that you perform
threat modeling for each functionality
that you introduce into a smart
contracts what about the differences
well the first difference is about the
sensitive data actually this is quite
easy for web applications we can because
we can keep sensitive data in database
and we can just protect it of course
this is not very easy sometimes but
still the main idea is to keep it in
database that is protected in case of
decentralized applications it's not that
easy because all data is on public
blockchain so actually everything is
readable and publicly accessible so
that's why you must make sure that no
confidential data is kept in smart
contracts in the storage of smart
contracts and like for example passwords
or personal data and no data is
considered safe or private even if you
use a private key word for your storage
variables this is quite tricky because
private variables are not that private
the next thing public access for web
applications it's quite easy to define
what is public we usually probably
publish the front end application and
some API in case of decentralized
applications actually everything is
public so each function that is in the
smart contract can be called can be
executed of course the logic may be
different the logic node may say that so
you cannot execute this function but
anyone can try to execute all functions
in smart contracts and that was the case
of the first poet you wallet hack where
a function that in it's the smart
contract was publicly accessible and
actually somebody could took over your
wallet and that's how 100 sorry 30
million dollars this is quite this is
variable right so today it's 30 million
tomorrow it's 20 and the day after
tomorrow it's 40 so I need to you know
update this slide every time I give a
Turk so for for today it's about 30
million dollars of course in
cryptocurrencies
so it's important to make sure that all
functions have the visibility specified
that this was the case of attack just
because the function was not
has not specified the visibility type
and by default it functions are public
so that was that was the power that was
the problem next wing randomness well in
web applications it's a matter of for
one function call either you want
statistical randomness or
cryptographically randomness in case of
decentralized applications it's a bit
tricky because smart contracts are
executed on many nodes simultaneously so
and they must be executed the same way
so we cannot use any local parameters
from one node and the problem here is
that it's not that easy it's not a
trivial to get a random number in smart
contracts and that was the case of a few
of actually many attacks many hacks one
is quite recent from September where
about 100,000 dollars were stolen from
us play a plea k ssin and one is a bit
older we're about eighty thousand
dollars were stolen from SmartWater e a
hack and all that was available because
the bed randomness implementation so you
could quite easily
you know predict the so-called random
number so the solution for that problem
is to make sure that you do not generate
set the random number trivially basing
on the publicly available data that is
kept on blockchain like timestamps or
block number etc also decentralized
applications introduced some new threats
like threat actors like for example
miners and validators these are the
nodes that validate the transactions and
add new blocks to the blockchain and
they are quite powerful because they can
see that transactions before they are
validated so they know the future and
here is a case of a report for a group
at firmware a miner could easily abuse
the business logic of this contract
so he could easily do s contract just
because some of the logic was based on
variables that can be said by minor and
that's how he and as you can see the
stability of this vulnerability is high
so that's important so to solve this
problem we should make sure that the
first the contract logic implementation
corresponds strictly to the
documentation and also that we have
business limits and we enforce them and
by the way we must make sure that we we
our business logic does not disincentive
users from using our smart contracts
because if using our application is too
expensive for users they will stop using
it it's actually also our some kind of
denial of service right ok so let's move
on to design phase we have some
similarity skills here as well one of
them is the rest least privilege rule
and the other is access control which
actually in case of decentralized
applications is a bit tricky because
it's again public so anyone can see the
rules and that's why it should be kept
as simple as possible and centralized in
one smart contract and the lease
provision can be ensured with the same
with the requirement that makes sure the
creator of the contract does not have
too much power because you know when you
create a contract when you implement it
and then you deploy it you can say that
ok I'm the owner I can do anything but
then you lose the trust lessness right
because people have to trust the creator
of the contract so the best approach is
to create a contract that cover all the
business logic flows and that creator
cannot change because then it's really
trustless and also the access control
mechanism should be kept in one smart
contract and
should which is trusted and should be as
I said as simple as possible next
difference are loops and I mean the
loops that lead to denial of service
well we have that kind of loops in web
applications there are usually infinite
loops but it's quite easy to find a loop
that potentially may be infinite in case
of decentralized applications we have
some loops that are not are not infinite
but they are so-called unbound so there
is no specified exact number of
iterations and if we have such loop we
can have a problem because as an example
of governmental smart contract the RI
that was looked became so huge because
of some kind of business logic it became
so huge that actually you couldn't Oh
iterate over it and that was the
requirement of the business logic so you
had to iterate over an array that and
that would take so much that would be so
cost full it would take so much gas even
more gas than the maximum allowed number
so you actually couldn't call it any
anyway because you cannot give so much
gas it's more than maximum modeled
number so that's the story how about two
hundred thousand dollars were frozen it
means that they are there they are on
this contract but you actually cannot do
anything with that so to solve that
problem you can first first of all do
not iterate over in unbound loops you
must specify exact iterations for each
loop and also to avoid other problems
with gas limitation you should not send
funds I mean the cryptocurrencies tokens
automatically in your business logic but
you should other store the number
attached to a person turn to an address
and allow those people to withdraw their
tokens or cryptocurrencies
with another transaction we've
withdrawal transaction and also we have
another case of the risk for
decentralized applications because as
you as you've seen on most of the
applications and smart contracts there
are some cryptocurrencies kept so the
more cryptocurrency is on the smart
contract the bigger the risk is that
somebody will try to steal it so you can
try to decrease the risk and you should
keep as less amount of cryptocurrencies
on the smart contract as possible
because that just decreed us that this
incentives the hacker to steal your
cryptocurrency okay so let's move on to
implementation of course we have great
tools like truffle or remick's there are
these are IDs and they actually perform
some security basic security checks that
you can integrate some other platforms
that perform some other security checks
but so it's like a partially cover cover
the security is partially covered by
these tools but still we have so many
bugs and it's very very similar to web
applications right so the most common
one of the most common vulnerabilities
in smart contracts are automatic bugs
they are not that common in web
applications now maybe they are a bit
more common in the software that
application web applications use like
servers where we have overflows but they
are quite common in distant relized
applications and I'm not talking about
simple overflows like you know adding
two numbers and we you know get the
number over the over the maximum I mean
so a bit more sophisticated talks over
flows where like for example batch
overflow or proxy overflow where and
details you can find under these
link's but actually there is a quite
interesting
consequence of overflows because if we
take a RC 20 smart contract as an
example which is a contract for managing
token which has some value in fired
currencies like dollars you can actually
using this vulnerability create the
zillions or even more of tokens so it's
like going to the mint in real life
going to the mint printing like millions
of euros and going out with legal money
and if you've seen la casa de papel or
money heist in english if you've seen
this series i'm sure that you know the
scenario of this of this attack so to
avoid such problem well you should make
sure that you don't you are not
vulnerable to arithmetic overflows and
you can achieve that using for example
safe mode library you should also
consider extreme values in your business
logic and you know handle them and also
sometimes strict equalities are a bit
tricky so you should avoid strict strict
inequality equality sorry okay another
difference recursive calls
well recursive calls are quite explicit
in web applications because we either
either need a loop or we need to call a
function inside inside the same function
in case of decentralized applications
you actually don't need a loop or you
don't need and you don't need a function
call in a function to obtain recursive
code that's because you can call one
contract from you can call the other
contract from the original contract and
the other contract will call again your
original contract so we have a loop but
between contracts not in the business
logic of one contract and that was the
case
I think the most known attack in a smart
contracts world the Dow Hawk we're about
three point three point six million
hitters were stolen which is like now I
guess uh billions in dollars and
actually that was the case why the
helium platform forked and now we have
two cryptocurrencies humanitarian
classic so that was a huge huge thing
you can find some more details under
this link so and even this this kind of
attack was got its name it's called
reinsurance II so if you want to avoid
you in France attack you must make sure
that no recursive calls from untrusted
smart contracts are available in your
smart contract and also you should check
them the result of call function calls
for a low-level function like st. call
because these functions does not bubble
up the exceptions these functions when
they fail they just return for example
zero like in C language right so you
should check you should check the result
because if you do not and you assume
that it always succeeds success then you
might have a problem
okay testing well we have also a bunch
of great tools for testing for both for
both web applications and there is a
plenty of automatic scanners for
decentralized applications and we
recommend to use them because why not
you have them and you can easily just
run them so that's why we have added the
requirement to use these automatic tools
and we've also created a whole category
just to make sure that the testing takes
place on in the whole process of the
development right from the analysis to
the to the implementation and deployment
and that's why you should very
by the contract logic you should use the
automatic scanners you should you should
also formally verify the specification
of the smart contract even before you
start to implement it right after you
design it you should formally verify it
and also you should not forget about the
manual tests because some kinds some
kind of bugs security vulnerabilities
are hard to find by automatic scanners
and that's actually the same like in web
applications and that's why we recommend
to provide a CSVs of course and other
security requirements and policies to
all developers and testers and talking
back about the vulnerabilities that are
hard to find we can talk about another
submission this time it's for maker Dow
platform and it's again on bug bounty
platform of hacker one where
vulnerability which was in the business
logic so it's hot it's actually it
cannot be find it cannot be found by
automatic scanners it allowed to meand
die which is cryptocurrency in this
platform and without cover so it's like
again minting new money like printing
dollars without you know Authority and
as you can see this bounty is quite huge
and it means that this is this is also
his problem it's disabilities hi
so a first what you should do is to make
sure that your business logic is a
consistent and that of course the it's
preceded in the sequential order this
check is actually very similar to the
check from ASVs above the business logic
in web applications
okay so let's deploy our application we
have implemented it now we want to
deploy it and usually deployment means
like setting up some configurations some
integrations and publishing the
application and usually for web
applications we do it once of course we
can later redeploy it but deployment is
the process that will perform once and
then there is no a logic in the source
code of web application that performs
the deployment in case of decentralized
applications you must perform the same
process you must do some configures your
smart contract and then set up some
connections between contracts and then
execute a function that deploys your
contract but the difference is that the
deployment function is in the contract
so it's still on the blockchain it's
accessible so we can try to call it
again
and what if let's say you forgot to call
this function so you actually didn't
initialize the contract or what if you
allow to reinitialize your contract
because you thought well I initialized
it and I forgot actually to stop other
people from initializing it again and
taking it over so that was the case of
the second per ATO track where there was
a smart contract that was shared by
hundreds of other contracts and this
contract was not initialized some guy
found out that he can actually
initialize this contract and by
initializing this contract I mean he
could took over this contract so he
became something like owner of this
contract and he could he could execute
some sensitive functionalities and one
of those functionalities was
self-destruct so he firstly he took over
he initialized the contract he took over
it and then he killed it like removed it
from the blockchain and the problem was
that all other contracts were relying on
this contract and when there is no more
the contract the core contract they
could not they could not operate and the
other problem was that there were about
500,000 eaters on this which is about
two
one hundred million dollars and again
this dollar these hitters were fro are
frozen actually at the moment so they
are there but nobody can touch them so
you know it's nice to have good money
but if you cannot use it if you can
spend it it's not very nice so in to
avoid such situation the solution for
that problem is making sure that all
your variables are initialized which
means that basically your smart contract
was initialized during deployment and
making sure that you cannot ruin ich
allein so you cannot call again the
initialization function and by the way
in this case there was that sensitive
function functionality self-destruct
functionality so you should make sure
that you really need such
functionalities in your smart contract
that contract did not need solve
destruct functionality ok maintenance
well when we maintain an application we
of course get some locks and in case of
web web apps we keep them safe on the
server nobody can read them but the
administrators in case of decentralized
applications is actually we also have
locks they are called events and the
difference is that they are published to
the public blockchain so actually it's
like you have locks but all other people
also have your locks and that's why you
shouldn't of course put some sensitive
data in this looks but you should
monitor them because in blockchain when
you find a vulnerability it's always
erased
who's first the owner of the contract
that tries to fix the vulnerability or
the hackers so you should make sure that
you respond you have the true incident
response in this case event response in
your in your applications and actually
this can be some kind of micro services
that are running on centralized service
they don't have to be on the on the
blockchain
and talking about the security alert and
fixing the security bugs well in case of
applications you can this this is the
general concept I'm sure I know that
it's not that easy always but you can
take down your application watch it like
deploy the fix and then redeploy it turn
it on again in case of decentralized
applications it's not that easy because
once you deploy the smart contract
you cannot just simply take it down but
the back needs to be fixed so the idea
here is to and this of course this is
arguable but the idea is that you should
fix the bug and then redeploy your whole
actually deploy again you're all your
smart contracts and to avoid such
problems you should first have a
functionality some kind of mechanism
that will allow you to stop the most
sensitive functionalities in your smart
contracts for some time
however this mechanism cannot it it must
still be able for people to access their
assets like for example tokens if your
smart contract platform has some tokens
uses tokens
you must unload the owners of these
tokens to transfer it or to withdraw it
whatever so only the functionality the
business logic should be stopped and
also you should make sure that there is
an upgrade process for the contract
which allows you to deploy the contract
again of course there is no one great
solution for that there is no one
upgrade process that solves all problems
this is this is in individual but for
each smart contract platform you should
for each smart contract you should think
over such process so to sum up a SSDs is
some well we can say that it fills the
gap of the ASVs
in the distance realized application
world and I told you that we have that
one known attacks category number 13
which is actually a category that allows
you to quickly check whether your smart
contract is vulnerable to well-known
attacks in the decentralized world of
course and actually these are the
requirements that are references to
other requirements from other categories
so for example if you want to check
whether you are vulnerable to silent
falling sands and unchecked sands
attacks you just need to pass four point
six and four point seven requirements so
these are the requirements from the
category number four and if you want to
make sure that you are not vulnerable to
reinsurance the attacks you should make
sure that you pass four point five okay
so the next plan the future plan above
the s CSVs is to publish it the open
source on github on our company's github
and we're gonna do it on the first of
October if you want to be informed about
this you can either leave me a card
after the presentation or just sign up
under this core code and of course it's
only used for s CSVs alert that's not
there's no any spam from from this
mailing list and we are also considering
running as CSVs
under a wasp and we would like to build
a community around this project so if
you feel invited if you'd like to
contribute to the project when it's when
it's on the github published just you
know just contribute ok so if you need a
security audit go for a CSVs from the
1st of October and as I said if you need
to be if you want to be informed just
with me or leave me a contact thank you
[Applause]
do we have any questions
hmm just a second give mine sorry thank
you for your presentation you have a lot
of knowledge about known vulnerabilities
now and I think that a lot of those are
part of the solidity language do you
also work together with creators of that
language no I do not cooperate with them
however well it's a bit true because the
the the language is not very secure
secure by design
however there are other approaches like
for example VIPRE there is language for
for each idiom because I was mostly
talking about a Tyrian platform which
uses solidity language but there is also
a viper in python that trans translates
your code into solidity but is it has
some mechanism that you know gives you
more secure code and but also the the
hack about else play was from eus
platform which uses a bit modified c++
so they'd also have problems that arise
from the fact that from from the C++
language one well the I think the good
approach is with card on a platform they
use Pluto's language which is based on
Haskell a functional language and that's
a good approach in my opinion because
you can easily formerly verify such such
contract okay
[Music]
anybody else the simple answer is yes
some of these are just because the so
EDT absolute no more questions left and
run would like to say thank you thank
you
[Applause]