alright good afternoon everyone so for
those of you who don't think so
requisite number of certifications and
agrees I've been doing that sperm good
number years at this point eighteen
years into this lovely I T stuff
so at present I work at Ennis I'm also
part of Maryland defense force per unit
so do some fun things
principally I'm doing risk assessments
and securing our athletes from outside
so I'm part of the defense side of
things I thought line with never hackers
and I'm allocated space some of our
lovely hacker organizations back in the
Dec metro region and just this past
weekend I became an Iron Man 2 so yeah
we have some crazy people in the
industry if you follow any of my Twitter
feed you'll see it's it's a lot of names
just like what's coming out so people
can't so this is the best we talking
about attacking mindset for defenders
how many of you are on the defense side
of things instead of like penetration
testing ok let's get and how many are
more on the attacker penetration testing
everyone else is somewhere between
that's a good mix I can work with this
one of the things we tend to see is that
you know we don't really have an
attacker mind set on the defense side of
things you know we we tend to just be
left article go through
here's our compliance has our checklist
template thing then we're good to go
there's not a lot of thinking evil so
people you know where little abnormal on
the defense side yeah you know this so
with that in mind talk a little bit
about Reggie me losing my lovely purple
teaming and what exactly it we're
looking at in terms of our wrists are
threats and what we can do you know why
serious business I'm sure you don't have
to explain to anyone here just what
exactly information security is but i
just give a presentation to a bunch of
DevOps so how do you know I included the
whole process of we're here to help you
help yourself has it really is a team
effort and without the bad guys that
security is often thought of that way
where their vilified as hackers where
they were
defenders or attackers Thank You media
for changing that wording on us
previously it was just thinking outside
the box which is what we really need
more of we have enough box check us out
there
and if you say this word you know what
to do
information security is where it really
is but if you have to explain it to
someone they will understand this could
play if not security and if you actually
look at the ref for 453 actually
includes in there that complaint visit
security the purpose of complaint is to
keep us on a common thread moving
forward so that our systems have a
commonality for security that we can
trust one another because at the basis
of this it's all about the trust and now
we've had these breaches they've been
PCI compliance that has not helped them
because compliance is just the beginning
everyone does compliance wrong it's not
a checkbox to be marked off and forgot
about it the starting point that we can
build from this is another one of our
issues being defenders cuz we get fast
with implementing all this compliance
docs PCI I so you name it
there's companies that need to have all
of it and management doesn't necessarily
understand that we can layer this so
that we're working everything they look
at each individual thing as its own silo
so we end up reading implementing the
same things and just reinventing the
wheel when there's no point to it we can
leverage it and we can do inherited
controls and start doing cross
referencing
we just need to work on educating
everybody in the entire process to be
more security mindful it's an uphill
battle it doesn't get easier and I
assume everyone knows the FBI cyber no
one likes it
that's true so along with us we have
people that fall under the compliance
officers this is part of my day today
risk assessment reports are lovely Nexus
output and other output from school you
know you have to be constantly
identifying what the issues on your
network what's false positives you know
what's really out there but things
change people don't do their patches if
you look at one of the recent Verizon
DVRs they have stuff from 1999 that they
were vulnerable 'tis out there that have
been exploited so you have stuff that's
out there but who knows when it was
updated and people to start talking
about us or they've gotten busy because
our sysadmin have a lot of work to do
you know they're not necessarily
security minded and that's not really
part of their duties per se their duty
is to maintain systems and ensure its
function money but we still need to
integrate into all these fields thinking
more like the devious attacker hey I
didn't do my patch cycle this month so
where's my weakness now there's
something new every month but it's not
really the hottest new zero day that's
going to end up getting you compromise
and it's going to be your catches a
couple of years ago right I told you
this would be entertaining with that I
think a little more interesting because
hey what are we all here to do
hack the planet everyone wants to be an
attacker right so what does that usually
tend to mean for us for us this is
generally penetration but not everyone
needs from the defenders point of you
wind up getting a lot of
adversarial relationships going whether
its internal team or it's an external
team you're fighting them because
they're grading you and this is the
perception we're being graded on how we
have secured our system immediately we
don't like you so clearly we need to
work on changing that perspective part
of the purple team approach is working
with everybody's so that we're not being
adversaries were you think this is a
learning opportunity for making it full
cycle you know to turn into a more
holistic approach everybody to do their
job and be awesome at it without
thinking that he didn't apply patch of
last month that's just not going to work
give-and-take guess we can always learn
something from both sides of it i mean i
attackers are necessarily doing but they
can't attackers famous things to it just
tap the hardest part is starting to
think like the attacker so my career I
started out doing Unix Linux system
administration before I moved on into
security while I had some of these think
evil processes going yes I know shocking
right but it wasn't fully there now
someone starts talking about hey I want
to implement this project can we use
puppet or darker and now my immediate
responses ok well how is that talking
two things you know where is their
communication where there is a trust
level and how can I exploit that
because what we're doing is we're
splitting trust where they were
exploiting people are exploiting
software there is a trust layer there
and that's what we're seeking to exploit
without trust and make a little harder
but sometimes when you trust and I think
compliance isn't security and it isn't
but it gives us a baseline for where we
can start building that trust level if
you've certified a system according to a
certain level whether it's low moderate
or high I know the baseline of what
security you have actually implemented
on that system from there you know I can
filter trust layer between your system
and one of mine of equal or lesser value
as an attacker I can also leverage that
in order to see well with the process
the way it is okay you've implemented no
PCI or or next moderate well you
probably didn't go along and do these
things so there might be something I can
watch it very easily and it's all about
thinking what hasn't been done we're
always looking for this little loopholes
are so much fun sex toy and the best
thing is the people
his people are always going to be our
weakest link there's just no way that
we're ever going to have a secure system
and this is why security is so important
because technology has taken over lives
right now we live and die by smartphones
we're connected 2417 electronic leash
and so much of her life is out there and
we have the CTF going on where you can
do a little digging on people who would
you could find out their social media
about him
have you ever had a friend that does
this kind of open source intelligence go
through until you shocking facts about
yourself or what they can find now you
know something like your address if you
own a house that's that's not really
shocking public record but when you
start thinking about other things what
conferences have you checked into on
Foursquare Twitter Facebook yeah when we
left at the doctor when did your doctor
all this builds more things that
attackers can see as far as finding
points of weakness to identify and start
building that trust level with you and
we can exploit this
as defenders we don't always think about
this with think we need to lock down our
systems we need to hide everything but
we're not thinking what exactly is that
they're looking for us to be a little
hard but you know sometimes it's just
really a share a whole lot some people
share everything and it's up to everyone
to decide how much you really want out
there just know it . put you out there
every week I really want to clear it did
you know there are some highlights in
regard to security process security
processes that sometimes it's just too
easy to get to things because people
circumvent the rules I mean they're
helpful they're paying but this is what
we have policies this is why we have
procedures why we have complained if
it's done right it should you know make
certain things might happen is really
easy stuff to do it's fun because people
don't follow the rules
any kind of scary at times the stuff
early isn't over data that out there
it's reachable so when we gonna do now
we need to start working together it's
actually more blue team in some places
actually most places and my experience
they don't have internal ready then I'll
have internal penetration testing
generally it defaults down to
vulnerability assessment which that can
be enough for some organizations but it
really depends on what your assets and
your dinner valued at so at least on a
yearly basis you should have a more
in-depth audit where they are doing a
little bit more in terms of testing both
your personnel and systems or because as
much as some people would like to think
that simply running necessarily want
this going to secure their systems
there's a lot more out there that we
need to test and keep tabs on and
actually keeping tabs on and having
those metrics for what have we done you
know how much you know what are our
attack vectors how many attackers have
we had and have been successful
well
if you can even tell and that's always
the hard part is not everything is set
up to where you can tell whether you
necessarily an intrusion we'd seen is
where it's been over a year
p.m. comes to mind when they were in
there for over a year before it was
found out and these are the things that
we need more in-depth testing that's
also why you want to have a good
relationship between red teaming and
blue teaming and when you're having that
in-depth testing done you can get these
things fixed cuz otherwise everybody
just gonna be unhappy I'm sure what are
our primary target and that's a pretty
much everything out there can be client
list it can be government secret there's
something of value to everybody and it's
not necessarily what you think may be of
value to you know your competitors that
really like your client Lewis and what
you're what you're paying to your
suppliers
that's going to give them an advantage
when they go negotiation so there's a
lot more things that we have to think of
in terms of where bilities live and how
many people being technical would you
assume that analyst is a priority
a lot of times it just falls down to
this is the you know this is our
intellectual property
this is the important stuff this is what
we're building our walls and other
things that end up being administrative
tend to fall by the wayside
so and evaluation in terms of the data
itself so that appropriate defense
mechanism can be in place everywhere
where it probably wasn't our fault but
are usually protecting the stuff of
course realizing what your threat is
actually coming from a lot of places
like to go overboard but the reality is
not everybody is the target of
cyberterrorism it's the hot sexy thing
that's out there but most of your that's
going to be people that are poking
around or your direct competition these
are the people that really want your
data and I share the government then
everybody is against you anyway so yeah
throw it all out there there's just no
winning hard
part of that is because of our old
method everything still works to back in
the day
think Cold War espionage and old-school
super old school things to work our
people are the weakest link and this is
our best way of getting in this includes
everything as far as we have our own
vulnerabilities and as far as going up
and making friends with a low level
employee because maybe they don't have
direct access to what you're interested
in that they have access to the network
if you can get on it and you can
leapfrog and it's fun from there and
recovered open source intelligence but
there's a lot of their you confine
besides just people you know if you look
at a government or if he's sometimes you
can actually get really good idea of
what their networks break down to so
there's a lot of data that's put out
there it's just part of their usual
business process but it can be
manipulated in ways that your business
personal may not consider this it's not
a weak point it's just business
you know we need a quote for fifty
Windows systems running this type of
server hardware and software but now I
have an idea of the footprint of your
network without doing anything besides
seeing what you guys put out for an RFP
so now I can limit what I have to do in
terms of attacking and I can start
specifically doing that for that OS
version for that software version that
you're standing up and then I just have
to find a weak spot where
someone hasn't changed the default
passwords updated and if anything it
should but it's easy so I can we do
obviously I mean information security
cover the broad very very broad gamut
but implementing more testing of the
appropriate level now we can't just rely
on vulnerabilities are scanners to be
catching all of our problems there's
more to it than that we have more
weaknesses and we need to start
leveraging our professionals that we
have to come in and do those tasks and
find those weak spots so that we can fix
them are real attackers come in
obviously physical and personal security
is always an issue
people are the weakest link and this is
something that everyone just gets here
because didn't you
annual training it really isn't enough
because we all know we just SAT there
and we click into work through with it
because it was the same slide show last
year at that is this year with that we
need to do more interactive training so
they started thinking oh you know what
maybe I shouldn't click on this link you
know maybe this African Prince doesn't
really want to send me a few billion
dollars these things to work their tried
and true and they still work
casino but security it's hard
attacking is easy but security I got
memes fifties obviously we're all pretty
well certified individuals and there is
a difference between a Certification
Certification glut and knowledgeable
testing however it does give us a
baseline because they've got turned on
something so what does but additional
training at a professional level
certifications can help IT
certifications or not the end all be all
actual hands-on working knowledge is way
more valuable than having certifications
much more valuable remember trust but
verify you are the weakest link so
confirmed before you start sending
information to people should be simple
but
there's a lot of hackers out there how
to use it so you know remember your
friendly when you got problems we might
be able to help you or we can at least
refer you to someone who they know what
they're doing and they can take care of
it and for me it really comes down to
you know security is still Kostner so a
lot of its getting buy-in and having the
right people in the management level
along with that though you get a lot of
pushback in some places let's say dear
do the great place to not get pushed
back because there's directives so you
tell them they have to do something that
will fabulous to work with civilian side
you get a lot more pushback well why do
I need to do this I don't have the
funding
and you know you just want to show us
weaknesses getting them to start
thinking about it kind of just showing
I'm walking through the process
especially if they've they don't know
security setting and going even
something as simple as going through an
audit whether I think these are things
I'm checking against and it's not a
reflection on you with its not met this
is your opportunity to get more funding
then they start thinking oh I can get
the toys I want so I just need to make a
use case and that will actually help
start that thinking process of what else
could be attacked I need to upgrade so
it it does help plenty of incentive
everywhere and just getting it in terms
of where people don't feel like you're
attacking them and being at fault for
something that a lot of times it's
almost they've completely missed five
years of patch scheduling you know
sometimes I simplyjust hardware and
software issues that it wasn't
implemented correctly so that's that's
been my biggest thing actually in terms
of having access to start buying their
own their own ways of presenting symptom
management
I finish at 11:26 p.m. I started at 7
a.m. I finished what's happening right
now clear ok yes according two days
seasons whatever I feel like today it's
clear it's huge that will throw that out
there