much better
alright I thought I turned out ok good
morning sorry couple minutes late just
for me to figure out how a computer
actually works best companies do not
know how technology works so this is
this is a fun little talk that I'm
really happy when given it's kind of a
shame that asshat who plays for first
was in that black hat movie and then he
was in a Moby Dick movie as well so no
matter what I can't seem to escape the
the peril of that particular actor
forget his name at this moment which
shows you how much gary have been any
event at the final talk about whaling
and take a look at some really really
interesting aspects and I think one of
the most exciting and I can only say
that as a consultant as an investigator
if a business it's not an exciting
campaign whatsoever they are previous
consulting me does not let you get away
with an agenda but long story short
we're gonna talk about some cool stuff
so it's really easy summarized for the
most boring part of the presentation
I'll talk a little about who I am a
drama based out of dallas texas I'm
actually incident response consultant
but that doesn't mean I don't constantly
sit inside the third the red side of
things and like to have a lot of fun and
the number of times my wife has looked
at my home lab and asked me what in the
hell you actually doing it may not be
able to answer either has been way too
many times we've got a little kid home
so I'm regional hacker I like to think
she's already starting to think and
figure things out and completely blowing
my mind everything today which is fun
imagine are becoming standard starter as
well so I like to get back at night we
deny blog and I like to tell everyone if
anyone here has insomnia and you're
looking to get accurate just go and read
some of the stuff I've written
that are not be right out so you get to
go this is not meant to be a threat
Intel talk we're gonna talk a little
about it but this is not meant to
replace what should be a very
comprehensive and well designed threat
intelligence it's meant to track break
through an organization and then just
have some fun with the Mediterranean
investigators you can't just give me a
puzzle and I put all the pieces together
I'm done with that I want to know what
was in the picture what happened how was
put together I'm also not gonna try and
sell you anything free open source
please the only way to go I'm hoping
that it won't walk out of here with a
better tool kit they walked in with if
not please let me know and all that
stuff this is boring and I'll find a way
to change it I also do not know anything
about recent awesome CEO changes at a
company whose name rhymes with neier tie
or anything like that
paid attention some dude who wouldn't
want it out and some other awesome dude
who does it created that wasn't so let's
talk a little bit about why this matters
why should I care about this particular
campaign anyway here working for a
business of some sort not a concern when
you're not a consultant alright so a
couple so some of you your job is to
correct me if I'm wrong protect your
house
locker room ok you have a house to
protect why does this matter
January 2015 the FBI came out and they
started talking about these business
email scams and at that point in time
there's only about 2,000 victims and
only about two hundred and fifteen
million taken so in 14 months in the
attackers at successfully taken but not
bad not bad at all not bad for a little
more than a year's work dollar dollar
bill love it
bring that money in fast forward to
August 2015 the FBI updates their alert
hey guess what these guys have actually
stolen now closer to eight hundred
million on your math with end at eight
month time frame that close to six
hundred million dollars now I really
really like my salary oh my gosh ok so
these guys are pretty serious they're
able to take some money out of my wallet
let's get even more serious we had an
alert come out beginning of April of
this year we're now up to 17,000 victims
and in that time frame
we've got two point three billion
dollars stolen in a six-month timeframe
1.5 billion dollars stolen from these
businesses
power that targets with the school but
1.5 billion a little more sexy than 9
million so you know you can keep your
mouth phone use your days you're
persistent access I'm just gonna email
one PDF or walk out with a billion
dollars we need to care we need to be
aware of what these guys are doing
because guess what why does anyone here
know why rent somewhere so prolific
because it works
anyone saw Dave talking what I mean to
be hired to pay bitcoins porn agency
only proves one thing it works they're
ready to pay and the attackers are
making a ton of money I'm actually not
sure what happened with Tesla why
they're like you know what forget it
because everyone else what are some
random crap like version 9 and 10 just
rewrite the code and move on but these
guys apologized and gave up the source
and give up the master key but in any
event to make a lot of money so why stop
if you make a lot of money you're not
going to stop guess what anyone here
gotta protect our help someone else
protect the house this is coming it's on
your way that hasn't happened already in
fact and I really hope this doesn't
happen in this room but I've Davis
talkative b-sides event earlier and i
three people come up to me afterwards
hey that actually happened to me I
didn't know that how they don't tell me
publicly you just lost a couple hundred
grand reorganization reorganization lost
that hopefully they weren't the people
who actually got targeted and industrial
victim to it so we know why we should
care a lot of money walking out the door
I'm assuming that there's some towns and
some western parts of Africa that have
like ridiculous cars and houses and
everything around and we'll talk about
attribution just a little bit that being
said let's look at a little bit of what
these look like so I called whaling
because of their targets are not
necessarily whaling because our approach
and our goals are little bit different
but what is a little what is supposed to
a fish what is well we're targeting our
seats we are a high-level positions were
going after the big 12 pretty sure that
the casino term justice am going after
the whales inside your orientation
usually I want crowds I want access to
something or I want your money
emails and I'm to look like from someone
who you know and I might ask you to do a
thing right
hey can you cook this website my
favorite fish as well as you get these
days are are things like helped a girls
in the holiday photo
that is like a hundred percent success
rate Spearfish the other one is can you
believe these guys at this party last
week it's always like everyone wants to
go and tagged everyone and let them know
who they know how important there may be
a part of your job but it may also be a
little bit different from the norm but
it's moved information but it doesn't
really cause of concern for you you may
be asking yourself thanks for describing
fear spearfishing to me
cannot believe I am going to sit here
for an hour and watchu talkin bout
spearfishing not exactly the best
spearfishing the sharper spear very very
targeted and we deal with all of the
Nigerian Prince lottery winnings Graham
are really bad grammar targeted toward
the uneducated type of email that you go
after they're very very specific set of
ingredients inside of the skin number
one they're smaller businesses I'm not
gonna say a company like Google doesn't
get these emails but the Deathly not the
top of the target list number one number
two you need an incorrect domain
officials come from every single thing
you can think of anyone can spam from
anywhere but I need to have something
different and new CEO name and I need to
see a phony also need some random person
in some sort of accounting function who
doesn't want to piss off the boss so I
need to do a little bit of homework
ahead of time before I can construct
these and you can see the home work
being done as well so to get sorry let's
take a look at our second greedy and you
will know the difference between these
two but that was a space and the other
thoughts
space it's a fun change in it the one
instead of an so it looks like a space
number one however you can have a domain
name with the space so this is actually
legit email or legit domain that would
go through to the untrained eye right
which we are not we're trained eyes this
makes sense to us we can see the
difference we can see the transmission
of the change of letters and numbers you
can catch that one as soon as it popped
up with schemers is Vicky and all I need
to do with that info AB is a coat at the
same here know the full scope of domains
that one of their clients that their
company has mean have you registered in
BOS and businesses from aids moving or
illegitimate moving point of view are
you aware of what else the portfolio is
now there are so many deals that it's
really hard to keep up but guess what
this group of folks the ones who make
all the decisions on what you can do all
the money the ones who approve are
ridiculously tiny InfoSec budget they
are not trained they do not know what to
look for and your attackers are banking
on that they're banking on these people
looking at email and saying oh yeah yeah
whatever just go through its
heard some people call them the yes
crowd like everyone yelled shut up I
wanna run the program just go through
this is probably the same people who
back to Davis awkward just yet I don't
care let's go legitimate have work to do
number two we also need a website how
could i acquire one of these domains
registered
M one christophe dot com well in most
cases that we see with this type of
attack vector Vistaprint to the purveyor
and we're using the printer used it
before there we go
all right we're going we might even see
the photos from people who've been doing
that for you in ninety percent of cases
Vistaprint as a purveyor why number one
you can set up an account with a valid
credit card it's a one month free trial
but there is no activation know any sort
of charge not even a penny to validate
it whatsoever so all you need is
something that passes along check which
is i think what was the rain doesn't
back in there even super proud and if
you go right to the dot-com one of the
first banners you see is try one month
free if I've already done all my
homework new CEO or CFO I know which
took control over the accounting person
to hit him up
I need and we'll talk a little bit about
what the time frame I needed but I can
easily get it within a couple days
really like candy on Halloween is very
very easy for attackers to disabuse the
service which we obviously see them
doing I'm not going to rewrite the time
I can recreate the entire will need to
be who works for me is actually an
awesome post on he actually walked
through registering a domain and what
that looks like and how easy it is and
just how completely charge free and free
it actually is to do recommend checking
that out if if you're interested in you
know having a source to register a
website with no charges whatsoever that
you can drop within twenty nine days not
sure how they do with that but the
couple examples so Vistaprint there's
actually a website Vistaprint at TK that
hosts file called latest I JSON and at
that point in time it is the last 24
hours of every domain registered with
Vistaprint actually gotta get a box back
in the red grape I had nothing else to
do it so I haven't just every 24 hours
described in this town and then doing
some analysis on these domains I put a
couple of samples out here I don't know
if we're going to be easy to read on the
stream but long story short of a company
called Talon gurus someone right after
the website talent guru talent gurus
dotnet with an I between the final you
and yes and they also set up a gmail
account for it as well so if you've got
something like MarkMonitor some sort of
Domain Service thats registering domains
for you just so that attackers don't
squat while also registering a webmail
service with it well you don't need to
have that number may be it may be a
default setup done by Vistaprint but any
event you need that for the legitimate
service number two MarkMonitor to the
use Vistaprint register domains will
take a look at another one here
fucktard compression by the late either
of these companies in work that I
apologize this was not intentional
someone registered but our compression
with the final 0 actual final oh as the
numeric 0 so at some point in time again
set up with hope with with webmail now
again maybe someone looking to prevent
squatty but very very suspicious to see
this type of activity happening again
with the corresponding with now and I
were talking about whether he'll talk
about how attackers you this a thought
on this email you guys like
three or four sign anyone anyone notice
anything suspicious about this at all
I'll say that and actually no I tried to
make it look the best they could
number one this is not an actual forward
it looks like it
anyone here use Outlook 3 change into a
forward string and it starts to turn all
career knew this looks like an actual
for this is what people are expecting
see this is what your attackers are
expecting you to think gosh don't just
forwarded this and we hear of anyone in
the organization like the forward or
reply all King
those guys get targeted a lot your new
home seems like you know who I'm talking
about there's one dude just if there
wasn't a Reply All button he would not
send it you know they won't catch this
at the top Acme ABC and acne ACB it
slips by really quickly because you're
not looking at the from the two when you
first think about something suspicious
social engineering training doesn't
necessarily say hey make sure you check
these things out first is it from
legitimate person if you've got an email
are using something that accepts outward
and doesn't give you any sort of
internal or external notification your
subject lines you're not really gonna be
paying attention to that what else do we
have
4:56 p.m. on a Friday at the end of the
month
guess what that accounting person wants
to do right now go home and not
responding anymore emails they're done
they're completely tired they want to go
home they want to be finished with this
quarter this month and they want to move
on get on with their life there is a
reason that emails come in at that time
this email is made to look like it's
from gym who it's from Jim sent to Jane
and then Jane poured it on the John and
said hey James out can you please take
care of this transfer real quick because
we've got we've also got a PDF this is
where as a responder as an investigator
I start to get really really interested
in my heart finally an artifact it's not
just convoluted email letters email her
analysis is my gosh such a pain but it
can be super useful so we've just taken
what was a really really simple email
and I forgot to highlight too there's
one that always sticks out I see if
anyone catches it
there's always the grammatical errors as
well as the double space between the
haves and the a good weekend but it's
really really easy anyone can think of
how an attacker would get around that
of how that would not seem suspicious
anymore all I have to throw at the
bottom out email is sent from my iPhone
and all of its okay shes right now on
your iPhone you probably made around
that's what average people think would
happen I double tap space I'm busy I
have time to go back I'm already home
gonna boss you're still at the office
could you not so do this thing from you
real quick so let's take a look at our
PDF it what's inside
really really interesting stuff we get a
bank name we get a company name we get
back an account number and routing
number and we all forget who we should
be credited this too is this normally
how a business receives wiring
instructions they would receive
instructions its way I didn't think so
this is not normally how this type of
stuff is sent through so what's our
first kind of preventive step with their
first measure hey accounting department
I know you guys are InfoSec I know
you're not super super I T Town 21 not
but if you see wiring instructions that
come in the form of a PDF that looks
like it was written in WordPad WordPad
then converted to PDF real quick
you might want to just throw up a flag
real quick but what if people do instead
I want to piss off the bus and I want to
piss off the CEO I don't pass up the CFO
so I'm just gonna send this thing and
they're banking on that they're banging
that has to happen but let's move a
little bit past the deficiencies again
it's easy to complain much better to
start to turn around and fix it
let's take a look at these indicators
this is where as an investigator got to
have a lot of fun and start to build up
the metadata this attack group number
one let's talk about our situation we've
got a company just lost a hundred and
fifty grant counties in trouble bills
are being paid productivity lost how do
we take this bad situation and as
investigators are as a team we have a
little bit of fun with it
well we know that's right we easily know
that we can figure it out we deal in
puddles on a daily basis there's a way
that we can fix this so let's start with
artifacts we have a domain and you will
hear the domains gonna be any use to be
anonymously register to vote supreme
with a stolen credit card there's not
really much of anything out of that we
have a PDF
any use from the media and even think of
any properties of a PDF that maybe would
be really useful I'm gonna start with an
offer right anyone here have a window
when you use Windows ok are getting some
hands of someone that way that's good
when you register windows was one of the
first things that ask you for your name
when you install any application going
forward that has any sort of signature
tagging guess what name polls and had
been to that the name that you gave at
the very beginning let you go in and
change it or remove it so guess what the
name that you gave the beginning is the
name that is gonna pull we've got a
table we've got an indie 585 gonna be
any use not really a single PDF that was
sent to one company we've got machine
information we've got time stamps now
we've also got banking information so
we've got a lot of artifacts from the
tiny little somewhat useless PDF that we
can actually start to extrapolate on
other thoughts for the business do we
normally work with this bank
normally work with Bank of America and
Durham North Carolina at four oh four
bucks and drive which I hope is a really
really good address to be a great back
not been kind of thing does information
match expected financial dijo do we
expect to see this type of information
it does the vendor look familiar to you
even do business with R&R engraving
that's for the business you know there's
a lot of business considerations you
think about us for info so let's just
have some fun with this so let's lay the
foundation what information security
training teach people about PDF files
PDF too bad the really really bad be
very careful don't run anything so what
do people do with PDS then they upload
them to Mourdock omnipotent virustotal
and everyone says oh ok this PDF say
therefore I can open it I don't
understand how we got past the content
park and just that there's no Malvern
cited to see media on it is texting
easier for us think that lets users to
our advantage
let's take these open open source sites
you obviously can't get the source code
for my recital but you can use it freely
if you like let us know where their
metadata summer talking about this field
that you have embedded inside Wikipedia
I'm gonna start with the author so in
this case we got an author whose name or
who goes by the name boss law I don't
know what that is supposed to mean I'm
assuming he thinks highly of himself and
he's probably quite vain but we've also
got time same format as well this the
time things are going to mean much at
the moment only because they're so far
back but they do correspond to very
closely when we saw the breach happened
so I'm gonna take that into a right I
got one pedia what else has boss lot
done because this is a field that it
dumped in streams and is tracked by some
of these open source site seventeen
different results for Boston so now I'm
starting to build out boss launch PDF
portfolio of what he was creating what
he was designing as he was writing all
of his fishes overtime I can start to
number one there to track all the little
details we talked about earlier what
companies using what banks gon from
here's some examples we've got companies
like our engraving oriental wiring Cpl
wiry Rick Rickert wiring Sparta wiring
wiring as as a turn so knowing that
knowing what we know can we assume that
bar code works alone can we assume that
two point three billion dollars is
stolen by one guy with a Mac in a PDF
career most likely not think of any
other terms we could look for I can give
you a little here somewhat set out what
that about what exactly
wiring instructions so let's start to
look for wiring instructions what else
can we find on these sites that has the
name wire instructions so what I'm doing
now is identifying how this attack group
works and I'm starting to build a
profile of not only the author also how
they maintain their documents as well
let's take a look at now our focus on
our life just goes viral total sometimes
get a little funny Mauer has 55 results
of PDF files war with wiring
instructions inside the note these types
of searches can very very quickly spin
off the rails and extrapolate out of
control remember to keep your focus on
the documents that you're looking at
your focus on PBS your focus on what
looked like wiring instructions
Republican kind of weird random things
like we've got things in here
Autolite limited again oriental wiring
shows up now we've got Hong Kong well
incorporated so what did we find what
did we find as we went through this
research and as we started to map this
out I did this in about half
an hour here's the zoomed out view red
is authors yellow is documents
green is banks that they're using anyone
seen each Oak Point banks obviously are
the easiest ones but look at the number
of documents these officers put together
this is insane for now are we doing
we're building out what this group I
don't take gang but there's been some
news article that referred him as a gang
that that we start to build out what
this game looks like what they're the
things that they're going out we also
get additional authors from all this
information is well past the stage of
boss lot now
now look at these names compact houdini
raid kills with the disease and also
called the same you always amused great
because he put his entire full name and
all these documents
actually likes to target individuals as
well we see them into the pediatricians
so without again letting this been up to
par control each one of these now
becomes a search term for all my
different sites I use virustotal on mars
examples because they're a accessible
and easy to use but if anyone's got
proprietary sources are you got a good
API your searches can be even more
extensive and even deeper and hopefully
find more artifacts would also be fine
we found the bank that they like to use
as well
HSBC Bank of America these aren't
necessarily foreign banks to anyone hSBC
is a massive multi-billion dollar
company corporation however does my
company normally do business with HSBC
so I'm in a blue team and I'm trying to
find a way to check my organization from
this type of attack I wanna know things
like this because I want to tell the
accounting team what types of banks
doing normally work with who we work
with these banks if we do that we need
to wrap controls around we understand
what our attackers like where they like
to park their money let's make sure
we're not parking money there as well
and we are what make sure we understand
what we're doing with money that's part
there we only have two accounting SVC
for example outside of those two are not
interested in transfers some banks are
only used once and I apologize maybe a
little harder don't mean that we've got
some banks and only used one that makes
a some of the questions as well why are
they leaving him one
hSBC is used multiple times wire some
like China Citizens Bank only use one of
the attackers testing now the damn
you'll fail them you'll get arrested on
their way there but again it's a key
data points we want to know about
because it stand out at an omelet or
normal accounting behavior again it was
about 2013 out a twenty thirty minutes
of research that the last 10 with mostly
internal this kind of stuff we got
hundreds of results we built a massive
dashboard tons of PDF we're able to take
the campaign a little bit larger
actually a couple hours
fully diluted out and doing every single
circuit thing go and just got larger and
larger and larger to the point where I
need to stop cuz im just gonna spend
forever on this 2.2 million dollars the
lot of documents I come through those a
lot of fun doing up this profile but I
think what I really wanted to make sure
we focus on is the tools the track
profile visualized as a blue team as
we're starting to defend these networks
I need something inside of my network
that helped me protect and resurgent
access my information a lot better so
I'm just gonna start by saying this if
you're working in InfoSec and you're not
keeping notes on previous engagements
adversaries malware suspicious activity
whatever it is I hate the sprays you
doing it wrong I hate it but it works
you need to be given ot need to be
finding ways to keep data from point to
point the point is cumulative it is
that's why we have version it's not
everything virgin one night only just
been really something new we get better
as time goes on we can't be resetting
the clock as defenders red team and
especially consultants have a little
easier every single companies different
let me start over and find something new
you have to continually be going to
learn the vulnerable vulnerable to
report to my job and the number of
vulnerability reports are at like two
three four years old and every year the
same vulnerability over and over again
you have to keep militantly be getting
better that being said if you are
looking at doing threat intelligence
this is all you need just get yourself a
pew pew map 70 inch monitor inside of
your lab and you're good to go
that's it
honestly just getting this is probably
the worst I've ever done so that there's
if you are running a small company in
new orleans' China attack in england has
nothing to do with you whatsoever in
fact it's probably not even an attack
it's just ip-based correlation that some
companies spent all of their money on
their way here from north to get all of
their money on visualization and actual
products but how can we start but
certainly basic one of the best
note-taking tool is no pet there's
nothing wrong with handing over to the
person coming out for you or the guy
taking the shift over a text file with
your notes from that show is funny I a
lot of movies that you watch anyone here
watching like pirate movies are old
style like you know explore moving line
that they always have these things
called captains logs and it's always
like the most it's always the narration
of the story like captains log today
John Smith almost fell overboard and use
Jason Segel or something like that it's
like it's so trivial but if I was taking
over from the captain I wanna know why
john's leg is broken you know that
little tiny detail how me know that so
keep notes you can upgrade your game a
little bit if you want good notepad plus
plus you could even go back to old
school and just do diary journal and
penned the paper as long as you're
keeping notes that you're not keeping
notes right now start with something the
simplest form is better than nothing
always include enough information that
if you read it again you would remember
the event voice so that actually kind of
plays into report writing as well
every single artifact should stand on
its own every statement should be a full
sentence you should be able to reread a
page a year later I remember what
happened in that incident I remember it
because this just refresh me not because
I had to recall much stuff I'll remember
this work 0 percent of the time they
were here said I'll remember this a
hundred percent of the time they
remember to do that exactly I did not
think so no one ever if you do that you
deserve some sort of in a global world
also ahead again I hate this analogy hit
by a bus but it's a very good strategy
that works if you are the sole keeper of
some sort of key in your environment
some sort of threat in telling your
environment and you were to not show up
tomorrow and the company got attacked
tomorrow and it happened to be the
apocalypse of sick days
and incident response would your company
drought if they do you're doing your job
wrong you should be able to and again
you may be the most elite personal TV
but you still need to equip others
around you to be able to act without you
there you can really step your game up a
little bit and go to bed sheets
spreadsheets are really really good to
an Intel because they give obvious
correlation you can look at a
spreadsheet and immediately say ok this
role in this column matchup we're all
trained to think through various message
of school and websites to look at a
table and understand exactly what's
happening
allows you to mean relational data and
make it I can also find patterns and
inconsistencies much better there is no
AI machine in the world ever ever read
about ever seen ever demoed that can
beat me at identifying patterns anyone
here ever done any sort of malware
string analysis we're done any time our
analysis how much power analysis is
running something and then just
scrolling cause you're looking for
patterns there's no way I machine I can
say oh hey by the way I don't know if
you noticed but this alphabet decreases
in increases in letter that you go down
I can only see that just by looking
through your naked eye can see a lot
better you gonna pick up patterns a lot
faster so find a way to maintain it in a
way that lets you find these patterns
there's an example of expression to get
him a little bit hard to read what one
of the first things you notice when you
look at that table right there there's
two empty cells if this is the indicator
source tracking for my entire
organization why are there two cells
missing did someone forget to record
them do we not have them do not get that
file was that not available that day
what is going on
immediately you're looking for things
that need to be improved we can also
take a look inside to see similarities
between these hashes lineup I can do
sort they can do different types of
elation don't matter what makes
spreadsheet even more baller is
visualization
use multi go before awesome tool the
case file actually just became
completely available to do community and
more recently so I highly recommend
using this nation however manual TiVo
and I hate sin then right-click typing
right click typing record however CSV
tumulty go really really easy member
this guy this little table that you're
tracking so that kinda multicore real
quick and it's gonna pop out with a
with the graph some sort of
visualization this right here in 10
percent tutsi sweet tea sweets wanna see
that grabbed at the bottom and you can
see them pretty things like already is
the number of attackers yellow is a
number of documents and green in the
number of bank that's totally get it
there's a lot of shit going on I should
pay attention to this down the wake up
and all of a sudden those people who
make the decisions on all the money but
visualization not only helps us
portrayed better and let us speak to
other departments as well let's find
this checkpoint let us talk to our data
scientist who may be our organization
hey help me find where we can tweak our
processes and find things to look for
there's also really great threat
tracking platforms out there as well I
actually there's quite a few screenshots
and hear of a tool called threat note
was written by Brian where I might be
mispronouncing Brian's last name I I
usually say it different ways everything
what time it allows you to track
indicators of many different types and
he finds IP addresses threat accurate
it's an awesome tool completely free and
open source to get better every single
day he integrates it with tons and tons
of tools out there I highly recommend if
you're looking for a way to track but
can you find what you're looking for
something that helps you just keep track
of everything that comes through I would
recommend checking this out I also make
sure if you're keeping track of these
threats and your profile and things that
are coming to your advantage as well
make sure you're not keeping track of
the noise and labeling into the true
positive and to be there and do the foot
high that make sure you're not throwing
true positives in with blankets as well
some threat Intel reports come out and
get a hundred and eighty-five cinema if
you've got one and b5 hitting your
environment that does not mean you have
that apec may mean that they use the
variation of some sort of standing tall
that happens to be in there as well so
from a list of a hundred I've got one
indy five that an actual indicator for
me 99 that are you don't pollute your
own potential source that unfortunately
mr. Yin wrong direction
API is your friend as well maybe I can
be used to enrich our data provide more
context now no money coming from any guy
china is not for at Intel
North an indication of an IP address
coming from China that does not mean you
are being attacked by the Chinese it
simply means that a computer connected
to another computer and one of the ideas
of that computer was in china doll means
don't get hung up on paid for his unpaid
either all the research that we didn't
hear I built a 2.3 billion dollar gang
campaign and I did it all with open
source tools on the Internet a matter of
hours there is no paid tool that would
have helped with that whatsoever
maybe it would have been my searches
bathroom maybe I could have done a
command-line search as opposed to using
the web browser but doesn't necessarily
mean I was unable to do my job
don't get hung up on the paid receipt
young paid but do get hung up on the
value that provide power now malware is
not a threat intelligence source
whatsoever they do not claim to be it is
online Google Sandbox but all in it but
when I get out of our again I built a
campaign ago that a profile so find ways
to use these tools that are readily
available to you and find ways to take
data out of him that can actually help
you as opposed to not useless it doesn't
mean anything from you whatsoever that
being said I have to give an important
disclaimer if you do find brand new
malware
uploaded please all I had to work a
breach of that a bank a couple years ago
and not only was the bank extremely
targeted and under an active attack but
they also do not want to work with us as
consultant whatsoever
the only way we found out the attack was
still going on with my refreshing
virustotal string search is because they
would get now and upload the virus holes
every 15 minutes
attackers would deploy new malware
create a new empty five the security
team would find it there
upload the virus will and they were
going to block the 95 they did this for
about three hours before fine I came
back I said hey guys look we've been
watching you for three hours do all this
just by watching virus so you're
obviously not going to win if you're
just going to keep on blogging is just
what the attackers were going at five in
the exact same page we're looking at it
well just wait and see that being said
how do we start to get better we know
there's a massive campaign out there we
were able to build out indicators are
able to build a profile with his
attacker to look like we're able to fill
out a profile of how they work
what may be coming into my organization
so number one will expensive ass malware
detonation device help be
no not at all 0 day prevention banner
you thought our essay will be useless in
this case because it is just a PDF of
texts there's nothing in there that's
gonna trigger anything whatsoever unless
you're doing some sort of crazy OCR and
you're looking for banking on
information inside PCs in which case
more power to you will expensive a
threat intelligence help is any threat
intelligence service here going to tell
you by the way we spoke to some dude the
Nigeria you are going to get fish next
month so keep an eye out for no no one
is going to be able to do that how do
you know when you get hit you don't so
we have a little bit better
will a malware only focus help I think
they've made a really good point earlier
and I i wish i could have said it first
but virtually usually says it better
0 days are super super sexy any red team
was in the room 10 days have you used to
bring new number not not commercially so
far paid for paid engagements you don't
need your own is again why are we
focusing all of our activity on all my
gosh you guys see that talking black hat
we need to make sure we're defending
against the super super elite exploit
that was developed in a lab by a bunch
of students who have no jobs and lots of
time and we're not defending against
this our organizations gonna be at risk
no problem
anyone here give any information
security training to the accounting
department gained 2.3 billion dollars
means don't look in your environment and
think about where your weakest links
actually are again I hate coming back to
the old adage of people people people
people people are people on trains
therefore they're getting it but now it
there's a lot of exploitable code up
there you're right there's a lot of
weaknesses found and yes there was
recently a security company who was
found to be running the patties route
and allowed for a couple exploit it turn
into a massive discussing legal
situation can't comment on that but in
any event yes there's a lot of crap out
there that happens in that puts people
in bed or bad situation however start
with start internally started beating
again if your job is to protect your
house then look at your house and say
where am I actually vulnerable here are
you going to pack everything web server
in the world are you going to get
complete security control over the
development
no they don't care they want everything
open they want everything to be by the
fall they can write scripts and they
want API's to be a simple what else
should we be doing to get better we
should be sharing this information
sharing it actually caring like this is
a very sentimental slide probably
because the puppy dogs carrying his dick
on there together something as prolific
at eight hundred million began now we're
up to 2.3 billion should not be news it
should not be the first time you hear
about a multi-billion dollar global
email scam the first time you get hit
should not be the first time you hear
about it we need to be paying attention
to what goes on out there again is a
smaller organization going to see the
same threats as citibank or as Google or
as a porous Facebook no they're not so
don't act like you're going to as well
and that's not to be demeaned anyone its
focus on what you're actually gonna be
targeted with what actually become a few
what that's going to be coming for you
krebs should not be your ideas it's like
this joke that started I don't know if
it was swift unsecured I don't know how
I got started with someone came up with
the phrase of Brian Krebs my IDs and got
turned to like t-shirts and bumper guys
an international press release about
your fault should not be your idea I
know it's meant in jest but at the same
time it should really be your goal is to
avoid that and it's funny to now I have
worked on a lot of financially motivated
cases people a call when you get all
this done before credit reports us like
that that's your motivation for finding
an attacker in stopping fraud in your
environment so that Brian Krebs as a
tweak your name out there we need to be
a little more concerned with what's
actually going on here not only is
sharing caring and avoiding krebs my
ideas we should also not be embarrassed
to admit what happened as well
blanket statement here I'm not asking
any company to give out any proprietary
information but it is ok to say you can
spare fished it is ok to say where you
were touched on the doll it's alright we
are all being targeted every single one
of us in some way shape or form whether
its 10,000 Nigerian print email that day
or whether it's someone coming after my
c-suite because they want to steal X
amount of dollars from my environment
we're all being targeted
it's ok to admit increases and decreases
a new campaign it's ok to share those
with others as they went here doing any
sort of industry base or collective
burden-sharing I don't mean you signed
up for threat connect anything if they
were here doing any sort of cross
company industry sharing see there's
ways for us to set up and share
indicators between organizations and say
hey other people who are in the small to
medium-sized you know oil and gas
business in the New Orleans area we just
got fishing we just lost $250,000 here's
what we learned here's what you guys
should be ok now for its ok to share the
details it's not embarrass easy it's
embarrassing when you get hit again and
again and again and again it's
embarrassing when krebs tweet about you
it's embarrassing when the FBI uses your
name as the case study for this story
it's not embarrassing to call up someone
that you play golf with every weekend
and just say hey by the way we got
attacked you should know about this it's
ok to share indicators here's the PDS
here's the names whose the bank accounts
get your county department we can all
start to collectively raise it up a
little bit not only are we sharing now
we've got a way to track and share as
well we have tools we have platforms
there was definitely a period of time
when it was very very difficult to
maintain a comprehensible set of
indicators is very difficult to maintain
actionable intelligence in my
environment those tool now exists in
their free and open source and they're
darn easy to install you when you're not
running Python set up I all right you
can almost all connected on out there
and you can always call threat
intelligence platforms very open source
very simple and last but not least I
think one of the most important
considerations your organization is not
expecting you they're not asking you to
become a threat intelligence experts
here signed a contract that says line
one you will be a threat intelligence
expert go back and renegotiated you're
gonna have a really really tough time
with that no one asked you to do that
but you are being asked to protect an
organization so again focus on what
you're actually being asked to do focus
your your research on that focus your
indicators on that because you're
tracking on that and you gonna find
yourself a lot more successful again I
hope no one in this room has been hit by
the scam but if you have think of ways
your organization grow and learn from
that and kind of a little encore part
sometimes it does get better that's
really really frustrating to put
together an entire case anyone here ever
lost the case to the FBI ok all your
very very lucky then I did investigation
a few years ago it actually turned out
to be apt 19 out work for many who
released all that but we are about three
months into a massive investigation of a
huge engineering company and we got all
the way through got the report written
got this beautiful analysis done we had
to know the whiteboard thing it looks
like CSI cyber inside there that's a
legit we work and it's just crap
everywhere pins are bred string all
kinds of with the whole thing mapped out
from soup to nuts and i cant in one
Monday morning and it was all gone all
taken away and I was like went to my my
possible time and I said hey it's like
six months of research and analysis and
an active investigation and active
attacker what the hell happened there I
call ya the FBI came in and took over
the case so we're officially done go
find another engagement to work just
like Monday morning done thanks a lot I
was really really upset at the time but
you know you get over things and then
something cool like this happens a
non-member the name called the same you
that we found inside of our pts guess
what January 2016 cold it's got arrested
so all of this and other we used
actually turned into something I i
worked probably about 10 to 15 of the
cases that they are crossed multiple
different states but I was able to help
put together the case that the FBI
eventually actually some of our report
text became what they put final press
release which is kind of fun but it does
get better I know sometimes it seems
very very futile to go through all this
you lose tons of money you spend hours
you lose a lot of sleep family misses
you all kind of stuff and you like this
was just a little fraud case but
sometimes it does get better sometimes
we don't just have an indictment of a
Chinese people and then it just gets
left that which is a funny joke into
itself but in any event he's now in
custody in Dallas I can only go visit
him to these days where I live in this
research and I'd love to know kind of
before happen you know how do you guys
talk about this but I doubt he'd
probably give me an information but it
was nice to see a lot of this research
actually come to fruition and then
someone is arrested this guy who's
stolen somewhere in the vicinity I think
he was about twenty thirty
himself he's looking at like 30 years in
jail and fines mark and stuff so again
there's sometimes a light at the end of
the top and then there are the particle
the end of the rainbow with that
everybody in this thank you very much to
number one everyone attending really
really hard to complain about being a
conference in New Orleans it's a
beautiful here and thanks to everyone
who helped out with the tools as well as
I mentioned that I love with any
questions if there are any and thank you