today right and are going to give a
speech part of espionage 2016 addition
the speech and topic that we've been
talking about cost twenty years I've
done this speech by title believe this
is year sixteen so what we try to do is
give you guys a basic primer on what you
need to do prevention and the kind of
like tricks and things that we can to
teach people on our day one so if you
were to get hired on to our team and
work with our our practice this is kind
of the basic stuff we'd run you through
that first day we kinda like doing this
more as a form type discussion with the
room so if you have questions during the
conference please feel free to or rather
presenting please feel free to raise
your hand and shout out you know it's we
rarely make it to the queue a section of
the slide deck especially in an hour
long format because I talk too damn much
and I he ends up telling stories so
alright so that all going to go down and
see who we are and say why we're
discussing this talk about the myths
fables and bullshit that exists in the
industry right now that keep getting in
the way we talk about how you can become
a spy and working in red team will talk
about how the changes over the last 10
years that we've observed in this
industry a kind of changed how we
approach our attacks and what we do
we'll talk about the actual process of
the attack itself which is the larger
media section of this where we stepped
through the individual kind of the the
life cycle we love how to conduct the
work and we'll talk about how to tell
the story of your client where they can
actually appreciate and understand the
assessment you've done to our way right
and I are best friends we've known each
other for twenty-plus years
we hang out and work together on and off
in various roles in various different
companies currently at this moment he's
my boss which kinda cool but we we've
been around and work together for a very
long time this industry as a collective
though were part of a larger 303
organization which I like to give credit
to the start of every one of my speeches
because I didn't belong to a larger
organization like 303 I would have had
the opportunity in time to learn a lot
of the stuff that I'm learning so what
about trying to do it on my own so I
want to credit everybody in that picture
her for their knowledge contribution the
years but we're discussing today we're
not going to talk about contesting
basics vulnerability assessments
incident response out case doesn't go
through and exploit moment you guys have
some of the best in the world
available this conference you can teach
you these things that's not what we're
here to do today here we're here to
discuss how to not suck espionage red
teaming some more importantly when will
I see you guys again mindset there to
get an idea of the mindset necessary
when performing regime testing which
part of that is staying fluid adapting
to change because no matter how many
plans you have that's not gonna happen
red teaming to define a conservative
bunch of different definitions
combination of physical social and
logical testing to make sure that things
are going to react the way to clients
expect them to win their action when
they're under an actual attack so the
idea of a network meant as a similar
meeting up in making sure that firewall
is the way most people more time I read
teaming we're combining fishing in and
lying to people in dressing up as UPS
guys and clock ticking and everything
else to make sure that all of all of the
assets they have in place to protect
against people like us will work we
expect to find the gaps and helping
mediate one of the biggest reasons we
want to include the slide is because
we've now for the last 34 years so the
new trend where people are starting to
use the term red team to describe
internal testing and were being part of
an internal security team that is not
the definition we're using today
running Nexus is not red teaming is a
very very small small small part of
retaining the Miss tables and bullshit
that we all deal with all of your in
this industry guys here this everyday
people sit there and say they're not a
target they have never been pwned that
hackers wanna put them out of business
next-generation security solutions gonna
fix blah blah blah all these different
things that you see on the screen but
shit and you guys know that because you
see it all the time you can deploy your
next generation signature-based solution
and it's not gonna stop us single bit of
a day you can sit there and you can tell
me that hackers wanna put you out of
business naughty all day long you're a
liar because hackers if they compromise
you want nothing more than access to
your data bandwidth everything else out
of business would be the opposite of
what they're trying to accomplish truth
is though that you really need to keep
in mind as we do this talking as we go
through this because a lot of what we're
introducing in teaching you guys
intentionally low-tech basic stuff is
that if a motivated to hack motivated
Tiger wants to get in there gonna get in
so you know again going back to the idea
of why it's physical logical and not
just one or the other
all these areas whether it's financed
with its hospitals whether it's a small
mom-and-pop shops it's about protecting
the data data doesn't just rely on the
internet doesn't just resign on a
computer printout fundraiser resides in
people desperate resides all over the
place in the plane's protect the data
credit card numbers on the health
information whatever it is that is vital
to that company's operations she want to
be a spy we love this because when we
talk to people who aren't in the
industry they listen to what we do we'll
show them sanitized deliverables are
sanitized videos that we can share
that's part of our speeches and things
like that and they're always like you
guys like a real world spice it's like
you guys are sneakers for real on the
truth matters both Ryan I love that
movie and when we were younger that was
one of the movies that helped kind of
influence our direction of where we went
professionally with our work was that we
we saw a lot of people in this industry
that we're out there to check a box
search to run a tester to get the thumbs
up they've done something good
but we didn't see was application of
attacks that were very real world based
meaning that if somebody was actually
going to target UN come in and an attack
your business they're not gonna sit down
with your sexy c-level executives at her
own room table and ask you questions
about things they're actually going to
attack your business so the first big
step we gotta do in order to be able to
do that is get smart as as all of you
know this this job requires you to be a
jack of all trades you can't just be
good a pen testing you can't just be
good at fuzzing you can't just be good
at lock picking you have to do a little
of all of that to be able to apply that
put it together to be successful this
work
one of the big things that we've started
doing is pushing people towards looking
at the industry developed and supported
standers so you've got HIPAA
sarbanes-oxley you have ISO 27001 02
you've got all these different PCI
requirements exist around credit card
processing now so you as an attacker
need to start looking at the different
industries and verticals of your clients
because that's the kind of thing that in
the end when you're delivering the
report you're talking to them about what
you did that's the stuff that's going to
make it matter to them they don't give a
shit how cool you are and how quickly
picked through that lock they care that
on the other side of that lock was a
datacenter hold of their PCI environment
and their PC I didn't you could have
gotten every single credit card
transaction simply by being able to pick
that nor you have to be able to type
that stuff together when you tell your
story and when you wanna get educated in
these are good things are good learning
spots but at the same time don't rule
anything out so beaches like this will
teach you some hopefully but there's
books that are that have nothing to do
with red teaming because there's very
little out there on regimen actually but
example one of the books I just picked
up is called the burglars guided the
city it's written by an architect it's
an amazing book talks about how burglars
have to actually used the architecture
building to break into it gives you a
different way of thinking it makes you
start seeing things a little different
that's the kind of stuff you wanna start
reading more
junior conferences your social
communities near hacks basis again just
like I said at the start of this slide
deck I i thought i was cool shit chillin
starting now 303 and it made me realize
how long
credibly quickly I was in New because
there's just no matter how good you get
something there's always going to be
somebody better and if you have an
opportunity to come together with those
people and learn and share knowledge and
information what a great way to learn
and get better yourself or drink a lot
we end up doing a lot of other great
source of Education obviously security
to.net has is kind of the YouTube of
security videos out there like to give
him a thumbs-up because they've put a
lot of work and effort into making not
data available for all of you
offensive security Metasploit unleashed
is a great great primer for people to
start with that they've never done
contesting her ever played with the
basic tools that is offered via
Metasploit and then obviously da condo
rogues a great one to Jeff Moss is made
it to where all speeches have been
recorded and published so you got 24
years of slide content speeches of the
best in the world city of you talking
about what it is that they do so please
take advantage of these free resources
and we end with getting certified which
kinda you know everybody in the industry
certifications whatever its peace paper
but the truth of the matter is when
you're going in front of Fortune 100
clients largest banks in the world and
you're trying to demonstrate to them the
value that you can do the work that you
can you can conduct for them it's
important to have those letters behind
your name because those letters do mean
something to the executives the AHR
people the people that are gonna be
responsible for hiring you so as much as
as a group we can also hearing kinda go
on paper that's actually good technical
choosing the rest of ya it's important
to make sure that that you got it near
where the spending time and resources do
this if you're wanting to do it
professionally so long the same lines
giving skilled so
people like digging and they did not
easy thing to do with blocking is
practice that's all it takes you don't
have a 200 piece by pick set the ought
to have crazy mother videos it's
literally just buying lots more hardware
store and is practicing over and over
again same thing with the NLP stuff for
the social engineering stuff it's
getting used to his being comfortable
its practice your practice social
engineering going to a bar gonna be
somebody you're not going and and get in
that might start getting yourself in the
minds of that person who goes to be
specified a practice
loves those tough to the survival
training is a bit much mister go right
over here staying staying healthy is not
a bad idea cuz when you're not healthy
start doing especially some of the more
physical aspects of the stuff you're
gonna fall and hurt yourself
military law enforcement training I put
up here mainly a lot of people can
discover that but the cool thing is that
if you join the right mail lists and get
on the right Facebook pages in this kind
of thing you'll find a lot of this
training is freely available for anybody
that signs up you don't actually have to
be a badged Ali were a mill officer in
order to take this training and and
paying attention to stuff like that got
it to where I was able to watch Frank
Abagnale talk about the work that he had
done before joining the FBI a few years
back simply because I was on the right
mail list at the right time so it's a
double take advantage of it
challenges duck pond games obviously we
have the challenges here there's ETFs
here that you guys to participate in
tools here you've got a great
opportunity to be able to learn how long
before if you are gonna lock picking you
got an opportunity to be able to compete
person time opportunity to the people
that wins the urban exploring climbing
rappelling you can skip the being Batman
part no one has that much money but the
urban exploring it could be quasi legal
depending on where you're going there
did you start thinking about things
along this virtually abandoned building
to start making it look at things seeing
ways into a
and paying more attention to your
surroundings and in game to play home
games complete home so I put that in
there out of that because I i do things
I do challenges of my kids like my boys
are now 17 and 15 years old that since
they were 56 years old
age you know I've done the basic stuff
like teaching lockpicking and you know
evasion and getting around things single
boot mode in Lenox all the cute little
parlor tricks that we all know news but
one of the things that really been
beneficial of my children and not just
with this type of work but in their
overall life is helping them get
situational awareness so we play games
were all walk into a room or they're
playing video games not be like hey guys
and I'll make them turn around and look
at me and I'll talk to me about
something and then I'll change stuff in
the room and I'll come back in five ten
minutes later and I'll be like when I
change and you'll watch the kids cuz
everytime I go when I changed since they
say that they go because they know they
have to look up pay attention really pay
attention
look at what has been modified in their
surrounding be able to pick it out when
I first started playing with this this
game with my kids and their 56 years old
it was horrible
they can never ever pick it out they
could never ever see what was going on
now that they're teenagers and they get
a little older it's frightening because
I make even like tiny little changes
like turning something that sitting on a
shelf and they'll pick it up and notice
it because they've program themselves to
constantly be aware of their
surroundings in their environment by
designing some of my daughter will go
into russia or something I'll change
rooms will go to a different cell maker
sketch out the last room like where the
laws where the source she hates it but
as a good job of making sure that the
biggest point here is to make sure that
we're talking to a company and position
ask the right questions to make sure
that you're going in the right position
and then the position that you're
thinking of going into
is what you're looking for companies
like to describe things in certain ways
and then kind of shift you need
something else you want to make sure
that for example if you think you're
going into the red teamed up to make
sure that they have a methodology
documentation template see you there
have a team or not just the only person
that suddenly doing this neighbor never
sold it
may have happened a couple of times
bigger than what we see is that people
want to get into this work they think
it's interesting they go to the great
and then they go and they get an entry
or the princess level light penetration
testing drop and get pissed because they
spend ten years learning how to hack
local networks and never ever once to
any bit of red tape the big thing that
we find that really kind of pushes that
are the safety figures as we like to
call it where you've got these companies
that love to put titles and descriptions
about what the work is but it's actually
not what they're doing are conducting I
can't tell you the number of times that
we've talked companies that you
penetration testing and all the newer
motor village assessments or companies
that say they're doing red teaming and
an internal development threat programs
and they do a very basic contest make
maybe some dogs are used to work for IBM
years ago and they would say we do you
do physical penetration testing when he
was water and they reject Lions
occasionally and idyllic do this again
and then legally get a hold on it
not know we don't do that thats rich and
liability so it's it's tricky questions
make sure you know what you're getting
at
remembers you do this job is the time
equals change when talk about this
little bit as we go through this but a
good way to look at his I took this
picture in 2006 for the same speech
these were the tools of the trade you
can see that I've got a radio I've got
an old PCMCIA wireless Orinoco cards up
there for cracking WEP all this great
stuff right and at the time that I took
this picture this was literally cutting
edge talk the tool Dr the type of stuff
that we are using has an entire RFID
cloning
actually this newest last a long time
still have that backpack but nowadays
when you look at what's going on
everything can fit in your pocket I mean
this is a pretty standard setup here
I've got a pump at all the individual
tools are very very small collection of
pics you can see there just like ron was
saying my previous slide deck you're
looking at you know $300 worth of pics
and all this crazy vision stuff I've
broken it down to a southern ordinance
kit that's just all I ever really need
one of the biggest things that you'll
hear from us as we go through this is
it's really easy when you first start
doing this work to just 12 pack like
five or six backpacks full of every
single be security and then you realize
when you go to the work that really all
you needed was a strong shoulder and
credit card right through the door so
the key is really make your make your
way count think about what it is you're
bringing why you're bringing it how
you're going to use it with the
likelihood is that you're going to use
it and how screwed you'd be if you
didn't have it that's really the big
thing that makes a decision no matter
how much more stuff you carry the more
you have to dig through it
find the right thing you looking for I'm
trying to get over this for a minute so
eight years ago wow we get that TV show
Tiger Team last two episodes of this
episode we had to break into a jewelry
store in Beverly Hills what we're doing
right now as we couldn't leave his way
to bypass the front door was going to
clone the guys I RFID card and a friend
of ours at bill this RFID cloning kit
which that's literally one of the first
in the world there was massive and heavy
and shit in that backpack and then you
have a cable that snaked down your arm
that upon the reader and you get really
close like almost grabbed the guy's ass
which and that's what they show is Luke
revenue guys asked why I always make
sure that you know you know you'll see
it in a couple of size but like RFID
cleaners now i think is bad we walk off
there's a lot of talk going on here but
the big thing to take away from this is
that when we did this testing and I
talked about this a little bit when we
did this testing before really there was
a handful about three or four people in
the world that we're looking into how
widely technologies were producing
equipment we're doing the work as a
cranking out amore those guys were
really killed it with our affiliate I
think it was called back but they were
really doing some research and work
they're presented on a blackout on it
and it kind of got us interested that
unit that's my backpack was put together
by dulcis another 30 three year and it
took him five months of testing in plane
to get to where he could capture card
and replay a single card using Adam and
acts like researched it to be able to
put that together for us and build it
and if you noticed a huge took an entire
backpack it was super hot as the other
thing that was interesting is to
generate enough enough current for us to
be able to use those readers like it was
three or four lantern batteries like
linked together in parallel and then
like going through voltage regulator
just to have enough charge to walk out
on the street from the batch walk back
to the car and pray to God the battery
connection to disconnect somewhere in
between we woulda lost everything
together the best thing to look at is we
can only capture one card at I'm at best
it was impossible
realistically to rewrite your own cards
that point most of us if we were doing
card rewrites all we're actually doing
was calling the company that produced
the cards and saying hey this is our
site
idea and we also need these card numbers
from this point to this point and we
would do these orders of hundreds of
dollars that would be overnight shift
where are all these little cards just be
able to hack 1 RFID card RFID card sorry
replay attacks were very reliable with
portable year at the time but now with
it being 2016 obviously we've got the
process mark three hits in your little
tablet I modified the tablet and I'm
using testing the testing software
that's inside for playing with your box
marked be able to log every single
region out makes it to where one carry
this little reader that's about this big
I can literally locked thousands of
cards as I walk through an area if the
battery dies it doesn't matter
already logged off I'll go back home
into the night I can sit there and write
these out to the various to discard the
right to the other things taking
consideration that handheld RFID writer
on there we all looked at it we've seen
it I've actually seen one work in real
life everybody looks at him and China
for $9 but I've actually watched one
work on an engagement and even cooler as
the Blue Key as he sat down there in the
lower corner what once was a backpack
full of beer for us to be able to
hopefully be able to do something is now
something the size of a quarter of the
you can place inside of an RFID reader
in the news your phone to be able to
trigger it to replay people's
connections as they come back through
pretty neat stuff the other way to look
at it is that backpack full of your was
almost $2,000 worth of research and work
put together
proxmire or the parts Mark 30 along with
tone pad set up that I've got theirs by
$1,000 worth of hardware to do it right
handheld RFID reader was 10 bucks I
think and the Blue Key
like 25 bucks or something if you get a
few Bible cover but it really just kind
of goes to show that it's one of the
things you need to think about his as
you're doing this work and as as things
at camps so we're going to be the
attacks or gonna be your approaches all
that stuff is is going to get different
and and you have to modify your approach
throughout the years so did the general
we love attack
prepared and ice ice a charge your phone
because your phone at this point is
pretty much the lifeline of a test you
have to communicate with the team
members have to collect evidence may not
always be allowed to walk out the door
with people working computers and shit
yet to take pictures videos etc to prove
what you were able to do your own due to
phone because we're talking on it when
you're pretending to talk on it and it
actually rings people notice and it's
loud it's been especially don't don't
charge your phone have a backup battery
too I just was on and get her last week
where my coworker is sitting under a
desperate four and a half hours and so
he couldn't text me that the lady inside
the office had noticed me even move my
car in a parking lot so that wasn't the
same spot she had noticed me and called
the police and he wanna sex me but his
phone died so he couldn't tell me the
police showed up that actively don't
look at part of the reason that you
don't see us using the big big antennas
and ham radios anymore and why we sit
here and tell you to use your cell phone
looks out of place you don't wanna walk
in looking like you're a spy looking
like your bed looking whatever it is you
want to blend in
but you need to be thinking and acting
tactically will you do this work
one of the biggest things that I watch
new people make a mistake with doing is
dole walk into a rumor an area that they
don't belong in that they should have
been in someone's there they do the
worst in the world
they pause they look scared they turn in
a walkout versus just walking in and
owning the the room
owning the area keeping it simple so
this is something when you're doing red
teaming this is not a threat clients it
shouldn't be a one-time thing should be
something that's never happened every
year every other year is the ideas you
start really low keep the lowest of the
low tech as if you start off RFID
cloning and going crazy and super
high-tech specially client has never
done this before and they're gonna read
it freaked out and not know where to
start fixing shit on the shelf and never
talk to you again if you start with
simple things hard shaming you may be
some lockpicking social engineering
tailgating is still a huge problem
start with a simple shit let them have
time to fix that given recommendations
on the simple things start off cheap for
them is usually cheap fixes for that
then they'll come back the next year you
made it more difficult yourself that
makes it more fun for us to know I want
to keep doing the same shit every year I
want to get to the point where
eventually you are like you're
stretching really having reached for how
the hell you to get in this building or
how they're using the flag to the point
where you can give a report and maybe
you got the flag but you can also tell
my clit based on your company based in
the threats that exist for your company
no one's going to ever really do this if
they do here's how to detect it because
you can't stop and remember number for
your the criminal this is your job like
your job is to replicate a real-world
attack criminals do not walk in I said
this earlier but criminals do not walk
in and sit down at a large desk and do a
system of checks and balances to make
sure that you've got a firewall
installed they're gonna walk into your
front door and they're going to pick the
easiest targets of opportunity and
that's what they're going to attempt to
exploit and steel but started
information gathering this is mainly
online you go through it we've got you
know Google Maps and movers and
LexisNexis social media is also a huge
every company has social media presence
as you want to know what they're bad
looks like to look through Flickr look
to the
Facebook account you'll see a picture
someone wearing a badge duplicated
exactly you make it look close enough
that when someone classes at it they see
the green panel with the black waters
one of the other things do is check out
the website of the company that you're
hiking going back into looking at the
pictures like he's talking about various
company events it'll tell you what kind
of dress they have what kind of clothing
they where you know are there a lot of
people that have big beard and Mohawk
sit at the place that you're walking
into or is it all really clean cut
people that look like they just walked
out of church those are things for you
to know your everyday on-site clients
wherever reason love to brag about who
they used for using Cisco Dell or go to
a true story by Adele sure and you're
there right in the front so when we
started this work and started doing this
work 1996 1998 timeframe we didn't have
all these online auctions we actually
had to go to do like you'd go to county
records and public service searches need
these types of things but sometimes be
able to pull data and information about
about these businesses now with Hoover's
LexisNexis Google Maps you can literally
with Google Street View can walk around
the facility over and over again before
you ever even there any liability on
site recon same kind of thing you know
we've all seen the pictures and videos
of people sitting out in the car and
done it for 10 to 12 hours where you sit
there with a little piece of paper
recording what's going on
modern times now guys there's no reason
to do that you can put a drone out and
you fly a grown up above the business
you imply a drone near the business
these things are fairly silent anymore
get the right ones makes it really easy
click the whole bunch of information
very very quickly without having to
reveal your identity or location I don't
know if you guys can really appreciate
it but the middle picture that I have
there is a glass window that someone is
a whole bunch their notes and passwords
and other types of things on make sure
that you have a clean desk clean board
policy people laugh at me about this
when I say this but I cannot tell you
the number of times that we've gone to
businesses and they don't realize that
just because they can see out during the
daytime and not seeing when the standout
smoking a cigarette doesn't mean that
that's the way it is it might if flights
are left on and you're sitting
a mile away and you've got one of his
camera lenses that he just bought for
this job you can literally take
high-resolution images the glass
multiple floors up of what people have
on the boards it's a great way to get
access to different things inside the
business the other thing is we still a
lot of dumpster diving again you guys
watch the Tiger Team thing you saw
examples in real-time bus like going
through bloody tampons and god knows
what else just food given this world's
done now days we have secure Benz that
everybody supposed to put their
documents into the cool thing is you can
usually open them with a flat head
screwdriver because the stupid hinges on
them they can have a nice big fat lock
on the front hinge on the back to
literally just pulled out looked up the
other way and use the longest the hinge
but the cool thing about those sensitive
document Benz is that you're guaranteed
to be getting gold because no one would
take the time to walk away from their
desk and thrown in there it wasn't
something critical and important target
selection obviously got some pictures
there these are things that we looked at
the only real one that I want to call
out here is that lower one with the
brick wall a lot of people ask me why
that pitchers in there you know
obviously got one here tailgating shown
examples where renews alarms to stop
like elevators to get on the course that
the the one on the lower part they're
the reason I showed that is that the
building architecture itself actually
provided me with the series of stairs
that I was able to use to get up to the
second floor where none of the windows
word they'd only thought about actually
locking in securing if you look at the
window that's right below there until
it's like nasty hardened lockdown window
all the ones that are above it on like
the second and third story just
literally go up so when you're talking
to a client began the project you need
to stop black whether that's a deal
whether it's the building for 30 minutes
of you could be anything but they're
still it can't be just as you break in i
mean that's fine but they're doing it
professionally cuz you still actually
opted to buy buy a scope what is the
client said that you can and cannot do
and it's really important to make sure
that you clearly defined that before you
start breaking into their especially if
they've never done before because they
might think this really cool but they
don't really understand what put
contracts are used against them to make
sure your conversation among casual
usually do no rule in or rule out what
you can and can't do and that's fine you
have to you know last week was a bank
they ruled out lock picking and the use
of specialized tools which kinda limited
so I used a pizza and a coat hanger in
the middle of water broke in big thing
to think about to us when you're doing
this professionally how much time you
out unlike criminal you can spend months
maybe even years I'm planning to do a
large coordinated to talk when you do
this professionally are usually given
somewhere between five to 10 days to
actually executing do the work you have
to work very very quickly and I will not
sure how did it all for you if you come
and work with us or any of the other
teams that really special in this type
of thing you will not have a two hour
workdays days holds 16 to 20 hours when
you're doing this work and and that is
just for you to have enough time to get
everything done that you need to get at
the same time you're really into it
you're not going to want to sleep and
even when you try to offset weak we can
do this and you can leave the hotel in
just gonna try to meet when discussing
the flag and the important things with
the client really talk to them about
what's critical for their business to
operate who gives a shit if you steal a
whole bunch of credit card information
if it turns out that it's all being
processed by a third-party processor
never ever want such as their
environment but they may be very very
interested about the fact that you just
don't two hundred and twenty people they
charge data about their medical records
about social security numbers home
addresses phone numbers that stuff means
more and that's really the key is why
you're talking to your client you're
trying to kind of scope the South
understand what's most important to them
planning will get into this little bit
more but the big thing to look at here
is that I i put this crowd in with
priestly because the big deal I've done
assessments with various people out
there I give a lot of respect to the
different people I work with but I've
met some people who are really hardcore
in this industry that have to plan a
plan B Plan C plan D plan and it becomes
this huge massive pre-planning when the
truth of the matter is you just have to
be able to be flexible so noticed the
stiffest tree is most easily cracked
while the bamboo for the willow survived
by bending in the wind really made that
quote it's absolutely true in a way that
we approach this look at it almost from
a martial arts standpoint of your
wanting to be able to see the threat
that's coming out you wanna be able to
react as quickly as possible approaches
and stuff will come out in europe online
training you're not talking tom cruise
once I hope his one-time got actually
repeal of the building to get into it
one time in 20 years of the work
planning and preparation so my favorite
thrift stores you'll probably find all
sorts of their employees that have left
a given to them are now or the crime
themselves gave to him when they were
trying to be nice and they changed the
new logo that is again with a Bachelor
play with a business cards of all these
things
if you can collect online before and you
can start making all this plan again be
waiting for you go on site for now
business cards easley no doubt bad as
ginkgo ginkgo is your friends everywhere
has a Kinkos and they're open 24 hours
planning the attack so when you do
you're actually on site were doing the
vulnerability insight analysis thing you
need to be thinking about is how are you
gonna get in without being seen wearing
a deal with the various security
controls it exists and and how are you
going to locate what it is that you're
looking for when the most interesting
things will bite you in the ass on your
first day doing this job is you broke
into the building you're in the facility
now now what if you don't never for plan
if you don't know where the data centers
out if you don't know where the
administrative offices are at your just
wandering in the dark and that shows in
back with that there has been flagged as
there is no flag you even know where to
start the first line of getting without
being seen that might be worth looking i
differ I don't care if I'm seen if I
already got away trade you a video tapes
of me doing something that maybe I'll
just do the videotape that's happened in
the past so execution when you go get
ready to do the attack you gone in you
gather your information you have a good
idea who these people are the different
types out there in place you need to
prepare yourself for that work part of
that his mental condition in which will
talk about the next slide but the other
aspects are you need to make sure that
you're aware of real threats that exist
how you're going to get what you need to
get in when you get in how to not get
caught
how to maintain persistence once you've
left and how to get out cleanly the big
key rule that we teach everybody is
don't fuck it up so states of awareness
I used to call this the the stop for the
stop sign
slide but the truth of the matter is
that I stole this from the United States
Military they train this mental
conditioning all soldiers go through
this training all law enforcement
training in more the aspect is that all
of us who live in life you see in this
room right now you're probably in a
condition green where you're comfortable
you're unaware of various threats that
exist outside of this room most people
live their life like this when you work
in law enforcement military or start
doing operational type work like this
you'll train yourself to continually
existence in the condition of yellow
you want to have that heightened
awareness you want to be attentive you
won't understand what's going on you
wanna be aware of the conversations that
happen around you it takes a bit of work
to get your brain train for this stock
something just clicked on all the big he
is that you don't necessarily want to
live in red red is after something has
already happened it's reactionary you
looked panicked you look stressed if
you're doing this work those are all
very very negative things the other
thing is really making sure that you
know the true threats that exist for
years we've we've SAT here and you know
models sister plug years we've warned
Kevlar vests when doing certain
engagements like airports large banks in
places like that because we're going up
against running costs that have real
guns and real bullets and we don't they
have no clue that were coming they see
us as a real-world threat which is
technically in my opinion the only way
to conduct this type of work in
assessment and have it be real is is for
the people who were responsible for the
security not be aware that you're coming
in doing this work but the big he is
also make sure that you got your get out
of jail free card printed on your phone
and on you physically to where you can
reach your back pocket and pulled out a
piece of paper that shows that you are
authorized to be conducted in doing the
work now that doesn't have to be a crazy
legal document that literally just has
to say with the date and time and a
signature of the the client her firmly
on the client letterhead saying you bear
this letter is doing this kind testing
here's what's involved here is the sites
that are involved with the dates that
are if you're in question of these of
the visibility of his top of this letter
call these numbers and it should be at
least three people at two o'clock in the
morning when you have to use that is not
get caught if you show your get out of
jail free card you you've lost
don't run catches you know it's a bad
idea they don't like that and honestly
when I and this is happening the past a
guard or drawn on you don't reach your
pocket for the letter just tell them
where it is a dude apparently giving bad
advice because if you look at breaking
in
on the TV show like three of those
people are hanging from court right
there so I mean I guess we did wrong
guys but we did include you a nice
little slider me looking like I'm giving
Chris Dickerson head and say for Tiger
Team ok physical ways of getting in our
favorite physical ways to get us in and
it worked over and over again in the
past is getting to invite you and guys I
mean it's cool to go sneak in and do all
that but that shouldn't be your first up
your first step should be reaching out
to building management building
maintenance talking to them about
various ways that you can get in it's
amazing when especially on these big
shared property facilities if you call
up and just be like hey you have offices
open we would like to look at your
offices were looking to open up a
location in your area
know literally walking in the best part
is the person is walking UN and showing
your out of the building their RFID card
opens every door and they're not
security people so they're not going to
think it's weird when you pull out your
little phone pad set up with rocks part
3 inside of it and you go oh that's
really cool back and then hand it back
to them they have no idea that you just
imagine doing that
utility companies one orion's favorites
bucks players and you can spray air I
got five bucks we're going to a
datacenter and IT guy come here and like
not at school I got this is like it's
it's special quick drying my watch it
has spread from that might see you can
tell it's wet
public bathrooms and and public reaching
areas are a wonderful just lift list if
it has a false ceiling ceiling tiles
left it almost always you can use that
to get access to secure areas of the
building where to actually find places
that have designed a building with the
intent of a data center or secure server
like I can't tell you the number of
times even like they just like this is
our safe room and you go over new push
up all four directions into other safer
miss you literally just crawl over from
somebody else's office into their room
why take the time to pick lock you can
call over it the biggest the big point
of all of this is you want to present
yourself as if you belong and be
friendly you don't have to be an asshole
it's not if people talk about how you
can be a cruel and social enjoying your
not gonna get very far with that nine
times out of ten shutdown smile
importing goes along way guys on side of
incentive we talk about candy contest
and pizza Eric Smith all use this
example one of our friends gentleman who
works with lawyers consulting him
another consultant went up to the places
they were hiking and they'd already done
the job they'd already got everything
but they want to see how they can really
push it on their last day they walked
into this facility took a folding table
set it up in the lobby of the business
not shared property this is like the
lobby of the blah blah blah business
they're tracking and they put up a
little sign that says come test the
strength of your password and they were
giving out free candy bars all these
people that are typing into an
application their password to test the
complexity of their password the crazy
thing was over seventy percent of the
people that walked up and actually typed
in their password gave them a legitimate
domain credentials for the business that
they were in it you'd be amazed people
are stupid guys other fun things to look
out obviously RFID we've already talked
about credit card trick still works
that's that's super hardcore badass lock
right there by the way that's that's
probably the lock them sitting there
shaming is probably almost a $200
installation on that
door for that that panel and that lock
and yet I got into the room key cards
gift cards are free and they're perfect
don't use your idea don't you and if you
do use your idea you're gonna get
questions every time you should it's not
hard to figure out what happens your
idea when there's very little Denson and
done it once and other fun stuff is if
you can see how on the third picture
there the gates exposed meaning that I
can usually get a tool in there to do
the credit card trick so if you're
installing a responsible for security
need to walk around your business and
think about the shit magnetic locks are
one of my favorites because I've got to
do is walk up there with a little bit of
iron filings and rub it across the top
of that magnetic bar any kind of a break
that you create even at my level between
the magnet and the bar itself makes it
or if you put your foot on some of those
bars or the like
take six thousand pounds of force to
open this door know until you put a
piece of duct tape on the reason I
included the one on the bottom on the
middle it's one of our favorite tricks
we carry a ziploc bag with the sponge
with liquid tide on it you can wipe down
a key pattern aqui cerca stays cool
thing is after people coming in touch it
the residue of the oils on their fingers
in their fingers touching it will
definitely affect cool thing about
liquid tide is looking tired how is full
photo passports so we hit with the black
light glows bright so you can see where
it's damned those of the buttons that
people have been touching are using my
favorite on this one is that key there
is a ridiculous and would be super hard
to pick that lock but it was awesome
because the janitor who I was talking to
as I told him I was taking pictures to
change all the locks for their security
he added me the key so I can take a
picture of it go home and come by on
other types of things that exist in our
little shittier power supplies for
datacenters lot of states require that
you can't lock these by law to walk up
shut off the power to the building is
the biggest thickest move you can do
great way to tell me that you're testing
their UPS's but you'd also be amazed at
the fact that because of loss of life
being the leader in how this stuff is
done when you kill power to the building
security controls like electronic
magnetic locks that they'll open by law
it makes a lot of noise rebuilding you
hearing like freaking out as they walk
outside to smoke cigarettes one more
great way to be able to RFID badges
offer people what a better way to put
300 potential matches out in front of a
business then shut off the power to the
business or triggered the fire alarm we
all know the tricks with motion sensors
like I showed up there in the middle
we've talked about the hot water under
the door the can of compressed air all
those things still work
show down here on one of the door
magnetic sensors that you can literally
peel back the cabling and bridge the two
and then it never ever knows that
connection has been modified or broke
alligator clips actually helped alot
with this and in the middle when you've
got time you got to glass doors shutting
this way means that you've got a
potential be able to go in with the tool
and it crashed car from the other side
my favorite thing to do with that is
just a strap aluminum pulled in and
that's where the bank last week
problem with that that's where the
manila folder in the coat hanger went
right through and triggered the exit
sensor in the door
members of can't break in like it's it's
unreal how many different security
controls are put in place the just
really have no purpose I I love the one
down there it's hard to see in this
picture but the one with the grass
there's just people driving away a drop
or alright breaking India technology
using technology again we're not going
to sit here and talk about one billion
justification testing but you guys have
the idea there what we're talking about
you get little keyloggers that you can
physically walk in and put in line with
small little cameras are easy to plant
place and they do a really good job of
being able to give you access to see
what these people are sleeping in to
keep out other types of things like that
I gotta give props certain that is or
ever now they have been the single
largest source credentials out there on
the internet so when you're doing your
initial reconnaissance you say for
example find out that they're using
wireless cameras and you can see those
cameras that's the best way to find out
where the inside the building looks like
without having to go in the door and
those camera systems are almost always
installed with Deepak credentials stung
by a third party and the people who are
using it inside the business never take
the time to go back and hardness
credentials when you get when you get
your official work and you've got your
told them that were searching for things
like cameras were bad name the kid no
Mames computers bad camera whenever
again if you can if you can use external
resources going on
take advantage of it that's part of the
whole blending social I got to love your
camera system then I got into the
building are countered or candles as I
just literally walked my guy and i cant
seem on the cameras so I said ok take a
left and then opened that door for him
and he went to the next time I called
the elevator down to 172 the 15th floor
open a couple of doors for me was
exactly what I needed to be all because
they click the link in an email the
other thing is don't ever underestimate
the power of stupidity bring your own
disaster is now everywhere even hardened
military facilities now even though
there's policies against it you will
always find some jackass standing there
with a smartphone that has Bluetooth
enabled wireless enabled there's a
million different tools out there that
you can use to me in the middle of this
and take control those devices which
they then carry into their secure
facilities other devices obviously lots
of other stuff here that we can hack and
things that we can look at pagers pac's
a complex series of Unicode foreigners
nowadays a lot of printers have you know
64 gig worth of memory it's an awesome
place to be able to store your tools and
be able to have a dumping ground to put
data to Excel traded out convenient have
made things really easy we have coffee
machine smart TVs smart gorgeous nasty
all these things now they can all be hot
all this stuff has been publicly
exploited pushed out there
smart TVs those things are in conference
rooms all the plays they have webcams
and microphones you can just let the big
key to remember all this technology
stuff is don't spend a lot of time
resources and energy trying to look cool
when you can just pwned people people
are stupid
the key is that we have an uphill battle
to fight because like I said people are
really really stupid and they do dumb
shit so they can even know that what
they're doing is the wrong thing and
they'll still do it on like a fish
unlike a technical control to review
program and not to do something it's not
going to do it
people don't function outweigh the crazy
thing is is that what ten years ago we
are having to build a strict servers
with boy band we're doing all this crazy
work to be able to do caller ID spoofing
and just to be able to get through
nowadays you can download spoof app on
any smartphone and pay what is five
bucks 400 minutes or something like that
for credits and in my opinion it works
better than the ostrich servers and
other stuff too because it's on your
phone you have it there you don't have
to have external access to that server
it it makes it really really solid
social engineering toolkit once again
props out to the guy's a defensive
computing but this is a great tool set
that freely available for everybody
download use this along with like three
or four other software packages for its
not into guys doing good work in the
keynote tomorrow but the key is you can
walk in and just ask for it back in the
day are are the thing that everybody
would talk about was walking around with
the clipboard and tend to look
professional looking portal well I argue
against that because that draws
attention to you and it makes it look
like somebody who if someone is
responsible for the business of the
operation are gonna come talk to you
again asking why you're walking around
taking notes the amazing thing is that
if you walk into a business during an
iPod and and your plan on your iPad into
your thing no one is going to stop you
were asked what you're doing the cool
thing is that the iPad or whatever it is
you're a million different hacking tools
on it where the piece of paper does
nothing more than brought attention to
you so again I show that between the
differences
ten years ago but he was saying the best
way to go and was look at thirty of them
say now the best way to go in
it's going to look like anybody else we
talk about a minute ago
make sure you make sure you wear
clothing to match them don't have
touched you showing if you can hide your
tattoos wear long sleeve shirt or make
sure they're now take your piercings out
their hair to normal color you're gonna
have to give up some things
job and when you when you're not doing
the job then you can have lived here
take the time to study again and all P
the stuff has been research for a long
time lot of people call the city's
science I can tell you find serious
science yet I have used it to hawk
countless people over 20 years time if
you learn how to read people's eyes
their emotions
attentive in your main close attention
to what they're doing it makes it really
easy to get them to buy into to what it
is that you're doing and what it is that
you're trying to accomplish
don't give you everything you want the
eye when I spoke with my wife she helped
me with it at a conference in Oslo
called paranoia earlier this year and we
walked in and she is a five and a half
foot tall girl with a foot tall
milwaukee has ball probably matters runs
Mohawk on it but we have her in this
really nice velvet dress and the best
part was during the first part of the
conference before we gave our keynote
she was walking around in that nice
dress talking all these people
collecting business cards getting
information
RFID sweeping people it was great the
best part was I go up and start giving
the presentation on stage I wait to call
her out to about this point me in the
slide deck that we were giving and she
walks out on stage with the red dress on
looking like the matrix girl in this
shot here and you watch half the
audience go cuz they realized as they
were flirting with this large breasted
tattooed punk look and check the entire
time she'd been harvesting in stealing
their credentials in their information
and getting information about their
business never underestimate the power
of being able to be cute smiling
flirting that stuff goes a long way make
people feel good about themselves when
you're packing them it's a lot more
successful than telling them that the
wrong or stupid
not getting caught so make sure you know
where your eggs are make sure you know
we talked about this for systems alright
so you're in the building access so
things like three kids to the USB thumb
drives the leave behind which we use
Arduino Zuhr home close all the time no
one notices a little white box that has
a cellular modem minute has plugged into
their network and then called back here
server home so you can do everything
else from from the hotel room or house
physical access once you if you can get
in there during the day when you're not
breaking and entering putting tape over
a door latch putting you know having
seized as you see them girls Destrehan
idea and those are things that are all
really useful the next night we're
trying to do and people for whatever
reason don't notice that shit missing
you don't notice that the door doesn't
really close properly because you taped
up magnet taped up the latch that would
normally allowed or stay closed big
thing though is when you're getting out
when you're actually inside that
building it's now time to leave the big
you need to think about keeping call you
need to look you you've got a backpack
full of their since the most sensitive
information you've got everything that
you need now it's time to get out the
key is to not look like you're in a rush
to get out or to not look like you
belong again so we get a couple t like
little teasers here but the funny thing
is every one of these thoughts on the
slide is something that we've learned
the hard way over the years you'll
notice that some of the things in here
like the don't hang out or things that
others beaches will tell you is
absolutely a good thing to do so you can
develop a rapport with people but the
point is is that once you got the
the kingdom get the hell out of Dodge
there's no reason to stick around and
taught other cool things like this slide
because right and I over the years of
taking a lot of pride in finding common
household items like it at Home Depot
that you can use to help you with the
work remains you like if you're breaking
into an office facility simply having
one of those stupid little rubber
stoppers corridor is priceless because
you can kick it into if you break into
an office in like a large complex of
businesses you break into an office you
can put that door stop in place and then
even if someone has a key they're not
gonna be able to open it up to come in
to look at the key to remember about
this stuff is remove it when you go to
his you can't leave stuff messed up the
little drainpipe cameras that you can
buy now there are about 50 bucks I think
for the ones that you like smartphone
now those are awesome looking under
doors always a good idea to have an idea
of what's on the other side of the door
before you walk through it if you're
doing this for you don't want to just
all the sudden walk into the middle of
you know central security when you're
trying to break into their place and the
reason I included the headset even
though you'll never ever see me wearing
a headset at work when I'm at work is
the filters white light is very bright
splashes you can see for miles and miles
away if you defuse it using a red or
green light it makes it very very
difficult for people's eyes to pick up
the differences in the separation so if
you're inside of an office near going
back and forth with with like a red or
green light it's not gonna show outside
of that officer outside of the windows
like you would with a Maglite
so once you're done and you're out and
and the projects finished part of the
client actually peace the report it
needs to have a narrative explaining
exactly what happened and not just how
about us you are and they are good at to
look at what failed and what would work
best when its tests not just to make
them feel it also should work to make
sure yet documentation on both sides of
that makes you know how their employees
don't necessarily name people in their
clients I try to avoid that
especially when it's when the person
acting is that they're supposed to mean
that personal make sure they understand
whatever you did whatever trainings
person got that work so write review
repeat that person himself helped teach
the rest the company in the ways that
they respond right away
2016 get away from delivering static
reports it's important to be able to
have something that people can sit
around a boardroom and be able to look
at it through and read but include video
presentation of the work that you're
doing i mean a GoPro silver 04 is so
small now days that if you have it on
your backpack and it's so common no
one's gonna ever ask why you're wearing
a camera and the cool thing is you can
literally record days in a video if you
have enough memory on those things and
and the right batteries and the client
will end up using that shown up their
bodies and becomes a sales tool of you
know you had because they're going to
look we did this is that ass examined it
was I was on the job and I took video of
the exploit process that I was doing
what I was going through and we got
through and I'm sitting there talking
about how how things are done and I'm
like yeah with our poisoning we are able
to secure man in the middle of a
captured your boy profit you know and we
were able to listen phone calls that
tune executive meant nothing when I hit
play on my computer and played back
aboard administrative call from that
business and he listened to 4 minutes
and 20 seconds of his of his more
talking about highly sensitive
information and data all the sudden
attack I did which two seconds ago it
meant nothing to him was super super
critical and key and he wanted to figure
out how to mitigate that issue
immediately contact us there's our
information
and we got all the way through the slide
deck but the questions comments stories
to tell
thank you very much so I thought I'd
like to thank you very much you guys
thanks