she was really like to talk by yourself
but I managed to get here so why you are
here this is a technical conference and
really social engineering music really
technical it's talking to people which
is not nearly as cool as circumventing
firewall but what if I told you that a
couple weeks ago
one billion dollar credit union let me
walk in completely unauthorized didn't
even check and I D
let me say that one of their cubicles
and plug into their network all while I
wasn't supposed to be there that is a
great
for grad school and got promoted to
assistant admin I did systems
administration for two years and a
little bit programming and systems
analysis and after that I can trade
security where I've been for two years I
fell in love with the industry kind of
awesome workout announcers and secretary
now I want to track and pedophiles owner
likes cheney I did not start off in
information security at all actually
start off and English and linguistics
major then became way too relevant to my
life and I decided I wanted to pay check
up went to college so I went to the
University of Arkansas at about this
time
Peter science while I was there to get
RFID security class and totally fun let
the industry I jumped right in became an
information security analyst just well
in this role he performed tests risk
assessment I T on its way to a bar
melody scanning and of course social
engineering engagements so far completed
sixty-plus social engineering as
yesterday this is everything from
walking there now that you know about us
why here so if you don't know
anthropology at the study of human
beings so it's actually really really
useful in social engineering and if
y'all ever wanna go totally can come
find me a couple of hours but I could
keep it contained a biological
anthropology addresses like evolutionary
character trait involuntary color
changing and social cultural
anthropology actually addresses like
social class and gender which really
important that I used and the quality
and they did in my background liberal
arts also really helps I need to know
how to craft just the right phrase for a
professional-looking documents and
know-how somebody's going to react to me
it's character analysis
another thing that has been really
useful is that I was a theater kid high
school if you're really serious about
doing social engineering I would suggest
he and processes whose line is it anyway
actually a really good training exercise
make sure that you can react no matter
what's thrown at you talk about why
these non technical things are really
important so where is this actually
gotten so far and my fishing projects
I've got a total of seven effective user
credentials username and password
the thing that people tell you never to
give out over the phone condition never
gonna ask for it while I got that five
of them or Active Directory and two of
them were for the quarter financial
processor
earlier with financial institutions
financial processor is the fifth and
they're pretty much the car and you may
be thinking what does that matter how
you that while they all get their extra
well all I had to do it I just need a
little bit of anti-war
thing and a little bit of changing and i
got a pretty easily I'm pretty socially
awkward as a whole but I would much
rather have someone for their password
because I know that way I can tell this
isn't just you know there's no place
that totally sucks this we have done
this on multiple occasions walked in and
out of a bunch of branches and I have
even come back the next day after I
compromise for locations I came back as
myself as a different assessment I had
to run and the manager that talk to the
day before didn't know I still was not
mediate compliance consultant she was
just like oh you know you're coming
again today
you know is there more stuff me to do
she didn't know until after I left and
there I T manager told them we find lots
of other sensitive information while
you're in there people love to leave
things on printers on lot puters been a
lot of mail rooms where they just go
ahead and hang out in the mail room with
your giant bag and certainly not going
to disappear so it's important to note
it in case anybody in here don't let no
I think most of us do social engineering
is the exploitation of human psychology
in order to accomplish a goal or as I
like to call people and you can have
their psychology thing can't be worth
and mouth instead of a firewall and it's
far easier than $2 host a working on it
there are three or four types of social
engineering depending on who you talk to
first one's fishing this is the most
common this is all your spam emails for
spearfishing
got target like at Sony then there's
indirect this one contested people say
it's not really social cause you're not
talking to anybody but this information
gathering dumpster diving even things
like leaving a USB in a parking lot or
handing them out of the security people
will flood the men because it's nice to
be here mainly talking now about fishing
which is boys fishing this is done over
the phone
normally either to get information like
credentials or to get someone to pay for
services they really don't need then we
have the physical which we also call on
site and this is where we actually go on
site and try and reach a physical
location so have you guys ever heard of
the Trojan horse not the computer virus
but the real ACT or SAT social
engineering that like a lot of our
people still calling for you think that
they learn well
very tight I'm sure you could experience
stereotyping in the industry
kind of a big deal hackers hackers all
look the same and there are more
important than you think
when it comes to social service
typically women have girl jobs teachers
not happy here and Bethany are generally
more successful because we are females
and it depleted evolutionary trait gone
that the anthropology and it makes users
trust us simply because when women are
generally quite maternal
people so it helps a lot like a lot but
we will address how to get around
science at the moment we can't really do
anything to protect you from humans are
trustworthy and helpful by nature even
if you're not immediately truck but we
still want to feel something venturing
out a train wreck happened partly so why
everybody slows down and social
engineers could step further and give us
social psychological reasons to trust
them like having company for example you
can actually really think you can beat
everybody in here to picture a and non
industry person think the social
engineer or a hacker looks like what
gender or they wouldn't their age with
the rain how did the rest
what is our stereotypes because people
be there are stereotypes that be the
people let everyone thinks we look like
what do you notice about what you know
about age gender everything I mentioned
in the beginning
young age
socially awkward looking like male
suffer very pale moving toward being
racially extended but we've known you
know for a little while women and pop
culture like to mention they always show
up at the surprise villain hacker at the
end
people usually disregard them and still
can't believe that I couldn't front of a
computer all day with three XY
everywhere you know we're pretty sure
she's speaking in tongues
actually on his first day my dog I
introduced myself and he was like that
sales person think but yeah my client I
had one point who chose the AT&T network
technician review the project because I
did look for and why did the freaking
CEO was like why did you pick AT&T bill
won't hire girl technician so most
people do consciously and you can't help
it
and a couple operation that have gone
over right now if you do fit the
stereotype you can use that to your
advantage for how you carry yourself and
your body language things like that and
you should be good to go
which go into right now everything
starts with you you have to convince
yourself and you need to choose a cover
story that's not only good for the
target but that's good for you I went to
school to be a programmer software go
you throw hardware in front of me around
however I did a part time job for six
years of being a worker and a
disabilities office
compliance consultant ruse is really
really good for me about accommodations
all day long for you your own knowledge
if you have a background in something
use it as well talk a lot about truths
and using troops under cover story and
that's actually really important and
even the plane expectations
another reason why the network to her
role doesn't work great for me because I
am I don't fit the stereotype typical
network tech that everybody thinks
obviously calls can be network tech and
if you think otherwise
somehow you what if you play along to
the expectation they're gonna believe
you a lot
disability accommodations typically it's
in a moment to you know take care of
other people which is all combinations
that going along with people don't
question
those are the big things down to the
details though he you don't need to know
your fake mothers make great your
nonexistent child is if you have too
many details you're going to trip over
your so here we use props used them
carefully I mean if you're an
exterminator you don't need to show up
with a work load of construction tools
now you're not going to chase the
termites around with us all when I am
compliance consultant normally I have a
fake I D a clipboard I'm sorry we're
still doesn't work and checklist but I
printed Google clothing is very very
important what I do I dress business
casual I have some workers though that
they do the pest control lot so they've
gotten polos logo embroidered on them
that's great if you can do that you have
the funds for it but really just using
the idea of the uniform can't work if
you don't believe that just having the
right colors will trick people put on a
blue shirt and khakis and try to go
shopping at Walmart you get asked a lot
of questions many pet grooming when
again I'm a consultant you know I have
my hair back all night I got modest
jewelry low key makeup that's expected
or female business people but if I am a
network tech I have a messy bun I'm have
no makeup whatsoever and I'm gonna look
completely different because of it and
it doesn't just have to do with girls so
guys you know if you have a big unruly
beard are a whole lot of tax choose you
know you don't fit the stereotype
insurance inspector however you know the
pest control guy somebody coming to give
up paint a painting you know those are
great bruises and then we have some fun
like color psychology where you can come
up with your shirt star is actually
really great example could think of all
the colors of light sabers thus if all
have read which is a very passionate
energetic angry color and then you have
Luke who has blues and greens which are
really calming you know the good light
side of the force you can do this by
just the color of what you're wearing
typically I like to choose calming
colors like blue or green or purple
because blue shows off you know
professional very calm but not purple
sky at Royal you know respectable Brown
is actually really good because it shows
your reliable but you don't want to go
monochrome unless you're trying to be
the UPS guy cuz you look like a
generally I just choose a button down in
that color and then just plain black
slacks black
he looked very professional but you
still are giving out the color so when
the obvious person modifications that
you making there's one real gold in line
with you you want to get your target to
trust you they will comply and those
things like that before humans are more
stranger and stranger get the nether
region you can trust you first
impressions I'm sure you've all heard by
now you all probably interview before
they're incredibly important how many
people you know
straight interested have a really strong
handshake but think about the science
behind the ball body has anybody ever
giving you advice about your face before
even seeing your body language and how
you carry yourself people look at your
face and human psychology dictate that
humans react different facial features
so used to study and a psychologist down
that facial structure to give someone an
idea of your personality like you have a
baby face you'll be really good at
dodging hearing anything but probably
masculine feel like the military justice
you'll just make people think that you
are in my first day on the job
one of the guys was like I cannot wait
to kiss you look so precious and women
with this topic they tend to be more
successful in health care education or
whatever caregiver role because they
look mattel and unfortunately for some
of us to anyone and includes attractive
people are still not attractive people
haven't outgoing friendly personality in
addition to being really intelligent and
socially complement its subconscious
thing nothing to do with
another theory done by Charles Darwin
said that your personality actually hits
your face in the Russell 2000 but one
could use more prominent
you smile off the muscles that you smile
more prominent here really happy that
mean well if you know your face and
trustworthy
smile March
not part and it's actually fun like a
school play sports are really you
thought if you can see this picture
having an upturn mouth and eyebrows
gives off like a more trustworthy and if
that is online just google it look at
what it looks like a pretty good
practice in the mirror like relax a
little bit raise your eyebrows lips
while more you know
friendlier yeah if you ask somebody is
my face trustworthy and they got ya know
which alright once you get the structure
of your face down we have to talk about
expressions there are two kinds of macro
and micro micro expressions are often
involved and voluntary which makes the
most dangerous this is little thing you
know the widening of the really supposed
to be there and somebody let you in on
the first try and you look surprised
that's a problem even just like a pic of
your eyebrows
signalled to the target something wrong
control but you have to disappear for
you have to practice it's very easy to
tell if somebody has a fake expression
especially if you're up against women
I'm really sorry guys but scientifically
proven that women are better reading
facial expressions the men tend to be
whenever your girlfriend says oh that
person was upset you know they're fine
that's part of it so here you know you
want to get these under control and
trust you this is more practicing in the
mirror but also more improv
have a friend saying things to you that
a target might fade you denials yes it
is letting you in case you need to see
this and learn how to react
appropriately
once you've got your yet their work on
your body language mutation is 55% my
language choices only 77 percent of it
your tone is another 38 percent and
we'll talk a little more about that in a
bit if you wanna be sick same supercar
inspire trust you know you do the whole
and argue that great shelters you know
this shows your trustworthy doing
sometimes it's good to look sympathetic
so kinda looking to that can actually
work really well for you pay attention
to your hands they actually tell a lot
about you
twitching and tapping showing Saudi
touching your face
thought years indecision my big problem
is I miss my hair which guarantee I
actually do have anxiety so they've been
doing that alot without thinking about
it and set trying to suppress it which
would be actually really hard for me to
do I work it into my contest you know
somebody notices hey you're really
twenty you know why do you look so
nervous
say something like oh I'm sorry I knew
this is my first time by myself you know
I'm just kinda nervous they don't screw
it up
people love to help out the new person
and you can use to manage to arms making
really how I see how your target reacts
to you you know if they're protecting
their they might kill their crossing
their arms you know they're hiding
something or they don't want to talk and
now putting your hands on your hips
generally means you're upset so this was
something I did even before I got into
this job I used to go to options
my father a lot and he would always tell
me that carry the heavy stuff while he
and the reason that was me bak you help
me get into the car carrying a gun safe
for me and it would be loaded before he
even finished but if you can't handle in
distress think it sometimes it looks
really weird
mirroring can be consciously picking up
their target and most people here
thinking about it but if you are
thinking about it you can use it to your
advantage because people like himself at
the subconscious thing it gives you a
sense of comfort or connection or below
and you definitely don't want do it
exactly the weekend we're really like it
and then they're so while not
immediately speaking to each other even
facing each other these four men are
nearing
all have their hand out there that I do
it when I'm on this project when their
car hit space to think about higher
sometimes all I know is that I usually
work like this and where their body
language and you can also appears beach
to get someone to fill your connection
which is so cool when you're actually
doing it and you can tell that it's
working
you can hear the tone of voice the speed
and a word choice and they'll change to
marry you back he'll go over a little
bit cold but we don't do it word for
word because then you will know that
you're copying them he said the exact
words they use it most and fishing with
its more fluid that weight and keeping
your your target first when they answer
the phone so I have like a party girl
that all answer the phone I'll change my
voice of work you know you've been named
like actually pretty Rachel and they
were
more likely to I don't know what it is
someone you okey dokey here great when
they're talking to you could say
something like alrighty are perfect
symbol or something but they're not
exact but don't do it if you're in
service all right so that really brings
into focus on questions first
ok we have open ended question these are
used to gather specific information
about someone something actually
something that they teach you a dialogue
also there's a lot of these kind of
these kind of questions in both
interrogation sales techniques which
kind of funny how those two para
open-ended question that's when your
instead of asking a yes-no question you
ask something that forces you to think
more like a so saying do you like John
Johnson just leave it that he say how do
you feel about John Johnson they're
gonna have to tell you then we have
leading question they can be a target a
specific direction
lots lots of sales and interrogation
techniques here instead of like to just
say something about my visit is a yes or
no question you did say we are able to
be the email that Jim sent out about my
inspection today at least on the think
there was an email
dotnet and they should have known about
this inspection
many of us some questions this is
generally when you have a really good
educated guess I should have information
it can be either used to gain trust
because you're right
all are in order to verify information
like if you go up and ask somebody yeah
right you're saying somebody's told you
firewall if the answer is yes oh yeah
you know about the network it's it's
about the network with them if they say
no you know
Sophos firewall then they're going to
one give you more information I know
exactly what kind of a lot of times will
be like who told you that you know now
let's get everything right
delegate and devote more information
they are and he want to imply hopeful
this you do not want to just go what is
your password
probably won't work if it does they
definitely deserve to be there and so
did everything get their trials yeah
people generally don't like being
something be demanded of them so in this
sort of cases have saying what's your
username say hey can you verify this
user name so I can make sure that I'm
talking to the right person or for the
password can you verify your password
for me so I can cross yup this list I
make sure not to call you again nobody
wants to be called twice and you sound
like you're helping them by then giving
you a password
you know they're doing something good
for them so not something terrible for
the entire nation you want you don't
bombard you with questions that might
make them shut down so you have to again
balance get just the right amount of
questions to get what you need and move
on
we have this is about how you speak in
general there's a technique called
positive confrontation this is just
making a strong and that Stern's
statement said walking and CEO in today
you can walk up and say I'm an
appointment with Tim Cook at 11 a.m.
that says you know tempo you have an
appointment and it's important and they
better hurry up and get you this is
being assertive without being aggressive
wedding falls back more on gender
differences John law in his book
outdoors and actually called tools and
duets talks about how guys when they
interact with each other they tend to
duel with their friends which is just
teasing them about something you know
things women would probably never say to
each other like oh my god where those
shoes look terrible or did you hear this
morning and it's playful is typically
between women people think a lot of guys
think that we're interrupting each other
when we're talking one person will say
oh you know this happen to me and the
other on will go oh yeah this very
similar thing happened to me it's
actually do wedding it's keeping the
conversation going and finding common
grounds and actually its defensive check
me because if you give personal
information out that person could use
them against against you but if they get
something bad you both have that black
male so you know your stuff is safe
white people tend to if you develop
something personal
they want to give it back give something
personal about themselves
seized on the ground
typically like work do a whole lot more
than I do normally cuz I'm surrounded by
guys were the only female
yeah there we take very qualities are
stalking statements which is another
thing women do a lot this is a way of
making a statement
gentler so that you don't push them into
defensive alright confrontation program
called them being diplomatic diplomatic
and search saying you know like yours
you set this up for all said something
like I might be wrong but I think this
configure it
rationed setting should be this and not
this gets them to go oh you're hoping
you're not saying you turn them on and
they actually think about what you're
doing and are more likely to fix it can
bring back to anthropology I love you so
one of those deeper into that we can
talk about the stress think local it it
makes a lot of sense when you think
about it there's a chance that you'll
see each other around town or you know
friends of their friends or family maybe
we'll go job one day so people don't
want to have awkward encounters with
each other each other because the
conflict so a lot of us in here from
cell which we had some pretty unique way
of thinking how he appeared local to
other people start with your boy it's
probably the easiest method to tell
where people usually a certain way
forward
critically
I don't know if you haven't noticed I
tend to pick up a midwestern accent
so it's hard to imitate but if you can
and use that to your advantage though
are you call someone else but when in
doubt you want to use your natural
accents because that that can get you in
like an idiot legally we also have
regional terms things I catch myself
really hard not to when I go up north
because yes that is a flag you're not
and that's incredibly difficult even
small things like same soda pop can get
you in trouble someplace I got made fun
of Anansi Asian is also if you go
somewhere and you don't know how to
pronounce either ask the local that has
nothing to do with your situation are
announcing it whatsoever I mean and
Louisiana it is really easy to tell it's
a year or so and yeah I'm not tell me
that word most enriching but when you
say that you just move here or you're
going to school year with something that
I before I went to my first project and
we the guy was training that we should
probably try to look local it was
November and I'm from Miami Florida so
do the accent so I just said that I went
to school there it might work out in
your favor of you that you sent me very
welcoming people think what people say
so what happens if they think well
before you even start your test you want
to plan for like think about everything
that happened what pop more than I'll
still get
and plan for them I've made a pic you
check with inward with the local I found
on Google and if someone says they will
not give me physical access from my
insurance can you please just answer
questions make it look like I did not
have a silent alarm the dye packs but
they're all really catching but I have
to like how many disabled parking but
you have even if that fails I have a
signature line so if they're like I
can't answer those questions can you
just fine if I can tell my boss here and
I'll give me a signature which is also
really bad idea you can also plan things
like that no man I have five locations
that happened and you don't have time to
wait for confirmation
anything we can do I get giving you
something
fan difference which is something that
kevin Mitnick for I could do whatever
you want to be here
here but you don't have to say that I
think walk out the door because then he
ok fine by me just want to have a reason
to just relax and not be alarmed if
that's when you leave I'll give them a
reason to think that you don't really
care about getting there and if all else
fails you're probably doing overall I
hadn't hear ya well if you get too pushy
regret he could trigger warning bell
call the cops
and what do you get away from the topic
but you want to build rapport rapport
and trust will get you what you want and
what better way to do that is to be
genuine and I don't like most people so
this is really hard for a human being I
would smile and pretend to care more
about them than anything else I really
care about your password so you know get
to the degree here and get your passport
everyone likes to talk about themselves
and also make sure that my parents but
my demeanor technician but I'm a really
small female Soper keep its kinda well I
don't do intimidating looking so I tried
to pick ax they'll fit my
grapevine
don't look that up if you're a really
big dude and you said that you look
intimidating you can do it I did and you
can change your demeanor and you have an
input petty verify what I don't know
what it is and you don't talk about
yourself you don't want to avoid it at
all costs because that's incredibly
people be like why is this person but
you want to be more interested in what
they have to say which you can be anyway
because they're probably going and try
to find this is so you can take
advantage of your surroundings and look
around their debt what they're wearing
you know maybe if you see like a picture
of a dog or something like a lot of
pictures of dog chat about it even if
you don't have a dog make one up they
might think that there's a chance that
they'll see you at the dog park later on
because your local and they will bend
over backwards to be accommodating
because they don't operate social
interests are really powerful
and one of the most common mistake you
can make it over thinking when I did all
the time and not just I get around that
usually in such a project because I
don't speak out and pulls hand I go with
the flow of the situation around I just
watched think tank
potentially be over thank you can make
three body language or you can't
overthink things well you want to keep
that balance in mind when you when
you're planning out your paycheck if you
work too hard on your details like
loading up on crops like Bethany
her thing i think thats trip you'll come
off at rehearsal and natural people be
quiet but I'm sure you can tell which
parts of our scripts are brand new ones
we've been working on for a while we
finish the morning so surprised
figures that we had to go
don't don't rehearse at all in one trip
usually what I do and professional
engineering our her sippy different
things and I won't actually know what to
tell them that way you don't you still
know if they don't sound rehearse and
that it's taking so so is your pre-tax
gone wrong
talk through it and act like he wanted
that where you really really useful for
the more trees that you haven't heard
that the more not feeling protect will
be like that we also had a very very
quickly have a tendency to blush really
easy and when people from either case
I'm so sorry that sits alongside and
really nervous right now I get nervous
and i get some which some people be like
oh sorry let me help you feel better ok
and finally forced the best body
language to me to change it felt really
easy and it can be packing and find
think about it right
a lot of people don't think about it
like a network social engineering can be
done at work and you can think about it
like a network navigating through human
psychology
security controls Right changing your
talent and your body language and your
demeanor to be like pooping an address
to bypass the DHCP filter works nothing
like that I can be happy if you put it
all together we mention and do a little
research on doing a lot more and it
would like a list of references or if
you like about anything we have talked
to both of us and we will be around
afterwards probably get so we like to
thank you everyone for coming