and I'll go ahead and skip school so
welcome to our talk this is the
introduction to the Elias baby I
security project which is a project that
leave and I've been working on for
probably about the last eight months or
so we're really happy to finally be
unveiling that and hopefully giving some
of the people involved should be pretty
good this talk is a little bit different
than some of the other talks at this
conference and something out of talks
that even I have given in the past will
display some research that we've done
but really what we did as our research
for this project is what we consider
somewhere preliminary we basically took
the day that we could find in the
statistics that we could find compiled
that into what we think is a pretty good
first step for this project but really
more than anything else is a call for
participation
we're not saying that this is done in
perfect but we like to get the products
and exposure and hopefully our guys is
injurious so the agenda for today is
pretty straightforward I'm gonna do the
general introduction stuff you know who
are we
what's a lot you know why are we even
doing this project in the first place
will give some real-world examples both
that we've seen in the media has seen
through working for background gives him
some visibility there will go through
the top 10 Apr security risks or at
least what we have of those so far about
how you can help I can join the project
how you can
be involved in one way or another to
start off for those of you that don't
know me I don't think I know too many
people here
my name's David job I'm on tour de sha
underscore the other guy is not me I'm
chief information security officer at a
software company called holio based in
Santa Barbara California it was a pretty
rough travel to get here we got here
early this morning after several cancel
flights I was a former CTO Reds in which
is an application security consultancy
until it was acquired last year I
presented no con twice before on more
in-depth technical security research
again that's not really the point of
this talk today and I will drink with
you either with our selection of busy
air war hopefully the bars are open at
which point we can just go do that i'm
happy to talk about these ideas are just
security in general with anyone at any
time or not with a drink if you don't
drink that's fine but I'll be here
throughout the weekend so hopefully you
guys and have some good conversations
leaves Chrysler I have a much more you
need twitter handle considering that
there's only one with Chrysler security
engineer for bug crowd and I used to
work with David Reds been given
conference presentations at a couple
different besides and things like that
and I'm the Indiana Jones it means so
hopefully find some enjoyment as a as a
side now I mention our flight was
canceled so I got in this morning really
tired about 90 minutes of sleep and I
finally feel like I did you get this
time he's like yeah I made a lot of cool
editions for you and I might what do you
mean by that we finalized it like we had
to slide back everything's going to be a
good idea to just added a mean and into
means an image so we can probably 45
minutes going through and removing me
from the top after so many of you just
so I can get sore like a quick survey
how many people are familiar with a lot
that's most people probably like half
two-thirds that's good so now is the
open web application security project
which is just a nice acronym sounds
huge repository of information on the
ice but or if you've never been there
and you work in security I strongly
recommended a lot of cheat sheets
argumentation things like that they
really some tools that are bad
zappa's that attack proxies basically a
free and open source intercepting proxy
they have some tools that are bad but we
won't talk about that probably not good
for the talk when they also organize
some pretty high profile conferences
that the most high profile it is
probably being upset USA every year most
of the absentee you are staff at Absa
California so you know they're pretty
reputable organization they really try
to give back to the community which is
why we're trying to purchase with them
to sort of you know move move things
forward so in addition to their tools
and their projects and conferences also
has documentation project and some of
these are actually pretty famous right
so the top 10 guides are pretty much
like a like water some web security
vulnerabilities its gonna come up a
bunch of pentacene firms use web
application top 10 is like security
categories are finding categories
it's very common you can't really avoid
it but they also have you know like the
mobile security top 10
the Internet of Things top 10 scariest
that sort of like their flagship
documents that people using it so I
exposure and they are big fans of that
API Security Project sort of the seeking
to document the pitfalls and mitigations
those pitfalls in deploying API's and
also assessing this API if you try to
say hey I'm a pen tester I'm trying to
assess Apr security will probably knows
there isn't really that much
documentation probably because in
general it's harder than assessing a web
application so we're trying also seek to
address for that shortage there but
after I just told you all this
documentation that's on the oscillating
how great it is like you know you might
be wondering you know okay well why do
you actually need to create you know
this document this project
security is really important into its
growing in importance pretty much every
month to rate at which companies are
deploying API's is is increasing very
rapidly and there's sort of a couple
reasons for that right to public API is
meaning a user or a client can connect
and do things via public API very
widespread also internal API's and micro
services are continuing to grow in an
adoption all the time so the company
where I work we sort of have one
monolithic rails out that the primary
flagship product but when we add on to
that if we had treasury services to that
those are deported marker services and
we just right
API's we can have both the application
or other applications clear each other
and basically make things work fast in
an easily deployed way very useful have
sort of the challenge platform-based
issues right so if you're hot new
start-up cloud and you decide that you
want to just have your application for
Facebook platform
well you're basically only interacting
via API is right I mean without the API
the Facebook platform on which you're
basing on occasion nothing would work so
just a couple examples that have come
out recently the first one is recently
Microsoft
put out a blog post stating that they're
working on a REST API that allows you to
configure and manage I guess the goal of
this is to make IIS configurable from
any device that knows how to make a web
call specifically mobile applications so
you know configuring something as
important as your web server from an API
there's a lot of security concerns that
would be in place with having something
like that
be more open another example is in March
of this year
release a blog post detailing the
specifics of the bug bounty program
including documentation of API's these
API's can do things like find nearby
drivers
affairs with friends or allow people to
build it applications that interact with
hoover so there's a lot of functionality
that API is contained and some of it can
be very sensitive imagine if you could
share the airport or back from the
airport in Oakland and I could make it
said I'm paying significantly less fair
than David thanks not that I would do
that expensive so I'm sure most people
here now if they're in sort of the
community have pretty major security
problems right i mean we hear about you
know major bridges throughout kitchens
pretty much all the time
injection cross-site scripting
cross-border it's alright but with the
exception of you know sort of like weird
side channel attacks there's not really
that many new techniques for breaking
news web site I mean yeah there might be
particularly cool instances hey we found
this really cool see one direction or
sexy or whatever or even hey you know we
found this minor cross-site scripting
value we were able to hook in beef and
you know take over an organization
that's great but in general these
vulnerability types are our salt
put the Astros care because obviously
people are still getting breach that way
but the actual vulnerability that we
know how to tell a developer not direct
sequel injection in their code not sure
yet it's a solvent ability type yeah I
mean you can just mitigate these things
so that said it many API's especially
ones that are being sort of Britain as
may be an afterthought more flagship
products from major organizations are
sort of like ok with a different team is
gonna write this and it's gonna be done
much later and they're not going to have
necessarily the same protections for
example Instagram right now is a fully
functional basically we won't say it's
completely secure but find fairly hard
an application that you had a natural
API to post photos are to do all these
different tasks you can be easily added
security holes if you're not doing the
exact same permissions check he might be
doing the actual application then you
gonna introduce holes were what you
think you're doing just making something
easier user opening up your platform for
further years so good example of this is
that last year United Airlines launched
about Benny program may be this
successful thing that they are now so a
little bit of a mystery so they say when
the most critical vulnerabilities that
was released through this is basically
by using the mobile out you can see my
request they spun up an API to support
the mobile out that invisible to the
user so users are actually saying 11
EBITDA I'm gonna go through I'm gonna do
all this stuff it's really just a little
bit up you know intercepting proxy or
take a packet capture wherever you can
see the actual API request on the wire
so basically what happened in this
particular instance I'm not gonna go
through the first case study of a say in
this particular instance if you had
someone MileagePlus number which you
could not really considered super
sensitive you put it in hotel bookings
things like that you get what's called a
record locator
and using this record locator you can
make a series of requests they're
basically I'm unveil flight plans to
change flight plans would be less per
credit card would basically do all these
things that not only does it matter man
hope it's fine you can go through with
this record locator to change flights
you could add yourself to pledge
exchange names you could take someone's
well there is really bad right that was
super critical to major organizations
are basically accidentally exposing
sensitive data and methods Vapi access
they're not clearly not meaning to do it
but they say oh you know every injuries
API's we should you that you even we
have a legitimate use case to do so but
we're not putting the same security
controls or even thought into the death
process that would be done for the
actual formal formal applications show
roughly a quarter of the bounty is that
that people have seen our butt crack of
one sort of include the API in their
scope and that's only things I believe
that we're specifically called out so
like the United Airlines thing isn't
saying hey we have a specific API that
we'd like you to trust that they had a
mobile-optimized scope which made API
calls on the back and we're working very
tiny thumbnails of slides in case you're
wondering yes I of course there was that
swings slides yeah you should be asking
you know it's me
alright so I'm technical they're gonna
go over some API security examples one
of the really
recent Magento security bulletins and
they do fairly detailed pass notes for
those of you who aren't familiar with
Magento they help companies run and
e-commerce platforms a ton of companies
use them they're part of the eBay family
of companies in their most recent
security boards and 50% three of six of
the vulnerabilities that were fixed or
API related vulnerabilities there was
one critical though its remote code
execution there was one high which had
to do with account hijacking and there
is a medium which had to do with being
able to manipulate the items in the
guest cart so if you have you know you
haven't logged in yet you're working on
a on a cart somebody else could make
manipulations to your cart another
couple examples that were in the news
recently there was one from Qualcomm
that was not that i dont the notes up
its gingerbread through lollipop I think
so not the most recent version of
Android but just to give you guys an
idea
diversions that are affected cover about
92 percent of Android devices obviously
not all this have Qualcomm chipsets are
not ninety percent of Android devices
were vulnerable but still a huge
percentage and the vulnerability I
forget what the API name was but it was
pretty low level obviously if its
vulnerability in Qualcomm they make the
radio chipsets for a lot of cell phones
allows you to read text messages view
the the call logs and also perform radio
actions from the device so radio actions
are basically all the stuff that you
barely use your phone for anymore so not
the ABS not browsing the web but some of
the more basic things like sending text
messages and calling people and other
one was the Instagram bug that caused a
lot of news outlets due to the age of
the reporter
a ten year old kid found a bug in
Instagram that allows you to delete
comments from other users and got
rewarded $10,000 so that was an internal
API within the Instagram code that had
that vulnerability another couple ones
that are that are interesting and fun to
look up after this the person was a
manipulation of it s late so whether or
not you release the API to people if
it's in something that they can access
their gonna poke around they're gonna
either look at your source code if they
can if not they're gonna look at the
request on the wire so both of these
stories come from people basically
looking at the web calls from the mobile
clients that snapped and Tesla have and
I know if you guys saw the video but
somebody used Alexa from Amazon echo to
be able to open up their garage door
turn on the Tesla and pull their car out
of the garage similar tonight writer so
that was kind of fun
snapchat one speaking of Absa California
if you ever wanna come out to california
during January we basically don't have
winter if you've never been out there so
if you're from an area that has winter
can be pretty pretty fun to come out
anyway the director of info second
snapshot this year gave I thought is
really good presentation about all the
issues that they have with people
manipulating the API's and using them
for functionality that they weren't
designed for so snapshot doesn't release
a public API for their program but what
people do is though piece together
different versions API calls maybe from
an older version Android a newer version
of iOS something else in the middle I
don't know if there's a version for
Windows found that you might pull
something from there too and basically
what people do is come up with these
third-party additions to snap trap that
all out for new functionalities so maybe
you can save messages without notifying
the person that sent it to your things
like that and this is a major problem
for them because they can't just shut
down these older versions the API is
because they risk locking out people
that are using all their versions of
snapshot obviously you know the more
users that they have the
more money that they're making so it's
very difficult for them to monitor the
functionality of these older API's and
things that shouldn't be happening and
allowing people to counsel you
compromise on a few guys remember but in
there's a major act against snapchat
snapshot said that it was actually
third-party services that people have
been logging into it there snapped a
credentials the way that those
third-party services work are based off
of manipulating the API using it for
things that it wasn't intended or so
david mentioned this a little bit
earlier but API's are often neglected
during testing usually API is are harder
and less fun to test I know that when I
was doing pen testing I mean what would
you rather look at some web app that you
don't know what the heck is doing but
you can still find fun things to break
in it or just a bunch of simple API
calls were you have to do a bunch of
work to fill in parameters you know
you're not doing the same air messaging
that you're frequently getting from the
web application just generally not as
fun in my opinion to mess around with
just the text it's more fun to break
stuff that you can see in addition
depending on how robust the API is maybe
it's more like an SDK you might actually
have to build something which not all
web 10 testers are comfortable doing
especially you know if you don't really
have as strong a development background
and even if you do it still just way
more time consuming than just looking
through somebody's web application for
abstinence himself in the background
you're looking for some stuff on your
own but the API's you're gonna have to
copy and paste a bunch of stuff into
whatever intercepting proxy or using so
some of the standard tools that people
rely on bill with API has in mind for
testing we don't really know where to
fit this mean but I just typed in
spider-man security me when this came up
so I felt like it needed to be somewhere
just put it to you signify that David
was going to take back over for a couple
slides
yeah Thnkx least yeah I couldn't i
couldn't remove that mean I mean look as
I feel like it's probably okay so you
know as part of this project and like I
said we're trying to do this you know
documentation for trying to actually
create things that will help developers
will help end testers although if they
don't have a code that's going to be
difficult no matter which basically a
sort of like a document that we can
released to the world that will actually
bring some exposure to the project and
will actually you know actually help out
some people quickly we decided to put
together an API security top 10 as I
mentioned before really all about these
top 10 lists I don't know why I feel
like a Busby article but we decided to
use or to just go with the scheme and
say I separate pages
APS security list next release candidate
as I mentioned it began to talk we
looked at the statistics that we've put
together from that crowd we looked at
major high-profile breaches that we
could see in the media and we said ok I
think we can correlate these into what
we find to be major pitfalls you guys
might have a different experience we're
more than happy in fact very much
encouraged people to give us feedback if
you say hey like you're missing
something or hey this isn't accurate
we'd love to hear that bill said we'd
love to hear that ok so like I said this
is based on the aggregate data we
couldn't release the full day that we
use some big crowd because that's
actually people security findings
fix them all things along those lines
but we're gonna actually released the
top 10 right after this talk you guys
will be able to download it assuming I
find my laptop in washington stuff like
that
barker's ok
shift so every time so everybody who's
familiar at the cost of ten is familiar
with things like cross-site scripting
sequence action command injection we
decided to kind of just bundle all of
these into a single category injections
been the injection has been the the top
number one slot in the office top 10 we
thought you know it's getting a little
bit too much tracks on its own
bring it down a couple notches and
combine it with some of the other the
other groups and from an API perspective
a lot of these kind of fall under the
same category of remediation or more
prevention it all boils down to improper
data sanitization tables and shit bro so
the second one is insufficient access
control this occurs when API methods are
not check correctly for privileges so in
this example there's the device
manufacture and all it was checking was
making sure that you are a user in the
organization that was able to make
configuration changes so if I mean user
and david is a Super Admin it didn't do
any checking to make sure that I wasn't
a Super Admin I could do any of the
changes that he did just by having a
valid credentials are basically made the
role-based access control for the device
meaningless considering the lowest tier
performing the highest actions another
example of this is the Instagram hacks
wasn't checking to make sure that the
person to leading the comment was the
person that had actually posted it and
so if I posted a comment on senate
David's Instagram photos that he didn't
like he would be able to you know them
from from his account you might actually
be able to do that anyway I guess I
could delete things that he had posted
on the event photos that's a good
example and one that actually makes
sense
the next category is insecure direct
object reference this is probably one of
my favorite ones from doing web pen
testing from the normal oh I stopped 10
I will say that my favorite is actually
see search just because it seems that
sneaky and it combines things are social
engineering I don't know why I was just
like CSIR findings but I'd or insecure
direct object reference is definitely an
old favorite from from the web app top
10 this example was another device
manufacture and what would happen during
the registration process is as part of a
POST request you would send along the
devices serial number as part of the
registration or lock the device to my
account so that nobody else could
register it generally a good idea
the problem was is you could just
iterate through and register as many
devices to your account as possible
which would then lock out all the other
people that it actually bought that vice
so if we both thought the same little
device I could just register Davis and
then he couldn't use it
ok so this one is similar
another 14 insecure direct object
reference this comes from a company that
companies will use the send out
questions to people you probably gotten
one that's like oh hey how happy where
you at this product please rate it
125 you know maybe this section 4
comments or something like that as part
of this you could initiate a request
that would allow you to gain access to
anyone's responses so whether or not
they were in your organization whether
or not it was a search a survey that UN
even sent out to your customers you are
able to access that information so you
could get information about how happy
somebody was with your competitors
assuming that they're using the same
service and that you could enter it
through and actually find their company
this x1 I believe as part of the top 10
in 2010
and then there's a similar category in
the mobile application top 10 except
they call it
insecure cryptography attack it and I T
I think that also covers stuff that's on
the devices too so it's a little bit
more broad but without web browsers
spewing big areas which they've gotten
pretty good at especially chrome trim
has been pretty aggressive with
deprecating things like Shah 1922 the
kids things like that I mean there's a
ton of reasons now I companies at least
have the little red marks to the HTTPS
if not a big old warning that if Greece
people out we see frequently with API is
that people just aren't even adding the
s in HTTPS I mean it's really that easy
for a lot of these things for whatever
reason maybe there was some problem that
you had earlier maybe there is like some
certificate problems and whatever
library or you are using for that was
failing and not letting you why so as a
developer you alright well let's just do
HDPE it works he just don't revisit it
is too so i flying public API is
released oftentimes times for example
some really good gem to make it easily
accessible like some other sort of
package and oftentimes even though the
actual API documentation is saying hey
you know this is a niche CBS called it
is those same people that are releasing
that EP I will not restricts non HDS
request and then you have the third
party making this wrapper saying that
while the West earlier so that would
actually make your chance to even the
API itself is documenting itself
correctly they left they left a hole an
example of this was there is that vitek
breach at the end of last year for those
unfamiliar as a toy manufacturer and as
part of the breach there was five
million parents names addresses other
Pai as well as the
the names and birthdays of 200,000
children so that got a lot of press it
it was unclear exactly where that breach
came from it seemed to be sequel
injection not related to transport layer
security reason why I brought it up is
because I hunted a little bit of extra
digging into the security of their
products and their websites in town that
pretty much nothing was using HTTPS for
the web calls so this is definitely
something that still a major problem
even if it wasn't how that company got
breed so it's a pretty big breach of
last year so we thought it was worth
mentioning as as an example
sensitive data exposure this occurs when
API is allow queries that are
excessively broad a major example of
this would be social graph style API is
that seem to be particularly vulnerable
an example of this would be the grinder
vulnerability from a couple of years ago
basically is an unauthenticated user you
can login to Grindr and say show me the
50 closest people that are also signed
up for Grindr if those users had their
location shared within the application
you can use a process called trail
adoration which is basically you make
that same request three times and based
off of your location changing and the
new distance for those people I guess
you have to move around between the
request but so you could move around a
little bit make the same request as long
as that person was present for all those
requests and they didn't moves you can
use that to get their exact location
using some of the math and geometry that
that's on the screen
they would expose some of his exact
location so one so this was a problem in
countries that have rather strict anti
gay laws you can use it to find not just
kind of the general location of where
somebody's out but you can use it to
pinpoint exactly yeah talking to
yeah exactly that's how he found me to
hear it sends a clear yeah is it is it i
think as a referral right now we also
had a pretty long conversation about
trial adoration restraint violation
different things
ok so we serve said security pretty
straight forward in terms of what that
actually means so much and no issues are
known vulnerabilities in third-party
components basically occurs when the
server itself the API endpoint is
vulnerable so there's a lot of different
ways that this can come to light a lot
of different ways that we've seen this
happening in the real world for example
if your opening ACL's on Apr 10 points
you might just say whatever just all
trafficking go to this we're just gonna
remove all security and then your tax
service will obviously increase if
you're allowing every service to behead
you'll have the standard Internet know
is that everything i've been the
internet will see then there's also
service are vulnerabilities like partly
it's tragic I chose the name drugs
because security but you know we see
things like we have is a VMware has been
running for five years basically
sometimes people don't monitor it
oftentimes you see like cops teams that
aren't really touching what they
consider to be developer control ABIM
points and then went something like
hardly comes out or image tragic of an
image processing API people don't
necessarily patches and then you have
vulnerable systems just sitting on the
Internet in property handling is is kind
of cool because its unique 22 API is
this is this is I gave leave credit for
this image is pretty great
basically it's a PR specific in that
generally web applications are manually
giving you choose to use right i mean
you could say a certain thing sort of
just yes things like that but really
it's sort of API specific API keys for
those of you who may not have
implemented an API basically popular
authentication mechanisms always managed
in the same way so like if you're gonna
maybe say like having a check for ever
question you're making ok that's pretty
secure actually making sure that they
have the key to have a secret things
working but a lot of times we see ok
here's a forty character alphanumeric
string this is your key don't lose it
this is all you need right
the problem is it's not always say a
forty character random string we see
things like lackey verification meaning
if you have the right schema and that
it's safe for the characters doesn't
have special characters they say oh this
looks like a valid key we're gonna
actually allow any requests from which
is pretty bad
sequential or otherwise predictable keys
provable admin bits and he is like
having a secondary Kiwi basically like a
diamond had been using your own etcetera
so we have basically a really simple
example for this this actually
highlights two of those problems if
you're sending a request you API in this
case your listing users and you have a
Pik first of all this is definitely be
in the URL get requests as its get it
also if you're curious something like
1336 that's probably going to be
sequential write a it's only for
character or four digits and being mean
it's a pretty well one at that
so a lot of organizations just increment
a counter they use the idea of you know
and that's how it works so clearly if
you have that you can very easily sort
of brute force everyone else is just
quickly run through 10,000 numbers and
all of a sudden you have access to
everyone's count inconsistent API
functionality is something that we
alluded to a little bit before and is
generally pretty severe this basically
occurs when API functions work
fundamentally differently than those in
the primary application so a secondary
team came in
wrote the API to basically say hey we're
gonna make all the functions but again
they're not spending may be an
eighteen-month dev Psychol on creating
like a really nice heart medication they
don't have the security team coming in
and do incurred if you like we can just
open up these functions its final
stretch of database an example here
would be you know in like a facebook web
at taking care of her with the person is
tagged but if you're taking the API
access but as you share with everyone
right i mean that's just not correctly
mimicking the actual function that
you're trying to implement via the API
just saying this is pretty pretty much
doing what it's supposed to one of the
really high profile examples of this
would be a sort of rate limiting in the
face vs the API the most the most
well-known probably being the Apple
celebrity photo basically if you're
logging into an iCloud account you can
do something like I don't know five
attempts and slows you down or locks you
out something like that
pretty standard to have in most
applications but there was a point where
you could basically just brute force
they didn't have that same rate limiting
in place for that particular API request
so that he can say okay I know whose
email address I'm trying to get into you
I can go through you know ten million
passwords in Seattle take some time to
send their request but there's no actual
rate limiting the pastor that way it's
unclear if thats exactly how that had
took place but after a did Apple patched
the vulnerability so maybe ask you to
configure this configuration yeah I i I
always hated this type of this title is
but we as going through the data and
high profile data we realized that we
needed to have this kind of catch
alright other tight ends to energy use
it it's basically saying that due to
some sort of human error whether that's
how you're deploying
it or developer and made just some
horrific mistake the AP is not behaving
the way that it should it's not doing
exactly what we expect and it's causing
problems opening the attack servers
causing more vulnerabilities to flaws
that we talked about before and the rest
of these less or just being kind of
uniquely messed up there is there's a
plethora of weird examples for that but
they're hard to go over without
disclosing that apply to so we've gone
through you know why it is important
we've gone through a sort of our process
some examples there and what we consider
to be pretty much the top ten major risk
categories when deploying an API things
that if your pen tester you're probably
going to want to look into some sort of
the real I don't see the point of the
talk but it would be great if someone to
sort of help with us right now it's
mainly in our spare time today we're
publishing the first draft of the API
security top 10 it's going to basically
be a nice concise version of the size
that we have here and easily readable
PDF short descriptions of what's going
on
we'd really like to get feedback on what
we've seen here you know and if any
researchers want to you know help us
create more of these that'd be great
again if if it's hey you've missed
something that would be great for me to
say we don't agree with one of these
findings that would also be but our
goals as I mentioned the very beginning
of the stock are really a lot of broader
than just saying hey we're gonna make
another top 10 document it's really easy
to display that via the slides and to
have a nice presentation when we go to
the top 10 but really our goal here is
to sort of make a documentation that can
really help out
developers and testers I sort of mood
from the red team when I was 22 of the
blue team and helping out developers and
it's it's a little sad how little
information there really is out there
that's like hey we can actually help you
write something in a super secure way
and said just like hey we're gonna teach
everyone how to break it which is
admittedly much more fun but you know we
have to help developers to you were
trying to basically make this portal to
help Deb strain deploy security guys so
we're looking for security researchers
to expand on the risks here to critique
what we've already done
technical writers you know basically
create cheats cheat sheet style you know
tutorials for developers if we have any
designers in the audience this is really
a market for designers but designers in
the audience base to help us accurately
display our data look pretty for people
you know sort of general evangelists for
help spread the research programs
project see you probably think saying
like wow that sounds great I'm so
excited like you guys are the bestest
person best presentation ever seen how
can I sign up right and I we like we'd
like to tell you how to do that you can
find the alpha stage of our project at
hola squeaky I'm not gonna read out that
whole URL but I security project you can
search for it if you'd like to help you
can contact me directly via my email
David outshot and I just put the slides
online so for all the links and the
research and things like that
their availability shot on net / no luck
on underscore 2016 tapia so thank you
guys for being here right now it's
Friday afternoon Orleans so you know
there's that any questions or concerns
or anything like that I i mean I don't
drink it
that's a good question with no questions
since we took longer than expected and
yeah it please feel free to find us
we're gonna be around all weekend happy
to hang out with anyone or talk about if
your security or so thank you guys