in a few of tokens is good for that if
you need more tokens you can harass
sponsors to give them to you or we are
selling the tokens up at the front desk
as well they're five bucks a drink with
the hotel charges for drinks so we want
to help out so with that said I would
agree X if you're not playing with any
of our to CT office please check them
out we have been nice pyramid technical
CTF going on all the way down the hall
in the open source stuff last I checked
so few people were doing the open source
in the trader based CET effet victory
was like guaranteed and come up with you
can you can only wins
alright how's everybody doing you know
the thing I like about no luck on first
talk is it 1 o'clock that's awesome
stench alright well at least I got to
sleep in today
rights who today just give a basic
network monitoring in analysis talk so
we're gonna go through this so
traditional disclaimer you know these
are my own views they're not the views
of Lake my family my kids my way my
in-laws people they work for customers
to the stuff like that so these are all
mine so I hill from the medal dc-area so
is there anybody from a dc-area here now
I knew few people that were gonna be
here but so a little bit about me so the
industry for about 20 years I think the
slides of the year old but then in
industry for over 20 years of about
seventy those years have been focused on
information security prior to that I was
just basically doing I T type stuff
which is where I learned all the basics
in all the different I T rooms that you
know really hoped when I transition to
the security in in choosing a career in
Information Security past five or so
years I've been working in more of an
operational environment doing sock type
stuff
but as you can see there you know I over
the years I've done a lot of things you
know it started out doing fun stuff like
10 testing and web application testing
and then I got into more the paperwork
tape stuff in the middle of my career
sitting like security engineering
working for the government doing this
type stuff for accreditation did props
and fine in that you know really fun
stuff but at a certain point I decided
that he wanted to try to get more into
doing some of the technical aspects of
security so I was able to win a job just
doing cannot read studies with looking
at all the different products that are
out there doing take us said that was
fine in like I said the past few years
I've been working in a sock everything
from me in in almost all the way up to
now where we are merely doing training
and I guess sort of advisers so you know
trying to help people make their socks
more fish in to this is my website if
you wanna check it out and over in the
sector com been running it since 2008 I
go through periods where a blog a lot
like sometimes three times a day and
then some times where I do you like 10
months so depends on how much time I
have so doing you know trying to like
everybody else in security I'm trying to
start my own thing cause I'm tired of
trying to work cuz I'm tired of working
for the big man in making money for them
and not myself to be interested hit me
up
alright so today on to the topic that
we're gonna be talking about is is
monitoring and network security so just
go through a little introduction talked
about an environment of how you can set
this up to learn your so we're set
something up in an enterprise
environment the methodology for how to
get through so if you're an analyst you
know what's the process for going
through that and it secondly we're to
learn more
for people that want to get into it as
well as analysts that they may have
certain
knowledge gaps to help fill fill those
most of those are off read and then the
next thing is you know what now so
you've heard this talk you've done these
things and you know what can you do now
rights to first I want to talk about
just you know why why I'm doing this in
in just some basic definitions to do so
that we all get baseline to the same
level so the first one is you know it's
for
I don't know I get somebody like myself
where mid-career I was doing more people
based security and I want to get more
hands on to it was a great time for
maybe general security practitioners to
go in and get back into doing something
hands on stuff a lot of the knowledge
that they have we was very useful in in
in so it it wasn't that bad of a
transition plus it was in an operational
environment so it was a lot more fun if
you spend too much time designing
security you know you have these
theoretical understandings of you know
these academic understandings of house
stuff is supposed to work but when you
get in the real world doesn't work like
that so it's good to get that experience
regardless in the second group is you
know maybe you just started working in a
soccer doing analysis and II kinda
giving giving you a crew a career path
here how to do your job more effectively
and also if there are any specific
knowledge gaps
trying to give you sort of the map of
what needs to be filled in nicely it's
kind of fun you know we all like to
watch TV shows and you know mystery in
order to solve the crime and stuff and
so you know essentially that's what it's
kinda like you know so you're gonna get
in there and get this alert and then
you're gonna have to learn as much about
that it is possible to de- termine you
know hey is this something that we're
going to investigate
for there is something we can
investigate further there in then make
the decision if you want to go down that
path so the first thing is so how many
of you here you know done worked in an
operational environment like a soccer
something like that
ok for keeping hands up for the people
that are brave enough to put their hands
up so how would you define what network
monitoring and announces
everyone's learning that he and now any
anybody I i have candy she should get
that was hoping you can spot a pattern
quickly and way too much
yeah right any other thoughts here what
do you like Twix Snickers Milky Way
nothing no I don't you can tap somebody
that if you want to give it to someone
else would he tell him we're all getting
old are you want what would you want
Nikki way nice catch nagano Holden
watching on sugar kind of fun stuff
anymore
any israeli is there anyone else wants
to you take a you know shot and get some
free candy I need to have like a really
good candy apparently is not a
motivating factor right so so my funny
answers it's basically the monitoring
analysis of networks right so and in
this is from Richard be a liquor towel
security to follow him on Twitter in one
of his old books you know I think it's
like 2002 2003 and so he basically
defined it was the collection analysis
and escalation of indicators in warnings
to detect in response to intrusions so
there's a formal definition you know I'm
a process guys why wouldn't a process
that more like a framework I so I I like
to have kind of a path laid out until I
kinda just tentatively kind of break
things down into there's a selection
says there's a there's a triage phase
and there's an analyzed his right so
keeping that in mind so for those that
have heard in socks before like what do
you think how would you define what goes
on in a selection of teas ok signatures
so so you're gonna like stuff based on
certain signatures ok thats foundation
Milky Way got my arms gonna kill me
after this election him no assets or
anybody else selection what's the
selection process like how do you select
the of your gonna look at anomalies
sessions are uncertain about their
training people right so that's enough
of that so really it's just basically
just you know don't using a letter to
investigate just kind of like what you
guys said you know there are different
ways and we'll go over that of of how to
choose them but those are two really you
choose the most high quality and
relevant alerts from the centers that
are out there and really we're looking
at you know not necessarily what the
vendor says is high but the key word
here is role relevant trying to
distinguish out of all those alerts are
flooding our systems which one are
relevant to your organization rate so
then so then the order so it really
varies by organization you know some
organizations if they're just starting
out it's probably just to see you see
just do whatever you want if it's more
and more mature they probably have a
process that they want you to follow
generally like going from you know some
high priority events all the way down to
low priority events right so I thought I
mister slide their rights to the next
area in Lake the second phase here is
triage and so how would you define would
realizes does it say what it's supposed
to
ok right away are expecting traffic to
look like versus you know what is
actually doing alright alright sorry
about that
get bad reviews right and anybody else
yeah
yes he made the medical analogy where in
your near the battlefield in in trying
to dive into the things that you can be
saved now vs stuff that can be pushed to
later right and you don't want any candy
I'm gonna stop throwing candy but I
think people are mad at me but alright
so basically quickly separating the
alerts needing further analysis from the
irrelevant ones like you at least in
security room that that's how I kind of
look at it because depending on how much
air sensor admins are you could be
flooded with star so you know really
being able to parse through that and
pick out the South its most relevant to
your organization so the goals are to
you identify alerts needing for their
investigation disorder reseeding that in
the eniac activities that you're gonna
be doing here is your gonna be really
looking at the alerts in further detail
to discover why it fired you know hey
this stage the signature fired in in
sometimes you can get a little bit in
network traffic in looking at the
network traffic in saying hey we were
trying to alert on the keyword secret
you know but you know it it maybe
somebody emailing somebody else seen
saying oh here's the secret book here's
the secret anniversary location that
were gonna meet up rate so it may not be
as bad as what you think and I think one
of the most important things here is
what is whenever something fires you
know if if you get past that that point
is to look through the prior knowledge
that you have so missed organ
organizations is going to be incident
reports but I encourage you know socks
to have other I guess like analysts
knowledge bases where they can document
common things so so that is new people
come in they don't have to reinvent the
wheel
it endlessly just doing some basic open
source analysis as well some internal
analysis to determine things like re
well let's look at the source and
destination IP and in the ports and
proved caused you determine if this is
something like say it was like a Linux
attack against like a you know Microsoft
Web server well you know we really don't
care too much about that until the last
area that we're looking at here is an
analysis based on the first two phases
what do you think I'm talking about here
whenever I say announces ok looking into
the incident so what types of things do
you think we would be doing there now
we're source destination IP IDs yeah
anybody else
the response traffic in how often it
happens if there's damage with that
damage is ok right now I'm not gonna
throw these anymore but if you wanna
come up in USD questioning just leave
these appeared for you to grab alright
so I tried defined as you know so you
have your your primary sources which are
you are usually your sensors you know in
in in in in there are 0 none of these
things that aren't specifically centers
but their devices that are supporting
resources to determine the validity of
that attack into the girls here are to
determine the actions at the attacker
may have taken within your network
key activities that you would be doing
here is basically the key indicators
which you've found probably from your
alert such thing is like Eyed Peas dont
means ports things like that you know
look using those as pieces of data that
you can get off of to go look through
these data repository so things like you
know hey i'm looking like that first and
if you're lucky enough to have full
packet capture unit being able to dive
in and there's a whole bunch of
resources hear that a lot of people
don't take advantage of a number to talk
about that a little later Wright city
environment ok so the first areas and i
wanna talk about you know is you know
really what is so we're talking about
the centers here in this doesn't do
traditionally were talking about like in
IDS and IPS you know it can be networked
laser can be no space but if you look at
more generically I mean you have
different sort of detection systems were
almost every Aussie have suffered losses
on emails to focus is on you know web
applications there is you know your
fancy stuff where where it
tools that you strip attachments out in
intraday explodes in a chamber to see
what they do so just think of it that
way so it's definitely you know nowadays
much more than just a basic network
ideas and usually you have there's two
types of their signature base which is
like a well whenever this attack is done
there is this specific series of
characters
folks idk again unfortunately every
media has yet again failed me and yet
the fastball to about the ninety minute
35 seconds mark for the audio resume so
yes I am looking for better video
capture devices to do not tell me
so i cant
alright so you have something the
network level traditionally you're
starting out with NetFlow which is just
basically you know never statistics you
know based on source and destination IP
imports you know determining who talked
to who and how much data is transferred
so nesler the advantage of that is its
relatively small see store for long
amounts of time you know great for doing
running stuff that may have occurred
like six 6 months back in the second is
for packet capture and so you know
depending on the amount of traffic that
you have you may be able to store like a
few days of this you know the goal would
obviously try to get you know seven to
10 days or thirty days but depending on
how much funding you have that may not
be possible so the other thing that's
the actual network traffic but then you
have the logs that are sort of device
plugs that are helping transmit this
entry information throughout the network
so it seems like you're just firewall
logs and those are tremendously helpful
just looking at connections that are set
up torn down there are certain protocols
that FTP added that have a lot of
information they're in the same thing
with routers and switches there's you
know all the words associated with those
two then you have application logs so
you know I think of like your mail
server your web server file server dns
whatever said these are logs that are
associated with that so you know right
now like DNS is big and I think proxies
have especially like HTTP proxies have
always been big has a lot of traffic
does overreached HTTP because it's wide
open hole so you know that used as an
attack vector as it's easy to the actor
has an excellent actor so it's a proxy
logs you can actually see a lot of that
stuff happening
if you didn't stop there and in other
detectable preventive sources is you may
have an idea system that has low alert
that you would normally just e nor well
you know whenever like you can also use
those those low priority in your sensing
infrastructure to gain more information
about a potential tax so they can be not
only a primary sources alerts but they
can be you know as supporting resource
as well to the external there's like a
gazillion places on the internet where
you can go and grab stuff so you know
dis with the stuff that I've done and
stuff that a teach-in a lot of people
that I talk to you
of trying to put together a kind of a
basic list of where to start until there
is other places
obviously Google is a big resource and
mean a lot of times you can distance
there's an indicator you can just search
for hidden like an IEP and see what
comes up for a half hour or so something
like that there there's also I think was
Jack crook put a cust a few years ago he
put a customized search engine a
customized Google search and in together
called active threat certain said he did
the same thing where he found like the
20 or so sites that he always uses for
doing OS in and he created a customized
search engine for it so you to search
for that good resource and then
definitely when you're dealing with like
I peas and beans looking at you know who
is dns type stuff so
and you never ever me a glitch but it's
starting to audio back up shortly
it I didn't move that I swear so passive
DNS is huge and then you also have your
old you knew traditional command line
type such as who is so the next category
Israel his reputation databases so you
are worried is so mean I recommend you
know if your gonna check out as you know
definitely doing the search first to see
if someone else had searched on it you
know there's a scary that that is you
get in
alert and you submit it lives
analysis to europe you are worried that
you know you're hitting the attackers
interests infrastructure and that's
tipping your hand it that you know how
to detect them but depending on you know
the sector that you're in you know that
may or may not be of significance in
enter a URL void in IP voice of those
are just kind of meh engines that put
together data from various sites that
measure website reputation in nineteen
reputation web archives is huge so
Google cash is always a fun you know
like a lot of times if if you'll find
out if your gonna go to try to see that
adversaries infrastructure maybe it's a
website or whatever you know you can
just google it and I headed directly in
an area and also the traditional way
back machine and then passive scanning
so I'm not talking about like you know
during active scanning say with nmap but
there's a lot of tools out there there
are already two scanning the internet so
why not take advantage of those results
so that we can learn about what the
attackers infrastructures so
traditionally I think most people here
have heard of showed in awesome
awesome stuff they're just put in IP in
get tons of information associated with
it reports that are open for each one of
those you have banners
lot of good stuff in academic realm
there's something called it I heard
about it recently but it's it's called
center style that another resource you
may want to check out in this was
released like a few years back on April
four years ago was called punks player
to work continues on that and that's
focusing on web applications so for
websites it'll go and you know scandal
website and determine what some of the
basic
vulnerabilities associated with it are
or if it's good and then just turn it in
there you know just kind of old school
you know the cross you know what what
what's a site running if you want to
learn more about it see then add the
medicine it's great to virustotal
obviously you know it started out where
you could just make files in the net
file scan by Lake 38 the engines but
it's really evolved into you are able
you can do the same thing you can see me
URLs to it you can search for it you can
search for houses there's even I don't
know who they're working with but they
even though they seem to be doing
behavioral analysis to use if you submit
a file through one of its partners in a
pool in some behavioral analysis sort of
a detonation and in what that did too
passive total as a name you know this is
kind of your passive way to learn as
much information as possible
it started out as being more of a passes
DNS type service where you could search
and it was free but now they've gone
commercial but they were like the
average user like you get I don't like
50 free quarries per day so
ok yes so if you're a researcher you can
email them and they made you up to now
they start out with massive DNS but
they're also pulling in a lot of other
good stuff to you so excellent site to
check out in the crowd crowd which is a
crowd-sourced say they have put in IP an
indoor pool in some information about
that in in from various resources so
that you can get a better understanding
of that it has a school where a kind of
graph where you'll have your IP in the
middle you can click on it and you can
pivot around and stuff it looks really
cool but to be honest I would rather
write it down on the notepad next to my
keyboard way but it's kind of course for
you know management right to sue the
third
the other the last mean component of the
environment here is simply store this
off so you know a central place to pull
out all the stuff into one place so the
sources include obviously your sensor
alerts blogs and stuff from all your
different supporting resources and
external resources here but it just
Steve like I would just wouldn't come
tons of external stuff and I would find
this stuff that most useful for you and
maybe keep that in any event for the
rest of the stuff you adjust to life
searches so whatever this device is you
can figure it to show alerts you know if
it's the same type of thing maybe you
can correlate multiple alerts together
to to make it to increase the alert
fidelity by so there's two aspects there
there's kind of like your pearson's
which are things like art say it or you
know tons of other ones that are out
there but you know just to get started
Ely involved you know it's based on open
source so you can start out with that
in then they have a commercial there's a
whole bunch of them out there if you
wanna do you know how to categorize it
but more like adaptions so you know is
you know more of just a great place to
display all your logs in but you know
they've written modules so that you can
have sort of an older teen you know it
doesn t correlation as well but I don't
personally like I see money going and
invest money in in all these expensive
seems they can do
correlation but then like no endeavor
using it so so that's a situation you
can go something like that and it's free
for up to a certain amount of data if
you just wanna check it out of Splunk in
if you wanna go open source search the
technology to go it is probably more of
the stock so it isn't that bad to set up
its pretty clean
takes a few minutes he even I did it so
putting her big picture together it
looks something like this where you have
the year you know the blue says we're
all your house estate is pulled together
maybe you have you know like your log
collector there and maybe you're logged
collector is acting as your central
place design alerts or maybe you have a
system that doing that and then you have
your analyst workstation so you're
usually in you know you usually have
having some sort of in in point security
solutions so you know just your
traditional AV kids whatever is out
there in this survey on you know you
basically have the same thing but but
agents are you know more focused on
doing server stuff and you definitely
have you like all these green things are
the data associated with those you know
you have there's logs there and you can
use that as a supporting resource
something with your router so having
some sort of the network intrusion
device you know you can place that
wherever depending on what your strategy
is but you know here I just stayed
behind the firewall and you have your
firewall logs in and you maybe have like
your web server logs in your email
you know and you may have agents on news
machines as well
your full packet capture sitting where
ever you know if you just turn out maybe
just capture for a limited time from
sitting on the outside maybe you wanna
concerns do you do that to the Indian
side and if you get real mature maybe
you have full packet capture on each of
the different way and they're so the
agency in early in traffic and then when
you have your stuff that you can get
externally such as all the stuff like
Google who is tough
etcetera so so where to start out here
it's so integrated environment you can
kind of start with is you know it's been
around for a few years now that works
without security onion it continues to
evolve mean this definitely isn't
something that you want to work on the
UN using a big enterprise but if you're
in a small you just starting out this is
like a great thing it's a great solution
to get going in the Indian doug has you
know he's working to try to come up with
you know box if people could just just
by this that has all this integrated
together as well but essentially you
just need like just an old PC the winner
on it has various different there's
different deployment options there's
three
component and you can either have them
all in one box or you can distribute
them however you want essentially like
you said you see this old beige box and
needing you need some sort of a router
that supports nearing or tapping in for
this at home you know very small
environment like the nETGEAR ProSafe are
good to start with the other one that I
like is pfSense so this is essentially a
firewall distro based on Debian once
again I just had an old desktop I just
installed this thing
click a few extra Knicks in in ready to
go
it does all the automatic updates like I
can see like one pushing I can get it
updated it has tons of modules you can
add stuff to it you know by default it
system firewall but you can add they
they have there's a snore model in style
on it there's a proxy module there's
even like you can run the OpenVPN on it
but there's tons of stuff there it's a
very nice system they also sell it as a
little box I think it's like a little
negate parks etc as well as well and
you're helping support them to two
security onion just to break down into
the different components that it has
it's based on Ubuntu you from an IDS
perspective it has snort terracotta and
bro from host intrusion detection system
its support from a supporting resources
you know so it has not slowed so you can
have to being one's two big ones there
are guests in then bro has sort of a net
flew like their connection log so it's
natural lake in an application in
product protocol ugh so gross and that's
basically you know like if you don't
have your actual application logs broke
basically read all the network traffic
over it and creates applet lake
application like logs to that very
useful for as an example if you didn't
have any HTTP proxy it has an HTTP like
that is sort of like ittt prior H H D
prior to get the door but but it will
produce you know web server type blogs
were male type blogs so it's a nice
in-between between just an FYI which is
purely the lake just networks based on
the 52 balls and for packet capture and
so a lot of times you know instead of
having a beautiful packet capture you
can just looking at slow and look at
your bro application logs in in in
really have a good understanding of it
is something I have to worry about were
not and you don't even need to jump to
the full package then from an analysis
point you have it has various interfaces
so there is can even read in almost 30
square in another 10 snore my screen is
a little messed up here or I'm getting
old and need to get new glasses but
whatever so just various interfaces for
looking at all the traffic that is being
deducted by the Centers it has the same
sort of water with the elsa
Henderson miscellaneous stuff they're
such from an analyst perspective such as
network minor in Wireshark and its
linux-based so it has like all the other
cool things you can do with it to see
you can login and you know parse through
logs me nearly as well as I said there
are there are various deployment options
so you can either just have the box is
you know all three components together
just sitting one place in just watching
it there but if you put if you're
pushing it out you're probably in a
separate out your sensor to where you
want it to be in then you can have a
server that is probably inside your
network somewhere so the center of seeds
the server in then there's a
console aspect to it which is what the
analysts would be working at day today
right so so we had like this environment
in which I know what it is but the next
question is you how do we do it right
and so does trying to go into the
methodology here so the first phase is
is your selection phase which I talked
about and essentially you know like we
talked about earlier to choose an alert
tu esta gate organizations may already
have a process or a priority like this
setup so you know one method which I
have it there as rate is usually hey
maybe you know high priority based on
vendor cigs you know any custom
signatures would be the next priority
you know and then you get down to you I
think this gentleman talked where you
would look at you know you would group
alert and do counts he can group them on
alert type you can also group than in
other ways such such as on the target IP
the victim the attacker I do the same
thing with ports to you so you can look
at it the data in different ways where
you have a lot of hits you know you
probably need to talk to your sensor
admin to look at that and in figure out
how we can make this signatures more
haven't worn the deputy but where you
have just a few hits you know those
maybe things that you may want to
investigate further
so then maybe you would go after that
you would maybe over the vendor says
this is medium alert maybe you would hit
that and if you can get through them all
you know then you can go all the way
down to you to whatever the little ones
are business people can't get through
them all so you know tips here if you're
just starting out you know don't you
pick so I worked in environments where
the ABC the CRA will your performances
based on the number of our search
incident reports that you put out and
you know and so people to cherry pick
the easy ones they put all these things
out and then write you know that's not
good you know you're not only
any first of all you're cheating
yourself especially if you're starting
out because you're not learning and
you're also cheating near organization
'cause there may be more you know more
threatening alerts that need
investigation and also you know if there
are a lot of alerts the always are
seeing its false positives you know work
closely with the sensor admins to you
you know really add more ability to
those signatures or you know get them to
turn them off because you know the more
stuff we have to go through the harder
it is to find so so the second phase was
triage into this is where you're going
to examine the details of whatever
alerts you selected find out why it
fired so here are you gonna start out
with you know if you're in assume you're
gonna
you may start out in a similar look at
all the data that was passed to the same
you may look at other within the send
you may look at rival what else what
other alerts
do we have with him with his target IP
or this attacker I P or maybe this alert
type until there's a lot of stuff we can
determine there or you may kinda dive
down into the source that generated the
alerts and maybe your ideas he would go
into higher and you look at the alert
and you look at the signature and
usually there's the write-ups hey check
out this link goes you know this
particular attack and especially if
you're new like you definitely want to
go and read those in turn them in and
make sense of it usually in the sensors
you're going to have the least some
snapshot of what the pcap looked like of
what it alerted on to you can actually
look at the peak out there and make a
quick determination if this was like a
secret document that was being sent over
the over the network or if it was just
somebody that used the word secret in an
email so but eventually you know all
this stuff you get to the point where
where you want to compare it with the
prior knowledge you know in the big step
here is to save time I think the
military term is you know force
multiplier
but he basically interview doing an
investigation from scratches somebody
didn't
investigation similar you can go back
and kind of do a lot of stuff based on
Lake Skip Bo lot of steps based on their
works he can go through your analysis
faster and so I'm not only talking about
incident reports were formally written
up but if there's a way that you know
the organization in like anything you
investigate even if it's a false
positive or it's a it's not relevant to
your organization in like even having a
database of those two things available
to is very useful so that you can go to
that internal knowledge so that you can
look at events go through of the that's
more efficiently so here is and I wasn't
sure to put this step in a tree I step
of the analysis phase but really so
looking at basic source destination IP's
just you know like I said if it's you
know it's a Linux attack on a on a web
server you know probably something you
not to worry about but if you get it
looks good in in in need to go to the
third third step that's where you jump
to the analyzed step into this is where
you really can't cut into all those
supporting resources that he's been
gathering data data from in based on
what you've gathered so far which are
usually indicators new search through
all the relevant resources you know and
learn as much as you can about those now
and then you're gonna be pivoting
authors because from one indicator you
will find maybe in IP in then you're
investigate dad and then you'll see
you'll find another internal he that
maybe like an attacker pivoted to so
you'll be pivoting around
doing fun stuff like that so this is
like I don't know what to call it but
everybody's coming up with with chains
you know so I just called this the cycle
so I was trying to come up with like a
unique analysis and wants a step but in
in analysis component to show people how
to do it and so I came up with this like
indicator analysis cycle so you
basically like there's usually some sort
of a stimulus which is in in in you
determine you know you would determine
what the indicators are searching
knowledge base to learn as much as you
can about it
determine where in auto logs they have
you can go look for it so you gonna call
you that methodology and then you get to
the final phase where you're going to
document the results that in some sort
of a knowledge base and then you have
two options while could that indicator
mediocre in another log well hey I'm
gonna go there and check that out to you
or you may get through this whole
process in this is where you at I
started out with IPA and oh my god I
discovered like IDP might be infected
too so you essentially destroyed the
process over again in in in in it sort
of comes up and it looks something like
this iterative process and eventually
you can get you all the announces that
you need to do and things start to fall
back in in your done obviously I think
most analysts don't have enough time to
Lake come through like follow this
process all the way through the end so
so that's where you come up with
different philosophies you know it's
it's really know the basic premise here
is to hypothesize based on what you know
what the attacker could you and then
look for evidence associated with that
you are a few different ways of doing
that and then you can use timeline
announces to kindly lay things out put
in place a lot of the intelligence
frameworks out there you can use those
too
rate is in a disease in attacker in I
detected them in the internal affairs
you know if I work backwards you know I
need to find the exploit delivery
cetera and then maybe work forward to
you so in there is other in there's a
bunch of different interference out
there I won't mention any but basically
just go out into the one that works for
you and if none of them work for you
discreet just create your own and start
working with it so we had to learn more
so there is Jack it's his twitter is on
the screen here J I think I miss me yet
its way
oh yeah jackson are sorry but yeah you
can check him out
follow him on Twitter but he came up
with his blog post where he was doing a
training plan for the analyst and he is
very high level and so I used in this is
a few years back and I use that in some
of the training that I put together two
but basically you know some fundamental
stuff that you definitely want to learn
up on you if you wanna get if you want
to become an injured in this field is
you know so the first one is links you
know the great thing about Linux is all
your analysis tools that you need are
built in right and you doing command
line stuff so you can definitely it's
harder but you can definitely take
analysis deeper into you more advanced
things we're doing is sort of like you
can only take analysis so far news hits
were to the limit so I just looks like
some Linux me don't need to be like a
Linux guru you just need to know some
basic stuff you know just how did you
listening make directories changer on
how to get help rate because that's when
you can do that and to learn new things
intermediate you know being able to use
things like grow up and we're counting
stuff 22 gay gather basic stats strings
is also a big depending on what you're
doing
operators for directing your output or
for meeting output in and directing it
out and also putting different
communities together so you can you
really advanced cool stuff and then
advanced stuff you know where you start
doing more statistical type stuff for
you can do it so can cut xargs home
until like regular expressions are
awesome for being able to find stuff in
in in in in learning some some of the
scripting languages like you know aux
said you're just doing basic parsing
data bash you know just learning that in
in in Python speak to
so the other fundamental is networking
basics just understand the basic
networking contacts you know the whole
tcp/ip stack on important but also
understand what it looks like you know
don't understand what the TCP handshake
is understand you know what in HTTP
session looks like after that one in SSL
session looks like exeter so really you
know be able to bring these things up in
Wireshark and be able to just quickly
identify them
0 gap analysis you know you are already
talked about Wireshark just being able
to use that tool as as much as possible
and also would like to remind stuff i
mean there's no t-shirt which is the
command line version of Wireshark
there's also a tcpdump then there's also
a lot of Lake interesting tools that are
in Linux by default lake Lake little
scripts that will automatically go
through and pull out
attachments or or you can do regular
expressions searches through the binary
teacup like just lots of cool stuff
there and then flow analysis so you know
basically understand that how you can
use it you know I talked about what that
was the tools you know it's kind of a
big houses framework but like I said if
you can use you know security onion and
you can learn our guests in my mind so
it's not as fun but but you can only
carve up the data and grab some
interesting stuff so the final part is
loud analysis and so on the network side
this is just understanding I mean you're
going to be an expert but just
understanding the basics of all the
different laws that are out there you
know and then being able to google the
rest if you need to dive in two more
details so have you know proxy log your
firewall logs in certain critical in the
same thing on host you know most of us
are you most enterprises or Windows so
you have all your Windows logs
endpoint security solutions so being
able to pull this off
pull this off of the management server
associated with them and like I said you
don't have to be like a super expert in
all these but you need to know the
basics and just be able to use Google
very well so there is no where to learn
more so training dot info I'm a big fan
of them and they have a whole kind of
school of stock type thing so there's a
lot of good stuff they're just kind of
point out there's some of the act of
classes that they have now are the ones
at the top there flow analysis in
network honey introduction in network
forensics analysis network
ironing out of those they have videos
that are recreated the have labs with
the NZ you can download because you can
download and then slides too so it's a
great resource that people are sort of
like open knowledge that people are
publishing stuff there for training and
certifications I mean if you can do
scenes you know the G CIA in the DCI
agers are really good if you're in the
federal space Daytona specify those to
see answered they also the CH which you
know not really sure about that but I
guess somebody pay them enough money in
a vendor search too so you know if the
company that you're working for uses
arcs a tour like new nitro or involved
or whatever there's training usually
associated with all those tools in same
thing with your center still in Doug
Burks has a security onion course but if
you want to stick with the open
platforms
he goes by like once a month so
definitely take his course I think he
just think he just finished one this
week
defensive challenge is so definitely
where I learned a lot just there there
were these things called cyber quest a
while back and they're still doing them
being there for high school students
behavior just learning it you just get
on in and learn as much as possible so
you get key caps in memory dumps and
then you can basically do analysis on
that but you know just you know just
some top one that I reckon dinner I mean
there's tons of fun out there but
there's an hour traffic analysis dotnet
so dead deafening check out his
challenges he does like one per month
and then a person challenge out and then
he puts into a week later or you can
submit for it I think he went something
and also there's an old saying cultural
stormed out or capture the flag
repo and so it does it tries to capture
a lot of the capture the flag from all
the different kinds over the years even
grab the artifacts the questions in
doing on your own and there's lots of
other stuff there and there's many many
others so just check that out and just
kind of close things out you know what
what now you know if you're interested
you know even if you're doing this now
first thing you should do is set up
security at home and start investigating
stuff that's going on in your local
traffic kinda talked about the cherry
picking things where make sure if it's
your getting tons of irrelevant alerts
make sure to work with us in admin so
that you can tweak those to make them
better or disable them never touch
adversary infrastructure if that's your
thing you know you may be in an industry
where are you don't worry about that in
the last thing is to you know know your
network and your spurred interest in
your infrastructure inside out and he
knows it defender that's the only
advantage we have you know I meet
analyst after endless endless that just
has no idea there just like I don't know
the sensor alert pops up and I do this
you know where that Senser said you know
what
what do what other device is following
that network path you could investigate
into learn more about the attack you
know and knowing your infrastructure
where your sensors are where you have
logging devices allows you to easily
direct your analysis and I i guess im
just gonna take questions after the word
afterwards I never finish early just FYI
but I do want to take i doing a big just
give a shoutout noak on this is the
second time that I've been here I was
here the first year that they did it so
you know robin Eric and the entire
support staff here thanks for having me
you can reach me on twitter
cracks my website if you wanna contact
me it's basically grax
pinterest.com and I have little like IE
/ cards if you want to see me afterwards
so that I can close it out and give the
stage to the next speaker thank you