i'm just reading your
I'm in Egypt but I woke up and actually
city below to find a support service
their own a company called out on
cybersecurity
primarily work bodyguards so did you
make sarcasm
by Chris Haack something that looked
like that mental state university that
is nice big thing in line to get the
disclaimer specific case information
contact well as we cannot be tails the
cost of cybercrime to share with you
guys want give you some real talk about
cybercrime we tend to focus on the
celebrated cases you see the news in
brandsmart scares and that in our
databases pretty where we don't deal
with things like to give you an idea of
what longworth deal with some of the
challenges that we face and then
hopefully get you doing with that
awesome cybercrime
and where one trillion dollars and
reason about that later on that's a
pretty broad range quite simply we don't
know how much we do know that on average
about a hundred and sixty set tax which
just last month
five million voters records Philippines
93 million records in mexico not a place
that I was the actor about 11 million
users can rest of our attacks healthcare
school districts by the way they
actually just for us to look at that say
that crazy all the other talks are
designed around that site prevent that
in mind some point bad things are gonna
happen probably gonna have to call one
and then the real problems action start
that they recognize that and we interact
as have directed you know their minds
Penelope very good at beer I could see a
sign so when you think about long
capabilities this web right high-tech
here's what is the reality is more like
even know who this is the original
dragnet 1967 something about that
excellent care uprise again 1968 one of
the biggest challenges that awkward
places you tend to identify with things
in your teens were exposed to so the
people running right now
guess where they were watching on TV
dragnet well that's their experience
that's what I thought processes reality
in this room and its operands it's just
what we talked about cybercrime tend to
break it down to different areas person
is used as a target of attack and so we
have things like they're reaching parity
fraud intellectual property
child molestation of minor cyberbullying
is simply harassment somalis that we all
dealt with except now use something new
the second way that we tended you may
have evidence so even investigations
murder investigations sexual assaults
burglaries narcotics drug offenses
credit card debit card users record
revenue from awkward fact it's fine that
we can build the case by the way the
murder in the last year we tend to talk
about computer networks and servers
thing but guaranteed everybody in your
tablet's huge
evidence that you break it down these
individual victims and then for perfect
people tend to run across pretty good
loss identity stolen credit cards are
cracking and then ransomware pretty
you've ever had to deal with that indeed
that one person that is crazy like one
else will talk that that's what it
really so you're
identity so you pick up phone call 911
some of my stuff and we're gonna send
out our crack investigator for the
specialized reality is especially since
end up in a prolapse for most part you
know what they are not they do not have
the specialized training or experience
to release your cyber a lot of times it
is right there you're going
crimes what I do and I like you know
where you at this is actually a real
case report that was sent over to me on
so much your place and that yes I
sarcastic but a lot of time is actually
the wet out there so I worked there were
332,000 reports of a in the United
States seven million Americans sixteen
to eighteen billion dollars in Los the
last 10 actually back to resolve the
route the bank is in the habit you call
them and say my cart
like ours that the money back but that
why you're no longer you got your money
so person who was really unless you have
the special need psychological it's hard
to get a return after the bank get some
money and so probably our second
challenge is the overlapping last case
Carolina money stolen or his card
numbers card is used to Texas three
places three different counties three
different cities got a pile of different
82 take that best get it
and let's not forget that the victim
doesn't like victim anymore so were
business thanks that's right off guard
somebody a little bit more on know
anybody heard of personal experience I
was shocked you're so you're
investigating research darkness that so
many guys who don't know what part
Gregory yes first of all set up this is
the target victim market very young
people eighteen maybe 20 or public most
of them that you would see at Bourbon
Street look around number when you're
out there these guys tensely victims are
correct so what happens is it contacted
you so I hate working to pay you money
for going out partyin working to use
your social media you're going to the
bars were gonna pay you to party 21 a
two-part also the perfect are you need
to do is send us your bank and your pin
number that way we can direct deposit
money straight because I know that's a
bad idea that they pocket the salat we
get reports this week is happening and
predominately comes out of old nice rack
problem is that I don't like to get
ready in this house to put the central
bank card you're in this once you tell
someone that yes they become an
uncooperative and they're taking its
just like I did that money back right
now because sent someone your pin number
is a violation of your bank's your user
you owe them money is the way the
Campana work someone that uses that cart
they posit bogus checks can you get
someone in another part of the country
also finding out just a little loose
fitting banks ATMs ATMs ATM
money out back out all within 24 48 hour
period thanks
checks but you do all this money where
is our money last one I personally
worked on was about $7,000 in today and
the really important thing was her
parents it signed and so the bank when
parents yet she doesn't obviously have
money there's a kind of a secondary
victims but the second part of that is
that investigation
texting the sorts of patients so as an
investigator and saying no to meet
actually investigate this case and your
mom and your permission look inside this
room would be excited about it and
everything
by one sign up for that very few things
at the third challenge so far as victims
by 10 and CSI and NCIS those labs
everywhere so we have a corporate or
business victims intellectual property
of insider especially
denial of service that one PCI card
industry are like happy days
image to your company to your corporate
training and it's not the one that you
walked in one day and said you know what
I'm require you is the person sitting
there for months thinking about thinking
about what I work work by the time
everything on your back at work
31 all incidents involved in my name's
drop cable median cost for crisis
services forensics
the guidance and other one earned
$10,000 they really big corporations are
by can't small medium wallet thank you
thats stop get small business say which
did you too small and this year three
hundred grant this year because of
insider is really really tough so we
have problems
job yet in let's get it back up and
running as quickly as I understand that
is for us once it goes away even when we
do recover its custody court saying you
know i no evidence release a lot of
counties
considered insider grats civil matter
because it was on track so you just need
to fire them they don't have a job
money and they certainly are not gonna
have a hundred thousand dollars or
target lost two hundred million dollars
not one year we work one where he lost
12,000 over the house and then why those
to this part luck with cycling credit
card number twelve thousand that ones
the company so from March lacquer that
time were considered armed and it we
don't know because the tests were
actually quite who also notified them
what did they do all the rights and the
stream so it could have come from any we
know that narrowed it down to business
no idea because again it went on for a
while longer that harder
saudis and you're so we all know
PCI or PCI compliant if your PCI
compliant they're not gonna charge back
he said they were to come in and say
you're an idiot you had WiFi in your
payment system you know it's your call
in that case we assume that they were
attacked by the time we got notified
that contacted them and they already had
people come out quite that lack of
timely reporting occasion I would say is
tension
people reach happened six months ago so
that 111 million user accounts they're
floating around in the dark
been out there six months because people
kept saying here sometimes
traded companies their stock 10 jobs to
maintain shareholder value that's all
they care about their not interested in
telling the world just lost
challenged members expressed lack of
personnel talking about our program just
in general lack of trained deal with
sideburns most everyone in this room
you're working tonight see you would not
want to go to work
entry level and long are you in New Year
intake someone that actually a skills
now it's that's why they went and did
this morning I wanna make it so it's a
real challenge to try and get assistance
center on your taxes either number seven
number 614 million residents say now
coming in at City or second only to
washington state's yes how many trained
investigators work in that metro or
cyber
not nearly enough little more than by
around 2020 people that spread out over
federal state that happen to be down
there and altered exactly not nearly not
run the ball you come in
calls actually make a lot of a dyin that
recording
wants a bigger
black specified resources on the local
level
governments are starting to understand
the need for hearings starting to get
state grants federal grants are out
there something I would hurt university
partnerships morning talk about things
that you hear there are ways to get
involved where you don't have to work
hard to get here
through universities Secret Service has
i kak dela number eight terminology
reach you
the dark figure truly do not know how
much are only about 20%
iceberg great example of that little bit
concert what's actually out there and do
bear some great mark what's this
fortunately the tickets will prolong
they won't bother to less they think
they can get a big part of your critical
incident response setup rush Holt this
type of the ninsu we're going to contact
this is a problem we tend to focus on
this is things I'm gonna do
technologically and there is an after
thought it becomes this was really bad
and so much is your rationale for what
we're gonna call some companies are
working to call every single user that
you were launched something that part so
now the second try and preserve evidence
is best understood chain of custody
chief legal work release you know where
did it come from
were used to document
procedures not that the challenge is
Gina custody and then don't leave a
heart transplant out what to do with my
left my card required saddened
conference room doing that you'll be
fine but definitely not understand as I
T people want workman is limited by
Mehmet unreasonable search and seizure I
can't look at your wife or your
permission if you're an admin and you're
running the system all of your users
find are saying my stuff I maybe that
means you gather up evidence of illegal
be things that I could not do that one
back and writing writing where the same
problem judges not really you write a
probable cause based on facts right down
there like what what is this a judge SP
what is an IP what do you mean age was
kick what is what is what why and
minored in user got a lot of remember
when you signed up
he's not gonna you know him a little bit
of break really good traffic law
breaking up by mess that's mostly when
they show up
formation then start asking preferably
or something bad happens just like
setting a threshold in their mind may
contact you yet all of those people
directly now
secret service and the FBI book I know I
have a little bit I'm committing to one
meeting and we normally it's going to
lunch but yes on Portman other experts
that they can tap something that you
don't understand something call and the
last concert you know something he
believed to be criminal report that said
you know what we've taken this number
just number
cases of this allows the route
what does the FBI it's not really our
scope