welcome and good afternoon to this uh
today's session of the serious security
seminar from purdue university our
speaker today is gideon rasmussen idiot
has a long history of cyber security
executive management and is now a noted
cyber security management consultant
his professional background includes
experience in corporate and military
organizations and he's designed and led
programs including
information security pci third-party
risk management applica application
security and information risk management
he's served time as a cso uh and he's a
noted author and we're lucky to have him
today as our speaker gideon welcome to
purdue
perfect hey thanks joel
uh today team we're going to go ahead
and cover how to conduct cyber security
assessments so
i'm going to move very quickly but uh if
you stay with me
hopefully you'll come away with with a
new skill a new tool in your tool kit
so we're going to get started in the
presentation with scoping or trying to
understand the organization that you're
going to assess
we'll talk for quite a bit of time about
work paper so preparing for the
assessment before you arrive on site or
conduct
a remote assessment
we'll talk briefly about the report
and presenting findings and
recommendations to executives
and then we'll briefly cover future
assessments
uh beyond a program assessment which
we'll spend most of our time on
this presentation is designed for cyber
security students
as an audience
again i'm going to cover probably about
30 slides in a really short span of time
about 40 minutes
so i'll be using air force crash course
format and if you're not familiar with
that you're going to see me move through
many many slides uh please feel free to
ask questions at the end we'll leave
about
10 minutes or longer if if there's time
permitting within the organization and
also you we can have a one-on-one call
if we run out of time
so left to my own devices i like to
start cyber security program assessments
within this cyber security framework and
the reason being is
then this csf has
108 controls and when you're looking at
the totality of cyber security that's
not too many so it's manageable it helps
you
establish a foundation of
basic controls common controls
for your assessment
i also like that venus cyber security
framework provides a good presentation
layer for executives so
we're going to
identify threats and vulnerabilities
we're going to implement
preventive controls we're going to
detect suspicious activity we're going
to respond
leveraging our
incident response plan and we're going
to recover
go through lessons learned and we'll
move back to a normal state business as
usual so if you noticed i didn't get off
into the traditional cyber security
domains
such as
access control or physical security we
start to leave the executives behind
i i covered that and leveraging
um the the overlay that nist provides i
was able to cover that more in terms
that would resonate with an executive so
that will benefit you as well
next we're going to transition and we're
going to talk about preparing for the
assessment
um scoping is really an exercise where
you're trying to understand what the
organization is
their assets their critical services
typically what i'll do to start off with
is i will do research on the internet
as an adversary might do by the way
and i'll go on the organization's
website i try to understand at least how
do they promote themselves
what products and services do they
offer i'll also go through
and look at if they have an area of for
news or press releases i'm trying to see
if there's any new services or
technology about to come on board
are there any mergers and acquisitions
so in two or three hours i can get a
pretty good understanding of what the
organization is
at least from the outside
sometimes i might go to glassdoor i
might go to linkedin and poke around and
just see what i can learn
so finally once you've done that
you've got about as much information as
you're going to have
from internet research then i'll ask for
60 minutes
with the it and business leaders of the
organization and i'll prepare
about 20 questions for the 60-minute
call
and really what i'm looking to do is
just give a little bit deeper than what
i can find on the internet
so some of the questions i'll ask is
what types of sensitive data or assets
do you have sometimes you have to lead
them through what types of sensitive
data might be present
such as pii or or phi intellectual
property
i'll also start to ask where
that data is stored
which data centers they have where the
data center is located is the
organization
using heavily using cloud yet like
microsoft azure or aws are they heavily
leveraging third parties
and in general i'm just trying to
to gauge
where the sensitive data is stored
processed or transmitted
one of the questions that i always try
to leave time for at the end you can
prepare as much as
as you can
but um i'll ask
what are a few nightmare scenarios for
your organization so
we have to keep in mind that we're
dealing with
technology leaders business leaders that
have worked
in the organization for years so i want
to understand what keeps them up at
night
where do they feel like they have
exposures
have they had incidents before
and any kind of data breaches things
that are serious things that i should
know about and that kind of helps me
craft
assessment work papers
which we'll get into soon
so next we want to think
logically about
given the type of business
the types of services the type of assets
that the organization has
logically what type of threat actors
might come after
that data or those assets
so i'm going to go over three categories
of threat actors yes there can be more
and it can be broken down further but
i think this is good for our purposes so
one we can have
nation states and
nation states
um oftentimes china for example are
looking to
grow their country economically so they
may go after
intellectual
properties such as
pipeline drug formulas
and
get get a hold of that information give
it to companies with in their country
and then those companies can bring
that product to market without incurring
all the costs of research and
development
there are times too where threat actors
will go after human resources and
clearance records typically that's of
government organizations they may also
go after critical infrastructure
election systems you see it in the news
and at some point
we may have to
contend with cyber warfare so it's
something to be mindful of depending on
what type of organization
you're assessing
many organizations need to worry about
organized crime or criminal enterprises
and their motivations are profit so
they'll come after financial accounts
they'll see
if they can
through social engineering
have someone
send a wire transfer overseas
fraudulently
they'll come after payment card data so
if your organization processes credit or
debit card numbers
adversaries will come for that they'll
also come after
pii personally identifiable information
and look to monetize that
every organization needs to worry about
insight or threat and there's a variety
of motivations there sometimes you can
have someone that's disgruntled or upset
with the organization sometimes you just
may have someone that's looking
to benefit themselves financially
and typically people are
targeting intellectual property
strategic plans
oftentimes
customer contacts are forgotten as
something that's valuable i mean it may
not be protected so we have to look for
that
obviously company funds
activists
typically aren't coming after an
organization right now but if something
hits the news
where
maybe a line of business or one of the
executives has done something
that is unethical
activists can get upset by that and
they'll either do denial of service
attacks
or they might disclose sensitive
documents so we can look in our
assessment to see
does the organization have a good crisis
communications plan and and some of
those other techniques
set up
so next we're going to get into work
papers and we're really
much deeper going to prepare for the
assessment at this point so as i
mentioned earlier
i like to start as i
design or architect an assessment for an
organization i like to start with the
nist csf as foundational or common
controls
and i'll use
work papers to prepare for the
assessment so this is a relatively
straightforward format
you're going to
have your question or test
in the beginning so
really three different things that you
may do
three different actions you may take to
validate a control
you may ask a question
you may look to observe the control
you may review a document or an artifact
or a screenshot
so obviously as much as you can
you want to observe the control to see
if it's in place or not or go through
documents or or artifacts or screenshots
evidence so that you're
really as much as you can having a fact
based assessment um that being said we
will ask questions as well
so the response results
feel there is where we're going to take
our notes as we go we're going to have
many hours of assessment activity and we
need to capture the details of whether a
control is in place or not
as we're thinking about validating a
given control such as
system hardening or encryption
you're going to want to focus on
which job function which person are you
going to validate that control with
so it's important to have that in your
work papers
as you go along and you're conducting
the assessment controls are going to be
in place or not in place and you're
going to cover
perhaps four or five hundred controls so
as you go it makes sense to mark them in
place or not in place so it's easier for
you to
fill out the report
and also when you think in terms of
writing out findings it's good to cite
the control so we bake that right into
the work papers
in the the g column on the right
so next we're going to continue to flush
out those work papers
um
so you can see
the first main bullet there is one of
the 108
cyber security framework controls
i'm not going to just look to validate
that one control as written nor should
you so you can see we're flushing out a
little bit beyond that and we're getting
a little bit deeper uh is the full
contract language in place to mandate
compliance with security requirements so
i'm asking a question
if someone says yes we have default
contract language then i'm asking for a
copy of the default
contract language and and if you think
about that i'm pivoting now i've heard
that this is in place so someone
answered a question
now i want the artifact i want to i want
to be able to review something
as much as i can to to determine myself
not just from an answer to a question
whether that controls in place and to
what extent that controls in place
and in terms of default contract
language i'm probably going to spend two
or three hours reviewing that
and most times i will make
a recommendation to add
five to ten different topics
into that default contract language so
you need to have that level of attention
to detail
also uh what's the process if a supplier
or a vendor wants to redline or cross
out security contract language what i'm
looking for is that
say the legal team or the third party
risk management team is going to have
somebody with a cyber security
background get involved in that and for
example a vendor may say look the
services we're providing
don't really require that control it's
really not applicable to us would like
to strike it that may be reasonable you
have to make sure they're not
striking
controls that really should be in place
to protect your organization then also
does the process require the security
team
to review contracts pertaining to i.t
services and this is especially true
when the contract isn't written by our
organization it's written by the vendor
so we want to make sure
that either we can just take our default
contract language and put it in as an
addendum
or if they're reluctant to have us do
that we may have one of our security
professionals just kind of negotiate
peppering the same language in
throughout the contract so we need the
right people doing that work we need to
check for that in our assessment
we're continuing to flash out our work
papers and just some examples here
of security monitoring
and from a to f4 really kind of
increasing in maturity so we want to
make sure
as we're doing our assessment that we
confirm
that security logging and events are
centralized run operating systems
commercial software and custom
applications
we're also going to look to make sure
that there's a sim in place or log
monitoring so that there's software that
that parses through all the logging and
events that come through
and alert us to suspicious activity
we're checking to see if there's a sock
operation center
or something similar to that where you
have
cyber security personnel monitoring and
responding to suspicious events 24 7.
also we're looking to see if there's
some sort of threat hunting activity
that goes on where again you have a
cyber security professional that's
leveraging the sim and they're searching
for adversarial activity they're
searching for indicators of compromise
also what we're trying to understand
does this organization have
user behavior analytics so software that
looks to see
if
the behavior of the way that
an end user typically
uses computer systems and acts accesses
computer resources
um which systems they go to what times
they log in is any of that really
radically changing and if so we might
want to have someone take a look at that
so we're looking to see if user behavior
analytics software is in place
then finally probably the highest level
of maturity and you don't see this often
is is there a cyber fusion center in
place that shares threat intelligence
information between security operations
it operations and our development ops
teams
so i'm i'm not in all of this scene
all of these things must be in place and
if they're not in place their findings
in some cases these aren't foundational
controls that you'd find
in the cyber security framework
or similar control framework like iso so
we may make recommendations so breaking
things out between
a clear violation of a framework or the
policies or standards of the
organization and something that may just
be common sense or a best practice that
would probably be a recommendation
we're also continuing to flesh out our
work paper still in that mode so you
remember there was
one of the
four types of threat actors were was
the insider or insider threat so
a great resource for you to review
as cyber security professionals
is
certs common sense guide to mitigating
insider threats
it's
a very large pdf that's online
and what you can do is
either leverage it to do
an entire insider threat vulnerability
assessment or if there's an insider
threat program
in place an insider threat program
assessment but in this case
i'm conducting we're conducting right
now we're preparing for
a cyber security program assessment so
we're going to just take a few controls
out of here i guess there's
five highlighted
so we're going to get with hr and we're
going to ask them
if you become aware
of an employee that's very upset or
disgruntled
it may be because of some sort of
human resources action that's being
taken against them maybe somebody made
a complaint against them
um
or
they're having a very negative
performance review like does not meet
does not meet and they're upset it's
very clear hr has realized this do they
have a process to reach out to the cyber
security team and just say
for this employee or for this contractor
can we
have an
enhanced period of monitoring say a
month or two so not giving any real
details just saying
for this process we've established for
the next month or two would you
monitor this this employee
that's something good to check for
also and this is kind of reinforcing
what we talked about before
what is
that the baseline of normal behavior
from employees for systems so if you've
got two systems that talk to each other
for the first time
in a year maybe somebody should go take
a look at that
enforcing separation of duties and lease
privilege
so
one area i look for
is are
there um access control reviews that
take place when someone switches jobs so
if you've got someone moving around in
accounting for example
or are you making sure that
their legacy accesses are being
rescinded so that the right
separation of duties
remain in place and they don't have
privileged creep right so they retain
legacy accesses and they keep moving
through jobs that can break down
separation of duties
and
enable them to commit fraud so need to
be mindful and make sure some of those
processes are in place
close the doors to unauthorized data
exfiltration so as cyber security
professionals we focus on that a lot
it's something we need to be really good
at to understand
modern day
real time threat landscape
how our adversaries exfiltrating data or
removing exporting data from
environments during data breaches
and we also want to make sure that
again within our work papers we're
looking for a comprehensive employee
termination procedure so systematic
removal of accesses for everyone
as they leave the organization last day
we're going to rescind all their
accesses then if someone's being
terminated or fired
then we probably want to have better
coordination
and as they're being asked to come into
an office
um
to be informed of that we want to make
sure that
all of their accesses are rescinded you
know that
so i wanted to get started with um a
couple of of quotes in the presentation
so one is from the 911 commission report
so defenses also complicate the plans of
attackers increasing the risks of
discovery and failure so we want to have
layered
preventive and detective controls really
following where our sensitive data and
our assets are and that's why we're
still flushing out work papers
so we're going to pivot a little bit and
we're we're going to have an attack
centric focus
so you know that
when an adversary is trying to
um
get into an organization and exfiltrate
data commit a data breach
they start by sending a phishing message
and they're trying to get an end user to
click on a malicious link and or
an attachment with malware in it so
we're looking to make sure that the
organization has
a program
where
test messages or send phishing test
messages go to all the
end users on the network and
not only through awareness training but
through receiving these test messages
they're learning what does a true
phishing message look like how do i
report it to the cyber security team and
and hopefully along the way we're
getting to the point where they're not
going to click on a malicious link
or a file attachment from someone they
shouldn't
we also want to check and see if
email authentication been enabled on the
domain to protect recipients of our
email messages uh make it harder to
spoof them
eventually an adversary will gain
system access
they're targeting that
in order to gain access to the data so
we want to make that difficult um so
we're going to rescind workstation admin
access from end users hopefully they
never get it they don't need it and that
also makes it harder
for malware or ransomware to execute if
the person that's logged in doesn't have
administrative access
we're also looking for some type of
advanced endpoint protection
not
anti-virus
with
that relies on signatures we're looking
to ensure
that
microsoft powershell is locked down so
increasingly adversaries
are avoiding bringing their own
hacking tools
binaries software
into their target environment they're
looking to
avoid detection by using the software
that's there so i'm
i'm sure many of you know that
powershell
is
um
software that comes with microsoft
operating systems windows admins use it
so what we're looking for here as has
our organization that we're assessing
have they followed microsoft's
recommendations
to
uh install
security configurations within
powershell including
enhanced logging for suspicious activity
we're also looking to see if two-factor
authentication has been enabled for
servers
it just makes it much more difficult for
an adversary to hop from system to
system and speaking of that
we all know that when the adversary
first gets into
the network
they're most likely not going to land on
the system with the sensitive data
they're looking for so they're going to
pivot and move laterally east to west
across the network
so we want to make that difficult as
well
so we're going to use network
segmentation and we're looking for that
in our assessment and looking for that
within our work papers
so that
there's network isolation or network
segmentation
where our sensitive data is so
the organization has
research and development data so
intellectual property
payment card numbers whatever the
sensitive information is that should be
isolated on a network
and and also have something like a jump
box so in order
for a user to get into that
network and to gain access to that
sensitive information they have to
authenticate to the jump box typically
there's two-factor authentication there
too just another layer of controls to
make it more difficult you don't want
everyone on the network
having a flat common use network you
want any end user on the network to have
access
to the systems that have sensitive data
also we're looking
we realize at some point an adversary
may get access to a system with
sensitive data this can be
an authorized insider
thinking in terms of insider threat
so we want to make it difficult to
exfiltrate data so how can we do that
well we can have
firewall rules
with granular source and and destination
entries in there
we can also look to resolve from
internal dns servers so that we don't
have
systems with sensitive data that have
something like port 53 going straight
out to the internet which an adversary
could use
to exfiltrate data so i think all of you
on the line right now realize that we
could have a whole presentation or maybe
three or four hours talking about
how adversaries ex-filtrate data and
what controls should be in place
fortunately we don't have that time but
it is good to do some research and
include
different tests and questions
within your work papers to look for the
necessary controls
we're also going to want to detect if an
adversary is in our network we're
looking for suspicious activity so we
covered a little bit of this earlier
we're going to centralize
logs uh to the sim
um you may also look to see if your
organization is familiar with a miter
attack framework and and how adversaries
operate and their tactics and that can
be used
to design some additional controls
within the network in the systems
also
we are from time to time going to have
incidents and we want to be very good at
incident response
to prevent an incident from becoming a
data breach so we need an incident
response plan
with scenarios and then we need to at
least once a year
conduct incident response exercises not
just with it
with lines of business senior leadership
we need to be looking for all of this
within our work papers
also our work papers need to be current
and i've kind of hit on this a little
bit before now so it's good to be uh
attending
um
different webinars
such as the the serious uh security
seminar series that that we're
participating in now
um also
organizations like infragard uh they
have good
um security webinars and what you're
looking for is
coverage of a recent data breach
how did how did that occur what were the
what were the tactics that the
adversaries used and then i
stole this slide from a dhs presentation
it's about a year old but
these were
recommendations that could have helped
prevent the data breach
that was presented so don't white list
network traffic with trusted partners so
we already talked about
firewall rules with
granular source and destination uh
important protocol network segmentation
so it but it's good to see what has
happened recently
with a threat actor and a successful
data breach and what is being
recommended to prevent that same
type of data breach those same type of
techniques from being successful in our
organization so good to watch out for
these webinars to attend them
and add those controls into your
assessment methodology
need to also be mindful of physical
security right so
um i will when i conduct an assessment
asked to review the id access card
system and yes in
assessments that i've done i've seen
ork and minion badges and the orc badge
believe it or not had full access to
everything
in the building and and that campus
so you can imagine um
the orc isn't really affiliated with any
person and if this badge was lost it
could be used to get in anywhere and we
wouldn't really be able to track it
so obviously that was a high risk
finding that was
documented in the assessment but we need
to look for this so
scan through see if you can find some
fictional characters and then
follow along the path there and see what
kind of accesses those illegitimate
cards have but you also want to see
which cards have access to
areas where sensitive data is present
computer rooms
all access to the building or the campus
and ideally we're looking for
groups and role-based access in the
physical security id access cards just
like we do with networks and systems and
applications we're also looking for a
process where
someone separate from operations
at least annually is reviewing a list of
the employees and the contractors and
comparing them to the active access
badges
and this helps catch if someone
resigns or is terminated from the
organization and somehow the process
broke down and
their
access card privileges were not
rescinded
we do need to be mindful too again in
physical security
still within our work papers
are the right controls in place to
prevent use of physical breaching tools
so the tool on the top the c-ramp tool
the way that that is used is
oftentimes you'll see computer room
doors have a metal plate to prevent
someone from using a screwdriver or
credit card to just slide the bolts back
well the c-rat tool
essentially you unfold it and it's
almost like a jackknife but you have a
very long metal um almost like a ruler
and you can just get around that plate
slide it up and open the door
so
you're not looking to use any of these
tools because you could damage
the doors um within the organization
you're assessing but you're looking um
could i use a c-rant tool here or
are there barriers
uh that have been put in place
on top and and and the bottom
of where that
that bolt is so that you couldn't really
be successful using a c-wrap tool and
also you're looking
on your high-security doors like the
door-to-wood computer room to make sure
that the hinges don't face out if they
do
can use the tool at the bottom there
it's about five dollars on amazon
to pop the hinge pins and just pull the
door out it takes about maybe 10 or 20
seconds
and there are to defeat that tool there
are screws
that you can buy also off of amazon that
kind of back into the the hinge
and they defeat uh that vulnerability
and that bottom tool there
as you recall at the beginning of the
presentation we had
this 60-minute scoping call with the it
leaders
with
the business leaders and we learned from
that right what is your nightmare
scenario things like that so
we want to
continue to flesh out our work papers
right based on what we learned from them
so are there large sums of money present
are their fraud prevention controls in
place um is there sensitive data present
uh is are there additional layers of
controls around that internally
two-factor authentication to access the
research and development systems
are there administrative or super user
accounts
associated with this data we should know
about
is the sensitive data
on its own network segment so
definitely important to really take what
we learned from the scoping call and
bake that into our assessment
we do want to cover some bad practices
too right not just the controls that we
want to see in place but the controls or
the vulnerabilities
that
shouldn't be in place are so are there
any shared accounts in use and we may
want to cover that with you know several
roles as we go
um
do developers have access to production
data they probably shouldn't right um
are there any any firewall rules in
place so
we talked about having granular source
and destination and important protocol
rules if you have an any any rule that
allows
any source or destination any important
protocol we want to look for that and
maybe
have somebody walk us through the
firewall rule base
i do sometimes ask survey questions so
at the end of each assessment interview
um i will have already talked with the
cso or whoever the security leader is
said are there any vulnerabilities or
controls you're having trouble getting
in place
with your senior execs with your board
of directors sometimes you have
challenges rescinding access to things
like gmail the personal email so what
i'll do is i will go through and i'll
talk to the 20 or 30 people that i'm
interviewing as we're going through the
assessment and i'll ask them questions
like that do you need these accesses for
your job and then not only am i writing
up findings for for data leak
vulnerabilities here but i'm also saying
oh and by the way i spoke to the 20 or
30 people
listed further up in the report and they
all said they didn't need these accesses
so hopefully we can help influence
getting that rescinded
i will also ask
are there any security or risk concerns
uh that should be raised so um that's
kind of like the nightmare scenario
question
in scoping i'm asking each person
i've covered a lot of specific things
are there any security or risk concerns
that ethically
we should put in this report that i
haven't specifically asked about and
you'll get good results there
i will
ask questions and confirm
controls across roles and so should you
so some examples is
documentation of where the sensitive
data resides
business continuity planning you want to
make sure it's not just in one or two
business units it's in all of the
business units that
have critical processes or services
system hardening across the different
technologies just not one or two of them
also access control across functions so
we're trying to comprehensively cover
these controls
not just in one place
finishing touches on these work papers
we're going to sort by job function you
remember that from the
work paper screen that we were on so
you may sort for example by the backup
administrator and you only have a few
controls you're checking and like wow
even if i'm going to spend a half hour
that we don't have many controls here
and you know what i'm noticing now that
i've filtered it this way that here's
four or five other controls that we
should be checking with the backup
administrator would be an example
you also are going to be speaking with
people so you might reorder some of the
controls a little bit just for a better
conversation you may also notice you
know what uh now that i think of it i
should probably add this control to a
couple of other job functions and you'll
copy that across
remember from the beginning of our
conversation
we need to make sure we're following
the three assessment techniques so
interviewing staff or asking questions
where we must right but as much as we
can we want to observe whether the
control's in place so we're doing a
factual assessment
and we want to review documents policies
standards
screenshots artifacts
at this point
we're going to ask whoever's helping us
schedule the assessment interviews
um to set those meetings up so we're
going to know
we're going to do this assessment over
the following couple of weeks
and we now know from our work papers
which titles or roles of people that we
need time with and if you filter your
work papers you're going to see whether
you need 30 minutes 60 minutes probably
going to need longer than that for the
physical security tour something like
120 minutes
you're also going to want to have an
assessment status call at the end of
each week if maybe one of the people
called out sick we've got to reschedule
that interview
if we've been asking for artifacts and
we're not getting them
and you also do need to tell the person
that's going to schedule the interviews
we need to meet with the people that do
the work
people that know whether a control's in
place or not i've had some times where a
manager will say oh this is great i can
cover you know four of these roles
no we need to meet with the people that
do the work so we want to meet with the
sysadmin the dba
and if the manager wants to come along
and they want to listen in that's fine
but we need to speak with the people
that do the work
i've talked about artifacts before so
again fact-based assessment this is a
very small portion of what i'll
typically ask for aligned to the
different controls so you're going to
want to ask for
artifacts up front and you may ask for
some by discovery things that occur to
you in the conversations
as you go along in the assessment
you should be spending as much time
preparing for the assessment so scoping
work papers as the time
spent conducting the assessment over a
couple of weeks
and then also documenting the report
presenting the results
the assessment report is going to have
an executive summary so typically about
one page
and
we're telling the executives at a high
level the trends that we saw
on areas that could use improvement
and then typically will
detail findings which would be a
violation in this case of in this cyber
security framework or a policy or
standard of the organization and
recommendations
may be other best practices or in some
cases just good common sense
i did want to mention that as an
assessor you should be giving the
assessment report to one person
initially it'll be a draft and they'll
get feedback you're looking to see if
there's any significant issues something
that's just blatantly wrong
perhaps miscommunicated by someone
and then you give that person the final
report and they control distribution not
us so if someone asks me hey gideon can
i have a copy of that report also say
sure you can get it from jane
you may be asked to do a presentation to
executives so you could steal some of my
slides on thread actors assessment
methodology in this csf you're going to
want to do a findings overview that's
really what the execs are interested in
perhaps
covering the high risk findings and then
some of the
higher risk moderate findings or
doing an overview of some of the trends
that you're seeing in residual risk
swot analysis is great to conclude with
strengths weaknesses opportunities and
threats
relatively straightforward remember that
you're dealing with the c-suite or
senior executives and they're focused on
operational risks we want to talk more
about operational risk
than we do cyber security and they will
be looking for remediation plans which
is not us the assessor you want to kind
of nudge the cyber security team
to be maybe put a slide or two in there
or be ready to speak to that
future assessment so he who tries to
defend everything defends nothing
i'm going to ask you to accept a little
risk here
as you do
future assessments beyond the the cyber
security program assessment we spoke to
it's fine to start with
existing work papers things like missed
cyber security controls but you do want
to focus on the function that you're
covering
like a security operations center or a
line of business
people will ask me well what would we
focus on on a line of business
how do they
deal with access control so they have
control over sharepoint sites
file shares things like that
access to
sas applications that are provided by
vendors how are they dealing with access
control they have critical processes
where sensitive data or assets are
involved do they have processes
documented are there controls in place
for insider threat or fraud
do they have a call center how are they
authenticating callers as as they call
in and ask for information or ask for
access
application governance so in addition to
access control if they're dealing with a
vendor
are they dealing with the vendor shared
security model for example if the vendor
says you know you really should
implement two-factor authentication
here's how you do it
um
and we'll keep going
there are other options for future
assessments
beyond
a line of business i think
there can be good return doing business
process risk assessments
um failure modes and effects analysis if
you're not familiar with that that's
um
worth orienting yourself with
there's a variety of assessments here
that we could discuss
so
with that i am a cyber security
consultant and i offer
cyber security program design and
assessment services so
if if you or some of your contacts needs
that type of support keep me in mind my
wife mary and i have a woman and
veteran-owned small business
if you'd like a copy of this deck feel
free to shoot me
a an email the address is here you can
also reach out to me on linkedin and
with that i'm going to open it up
to questions
if you have questions please drop them
in the q a box
but with your permission getting i'd
like to start us off today so you i
loved your overview um on how you uh
conduct some of these assessments but
and their every company is different but
let's say
sort of your average medium size or
small business how many hours
is needed to be invested to do a
thorough assessment what is the typical
time frame for you
so so end to end and obviously this was
very involved right so to orient
yourself to the to the organization to
go through and flesh out work papers to
execute on the assessment to create the
report which 90 of it is going to be
unique content and to present that can
be around 160 hours so it's it's a lot
of work primarily in the prep and then
there's a lot of work
that goes into the report so yeah
give or take something like 160 hours so
it's it's a lot of work
so of the various types of assessments
do you tend to favor one or the other
and and why
so
my whole career i've tried to be risk
opportunistic right so i i would say if
you're just starting out
and you've got a good cyber security
program in place but you really don't
have
many assessments or much assessment
activity it's good to start
with
a cyber security program assessment
which is really kind of covering
um the core controls and the controls at
the enterprise level
so maybe you do that year one
year or two
perhaps you do
an assessment of the cyber security
controls with the one within one of the
the riskier lines of business so for
example a pharmaceutical company where
where are the pipeline drug formulas
um
or maybe you do
finance
where there's large amounts of money and
make sure they have the right
processes and controls in place
then probably the third
year you might choose some critical
business processes
and
work like that and then
within the deck there's a litany of
other areas like i didn't really speak
much as i
breezed by this the security operations
center is really core
to the cyber security program
so it's not just where the logs are
coming in and the sim is
but
it's where
the sock analysts are and threat hunting
is going on in incident response so
there's a lot there
so
um this might be the fourth level
um i hope i answered your question joel
yeah yeah you did thank you
and we are right at 5 20. uh the
students in the audience know what that
means those who may not be students
knows that this is technically the end
of the official four credit class at
purdue university which is computer
science 591 so with that i getting i'd
like to thank you uh personally for
uh
presenting today
uh as
you know from of our previous
conversations i follow the virtual cso
uh on linkedin and i've
for a long time have enjoyed reading
your articles and i'm glad we're finally
able
to get you although virtually get here
get you up to here to purdue to to
present
uh one announcement for the students in
the audience you probably received an
email from me uh earlier today but the
purdue cybersecurity student welcome
will be starting in about
about 40 minutes at six o'clock that
also is a virtual event or an in-person
event
so go back to your emails take a look at
that
and unfortunately you're gonna have to
see my my mug again in about 38 minutes
telling you
about the great things that sirius does
for its students so with that i'd like
to thank everybody and look forward to
seeing many of you or at least your
names in the chat list uh next week as
we continue with the next session for
the serious security seminar good
evening everybody
thanks joel
you