let me start by saying hello i'm gene
spafford
i'm the founder and executive director
emeritus
which means former
uh executive director of sirius
and sirius is
a large organization here on campus
it is a campus-wide institute devoted to
a number of issues primarily cyber
security privacy cyber physical systems
explainable ai
things that affect
people if systems don't work as they're
supposed to
what we're going to try and do here
is
switch this presentation over
to joel rasmus who is
our managing director and he is going to
present this remotely
um and
[Music]
joel i don't have a second screen so
you'll have to send me messages when you
want me to advance
will do
good afternoon everybody and uh thank
you for showing up we have a nice
turnout
um and as professor spafford had
mentioned
that uh this is being recorded we will
post it on our uh our website
so please help spread the word to the
other students uh that might be in your
classes your friends your labs what it
may be
who have a interest in cyber security
and as spaff has mentioned our
definition of cyber security is very
very broad so if we go to the next slide
please
oops there we go
there we go
so this is kind of who in a nutshell
this is the elevator pitch and what is
serious or who is serious so
we're the largest oldest and top-ranked
interdisciplinary education and research
institute for cyber
and cyber physical systems and our
faculty and students conduct
impactful research in the areas of
security
privacy resiliency autonomy
trusted electronics and explainable ai
so while the world is in still in need
of top
it security talent
there's more
that can be done to provide a more cyber
secure world
so one of the serious goals is to bring
together these world-class faculty
students and industry partners
who are all working at least try to move
this into a more secure world so next
slide
so there's often a question is that well
i'm in computer science or i'm in the
polytechnic i'm in the computer science
undergraduate major i'm in
ece but i'm working on trusted
electronics there's
there is no one discipline that is
considered cyber security
and so as such
we have affiliated with us 135
purdue faculty who come from 20
different academic departments
across eight different colleges
so i've mentioned some of the
departments and colleges right now that
make sense computer science ece and
other engineering disciplines and
several disciplines within the college
of science primarily being i'm sorry in
the polytechnic primarily being the
computer science and cit
but there's also those that are spread
out across the rest of the disciplines
and krannert a number of students and
faculty who are working on the economics
of cyber security who are training
people to be csos and cios who are
working on
the idea of how you can work against
fraud in social media
social media is also an area of interest
by people in computer in
communications and liberal arts a number
of people in liberal arts who are
affiliated with this there are people
across campus and as i just mentioned 20
different departments
now that's just this faculty if we take
a look at the students there are
thousands of students at purdue who are
studying in a discipline
that's related to cyber or cyber
physical security
so on the right hand of this slide you
will see the different uh home
colleges at purdue the one that is not
there is the honors college but all but
two of these colleges do we have faculty
who are affiliated
those two without serious affiliated
faculty are pharmacy and veterinary
medicine interestingly enough our
faculty are conducting research in these
areas it just happens to be
faculty in different disciplines who are
working on problems for pharmacy and who
are working on problems for veterinary
medicine we don't have any pharma
pharmacy
professors or
veterinary professors who are working in
cyber yet
i suspect we'll take over the world
sometime and and across absolutely every
department there will be or at least
every college there will be somebody
involved in this and next slide please
so
in the definition of who is serious i
mentioned three constituencies
i said world-class faculty students and
industry partners
so
while i'm happy to talk at any time
about our faculty and our industry
partners uh tonight's focus obviously is
on our student constituency
you in the audience both here in lawson
as well as online and then the
well over a thousand who we have not
quite reached yet and you're going to
help us connect to next slide
so this entire presentation is really
why would you want to be a
a serious affiliated student
so students why register was serious and
that's what we're all driving here in
the chat box i've put four different uh
links to things on our on the serious
web pages and the first one is also here
on this slide and i think nearly every
other slide that i'll be showing
and actually this is an incorrect one so
it should be new student
so students receive a number of benefits
so the student from any department that
has an interest in cyber cyber security
can self register self-affiliate with
sirius and what that primarily does is
it puts you on our it puts you on our
rolls but puts you on our email list so
that when we have announcements or
things to share or events to host your
recognize and get special treatment
because of that
and these next few slides are all going
to talk about that i'm not going to just
read the slides because you can all read
these slides but i will touch base on
some of the points so throughout the
year we host and others on campus will
host
special events whether that's lecturers
challenges competitions or workshops so
we use our serious student list to be
able to promote those opportunities
because if you're interested in cyber
security there's a darn good chance that
you're going to be interested in some of
these special events
that are on campus
we also have we also host purdue
signature cyber security event
each year in the spring well
lucky you guys that the event that it
was supposed to take been take place in
the spring because of the pandemic has
been postponed so
the first time ever we'll have this
serious the annual syria security
symposium held twice within a year and
the first one is coming up next month
october 19 and 20 and registration is
already open to that and because you are
going to be a serious affiliated student
it is free for you to be able to attend
and because it's virtual you won't have
to miss any classes you can pop in and
out and be able to participate in any of
the events that you have an interest in
we're going to return to this late in
the presentation
and then we were we are planning to
return to our normal schedule of hosting
the annual symposium in the spring and
that will be at the end of end of march
next
slide please
so career assistance
purdue and sirius has the reputation of
churning out unbelievably great
well-trained students and so many
organizations are reaching out to us
both commercial and government saying
what can we do to hire your brilliant
students and so one of the things we do
is we try to connect our brilliant
students with organize with top
organizations who are looking for talent
again across the very very broadly
defined area of what is cyber security
so
there will be organizations that will
want to come to campus
we will have some coming up very soon
for mitre corporation which is a u.s
federally supported research laboratory
several of the department of energy
research laboratories and then
commercial companies as well that will
come
they'll show up their laptop
oftentimes they will uh order pizza
and then they'll run through and say let
me tell you about my company it gives
you an opportunity that you can wear
your jeans you can wear your shorts you
can wear whatever your t-shirts you can
take in the information and then decide
whether this is an organization that
you'd like to learn more about that you
potentially like to intern in the summer
that you potentially like to work at so
it's a low pressure opportunity to be
able to learn everything learn some
things about the organization
we also have career job announcements so
our partners will send us hey joel we're
looking for entry level or mid-level or
we're looking for somebody with very
specialized expertise
can you share this with your students
sometimes that share this with your
students is can you blast this out and
let as many students at purdue know
about this
sometimes it comes in and say this is a
very computer science oriented can you
just share with cs students who are in
the security track or we're looking for
front lines applied people to be systems
administrators systems architects we
probably will find those in the
polytechnic can you share there and
again the examples can go on throughout
it there's also the opportunity that
they'll come in and they'll say
joel this is requiring somebody with a
phd so we try not to send those to the
undergraduates if you're a freshman
you're probably not quite ready to talk
about phd candidate jobs so we will
parse that down and send it out now one
very important notice that because we do
have several u.s government
uh entities that are part of our
organization and because many of them do
work obviously for the us government or
the military that they are required
to hire
uh people who are clearable meaning that
they are able to have a u.s security
clearance
and it is it at this point it is
extremely rare for a non-us citizen to
be able to get a security clearance so i
cannot guarantee
to all of our international students our
non-us citizen students that you will
not ever see a job that will come out
that will require you to be a citizen
but we do try to parse those back
so if you do see when that comes through
and often times they'll come through and
here here are opportunities at four
different companies as we are now
entering into september the hard
recruitment time for these organizations
there's an opportunity that you'll see
of those and and you look at the job
description and realize that there is
that requirement that precludes you from
from um
from applying
apologies in advance if you see those
that is just the nature of the world
and we know the same thing in students
who are in your home countries and other
countries that there are those same
opera there are those same restrictions
the globe over we just understand it
but as you all know there's more than a
million job opportunities right now of
open wrecks first for
uh for cyber security people so
if it's not a job that you can't afford
that you're not able to apply for
because you're not a u.s citizen i'm
sorry then that's we still have 999
other jobs that we'll be able to help
you potentially look for out there
so
we also host a
cyber security job fair every year this
year will be virtual it'll be on
september 20th there will be a slide
devoted to that specifically and it is
one of the slides that's later one of
the the links that's in the chat right
now
sirius is also the holder of the center
for academic excellence and cyber
security that's a certification or a
designation that is given out by the u.s
department of homeland security and the
national security agency so dhs and nsa
so we're actually one of the i'm going
to use the air quotes original seven
when they introduced this program we
were one of the seven universe one of
the original seven universities that
said
this organization this college is doing
a great job in training uh students to
go work in cyber security
so as by virtue of being part of the cae
the center for academic excellence
there are several
u.s government hosted
job fairs and they may be located around
the country and they're also virtual so
there will be one that i'll be sending
out in the next day or two to promoting
one of those virtual career fairs that's
not hosted at purdue but is open to all
purdue students because you are part of
a center for academic excellence
next slide please
oh by the way is monica in the audience
if so raise your hand
i caught this on twitter i knew that you
were you i knew that you'd kill it
in your internship but it was great to
see nasa tweet out uh how great of an
internship that you had this summer
next slide please
so
um
i do know that these both of these
students i saw your name in there that
you're either in the room or online
there so
also students are usually looking for
funding at the graduate level that means
you're looking for somebody to either
underwrite your full education and or
your research and at the undergrad level
you're looking for potentially
opportunities to have some of or all of
your education paid for
these opportunities don't come up every
day but we do have opportunities to
promote scholarships for cyber security
focused students those are primarily
undergraduate focused and then
fellowship opportunities which are
primarily graduate
student focused
and i will be sending out a few of those
in the next couple of days as well
and then opportunities that are right
here on campus are the next three so
whether they're teaching assistantships
most you already recognize those as a ta
or a grad assistantship a ga those
announcements will come out to help one
of our fac one of our affiliated faculty
with their classes and their labs
whatever
there are also serious research
assistantships and we'll be announcing
some of those soon
and that will ask you that if you are
funded graduate students if you are
actually undergraduates as well that if
you were to be chosen what research
would you want to conduct this semester
and that would be next semester uh and
then uh sirius will pick up your your
tuition
so uh and fees so it's absolutely pretty
cool so look for those opportunities
then i put down there that these cover
not only tuition and fees but if you're
a graduate student it actually provides
a stipend or monthly salary
next next slide please
so i mentioned uh some student clubs
that are out there so there are a number
of clubs so the next couple of slides
will do there so this
slide is actually a brag on two of our
team
two of our student clubs
that have done very very well in the
last 12 months
and are preparing for competitions right
now
so there are a number of these clubs
competition teams honor societies that
are here at purdue and at our sister
organizations at iupui
and iupuis the cyber jags
function as an extension of purdue cyber
security
so anytime one of our
clubs teams honor societies has an event
we'll also promote that through through
the website next slide
and here are the list of those
organizations and
you know any student group any student
group can get together and form a new
club or a student organization so if
you're so if you are aware of other uh
new uh cyber security oriented uh clubs
at purdue or at iupui or at any of the
regional purdue campuses please let me
know we'll reach out to them offer them
a seat on our cyber security student
advisory board i do know that there is a
there is a organization that is uh that
hosts an annual hackathon uh and i have
struggled to make contact with that
organization so if you're affiliated
with that group please drop me an email
i would love to know more about your
organization and promote your club's
opportunities
so each of these organizations that are
on here do have a website link off of
the sirius website that you can contact
those organizations direct they all are
having their call outs at this time and
at the end of our talk if any of the
leadership of any of these clubs uh
would like to have a few minutes to
speak please raise your hand at the end
and we're happy to turn over and and
have you announce your call-out dates or
give us a brief elevator pitch about uh
what makes what's cool about your club
and why you're different than other
clubs uh it's very very pleasing to me
personally to have a student advisory
board that has each club uh represented
on it
because we've seen great
cooperation between all the clubs so
these count these clubs do not compete
against each other they're all part of
the very diverse landscape and ecosystem
at purdue of what is cyber security so
we've even have opportunities that we've
had competitions said aha this isn't
necessarily a perfect fit for any one of
our clubs but we've had members of the
forensics club members of wheasus
members of the ccdc club and boilers
which is the capture of the flag club
put together odd ad ad hoc uh groups and
go and compete together so it's a lot of
fun to see these things
and very proud because student
organizations at purdue always seem to
do extremely well next slide
so student serious students also receive
click line there we go the opportunity
to promote your own work so if you're a
graduate student you're probably
working in a lab or soon we'll be
working with a faculty member or
conducting research on your own
undergrads some of you will get involved
in research and many of you will be
working on class projects
at some point under your undergraduate
degree times
so we use this as an opportunity to be
able to help you promote your work and
there's a number of things we do whether
it's the poster session that's held at
the annual serious symposium or this
year the bi-annual series symposium
or opportunities throughout other events
to be able to promote and there's a
number of events outside of just sirius
that will be computing oriented or
industry specific poster sessions and so
we will share those with you as well
and then the last couple of points on
bullet points on this slide so if you do
get invited to a conference
to present not just a conference to
attend but to present
and the presenters or your research does
not cover that reach out to us we do not
have a large pot of money but we do have
a small pot of money that has been
donated by past students and alums
of purdue and and of the programs here
that enables us to give out small grants
to students who have been invited to
present at other at uh at conferences
and if you've been invited to
present your poster at a at a conference
or at the serious conference each year
we have complimentary poster printing uh
services that are available so
mike fakosi who's at the front of the
room uh and you can find his information
on our website as well as my information
and all the rest of our staff
just reach out and we're happy to print
your posters for you to take to the
conference or seminar that you're at
next
now there's a good looking guy in this
slide
talk about the two on the left of course
oh there are other things that we do and
this is almost the other uh slide so
there are routinely our faculty come up
affiliated faculty come up with new
classes they're going to offer or
there's a visiting scholar or a visiting
faculty member from another university
or from industry who said next semester
i'm going to teach this class and
they're typically things that are word
of mouth
that students will hear about to be able
to register well we try to be part of
that word of mouth and sharing with
all students regardless of department
who have an interest in cyber security
about new class offerings
we also throughout the year will host
cyber security interested students from
other universities
at this point we are planning to have
cyber security students from across
central and eastern europe come in uh in
january february time
not the time that i would recommend
visiting west lafayette but that works
for the schedule
so there will be opportunities for
serious students serious affiliated
students to be able to play host to
these bright students who are coming
from uh
emerging u.s partners across
in this case across europe but we
certainly have opportunities to draw
student visitors from other places
around the globe and of course from
other universities across indiana and
across the united states and the rest of
north america
so there are times that student projects
or graduate students or undergraduates
who are doing research will need
equipment or technical assistance
now we don't have a large supply of
every single piece of computer or
industrial control
equipment sitting in our storage but we
do have a sizeable amount so if you need
to spin up a simple it network or a
simple ot network or
a quite complex it or ot network
virtually on the solus laboratory we do
have an awful lot of equipment and uh
virtual research platforms that are
available to students for short-term
long-term research prop
research projects or class or club
projects so reach out to either me or to
adam hammer again you can find him
and i believe he's in the room as well
and we can help
we're always looking to help in our
students
and then uh several of the clubs use the
serious conference room as their monthly
meeting location so if you're looking
for a place to meet
to hold a meeting to uh to to host a
small event
uh please contact us we're happy to
share our facilities uh uh with you
also within our facilities is a quite
extensive cyber security lab
library
that is primarily there
because of professor stafford's personal
collection and the many books that have
been donated to him
that the years ago he said sitting at
home in his library look good but after
he's read them once uh he occasionally
will refer back to them but why not
share
this great resource so there is a cyber
security library within sirius and you
are able to come out in some cases you
can check out a book but many times you
just can come sign it out and and read
the chapters that you need or pull the
information you need from those books
right there so reach out to us lori
floyd again on our staff coordinates
that for us and we're happy to help you
next slide
so
there's also some near-term
opportunities that i've alluded to all
of these but i want to talk about in a
little bit greater
detail here
so throughout the academic year every
wednesday at 4 30 to 5 20 so almost
exactly preceding this event today
is the serious security seminar and it
is actually a for credit for credit
class computer science 591
but it is available to any graduate
student who has an interest in cyber
cyber physical security
and any upper level
undergraduate student so junior or
senior undergraduate
with permission from any serious
affiliated staff or faculty member
so even if you're a junior and you're
only now starting to get into cyber
security you can ask one of your
professors or send a note uh to me email
to me uh in stating that you'd like to
take this for credit class
and oftentimes we're able to approve
that and you can take it for credit
now
you're in a unique opportunity right now
because this has been for
traces back to 1999 when we started
offering this class well in the days of
the pandemic with like everything else
in many of her classes especially last
year and again this year there is the
virtual option
so
you can sign up and take this as a four
credit class
uh and attend virtually but because it's
virtual we now allow any student in
quite in fact
more uh
correctly
anybody student or no student can tune
in live and participate
in
the serious weekly security seminar so
on the bottom there is uh is a website
uh that you can click through uh you can
take a look at the
slate of presenters throughout the
semester
you can tune in live every week and
participate or you can tune into just
the weeks that you have interest
now if you actually do sign up for the
class
it is probably
the easiest class for you to pass at
purdue
because all you have to do is is
attend
throughout the semester they have these
if you miss
one or two of these classes
you still pass the course and it's pass
fail you do not get a letter grade so
you pass
if now let's say because of demands of
your laboratory or homework tests
whatever get in the way
you may miss three four five and now
you're afraid you're going to fail no we
make it very easy for you all you have
to do is go back and watch the video and
interestingly enough if you happen to be
interested in a certain specialty within
cyber security and this week's talk was
something that doesn't necessarily align
with your interest i would still
encourage you to take a look at it to
broaden your expertise
but you can go out to a keyword search
and find something that's right in your
wheelhouse watch that it doesn't matter
whether it was from this semester last
semester or from 1999 you can watch that
video write a short paragraph of your
takeaways from the video and submit it
to the professor of record and you will
be given credit for a class
so
unless you sign up for the class
for credit and then never attend a
lecture or never attend a video or never
watching the past videos
it's virtually impossible for you to
fail this class
and because the
slate of speakers is different every
year
you can take this class every single
semester at purdue now note it's an
elective it does not count directly
towards the requirements for your degree
but it will end up on your transcript as
you
receiving a passing grade in the serious
security seminar for whatever semester
next slide
please so uh the next in chronological
order september 20th coming up will be
the serious career fair
this in the past has been held in
conjunction with purdue
industrial roundtable for those of you
who are new to purdue the
purdue engineering student engineering
student council piece
hosts the
purdue engineering industrial round
table it's a three or four day event but
there are two days of it that it'll be
the largest career fair at purdue
and it started out years ago as
engineering focused it is broadened to
stem
based and then broadened through almost
any discipline it is still heavier
stem and business than than
excuse me than some of the other
departments but nearly every uh
department uh every college has uh
students who are at that job fair
so our event has typically coordinated
with that been the night uh of those two
day event but
because we have gone virtual uh and
there are and we would compete against
other uh campus entities that were also
trying to coordinate
their career fairs during the ir
we've revert moved virtual and moved it
a week later so on september 20th in the
afternoon will be the opportunity so at
the bottom there is a web address to be
able to get more information to register
and you must register and there's
actually a
vimeo video to be able to watch because
a virtual career fair is a little bit
different you will be still talking
one-on-one to a company but it will be
virtual and there are lines just like
regular uh career fairs as well so it is
worthwhile going take a look at the
short video registering and then
attending that uh looking for either
internships
for this summer or career opportunities
or even if you know those are in the
near term to put yourself on the radar
some of these companies that are
desperate for top talent and they may
not be interested in hiring you as a
freshman or sophomore but they're gonna
put you in their list to start tracking
and they need to reach out to you in a
year or two and say
how's your grades going i remember
meeting you two years ago we would be
interested if you're interested in
talking about opportunities at our
organization
next slide
and as i've mentioned several times
already the annual uh serious security
symposium this is purdue university's
signature cyber security event
when it was live and in person we would
have 400 plus registrants
and phil rooms and steward center last
year we went to virtual
hoping to do okay and we had over 700
registrants for it
uh so uh
very well attended uh there are keynote
addresses from high level people ceo
white house staff high levels of
government military we'll all provide
keynotes there will be topical panel
discussions that's when we slate purdue
faculty with their featuring their
particular research expertise as well as
people from government and commercial
industry who will discuss and sometimes
debate particular topics so
i do know that one of the panel
discussions this year is going to be on
microelectronics trustworthy
microelectronics so
not not very uh software oriented very
kind of hardware and actually down in
many cases
silicon level how do we make trusted
systems but the other panel discussions
will have other topical uh
conversations of great interest within
the industry is an excellent opportunity
for students to not only hear from
fellow students asking questions but to
hear from your faculty talking off the
cuff and from hearing from industry of
what keeps them up at night
technical talks so this is where your
faculty will be the various faculty
across purdue will be giving that talks
on their research and their laboratories
those of you who will be looking for a
grad advisor this is a great opportunity
to be able to start here some of the
expertise of the different labs so that
you can contact those faculty or that
lab and say i'm interested in joining or
i'd like to hear more about research
opportunities or rhea opportunities uh
in under your program
because it will be virtual there will be
a virtual poster session so it won't be
a printed out poster but every student
who would like an opportunity to talk
about their class project whether you're
a fresh a first semester freshman or
whether you're a postdoc and you were
deep past your dissertation and now deep
into your research we want all students
to be able to talk about their research
very short presentations you will see
emails on this and i highly encourage
you
to take up this opportunity
every year no exaggeration every year
students get internship and job
opportunities um from industry from this
and many times um
that job opportunity said well i'm still
two years away from graduating or three
years or i've just started my grad
degree i've just started undergraduate
but again
you'll those people go back to their
company and say listen to three years we
need to be all over this student
based on their presentation i saw the
serious symposium so take advantage of
this and there will be additional
opportunities for organizations to flag
that they are interested in recruiting
students at this event and there will be
a slack channel set up they can make
connection to it
regardless of whether the event is
virtual this semester or next semester
knock on wood when we hopefully move
back to an interest in person event
serious affiliated students do not pay
to attend this this high visibility
event
next slide
well guess what we're getting to the end
of my presentation and this is the
correct email address that i want you to
note
so all of these things that i talked
about and i hope a few i hope more than
a few of them are of interest to you
and the way that you put yourself and
start to be recognized as a serious
affiliated student is go to this website
you use your purdue credentials to log
in
and it just asks you some basic uh
demographic information what program you
are in what is your uh what what year of
study you in
where you got your other degrees if
you're a graduate student or an
undergraduate who's transferring into
purdue or let's say you got an
associate's degree and now you're
working on your bachelor's at purdue has
some basic information
and your research or education or career
interests
so
then there's opportunities for us to be
able to then again be the key word so
that we can send the right opportunities
to you
and then you'll see below there
optionally you can also add your resume
or cv to this and update it at any time
so there will be times that we will then
send out we will ask students can we
share your resume with our partner
and so unless you tell us no we'll be
able to share that out there and help
identify opportunities for you to secure
internships and jobs
and next slide
thank you
i appreciate it um
mike adam and professor spafford were
there any hands that were held up of any
immediate questions or potentially any
of our student clubs uh that wanted a
few minutes to be able to talk about
their club honor society or competition
team
yeah anybody here from any of those
organizations yeah come on up and
i think you can use the mic here
wonderful all right i'll turn my i'll
turn my mic and video off and turn it
over to students
hello are we good
you are good
so hello everybody uh i'm rowan hart i
was previously the event coordinator and
vice president of boilers which is the
capture the flag team that joel uh did
us the
honor of talking about here um so
basically if you haven't heard of us
what we do is we focus on playing
offensive security competitions so
essentially every weekend there's what's
called a capture the flag event and some
organization whether it's another
university or another team
um will come up with between 10 and 40
challenges of just super hard hacking
competition stuff they'll throw it at us
we have no idea what we're doing and we
just sit down and we start solving
challenges so that involves things like
binary exploitation which is you know
come up with an exploit for a binary
that causes some vulnerability to be
exploited you run your own code on
somebody else's server
that's the classic you know every cve
you see the cool ones are always binary
exploitation
we also have reverse engineering where
we'll get
again usually a binary but sometimes
just a really hard to read python files
and we'll send it to us and we sit down
and we try and figure out exactly what
it's doing usually there's some hidden
functionality that we need to take apart
and so we reverse engineer that and
extract some sort of flag from it
and then our other two categories which
uh i'm not as good at but are also just
as fun or web exploitation which is uh
you know you look at a website you try
and find vulnerabilities in it whether
that's through javascript or
cross-site scripting or sql injection oh
thank you joel um
or something like that and then finally
we have cryptography
where
we try and break
cryptographic protocols sometimes
there's a custom protocol that has some
sort of vulnerability sometimes it's a
real protocol like uh tls will be
implemented using some bad value that
makes it so that you can decrypt the
traffic things like that
so
we play basically every weekend um our
main communication is discord um so if
you go to this website all of our
information about us when we meet our
link to our report is on there so
if you're at all interested in playing
competitions with us all you have to do
is join us and we will tell you what to
do from there
and there's two critical events coming
up one is our second call out we just
had one on monday so if you were there
hello i missed it
if you weren't there we have another one
on friday it's at 6 30 p.m in lawson
b155 right downstairs uh so come swing
by say hello uh we'll just have
essentially an extended version of this
um
and also a little demo of what you can
expect from the types of challenges that
we solve
um and then our more important event is
the boot camp so
we don't expect people to know what
they're doing in this field right away
there's not a whole lot of classes here
especially at the undergraduate level
that teach anything remotely related to
what we're doing until you are at least
a senior so
we run a boot camp for four weeks
starting next monday
and details about that are on our
discord as well in the announcements um
so twice a week for about an hour monday
and friday at 6 30.
we will be doing a crash course in every
topic that i just talked about so it
should be pretty fun if you're
interested in it come learn something if
you enjoy the competitions stick around
and play with us
our most recent top rank was fifth in
the us we hit that in may and then
everybody did def con and passed us so
we're back down in 10th but uh
yeah oh no top ten
just horrible rolling two things rowan
will you make sure you send me uh the
information on the call out and i will
send it out to all uh students who are
are who are serious affiliated and then
also unless i missed it i thought there
is one piece of information that i think
it's important for you to share
that this is a club that is not just
geared towards any one particular major
or program you have members of your club
who are from numerous majors colleges
and departments across campus who all
bring their expertise to your
interdisciplinary competition team
correct
that's exactly right we've got you know
we have a majority probably i would say
of uh electrical computer engineering
and computer science and data science
students but we also have people who are
just interested in it and come and
decide that they really like it
one of my favorite stories is professor
former professor
dennis mulnar from the physics
department came and he actually first
took uh professor garmin's 526 class and
through that class he heard about our
club and he started playing with us and
he's one of our best players
and
before he came to our boot camp he
didn't really know much about cyber
security and now he's one of the one of
the better hackers i know so um anybody
can do it highly recommend it if you
think it sounds fun come find out we're
a competitive we're a competition team
we're not a uh
uh sit down and do class every week club
so if you like to compete and you're
competitive you'll probably like it
another advantage to this is
uh you can practice
breaking systems getting into systems
legally
it's permitted
um if you do that on your own you can
get yourself in some trouble so
this is a much better way to do it
let me just briefly uh
mention we have
some of our staff present here in the
room
and sort of uh these are people that
joel mentioned in his introduction
it's hard to recognize people with masks
i realize
but nonetheless
uh we'll at least give this much
recognition i'll start in the back adam
hammer back there
is
our jack of all trades when it comes to
system configuration management software
um if you need something to put together
for a project or you're having a problem
with some of our equipment
he's a good person to talk to to get
that resolved
uh if you haven't set anything up yet
then you really should go talk to joel
first
but
adam will be the one who carries that
out at the back end
moving forward next up lori floyd
uh laurie
uh
keeps track of
our physical facilities the library the
conference room she's the receptionist
uh manages uh some of the online data
does a lot of other administrative
things for
the center and if you were to walk into
the serious offices on the second floor
of recitation
uh in normal times she would probably be
the person that you would first meet
currently because of
coveted restrictions
we have different people who are taking
their turns and staffing the office so
not everybody is there every day in
person but laurie is the one that you
would hear from or you would contact if
you want to reserve the conference room
uh or some of the facilities
and then mike focusey
is our webmaster data manager uh
everything on the website
the ftp archive
a lot of the other online databases and
resources he's the one who manages those
and uh he is a incredibly expert in the
ways of html and uh
associated protocols
so he's our wizard of that
um
we have lots of faculty i think
professor garman's here
and uh she teaches in this area i don't
know do we have any other faculty here
hiding behind a mask
okay
um
so as joel said
uh
sirius uh really formally started in
but informally started in 1992
the precursor to it was a laboratory
here on campus that i started
so it's been going for a long time
has an amazing reputation
because of all the great students and
faculty who've been involved over the
years
just this afternoon i was in my office
had a knock on the door somebody i
hadn't seen in about 12 years
a student who graduated from here
stopped by my office he's now a senior
engineer at crowdstrike
and he got started in security because
he took cs426 from me
and now is a senior engineer at
crowdstrike and said
because people at crowdstrike
not just him
but the people at crowdstrike
know what a great program this is they
want to come and recruit
so if you're interested in a career in
security they're willing to train
if they can find students who have a
good background in security basics and
software basics
they're looking
what a great company
uh and that's pretty much true of most
of our partners
joel uh
is it easy well maybe i should
try to bring up quickly on the web
you have given a slide with all the
corporate partners that you can
i i do uh it will take me just a moment
to pull that up but while i'm doing that
this is a person a perfect opportunity
uh mike could you find um
yancy keems uh
[Music]
spot and unmute her so that she can uh
talk about deweesis
she's currently president and we have a
strong relationship with weases
you're live
oh thank you i'm trying to start my
video but for some reason it says uh i'm
not allowed so i'm okay with that
all right um thank you so uh hi everyone
i'm yanji i'm president of women in
cyber security club uh so we are
basically purdue chapter of this
international organization
uh what we do is we bring together women
from
women in cyber security from academia
industry and research
so
once you are in the club or in the
national organization you get to meet
the women and share their knowledge
their network mentoring and resources of
course
here at purdue how we contribute to this
mission is uh by bringing uh us all
together you don't have to be
necessarily from cyber security major
like currently we have uh
folks from i guess liberal arts from
computer science
especially this semester
and uh
it's totally if you are at all
interested in cyber security you can
come join us we have uh one-to-one
sessions with a lot of companies this
semester i think we have already talked
to uh ernst young
amazon sales force that are coming um
other than that we provide you a mentor
generally a junior and senior who could
guide you through the process
uh we also have
a scholarship guidance so this year
alone we have 20 women from our club who
got the scholarship to attend the annual
recess conference and a bunch of them
got the 500 travels uh stipend grand as
well so that's an annual thing um and
most of you uh there's good chances to
get the scholarship given you follow the
rules and advice
so i would uh i'm gonna email uh
uh i think joel uh we have our first
call out tomorrow at 7 p.m uh i'm gonna
drop our group me that's where you can
get all the details so that's the
quickest way to join us and we can lead
you from
thank you
thanks
so in the field of security and in
computing but security as well um we we
have
a smaller proportion of women that are
present in the general population
and uh so we sis is an organization that
helps support
uh women we're
sometimes feeling a real minority in the
field
uh to be able to
effectively participate
and
uh without some of the pressures and
some of the environment that they might
otherwise have in a more general
organization
so it's a great it's a great
organization the conference is wonderful
and if you're at all interested the
conference is not is is open also to men
it is not just limited to women but
that's the focus and so if you're
interested
you know check out the check out with
the ansi uh for the group
we mentioned about organizations doing
recruiting and providing internships and
research problems
and other kinds of things
these are the current partners
for series
i'm sure you don't recognize anything up
there right
you know these are major organizations
internationally
and
you have an opportunity
to find out more of what they're doing
in security
to possibly participate in research
at every level
it's not limited to just graduate
students but at every level with people
from these companies
to get internships
and maybe even job offers
we're adding more
all the time
um we're somewhat selective which is why
we don't have 200 up there
and
if you can't find somebody there who's
interested in what you're doing
we have other kinds of connections as
well
for the research that we do and for the
education
so with that
does anybody have any questions
or does anybody
yeah
haven't paid for all the sure you're
doing if you're interested in let's say
you find requests on there you're really
passionate about the project can you
reach out to them
through there or
we recommend waiting to hear
what you mentioned earlier um
okay so let me let me give you two-part
answer
the first thing is the projects that are
listed on the web page
are only some of the projects
that are going on
so if you don't see a project there that
really catches your interest that
doesn't mean there aren't any it's just
those are the ones that for various
reasons the faculty and the students
have decided to promote by putting them
up there
sometimes we're doing work that is
under non-disclosure and we can't talk
about it so you know that's just one
thing about those projects when you see
them the second thing is more general
and i'll tell you this as a faculty
member
come talk to me at any time you don't
have to go through a website you don't
have to wait to hear about it if you run
into an article i've published or
uh you see a project description or or
my name is written on a bathroom wall
somewhere you think it's interesting
um
come see me
uh or or make it or make an appointment
to talk to me
because i'm here to work with students
any of you who are interested
you know let me know
i may not have something you're
interested in
i may not have money to support you
uh which is
currently the state for most of most of
my research but
any of the faculty here
uh if they've got a student who's really
interested and is willing to work
will spend time to talk to you about it
so if you've identified something that
looks interesting
um
then
set up a time to talk
let me give you a a clue though if you
start off with
i'm looking for somebody to support my
my work what is it you do
that isn't going to succeed
you know that that does not help at all
we would like students who at least have
some idea what we're doing and what
you're interested in to come talk to us
about that
if you're a little reluctant about that
okay you can take a class
or you can wait until you meet somebody
at one of the meetings but uh don't feel
intimidated
i mean we have faculty here
and i dare say i'm sort of one of them
who have
uh uh you know a distinguished career
and that that may be great but we're
people and we're here because we want to
work with students
so don't any of you be
shy about
coming to calculus if you're really
interested
you're welcome
until all of you line up and see
professor garmin because she's
she has too much free time on her hands
no
any other
questions
so we gave you a lot of information
the first step is visit the webpage
register yourself
you'll start getting things in email
explore the website
mike has done a great job organizing it
uh we have a lot of information there
a lot of history there
right we have video that goes back
uh 20 years more than 20 years of talks
that people have given we have videos of
uh the lat of
well most of the annual meetings and
some of the speakers you'll find people
there who are speaking who are ceos of
crowdstrike
uh of um
of rsa
um a white house advisor
uh former uh director of national
intelligence
um
the research director at the national
security agency an assistant secretary
of state some really high profile people
with some very interesting things to say
the person
who gave
keynote
uh was it i think it was last year
is currently the white house cyber czar
um chris inglis
he gave a fantastic talk as a keynote
and you can see the recording that's the
kind of person we have come talk
that's the kind of person sirius draws
because of our reputation and you can be
part of it
so the first step register if you're
interested
start looking at things fill in
maybe some of the student groups come
talk to faculty
and
have a great time
thank you so much for coming tonight
um realize there's a lot to do in the
first few weeks of classes
so
get off and do your homework
and i hope to see
all of you again sometime soon
thank you for everyone online
you