good afternoon and welcome back to the
22nd annual serious security symposium
live from purdue university it's my
pleasure to introduce our first
technical talk of the day
uh jin we kosic is an assistant to
professor in computer and information
technology her research focus includes
deep learning driven security and
privacy for cyber physical social
systems and blockchain powered iot
enabled secure and privacy preserving
crowdsourced computing paradigms jen
good afternoon
sorry i mute
and thank you very much for the
opportunity for sharing some of our work
in our research lab today i would like
to present some of our work on deep
learning powered situational awareness
for securing cyber physical critical
infrastructures
due to the advances of sensing computing
and networking more and more several
components and physical systems has been
combined with each other for different
operations in different critical
infrastructures such as smart
manufacturing infrastructure smart
energy system and smart transportation
systems
those tight cyber physical coupling
dramatically improve the effectiveness
and efficiency of the different
operations in those different critical
infrastructures however at the same time
it also raises a series of unfamiliar
attack surface and results in the
increased vulnerability of the
operations to the potential separate
attacks and the physical failures
different research and solutions have
been developed effectively to mitigate
those several physical attacks in those
critical infrastructures in order to
enhance the security and resilience
however they still remain some
challenges in the real application
operations
so those kind of challenges have been
demonstrated in the different
real world attacks occurred nowadays for
example in 2015 there's several attacks
occurred in the power system in ukraine
this power system has resulted in a
large scale power outage this attack was
launched on the computer and the scalar
system of the regional electricity
distribution company and resulted in the
disconnection of seven substations for
three hours and the first operators to
switch to manual mode so there's another
attack occurs in the
water treatment facility in florida in
201st
due to the
investigation this attack occurred about
15 miles away from the location of the
facility and the two days before the
super bowl this cyber attack managed to
adjust the levels of a sodium hydroxide
from 100 parts per million to once
eleven thousand and one hundred parts
per million luckily this attack was
about and terminated by the operator of
the facility in time we can imagine if
this
this attack succeeded we can potentially
cause very severe
safety related accidents
so we can see it is really emergent and
it's very critical to
achieve
the work improve the security and
related
solutions in order to enhance the
resiliency and security of the critical
infrastructures
in the light of those challenges and the
demands our cyber physical social system
design like aims to leverage the deep
learning technology to provide
and achieve the deep learning power the
situational environment solutions for
securing the separate physical critical
infrastructures
so in this talk i would like to present
some of our work aligned with three
research directions first deep learning
based architecture for detecting cyber
attacks and physical failures second
attack resilient communication
infrastructures and the last
value-inspired intelligent
decision-making under control
so first deep learning-based
architecture for detecting cyber attacks
and physical failures
thanks to the advances of sensing and
computing deep learning techniques has
been widely and successfully applied in
the security domain and provide a series
of promising solutions for achieving a
timely situation awareness however there
still remains some essential challenges
to achieve the more practical solution
for addressing the real world problems
for example the security related data is
very limited especially device
associated with some very happened
security related incidents
and also those data is a sparsely
labeled because labeling and the
achievement annotation of the data can
be very time consuming and the labor
haven't
and also thus in recent years many
evidence have been shown that the
decision making of the machine learning
model
can be misled and
because of some carefully crafted the
preservation or adversarial
perturbations in order to address those
challenges
they provide or i talk about the two
solutions have been provided in our
research lab first the hybrid reach
provision based on research by
exploiting human domain knowledge and
second blockchain enable decentralized
secure situational warning system the
first the hybrid weak supervision based
on myself this aim to address the first
challenge viscosity of label the data
this architecture provides overview of
our proposed method we can see here
consists of three main learning
primary learning model secondary
learning model and latent feature
learning model the primary learning
model designed aimed to extract the
features from the limited label the data
and interact with other two learning
models the second learning model is
designed to interact with the primary
learning model and to extract the
critical features from the unlabeled
data that is consistent with the
features from the labeled data
and the latent feature learning model is
the critical component in our work it's
aimed to interact with the primary model
and the second learning model
accordingly in order to seamlessly
integrate the domain knowledge with the
separate features presented by the data
directly
by doing that we are able to achieve
appropriate and reliable decision making
for situational awareness even the
system only have the limited data has a
very limited um or which is sparsely
labeled
and yeah they also provide another
solution blockchain enable decentralized
and the secure situation environment
system
this will aim to address the other two
challenges first the lack of valuable
data and security of motion learning
so this one provides the overview of our
provost structure so the main idea here
is we designed this blockchain to enable
the decentralized corporation
architecture so that the different
computing units they can have very
limited computing power limited data and
even untrust diversity to each other but
they are able to collaborate with each
other in a secure and privacy preserving
way to solve the associated tasks
so those computing nodes
can participate in this collaboration by
playing about the three functions
application initiator computing
contributors or verification
contributors if the nodes or the
computing units play as the application
initiator it will announce the learning
driven or data-driven situational
various tasks via this a
blockchain-based middleware and they
will specify their objectives and
constraints of the task
via the blockchain smart contract and
submit the necessary training and
testing data and the decentralized and
secure data storage systems
and the computing contributor if they
would like to participate this task will
join their local learning model based on
their private local data or the data
shared by the application initiator
according to the objectives and the
constraints shared by the application
initiator via the blockchain smart
contract
after those local learning model trained
and claimed about the blockchain-based
middleware the randomly selected
verification contributors will conduct a
quantity verification procedure to
evaluate the trustworthiness of the
claimed local learning model and inform
the application initiator with their
decision making if the majority of the
verification contributor have the
positive decision-making the transaction
of this local learning model will be
established between the associated
computing contributors and the
application initiator and after
achieving the local learning model from
the different computer contributors the
application initiator be able to conduct
multi-modal and
fusion mechanism to achieve the metal
model to solve those challenges
situational wireless tasks
this work has been developed in a nasa
project and in this project we are able
to
establish a hardware in the loop
prototype for this architecture and
evaluate the performance in the nasa
deep space exploration tasks and other
related tasks and the performance is
successful factory and currently we're
still working on improving the
performance and efficiency
so another research is about the attack
resilient communication infrastructure
we know the resilient communication
infrastructure is very critical for
maintaining the appropriate operations
in different critical infrastructures
however sometimes it can be challenging
to directly leverage the established
communication infrastructure which were
originally established for the other
commercialized purpose for maintaining
the operations in the critical
infrastructure here identify two of the
challenges first due to the different
operating conditions we may need the
tremendous amount of sensing and
operation data and the delivery of those
data may eat the different the quality
of service or production as for short
and the quality of experiences were
called qoe for short requirements
second we also need a resilient
autonomous networking management even in
the presence of certainty this is
because of the complexity and the
critical
property of the critical infrastructure
operations
and to address this challenge we provide
two solutions first attack resilient the
networking middleware mechanism second
the blockchain-powered multi-controller
software-defined network-based
networking architecture
first attack resilient networking
middleware mechanism here show the
overview of our
architecture we can see in this work we
develop a deep learning enabled
middleware architecture which is able to
upgrade the established communication
infrastructure with the low retrofitting
cost and the meet the requirement of
operating in the critical infrastructure
such as power systems
as shown in this diagram our middleware
is able to monitor the qrs and the poe
demands of the associated operating
conditions and evaluate the operation
condition of the networking in real time
and then they are able to achieve a
hierarchical and intelligent
multi-cloud or say the cross-layer
operations of the communication
infrastructure
and by leveraging the deep learning
technique we also able to detect the
potential attacks such as integrity
attack in the real time and
realize the mitigation strategy
accordingly so these workers develop a
qoe project by collaborating with the
national renewable energy lab we were
able to develop a large scale
and hardware in the loop testing system
to evaluate the performance of our
developed middleware mechanism for
securing the communication
infrastructure for a large scale
power system with a high penetration of
cleaves
so and another solution is blockchain
powered the multi-controller
software-defined network-based
networking architecture the overview as
a following we can see our networking is
relies and managed by multicontroller
sdn there and the multiple controllers
will collaborate and operate each other
via a
blockchain based layer and this there
you ensure the security autonomous
management of the collaboration
so our proposed networking management is
able to deliver the functionality of
integrity verification so here show some
details of maintaining something in
order to meet this goal so we can see if
the controller runs on to send a command
to the controller n before they send or
instead of sending that directly they
will generate a combined hedge value
based on the time step of generating of
this command and the content of a
command and this height value will be
archived in the blockchain middleware
and then when the controller n received
a command instead of directly deploying
the command they will also generate the
highest value and compare with the ones
archived in the the blockchain based
meter value the other to verify the
integrity
so by using the functionality of the
blockchain smart contract they're also
able to realize autonomous detection of
malicious hosts to improve the security
and autonomous bandwidth provisioning to
improve the responsiveness and
reliability of the networking management
so the last work i want to provide some
overview about is about inspired
intelligent design making under control
so here i want to try to answer two
essential questions first in order to
realize the transversely situational
awareness how can they dynamically model
in the complex several physical systems
second how could heterogeneous separate
physical components be able to cooperate
for securing the operations in order to
answer those questions smile forward is
to develop a flocking inspired
multi-agent resilient control
this research developed by considering
the microgrid is one type of smart
energy system as a concrete application
domain
so in this work we're leveraging the
flocking philosophy which comes from the
biology area to formulate the coupling
the cyber physical coupling between the
different components in the microgrid
and based on this coupling modeling we
are able to generate a flocking inspired
reference model whose output will be
established is
expected
normal states of the individual
components in this system
and then another reinforced
melanin-based situational awareness
mechanism is able to monitor and detect
abnormal situation by comparing the real
situation and with the respective states
generated from this reference model and
generate autonomous and secure operation
accordingly to maintain the stability of
this microwave
so after um
providing this uh some of our works
overview i would like to end without my
talk by providing some final remarks the
main idea here i want to say is and
in order to provide a resilient
situational awareness for securing the
critical infrastructure it's difficult
to only focus on one layer such as
application layer communication layer or
the
physical layer we really want to
secure those
different layers in a collaborative way
because in the application layer they're
able to provide sensing and environment
data they really like the leaves of the
tree because they
directly interact with our situation
awareness provides also data evidence
and the communication infrastructure is
like the branch it's really connect with
the and leaves and the tank of the tree
so and the last the physical system
because we really interact with the
system physical layer and also
potentially will result in the
safety critical situation if another
operator properly that's why that layer
is a very essential so my work and our
research lab work is a focus on how to
integrate these three layers in order to
provide a prominent solution thank you
very much
professor thank you very much for that
presentation
thank you
you