so i think it's like around uh 4 30. i
will just turn off my camera
and when hi you can just introduce
the speaker today okay yeah sure so
um i'm glad to introduce today's speaker
um dr chamin yimin chen and he's
currently a
postdoctoral associate in the department
of computer science at virginia tech
and then he received this phd i think
from
arizona state university in 2018
um his pt research focuses on the
the security and the privacy in mobile
computing and before that he received
his
best degree from the school of
electronics engineering and the computer
science
at pecking university in 2010
and his master's degree from the
department of electrical engineering
at chinese university of hong kong
in 2013
his research interest i think
includes security and privacy in machine
learning and
meta learning and networking security
and networked systems
so um and also i think he's the
is in the job market this year so um
and looking for faculty positions so
good luck
for that um so um yeah
i think um that's a quite a brief
introduction to dr ching
um with that i'll and i'll turn it over
to
to you dr chen
thank you for the warm introduction
professor
and good afternoon and thank you for
having me
here today my name is ian chen
and i'm currently a postdoc in the
department of computer science
at virginia tech today i'm honored to
introduce my our research in
machine learning security and privacy
from the perspective of
metal learning which is becoming an
increasingly important topic in the era
of
artificial intelligence of things or we
call it aiot
and these are the joint research with my
colleague
miss miss ning wang miss yang ho
and dr wen jingle at virginia tech
so for today's talk i will first
introduce the
importance of metal learning perspective
in
machine learning security and privacy
research
then i will share the details of two of
our ongoing research
project the first one is about defending
against uh data point only attacks
on uh distributed learning models
and the second one is about defending
against a privacy attacks on
federated metal learning systems
i will leave some time at the end of for
the q
a and i hope today's talk
can ignite and engage in and continue
conversation
so why is the meta learning perspective
meaningful
for our research in machine learning
security and privacy
to answer this question i will first uh
briefly introduce
so uh what meta learning is about we all
know
a machine learning model is to train to
learn one specific task for example
uh learn to do image classification
and in comparison uh the high level idea
of meta learning
is to learn to learn from many tasks
so for example in this figure we show
that
the robot here is exposed to
100 learning tasks and through meta
learning
it learns some skills from all these
tasks
and becomes more confident to learn
new tasks for example task 101
and usually the skills it obtains
uh common knowledge shall among the
previous
100 learning tasks
this is the high-level idea of meta
learning
however in today i will only focus on a
very
small slice of metal learning i will
focus
on using metal learning as a
pre-training technique
for generic deep learning models
and in this figure i illustrate the
benefit
of meta learning as a pre-training
method
so we can see here
the blue circle is the parameter space
of of our learning task and
we all know that the most common
initialization method
is random initialization right and in
this figure
random initialization is the center of
the circle
here here and we assume
that the r into star here
denotes the parameters of our task after
convergence
so the net the machine learning training
process
is to move the parameters uh the
parameters
from this starting point from random
initialization
to the parameters at convergence
and the intuition of meta learning is uh
simple suppose uh
suppose uh we have a lot of tasks for
example
task 1 to task 100 and
they are similar to our new tasks here
and very likely through a
metal learning we we can obtain a
starting point a starting point here
that is closer to the uh to the point
after conversion of our task
so we can see that the keywords for
metal learning as initialization method
are common knowledge and also fast
learning
and these two will be are very important
features
in our research
so now coming to part one of today's
talk
defending against data poisoning attacks
on machine learning models
first uh so why do we care about data
poisoning attacks
in fact they are of a big concern right
now because
data poisoning attacks usually cause
severe damages to our society
today we are we are using uh
machine learning models in many uh in
many sectors of our society
for example we are using them for
application
including medical diagnosis
autonomous driving and also
institutional intrusion detection
and data point only attacks are to
insert
quality samples into the training set of
machine learning models
and eventually harm the models
we can see from the lower figures here
a fewer poisonous samples can change the
decision boundary of the vitamin machine
learning model
and cause wrong classification results
on
tested samples and we all know that
misclassifications
in some application could directly
impact people's health and wealth wealth
and wellness
and what's more uh the threat of data
pointing attacks
also comes from that they are very easy
to launch
and they are also very effective
on most machine learning models and we
can see
in the figure on the left here
so in the area of iot we rely
more and more on with most on remote
nodes to collect
trending data these remote nodes are
usually iot devices
and their numbers is growing rapidly
over the time
and the central server here aggregates
this data
and collect and conduct model training
however such open nature of
data collection process also allows
attackers to act as remote node
here and then launch data point only
attacks
for example the central server may
publish a data collection tags of
collecting
images of digits of digits
and but the attacker can instead simply
upload image of letters to launch the
data point on your attacks
and considering there are so many
vulnerabilities and cyber attacks
on iot devices defending against data
poisoning attacks have practical
impact to our society
the uniqueness of our approach to
defending against data poisoning attack
is that we try to tackle the challenging
from the meta learning perspective
so first uh i would like to
so let's look at uh fundamentally what
happens
in a data poisoning attack
as illustrated in the figure here in the
figure here
the purple dots and the green dots were
present to different classes
and the white curve is the decision
boundary of the machine learning model
and in a data point only attack
the attacker may insert a few samples
with modified labels
for example on in the figure on the
right here
the attacker may modify at least
these two uh purple dots into
a green dots and at the same time uh
she or he may modify the green dots
the three green dots here to purple dots
and then training on such a data set the
decision boundary of the machine
learning models
is totally changed because it tried to
accommodate
at least fewer poisonous samples
and this is also known as overfitting of
deep learning models
so compile uh the left and the right
figure
the machine learning model is very
likely to misclassify
the text sample for example on the left
a
list testing sample will be classified
as the purple class however
in the figure on the on the right here
it will be classified as
a green class
and our intuition of using meta
initialization is that
meta learning as we mentioned is to
extract
common knowledge from the training set
and therefore
the initialized initialization model
is much less affected by the poisonous
samples and meanwhile the initialization
model
also helps model training to converge
faster due to uh
the property of initialization model
and by doing so can further reduce
over 15 as well
so we can see that the
initialization model from meta learning
uh can have two uh property
one is to uh reduce the overfitting
and once one is to enable fast fit
faster conversion
so based on such a intuition we propose
our framework here to defend against
data poisoning attacks
and we call our our approach net
so as shown here uh deploying our
approach
as the defense mechanism is very
straightforward
uh it can be done in two steps first we
put first we conduct uh meta learning we
can that meant
meta learning on the training set and
then we can
obtain a meta initialization model file
here
and we can see that the training the
training data set here
already have poisonous samples
here then we will use the initialization
model
to initial our task and
and and do and conduct with training
using the
original training set
and from the from this trend model
we have to output we here we can see
we can see here the first output is the
probability uh is the probability vector
of the
text of a text sample which indicates
the probability
of uh for different classes
and then we also have another uh output
here
the output is the loss function of a
text
sample first we assume
that the chain model here we obtain
is not affected by the poisonous samples
then naturally the loss function of a
clean sample
will be very small while the loss
value of a poisonous sample is very
large
so we can simply use a threshold to
differentiate
a clean and poisonous sample
after proposing our defense approaches
we evaluated its performance on
different applications
including image classification
document classification intrusion
detection
and malware detection
and we use the most popular dataset in
each state
in each domain for evaluation
and additionally we also compile
our defense mechanism against to
to baseline one is a random
initialization method
and the other is uh called
dp method which is the state of the art
to defense against data poisoning
attacks
and now let's see how effective our
proposed attack is
throughout this project we will use the
area under
precision we call curb score
au aupr score
as our evaluation metric and we can see
from the two table here the detection
results
on poisonous samples in uh intrusion
detection domain
also on the left table and results in
malware
detection domain uh is uh in the
right table and we and
and for the and for the different magnet
model
here they correspond to
uh to the uh to the magnet model with
different meta training uh meta training
iterations
for example uh magnet 100 corresponds to
our model with 100 meter training
iteration
and we can see that our models achieve
higher
aopi scores consistently in list two
domain in this
domain and if we look at the male well
detection domain
actually the the state of the rms the
dpms
achieve achieve a lower aopr score than
the random initialized
random initialization model
and we also test our our approach in the
computer vision domain
to see if it can detect points in the
samples
uh from the attack as well and
for the for the row here uh
the row here is the ratio of poisonous
samples in the training set
in the training set and
and the results here again show that
our approach outperformed to baseline
consistently
so indicate that our approach can be
applied to
a wide range of machine learning models
after introducing using my research on
security attacks in
in previous part naturally i would like
to talk about
privacy attacks on machine learning
model as well
so in part two i will discuss our
research to defend against
membership influence attacks on
federated meta learning systems
and remember that in part one we
mentioned
one notable trend of iot devices
that in recent years
iot devices are estimated to grow
substantially and and the trend is not
stopping
actually another secular trend of iot
devices is that their capabilities are
increasingly diverse as well
and this is actually very exciting
because uh
iot devices are used today are used
not just for data collection but also
for advanced
tasks uh including learning
so in other words the next generation of
iot devices are
actually expected to equip with ai or
machine learning
technologies and this uh transcends
into what we call aiot
error
so in aiot we envision that
federated metal learning may be the more
suitable learning
paradigm than the then the traditional
federal learning
than the traditional federal and the
difference
between these two learning paradigms
is that the goal of federated meta
learning is to learn an initialization
model
while federated learning is just to
learn a machine learning model
for one specific task
so obviously the initialization model
from
federated metal learning has a much
greater application potential because
it can be used for many many tasks as
long as
they are similar and more importantly we
have two other intuition for federated
metal learning
the first one is that um participants
in uh in distributed learning system
do not necessarily have a lot of data
to train a local model uh which are
meaningful
for the global model in federated
learning
and in comparison uh federated metal
does not have had such a requirement on
participants data set i mean
federated metal learning do not require
other participants to have a lot of
training data to generate a
strong local model and
the other uh the other intuition we have
is that
it's not wise to assume the sample
distributions
in all participants are almost the same
and including uh the data distribution
uh at the future model consumers
so in this way we got it will make more
sense
that to assume that the participants
data set
only share some similarities and
we can use federated metal learning
to extract this similarity and
and use them for for
model initialization
so um although federated metal learnings
has the tip has some difference from
federated learning
uh one common feature among list two is
that
these two systems will be uh
subject to privacy attacks such as a
membership influence or property
influencer tax
and in our work we focus on
membership influence attack in such
attacks the attackers
use the published initial initialization
model
initialization model to infer whether
a specific user or a specific
samples participate the meta training
process
and naturally to defend against
membership influence attacks we
we will use the popular differential
privacy
mechanism and and incorporate
into the model training process of
federated met
meta learning systems
and first i would like to uh i would
like to briefly introduce the training
process of
federated meta learning system
specifically uh we actually use one of
the most popular
meta learning schemes called memo in our
in our system
and we call that we have uh and we call
that we have
a participant and central server in
a federated meta learning system
and at the participant site she or he
will conduct local learning will conduct
local learning
and obtain a local model for example
theater i hear then
then sure he will upload the local
gradient to the central server here
to the central server and the central
server will aggregate
many many gradients to update
the uh the global model series
here and at the end of meta training
the the central server will publish the
final meta
model to the model consumer the model
consumer will use the
meta model theta to initial
to initialize uh their own model
and and do training on top list
of of this metamodel
so we can see that in this process
in this process they they are actually
two parts that could potentially lead to
privacy leakage
in the first case for case a
the meta the the central server will
publish
the metamodel theater to the model
consumers
and the model consumer can use
silt silta to infer
to infer the existence of
for example of satai the existence the
existence of one specific task
and for case b so we can see that the
participants will
will submit a silta siltai
to the central server and actually the
central server can
use theta i to infer the existence of a
specific training sample
in setai so based on these two
observations we propose to add
differential privacy
in list two parts in these two parts
for to achieve privacy protection
so so naturally we have two privacy
levels for case a we call it
a task level dp we have
we use this uh list dp to pro
to prevent the model consumers from
informing membership from employee
membership
of a certain task of a certain type
and for case b we have the dual level
differential privacy
and it will not only prevent the model
consumer
to infer each uh clt
eye and you will also prevent the
central server
from info from informing
the existence of a specific training
sample
contributing to each silta eye
and corresponded uh to protect uh
the privacy uh within silta we
add a differential privacy to it here
in this stage and and then
to protect the privacy within celtai
we we also add a differential privacy
here
uh to protect co2
and after proposing our defense
approaches we evaluate its performance
on several more on the most popular
data set in field short learning domain
and additionally we also compile
our our approach against
uh against one baseline
gbml and this is the state of the
art of differential private federated
metal learning schemes in the literature
and the show and and the data sets we
use
in for our evaluation
the first one is a ohmic law and the
second one
is a cipher fs and the third one
is the mini image net
now let's see how effective our our
proposed approach is
throughout this part we will use the
in-way case short
accuracy as our evaluation matches
away k short denotes that the learning
task
for the for the specific machine
learning machine learning model
it has earned classes and each classes
has a k samples for example uh
five way one shot means that the machine
learning model
has five classes and in the trainings
and in the training set each classes has
only
one training sample and sort the same to
uh the other away casual setting
and and here we evaluate different
different methods including
random initialization non-private
and list 2 dpa gi and dpa gilr
are the two methods we propose for
case a and case b and also here we have
the gbml
and for the random initialization it
means
it means doing machine learning without
any
fuel approach future approach
and for this non-private non-private one
it means adopting our federating
meta learning system without adding any
differential privacy
and we can see from this figure that
when there's only a field trending set
a field training sample at the
participants
actually we can only obtain a very
low classification accuracy
and then when we adopt some future
learning method for example memo then
the accuracy immediately goes up to very
high
here and of course
when we would like to use some privacy
protection mechanism
we need to sacrifice a little bit
the classification accuracy and we can
see that
for case a our accuracy will drop a
little bit
and if we would like to protect more
privacy then the accuracy will
also decrease will also
decrease decrease further
and however english in this figure we
in this table we can see that our method
can still
achieve a higher accuracy
than the state of the art and
and folders and for the suite method for
the three method with
privacy protection their privacy
batteries are similar
and we also plot the
the accuracy curve of different model on
two
data set one is the omegle and the other
is the mini
image net for a better
illustration and we can see that
we can see that of course the the
non-private federated metal learning
achieve the highest
uh classification accuracy on list two
data set
and and still uh our two methods
one is the dpati and the other is the
dpatrl
achieve higher accuracy than the state
of the art
and within our two methods a
dpagr has a higher privacy because it
only
achieved the task level it does not
prevent the
central server from informing the
existing of a specific sample
contributing to
a specific co2 eye
yeah with that i'd like to open up for q
a
and i'd like to thank you all for having
me here today
all right uh you mean thank you so much
it was a nice talk it was uh
very related to the course that i am
teaching
okay really i'm teaching a security
analytics course
which we cover in the first half of the
course
the common machine learning algorithms
and in the second
half of the course basically we covered
the
recent attacks to the machine learning
systems
basically the systems that build
on uh that that integrates machinery
such as we cover evasion attacks
eventually attack
yes we cover you know like white bugs
and black box attacks
additionally we cover some privacy
issues
as you mentioned membership inference
attack model inversion attack
and also uh because it's a hot topic
sometimes i cover
differential privacy and generative
adversarial networks
as well okay so
your research is like kind of like
really related to
you know like the course materials that
i'm teaching
okay sure um so we have some questions
in the
q a if you click you will be able to see
the question
okay so uh maybe i will first
read the question to the audience i
don't know if the audience can see the
question
uh and then i will try i will try to
answer that so
yeah uh and the
the question is from chris uh clinton
and uh and the question is what ibsen
are you using with differential privacy
and how are you calculating sensitivity
for images
yeah that's a good question and
and for the uh we are we are using the
epson delta differential privacy
and if i remember that correctly for the
for the epson we are using uh
the values between
between 10 to -4
to 10 to uh to
10 to -5 yeah
10 to -4 to to 95 and for the
for the delta uh i remember is
uh between uh
it should be less than 0.2 if
if i remember that correctly and
actually for the
for the uh for the for the related work
we are referring to the
uh the gvml their privacy battery is uh
the the epsilon is 10 to the power of
uh 10 to the power -3 and
and i i i did not remember their delta
so i mean they are using a much larger
privacy budget but as you as we can see
in the figure
their accuracy is not that good
and okay and the sorry the second types
are
how are you calculating sensitivity for
images
actually let me see i will show my
screen here
yeah so traditionally they are
there are three uh three parts that can
that we can add differential privacy uh
into model training process uh we can
add
a differential privacy in the training
sample
in the training samples and then add
differential privacy in
in the in in in the gradients
in the gradient computation and the and
the last
position is to add at differential
privacy at the output
and the most uh the mainstream
uh method to incorporate differential
privacy is to
to add them into the into the gradients
so as as you can see here for example
for the task level dp for start level db
uh the gi here denotes the gradient from
each node from each node and these are
these pi is the
this is the noise that will generate the
differential privacy protection
and and basically the two parameter here
for the say here is uh for the say here
is a normalization factor
and then for the say here say is will be
related to
the uh sensitivity you are mentioning
so we did not care about whether the
input is
image or our text or
our arbitrary input uh we only look at
the gradients here
so we we can imagine that c should be
proportional
to the value of gi here because uh it
will
actually try to cover the impact of ti
yeah i don't know if i answer the
question or not
let me see if there are other
yeah professor chris clifton actually
posted some more comments to the chat
uh okay yeah for uh for the
attention to the uh you know like the
participants here
essentially all right so you don't need
to read that
okay it's just an additional comment for
your information
thank you professor kington
okay all right
are there any other questions from the
participants
all right done uh you mean thank you so
much again for your interesting talk
and i hope that uh we see you personally
yeah yeah it produced some time you know
like
probably probably like after the
epidemic yeah actually i
one of my family members went to purdue
for his phd
in information engineering department
in industry engineering not information
in industry engineering department
i see industrial engineering yeah all
right
again thank you so much everyone for
attending
and i will see you next week in another
series seminar
thank you for having me here today take
care
you