thank you spaff uh yes my great pleasure
to produce uh
see he didn't always joke because i
butchered her poor last name and it's
not that hard eda nagombecki who's an
assistant professor of computer and
information technology or here at purdue
ita's research investigates the human
factors in cyber security and includes
cyber security behavior social
engineering cyber security education
cyber policy and workforce development
eda welcome
hello thank you
one of these days you're going to get it
on the first try joel i believe in you
i welcome the opportunities i always
enjoy your speech
okay let me see if i can share my screen
here
all right can you see that
looks great okay thank you all right so
today i'm going to talk very briefly
about industrial control systems
security and the educational challenge
posed by this field
and um my talk is going to be based on
work that i actually did with staff so
eugene stafford and i collaborated on a
project to develop a curriculum guidance
document for a hub and spoke system to
help address the industrial control
system security lack
but i'm also going to talk about work
that we did with our graduate students
we had four grad great wonderful
graduate students on this project and
also some work i did with sean mcbride
at idaho state university
okay
so um
basically what we found here was that
industrial control system security is a
problem it's a massive
problem
right
um
before we start i want to
define some terms because
going through this what i've found is a
lot of people in the cyber security
space are really not that familiar with
industrial control systems
and so when we talk about industrial
control systems i think sort of the root
of it is industrial processes which
basically involve the use of machinery
and equipment
to create physical goods
usually in bulk quantities so things
like motors temperatures pressures
levels flows all of those things
are what we consider industrial
processes right
and industrial automation
is the field that deals with the
creation and application of technologies
that perform these industrial processes
while minimizing human oversight and
intervention right so that's sort of the
purpose we want as few humans as
possible we want these systems to be
able to run on their own we want them to
be able to be robust and resilient
and so there's operational technology
which encompasses the communication and
control systems used to automate
manipulate or acquire information
and
this is different from information
technology which i think most of us are
much more familiar with that deals with
data
operational technology deals with
industrial processes and
when we talk about operations we're
talking about scada we're talking about
ics systems so operational technology or
ot tends to be
used as the most broad umbrella term
here
industrial control systems is used
interchangeably with operational
technology they're not exactly the same
thing
ics refers to the equipment that enables
industrial automation
so programmable controllers sensors
human machine interfaces scada servers
so it's it
it's very similar ot but it doesn't
incorporate that
focus on networking technologies right
but when we talk about
industrial control systems
there's another school of thought that
basically says that equipment used to
manage
a multitude of computerized systems
which interact with the physical world
right so there are those camps who think
of industrial control systems as those
systems that are used in industrial
processes those systems that are used
to control things like manufacturing oil
and gas processing water distribution
right and then there are those who widen
the term industrial control systems to
think to include things like the
electrical grid
right
information technology i think we're all
familiar with computers networking
equipment software that
basically supports decision making
right it provides us with information
so what we're talking about the focus
of our project was industrial control
systems security
also referred to as industrial cyber
security
and basically these are efforts to
ensure the safety reliability
controllability functionality and
robustness of industrial control systems
and operational technology
so we wanted these are the systems this
is the field that is going to make sure
that in the face of threats in the face
of vulnerabilities the computerized
systems and networks these systems these
industrial processes can continue to run
so that's what we're talking about here
and the challenge
that
that where
we're focusing on is when you look at
this you find that
industrial control system security is a
major economic and national security
problem i think we all know we've been
hearing all day cyber security one of
our primary national security issues
icss is a subset of that
and
it shows up in so many ways right i
think the the most famous was sort of
the colonial pipeline
um
disaster i think we all heard about
which was a ransomware attack on the
colonial pipeline that um
provided
oil and gas to over
um over 17 states were affected by this
ransomware and the company ended up
paying
something like four million dollars to
get their operation systems back up and
running again right and they're more and
more and more of these attacks
every year
right it's definitely increasing
exponentially
and if you talk
to companies you talk to
ceos and cios
reported in 2019
that
this is 88 of ceos at companies
responsible
for um industrial control systems
companies that use industrial control
systems on a daily basis for their
operations
they were
concerned about cyber attacks most of
these companies consider industrial
control systems amaze industrial control
system security a major priority right
um 66 of these ceos and cios actually
said they expect to be victims
of an industrial control system cyber
security attack within the next three
years
that could result in a catastrophic
event right and these threats are not
reducing these starts are actually
increasing they've increased 2 000
in just the last three years which is
slightly ridiculous
so i think we can all agree it's a major
economic problem it's a major national
security problem
and in order to deal with this problem
we need people
in the workforce pipeline we need people
trained
we need people
with the skill set to be able to
design secure systems to secure the
systems that already exist
and make sure that they can hold up to
these cyber attacks and if they do fall
victim to these cyber attacks we need
systems that will be resilient right
that can recover
from these attacks
but there is a decided lack of talent
in this sphere in the workplace
right
the current national education
curriculum lacks essential
programs in industrial control system
security if you look at cyber security
generally
82 percent of employers reported the
cyber security skills shortage
71 believe this
um this talent gap that exposes their
institutions their companies to harm
right
so just to keep up with current demand
they're currently almost half a mil
half a million open cyber security
positions just in the united states
right the cyber security workforce needs
to grow 89 percent to keep up with
demand in the us 100 and 45 globally
right
so what portion of that is industrial
control system security it's kind of
hard to say
we can say about 60
our jobs in
operations and maintenance and secure
provisioning which is sort of the area
that would
encompass
icss
so
i think it would be reasonable to
estimate that about half of that 60
is directly
icss jobs so that's a significant
proportion
of the lack of talent in the cyber
security workforce is because of this
lack
of industrial control system security
professionals
right so we have this major economic and
national security problem
we have a lack of talent
that is able to deal with this problem
in the workforce pipeline
so
where does that leave us
right that leaves us with
looking at the beginning of that
pipeline looking at training and
education and saying okay obviously
there is a problem there obviously we
are not educating enough people we are
not educating them well enough
to make sure that they are able to enter
into this space right so it's very clear
that our current educational efforts are
insufficient to address the talent gap
in industrial control system security
so
we have taken some time and looked at
what
that at what the educational landscape
looks like and where the source of this
problem might be and there are various
places that i'm going to talk about them
right
one of the first places that we looked
was the curriculum guidance
right
every educational program starts with
building a curriculum that's going to
guide the ways in which we educate our
students right
in cyber security we have
three
primary curriculum guidance documents
you might all be
hopefully all of you are familiar with
them um there is the nice cyber security
workforce framework there is the csec
and the um cie
um
the centers of academic excellence in
cyber defense knowledge units
so these are
there are others but these are the three
that are most referred to the three that
are most used so these are the three
that we took a look at to see where we
stand what kind of guidance is available
right so let me start with the nice
framework for those of you not familiar
with the nice framework
the nice framework was developed
originally i believe it was 2012 when it
was first published
um
developed by the national initiative for
cyber security education
led by the national institutes of
standards and technology and the idea is
to look at the cyber security workforce
the cyber security landscape
and describe and categorize cyber
security job functions
right they've obviously been revisions
on this document i believe the latest
revision was was published last year
right but basically the core of the
document describes the work roles
expected or envisioned in cyber security
and the knowledge skills and abilities
that are needed to perform those work
roles successfully
okay so it's a very useful document
and
a review of the framework actually shows
very little attention to industrial
control systems in fact the term
industrial control systems
is not in this document at all
right
the term scada which is sort of a subset
of ot
um appears in
three
of the ksas this is the knowledge skills
and ability statements so they're
you know over a thousand of these and
only in three of these
only three times does that specific and
possibly the most common reference to
industrial control
um appear
if you look at anything related to
critical infrastructure or other terms
that could be argued to be relevant to
industrial control systems you get
a handful of knowledge skill and ability
statements right
so we were curious
as to
whether this was sufficient for what we
were seeing in industry so we did a
really small study we looked at the five
most um popular
job search websites
and we looked for basically
we looked for jobs related to ics
security so this was automation and
robotic security operational technology
security
industrial control systems security
cyber security analysts in industrial
control
you know we used a whole bunch of
keywords to search and then we looked at
all of the
um job calls that we had found
and
we narrowed this down
right to what were the actual work roles
we're looking at and we came up with 10
distinct work roles
for each of those work roles we looked
at the knowledge skills abilities we
looked at the tasks the work tasks
and so i just wanted to show you what we
found in terms of knowledge statements
now you can see from these
these as compared to
if you map these back to the nice
framework they're very different the
nice framework
actually only about less than a third of
these are
just general cybersecurity
statements right the majority of them
are highly specific
to industrial control systems so
somebody would need specific knowledge
of both it and ot in order to be able to
complete these tasks and not just ip or
ot but actually the integration of the
two
so obviously in industry there is a
and a desire
for these work roles right so for people
who are
educated trained um competent
in their ability to carry out industrial
control systems security work
okay
the second curriculum guidance document
we looked at is called
the curriculum guidelines of
post-secondary degree programs in cyber
security affectionately known as the
csec 2017
this document was um created by a joint
task force composed of the association
for computing machinery so the acm the
ieee computer society and the
association for information systems
um
the special interest group on
information security and privacy
i think i got that right right and then
also the international federation for
information processing their technical
committee on information security
education so a lot of notable academic
and professional organizations came
together they contributed um experts
to look at
what are
the
what are the components of a cyber
security
program
what does a society what does cyber
security as an academic discipline
look like
right
so they did a whole bunch of workshops
they did online surveys they talked to a
lot of people
and
as i recall to make over 300 people
consulted on this and what they came up
with was these eight knowledge areas
which break down into knowledge units
topics and learning outcomes
right and the purpose was to represent
the full body of knowledge within the
field of cyber security that's what the
csec 2017 does
looking at industrial control looking
for industrial control systems within
this document
the term industrial control systems
appears as a topic
under the knowledge area system security
right so if you look at a topic you
start with a knowledge unit then that
breaks down to knowledge area and then
this is a topic
right so topic you can think of it
as of like a module
right so under system security
right and
scada is included under that
the term um cyber physical systems
appears as a topic under organizational
security again
a very limited treatment
right
so compare this to what we found in
terms of what industry is looking for
this treatment would not be enough for
somebody who wanted to go into a role in
icss
okay
um if you look at the nsa cae knowledge
units this is prob this probably has the
most comprehensive treatment of the
three when it comes to industrial
control systems it's actually an entire
knowledge unit
that is dedicated to industrial control
systems
right
and
it actually lays out learning outcomes
topic areas right
however if you really examine the topic
areas included
um
they're not really fully representative
of what a professional
in icss would need to know and need to
be able to do to be successful
right
so just looking at the curriculum
guidance documents it's obvious that
there is a problem we have a bit of a
challenge
here there is not enough curriculum
guidance to actually create a full
program industrial control system
security
right
so not only are the curriculum guidance
documents
um insufficient if you look at the
landscape of what actually exists right
so we did
a nationwide review
and we tried to identify every
industrial control system security
program
certification
right
so we looked for operational technology
security industrial control system
security industrial cyber security
industrial engineering technology
security automation and robotic security
right we use a lot of terms
and we came up with
there are very limited set
right
the most that we found were industrial
training programs in cyber security
that were specific to industrial control
systems right so giac has a bunch of
certifications in response industrial
defense critical infrastructure
protection
um global industrial cyber security
right that are specific to industrial
cyber security cisa has a bunch of
programs
um to train people
in ics cyber security
um isa has a handful right
but basically what we found
a lot of programs in cyber security a
lot of training in operational
technology and industrial control
systems but actual industrial control
systems security
we found less than 20 training programs
and these training programs vary from a
few hours
to basically a few months right
we found less than 10 university
certificates
these certificates were anywhere from a
few weeks
to uh a year
and we found exactly one degree
one bachelor's degree
it is at it's a four-year degree in
industrial control system security i
believe it's called
industrial cybersecurity engineering
technology i believe is what it's called
um and it was the only one
that we could find
right so obviously
there is a bit of a lack
right there
so
there is i think we can agree an
educational challenge when it comes to
industrial control system security right
so what we proposed as a solution
is the creation of a program of programs
basically we need many more in
industrial control system security and
we need to create curriculum guidance to
help support the development of those
programs so that is what we undertook to
do
basically the plan was to define the
need i think you we can agree the need
for this is very clear
we have ongoing cyber attacks we have
these systems becoming more networked
and therefore more vulnerable
uh we have a talent gap right we looked
at the current landscape and we find
that there is definitely not enough
education and training we have looked we
looked and identified what existing
curriculum and existing curriculum
guidance
was available
so our next step was to actually
identify
critical knowledge skills and abilities
that are actually necessary to become
proficient in industrial control system
security
in order to do that we undertook a
delphi study so basically um we reached
out to there is a national
industrial control systems community of
practice that's actually housed at
the idaho national labs
i'm a member of that and i think staff
is too a few other people might be as
well
and they have some working groups that
are working on developing resources
developing standards
and training and so on industrial
control system security but um it's
professionals from academia government
and industry we reached out to them
and
we asked them this question what is the
critical knowledge skills and what are
the abilities that you need when to be
successful in icss
and based on that and based on their
feedback we developed a concept map
which you can see here
this concept map shows what they felt
were sort of the core
topic areas the core skills areas
in industrial control system security
the second thing we did was we ident we
tried we took
that concept map and we tried to look at
existing programs and see what
were the gaps
right
the project we're working on was founded
was funded by the department of homeland
security uh in collaboration with
um researchers at the university of
illinois out of verna champaign
and so they asked us actually to take a
hub and spoke approach
to this
and so we focused on
fema region five because that's our fema
region and the six states illinois
indiana minnesota
michigan
wisconsin right in that fema region we
looked at a whole bunch of institutions
and basically um we surveyed these
schools and looked for
what existing programs they had
most of them had some form of cyber
security everything from a full degree
to you know a course or modules within
courses in cyber security or information
security
most of them had
fairly decent engineering programs
some of them had engineering technology
programs
and so
between all of these so cyber security
management forensics network security um
engineering
technology electrical engineering
industrial engineering right so we
looked at all of these and tried to
identify okay so if you would if you
wanted to create a program industrial
control system security what do these
things have and what's missing
right
and what we
realized these are
the concepts that across
the majority of these are missing
right there's some places that don't
have enough cyber security they will
need to build that up some places that
don't have
enough um
electrical engineering right they need
to be fed up but broadly speaking what
was missing
was topics on safety on industrial
operations on instrumentation and
control
and especially on security integration
and what we've realized is that
any program in industrial control system
security
would need to be
ideally interdisciplinary
more realistically multidisciplinary
right they're going to cross multiple
departments
um
and they're going to have to be some new
classes created in these areas in order
to fill in the gaps
that we're missing
right
so
having reviewed these critical concepts
and gaps we created topic areas
right created five topic areas in risk
governance information security
industrial control systems and
electrical engineering that we felt if
classes hit all of these topic areas
and their specific
concepts within these topic areas that
would be a reasonable program for
industrial control systems security
and we went further than that and
actually created model curriculum
so we created so we looked at what are
the classes that would need to go into
an associate's degree a bachelor's
degree a master's degree and a phd in
industrial control system security we
based that heavily on classes that
already exist we took into account
things like existing credit hour
requirements we took into account um
things like requirements for general
education right so we didn't ignore
the classes in language and professional
writing and so on communications
um
there is actually a report on this i
don't think it is currently posted but
it will be within the next few weeks if
you want to if you want to see how these
classes actually break down
um it will be posted as a serious
technical report if anybody is
interested
right
a couple of additional things that i
want to note when building programs in
industrial control systems security i
think it's really important to take
advantage as much as possible
of the potential for online offerings
right now icss because by its very
nature requires a lot of hands-on work
it's going to require a lot of lab work
but not exclusively so there are things
that students can learn at a distance
and i think having that option would be
beneficial to them
and also
much more than many other fields this is
an area of cyber security that really
needs work integrated learning right so
um any institution trying to create this
kind of program is going to have to
partner with some sort of industry or
military or other critical
infrastructure so that their students
can get some hands-on learning depends
on training
in these things not just labs but also
hand
work
professional work environment training
and
so the program any program would have to
think about how to
integrate that
professional work into
their assessment of the curriculum okay
so that's a very um sort of high
overview
of what i think is the educational
challenge
in industrial control system security
so are there questions
professor nagenbecky thank you very much
for your presentation uh we are right on
time to go to our next segment uh eda's
contact information
into the uh the chat line so please do
follow up uh on this or any of the rest
of her research that she has there