hello everyone uh welcome to the uh
wednesday security seminar yet again um
it is it is my distinct pleasure to
introduce someone who
uh is is really a legend in the field of
cyber security to the people who've been
working in it for a while
um he's uh he's got a history that goes
back in this field
um about 50 years really
uh with uh started in mitre
corporation um then went to digital
equipment corporation and participated
in the development of uh one of the
first um a1
secure systems under the old orange book
series the reba series
uh after more time at minor and trusted
information systems
he went to microsoft where he
was partner director of software
security
and helped lead the development of the
software security life cycle
software development life cycle there at
microsoft
um after doing a lot of work there and
and
uh i'll say that microsoft uh colonel
went from being
one of the the least uh trustworthy
colonels to one of the most under his
supervision uh he retired a few years
ago
and is now the executive direct director
of safe code
so he has a long history of experience
building
very secure systems and helping to
secure systems that
weren't quite as secure and along the
way
learn some lessons and he's going to
share those with us today so
steve thank you so much take it away
thank thank you spat thank you spaff um
so you you sort of you sort of hinted at
some of the things
that um that you know that i was going
to introduce in the in the first
first uh first slide um i uh
as you as you said i started i actually
started working
on on computer security as it was called
them
in uh in 1970 and i
i never i never quite got out of it
actually my my
boss at mitre said we've got this
problem
and i said well my degrees in civil
engineering i don't know anything about
the
you know computer science or you know
you're probably talking about proving
programs i don't know anything about
that
you want to get somebody with the right
background and and he said well i
that makes sense to me but i don't have
anybody to put on that assignment right
now
why don't you just see what you can do
until uh until we can hire somebody
with the right background and that was
in 1970 and i never quite got out
um and um a lot of
interim steps which spaff alluded to in
which i'll
talk a little more about in the
following slide
um as uh as spaff said i joined
microsoft in 99
uh was primarily responsible for the
creation of the security development
life cycle process
um that did make a a
difference in the in the way we looked
at building
secure systems uh and retired from
from microsoft and 15 started working at
safe code
in 16 safe code is a is a small
non-profit
members are companies in the industry
they all have uh secure development
processes
similar to the security development
lifecycle and
so as executive director i try to sort
of provide
uh strategic and technical guidance
this presentation isn't about
sdl or things that
i i've normally given given talks about
a lot um instead more for
you know sort of new folks in the field
or
folks who are trying to learn some of
the background or or
history or other considerations
it's focused on mistakes things that i
did
that i wish i hadn't done or wish i
hadn't done as much of
over the last 50 years and maybe
maybe that maybe that tells you
something about how to think
about what you're facing and hearing um
i'll i'll wrap it up
with some some lessons learned and
suggestions
and then uh i hope that'll get and i
hope i'll do that
in time to uh to let you let you get on
with your
your day and um and and consistent with
the
uh with the schedule for the for the
class
um so relevant career history
as um as uh as maf said
i was with the mitre corporation
actually i was with mitre from 70
to 81 69 to 81
so these are the times i was working on
primarily on security
um and that was at mitre just from 70 to
76 i did other things
before and after that time um
81 to 92 with digital equipment
corporation
uh company doesn't exist anymore um
mini computers super mini computers um
the the industry took a turn to pcs
digital didn't and that was the end of
digital
trusted information systems um
largely a government research contractor
we built a
a commercial business went public
um i was with the company
got bought out uh by a bigger company in
the
in the security business in 98 um and
then microsoft
um lives on i talked to those folks
they're a safe code member
but i was there just from 99 to 2015.
i joined them to run the security
response center
which was the organization that dealt
with externally discovered holes
in microsoft products and i used a joke
that when i joined them in 1999 i was uh
i was 20 years old and you're supposed
to look at my
appearance now um add 20 to
the 20 20 to the time since
since i supposedly since i joined him in
and laugh at the aging effects of uh of
working for microsoft on vulnerability
response back in the day
but in fact it was it was an interesting
adventure um
not really primari primary subject of
this this talk
so let's talk about about some of the
mistakes
um mistake one
was um was is is the bella padula model
i don't know whether you've studied
multi-level security whether you've
studied security models
but bellapadula was one of the earliest
security models for dealing with uh with
with classified information it was
explicitly driven
by the objective of of meeting
the defense department's needs for what
they called multi-level security
i want a system that can handle
both top secret information which is uh
very sensitive can cause damage to the
national security
and unclassified information which is
is public or close to it and
i want users who are only authorized for
um for unclassified information to
to darn sure not be able to uh
not be able to access uh classified
information not be able to access top
secret information
and so our um our first
challenge when we started thinking about
that um
that requirement was to figure out well
okay what does that mean
in precise terms that we could implement
with the computer system
and a couple of uh
really very good mathematicians named
david bell and len lapadula uh
both of whom are now members of the
national cyber security hall of fame
um tackled that problem
and they came up with a mathematical
model
um whose effects i've tried to
illustrate with the with the graphic
here
you have top secret files you have
unclassified files
you have top secret cleared user or
process and an unclassified user or
process
and the rules of the model and we'll
give you the mathematics
are that the unclassified user can read
or write
the unclassified mob file and the
top secret user or process and reader
write the top secret
but can only read uh only read
the unclassified file and so that gives
you
sharing of information that's consistent
with the dod model for
uh for information security and it also
has the effect
which is important in building a real
computer system
that even if the top secret user top
secret
process is running um
a trojan horse some some very
untrustworthy software um it can't take
the top secret
and disclose it down into an
unclassified file
and um and and and and
you know then south out the internet or
out the door in somebody's pocket
um and do harm to national security so
at the time
that was you know that was the
requirement set
and the model was a was a major
breakthrough
it wasn't the first uh um
security model that attempted to address
multi-level security
but it was um it was the first
that was resistant at a model level
uh to this to this threat from trojan
horse programs
um and if you so if you built a system
right that enforced that model um it was
it was pretty useful and a pretty
significant breakthrough
and we actually built it into a
time-shared multi-system
that was used at an air force data
center in the pentagon
and i believe there were there were
other multi-systems in the defense
department that probably used the model
as well and it worked
quite okay there the users
were happy with it they shared
information they shared programs
um and and it was it was usable in that
context
of a 70s time sharing system
i believed as i say here that it was a
general solution for multi-level
security
you know if you've got a system uh if
you've got a requirement for a system
that's going to climb
handle classified information about
lepage
bellapadulis your answer
turned out that bellapagela wasn't your
answer
um in practice there were too many
reasons
to violate the the requirements of the
model
um what's an example
well i i get a i
i'm logged in at top secret cruising
along
and i get an unclassified email and i
want to reply to it
okay so now i have to log out
log in as an unclassified user and then
i can
reply but from top secret i can't
i can't i can compose a reply but when i
click send back to the unclassified user
the the model enforcement is going to
say nope you can't do that
and in the real world what we did was
wound up
was wind up inventing pop-up fatigue
um anybody remember windows vista and
the uh
um the the allow or deny
permission when when people wanted to
install new software
well that was a very similar model
called the biba integrity model
working its way with a highly
interactive uh
highly interactive system with real
world users
um i i remember seeing um
a male system that was running the bell
of agile model
where you know where we had users just
sort of constantly clicking okay
clicking okay
clicking okay and you know and that
says there's not actually any top secret
information going down there
and you know and and if if people have
to do that
once a minute or more often there's no
way they're exercising judgment they're
just clicking okay
so uh good idea didn't stand
uh couldn't couldn't really withstand uh
interaction with with the real world
um mistake two
was kind of a compound on
on mistake on miss on on bella padula
the defense department i think staff
referred to the orange book
the defense department built
liked ballon lapajola and they built it
um as a core tenet of
their orange book security evaluation
criteria
of the of the 1980s um
and so uh there were various levels of
systems that
uh that that you could build depending
on how much
effort you put into enforcing the rules
and making the system secure
um at the highest level you
uh you had you had to implement the bell
of agile model
and you had to do that with high
assurance formal formal specification
formal verification
i sold digital equipment corporation on
the proposition that we needed to be in
that security market
and so what we should do was build an a1
system a system that was as secure
as dod knew how to evaluate um
and we actually built
um a virtual machine monitor um
for the vax architecture uh super super
mini computers
that um that implemented below padula
uh used a virtual machine monitor
architecture to minimize the amount of
software that we had to trust
and still because it was a vmm
still provided compatibility with um
with the existing user operate
user code and operating systems that ran
on the vaxxed architecture
so here's a little sketch uh from a from
a paper
you you've got multiple virtual machines
one at top secret one
secret one and unclassified some of them
running vacs
vms some of them running the the ultrix
operating system which was dex unix
we got that for free the minimal
mechanism was all
in the the vmm the virtual machine
monitor
security kernel users connected through
that
and if you had to uh you know if you had
to switch from top secret uh
to unclassified uh we gave him an easy
way to do that
um so it was pretty cool uh
we built it um we got it to the point
where we were actually able to uh to dog
food it to self-host it
in our development group and we were
doing the uh
the svs development on
svs systems uh which is sort of a test
of whether you've got a system or not
um and and that was all that was all
pretty cool
um but there were some
some real world problems um
the you know the as i've shown show on
this slide
um the development wasn't easy uh we
were trying to minimize
the trusted code um the uh
performance bmm performance is is a
potential problem in any case
um and the the vax wasn't really
designed to be
virtual machine monitor friendly
i think that systems like vmware
today offer
implements and technologies that might
either have been not
viable the machine's as slow as the
boxes were
or or we just didn't have them um and
then
uh the uh the the the performance the
the security evaluation process for our
secure system was what i would call
adversarial um the
the uh evaluation people got points for
a fine
you know for making us fail not for
making us succeed
and so that was that was interesting
uh all those things said we ran well
behind schedule
i don't think we ran over budget because
we uh we
always had trouble getting enough people
you know just hiring enough people to
work on the thing
um but we eventually got the system done
enough to be in beta test um and some of
the users liked it
but in general users had moved on um
they they wanted pcs this was the late
80s they wanted pcs they wanted networks
they wanted graphical user interfaces
and what we had was a terminal time
sharing system
that was really compact worked really
well compatible with the technologies
that you had in the mid-80s
and so you know my characterization is
nobody wanted a system that
secure or more accurately nobody wanted
a system
nobody wanted to pay in performance and
usability
the price of a system that's secure and
i wound up canceling the project
in uh in 1990
um one of the one of the sadder days of
my life
but but clearly the right decision
is if we had continued to build it we
wouldn't have sold enough
and we would have lost a ton of money uh
trying to enhance it
and uh and and support it over the years
uh i can answer more questions about
about the cancellation decision um and
uh and what i mean by losing more money
um when we when we get to the to the end
if
you're interested um so that was that
was mistake
two um you know sort of closely linked
to
uh to the bellapadula mistake
and and doubling down to make a bigger
and more expensive mistake
after an another another
um another product of that same deck
era was what we call the desnik
the digital ethernet secure network
controller
dec had adopted ethernet in the mid 80s
and i assume you've studied ethernet
you know it's basically one a single
shared medium
anybody can transmit or receive on that
medium
and without without encryption you know
anybody can hear
hear what anybody else is saying or
anybody can spoof what
anybody else claims to be saying
our deck product family at the time
used at least a couple of transport
protocols
one of them was dec net which was dex
proprietary
networking protocol for connecting its
own products together
another was lat which was stood for
local area terminal protocol
and it was used to connect uh
servers that were users dialed in or
connected with dot
dom terminals um connect the terminal
servers to uh
to time shared timeshared mini computers
um and so we had multiple transport
protocols
running over over ethernet we obviously
wanted a security solution or we wanted
a security solution
and what we came up with was that was
desnik
and desnik this is a drawing from a
from a pat from a from a patent uh
looked like this you had in encryption
controller boxes
which weighed about 20 pounds and
supported four nodes each
um and and each of them had enough logic
to keep the individual nodes separated
um
and so uh so information
uh would flow uh
there's the lost the cursor all right
well then
information would flow from um
from from uh from an end node say a1
up through encryption controller a then
through the transceiver and onto the
under the network uh down to encryption
controller n
um and then back to uh back to note n1
where it would
where where where the encryption folder
in
would decrypt it and it would uh flow
back and play
next to node n1 um and the four
i think it was four in nodes per per
controller
or a way of offsetting the cost of
building
this thing in in discrete logic um
we also built a key distribution center
which was basically the same
controller hardware with slightly
different software and data
and it would uh establish authorized
um and keyed connections
between that allowed say a1 to talk to
n8 if that was what it wanted to do
um and so it was it was a it was a
pretty nice solution and it had some
appeal
um but um
but there's always a bot um
and in in the desnet case it had both uh
what salter would refer to as
technological and fundamental problems
the the hardware was too costly and we
had performance problems um
and you know so that was our
technological problem um
the fundamental problem was that it was
a uh
you know sort of a solution to the to
the wrong
to the wrong problem the
deck net was going away terminal
concentrators were going away
um all the other vendor proprietary
networking protocols were going away
and the world was moving to internet
protocol and the right answer
would have been a software
implementation of end-to-end encryption
at the ip layer
which would have been would have been
great but if you said tcpip
within the bounds of digital equipment
corporation
that was what what you might think of as
a career limiting move
and so uh we really had to do something
that would work um that would work with
the
with the then deck proprietary protocols
um the desnet
[Music]
and people did you did in fact use it to
secure
ip networks but it wasn't a real success
because it was too expensive
and had a lot you know basically the uh
protocol independence
uh drove a solution that just wasn't
wasn't the right one for the time
so that was that was that was mistake
three
um by the time that
that svs was cancelled and
and the desnek actually made it to
market um
uh digital as a whole was going into uh
into a decline um caused
primarily by their i would i guess i
would say their failure
to pick up on the pc revolution failure
to pick up on uh
graphic workstations quickly enough um
and maybe their failure to get on board
with
uh without tcp ip networking quickly
enough
and so i left deck in in 92
worked for a couple of years with mitre
again and then joined trusted
information systems in
in 94. trusted information systems
had built with darpa funding um
an application firewall toolkit
it was a it was people didn't refer to
open source back that long ago
but it was basically an open source
deliverable that we put up on the web
and anybody could download
and use to implement a firewall for
their own use
we retained the rights to productize
gauntlet uh they are the the firewall
toolkit
and and our product was called gauntlet
and it was the firewall toolkit
code plus a little management software
um and at various points we uh
we actually packaged it with hardware so
you could buy a box
with the firewall uh software pre-loaded
and somebody would come out and
configure it for for your installation
um and it would be up and running um it
was reasonably successful
um but in the in the
in the process of of running that prod
uh that product uh i ma
made a couple of mistakes and they were
both connected
to you know sort of the the fundamental
principles
um of of having um
of having complete mediation and
especially minimal trusted code
you know we thought that you know if you
didn't have much software you couldn't
make many mistakes
um and so that would lead to a secure
solution
um and i made two mistakes both
connected to the sort of minimization
one of them is i didn't invest soon
enough or deeply enough in a fancy
management graphical user interface
um you know uh you had to go in and
configure the gauntlet firewall
by building ascii text tables
um of who could talk to who and what
node was where
what the ip addresses were and users
didn't like that they wanted to point
and click even by uh
even by 1994-95 and we didn't have
enough of that
capability soon enough uh specifically
when we ported
um the gauntlet ran on uh on bsd unix
when we ported it to nt uh we
there was one feature called network
transparency
that would basically let the system
detect
connectivity without much user
intervention without configuration
and we getting that on on the unix
systems was pretty simple
getting it into uh on nt at that time
would have required a complex hack um
that we were loath to do and we went
back and forth arguing with microsoft
about giving us an api to make that
function simpler they didn't do it in
the time
uh um in the in the time frame we needed
and uh so we we went with with manual
configuration uh rather than trying to
build that pack um those two things
sort of reduce the user usability and
acceptability
of uh of gauntlet and we probably
weren't enough of a marketing company
anyway
but the bottom line was that checkpoint
firewall one
which i think is probably still sold um
had uh had a a a really slick graphics
interface
had better nt support and they ate our
launch
uh the company was was sold about a
a year after i left and the product
rattled around the industry
probably 10 more years and then i think
it's now disappeared from view
so um sad story um
no excuses or maybe maybe maybe
prioritizing
prioritizing a set of security
principles
at the at the expense of the market was
a uh
was in retrospect not the right thing to
do
um another sort of interesting
interesting mistake in
in today's world um
had had to do with uh
with uh what was called a key escrow
system
i don't know whether you've followed the
uh
the the debates among uh
fbi justice department and so on and
uh and the civil liberties and internet
community
about law enforcement access to
encrypted information
but that debate has been around for
almost 30 years now
um and it started with a system
called clipper which um
was uh was a uh
actually it was a secure voice uh device
that sat between a telephone and the uh
and the wire i know it sat between
telephone handset and the telephone
and provided encryption but did it in
such a way
that there was an extra key involved
that was held by a couple of government
agencies and could be recovered
to break your encrypted communications
if the government decided it needed to
do that
um and that was was controversial
tis was pro crypto
export they thought that people should
have uh access to encryption
uh worldwide um thought that um
thought that um that that the export
controls were bad thought that the
clipper chip was bad
um and our ceo the late steve walker
asked me to invent a way
to invalidate a couple of government
claims namely that you the only way to
meet their requirements
was to uh use a non-public algorithm
implemented in hardware
and um and and to
and and to use um yeah those are the
requirements the non-public algorithm
and a hardware implementation and so i
came up
with a solution that implemented that
could be implemented in software
met the stated government requirements
and still provided
uh key escrow access
and a level of security for
for users within that context
when that happened when i came up with
that solution
our ceo who had previously been um
pro crypto export opposed to the clipper
chip decided that hey
maybe there's a market commercial market
for kiev for a key escrow solution
we'll sell it and so
uh we invested significant resources
um in building and selling a key escrow
solution actually one of the versions
was was added to the gauntlet firewall
with the aim of meeting customers needs
for being able to export encryption and
still having
having government license because the
government could could intercept
there's more to the story than that but
i think that's enough to give you a
sense of what
happened and um
in in the ensuing scuffle um
the investment distracted the company
from the gauntlet business
so we didn't we didn't invest as much
in in in graphical user interface or
uh ent implementation as we probably as
we should have
and then um after arguments back and
forth with civil liberties groups in the
industry and so on
the government abandoned the uh the key
escrow mandate
and that would although we claimed that
there were commercial needs
for key escrow uh the fact of the matter
is that you know once the government
abandoned
the escrow mandate all the customers and
um
and resellers abandoned the kiosk grow
mandate and we were left with six
patents but no uh but no income
uh so a less a lesson learned there
um in the process
final final mistake
is i think of as much more recent this
is the only mistake
that i'm going to associate with with
microsoft
um in 2002
um we we you know after
after some real the you know disasters
or at least
you know major embarrassments associated
with the security of windows software
um we took the entire windows division
and stood them down
gave them all training on
what we understood then to be
secure development
and then then
you know we we trained them uh for a
half a day
you know each every engineer got a half
day training
uh there are about 8 500 engineers sent
them off to
try to improve the security of the
product
and a lot of that worked very well
but one of the things that our training
tried to do
was to teach our project in product
engineers
to think like hackers and find
vulnerabilities and invent attacks
and it turned out
that a few could a few of those 8500
could
but both couldn't um and so
our our investment in teaching them to
think like a hacker
to invent new vulnerabilities from
scratch
really didn't work fortunately we had
other things
like running static analysis tools
looking for specific code patterns that
we taught them
building specific kinds of tests looking
at specific
uh configurations doing what what we
call threat modeling that's another
story
those did work so overall um
there were there were certainly benefits
from it
but um but we we assumed
that we could teach all our developers
to think like hackers and they'd all
find new classes of vulnerabilities
by understanding what a vulnerability
was
uh and that that just didn't that just
didn't pay off
we didn't get a payoff and
vulnerabilities
that corresponded to the effort people
should pay
uh put on it and they should have been
paying more putting more
effort on uh code reviews for for known
bad
patterns um either manually or with the
static analysis tools
so another lesson learned
so here's here's sort of the bottom line
that i've taken away from those um
from those uh 50 or so
years of of of more mistakes
i'm not sure more more mistakes than i'd
care to admit i guess i just admitted
them
uh you know the the customer's right
um even if the even even if
if you think the customer is wrong from
a security
fundamentals or what what he or she
should be
wanting um the customer gets to
decide whether they use your tech
technology or not
and that's um and that that turns out to
be really
really important i mean it sounds sort
of stupid to say
but when you're a security person you
think security
is is the thing that it's about and if
the customer doesn't agree
and you can't convince them then then
that's not going to end well for you
um usability is important i know people
spend a lot of time now on on trust use
user experience and secure usability
um and that you know that's that's a
that's a good thing
um it's something that i think the uh
the security field came to light
and is is very important um
security isn't everything i think i just
said that and talking about customers
um it's it's a balance um
something that i've learned a couple of
times both with the orange book
and and with the key escrow exercise
is that the government is
perfectly capable of promising you
that they're going to go in a certain
direction and that their standards and
requirements are going to create a
market
and the government is also perfectly
capable
of changing its mind or backing off or
granting waivers
so you really want to think carefully
before you decide that a government
security requirement
is going to create a market that you're
going to fulfill
um you know that's not that's not
guidance for government contractors
obviously
you know if they're paying you a
contract they're paying you a contract
but
if you're trying to build a commercial
product based on a government rent
mandate that may or may not end well and
you need to really think
you know how am i going to sell this
even if uh even if the
if the government changes its mind
time to market um is better than perfect
uh if you're fooled with security long
enough
it may have moved on and you may have
the best buggy weapon
in kansas or something and then finally
um think about what your your
organization
uh norms are
telling you as you're trying to build a
solution
um the norm at trust at uh
digital equipment was uh was
uh dec net and lat you know their
proprietary protocols
and the and the reality was we would
have been better off with
with ip the norm at
tis was uh was
was small you know small simple minimal
code
uh trust at all cost um and we would
have been better off
building a hack for transparent for
transparent firewall access
and building a big complex gui that
people
liked and would use to configure their
firewalls
so uh so a lot of a lot of challenges
as you're as you're planning and
strategizing uh
to to do something that is successful
and and my definition of success is
really something that people will use
that will help them get better security
not something
uh not something perfect that maybe
maybe nobody wants
so with that um i think i'm a little
longer than i had hoped to be
but uh got some time for questions and
smash said
that it's the last slaughter you don't
have to walk to your next class
so if we stop now let's take some
questions
can you see the question and answer
window there
steve or would you like to open it okay
how did how does how did how did okay
somebody asked
how to i'll do i'll do these
i'll do these unless we get overwhelmed
at which point
you know we you know i'll punt it punt
it to you folks
um how does bellapadula deal with
compartments those technically would be
pure levels above
uh top secret um so
um the
um it's a lattice is the is
is the the answer uh so you deal with
um you you deal with the security levels
as um you know thing as as integers
with a less than greater than comparison
and you deal with uh with compartments
as uh as um
as binary attributes they're there or
not and you deal with them by set
inclusion
so uh uh top secret
um apple banana dominates
secret banana top secret
um top secret apple banana
and secret cherry are incomparable
um is is that is that is that
is that an answer i don't know whether i
know whether people
can answer can talk back or whether they
have to uh
to type their questions but but if you
if you can if you can talk
if you can talk and you have uh
want follow-up uh you know either type
or hauler
thank you i was just uh typing the um
question but
yeah so basically you're saying that um
if i needed to
move a piece or copy or make a piece of
information available in more than one
compartments that would be equivalent to
applying an additional label to it right
it's it if you
if it the the compartment the
compartments are
are um or our orthogonal
um departments are orthogonal to the the
security levels
and they're you know they're a set of
individual attributes
and you can um and you know to
to read to read to read a uh
to read a document or an object with uh
with with compartments uh compartment
compartments associated with it you have
to have all those compartments on your
uh on your process yeah and basically
if if i needed to have information from
one compartment
accessible in another compartment that
would require an external it would not
be the user doing that but it would be
an external force that would basically
change the label or add an additional
label right yeah that's
that if right if you if you know
let's say let's say if i have top secret
top secret apple banana
and i want to share information derived
from that with somebody who
who only has access to secret and cherry
you know that's a case that i was
talking about
you know when i was talking about the
the model you know you you have to
you have to drill a hole in the model
somehow to get that
information through yep yep got it got
it thank you
okay other other questions
let's see that i've got oh okay
um yeah all right
um yeah somebody bill malik who is
the name i remember from the past in a
sense the government didn't
abandon the kioskrow
initiative so much as redirect the
funding to crypto ig
that's a different story bill
other other questions
well um i'll uh
i'll pop in here and um uh
ask if you could say a couple words
about
what safe code is doing now uh and what
you're enabling in the community
because you've you've retired but you've
not you're still at it so
okay so so safe code is an organization
been around for about 15 years and
we really do two things at this point
one of them is that we
we have our members work together
to share best practices and techniques
for building secure building software
securely
um you know you know what what kind of
what kind of testing approaches um what
kind of training
um you know can we can we work together
to build training developer training
that then
we can then use all use across the
member organizations
and the other thing that we do pretty
closely coupled
is that a lot of what we do is aim not
only for sharing among the members
but we make that public so
if you go to the safe code website
um there's a series of blog posts
that are basically an introduction and
recommendations
and trade-offs about using fuzzing tools
to improve uh
product security there's another series
that's uh underway as a matter of fact
i'm i'm delinquent reviewing
the next couple of posts about the
transition to post quantum encryption
um there's a series um
that's that's going on about uh
developer training what kind of training
the do developers need and how do you
how do you
how do you get and deliver that there's
a series
uh from about a year ago about
organizing security
champions basically people in a product
group
for the security advocates for uh for
for building uh for building products
securely
uh so a lot of uh a lot of of different
topics
all associated with soft buildings
software securely um and most of them
uh shared with the community uh
anybody basically anybody who wants to
uh who wants to download them or read
them or use them
that's great um
and i i hope some of the listeners uh
both in person now and uh for the
recording
do check out the site there is some
really valuable information there
thank you yeah it's um
lots of information look at look at the
blog look at the documents
a couple of a couple of longer documents
you know supply
supply chains another topic um there's a
fundamental practices for secure
development that
that uh folks might may find uh
interesting just in terms of you know
sort of what the uh
the sdl approach to secure development
has evolved into
well i'm not seeing any uh new questions
open up here
and so uh
we're at close to the end time and
uh no questions so steve thank you so
much for taking time to
speak to us today and i hope maybe we
can get you back on another occasion
maybe even in person
and that would be uh great fun to hear
some more about
lessons learned yeah i i'd
i'd be happy i'd be i mean the
the the lessons learned talk is is sort
of more historical i'd
i'd be i'd be i'd be happy to talk about
you know sort of as well about what
works and doesn't
in in secure development because i think
that's you know that's
that's possibly more you know more
relevant to today
and the and the way people actually
create and operate security programs
thank you for inviting me staff thank
you um
uh to the folks at sirius and looking
forward to seeing you again
all right all right everybody thank you
for attending and uh
stay safe bye for now
thank you bye
you