we are delighted to come back to sirius
this year to continue our journey
through
technologies that we developed over the
last several years
um the first one is called structured
data folding with transmutations
it is a secure messaging protocol
and then the second
technology that we discussed last year
was encrypted user data transit and
storage
and it was a complex data structure that
basically formed what we called a nut
container
this year we're going to show you
a nuts ecosystem that uses sdft and nuts
as a foundational layer
to enable this system and it's an
example of a data centric ecosystem
where
it's all about the data
and i am yoon al
the inventor of nuts uh nsdft
and i have with us so tyrios trantafilou
who will actually be um
operating the demonstrations
and showing us how this nut ecosystem
functions
i'd like to introduce our special guest
today
colonel robert banks
colonel banks retired from the u.s army
after a distinguished 37-year career
he previously served as deputy director
current operations of u.s cyber command
he also served as chief of operations of
the army global network operation and
security center
and he also commanded the largest army
helicopter battalion of 64 chinooks
covering eight states
and colonel banks provided significant
contributions at the joint staff
cyberspace division
the national counterintelligence
security center the army defense
industrial base electronic warfare
section in the asymmetric warfare office
national guard bureau
and co-chaired the smart grid
interoperability panel while supporting
the tri-county electric cooperative
amongst colonel banks numerous academic
degrees he holds a doctorate in
information technology from george mason
university
specializing in hybrid security risk
assessment bottles
he also holds a bachelor of science in
industrial engineering from texas a m
university a master of science in
engineering science electronic
manufacturing for the university of
texas at dallas
a master of science of strategic studies
from the us army war college and a
master of science and national security
and information protection and security
for the university of new haven
that's quite a list
on a personal note it was about five
years ago that i first met bob at a
cocktail party during dc cyber week
throughout the evening
bob kept coming back with curiously good
questions about nuts
so eventually we decided to meet for
lunch a couple of days later
it was at that lunch
the full weight of bob's service to the
country
and expertise in cyber security was
revealed and ever since then
it has been my honor
to know this patriot who continues to
play a part
in keeping our country safe
welcome dr banks
thank you very much and truly the
the privilege is mine to have um
you know
learn so much from
the opportunities as well as
you know uh the research that i've been
doing that has led me in the direction
to you
know as we we talked about my background
is one of curiosity i'm an industrial
engineer
cyber security is not just technology
but the process the economic incentives
which motivate people towards
alternative solutions
my washington cyber opportunity
had more tax in that year than all the
previous years combined
my research over several years have led
me to focus
on cyber economics
because i was just unsatisfied with the
answers that i had and
my pre-doctoral research uncovered um dr
arthur pal which you see his diagram
right here
um
you know he is a principal scientist at
bbn raytheon
and he talks about the generation of
cyber research
and at that time you know we were in the
third generation and i was in the big
board views of attacks just tolerating
all the attacks
i also got
in that research i got to meet a john
streifer he was the director of federal
national resiliency for continuous
diagnostics monitoring
which was my role there at you know army
cyber
i also met up with lieutenant colonel
ron
ross doctor at nist who led the phd
i'm sorry sps 853
publications which is still very
prevalent today
in intrusion tolerance i got to back
brief the lieutenant general three star
bob elder who stood up air force cyber
command
and he kind of jokingly told them he
says bob i want on your phd committee
because
you have the ability to explain highly
classified programs in plain language
that even i as a general could
understand why it's important and what
the program benefits was and and folks i
was just trying to understand what's
going to work what's not going to work
but but that still not satisfied
that has led me um
towards a philosophical view of the
problem where ross anderson defined it
as misaligned incentives information
asymmetrics and externalities
uh so okay how do you measure it
well you can look at the volume the
velocity the variations the veracity for
data at rest motion many forms and data
and dot well at rest
the hp study will tell you that data is
doubling
the verizon reports attackers are
successful um
80 or 90 percent of the time where we
only detect 20 percent
the semantic report 2015 showed over 430
million unique malwares or 2.6 million
unique web attacks every day
ibm defines most attacks even a year
later as unknown so my mit presentations
i ask
what's the equations for these unknowns
who's writing 2.6 million
unique scripts every day
so this led to the current generation of
cyber security uh where mit's lincoln
lab staff scientist dr hammond okra
rava
wrote the survey of the moving target
defense where he's trying to make it
difficult for the attackers
they have networks of dynamic host
configurations
platforms for rotating servers virtual
virtual servers
run time where the address space or the
layout is randomized but yet the
challenge still comes from the software
and the data
because of the benef because of
trying to randomize that
you lose the benefit of language
standardization
so obvious obvioscations or making it
more difficult requires more overhead
and costs
dr oak herrera defines moving target
defense as speed ups obscuration
but the challenge of completeness still
remains
they are siloed defenses as part of a
defense
and enterprise subject to the weakest
link
while we defend vertically
we communicate horizontally
we need a more complete solution
i think we need to define
the fifth generation
of security for data security
examples could be blockchain of a public
ledger and proof of the works
methodology to support supply chain
message flow which uses the data or the
business process for the insider threat
and it performs at micro speeds
now one of my favorite conversations was
on trade policies because
i took
a distinguished professor of
international trade stuart malware
and
general hayden's construct for
a forward way to
afford looking way to address the the
problem and it gets back to the
misaligned incentives of using
exterminalities
um
but
that solution of trade agreements
whatever it's not going to happen you
know
anytime soon so but there are
developments being it's being discussed
there are
publications that are coming out and
actually a book of you know cyber
operations from a legal point of view so
there is development moving but that
takes time
so
but what this leads me towards is this
this
asymmetric anomaly
that covers a large patch of data
security's overarching needs
you know for the real market and the
developing markets kovitz business is
now requiring security for increased use
of you know work at home ransomware
where they attack the data security
which this type of technology can help
rebuild it
because you're not centrally located but
you could take advantage of the
decentralized nature of the network
you know
this approach is rare because the
technologies in terms of the
bio-inspired that's
actually quite accurately more than just
a marketing slogan
so in in turns i'm very grateful for the
opportunity to learn what this product
does
where it's going in direction because
i believe it gets back towards the three
questions
that
uh dr ron uh ross anderson is saying
you know in terms of that the
misalignment sentence the information's
asymmetrics and the exterminalities and
lots i just want to close that
i have bookmarked these presentations so
um i intend to uh partake in many others
in the future because i think your
approach you know goes beyond just the
technologies but brings in the
frameworks that we're currently using
brings in some of the legal concerns um
because again i do not believe that the
challenge in cyber is purely
technical i think that the process and
the economics have to be considered
thank you for your time
thank you bob for uh joining us today
and giving us that great overview
of the feel from your unique vantage
point
and now we'll just continue with the
rest of the technical demonstration that
we're going to show you today
a simple question is to say what started
all of this
why did we create nuts why was nuts
necessary in our minds
and some of the questions that led to
that are things like how do i secure the
work files on my home pc how do i email
this attachment securely
um
you know how do i stop the admin from
seeing his pink slip um
how do i stop the cloud provider from
reading my stuff um
what happens to my files on the cloud if
they get hacked how do i recover from
ransomware
how do i minimize my email spam and
there's there's plenty more questions
you know
why am i always comparing files for the
most recent version um
if you've ever asked any of these
questions on the left-hand box
um they lead to
various technical terminologies that
have been
put out in this field of cyber security
and data management
and some of these are listed here on the
right side
and these are very
wide-ranging topics and terminologies
and they each have
various specializations it is a
complicated question
our solution to all those questions uh
or our attempt
is to
create a decentralized and distributed
system
that at the core is all about security
and making sharing easy
nuts is a bio-inspired system and we
propose that dna is data
and that
if dna is data then your body and all
the cells involved is a data model
and from that we
try to extract the
operating principles of the data model
and
design nuts around it to kind of mimic
that
so what we found out is that when you do
this
and you'll see it
today is that
that the ecosystem actually makes
computers work the way you think they
should
so when we take a look at
what drives the nuts ecosystem
there are three components to it
at the heart of it is an immutable data
container that is secure
and we call that a nut file or a nut
container
it has one or maybe more payloads and
it can contain anything that you want
whether it's text files you know word
documents
spreadsheets entire databases or even
folders doesn't really matter or file
system
and then what we
mentioned before is that we put in a lot
of metadata that's protected
some of it is clear tech some of it is
not
and
these characteristics are
extracted from how dna operates in a dna
data model and we put that into each nut
separately
so every nut container therefore nut
file has various protective metadata
that could help it
navigate
and
kind of enforce
and ask to be handled in such a way
and then the third part is
the organization of these nut containers
so we created systems
and sets of applications
that managed to
you know
deal with these nuts across diverse
environments
there are four parties in our demo that
is set up as follows
we have rachel the real estate agent
we have a buyer and seller named bob and
sally
and we have a banker named fred from
first bank
each virtual machine in this demo has an
up browser installed
and when you install the not browse on a
set of your devices we call this a nut
ecosystem
or you may also hear us using the term
eco group
and in this example here we have four
equal groups one for each party member
the notebook that runs on your devices
in your eco group is actually comprised
of four underlying applications
the notebook
itself which is a contact password and
key management system
the nut browser which is a user
interface for your net files a nut
server which manages all the local nut
files within your device and your eco
group
and the rendezvous server slash the nut
router
we discussed earlier but this is a small
local version
that decides whether uh internet files
need to stay within your eco group or it
needs to find other party members and
send the file to them
let's introduce you to the net browser
it's your ui it's the nuts equal groups
first you have your quick action buttons
at the top for your common functions
that you could access
you have your folder navigator on the
left so we call them fogs they're smart
folders that manage smart shortcut links
uh here you'll have your workspace this
is where you actively be working with
your nut files
to the right of that you have your
metadata window where you can access the
metadata of the nut itself
below you have your secure peer-to-peer
chat window where you can send secure
chat messages
and lastly on the top you have your
progress bars to show you the encryption
decryption operations of
the nut file
in our first technical example
rachel and sally will be exchanging a
data file
here we will show you the basics of
enough file and what it means to notify
how we encrypt data into its portable
and secure container
this is the heart of our data centric
design the ability to securely send the
data file in its current form carrying
with it all of its keys and protections
and securely sharing updates back and
forth between each person
so our story is going to begin with
rachel the real estate agent
representing and selling sally's home
now
before we dive into
the transaction portion of the of the
real estate process we're going to talk
about what a nut is so at this point
we've
kind of explained in this presentation
that we have this container called the
nut that it's portable and that we use
cryptography to
manage the
keys and the accesses behind it so what
i want to do here
is create something very simple
and what we're going to do is create a
file called some data it's just a simple
text file
and within this text file i'm just going
to put some type of
data in here
so just save
and here now is we have what you would
traditionally see is a file that exists
on your
windows explorer or file explorer
depending on the system that you use
now in the world of nuts
once you import this
this file into the system it becomes
what we call notified
and to show you how easy this is
i'm going to pick within my
personal management space i'm going to
go to sally
and i'm going to click on her here and
our options now is you can either
simply drag and drop this file into the
workspace
or you can right click select copy
and here now select an open area the
white space in the within the workspace
area
and you'll have an option to paste and
just go ahead and paste that and now
we're going to start the process of
importing the file
applying the encryption on it
and you'll see that end users
are able to encrypt their files
have them keyed and not have to worry
about any of
the technicalities around it and that
was it it's been imported into
the nuts ecosystem
now again this is enough file and to
look at what it looks like
you'll see that we have our original
document some data
and now we have something called some
data.txt but this is actually a dotnet
extension you could tell with the nut
icon here
this now
is going to live and this could be a
breathing document in the world of the
nuts eco group
one thing we could do real quick as well
is open this dot nut file and see what
it looks like
and here you can see
where we have its id
and again we stamp every
not file with a unique id
and that is an encrypted
document
opening it up back into the original one
this is what originally looked like
now when we say that it's portable
and secure
i could take this document
right click it
select share with
i'm going to share this with sally
and hit apply it's going to go through
the process of
applying the encryption that it needs to
encrypt it with the appropriate group
and it's going to share it with that
group and then send it off over to sally
and we'll look at sally's uh virtual
machine machine in a second
so here you go once a
document is shared within our nuts
ecosystem it goes from blue to red so
red means that you have a document
that's being shared with the outside
world whereas blue means it just resides
within your space
now let's jump over here to sally
this is sally
there you go here's the original sum
data
and i'm just going to add
more data to this file
save
and i'm going to close this up
so at this point
we've spoken about the ability to import
and encrypt the file automatically we're
able to perform a secure file transfer
from rachel to sally
by our group relationship here
sally and i was able to add some content
to this encrypted document
and what we're going to do here is we're
going to go back to rachel's machine
and we're going to talk a lot a little
bit about
secure
file and sync sharing as well
so secure file transfers ability to
securely transfer files from point a to
b
secure file in sync is what we call is
our version of collaboration where
you're able to not only securely
transfer the file from point a to b
but then points b c and so on and so
forth can actually make modifications to
that file and that file is propagated
and brought back around
to all the other members of the groups
that change that sally would have made
would have had two instances of some
data would have been the original
document then some data underscore
sally's versions or version two or
whatever
again but we'll get to that a little bit
later
where are the nut files
in this example we want to point out
that the sum data text file shown in red
resides only in these two eager groups
and nowhere else
this is a distributed system and does
not use a central server or store data
in the cloud
its portable data centric design does
not require traditional third party
services or dependent systems
as you can see here the file only
resides in two eco groups
rachel's and sally's
in our last seminar we showed you what a
nut looks like in diagrammatic form
and on the top left you see a very
simple nut configuration which is linear
in nature
and generally a nut is a directed
acyclic graph structure
composed of lock nodes
uh as the nodes or itself and the edges
or the connectors are cryptographic
links
now
there's many reasons for this type of
structure but one reason is shown on the
right side where we show you three
different
nut configurations of different types of
lock graphs
using
lock nodes
and by using these lock nodes in various
ways we could express different security
requirements of whatever payload or
payloads the nut is supposed to carry um
so in the end the nut is a container
that has a complex data structure
and within it it has sub data structures
called lock nodes
and next we'll show you exactly what
those knock lock nodes look like
at a
schematic level
each nut is a lock graph and a lock
graph is composed of
connected lock nodes and each lock node
looks like this
it has five major components in this
particular data structure
and
everything is
functioning towards protecting the bag
or the payload where you're going to put
your data in
now we have a universal keyhole for
every lock node we have something called
a variable lock there's three types of
locks in there which is the or lock the
secret sharing lock and the max lock or
otherwise known as the and lock
and
you have something called the stratum
access control and the nut access
control and all of these four
protective layers work together to
protect the bag or the payload
so what does
somedata.txt.net look like from our
previous demonstration this is a 7 lock
node lock graph which represents this
particular duct file
and it has this configuration where it's
connected in a different way it's it's
non-linear
it actually has five payloads at the
right hand side and you could tell that
in the front where level zero is we have
a nut lock so that's a lock note acting
as a gateway
and that is where all the key holes are
defined and
the proper combination of keys will give
you certain types of accesses into the
various payloads
now
the payloads themselves there's five of
them
the data that we were showing you is
actually going into the third payload
called the payload
block node and
these are protected in various different
ways and we'll go through that in the
next slide
you might be asking what about that
structured data folding with
transmutation stuff that you mentioned
we went over that last year as well as i
mentioned in the beginning of this
presentation
well
if you take a look at any of the lock
nodes
as a data structure
this is where we start using sdft to
enable what we call structured
cryptography
and
since each lock node has various
segments that can lock and unlock data
what we mean by that is it will
cryptographically cipher it or decipher
it
we need a more systematic
compact portable and embeddable method
of doing that and what you're seeing at
the top right
rectangle
is an example of a tar
instruction so it's a transmutation
audit record is what atar is
and in this one it's called b1 nonac
encrypt and dyn so
you know when we read down that
transmutation audit record press
serialize and code compress
s cipher digest and encode you could
almost read the recipe
of how
that particular payload within this
carnac lock node was actually processed
excluding the key obviously
and
and and you should be fairly familiar
with all of these types of operations
now
normally
uh data transformation
functions and
cryptographic functions are
generally not normalized together
here transmutations actually normalizes
them so that they could be used
interchangeably as long as you you do
operations in a sequence that actually
makes sense
so what happens here is that
we could now process
this payload
in this method of pressing it of
serializing it of encoding it
compressing it
symmetric ciphering it and then
creating a digest and then
base64 encoding it we do that that's
called the forward mode
now when we go when we're receiver or
we're trying to unlock this lock node we
do the reverse
and that's where the special properties
of transmutations come in is that we've
actually mapped the reversible
characteristics of any
data transformation or transmutation
operation that is reversible obviously
not all transmutations are reversible
but most of them are
and when they are we can do it so the
programmer ends up really just worrying
about
half the instructions because if you do
it right
the other half which is the reverse
process is guaranteed right now
here's another one so within the same
nut we actually have a different tar
operating
on a different payload and
similar type of lock node but in this
case we have something called the nut
access control working
and so that requires a different type of
locking
and here the difference is really
the size of the aes key
and that we're using actually a 10 24
bit rsa key to digitally sign
this particular message and that gives
it different properties of control
so
this is actually sdft in action and you
can see the lock node is actually
composed
of
secure messages and pieces of it can be
unlocked locked at will
in our next demo we'll cover with the
use of well-known cryptographic
techniques
how we can create history for a file
and manage its versions
digitally sign it
make it resilient and even pass urls
privately
we'll use the actors bob rachel and fred
working to sign a real estate document
start off is
we have a loan document and rachel needs
to see this loan document it's already
been shared amongst the group but we're
gonna we're gonna
represent this by having a three-way
chat
and rachel's going to ask them to please
send some documents
and of course she's going to want them
to sign them as well so bob and fred are
going to ratify these documents by
signing them and we're going to do that
in two ways
the first ways the first way we're going
to do this is
fred here is going to take his loan
document
he's going to open it up
and he's going to say
fred's
signature
he's going to save this file
[Music]
and we're going to let
replication occur now what we're going
to go through right now is history and
payload versions so we have the ability
to package multiple versions of changes
uh kind of tying back to the uh
synchronizing uh and sharing of files
and we're gonna demonstrate that here
right now so we're gonna go over to bob
here
here we have three-way chat bob has
received this message police on the
docks so obviously he has to
go about and make sure that he is
signing his docs as well so here now bob
is also going to
double click
on this file
now double click occurred because those
replications coming through
let me save this as well
so this is updating at this point as
well so here we are
we have
fred that signed the document paper has
also signed this loan document as well
sorry absolutely completed
the latest payload has been placed in
there
go to rachel
let's see where status is with this
replicating around she is version nine
double click on it
and here we are we have bob's signature
and fred's signature in here
now the cool thing going to history and
version control as you can go back
say open
and i could say history and show
a previous version of this
open specific previous version is what i
wanted to show not open previous version
that opens up the previous version so
here you can see all the changes have
been made fred signed it bob signed it
so here i could select this
version here open it up and say let me
look at it what it was before bob
touched it and at that point it was fred
that had signed it but bob had not
signed the document yet
and you could go and traverse back
through the history and the versions of
this payload
and see all the various
versions of this file here and
everything that's happened to it
now
that covers
payload history and being able to look
at different versions
and there's another way you can also
sign this document and that's actually
applying a digital signature now we can
go back here and have fred
say you know what everything looks great
on my end what i want to do is just
highlight this document here
i'm going to digitally sign it by
clicking on digital signatures
over here he could find his signature
enter his
obviously his password that he needs to
access in order to
sign it with a certificate and this now
is going to go through the process of
actually signing this file itself and
securing it and
and sending it off
to the other two people in the
group relationship
select bob here next
bob needs to perform the same action
there it is a loan document
came through
you see now that there's a signature
it's highlighted i could click on this
and i could see that
again this is a bob's signature here
that he signed digitally signed it
and bob's gonna do the same thing he's
gonna sign this as well
enter his password
and it's going to go through the process
of signing the nut
performing the encryption operations
again and sending it off to the group
so now
bob has signed this document digitally
signed the document as well
fred has done the same thing
and while we're working through this
we're going to come back to rachel the
real estate agent
and we're going to talk about this test
file so we're also going to talk about
data resiliency while this process is
going through and the documents being
passed around
one feature about nuts is its ability to
have data resilience and what that means
is that if you illegally tamper with
your nut files we have the ability to
bring them back to life and also be able
to preserve
the data that is in there so in this
example here
i'm going to delete
this file illegally
from rachel's desktop now this is a file
test file that was shared with
fred and bob
so
we're going to delete this
and this process takes a little bit
longer so
while this action has occurred where i
legally deleted it we're going to come
back and look at
check on our loan document this point so
now it's in version 11.
so we want to go and check the
signatures here
and here you go now rachel
can confirm that there's been two
digital signatures applied to this
document one is bob's
and one is fred's
so that has been validated so now we
just showed you that we're able to
digitally sign the document as well as
do signatures that are embedded within
the file inch and we could see either
the signatures or any changes to the
payload file through going through this
history
coming back to our next
little demo it was
the illegal deletion of a test file now
this process takes a little bit longer
because what we do is we have a method
in which we catalog every single nut
file on your system and what the system
does is every so often it walks through
all your nut files
and verifies as hashes and make sure
that the integrated files are correct
and they're there now in this example
here because i illegally deleted it
what's going to happen is it's going to
walk through its catalog
it's going to see that the actual file
the nut file is missing and because it's
missing it's going to say hey i need to
pull back the copy because the
file is supposed to exist in this folder
structure here
so what it's going to do it's going to
go off to
fraud and bob's
ecosystems and say hey i've shared a
file with you
i need to copy that file can you please
someone back over to me
so that is what's currently happening
under the hood here so while that
process is in flight there's one more
item that we could uh go over and talk
quickly about
once
bob has signed and completed his loan
documents
he has now purchased the house and of
course like any other loan
you're gonna have to start setting up a
portal to log into your bank site to
make sure that you start making your
monthly payments
now the one thing fred's gonna do here
is he has a bookmark
and he set up this bookmark where
it's a private
url
to their website
for bob to be able to access this portal
privately
so he's going to share this
with bob
hit apply here and we're going to let
this
url
uh
go through the process of being shared
with just bob himself
so while that is in flight we're going
to go back and check on rachel real
quick and here you are
the test file has come back so
i illegally deleted this file the system
said hey there's something happened to
this data
supposed to be there he didn't tell me
about it he went and fetched and brought
it back so this is part of what we call
data resiliency and again the ability to
keep your data in place think of stuff
like um like ransomware or an insider
threat that may
uh be someone that decided to delete a
bunch of files off your machine or
ransomware they may have encrypted that
file you just delete it and the system
auto recovers it for you
now to go back to
bob here
so here we go now to bob's
world his eagle group clicks on his
relationship with the bank he sees that
fred shared a private access link with
them so
fred prefers this link to be opened up
with
internet explorer and what you're going
to do is go double click on this and
it's going to take them to this private
site
so this is now a private bank site this
is a privately shared url that fred said
that bob
this is a complete random url at the top
here just to highlight that
so in the world of internet you can make
this completely private
no one has to see it
you don't have to have him go to first
federal.com to set up a login site he
could be sent a very private url
and here i'm going to just go to and say
hey i'm bob i'm logging in and here you
go he's accessing his account online
directly with the first bank
and that completes demo number three
where are the nuts
as mentioned in the previous demo all
the files chats and urls reside locally
in each actor's eco groups
to recap this demonstration
with history we can retain all versions
of the files chats and urls for
providence and audit trails to the use
of our cryptographic techniques
with digital signatures we can place
these into the payloads of enough file
in a particular version as a signature
by one of the actors
think of it like a confirmation
the use of digital signatures in this
example is different
as the traditional use of signatures is
used to detect tampering and forgery
which we already covered through our
data resiliency example
as you know data resiliency is a hot
topic in cyber security
our secure data center container
carries with it its history and access
control so it can protect itself
lastly
private portable data structures that
are identifiable like are knots
can be used in the private url sharing
example
here with this technique
we could show that instead of having a
dedicated public home page that people
need to go to we were privately sharing
this url with a certain person
public home pages as you know that are
dedicated are subject to ddos attacks
and hacking attempts
we can even throw around and entertain
the idea and concepts of url rotations
kind of like key rotations
when we demonstrate this ecosystem to
various audiences
we
we get a common question and the
question is
is the nut router necessary
um some people have suggested that
there's stuff that we're keeping in the
nut router that makes the system work
that there's a centralized database
somewhere that we're holding all the
nuts there
that we may actually be holding keys and
in order to prove
that the nut router is not necessary
we started a little project called
remora
and
in this case what we do is we actually
show you that the nut router is
completely unnecessary
and that all the information that's
required to make the system work and
throughout the ecosystem
is the source nuts themselves and that's
it
and so
fun things happen when source nuts
collide source nuts that have identical
ids collide
and it's how we deal with that collision
that makes all of this stuff um
you know fascinating and and it actually
allows it to work
so
here
what we're we're saying a couple of
things here by this example we're saying
that
the nut system is transport agnostic
it is completely independent of any
centralized services including an outer
and any mode of transporting nuts
will
give it its full functionality
our project memorial demo takes us to
rachel and fred collaborating over a
sensitive document
here
i've selected the fred from first bank
relationship that rachel has and they're
collaborating with over a time sensitive
document
and
there's a
denial service attack that has suddenly
started to occur
on the cloud provider that hosts their
nut router or rendezvous server as we
also
may call it
and from what we've mentioned in
previous demos
there's this router that helps
you package and send
the nut file from one equal group to
another and in this demonstration here
we're going to show you how we're not
dependent on that
service at all and that we could pick
any type of medium to transport our nut
file over from one eagle group to the
next
and in this demo here we're going to use
uh gmail so what i'm going to do first
is
replicate
the outage
of your cloud provider by
turning off the rendezvous server
now this is a cloud hosted rendezvous
server uh just to mention you could also
have your own hosted rendezvous server
as well so desired and you can see on
the upper right hand corner here that
it's turned from green or red
so now we have
rachel only using gmail as an option to
communicate this time-sensitive document
now what i'm going to do here is i'm
going to double click on it
and we're going to continue
collaborating
by adding more data
and
the eco the notebook is still going to
go through its process of encrypting the
file with its updated payload packaging
it and wanting to send it off over to
fred
and it's done that and it's going to
find its medium to send it over to in
this case
like we mentioned earlier running the
servers down because of the cloud outage
and we're going to use gmail instead i'm
going to come over to fred now here's
fred i'm going to
take a look at his gmail and here we go
here's a file that's coming from rachel
i'm going to click on it
and it's a nut file
it's
encrypted
this file contains all of the access and
key management systems that we've
discussed in other demonstrations as
well as the payload
file version histories and all the
metadata
i'm going to minimize this here i'm
going to open up
his
notebook and you could see here that
i've already turned off
the rendezvous server because there's an
outage and i'm going to double click on
this file
and here's add more data
and we're able to use alternative
methods such as gmail
or any other cloud provided service or
any other email service or any other
mechanism so to speak of being able to
pass data back and forth
the last feature we'd like to leave you
with today
is
we asked a very simple question
who said history has to stop at the
present
and we call this project carnac
remember karnak is carnac the
magnificent and it was a johnny carson
character
that sometimes could tell the future
anyway
we saw the example where you could
actually delve into a nuts history and
you can see the revision um
versions in the ba in the past
and then you could resurrect it if you
wanted to and change it over
well
question begs to be answered is who said
history has to stop at the present that
is
that is the conventional thinking is
that history stops at the present
we took it further and once you once you
change that perception
it becomes
where the future
is really a calendar and if you take it
into the computer world
that is called
you could put in a scheduled event
so we actually see
the previous history of revision
histories as a continuation of a
timeline where you're just standing in
the present
and everything behind you there are
virgin histories and that's passed and
everything ahead of you
is possible future events
therefore we gave every nut a past and a
future
this is nuts
in the carnac demo we have a file named
text records.txt
as you can see right here
and we're going to do a
couple of things here we're going to go
to metadata
and we'll select view event calendar and
with this file today what we do is we
select the option of deleting it
and this is our seven year retention
policy
so this thing is set at the corporate
level and this is something that
compliance
requires
to delete
and everyone's pretty much familiar with
what that means uh so here we could date
this uh sometime in the future in this
example i'm just gonna date a few
minutes ahead but it could also be dated
to
be performed
seven years into the future
now we're gonna select this to apply and
let this apply and take hold
and again we're applying this metadata
to the nut file itself
and uh
to remind everyone a nut
file is because it's portable
that entry carries with that nut file
wherever it goes so this isn't a setting
that
is set to activate on the system itself
that requires this particular notebook
application or this particular nut
server
this event is placed in the nut file
because of its portability to go
anywhere that it needs to go and carry
it with it in this example here i've
shared it with ewan in the group
relationship and he has a copy of this
tax record with the exact same retention
policy as well and
now here we're going at the
the time is up it's going through the
process of deactivating this next
tax record
out of the system
this nut file should no longer exist
within the eco group
and it's deleted it and that is karnak
the data centric ecosystem that was
demonstrated today
can unify your data
in a way that
very few if no systems that that we know
of can do this
and it goes across
almost any network any operating system
that could support nut software
um and any hardware
and therefore
your data is everything and everything
else gets commoditized
it's a very very unique
type of technology
that we believe shows a different
approach
to how we think about data
and that
once we start thinking about data a
little bit differently like this
it starts doing a lot of things
on its own
with permission
it is data that is intrinsically
protected both at rest and in transit in
a consistent fashion
and that security is actually portable
and under the direct control
of each user
where they hold the keys
where do you store the keys you store it
inside a nut where it's secure
so
the nut itself kind of gives you that
recursive nature almost like a fractal
behavior
and
it's a very elegant scheme
and you could see that benefits are many
and the promises are very cool
here's the familiar reference models
from the osi and the tcp conceptual
layers the osi has seven respective
layers and the tcp has four of them with
their equivalences
what we started realizing when we're
working on nuts
is that
it not starts acting as a type of data
operating system that sits on on a
higher layer so it is a series of
applications
obviously it uses transport and network
layers
but it is where the data is king and
it's the data that's protected from end
to end so
it is a little bit more than end-to-end
encryption it is beyond end-to-end
encryption and um
we started thinking of this as how does
it fit
in these models and
maybe you know we thought hey you know
maybe this time to quest a question
whether this model needs to be extended
for
a
ecosystem like the one you just saw
today
so this is a this is a good thing to
debate on and
and discuss but
i'd like to leave you with this and
you know we're open to any questions and
thank you for
coming to the seminar today
great great great job great presentation
um attendees if you have questions you
can go ahead and use the q a button
it should be located
in your zoom
window
or raise your hand and i can turn on
your microphone
okay looks like we have one question uh
from eric it says uh how does the nut
router make routing decisions
so
that's a very good question um
the nut router obviously has to keep
track of
ip addresses while while there's
connectivity because
we have to work through the nat walls um
which still exists for ipv4
um
we're moving to ipv6 but that's that's
two decades in the making so someday
we're going to all get there but not
today
and
so the nut router does make dynamic
tables for ip addresses ports
in order to route it back
but in essence the main driver of the
routing is these nut ids and a nut id is
a 512-bit shock to hash
it's practically unique there's no
guarantee of uniqueness but with a
512-bit number
it's um it's large enough to be
considered uh practically unique and um
we actually route based upon that um
and whatever ips that you tend to be
coming in from
uh from any number of computers in your
eagle group it'll just map it to that
but really you're just working with that
ids
okay we have another one um
for remora
how does the software know what email
address to forward the nut to
so
um
i think you saw that part where uh some
tiers showed that there's a rendezvous
server switch and a gmail switch
so for the demo
we put in a gmail thing and then part of
the configuration for that user in that
duct browser is to put in your
your
gmail address
and also i think it may require you know
for you to get an
api key from gmail as well but also
you'd be asked for the um login
credentials at that point so that your
nut server running locally in the
background can connect to um
your gmail api and and submit that email
on your behalf
there any more questions
does not look like there are any more
coming in but yoon
so so tiara and uh bob i you know i'd
just like to thank you guys for
uh presenting today i really appreciate
it uh i think what you're doing here is
uh pretty powerful and pretty uh pretty
amazing you know and
a very important need i you know that i
can see that a lot of
businesses are looking into and you know
are definitely going to need in the
future
i think one thing that i could leave you
with as an overall comment like is that
um
what we're trying to do in one way
is that
you know companies and systems out there
want you to use their resources their
services and in some way monetize that
um
our feeling for one of the motivations
of the technology is that
you know we carry in our pockets immense
amounts of uh storage that and
processing power that that doesn't even
we hardly ever use uh but for the most
part it's the title
and what nuts technologies is what was
created for one of the motivations is to
try and make use
of your own resources as much as
possible as much as you would like
so think about all the laptops and
desktops you have at home
that may not be the cutting edge but is
still clearly capable of storing your
data in a redundant form so that
we make more efficient use of it and not
get charged twice or three times for the
same space
on the cloud drives
um or
you get three cloud drives but the the
bargain that you strike there is that
they get to rifle through all your all
your data for free so
this is a different way that you know i
started this mainly because
i felt a severe frustration with the
lack of ability for you to really use
your devices and resources to the extent
possible that they're being
underutilized and why do you want to pay
for more and then why do you want to
give away your data that you've
carefully collected
and should remain private and um so
that's that's kind of the overall you
know um
you know reasoning behind this and i
think
most people who who we've spoken to when
you when you talk about this motivations
they they readily agree that
um it is a problem but we've almost
gotten immune to sort of
realizing these are still problems
so i'll leave you guys with that
great great thank you so much really
appreciate it um
and you know we'll be looking forward to
hearing more uh
about this technology and from you too
and you know
hopefully we can have you guys uh visit
us on campus too at purdue uh in the
future when things start opening back up
uh we'd love that and uh you know we're
always open to uh
educating um you know at any point
great great well you guys take care and
stay safe right thank you thanks bye
you