good afternoon and welcome back to the
22nd annual serious cybersecurity
symposium
uh it is my pleasure to introduce the
next our first panel discussion of the
event uh but the idea of this panel
discussion came out of conversations
with a number of our our partners two of
them who will be participating in this
panel discussion and as mentioned
earlier by our director professor dun
young shu
is that he often refers to these to
these areas as cyber plus
cyber alone doesn't really matter it's
cyber plus
and so cyber plus arrow is an area of
great concern by many within the aero
industry the travel industry and can be
expanded to astro and train and
everything else within that area it can
broadly be even expanded out to almost
anything that is cyber physical but
certainly there are some unique
attributes to the aero industry when it
comes to cyber we joke that uh
as important as cyber automotive is if
there is a problem you can pull over
it's a little difficult for an airline
to be able to pull over if they're
having a cyber incident in flight
so with that it's my
distinct pleasure to be able to
introduce our panelists
so
john bush who is the product security
engineer at boeing
michael ghan the chief of technology for
product cyber security at rolls royce
professor berkey chellick who's an
assistant professor of computer science
here at purdue and insecuring a
professor of astro and aero engineering
at purdue
and our moderator for this panel is a
professor dan hurleman who's the
executive director of international
advancement and a professor of
mechanical engineering dan
it's yours thank you
thank you joel and it's great to to be
with you all today thanks for joining us
a great
couple of presentations earlier and
thrilled to be involved in the first
panel
as joel said we have a great group of
panelists
but our topic is aerocyber
aerospace
aeronautics aviation
and embedded systems and the resource
constraints thereof and certainly
all mobile systems i think have embedded
attributes and that ends up with
resource constraints on energy
on memory
power
all those things and so
and that's a challenge because our
threats our cyber threats are often
working in unconstrained domains with
very large resources to go after us
especially nation states
and so that translates to significant
challenges for designers
and operators of of these systems so
that's generally the topic uh for
today's
panel
very briefly there is a an organization
a new one that's just stood up that's
related to this area uh it's called it's
a space ice act space information
sharing and assurance center
it's been going for about a year
purdue's a founding board member and
several of the
serious members on the founding board
are northrop and lockheed
microsoft boeing's on the board i
remember
raytheon applied physics lab
and there's only two universities purdue
being one on the founding board and that
group
works in this area kind of an industry
centered
activity whereas sirius here at purdue
is more of an academic centered activity
there's a couple of working groups in
that
i co-chair one on our research and
technology for
cyber physical security and space
systems and one on workforce
and so i snuck in a couple questions to
ask our panelists about those two things
so if you're interested in that
that organization google space isac or
email me or chat me and we'll
talk about it
but before i introduce the panel
uh let's uh
the format for today we have an hour
my five minutes is about up so we'll get
down to business here in just a minute
uh we're asking all of the panelists to
give us a sort of a position statement
two or three minutes
share their perspective and position on
this the challenges of resource
constrained
embedded systems for
mobile aero and space systems
um
after that uh
i've
shared a set of questions with them that
we'll try to go through maybe informed
by some of their points of view and
that'll go for 20 or 30 minutes
and then the last 10 or 20 will have a
chance to
take audience questions and i assume
joel and i will somehow
co-handle that and get to your questions
as well
so with that let's start through our
group and again thank joel thanks for
introducing this this uh
this group so john uh boeing i'll turn
it over to you and for your uh
introductory remarks
all right thank you very much can you
hear me
okay
awesome so
i'm john bush
i've been in boeing commercial airplanes
for
30 plus years
and i've been in cyber security for 10.
so we've been
working along just like damn was saying
we actually founded
five years ago an aviation ice sac that
got put together to concentrate on the
aviation piece
of the information sharing and now you
know with
with space
the thing about
really in aviation
cyber
is just an attribute you know like they
were saying cyber plus arrow it's really
the other way around it is
functions and then cyber we're using
this technology
to effectively um
do the functions that we want to do so
the emphasis is very different you know
it
you know it's an afterthought 10 years
ago was like we don't want to know about
cyber you know lots of hacks have
happened people have got their credit
cards now the question is what are our
cyber requirements
and it's very different in the aviation
world because
at boeing and an oem we work at a very
airplane level set of requirements
but cyber is down at the implementation
and so you have people using the same
language but they talk a lot so a lot of
it is about awareness trying to get
people to understand and stuff
the other thing about aviation is like
when the ground communicates to the
airplane
it's via voice
there you know there is some digital
communication but
nothing about encryption nothing about
message authentication or any that and
these things have been around you know
voice since the 40s
uh digital communication since the 80s
now we've got adsb there was just a
mandate on that there's no encryption in
that signal there's no authentication in
that signal and it's
just been mandated so cyber is really
an attribute that is growing in aviation
and has to be there
but
you know it um
it's gonna be you know we're still at
understanding the big context
you know down to the details of doing
that and so it's it's a very interesting
area you know i'm glad we're having this
seven this panel to talk about it
because i think it's gonna be very good
uh back to you
thanks so much john and now i'll turn it
over to dr jelick
from purdue as well
hi everyone uh thanks for being here i'm
bertie selig i'm an assistant professor
in the department of computer science at
purdue university
so mainly uh my research investigates
the design and evaluation of security
for software and systems specifically i
focus on emerging competing platforms
and the complex environments
in which they operate
so my research approach is basically
best illustrated by the my work in
safety and security of internet of
things and cyber physical systems
also in robotic vehicles and automotives
uh so i'm very glad to be here we have a
couple of projects going on
what i see is uh recently
the aerospace industry have well
recognized that they need they need to
move faster
towards the digital feature
so this means that the companies adapt
technologies by using different sensors
and
actuators from different manufacturers
and also they integrate some edge
competing or cloud computing
technologies which drives the efficiency
and correctness of their products and
services
however during this process
these developers or the system designers
needs to understand the system in detail
as well as they need to have some
set of security skills in order to
make the trust and their track models
very accurate
so that they can understand the trade
space of their
products and developed
some efficient techniques against them
however this is challenging because
these systems are oftentimes very
complex
and
on the other side uh the people who are
designing this mostly focusing on their
efficiency maybe they are eliminating
the some designs perspective that would
make these systems
safe and secure
so i see that there is a gap here
additionally what i see is because these
systems integrate multiple different
components which are able to work in
both digital and physical domains this
also introduces new attack factors to
the adversaries and new challenges that
we should consider in order to create
efficient defenses
great thank you thank you so much
our next uh panelist is
michael gahn he's a mechanical engineer
which proves emmys can do anything i
think
um fellow mechanical engineer and uh but
also he's really the executive sponsor
for our purdue rolls-royce phd cyber
fellows program and and the consortium
so
thanks for all you do there mike uh and
turn it over to you
oh uh thank you dan and thank you on
behalf of rolls royce to be on this
panel today on this important topic so
when you think of rolls-royce i i'd like
you to first think of power and
propulsion systems such as jet engines
and not as cars
even though we share the same name and
logo so
i just set the stage there
our customers on the defense side with
the department of defense in the u.s and
the mod in the uk
and civil uh within faa and yasa are
fortunately increasing our cyber
security is as important as
as john recently kind of
mentioned
and our latest announcement on the b-52
win on the commercial engine
replacement program
there was a threshold requirement on
cyber security that that you needed to
meet even to be considered as a
competitor on that program
so
it is absolutely an attribute that's
growing within aviation and aerospace so
um
so i'd like to uh just mention a little
bit about myself so i've been at
rolls-royce 14 years and as dan
mentioned i am a
mechanical engineering and aero engineer
by trade and i've only been in cyber
here for a few years um but prior to
that i was with the u.s air force in the
u.s navy so
um
and and it's uh i'm it's great to be
here talking about this
subject today um because our
collaborations with universities and
governments are what are going to or
what's really going to enable us to move
forward and secure the aviation space
great thanks thanks mike and
now professor wong
hi um i am enzo quang in the school of
aeronautics and astronautics and my
research area is autonomy and controls
and especially focused on the higher
insurance autonomy for cyber physical
systems with the application to i mean
the other department so the aerospace
applications
and my focus is on the cyber physical
systems and our traditional systems are
typically physical systems but nowadays
due to the rapid advancement in
computing sensing communication
technologies
our
used to be dumb system becoming ever
more intelligent
and to be intelligent they are relying
on sensors on both sensors and
communications
and this opens up the door for
the new challenges in the area of cyber
security as john just mentioned he's in
the air department so in aero industry
so the airplane traditionally we don't
care about cyber security i never heard
about cyber security when i was graduate
students for example but now the cyber
security getting more important in this
area because
just like iot airplanes gets connected
to other airplanes and also new types of
airplanes now and will be operating
thing soon such as the unmanned aircraft
system say for say drones
or the uh air taxi that we call the uam
urban air mobilities and personal area
vehicles and all sorts of different
these vehicles
and highly rely on autonomy and this
autonomy again as it says that relying
on on-board sensors and communicating
information
from the ground control station or from
the other vehicles surrounded in the
neighbor
so
the different from traditional cyber
systems where the computer science
the scientists work on a lot and the
information security for example
encryptions authentications all these
and in these cyberphysical systems if
you lose security or breach it is a part
of the security
uh then
not only we lost uh we lose the
information and more importantly
we can suffer from the property damages
and even human losses because airplane
can crash want to hit the other
airplanes or hit the building just like
911.
so the if you consider the how
dangerous
the system could be if serious cyber
attack happens breached into the our
autopilot systems
the our systems again this is also
applicable to
ground system too the intelligent cars
and then
and there are many
accidents incidents and you know
simulated incidents that hackers can
crack into the uh automobiles control
systems and you know stop the car and
accelerate the car hit the buildings and
all sorts of things can be possible but
unfortunately so far
the
cyber security never ever been seriously
considered so the uh the communication
channel for example
the uavs and the urban air mobilities
even the commercial airlines
they use the narrow only voice
communication channel growth data link
he mentioned the john mentioned the adsb
is not encrypted at all and also drones
using the
the specialized communication protocol
or link and bevel link is not
encrypted at all either
so
the again this opens up the doors and
then since i'm in the
autonomy area and controls area
different from the traditional cyber
security again such as encryption
authentications my interest or interest
in this autonomy domain is that can we
design an autonomous system for
including the
uh health monitoring system of the
physical system and the autonomy
controllers even mother-based one or
nowadays ai-based ones can it design
such algorithm can still operating
within the allowable range under cyber
attack if there is a cyber attack system
is vulnerable can it tell
by analyzing the system even before they
are implemented
and then the next step is that if cyber
attack is feasible
can we
how severe certain type of cyber attack
will be it can crash the airplane it
just slightly perturb this attitude i
mean severity widely varies
at the same time
then the if attack is possible can it
detect it some attacks are well designed
in a sophisticatedly designed such that
you can bypass the monitoring system we
call such attack as a stealthy attack
and third attack can be designed
possibly designed by placing a game
monitoring system
and so if so can we design the
monitoring system more sophisticated
country
and also eventually that can it design
cybertech resilient autonomy control
algorithm such a way that even if there
is a cyber attack system operate more or
less safely even though the performance
may be degraded but still
they operate and then safely you know
land and that sort of thing will be very
important and that's what is my research
area thank you
thank you
uh so now we're going to a set of
questions i'll try to help balance it uh
the first one's uh
i know we're all running as fast as we
can to stay even
uh but if you took out a crystal ball
and kind of looked ahead
what do you see coming in the next
handful of years few years in terms of
trends are going to change
in some way the job that you're trying
to do so
let me start with john and
mike
from the industry's perspective of what
trends do you see that's changing the
job you're having to do
so
a lot of what's changing is just the
awareness of cyber security
and the regulators and the operators the
environment that we work in
is becoming much more aware that we
cyber is
a
a major threat issue
and the fact that we have been
transitioning
our data more the airplane systems to
commercial off-the-shelf airplane
systems when i started as a young
engineer we had these things called
errant buses and they were aviation
specific just made for aviation
now we are using ethernet and ethernet
based
things that
you know are are where all the
vulnerabilities are and using operating
systems that uh
are based on you know commercial
operating systems versus very unique
ones that we used to use and so there's
just gonna the the threat surface is
just getting much larger and
and
more functionality so i think that's the
big trend is that it's it's just going
to be more impactful but what is really
important is to really understand the
context like professor is talking about
attacking the control services we have
so many layers of defense
that
that would be very very difficult on a
big commercial airplane on a small drone
in some of the urban air mobiles maybe
not you know there's
and that's kind of an area you know
where there's going to be all these new
entrants that are going to want to use
commercial off the shelf and that
and we have to be really
diligent in our cyber
work to make sure that those those
things stay safe so the whole air space
is safe because we all share the air
space there's only one air space so
it's gonna be you know it's gonna be a
challenge and good
indeed hey thanks john and my first
internship was with boeing working on it
database in fortran so i go back a ways
with you
yeah
who did you say dan
um
okay
um so from our perspective there's uh
two different engineering uh mindsets
and skill sets that are converging and
this was hinted at by one of the
professors here
one is safety which is deliberate in its
pace and cyber which needs to move
move fast to keep pace with the
attackers
um so there's no easy solution of how we
handle this
uh
the differences arise not only from
engineering teams that develop and
design but that has to continue through
the verification validation
uh testing and evaluation through
in-service operation however we need
both not just one or the other
and i'd also like to point out that
in aero we have
very large lifespans in our products so
common consumer electronics and iet
equipment are expected to have
be supported for five to five years
maybe ten
our products are expected to continue
flying for 20 plus years and even longer
on the defense systems uh sometimes up
to 50 years
so what technologies threats and
capabilities and strategies will be
present then
and then uh
one positive trend that we have is that
increased focus that john mentioned uh
from our customers in the industry
coupled by our ability to make very
bespoke systems so
i'll end with that
great thank you thank you um i want to
move on we'll we'll have the faculty
take on the second question for us and
then of course if john or mike if you
want to jump in this is about knowledge
gaps
what what's hindering us from doing as
much as we need to do today and in the
future on
uh assuring uh these space cyber
global
transportation cyber systems
and what's the are the sort of the
research and technology needs that can
help fill those gaps uh let's start with
uh you professor chilling
yes so sure this is a um
great question so the gaps right the
knowledge gaps
so what i see is
in order to secure a system
we need to first understand how that
system operates right and we need to do
this in detail
at both the system level and also the
application levels
thereafter we need to conduct threat and
trust model assessment by asking a set
of questions
so these questions might be
like what are the assets that we are
trying to protect right what kind of
threats um that might be this system uh
face
or can we envision any feasible attack
that would violate any our security
goals
so mainly the answer of these questions
is called a chat model
a characterization of threats that the
system must deal with right
this will
after we define the threat model this
will enable us
to identify fundamentally new algorithms
techniques and tools to design
and build and operate these techniques
in order to have secure systems and
protect our critical infrastructure
however
there is a gap between understanding
these systems
and
also the training and education of the
individuals about the security
of these systems so that they can ask
the right questions right
so without without having this
understanding
we are missing some threat models
or we are missing some parts of the
threat model that
kind of uh prevents us from developing
efficient techniques
especially i see this gap in aviation
because
maybe the institutions or students do
not have access to this type of
like the real operating devices or their
test pads or their simulations at all
right
thank you so
okay thank you
could you uh weigh in as well
yeah i i agree what the
berkey said and on top of it i want to
say that
cyber security as i mentioned the
psychophysical system cyber domain
traditionally computer science
the area and then the physical systems
aero mechanical you know
domain so multithis plenary effort is
the uh the gap we even though
some of the problems are very
recognized by both communities their
language is quite different and turns
out to be that we are talking about the
same thing but we could not understand
the others ideas and concepts because of
these language differences
and then the awareness as john mentioned
that the now the awareness growing in
this autonomy group
and so that the uh the our students get
more used to
or exposed to
the computer science concepts and ideas
and how the system is operating as well
as our traditional domain of the
physical systems you know dynamics
differentiations and so on but many
times students lacking that all the
different conceptual model is used and
concepts use the different mathematical
tools used in the computer science so
bridging the gap is the uh typically
what i have encountered by interacting
with the uh industry you know the
national the agencies people
and then the uh our students
so the interdisciplinary organization
these plenary aspects
i think is nowadays the gaps that we
have to feed
thank you uh now mike and john let me
say if you had
one silver bullet to fire at a gap
somewhere in the technology
domain that you deal with what would you
fire it at
so i don't think there is one silver
bullet and
10 years ago
that is what all the managers were
asking and that's what industry was
asking what is the one silver bullet
and
cyber is a is an onion and there are
different layers and different pieces so
um
you know
we
the one thing i wanted to say to you and
all the students is
cyber's still so new in aviation and
stuff
anyone here that's taken a cyber class
has more formal in
more formal education than i do
i have never had a formal cyber security
class and a lot of people in in aviation
don't have that
so this is a great place to come in and
take that knowledge even if it's just
and really understand the context and
understand because we deal from anything
from supply chain
chip vulnerabilities up to big systems
talking you know systems and systems
and all the things we have all these
different layers and it's really hard to
say one thing i think awareness is
really okay you know it's not a
technology but it's really something
that's important that i think everyone
still has to
has to be able to figure out
all right mike you get a silver bullet
we don't know where we get it from but
what are you fired at
i i i'd like to echo a lot of the things
that john mentioned um you know aero
cyber embedded systems are
are not like it systems and
we usually have bespoke processors and
modules do the environmental constraints
that these things fly in
and they're much more resource
constrained so a lot of the common
security approaches that
that are out there they need to be
developed adapted and integrated into
our systems there's nothing that's
really bolt on so
um and i i will absolutely second the
lack of any kind of cyber uh formal
education
um and uh
because uh a few people on our team do
have that but not many um and uh and so
there's there's a lot of unique r t
needs and it covers the whole gamut of
the nist um
uh cyber security framework from protect
detect or identify react and recover
and uh and i think the the key thing i
i'd like to uh stress is
uh because it's so new
um and and uh you really need to have
the people that we're looking for need
to be good communicators have good
emotional intelligence because a lot of
times it's as much of an influence
campaign
across all the different disciplines
that that go into building that system
such as the supply chain or the
different uh components of the aircraft
uh in products um and and having those
goods uh eq skills and good
good communication skills is very very
helpful
okay thank you
all right i'll switch to either i'd like
to
i like the eq skills i think is
extremely important because we are a
cost
that's a resource limited thing and so
if you're doing cyber you're not going
to do some functionality
and so your job as a cyber person is to
basically say no you can't do that you
have to do this
so eq is really important i it's a thing
i wish i would have known 30 years ago
in school because i would have taken
more classes on that because
that especially with cyber in aviation
it's really about emotional intelligence
that is really important and being able
to
talk with everyone and understand what's
going on and being able to influence
people just by talking is really key
great
okay the next question is about uh the
asymmetry between the threat actors
and our embedded systems and and the
teams of people working on them so
how do you see i mean you're surmounting
that
challenge these days but it's only going
to get worse how do you think about that
asymmetry how fast the threats are
moving how fast can we move
and i'll just open it up if you uh want
to jump in on this just
wave or start talking uh and
uh
take an opportunity to
add to this
i'll wait to get it going um
i think one of the things at least in
aviation and around airplanes and how
airplane systems are put together is
that we really limit the threat surface
so there are very few
entry points for people to get into the
system
so even though
the hackers are going much
faster with
unlimited resources and that they have
very little ways to get into the system
so it's so
that's one of the things but
just like we found you know when we
built the 787 it was
inspect in 2004
it had like shaw one hashes
now
you know in the 20 20 20 that is not
acceptable anymore and so it has to
change so we do have that you know
legacy thing that
um
airplanes will need to learn to change
much faster but we have a slow
deliberate safety process that has
proven and driven out
accidents over the last 50 years so we
need to continue doing that you know and
be very diligent and how we split that
up so that
because that hackers are getting much
faster and better and stuff so we have
to limit our threat surface and be very
cautious and deliberate about what we
allow it to happen because you don't log
into an airplane
to fly it
now you will with utms and so that's
going to be a different thing you know
there there's a whole new market where
that's going to happen but right now on
when you go to the airport your pilots
aren't logging in so we do have that
safety built in and so that's sort of a
the embeddedness
turns into an advantage from that point
of view you naturally have a smaller
threat surface so i guess that's a plus
an upside thanks that was a good one
anyone else want to talk about the
asymmetry and its trend and how we
battle it um so i would like to add a
couple of things here
even though uh
like as it is said uh the trek threat
surface might be
um like smaller than the other
traditional competing platforms but what
i would say is
uh there are like many different threat
actors
but i guess particularly in aviation
these threat actors might be the part of
the advanced persistent threat groups
which are very sophisticated well-funded
and strategic groups right
in that sense i guess uh
so we should not underestimate
the the the attack surfaces
um by just saying that you know it's
difficult uh because uh we we are
recently seeing that
uh these uh apt groups uh advanced
persistent chat groups can able to
attack uh the water treatment plants or
the power plants etc after like
uh working uh many many many years uh or
um
even applying some uh psychological
attacks to some workers uh in order to
you know like use them as a stepping
stone
uh to go inside and
the companies or their software systems
great thanks
any other thoughts on that
question
i think one of the you know when i think
about
what can we do to help uh help with that
is we have to be agile and able to adapt
and this is not just from technologies
or methods
uh or designs and software sort of
perspective but also from a team's
perspective
and in our thinking as well uh so
you know the systems we ship are
resource constrained but you know the
whole of our business is not
um if we limit our view of security to
those things that are
in our products alone i think we might
be unnecessarily limiting ourselves in
ways that our attackers aren't
that's interesting yeah
and for me uh the aviation domain also
grow very rapidly by incorporating
varieties
of different types of vehicles including
drones
and so to accommodate this many drone
operations safely especially urban
environment
the concept called the utm uas traffic
management system is proposed similar to
atm education systems but this is more
rely on the
the technology than human
so different from the uh traditional
commercial airlines their systems are
the data link connected
and also the registrations or you know
data driven and so on so that it is more
vulnerable to cyber attack than the
traditional uh the aviation domain so
that's a growing effort so the one of my
projects sponsored by nasa
is the how we design a utm system in
such a way that it is not only safe
as safe as the atm system but also is
secure
so that the uh
safety level can be maintained just like
our traditional legacy very safe
aviation system
great thank you
um like to it was brought up a bit
earlier in a couple but i'd like to then
go to kind of the workforce education
and training
what uh what changes you know some
things have happened over the 30 or plus
years that
some of us have been out but
what are your recommendations on
workforce
development in
how the universities is one element of
this but of course continuing education
and others
what are your recommendations on
workforce going forward
so um i think i think one of the key
things um and it's been mentioned a
couple times already is we need a cyber
informed workforce
and so it's not just people with cyber
and a job title but it's software
engineers electronic engineers soft
systems engineers and program managers
and business people
we need to reach outside of our typical
cyber majors and help and help other
skill sets see how they contribute to
producing
secure systems
um and i i think from a you know this is
really akin to the cross-functional and
cross-disciplinary nature of sirius you
know that you guys pioneered and uh
insecurity here
we also need to continue the
collaboration between industry and
academia
and
this not only helps solve the hard
problems
but it it helps it introduces students
to the types of problems that industry
faces
and gives them uh practical experience
while developing a talent pipeline so i
think that that hands-on
work is will be very critical especially
in this near term as we try to
staff up to address this problem
john any comments from the boeing
perspective or like your perspective
yeah so
we've been hiring people left and right
and so we've just you know we've been
talking about what kind of training do
people need and where do we need
with
us a lot of it is understanding our
aviation context and how
aviation regulations and stuff again
we're using the computer technology to
do functions to fly airplanes to
communicate we're not using it for users
to log in and
surf the web and stuff
so
it's an embedded system and so
even though yeah you have authentication
and authorization it's used very
differently and being having
you know it's really systems engineering
is really a big thing so having
understanding the whole systems of
systems and very complex
and being able to describe it in detail
is really important
you know
the
you know the cyber piece and
understanding that i mean that gives
such a great foundation for people for
system engineering and stuff but again
being able to look at other people's
perspective is really clear because you
have to influence people and you have to
understand what they're doing because
they won't have
you know you go talk to some of the
works tcas or in-flight entertainment
they have no idea they understand oh
yeah it's network together there's an ip
address but they have no idea what that
really is going to mean from a cyber
standpoint and people that have the
knowledge you have to explain that to
them so really be learning to be a
teacher and explain these hard concepts
to people
is really kind of a key
a key piece and that's probably not you
know it's not all the academic classes
it's the part of being a a full engineer
you know and a total person that's
really kind of key
thank you
insult you've been uh leading
in well i say adding a cyber informed
mindset in aerospace engineering for
example what
how's that going and what are your
thoughts on going forward on
changing our education
so uh the
still struggling in the sense that the
our students say for example the
students are
i mean is this really aero engineering
stuff right this is computer science
stuff and why we have to pay attention
to this type of one so get them
motivated it's very important part
so
today
and tomorrow and the day after tomorrow
we have this special show course that
mike francis who's retiree from the
darpa and the lockheed martin and so on
he is teaching this autonomy
in the history of autonomy in the aero
applications that kind of a lecture
special lectures could be good for
especially for undergraduate students
who
do not have any motivations on this
autonomy in general specifically cyber
security and get them exposed to the how
serious autonomies are and then how
important autonomy is in aero industry
along with the cybersecurity and also
the by nature of this multi-disciplinary
aspects so students getting some courses
from say the computer science department
and stat department and also ece
department i mean the aae 2 and me too
so it is opening some of the the class
requirements open to the other
department even across the college of
engineering and college of science would
also help enhance this uh this cyber
focused
uh education
and so that's what i have found and we
are trying to
to uh to achieve you know from the past
and the next few years so
okay you come from the computer science
side and i i know you have
students from other majors in your
classes what are your what are your
perspective on this
interdisciplinary mindset
yeah sure it isn't going forward
um i think uh this is uh extremely
important topic and
uh it pays off uh in like five ten years
right we need to execute something and
then
we will see the benefits not immediately
but later on
um so there are multiple ways which i
believe that uh the education and
wordpress
of workforce training can that we can
follow so i would like to give you a
couple of examples
uh for instance
i believe that like both academia and
industry uh may work with like some uh
k1 teachers
right in order to introduce these high
school students some computer security
or these emerging team technologies
maybe this can be integrated uh to their
curriculums or there can be like some
corporate visits that you can show
around and um because these are all
young generation uh i'm pretty sure that
there will be like multiple students
will be influenced uh
on on these uh the the the content and
also the visits as well
uh such an uh computer security literacy
uh would provide some opportunities uh
such as they would in the future follow
some uh stem career pathways right
um also even though they don't follow
this at least it will give them an
awareness of in the context of societal
implications of security and how these
systems are used
secondly like in the university for
instance we have like a lot of
theoretical concept that we we teach
in our classes however like seeing a
kind of like a real
real world example or maybe it's just
like a test patch system
um or its simulation what i see is
students really learn fast and when they
apply the theoretical um
the topics that we have seen in the
class to those systems
uh such as you know like finding a bug
or making a plant stop working
um they really enjoy this and they also
work like teams with teams of groups
um
i see that uh
this will also allow these students to
look for jobs not directly going like
software engineering to the big
companies but looking for other
opportunities
maybe just working in that domain in
cyber physical systems so as a faculty
uh what we do is we are trying to you
know like get some
some systems some test beds
to our laboratories uh to give a
hands-on experience we use these systems
for research
also try to integrate these systems
in our courses as well and whenever
there are like some opportunities in our
department um like aspiring girls or
sometimes like in summer high school
students comes and visits art department
we kind of demonstrate these systems to
these students in order to achieve the
previous goals that i mentioned
thank you
um
now we'll turn to the
the audience uh and
[Music]
put in your questions in the chat uh
but first if if the panel has any
questions they'd like to pose to one
another that's you can jump in as well
but there is a question
uh that's come up about
i guess it'd be
prevention shall we call it so
global laws should
can laws
related to cyber crimes and uh
cyber security can they make an impact
in this
domain in your
in your opinions
so i'd like to say laws
well
hackers aren't going to follow the laws
so i don't think it matters what really
matters to us is
what the
is getting the right regulations so that
we design cyber safe systems
and we get the law makers and regulators
to understand to have a better
understanding of
what cyber is and how it is because it
it really is a different
viewpoint in a different reality
safety is all about functional hazard
assessment
10 to the minus ninth is safe it's
deterministic cyber's not deterministic
it's going to be the same emerging thing
that we have with the autonomy and the
ai
and that type of work you know we're
going to have this fundamental shift and
that's what's really exciting about this
is that
you know fundamentally we're gonna have
to shift over the next five ten years to
a different way of viewing things and
cyber is just one piece of it that's
gonna be very interesting
agree john
um
so if you had to guess
and i'll let you take this question in
whichever direction you would like but
in the next five years and so certainly
long term but not an extreme long time
where is the area that you have that you
believe is probably going to have the
most advances in cyber security for the
aero industry uh i bring this up the
which spurred my question is that
mike gone rolls-royce and i have been
working on a couple of projects that are
looking at adding ai systems to cyber uh
intrusion detection with some of these
systems but but we've had some very deep
conversations on
what what are the areas that we're not
thinking about that may have tremendous
asset to aerocyber so uh if any of the
panelists have uh have comments on that
so i think from an overall aviation
industry
the the what we talked about with the
urban air mobility and the utm
because that is computers working with
computers to keep people safe
and currently like i said with air
traffic control
we we basically keep people safe by
people monitoring something and people
talking to each other
so this whole shift to where it's a
computer talking to a computer
is going to be the area how do we do
digital identification there is no
standards no international standards or
any kind of standards for that
you know we just released a system
uh adsb there's no authentication anyone
can spoof it
you know we cyber hasn't been thought of
i think that's the big area is that
cyber will get in
into these different areas and the atm
utm is going to be the first area that's
going to
pull the rest of us dragging with our
heels in the sand
into the
cyber uh digital world
interesting comment john i i relay that
to some conversation we've had with
other serious partners that are not
necessarily in the arrow more in the
astro and actually some in the air
motive and very interesting thoughts
that actually align with some of these
others that are dealing with
as i returned to my opening comments
this cyber plus what is some of these
other areas that are not in i.t that are
dealing with these things
um
in such i know that you have dealt a lot
in there what in your research you
seeing that may be areas of potential
gains
that we could see within the next five
years or so
um so the two things one is the
application domain in aero industry that
the i chunk in with
john
so uam utm and atm areas are the
fundamental areas that we can see a lot
of improvements in there
and these are mainly the as you
mentioned that the mostly
automation-based operations
and then they are everybody connects to
everybody opens the door no
communication protocol there are there
are communication protocols but no
encryptions and nothing safety security
measures taking place they even though
they are now start looking into the
problems so some advancements and then
the government setting up the uh some
regulations and the rules and the
guidelines that
and so the industry and research
institute and then academia work
together to come up with
technologies to to address those those
areas and another one is that the
now
machine learning ai based technologies
has been advanced so far but at the same
time our systems different from the
traditional the ai domain for example
the
phase recognition there is no dynamics
but the airplanes follows vehicle
follows newtonian mechanics we know that
for last 300 years why we ignore it as
if we do we do not know anything
and then we so the i'm thinking my
perspective is that the this model based
approach plus data driven approach
and each method can complement each
other's work and the model driven
approach traditional analytically driven
approach has a lot of good things in the
sense that we can prove its property
we can guarantee the properties
mathematically not just the simulations
but machine learning based one if it is
working well it's working right but
nobody can say it's definitively working
in that way under any circumstances
that's very very very challenging area
right so formal education validation
place has an important very important
role especially air industry
certification is big part of it and
certifying something is very very
difficult so that area will be a very
very important area and we can see some
advancements if there are any
significant advancements in in those
areas
i i would say that any sub industry
would welcome the opportunity to have
some cyber metrics that actually
quantified exactly how secure we are but
that's another that's a topic for
another panelist
yeah so uh
burkay uh in computer science i i and
i've had the uh obviously the pleasure
of getting to hear you talk before and
some of your specific research but when
it comes to hardening controls or the
control systems for these some of these
zero systems is there an area there that
you think we can take some monumental
jumps in the next five years or so
um yes
um first of all um
i mean uh it's all technology what we
see recently is being like automated
right
um however like uh in aviation
because they are
exposed to physical domain
right there are many uncontrolled
uh i would say noise or environmental
factors right so this kind of makes
very difficult to model the correct
operation of the system so once we have
the correct operation of the system
anything deviates from that correct
operation we would say that either this
is cast by an adversary or maybe this is
a fault right
so what i see is
um
because we are trying to make everything
automated we need to also
test these systems in order to see their
operations are correct however
historically we also know that these
systems are complex
so
it's very difficult to model these
systems or it's very difficult to verify
whether a property
or requirement holds on the system or
not this is because it has a very huge
input space and there are some
linearities and the systems are
non-deterministic and also they have a
hybrid nature right
so what i see is the model based design
the model based abstraction of these
systems becomes very important which i
see that recently they call it like a
kind of digital tv as well in some cases
right it's a kind of virtual replica
that you can run
and then see
the real operation of the system and
this virtual replica
are like correct or deviates from each
other
of course this requires a set of
technical skills like how we can
abstract how we can analyze the source
code and then create a model and then
after we create the model how we can
ensure that this is realistic and how we
can develop some approaches in order to
run on these models to test these
systems
um so models has like multiple different
purposes that's what i see
and this model is basically um
extracted from the the source code
because the source code manages its
behavior
in that sense
the model design the program analysis
techniques
um
the fuzzing techniques in order to find
these bugs and formal verification
techniques in order to ensure uh formal
safety and security guarantees
i think becoming extremely important
because we cannot just give inputs and
test these systems it's not safe right
and the input space as i said it's very
huge
mike i want to change up the question a
little bit for you um in that
uh sirius and purdue is is very proud
and pleased to be part of the
rolls-royce cyber technology research
network uh along with our peers at the
scilab at carnegie mellon and then a
university to be named i know in january
uh uh very exciting but this is a
monumental program that rolls royce has
decided okay we're going to partner with
just a handful of universities who have
deep expertise in air oh cyber to help
address these problems so
from your perspective as kind of the
program manager for this entire research
program you know what are your kind of
those intermediate five year out what
are you hoping that that uh that we can
solve i i don't think that we're going
to solve all of the cyber security
programs for the aero industry but what
is your what are you kind of considering
this low-hanging or maybe not quite
low-hanging fruit but that you're hoping
that we can make monumental uh increases
in in contributing to the uh the
security the cyber and cyber physical
security of roll rolls race products
uh that's that's a good question so um
there's a number of different areas that
that we're interested in that could make
big changes
uh in in the security of our products i
think
you know there's different components to
that
you mentioned the ai bit
it was mentioned earlier mbse and
in digital twins those are all areas i
think are are right for uh for research
and that could make a
make things especially in these embedded
systems that that fly around
uh much more easy to to understand if
there is an intrusion in the system
and
but they are complex and and those are
not trivial
problems to solve
um
there's also um
i think that um
i just lost my train of thought so
apologies there um i i think that uh
um
the uh other pieces that that we're
looking at
um that one of the key foundational
pieces is
architecture um and
and it it it hits um from both the
certification side um that safety versus
the security side there's lots of things
that that we could probably do better to
help help be able to move at pace of the
attacker while maintaining that that
critical safety
aspect of our stuff
of our products
well thank you all um i think we have
hit the
the ending point here i i really
appreciate
each of the panelists bringing your
expertise to the table unique
perspectives and i thought it was a
great panel so
thank you all
uh turn it back over to you i guess joel
to set up the next
panel right thank you dan and thank you
for being the moderator on this a very
interesting panel
you