all right well welcome to another one of
our
uh weekly security seminars
and this week i'm really pleased to
introduce
our speaker jack daniel
uh there's a lot of things that can be
said about jack
obviously one of them is he definitely
is one of the great beards of security
you can see that yourselves uh
jack has had an interesting path to get
to
security but one that has caused him to
really appreciate
when it works among other things he's
a uh an advocate and champion
of security and the community at tenable
and is really responsible i would say
for a lot of the growth of the b-sides
conference
he's well known as a mentor a speaker
and a curmudgeon
and i'll leave it at that and i'd like
to uh turn this over to
jack daniel so jack please you and your
cover fish take it away
all right well thank you very much i i
am uh
honored to be here this is uh great and
i have to
have to either thank and or actually
thank and or blame
you spaff uh you were instrumental in me
making this
uh project happen but let's let's
dig into it so the important part
i started out as an auto mechanic and
stumbled into
management and they made me take care of
computers
i haven't been at this is a security
focus
as long as a lot of people think and one
of the things that we love
about security is that it's a challenge
many of us
are drawn into security because of the
challenges
although often times we find ourselves
thinking
i wanted a challenge this is a little
bit more than a simple challenge
but there we are so
let's go in a completely different
direction
if we think about popular music of the
past 100 120 years
it's pretty easy to find some threads
and pull on them and see some history
one of my favorites is surf guitar
you can go back a century and find
middle eastern
mediterranean folk music and then find
in the 50s 60s
up until a couple of years ago dick dale
mining that for
some incredible surf music based on
things like havana gila
and miserloo the movie pulp fiction
years decades now ago reignited the
interest in that stuff but that started
with folk music and somebody's saying
let's take folk music in a completely
new direction
you know we can uh look at the migration
of blues from the
mississippi delta up from acoustic blues
through chicago blues
into electronic blues and rock
and roll it's easy to follow that up
uh peer of dick dale's was link ray
somebody asked him to improvise a song
once in the 50s as he and his band were
changing from being country to
this newfangled rock and roll and in a
single song he
gave us the world's first power chord he
started doing some rudimentary shredding
in that song
at the end of it he twisted the vibrato
knob up on everything and got some weird
electronic
effects uh and paved away between dick
dale and link ray
for heavy metal for uh
rock and roll in general but heavy metal
in particular
you know a few years later the sonics
who aren't that well known there was
this song called uh
strychnine where singing the joys of uh
drinking poison for fun
that laid a path that went through
punk it went through grunge long before
grunge
uh you know the easy one to pick on is
the velvet underground right it
who knows how many bands were formed by
the
velvet underground initially they
weren't a commercial success
except with musicians who took it in
different directions
and you go back you know you come
forward another decade or so from there
i remember
in the late 70s a band or a group called
the sugar hill gang
gave us the song rapper's delight which
just
launched the the public acclaim
and altered the path that just paved a
path for rap
hip hop and it goes on and on
um you know it just it just keeps
going and we can go all right so the
disclaimer here wikipedia
is wikipedia but sometimes it's a good
starting place for things
uh google your you know you ask
wikipedia for your favorite band or
genre
um they're they're documentaries the
documentary about muscle shoals is
amazing
uh there's one on electric guitar called
it might get loud
bbc radio 4 did a documentary on the
song
summertime from its original porgy and
bess
incarnations through the decades to
being a brazilian jazz
standard to janus's you know ultimate
blues rock cover to being a civil rights
anthem of sorts
uh recently smokey robinson did a thing
for audible words and music
that was was amazing to see where he had
come from and the
things that he was adjacent to
so what's your point jack
do that with what we do tell us
who these people are what their stories
are
so there's a question that does come up
obviously you know
why why look back
and as it says on the passenger side of
your car um
you know those those things in our past
really aren't that far
back there they're a lot closer than
uh you might think and a lot of people
reinvent things that have been done
many times before so let's take a look
at why we don't know them
things were different
information security information
assurance
cryptography were part of what you did
they weren't an industry unto themselves
really um
for a long time you just did it it was
part of the job
um an obvious one is we just can't keep
up
part of the drive to do this talk was me
recognizing that
how much how little i knew and how
important it was that uh some of us make
an effort
to help tell these stories
um especially while some of the
first-person accounts are available to
us
but when you enter this field you run to
keep up and
the opportunity to stop and look back is
rare
so i try to do this as a way to make it
easy to look back
and find some things and keep us
aware of where we came from a lot of the
foundational work uh
isn't on the internet um if if
if if a paper falls in a university and
google doesn't index it did it get
written
well the truth is it did but it makes it
hard for us to know what came before
um silos unfortunately we haven't
cured this one some of it is for
um valid reasons but there are a lot of
silos a lot of things happened
in the military a lot of things happen
in the civilian side of government a lot
of things that happen in academia
aren't always well known in industry
and vice versa
a lot of folks are no longer active
obviously some of these people have uh
passed along before us
many here uh have decided to retire
um but we don't get to see these people
there we go
uh for those of us like me who do a lot
of conference
stuff a lot of folks are not on the
conference circuit or at least not in
the conferences that we're on so it's
easy to
just not see them and if you don't see
them you don't think about them
so we'll start out with some names that
you know and let's talk about
um them as as actual
people though um
so everybody knows alan turing okay no
all right it was a pretty good movie a
few literary uh
license takes but uh alan turing i'm not
gonna dwell here that he's well known
but alan turing opens the door to having
conversations about people like
doc keane it was called doc because he
used the leather's doctor's bag for his
engineering tools
touring didn't come up with an
engineering
blueprint for creating the bomba he had
ideas he was brilliant
he knew what needed to be done but it
took this engineer
to translate that into
something that could actually be built
and then supervise the construction
and it took people nuts and bolts and
solder to make that actually happen
so not to take away from touring but it
took a lot of people to make that stuff
happen and some of them are
are forgotten the history of bletchley
park is full of overlooked people
um henrik zykowski
jersey riziki marion rajewski
this was a trio of
polish mathematicians and cryptologists
and they came up with this perforated
sheet called the zagalski sheet
before world war ii this was able to
uh speed breaking the original or the
earlier enigma ciphers
this required um
the upgrade to the enigma that required
the bomba to break that it required
touring and crew to to do what they did
these people are
unless you're a crypto nerd um or into
history
these are these are not people whose
stories are known but these people
did amazing things beforehand
sticking with world war ii um
julianna mikwits born julianne
charlotte ernestine von miquitz uh
that probably tells you there's an
interesting story right
talk about her a little bit because
she's not well known she was born in
to finnish and russian parents tutored
at home in russian german
and english before she went to school
she and the family escaped from the
bolsheviks in 1919
uh went to poland uh joined the u.s
military attache office
escaped the nazis in 1939 eventually
arrived in the u.s
joined the army security agency the
precursor to the nsa
she is described on the nsa website as
being an innovative linguist who is
a prime advocate of new ways of
exploiting language materials
and developed highly invaluable
intelligence information at a time when
the u.s
lacked other sources so um
there's somebody that you wouldn't have
expected but there's uh
it took a lot of people to do what uh
what happened
we come forward this is one that um
is a story that i wish more people knew
being someone who hangs out in the
hacker crowd
as well as the more professional crowd
there's a lot of conversation about
ethical hacking
hacktivism
and things like that if you don't know
his story um renee carmel was
a punch card expert he was
a worked in the french census bureau
before the
um before the war and
during the war after uh the germans
overran france and established the vichy
government
rene carmel um cooperated with the vichy
at least that was the initial appearance
he knew more about punch card systems
than almost anyone probably knew more
about
manipulating the systems than even the
people in ibm
through manipulation of the census
we can't know how many lives he saved
we know that he saved a lot of jewish
lives
undoubtedly saved some eastern european
slav
roma lives um
and he did it at a great personal risk
this one i am sorry to tell you doesn't
have a happy ending
this one ends with his capture
imprisonment and death at dachau
so um sometimes
people break things for valid reasons so
he's he's one of those heroes that i
wish more people knew about
uh let's move forward elizabeth friedman
so
i have to say i'm conflicted about uh
elizabeth
um she developed her
linguistic and uh code breaking skills
during prohibition
and as someone who likes to occasionally
enjoy a fine glass of rum or
uh whiskey this frustrates me but she
was doing what she was doing and
enforcing the law but the great thing
was that a lot of that
illegal liquor was coming in from the
caribbean central and latin america
when the war began
she was the best resource we had
she came from the coast guard and she
was transferred to the navy
and she knew how people communicated she
knew the networks and the communication
lines
she led to the u.s being able to
intercept and compromise the contents of
an enormous amount of
german correspondence that was coming
through latin america
it was incredible due to her earlier
work
friedman's team she built the team which
decoded at least 4 000
messages sent on over almost 50 radio
circuits
so she is another one who came from that
she and her husband
went on to do a lot more uh crypto nerd
stuff but she's one that we we don't
hear about too much
so let's talk about some better known
people uh diffie-hellman
right everybody knows whit and
marty new directions and cryptography
changed
the way we communicate on the internet
the idea of exchanging
keys securely in an insecure environment
was a
was a stunning problem um the
diffie-hellman key exchange continues to
secure
our internet um was it sun forever
and his motivation was and you know he
cares about individual
rights and privacy thus the interest in
cryptography
marty is also interested in physical
security he continues
to talk about the dangers of nuclear war
he's been a
it was an early advocate of the beyond
war movement and to this day runs the
website nuclear risk.org
these are actual people with actual
passions they're not just names that you
have to
memorize to take a test now this is an
interesting picture though
because somebody's missing
um ralph merkel was a computer scientist
one of the co-inventors of public key
cryptography
the inventor of cryptographic hashing
he's later got interested in molecular
nanotechnology
and cryonics he is a foundational figure
that is often overlooked
but was a key part of that as you can
see from this uh
this dashing trio here
here's another one you know these names
they're not in order here but in case
you need a hint
they're in order here and uh
these are folks again it's not just an
acronym
it's not just a company ron rivest
invented several symmetric key
algorithms
uh authored md hashes
um interestingly long ago
he was concerned about this
integrity of voting can you imagine that
glad we solved that one huh um he
created something called the three
ballot voting system which doesn't rely
on cryptography because ron rivest says
i don't think we can trust crypto with
voting it's too important
our democracy is too important um it
allows for
anonymity but also uh verifying that
your vote has been counted
adi is one of the inventors of
differential cryptanalysis
um lynn besides his theoretical
computing science
and crypto has worked on uh
dna computing using biologics instead of
silicon
these are amazing people that
we're working on they're not just an
acronym they're not just that
but here's a question um
how about this guy james ellis
in 1970 so that would be before
rsa and diffie-hellman um
he was at gchq he was at gchq for a very
long time for those i assume most know
but that's
more or less the british version of nsa
um
and he had some thoughts and he put him
down on a paper internally and he called
the paper
um uh it was written about non-secret
encryption it was this idea
that you could um have encryption
in a non-encrypted space you could trust
things in public
um spaces
crazy idea a year later
two three years later couple years later
uh clifford cox
uh joined gchq brilliant mathematician
fresh out of university they weren't
sure what to do with them
one of the first things they did was say
here's
james ellis's paper what do you think of
this
well he came up with some stuff he
discovered some things and
created a few things
symmetric keys and some ways to do
things securely
and we now refer to everything
not everything we now refer to a lot of
what clifford cox
discovered and created after reading
ellis paper
as uh rsa
he went on to invent identity-based
cryptography
he i believe retired from gchq
he eventually held the title of chief
mathematician at gchq
which meant he probably could figure out
the tip at the pub without
a calculator a university mate of his
was malcolm williamson he joined
just after clifford cox
another brilliant mathematician uh
same thing what do we do with the new
guy yeah give him give him ellis's paper
in 1974 he thought about the challenge
of starting with an insecure environment
and came up with a way to securely
exchange cryptographic keys on an
untrusted network
a couple years later whit and marty
figured that out and it became and has
ever since been known as the
diffie-hellman key exchange
obligatory dog appearing in there so uh
none of this was declassified until 1997
and i really like to tell this story for
a couple of reasons
one um
there are a lot of really smart people
that pre-date us that have thought of a
lot of stuff that
we haven't thought of and maybe we
should think about it
but the flip side is what really matters
is what we do
with what we've done this stuff stayed
inside gchq and got
very little practical use at all ever
what the better known names did
was work out how to make it work and
change
the internet and the way we communicate
forever
so a little bit of humility but you know
what what you accomplish matters
a little humility um
tidbit james ellis passed away before
this was declassified
so it was one of those interesting
stories of
earlier construction but it couldn't be
shared
so let's let's now travel back in time
this is not
francois or louis blanc but it's a
french semaphore tower it's a recreation
of the symbol for tower
system that france used for
government only communications these
towers were all across france
back and forth up and down and they were
used
for government and military
communication only
uh francois and louis figured a way to
put
messages on
and get their messages across the
country and
it basically required bribing an
operator
to throw a message on and then
back off so there was a basically a typo
key you could
send a signal and then say disregard the
last letter
but what they would do is one would
place themselves at say a port city the
other one would be in paris at the banks
or exchanges get a message about the
state
of shipping about ships about battles
whatever they were trying to get
and they would game the stock market
they would game the systems
um and so they were subverting networks
uh and because these are clear these are
open in the air
you didn't have to necessarily
compromise both ends you just had to get
the
the message on the wire and then maybe a
pair of binoculars or telescope you
could see it yourself
or you could bribe somebody at each end
to subvert the network
they were arrested and this is for those
of you who have followed or
into the hacker history they were
arrested they got in a little trouble
but
then it turned out there were no actual
laws against what they did
they did choose to leave france wisely
but there were no laws against it so
they did not in their lives in prison
so our adversaries are have been with us
for a while
another one often seen as the first
modern hacker although i would say the
the blanc's probably ours is this
dashing gentleman
neville masklin
he was a victorian area english stage
magician
inventor of the pay toilet but he's here
because of
hacking marconi's allegedly a secure
wireless system
neville maskelin was
didn't believe marconi's claims of
security
and uh set up something marconi was in a
far-flung place and had his
an assistant of his in a parlor in
london with a group of investors and
interested parties
and marconi sent a wireless telegraph
message across the wire
masculine figured out how to do a
man-in-the-middle attack
and sent his message ahead of
marconi's the associate had read
most of an obscene limerick ridiculing
marconi
well before he realized what he was
doing for anyone who's done
morse code or other things you sort of
become a conduit and don't realize what
you're saying
and so unfortunately for marconi's
associate he read
an obscene limerick about his boss um
didn't go well so wireless man in the
middle attacks
in 1903 so some of these challenges
we've been working on for a while
uh here we go you expected this one
and you get homework i'm not going to
tell you anything
about grace hopper
which is amazing you got to know about
it here's your homework i'm going to
give you one piece of homework
you must have heard the stories if not
she was famous for giving people a
nanosecond it was how she explained why
it took so long for messages to get
to satellites and back to ships at sea
as an admiral
ask around figure out who you know
that has a nanosecond or had one because
they're pretty easy to lose
i've discovered i've never had one but
and ask how they got them and ask for
their stories
because the people that have these are
interesting people and the stories of
interacting with her interesting
there's if you want to see something
decades ago she was on the letterman
show and there's a great clip of her
the the internet has that um so that's
that so let's skip forward
here's one that i like to include in
these talks because
people know one thing about robert
tappen morris
people know that
um the morris worm
he was at school he created a worm it
blew up
uh and that's all a lot of people know
about him
so let's tell you a little bit more do
you know that
spaff did the forensic work on it how
did this do what it did
when he was just playing around you know
he had no malicious intent that didn't
keep it from doing
fun things on the internet but he didn't
have malicious intent
uh that proved that we needed some sort
of uh
computer emergency response thing like
say assert which came out of this
first person convicted under the
computer fraud and abuse act
he was charged in 89 sentenced to three
years probation in 90.
um but to me that's the boring part of
the story
he then went on to co-found two
companies
via web and the other one is y
combinator one of the companies he
co-founded continues to be an incubator
in the technology field all these years
later
the other thing that is not known about
him by many people is
that although he was not granted tenure
track at purdue he had to settle for mit
robert tappan morris has been a tenured
professor
of electrical engineering and computer
science at mit since 2006
so if all you know about him was the
worm
you should know that generations of
people that couldn't
get into sirius are doing pretty well
with him as their professor at mit
of course we can't talk about him
without mentioning his dad
um brilliant man was it
was at bell labs
for many many years worked on multics
and
later was involved in the development of
that newfangled eunuch stuff
uh he spent about a decade at nsa and he
was at nsa when
um his son got rolled up and the fbi
went in
to tell them that they were rolling his
kid up at school
and
the fbi normally comes in all fbi like
but
from folks that were there i've heard
that you don't go in fbi like
to fort meade so that was one thing he
also he's done some things there are a
variety of people
um one of the he's one of the people
that had this idea that we have phone
lines
wouldn't it be cool if we could send
data on a phone line by maybe modulating
and demodulating that
something that we got later abbreviated
to mo dem
he had three rules of um
cryptanalysis or he had a rule for
cryptanalysis three rules for computer
security
uh one of the things for anybody that's
ever done a capture of the flags
particularly with
with crypto challenges um
one of his famous quotes is never uh i
mean uh number one rule of cryptanalysis
check for plain text
if you've ever tried one of those
challenges and not look to read if you
can read the thing that's really
check for plain text
one of his things from bell end later at
nsa never underestimate the attention
risk money and time that an opponent
will put into reading traffic
he had three golden rules to ensure
computer security
for those who are as old as jaded as i
am i'm
you might agree with these uh one
do not own a computer two
should you fail there don't turn it on
three if you failed the first two please
don't use it
um so he was uh
he was that he was also famous for uh
chain smoking outside of his office and
uh burning up shrubberies at
the joint so let's uh come a little
forward did you know math and uh
security kind of
weave together uh dorothy denning
probably best known
for a lattice model of secure
information flow
which established a mathematical basis
for enforcing
information assurance information
security on a computer system
for those that are into hacker history
or part of that community
she was known for being originally quite
sympathetic
in her perspective on early hackers
later changed
her position on them she worked on the
skipjack block cipher
in defense of the clipper chip
i won't call her the nickname that she
earned but some people opposed that
she was at purdue for a while as a
professor then sri
uh then georgetown and eventually at the
naval postgraduate school
as was her husband um she's just
a brilliant character in our field so
now
we're going to
talk about a futurist i don't claim to
be a futurist
it's a lot easier to look back at what
other people
have done because that i can figure out
so there are people that we live with
today
if you said these things to them they
wouldn't believe you
the computer will touch men everywhere
and in every way almost on a minute to
minute basis
everyone will communicate through a
computer whatever he does
it will force and force change reshape
life modify career
accept the life of continuous change
in 1966 willis ware warned us of this
um it was quite a prediction he uh
his career started out uh working on
classified radar systems during world
war ii
worked on um iff identify friend foe
radar electronic systems in world war ii
he spent
40 years at rand from 52 to 92
he is the lead author of
it's got a boring title but he's a lead
author of what most of us know is the
where report
initially issued in 1967 i think the
final
iteration was 71
obviously it's completely obsolete
except that if you read that paper
you change a few words you change some
labels on a picture or two
and abstract it back to a higher level
it's
still highly valuable and very prescient
one of the important things that willis
ware understood
understanding all of these things was he
was concerned about the reliance on
computers
and that that would pose um
serious privacy issues he led a bunch of
committees
aimed at safeguarding computer user
privacy rights
um led the commission that was set up by
president ford
led to the first uh privacy act back in
i wish we had voices like his that
people listen to instead of the
government doing what they do but that's
enough of me being political
uh just amazing if you i assume most uh
but if you have not read the where
report
um grab it it's easy to find on the
internet read through it abstract
yourself
back just a little bit and think wow
uh that's some fundamental stuff
speaking of fundamental things
bob abbott
did a whole bunch of stuff bob led
the first
red team um at nsa he created and led
team at nsa to look at internal security
by poking at it
by today's standards it wasn't as
aggressive a red team as we've got now
but it was
it was where that started it was poking
at things at nsa to secure our stuff
before others violated it
he led a project called the research
into secure operating systems
the study ran early to mid 70s
[Music]
the guy the goal was to aid in
understanding security issues and
operating systems
and try to figure out what it would take
to enhance them this report hasn't aged
as well
unless you're into the history of it
however
there are some um there are some good
tidbits to be learned if you're really
into this stuff
one of the interesting things that came
out of the rice report was they
determined seven key things that were
real problems in operating system
security and the first two are
incomplete and
inconsistent parameter validation
implicit sharing of privileges and
confidential data
asynchronous validation and inadequate
serialization so yeah
race conditions in time of use time you
know time of checkout versus time of use
we were worried about these he was
telling us to worry about them in the
early 70s
one that we still maybe have some ground
to cover before we solve
inadequate identification authentication
authorization
um exploitable logic errors viable
project prohibitions and limits
and yes it's a lot easier to define a
problem than it is to fix it but the
first step is defining them
and it's easy to read to see these and
get disgusted but honestly we've
the industry has made progress in the os
level
operating systems are imperfect but they
have gotten better
unfortunately the commoditization of
hardware and software and
commoditization of software creation has
allowed us to push
all of these and many more up into the
application layer and that's what
that's the challenge that most of us
face now
he was the author of the first set of
data and privacy confidentiality
policies for healthcare developed the
first multi-user multitasking os for
crate class
supercomputers that ran uh 24x7
uh he led a project that produced the
first uh
monitoring systems for open-heart
surgery
patients and one of my favorites
is i mentioned that team at nsa the red
team
the movie sneakers was
he was an advisor to the movie the core
team and that was
based on bob's team at nsa um
the james earl jones character was named
bernard abbott
as a nod to bob and so uh bob
uh was that also arguable he
was arguably the first person to leave
those sort of big brand bell labs
government jobs
and do information assurance information
security what we now call cyber security
as a consultant arguably the founder of
the industry that many of us
live and breathe in
another one fernando corby corbato
we uh we recently uh lost him but
he's interesting because he's the guy
that came up with the idea of using a
password for security
um
and more interesting was he knew that we
had outgrown the use of passwords
um
he um
that's an important thing sometimes
we're protective of our babies
uh if you have a great idea and
technology marches past
time march has passed let it go
and you thought it was better than
post-its although
um there weren't post-its back then
from mits uh it is tributed to mit's
csail site
it's no overstatement to say corby's
work on time sharing fundamentally
transformed computers as we know them
today
from pcs to smartphones the digital
revolution can directly trace its roots
back to the work he led at that other
school uh mit 60 years ago
um another one that's not as well known
and it's
it's not just to throw stones at kevin
even though
tsutsumo uh shimomura best known for
helping take down kevin mitnick
studied under feynman at caltech worked
at los alamos than ucsd
then nsa and son testified before
congress on cell phone privacy issues
in 1992. um the
tracking and take down in 95 he's
founded companies
uh labs um his
father got a you know tangent but his
father
earned a nobel in chemistry in 2008
so an interesting family to say the
least
loving the commentary here so a
sentimental favorite
um not enough people know her those that
do um
i apologize hopefully of a handkerchief
or kleenex or handy
uh becky bass info mom
i gave a talk about her
and kelly you're out there somewhere and
referred to her as the nickname that she
got decades ago denmother of intrusion
detection
she ratted me out to becky becky made it
very clear that i was no longer allowed
to call her the den mother of intrusion
detection
she wished to be called the cranky broad
and i continue to honor that to this day
even though we lost her a couple years
ago
if you think about the names that we
know in
early network analysis intrusion
detection
[Music]
my friend and former employer ron goula
marty rash
marcus that the number of people that
she took under her wing when she was at
nsa
and helped advance the people she
connected and found ways to advance
the network analysis
was just incredible and then after nsa
she went into consulting and did some
amazing things
she grew up in south alabama
as she told it when she went north to
marry a yankee
her dad made her promise that when she
was done with all that nonsense she'd
come home
and she did she ended her career
teaching at the university of south
alabama
fulfilling a promise that she made to
her father uh when she left alabama
when she was much younger so um also
you know yep voices cranking amazing
hugs
so let's move on before i get really
weepy uh she was just incredible and the
number of lives she touched is
incredible
so um we're closing in on a point where
it's time for questions but this
project came about because
i wanted to uh share some things and i
started thinking about what to share
and i thought about this i dug into that
quote if i've seen further it's by
standing on the shoulders of giants
and newton who changed the way we view
our world
said that and he actually was
paraphrasing one of his mentors
this was uh not even an original
statement which i think is really
impressive that he
took that um for a while this was
actually on the
rim of the british pound coin as i
believe
the important thing about this
though is that it um
its shoulders of infosec and the project
shoulders intersect.it goes to an ugly
wiki
yes it's horrible no there's no padlock
the
like software stockholm syndrome i need
to move it but anyway there are a lot of
names there
um but the project is called the
shoulders of infosec
not the giants of infosec
newton talked about standing on the
shoulders of giants but um
giants is kind of a challenge uh we
can't all be giants
but we can all
in ways large and small offer shoulder
for others to stand
on and um if you'll forgive a little bit
of idealism
i believe that by providing shoulders
for others to stand on
that's the way we become giants
and so with that um
before we throw it wide open and i have
to find things a lot of people
contributed to this project i mentioned
many of them
becky um marcus random ron goula gunner
peterson
spaff has been instrumental in
pointing the resources and being a
sounding board for many things
and you know with that if you want to
find me info at shoulders of infosec.org
if you want to talk about that
i do a podcast everybody does a podcast
don't pay any attention
we don't have sponsors though at least
i'm on twitter if your life
is too shallow uh you can ping me at
work anytime i'm easy to find on that
internet
thing
and with that i i realized years ago
people say things like the end on
presentations that's dumb my
presentation is winding down
but hopefully this has inspired you if
you
know of people or stories that should be
part of this project
let me know reach out join the wiki if
you want to add some people yourself
it's pretty simple
learn share find out who you know uh
that's got a nanosecond find out the
story
they may have just met her briefly at a
conference they may have
had good conversations um
but then you know this is a beginning
every end is a beginning
and with that i will uh i will i will
find
glasses and try to read and see if there
are comments or questions i should
answer
uh yes uh we
we do all love and miss uh
becky um and like i said
one thing i would really like to um
[Music]
do is get more personal stories so if
anybody wants to share stories in any
way
about any of the people that we've got
on there anybody that's missing i'm
teetering on the brink of trying to put
the next generation in here
in the wiki i'm struggling with the
hacker crowd because that's probably
better for
people like jeff moss and people that
are part of that culture to do that
maybe someday when i no longer need to
be employable or have friends
i will write a book called how hackers
ruined infosec and how infosec ruined
hackers
but that's a later project so i'm not
sure about the how much hacker culture
but there is a
decided um inter
um there's a decided interplay and
a lot of us straddle that line between
defcon and and black hat and rsa
and so you know it's good when we break
down barriers as i mentioned earlier
there are a lot of silos in our world
and any of those that we can knock out
um
there's um we're all better off for it
and yes there's a
mention the babbage institute has some
great resources i link to those
at the top of the shoulders wiki there
are links to a variety of resources the
multician's
babbage there's some great papers at uc
davis as i believe variety links
anything that can be done uh it is a big
ugly wiki and i'm sure the link rod is
ugly because it's been a couple of years
since i've crawled it but
there's that um yeah
so i really appreciate the opportunity
to share this with you
dig through here
i'll uh volunteer jack
i met admiral hopper but it was at a
time when she was giving out picoseconds
rather than nanoseconds so it gotten
along to that point
and unfortunately
at some point in a move they disappeared
i i have heard that i asked on twitter
who had one to make sure i wasn't
asking an impossible question and uh i i
got the
uh you know a small piece of wire is
really easy to lose
yeah um well the pico seconds were
little packets of pepper she had gotten
right from the navy
and um so they were had u.s navy on them
little packets of pepper and she said
each was was a pico second
and um they disappeared and i i often
wonder if
a roommate somewhere along the line
decided that that was a condiment to use
yeah that went on their burger or
something yeah
i would encourage the people who are
listening who are interested in
cyber security do to check out some of
these resources
that we do have a rich history as a
field and as
as jack said we're often too busy trying
to keep up to really gain some of the
perspective
but when you look at some of the other
sciences like chemistry or physics or
mathematics
there are a lot of interesting people we
can point to
we need to do a better job of
understanding that in
in cyber security
so any questions for jack
good i've loaded them all to sleep so uh
yeah i think they're stunned or they're
all checking out the wiki
so there's a question what are you up to
these days jack so i
um i am at tenable i've been at tenable
almost a decade
ron brought me in i have a phenomenal
job
tenable is not a little engineering
startup uh
full of people that are out in the
community but we know where we came from
and
i am the community advocate for tenable
not the corporate community but the
greater community and
so working on the shoulders of infosec
project supporting
security b-sides globally and some
specific events
doing some uh work with stress and
burnout and coping skills
in our world which past years added to
all of us
a little bit of stuff on career studies
and what makes jobs great and whatnot
and uh just being out i always tell
people what i do at tenable is
i'm a little too candid for a publicly
traded company to be an official
spokesman
so i don't really speak for the company
but one of the things i always do is
listen for the company and
our ceo iran is a
understands the value of connecting with
community and so
he and a few others there want me to do
things like
talk to people listen to people share
what
what i've discovered and put in some
sweat equity and making conferences
happen and building community
jack there's a question in the q a
which i can read to you or you can read
it
um no this is not obs i was going to try
open broadcast studio but it gets really
temperamental feeding obs to zoom
this is actually a beta feature of zoom
if you go into screen sharing advanced
you can
grab a powerpoint deck and use that as
your virtual background
and so that's what i've done here there
is a green screen behind me
there are banks of leds and other things
because we all live here but that's uh
that's one of the beta features of zoom
is there they've made it easier
obs does cool stuff but sometimes when
you pipe it to something that it doesn't
have a native integration with it
it degrades the video quality pretty
heavily and i think that's on zooms in
they just don't know what to do with the
virtual camera but anyway there's a
zoom that if you are on zoom all the
time
they've made some advancements the they
hide them
uh but things like uh original audio
which is what i'm using because i'm
running through a solid mic and
mixer and things like that they've made
it better um
so but you have to play first to get
anything to work because technology
all right well i don't see any other
questions
popping up um
again i would encourage people to check
out some of these resources
for some of you uh i i
typed in the link there of the babbage
institute
um they
had a grant from nsf and they visited
and interviewed a lot of these people
about their backgrounds
the one with willis ware was captured
just about a year before he passed away
and there's also one of becky um
so there are a number of individuals who
are interviewed there that
you may never get a chance or will never
get a chance to meet
that you can hear some very interesting
stories from them along the way
but uh yeah there's a lot of history
there that's worth worth following up on
so jack thank you so much oops wait a
second yep there we go
thank you for an enjoyable hour jack um
i i if any of you are at a conference at
a con
at a meeting and you see jack he may
have a top hat on
he sometimes wears a top hat which
extends him to about seven feet tall
but uh i'm sure he would be happy to uh
to say hello if you were to if you were
to meet him well one question popped up
why don't you answer that and then we'll
conclude
so jack will system vulnerabilities live
with us
uh or do you think they're gonna end i
think um
i think we have some opportunities to
improve
things as whether we like it or not
moving to cloud means that we
have to work closer with developers so
that we can
work earlier in the pipeline to secure
software better
but we're never going to make
vulnerabilities disappear
and i don't say that because i work at a
vulnerability management vendor um
the built-in vulnerabilities are one
class of vulnerabilities
[Music]
the making systems vulnerable by
misconfiguration
is is another class and it's really hard
to make
systems uh so
that you can't uh that you can so that
you can actually use them the way you
want
but can't screw them up and make them
insecure
um i think it was douglas adams that
said
uh anytime anyone who tries to make
something idiot proof
uh is underestimating the quality of
idiots these days
or something like that um and i don't
like to
call people idiots but you know the
people are trying to do their jobs and
if we don't make it
really easy to do it the right way
securely
it won't be done securely
thank you again jack and thank you
everyone for being here we'll see you
next week enjoy your afternoon
you