up up
20 slide transition ur
other alright a lower-body
I'm German Jounin and followed by myself
I work for a a local large
transportation logistics company
biggest in the world doing pen testing
lebanon ability assessment and other
types a security assessment
and also an app by copious amounts of
spare time I work on a project called me
tel de
rejoiced are by Adrian and
keep that active on SourceForge do some
stuff with the low cost us a
and also run the weapon AZT you teach an
YouTube channel so today is going to
talk about
path relative Starshine injection as a
typeof a cross-eyed scripting
vulnerability so
star with brief overview of cross site
scripting
and this is a type attack
that occurs on the client side i've a
web application
so in other words it's running in the
user's browser and a basic laid
depends on the application
not encoding output so that the Browser
has a hard time telling the difference
between data that was sent into the
application
and scripts that were injected into the
application usually
if you take a script from one website
or one source even and you tried to run
in a separate website
there some protections that are built
into the browser itself
that well keep the script from
interacting
with the page also protects the cookies
in
some other resources on the page from
being changed by the JavaScript
so an example here
is we have Google dot com plus home
not in it or not a real page but
certainly a real site and if you look at
the script at the bottom of the screen
it's from the domain oh yeah I dot com
so if you were to include the other dot
com script
into the Google Page that Yahoo to
conscript would not have access
to change to go page and also I would be
restricted from interacting with the
cookies and the other resources
that are associated with Google's page
so the same origin policy works on
and theory three parts one is the scheme
so HTTP or HTTPS then the domain name
and then finally the poor number that
the web application is running on
essay this in theory because some
browsers
tend to ignore the port and so you
really end up
haven't same margin based on the scheme
and the domain
and a course sensors only two schemes
and a lot of pages will offer an exact
same
resources in both HTTP and HTTPS what
times are really comes down to the
domain name
an example here I
this script would only work
on the fifth line down the one that's
bolded
because that's the only one that has the
scheme
the domain and the port all matching
a port some clout as port 80 because
it's HTTP
in the courts not otherwise explicitly
listed
so with cross site scripting the idea is
to inject a script into the application
usually via some sort of input parameter
it could also be data that's sitting in
a database anyway for the applications
the selected
or perhaps in a file anyway for the
application to read it
but in all cases are trying to hang
get source code to be incorporated
into the web page that application
produces
so the application itself will be
serving
this moshe script sewing see in this
diagram
that a script has been injected via
the message parameter that is
part iv: this a URL
and so the attacker in this case says
injected some mystical evil method and
put that inside script tags this
parameter travels all the way to the
server
and then the servers source code
reads the value of that parameter and
then
uses that to create an h1 tag
and says hello and then the value of
whatever the parameter is
so in this case it looks like
they're asking the user type and maybe
their name and then
the application when a corporator name
into the response
and say hello frederick for that was so
the
the script is going to travel all the
way back to the browser
and when I finally reaches the browser
the browser understands
JavaScript and can parse it an executed
and that's when they hear the attack
will actually occur
as 18 gets back to the browser so
and this its theoretical example
if we pass n a
script
that can get a corporation page and then
the page does not encode that
that data value then
it's possible for the script XQ so the
confusion is that sometimes
developers expect all these parameters
to have data comment on
but there's nothing really restricting
someone from putting code into those
variables and sending them on their way
and two
the application server so at the bottom
here this is what the
the final page would look like after the
application got done
incorporating the data and and this is
what was originally
user's browser so in this case it's
syntactically correct
even though it's not intended the evil
method
what XQ so
path relative style sheet injection is
typeof this cross-site scripting and
typically it's going to be the reflected
type
the one we just described where
injection occurs
on the client travels all the way to the
server is incorporated into the page
and then sent back to the client work
finally is able to execute
an injection in these cases rather be in
javascript
is actually cascading style sheets I'm
sorry
I'm style sheets would be
yelled socially to be like um
whether you want to make the font bold
or change its colors
very typically and then there's a
pretty rich language is actually
developed in this third edition of CSS
we can do lots of things like
cause animations and three-dimensional
objects to spend and stuff like that
so it but it's a so in the browser you
basically have
an HTML parser they're all from there
with the Parsis the tags into
a drying and then you have the styles
that are applied by the browser
to format the HTML
and then you have script usually
JavaScript
that can interact with the HTML
so pages
are actually made up of lots of the
different files and
I took a partial picture I love just
what the
mathilde a home page looks like and
these are only about half the
the files that make up that page
and highlighted a couple love them the
question mark
I'm was about the tense follower so that
was fetched and
PHP logo was somewhere around fifteen
Thurso
and all those where called up on
by the main page which is highlighted in
the red square
at the top so
the main page is gonna ask for these
other resources
to be included when the page loads in
the browser
for actually has a chance to be parsed
you're gonna have images
scripts and styles typically so
at the bottom here got a couple of those
included images the ones that were
highlighted
and this is the full path to those
images
so to avoid putting multiple copies
above the same exact say JavaScript or
style
developers usually will house
those scripts in separate files and then
they will include them into the main
page
says a lot of advantages because if you
come up with a nice style sheet and you
want to use it on many pages
you can write the style sheet one-time
and then deploy it to all the different
pages
just by referencing it when the page
loads and also has another day and shame
what has been developer knows that
when you make a mistake it's much better
to be able to change
and or fix the mistake and one filing
have propagate out
than to have to go to a bunch of
individual web pages and make the
same correction over and over again and
in a picture here
this is the global style sheet for the
night on a project her lease
the first three lines anyway that is
included into the main page
to I'm format all the styles
make the border menus everything else
look nice
so there's
couple different ways you can include
these files you can have the relative
path
and the absolute path and
these has are generally specified
by tags: that will include these files
so there's the link tags which are often
used to include Style Sheets
anchor tags typically will include a
reference of two
another location on also have
references to JavaScript with the crew
the script tag
and there's couple of examples here
there's a link tag
in the middle that is including I
reference to
the global styles style sheet that we
just like that a second ago
and then down to bottom is a reference
to a javascript file called bookmark
site duh JS
and thats Benn reference by the script
eg
so with the absolute links
the source code is specifying the full
path
and this is pretty uncommon but in this
example
an anchor tag is referencing I'm
global styles using the full pass
starting with HTTP going all the way to
the server name
the filepath in all the way to the
resource
at the end the relative
link at the bottom only
link on references difference
between the current page and the
resource
so since the current page is already at
local host Mottola day the relative link
is going to just have the difference
which is styles
global that CSS
so
now we see that there's two different
kinds are links
we can talk a little more about how the
browser figures out
what the full absolute passes given
that only has the relative path well
the first thing is to do is figure out
the base URL
and that's the directory that the main
page
is n the page this calling upon this
resource and then it'll
a pen that relative path that was
referenced and after you add those
together
what you should get is the full path to
the resource file
the style sheet in this case so gonna
make an assumption that we're talking
about them until they project
and we have the past slash mathilde day
is where is the file that the main
resources and and so
we we need to add on the relative path
to that
to get the full path the reason the
browser
behave this way is its following the
RF sees on what a you are out looks like
and you are as ur pretty familiar to all
this but
may not think about their construct very
much they're basically have the
the scheme the HTTPS or http and then
the
hierarchy is going to be the essentially
the a.m
the authority it's the domain for all
practical purposes
and the port and user credentials but we
don't see those very much in
and web and you get into the
absolute path an important thing to know
sears just that it starts
with a slash and then continues with
found on directory locations separated
by more slashes
until you get to the very end so
the browser's going to match the file
name located after
the last slash easy enough
here we have an example has been worked
so the browser
has taken of the resource name
and its left with the base URL and then
its gonna read the relative reference
in this case in this a trap tag are a
trip better be
and help in those two together and get
the full path to the style she
and that works because that is in fact
the path to the style sheet in a bit on
a project
out if we compare that against how PHP
well get the file
that the browser ass for it's a little
bit different
so PHP has a configuration
inside Apache and
apaches uses the spouse match directive
to figure out
where for which processor should process
the file
so we see the files mash corrective here
for
php files and they can have lots of
different extensions like
PHP 34&5 for a
pH PTM our own things like that but
typically are all use the same stop
PHP's and thats
certainly the standard so
the way that the server is gonna fetch
the resources the browser s4
is its gonna see this index that PHP
which matches that regular expression
animal
invokes the PHP handler to
generate that HTML file and an Apache
will return $html back to the browser
so notice that there's two different
ways
that the is resources are
parsed and that can create some
confusion in certain cases
so in our example
both the browser and the server
agreed on which resource was being asked
for in both cases
they came up with indexed at Php and
both agree
that the passes mathilde so they both
calculated the path
the same even though they used two
different methods
but sense
the web server as parsing based on the
following stanchion
what happens if you end up having exter
directory
after the resource file
that PHP is looking for and so take this
path
at the top here we actually have the so
in bar directory specified
after the resource and XI PHP
so the browser's just gonna go through
its
normal calculations and it'll have
I the word bar will be considered the
resource
as it's after the last slash so across
that out and now we have a base paths
again
and then we need to add style slash
global styles that CSS
that relative path from earlier onto the
end of the base URL
so we will calculate this URL
is what we need to ask for in order to
gain get the Global South %uh CSS
from the web server so
the browser's gonna ask Apache for this
file
but the file doesn't exist what's web
server gonna do
well the web server
is gonna do it always does which is this
going to look for that
their regular expression matching the
dot PHP on the end
so what a patchy is gonna see is its
gonna see index at Php
and it's not really going to be too
concerned about all that stuff that came
after an ex that PHP
it's effectively gonna end up looking
for
this file here and text at Php
so you have a situation where the
browser is
asking for a style sheet named global
styles that CSS
at Seans at asking PHP for the index to
php file
which page he is more than happy to
return because that does exist
so the browser wanted a style she but it
got back in HTML file
and we can actually see this in this
screen capture here if you look at
an inspector on the left you'll see
that the browser is convinced that
global style Scott CSS was fetched
because that is after all
what it asked for but if you look at
what I was actually returns the doctype
is HTML this is actually the indexed at
php page that has been returned
so
the browser wanna style she got back
an HTML document usually this is not a
big deal
because the browser will
look at the type of document that was
returned it can pick up clues like the
doctype
and the content-type thats return back
as part as the
HTTP body in the history header
and it can reason that I wanted a style
sheet
I got back initial document something's
wrong and it'll just kinda bailout
and wall process the HTML document and
pretend like
it's a style so really we're not gonna
have
a problem except for sometimes
with browser compatibility mode
there may actually be opportunities for
the browser to go ahead and parse
additional document as a style sheet
anyway
so browsers wanna try to be
friendly two pages better older
and more frequently for honest
pages that are not written very well so
we might have pages that
I'm are not sent at tactically cracked
but the browser still wants to be able
to serve those pages
a render those pages as beses can
and obviously you wanna have as much
market shares you can anyone else Poor's
main developers as you can if your
browser
I'm in order to maintain market share
now
sites themselves can also of into
compatibility mode
so they can declare doctypes: like the
one seen here the transitional doctype
and tried to I'm topped the browser and
go on in the compatibility mode
in order to use some older content
that may not work strictly and the html5
specification
the current specification course the
users themselves can
actually set the browser and the
compatibility mode and I think intern
exploring
Peraza nice little button free to click
a sec compatibility mode
and all the browsers pretty much let you
go into the options
and sec at ability mod so
we go back to the style sheet show I'm
being asked for but the HTML file shows
up
if the browsers and compatibility mode
it will
scan through that HTML document and its
gonna try to find a style
that is syntactically correct and
use that style to mark-up the
page that it's drawing
and that's gonna let us inject some
style
into the page so
there some prerequisites we need we need
the page itself
to have a cross-site scripting
vulnerability
because we need to figure out a way to
inject script
in this case CSS crypt into the page
and have incorporated into that page and
output back
into the browser where the browser can
see it so
that's why the pass relative style sheet
is basically a type of
cross-site scripting out JavaScript is
the most
commonly used scripts for
cross-site scripting but Javascript does
have some limitations
if the injection is gonna land in the
middle if HTML
instead of landing in the middle of some
other JavaScript you're gonna need
script tags
to break out of the HTML
and get the JavaScript engine to execute
that script
otherwise your javascript just gonna
land right the middle of an HTML tag
it doesn't really mean anything to HTML
and so it just kinda be displayed on the
screen
style she's on the other hand
do not require tags: in HTML context
to invoke the CSS parser so if you can
get
a style injected it can be a little bit
easier
sense a lot of these on defenses are
built into browsers
tend to be focused on script tags or
other HTML tags to recognize that there
some type a cross-site scripting going
on
so here's an example
we have a javascript that
turns some text read: and we have the
equivalent style
that also turns they same text read:
and days should basically operate the
same way
but if you look at the style sheet
you'll see see that it doesn't need
the script tags and/or operate and this
is going to allow it to pass through
filters
and other types of kinda naive defenses
a lot easier
so economics this a started injection
interesting from that point of view so
we can see this with the demo and I'm
gonna use
the told a system for this demo recently
the path relative style sheet injection
vulnerability was
added into the project so now you can
download the project in
try this for yourself are injections
gonna have
several parts they are kinda run
together but
essentially run to start with path
extension because
we wanna have some directories after
the file name for the reason we talked
about earlier we want to get the browser
a little bit I confused about what the
base URL as
and orange area that's the prefix for
the attack
percent I am 0a is encoded
for the one thing character and I like
the way that up
the ports for your blog but that I think
he said something like it gets the
it's the page in the mood to to accept a
style
Anna effectively what it does is it's a
type a separator
between the enter the path in the
beginning of the style sheet
the the blue Astrix is called The
Selecter
and & Style Sheets a selector is
just a declaration have what you want to
apply the style to
their shirts as a special medicare to
remains
sorry about that and get here and
jamming
have we lost the audio from this point
on
the demo continues but not the audio
unfortunately
year even say about the last like this a
10 minutes you're talking
the first section was any good anyway
didn't miss anything
but yes I but this and operate the
camera
crap out on the talk to thank you much
fired back