everyone if you want to start making
questions and you feel more comfortable
using a mobile so you can you can use
slider which is pretty cool so just feel
free to to do any questions or you know
we're gonna have a Q&A session
afterwards but if you feel more
comfortable just you know you have to
just connect to the website slider comm
pbd which is privacy by design is the
the key word for accessing the the this
specific talk okay okay so let me switch
let's go
okay now
this is gonna be interesting think talk
I'm gonna kind of introduce somehow what
machine learning can do for privacy
I see privacy as a sort of extension of
security I think they're not different
concepts are very related so I'm gonna
try to you know explore pretty much what
what is privacy from the applications
SEC perspective so which is typically
called privacy by design
okay so just if you feel free to
interrupt me just raise your hand you
know let's let's make it you know kind
of to weigh as much as possible okay so
let me see if this works I'm gonna try
using this device just one sec okay okay
okay
so that's pretty much what I'm gonna do
this is not an awareness call talk you
know there are many many there have been
a lot of sessions about privacy
awareness like what should you do with
privacy but there's very little at least
to me very little content about what can
you do now okay so I'm gonna try to
introduce at least what I've been
researching in pass in the past couple
of years second thing I believe in a
certainly development centric approach
towards privacy right now privacy is
more like kind of top-down you have
compliance people saying this is what
you have to do and it's it's not even
very very let's say specific so I
believe in what I call you know
grassroots approach we're gonna win X
Pro that a little bit more and and then
yeah we're gonna see just see one way
you know privacy it's a huge huge space
so we're gonna you know I'm gonna kind
of share with you guys what you know
what AI can do for you and it's not so
let's call it AI can seem like very
challenging to approach but right now
there technologies kind of picked up and
it's more let's call it it's easier to
implement solution on top of that so you
can do a lot without having to you know
to build or to buy you know the latest
product so let me keep going so I'm kind
of you know pretty much I I see myself
as a developer I start as a developer
and even if I I ran my my company I
still keep development ok so that's the
way we typically do research and I'm
still very hands-on ok so that my my
heart I'm still a software developer
which is you know love security and
privacy just as a something even to me
that I feel it's very important at least
it's something that is affecting our
personal lives so I if I can contribute
something you know that's that's that's
great so well my first computer was
coming 64 so I'm old I'm not sure if
anyone here a comer 64 you know you had
a prompt and you had to just write basic
that's it so let's let's keep going well
this actually you know I have no
comments on that it's it's a very same
vague very generic but it still applies
for instance where I live in in San
Francisco I I've just once looked up my
name in Google and I found that there
was information about my my house so my
house it was linked with with my
identity so I know I never share that
information okay so I feel you know very
annoyed when these things happen you
find really personal information online
okay so it's not a just easy to fix that
now we're gonna see why it's not so easy
so
few years ago there's this professor
Carol can introduce a concept called
privacy by design so let me I mean start
using this okay which is I think those
principles apply to security too right
you want to anticipate yourself to any
privacy issue so that that's that it has
to be prevent preventative not reactive
prices default means that it's actually
more the the consumer side you know it's
basically you know by default enabling
disabling I mean all the features that
can compromise the consumer privacy you
know for instance if you download an app
typically all the privacy settings are
against you and you have to go to the
settings and say no I don't want to
share this information and so so that's
privacy by default okay so that I think
is really important but my focus today
sorry my focus today is going to be on
the privacy embedded into the design
looks like I lost my see if it works so
and the other concept is that full
functionality that means that if if you
for instance are using a VPN or let's
say an anonymous browser session you
don't want to lose any you know you want
to just stick to the same user
experience you know sometimes you know
when web sites or application detect
that you are whatever trying to protect
your identity somehow they you know the
whole user experience changes against
you so that's that's pretty much what
what do we mean by full functionality
and true and it means that yeah you have
privacy has to be bundled into the whole
sdlc the whole software of the lifecycle
and not only your your your your own but
also beyond the perimeter that's that's
very challenging right and I think be
stability in transparency it's pretty
much respectful user privacy it's it's
the same thing to me okay so if you if
you consider privacy as first-class
citizen you going you're going to
you know you're gonna get all these
attributes quality attributes so let's
see if atleast this works so this is
data at least I have fun 2017 so this is
all I think has been even worse okay so
but this is just an idea of what is the
financial impact then probably see I
don't want to get too much into this
because a lot of has you know there's a
lot of information about this and there
have been few a few significant breaches
you know the past couple of years
you know like Equifax and have been a
couple more so we can uh you know but
this is an idea they financially but I
think it's even more significant it's
very difficult to measure what is the
business impact when when you get your
personal records leak or some sort of
leak in terms of personal data so and
and this we go back to the same constant
to the original concept I was trying to
explain before why is it difficult
because it's it's totally bigfooters
it's not all infrastructure you have to
do it end-to-end as I said before it's
you have to you have to actually it's
not only what happens within the
perimeter but also outside with your
service providers you don't really know
what happens when you send personal
information of your users to I don't
know a service provider like Google
Amazon whatever how do you make sure
that they're they're protecting this
data okay so that's that's very very
challenge and even if you do a really
good job in a protected data you you
know you will never be sure about that
of course there are legal things you can
do you know for that but it's just a
legal framework okay it's not a
technical you know countermeasure and
the other thing is that I think that
privacy itself at all pretty much all
the the Condit I see is very high level
it's difficult to put that into
you know something that works you know
it's just say this is what we should do
and you get some many vendors providing
some very neat solutions but what can I
do now and right and and that's that's
what I feel it's it's just crafted by
design how many people know the term
privacy by design or pbd here cool okay
oh we got a few people okay that's
that's great so the other thing is uh I
mean the other thing is lack of okay
there are no tools very little tools and
if you want to I mean there are some
tools but are coming from startups or
large corporations summer bases Silicon
Valley but I believe that that's you
know the mindset that the tool will be
the solution is very dangerous okay I
think security there is no perfect tool
you actually it's a combination of tools
plus your know-how and plus the you know
kind of your expertise about what you
have to protect in terms of how your
business works so I honestly believe
even if I you know I work and try to
create technologies with my company with
terms of privacy
I don't believe tool is the tooling is
is the problem okay it's just part of
the solution just part and I think this
this is also applies to security and
typically management is it's you know
application of security it's some
somehow it's more known because it's
older but privacy application security
is a very new subject a new topic so
there's not a lot of information and so
it's difficult to get funding cific
difficult to you know kind of there's an
effort in to evangelize and do the
management so I'm going to do something
a little bit controversial here so what
do I mean by grassroot adoption I mean
that as security guys okay there are a
lot of I've heard that a lot of cyber
security people here you want to you
know you can actually start bundling
privacy capabilities into your
infrastructure right now that and I
believe that you don't have to wait for
you
permit me to tell you this is what we
should do and you know that's gonna be
probably too late okay you so my my what
I'm proposing here it's more like what
is called a you know the cathedral and
the bazaar that's a typical book paper
that pretty much explains how the linear
soft development process worked and
agreement is actually when you know
contributed to the one of the core
pieces of another kernel but the
sentiment but he he pretty much
explained how that works
I believe that bringing that all that
risque model to to privacy at least in
protecting you know personal data from
in the application I think it's a it's a
it's a very healthy approach and as you
can see here it's a you know you can you
can pretty much use techniques that are
available in existing software security
testing okay so static code analysis
that I'm a code analysis it's it's not
very different so what I believe in is
that you can you can start introducing
those capabilities incrementally because
to me I mean privacy security so if
you're responsible security you know you
can you can also and you should I think
that what I believe
start you know caring about about
privacy to how the application is pretty
much handling personal data flowing
through it that's that when I say that's
privacy by design pretty much
so here this is a kind of head-to-head
comparison okay
right now pretty much the process that
is described people you know promote
these is the first one policies what I
kind of call policy driven so there's
just a change to security policy or a
security architecture or something you
know that kind of goes top-down to
developers or security architects and
that process can take a lot of time okay
and I'm not saying to discard that but
what I'm saying is that kind of to start
doing something right away as part of
the security efforts okay so that's why
the main difference engineering dreaming
you know versus policy driven these are
all concepts coming from from the you
know these cathedral and the bazaar you
know kind of approach the other thing as
much before you can build on top of your
existing capabilities so the techniques
used for doing PII detection so techie
personal day they are not very very
different so it will take some time you
know to kind of walk these the learning
curve but at least I mean it's the
techniques are not very very very
different and the other difference is
you know typically all pretty much all
most vendors they approach the problem
from the data perspective that means
that you know they scan your
repositories and look for PII you know
personal data and they kind of flag that
I think that's that's very limited
because you know before you have the
actual data goes to the database of some
repository a lot happened and typically
the application is in front of that okay
so if for some reason personal data is
being leaked for some whatever bug or on
purpose who knows you know you're not
gonna know so I believe you do have to
protect you know your infrastructure
your databases whatever but you also
have to protect your software as much as
possible and make sure that the software
using the cloud which is something very
different
it's also
some privacy quality standards so it's
it's very difficult to know that
actually the other thing I'm suggesting
which kind of goes against my interest a
little bit is try to build your own
stuff you can make third-party tools but
try to build your own stack because
every company is different there is no
silver bullet okay this same thing I
think applies to security at least the
companies I know I work with they all
have their their own stack you know to
deal with security I think same thing
should happen with with privacy so this
is a kind of instead just we were I was
kind of I was a like ten ten thousand
feet okay so let's let's go a little bit
deeper
okay so let's you know this is one of
the concepts we've explored I've worked
directly with that but it's just one of
the experiments okay that we eventually
experienced from all these prototypes
eventually gets into the product or
whatever but this is something we've
open sourced and something out there you
can play with kick tires to whatever we
want it's just something as an example
that there are things you can do with
not so much effort so the main things
you know with privateer what is privy I
try VIH is basically geared towards
trying to detect personal data flowing
throughout your API endpoints okay so
any personal data flowing from from
let's say a web service yeah okay should
be and can be detected okay and at least
you should you should know and this what
I believe in is kind of to apply this
strategy while the application are being
developed now not only applications in
production so as your developer
application you can start checking
whether there are applications that are
just transmitting personal data into
your text okay for instance so as soon
as you start with the with your
development cycle you can introduce this
kind of practices so the the other so
these are kind of the challenges there
was no data set when you have
machine learning model you need the data
data is kind of the key thing at least
this is what I has been my experience so
if you don't how can you teach the
machine to pretty much know what is
personal data and what it's not right so
this was one of the one of the issues of
course there are no standards I didn't I
didn't want to into an approach where
you have a human being kind of labeling
and say yeah this is probably this it's
not that that's a lot of money that's
too expensive and of course PII is not
out there online right you cannot find
easily Social Security numbers I mean
you can if you want but I mean it's it's
not it's not legal right so that that's
pretty that's pretty tough so of course
there is they're practically I at least
I'm gonna have a very little very few
projects dealing with PII okay or
something that's related with privacy
you know kind of that works so it's kind
of you're pretty much alone okay there's
not much on that from just many several
commercial products but you know you
don't have the source code to to learn
from that okay so this is high level
architecture but we're gonna kind of
split it
okay I'm gonna I'm gonna it's going to
be clear as we kind of split it here so
so let me let me check the time and I
want to run okay so pretty much so since
we don't have the data there is a
technique in machine learning it's
called a which is basically generating
your own data set okay
the problem with that is that the data
set will be probably biased will be
artificial and will not match real-world
data okay so that's it's a very you have
to be very careful with that because if
not you know it's not gonna work you
know maybe it works in with your test
data but then when you run it with
real-world data it's just not going to
classify correctly you know any any any
restful api message so
so this works very much in the in the
following way so what we what we
essentially did is you know you know we
we wanted to generate the example API
request restful api requests so pretty
much Jason payloads okay so the way to
do that dream easily was to kind of tap
into existing restful api infrastructure
so instead of sending the message
through out the wire we can just save it
right we can tap into the into the
request generation process and we can
just say okay we're not gonna send it
for otherwise we're just gonna save it
okay so that's that's pretty much the
approach now with the data it's not
graph you have to tell you have to
actually define what kind of one or
whether that's it has PII or doesn't
have PII oh okay personal data promote
PII is personally identifying data so
that's why you have you know we use a
very basic approach and there's a lot
you can do in terms of improving the
labeling so Lebanese that is saying okay
this is VI this is not and for now it's
just binary but you can have many
different labels like this is PII this
is financial information this is health
care related information and there's a
lot you can do on that front okay we're
gonna explore a few few strategies at
the end so bottom line we have we have
these requests we can we label this
request and then there was the challenge
here I mean let me go I explain the flow
here the problem was that what we used
as an input we're open API descriptors
so how do we know how requests look like
so the good news is that opening FeLV
API descriptors are actually available
online they're pretty good quality so
with that we can actually we can build
pretty real world looking API
messages okay in terms of structure
think about you know how Jason messages
are tipping structure in API
communication okay so that that's what
we use and and this is what pretty much
I've I've explained okay one important
note it's this is just a baseline for
you to get started then you you know
ideally you want to to get some
real-world data you know into the into
the model because it's you know it's
gonna be it's gonna be very
domain-specific you know if you're a
financial institution your API payloads
will look pretty different from you know
healthcare you know service provider
okay so it's for now open API
descriptors is pretty much you know you
have a lot of descriptor from online
banks from Google Amazon Microsoft
whatever so it's it's kind of generic
but if you if you wanna you probably
have here you know your own formats that
you wanna you want to build on so the
training is pretty much easy so once
again there's something very interesting
you want to look which is called Tara's
it's a Google framework which pretty
much abstracts you from the complexity
of deep neural networks I mean you still
have to know what you're doing but this
the whole heavy lifting of creating a
deep neural network is pretty much you
know kind of solved by by carrots okay
so instead of implementing whatever your
your code will be instead of being 300
lines it's gonna be probably 10 or 15
lines okay so it's a it's more concise
mortars but at the same time you still
want to know what what you're doing but
it's it's much easier so that's why I'm
and kind of you know using Harris it's
also obstructs me from the specific deep
neural network framework so I can I can
I can use Microsoft I can use I can use
tensor flow like in this case so you can
you know whatever it's supported by
carriers you can you can use it's not
really like
but there are some features with
downward as expected so this is an LST M
there's a whole discussion about why you
know I'm using Alice TM but it's it's a
type of you know within neural networks
you have many many different topologies
lsdm happens to be really good at
processing at a kind of natural language
processing tasks okay so it's a it's
pretty much the main I think feature is
that it's able to remember kind of facts
that happen before so when you're
processing a Jason message it's a
sequence right you want to know when you
find the social to your number what you
know what happened before you know
because you have other Jason objects
before that right and that that is is
relevant okay because it pretty much
tells you whether that's you know a
typical Jason paler or not okay so
that's that's what we're using with with
this
so the training works as much before
it's here it's a little bit more detail
but it's vector headings is pretty much
let's call it the it's like the native
language of any machine learning
framework that that's the that's kind of
the the main representation the core
representation because you will you
cannot just paste our inject text just
like that you have to create something
that pretty much is all you know numbers
digits okay so the model doesn't really
know that it's dealing with text so you
have to pretty much map the text to
something that is that can be processed
by a deep neural network okay and
there's of course the mineral networks
you know you can invest if you want ten
years you know investigating that
there's so much but I do believe that
with with not significant knowledge you
can you can start experimenting and kind
of empirically you know and and and then
eventually you know whatever is missing
you know you can you can focus on that
or get training on that whatever or you
can just learn him by by yourself okay
so it's I think we are leaving a very
interesting times in terms of that it's
it's new technologies more approachable
and I believe security people are
typically the curious type of people and
I think if you're couriers and you're
willing to spend some time you know you
can perfectly if you look at the code
you'll see that the training piece is
like it's like pretty much the core is
like ten lines 15 lines of code okay of
course it's very basic it's it's it can
be improved significantly but still you
know it's a way to get started so so
once you have the model right you need
to do predictions with pretty much ease
you know you get a JSON payload and you
want to you want to make sure you want
to know whether that contains or not PII
of course not gonna be a one boolean
response it's not binary it's gonna give
you a kind of probability say well
there's a 70% chance that this is PII so
it will depend a lot what kind of data
you feed you know into the model so it's
very sensitive to that and the other
channel
is that you need a lot of data okay it's
not just a few few requests and curious
I think I was able to generate about a
30k you know data points so it's just
enough I you can you can generate much
more you know there are different
techniques to generate you know more
more entries eventually you can use add
other API so whatever so the prediction
works in this way you get the let's
assume you're in live system you get the
JSON request message you then you have
to vectorize this so transform it to
this representation that is AI friendly
let's call like that and then you say
well now tell me if this contains a PRI
or not and then you get you get this
probability okay so it's you know SPI I
here so this is pretty much why I
explain you know I I'm trying to I also
describe that so for the record so that
you know this presentation will be
available for download so you can still
still there okay
things to consider I said before and I
you know this is just a baseline
something you can use to start with it's
not you know depending on the data and
how you generate and how is how the
tools configure you you're gonna get
better
output or worse output okay so and one
of the key things here and I believe is
how you generate these synthetic data
this kind of fake data and the other
thing is labeling how do you know
whether that request is really PII or
not for now we you know we're using a
pretty basic techniques with trigger
words I'll say you know when we find
some some hint in terms of this could be
yeah yeah you know we just label a it'll
say well this is PII okay but there are
many more sophisticated techniques you
can use typically with natural language
processing it's it's a way you know you
can analyze kind of the JSON pail and
say well this this might be this might
be a PII contain PA you can label that
as PA
or not of course the other thing is that
of course you know a completely
automated approach doesn't work you
typically want to make sure that any any
labeling action has been taken or at
least the ones you're not you don't have
a lot of confidence it's actually
validated by a human being okay and say
well this is actually wrong so you can
improve or the person can say this is
okay and this or this is not okay so
you're going to improve the quality of
the model and the other thing once you
get the mobile online you want to make
sure that you know that model is updated
you know kind of a real-time not
real-time bad at least you know
continuously and and that that I think
applies not only for to pry API applies
to any 20 model but the the challenge
here is I think the synthetic data set
if you have a real-world data set I will
go ahead and use that instead or combine
it you know so let's see how much time
do we have
okay any questions so far I mean okay
yeah go ahead sorry I have the defense's
like yeah
I cannot hear it you have a make or I'm
sorry
yeah thank you yeah that's good okay so
yes so far like this is actually helping
go like as far as understood like food
like the linking of the API itself so
like if if the area is leaking some
other information back but maybe there
is like another use case where there is
for example like I have like my API is
not leaking any PII band it's probably
like I have like a developer the just
put the print statement and like that
print statement is just like login PII
in an elastic search cluster or whatever
mhm
that is actually like a login this
information in a place where it's not
supposed to be right like in an insecure
place that likely just like somewhere
else from the API but like based on this
model do you think that it would be
possible to actually set up like some
integration to actually check like if
there is because I know that like my
macro service or whatever like my API is
actually connected to an asset search
cluster right so like do you think it
will be possible to integrate this with
that elastic search class that I'm just
like make like the same kind of request
like whatever like like and just like
check if my PII is ending up in places
where it's not supposed to end up so you
mean in terms of for instance just
checking or classifying maybe Jason
messages that are not necessarily API
requests or responses could be documents
or a story in the file server or
something like that
anylock really maybe I'm logging this
kind of stuff it actually the demo I'm
gonna provide it it's not you know it's
not going to use live API requests it's
just pulling API requests from there
from a folder so you can actually you
can actually use pull these you know
it's just JSON payloads so as long as
using JSON it's fine if you want to for
it if you have XML you have to implement
your own parser okay because right now
we the only constraint says that it has
to be Jason okay but this Jason can be
any work store anywhere and you can use
just an API if you don't want to use the
command line interface you can just use
it as a sort of library you can just
grab the model and just use cameras if
you want to run the prediction whatever
you want how
it's it's there's no there's no
restriction in terms of how you can run
this classification process
alright thanks boys yeah
yeah yeah I have another question so in
terms of the model itself how does it
deal with outliers and how would you
handle for example changes on the
definition of the personal data if
something like in terms of policy
changes to a little more fields yeah
that's a good question as I mentioned
before go back here you can there's
there's a configuration descriptor for
now where you can you can configure your
what what is known is we know using
Python it's called faker so it's pretty
much those are like components building
blocks that you can use to generate fake
data and this can be customized so if
you want to generate social security
number you can use the social security
number faker or whatever so if you have
a specific data type that you want to
handle like let's say maybe health
record ID or something like that you can
build your own faker that's in terms of
the synthetic data set okay and then if
you have your own let's say open API
format and you wanna you wanna add the
model to know that you can just you know
injected into the catalogue so pretty
much the the data saturation process is
pulling it's pulling all the all these
descriptors you know from from this
category so just you can just add it to
the color and that way it will learn how
your your your specific Jason message or
payloads look like okay so so it's a and
then if you want to remove you know kind
of be do something more sophisticated
you can just work at the labeling phase
and you can use
you know natural language processing
capabilities and and also introduced the
you know human okay so that you make
sure that the model there you know has a
you know improves in terms of quality
you know the prediction okay thanks so
that's let me see if I have some time I
just don't want to it's gotta be yeah I
have three more minutes so let me see if
I can switch
actually interesting let me see if I can
okay now I'm seeing while you're seeing
okay now let's
okay this is just you know there's
there's a comment which is a shell
common I'm gonna you know it's Python so
what I'm gonna do I'm gonna run the
prediction task on top of a bunch of
JSON requests that I have okay
and I let me let me try to expand this a
little bit okay it's not that bad so I'm
gonna run this then I can show you don't
worry about about the the warnings
typical impotence of things so the
important thing is here the model is
generated is loaded you know this has
already been trained with generating
predictions and then they put you know
and the prediction of story in a CSV
file okay so predictions are here okay
so we're gonna we're going to type these
predictions we can we can see an you
know D JSON payload but what is this
saying this is magenta which has a lot
of PII actually is consider P is costly
PII you see this one it's actually flag
saying yeah it's PII and this is the
probability 92 percent that is PII and
then there's an Atlassian Jason which is
just a random in Atlassian Jireh you
know confluence is just just kind of
standard Jason with no personal data and
you can see that it says that it's not
PII okay it's zero and and and then the
other this is other it's just a misc
also J so we can we can see as some of
these Rob this also makes an Alexa as
you can see it's labeled as one ninety
two percent that is has PII
let me let's see for instance Magento
okay this is where where this is coming
from
see has a lot of information by your
first name last name region California
so it's pretty much saying this looks
pretty much as as PII okay and then we
can see for instance let's see route you
know so kind of going going back to to
your one of the questions I think the
first question was was whether you know
you could you could use these for for a
general purpose task yeah you can you
can't this is just a route definition
it's not even it's not even if this is
like a descriptor and you can still run
the PIAA process on top of that okay and
let's see an X is also Jason and well
it's singles here that this has PII its
can be questionable but it's seen that
there is a user user ID it's technically
you know it's its sequence its little
bit and anonymize but still they thinks
that that this is kind of a confidential
which it just selects so it's not that
bad that is saying that but answering
the second question here's here's how
you can you can actually define all the
all the fakers you know I mentioned
before you can say for instance you know
full name you want to use the full name
faker but if you want to use a different
one you can implement your own on top of
the fakers library
you know figures it's a it's a very
known pie in our library so if you're
not happy with the default ones you know
and as you can see this is really really
really basic you know I just enter you
know like credit card just basic basic
stuff but this is you should you know
this should be much more complex in case
you want to make it you know real world
and you know it can pretty much also
detect types so you can you can you can
also based on time you can have your own
generators and and that's that's that's
how it works there's much more but you
can you can just go to the website and
there's more documentation on on that
and and then I you know open source the
whole thing so you can also generate
data
called the whole data set generator is
also open source it's everything it's
you know with an apache license so you
can do pretty much whatever you want you
can sell a do whatever you form with it
okay I think I'm done let's see if we
have any question but I think I have to
leave room for the other speaker we have
a couple of more minutes or yeah let's
see if if we can if we have any any any
question already hello
yeah how's it going you and other other
tools like they seem to be focused on
focused on like feels like names or post
codes or social security numbers like
dependent fields can also be personal
data so where I have like a collection
of information on its own that isn't
like personal data the combination can
be identifiable yeah do you consider
that in your product this is this is yet
pretty simple you think about like a
sort of I would say it's still like a
prototype but if you want to implement
that it's part I would say it's part of
the labeling process so you can you can
actually say for instance social
security number it's linked to this
other field let's say it could be
information about your whatever your
maybe you know the account the bank
account or something related with your
you know where you want your your
security you know your money to go for
instance so you could eventually link
that I would what I would work there's a
toolkit called called snorkel it's
there's a whole branch in machine
learning which is called data
programming okay so their problem is
pretty much creating synthetic data sets
you know and and this this is this very
popular toolkits called snorkel I would
really check it out and then with that
you can actually do even something more
interesting you can
can apply natural language processing
techniques so it can be a little bit
more fuzzy than just connecting you know
dependent fields so you can say well I
find a social security number and these
also term is close okay it's closer it's
closer maybe it doesn't match SSN
specifically maybe it's match social
security number and you can extract more
semantics we then I'll be in techniques
and once you extract more semantics you
can level label your datasets better
okay so that's that's what I would
strongly suggest if you want to go kind
of real war you want to you want to make
sure that the labeling means very
specific to your domain your business so
and I would strongly suggest using LLP
and snorkel it's a great way to start
without snorkel it works really good
it's one of the upgrades we are thinking
of but right now this is just when a
prototype we're working on a kind of on
a product on a different area connected
but quite different but I would I would
check that it's called snorkel it's just
really simple source on get have a great
great product so I think the questions
are open but I have to leave so I will I
will keep answering questions so you can
you know leave it open until tomorrow so
you know just log into slider and PBDEs
the the keyboard okay I'll try to follow
up you know with everything any question
you have okay thank you so much for
anyone that likes to join us we are
doing an AMA with Alisa the keynote
speaker in the community corner but
there is a coffee break now