almost done almost done now comes the
point whereby we can give out some
prizes and say some thank you so okay
right so we got there I big thank you
everyone to making the fifth the fifth
dev second in London really memorable
and obviously it was definitely
memorable for some of us who had to cram
a lot of late evenings in the last week
but what's next well you've seen this
slide with plenty of dates that where
we're going to be doing dev SEC on next
year the penultimate one there dev SEC
on London September 30th to October 1st
the news already booked in it's going to
be the design no was at the BDC the
business design centre in angel we have
we have under under good get information
that their their accounts seem
reasonable so hopefully we won't have a
late shock like last time one big
important thing for us is that is that
you know we want people to provide us
with feedback and the feedback that we
want is really about a sessions about
the the way that the day's been
structured about the content about the
speakers about the food about the venue
about the accessibility what would you
change to make the conference better
also from from my personal snick point
of view I really want to know what you
thought about the snick acquisition as
well as whether you felt like you know
the conference was too sneaky or not
sneaky enough or just right so please do
give us that feedback and keep us keep
us you know continually improving dev
SATCOM okay the Leadership Awards so as
I mentioned Def Con in Seattle launched
this new awards program and we want
reward people who are individuals
communities and also dev SEC Ops teams
in and around the world and we've got
some awards that we want to give out to
individuals and I'm gonna go through
each one and we're going to give them
out - well I believe one of them is here
others maybe around the globe but the
first one is the outstanding deaf
Cyclops community of 2019 now for the
last literally ten years I've been
running many communities meetups all
around London and virtually as well and
I know how hard it is to run these
communities firsthand how much how much
time it takes and you know it's very
very rare that we find people who run
these communities actually do it as
their roles a lot of people are doing it
into their night and so forth so these
were their finalists for the dev psych
ops community of 2019 dessa
dev psych ops Netherlands Open Security
Summit dev Cyclops London gathering and
to have sex India and this was this was
brought down to a shortlist and then
voted on by certain members in the in
the CFP the the CF people would who
looked at it looked at the information
and provided the answers so I'm very
pleased to give the first award in this
group to dev SEC ops London gathering so
a big round of applause to dev Cyclops
London gathering and do we have do we
have anyone from the dev psych ops
London gathering team here at the top
thank you very much that's the wrong one
so Michael Michael has spent many many
many many many hours doing a whole bunch
of work on the London gathering I've
personally been to many meetups as well
so I know how much effort Michael put in
so please give a massive round of
applause to Michael man
[Applause]
not sure it's possible for me to have a
camera pointing at me and me not to hold
my gun I don't if that's a natural thing
right next up so inspiring dev say cops
individual of 2019 finalists so we have
Dominic - Schmitt we have muhammad imran
and we have michael man and the winner
of the inspiring to have said cops
individual is how many hands have you
got Michael oh that was mean wasn't it
it was Mohammed so give it up for
muhammad imran so we have an award for
mohammed mohammed is actually in
singapore so we're gonna be giving that
one to mohammed in march march in
singapore so and then finally we have a
short list of second he's here in
december at depths are cops london
gathering there we go we will give it to
him in December in London excellent and
finally the most effective dev SEC ops
team of 2019 we had a shortlist of two
MongoDB and Telstra and the most
effective dev SEC ops team as judged by
our panel in 2019 is Telstra so please
give it up for Telstra as well and
Telstra are based in Sydney I believe so
unless the whole of Telstra are coming
to a meet-up in dev second London
gathering I think will probably give
that to them in March next year so now
for people in the room who's done there
who's done their passport hands up if
you've done your passport call whole
bunch of people right so we have a back
here and Tammy q want to pick a few
names we have three iPads that we're
gonna give a giveaway so tell me if you
want to pick pick one and apologies I'm
gonna bastardize every name that I read
oh this is an easy one Kevin Sanderson
is Kevin here hey there we go
[Applause]
okay and our second winner is Connor
frein is Connor here hey there we go
[Applause]
there your health and safety okay and
the third and final winner has bad
writing earnest Bettencourt's earnest
[Applause]
awesome so final thang used to say and
first of all very very important say
thank you to our sponsors I hope you had
some great conversations f5 snicker
platinum sponsors Jeff Rivera code
secure code warrior hacker one its ownit
iPad gold sponsors and last what
Eileen's least defect I'll bet the other
way avatar equal experts contrast
security areas risk and detect afire
as our Silver Sponsor so huge thank you
to them without a sponsors literally
this wouldn't happen and there is one
massive person on last a person sorry
Tammy there is one very very important
person who who we need to say thank you
to and that is Tammy so I want to bring
Tammy up on stage to say a huge huge
thank you again literally if if if Tammy
hasn't worked extremely hard over this
last week we wouldn't have have this
conference so little thank you there
congratulations Tammy and also someone
else who has been very very supportive
of Tommy over the last number of weeks
months years decades maybe Sam Sammy and
if you want to yes absolutely please and
Sam has worked extremely hard not just
supporting to have set calm but also on
the secure developer as well as my dev
SEC ops community say thank you very
much and if you want to if you want to
help with dev SEC on please have a name
that rhymes with either Tammy or Sammy
and if there are any other staff as well
as volunteers that have helped please do
come on stage we want to say a big big
thank you to everyone who you know
without the logistics this this wouldn't
run as smoothly as he is so please thank
you to everyone and yeah please comment
in all around and speakers if we have
any speakers left please come up on
stage massive massive thank you to all
the awesome content and I'd also like to
say a big thank you to Hawker house and
the catering obviously it's not just our
team that had to work extremely hard
over the last week but hawk a house all
the logistics that they've needed to
take on in a very very short timeframe
how I would do when to be actually
signed the contract with
Walker three days ago so you know
there's a huge amount of logistics that
need to have happened in the last three
days to make this possible massive thank
you to everyone the catering has been
awesome as well really really great
we'll have John where's John John over
there somewhere John massive thank you
weary John I can't see this lights are
so bright well John the guy at the guy
he's taking photos
awesome awesome and there's I've already
seen a whole bunch of photos really
high-quality photo sooo so look at all
the photos and then hi John as well and
last but by no means least Rico's Rico
there Ricardo hey Ricardo come on up man
and bring that bring as many of the team
as you can so that this can keep
recording as well Ricardo Ricardo has
done a huge amount of work as well in
fact Ricardo we were going to be using
Ricardo as well for a code note as well
right and we brought Rico as well up so
please come up on stage so Rico's been
awesome all talks are going to be
recorded we have filet v and also Rico's
team we're also doing a lot of the audio
in the other room as well so a massive
please give it up one more time for
everyone on stage let's not let's not
let it end here as well we have my dev
sir cops as a community so please
continue the conversation online you can
go to my dev sack oops
io and join up for free get catched a
whole bunch of new content and and yeah
continue the conversation and the videos
for this will be on my dev se cops
community so you can catch all the
videos on the YouTube channel there and
that's a wrap so see you next year make
sure you buy your tickets when they
start coming out you'll all be on the
mailing list
September 30th October 1st 2020 in the
be business design census rolls off the
tongue thank you everyone and please
save travels on the way home
[Applause]