so good morning everyone my name Stephen
Archer from f5 I can't really see you
very well because I'm being blinded by
the lights but just out of interest I
wonder how many of you have actually
heard of f5 Wow that's well about
three-quarters of you I would guess okay
so the title of the presentation is what
is ingress really so the main aim of
this presentation is to answer that
question I'm also going to talk about
what I five are looking to do in the
kind of near and medium future and talk
a little bit about f5 cloud services and
yeah I guess if you've got any questions
of us our booth is just inside the the
first door there so please come and see
is a little bit later so first of all I
wanted to share some news if you hadn't
heard I mean how many of you had heard
that recently back in May a five yeah
completed the acquisition of nginx and I
just wanted to share some of the views
of the new combined team those from the
f5 side and those from the nginx side
and I've actually personally been
working pretty closely with a bunch of
the nginx guys over the last six months
and we've formed a really fantastic team
so from the f5 side those of you that
know f5 I mean we have Prague the most
comprehensive a DC solution anywhere and
we I guess if you're a service provider
we could provide you with you know eight
bladed chassis that will handle billions
of current connections handle you know
multi terabits per second of traffic
it's a very complex product very capable
very open architecture and we can handle
huge workloads but we can only shrink
down so far so the smallest we currently
make that capability available is in the
form of a virtual appliance but the
acquisition of nginx means that we now
have a data plane that can run in a
container so the nginx source code is
tiny you know less than 2 megabytes in
size so that means that we can go into
areas that we previously couldn't and
from the nginx side they tell me that
they are really really happy with the
cultural fit within f5 and and also
they're really really excited that the
extra resources that f5 can bring to
nginx now f5 have also committed to not
just maintain in the open source but
we're actually going to increase our
efforts in in open source so that is not
going to go away and I think from the
engine exercise that they were working
on nginx controller I think they had a
team of around 20 people and since May
we've moved a comparative team in f5
that we're working on a similar
controller into the nginx business unit
and that is now a hundred and forty
people so nginx have really been able to
accelerate the things that they wanted
to do with controller and we're going to
be delivering the first kind of combined
product later this year and early next
year so there's some really really cool
stuff on the way so back to the title of
the presentation what is ingress really
and what I wanted you to do and this I
built this presentation after talking
with various people at devops
communities and you know meetups and
conferences like this and some people
and I'm sure in this audience many of
you will already know what ingress is an
application ingress in particular but
many don't have a clear idea of what it
is so what I'm going to do is start the
beginning explain what it is and then
we'll get a bit more
technical after that and the way I want
you to do it is with an analogy now one
thing to say is the application ingress
or ingress as a term has been co-opted
by a welter almost to exclusively mean
traffic arriving into a kubernetes
cluster but it's much much more than
that so in this analogy I am one of a
supplier of your company and I need to
deliver some goods to your organization
so in order to do that the first thing I
need to do is to make some inquiries so
I get on the phone and I found one of
your call centers in order to try and
find a precise address for one of your
warehouses so speak to the person I get
an address of a warehouse and this data
they're all sorry this these goods that
want to send is analogous to sending
data to an application the warehouse is
analogous to an IP address and you know
telephoning the the call center is
analogous to a DNS lookup so I've got
the precise address so I can now start
to pack the goods into crates so these
are data packets of course I can load
them onto a truck and I can lock the
truck with a padlock and the padlock is
provided kindly by your organization I
don't have the keys and this is
obviously analogous to TLS encryption so
now the truck is ready to roll so I can
plot a route to the warehouse and this
is obviously the equivalence of routing
across a data network but there's a
problem with the warehouse for some
reason it's not available so I need to
go back to the call center to try and
find an alternate location now if this
was DNS I would keep throwing the call
center and they would keep giving me the
same address
obviously we've seen that that address
is not available so you know this can be
a problem with DNS if the call center
was the equivalent of GSL B or global
server load balancing then immediately
they would be aware that the warehouse
is not available they would be able to
give me a different address of a
warehouse that was available and had
capacity to handle the incoming Goods so
that's what happens
we now have an alternate address so I
can get my my truck on the road and when
I arrive at the warehouse which is
equivalent of your application IP
address I'm sent to Bay 443 and this is
obviously equivalent of a TCP port and
once there the employees within the
warehouse have the keys for the padlock
so they're able to unlock the truck and
unpack the crates opening the crates
there are smaller packages inside and
these packages have additional address
labels addressed to other individuals or
buildings within the organization and
one of them is addressed to mr. Baldrick
and he could be seen as an equivalent to
a vulnerable web server with access to a
database and he's opens his box and
finds a free gift inside a nice pair of
bluetooth headphones with a dongle and
through social engineering he plugs it
into his laptop but obviously this is
analogous to executing malicious code on
your web server not a great place to be
so a question would be would you allow
trucks from anywhere in the world
locked trucks to drive straight into
your warehouse without any checks
whatsoever and I mean I I wouldn't but
actually this is what many organizations
and many of our customers are doing
they're allowing
cryptid traffic all the way through to
their web servers so when we look at
automated deployments actually the
picture is worse there I say many of the
people that we speak to find that trying
to automate securities is difficult and
therefore we find you know a small
number of people or customers who are
able to do full automation so I'm
talking about CIC dsquared where we've
got automation from from the application
all the way through to the ingress where
you know you've now got your application
available and on the internet the
challenge people have mean with with
with security means that either they
miss out that last mile so you know
within the development teams automation
is working just just brilliant but then
they have to open a ticket with an
infrastructure team in order to open
firewalls and other things so you're not
gaining all the benefits of automation
the other alternative is that actually
we just forget about security or
together in in the infrastructure which
I obviously think is not a great idea
but it really genuinely does happen so
what could we have done differently so
first of all we could have checked the
routing manifests um that came with the
lorry and we could have identified that
it came from an unfriendly nation-state
and actually we could just have an
embargo and block all traffic from that
nation-state and this is equivalent to
geo blocking quite a simple security
technique we could have checked the
credentials of the driver or the
registration plate of the lorry and if
we looked on a crime database we could
have seen that those were associated
with a previous crime and we could have
blocked on that basis and that's like an
IP reputation database we could have
checked the fingerprints of the driver
and that's kind of like device
fingerprinting
and we could have found that you know
that device we've seen you know
performing malicious things previously
now when the truck got to the warehouse
what would it have looked like if we'd
have implemented a network firewall well
I guess it would have been somebody
saying you're not allowed to go to port
4-4-2 and you're not allowed to go to so
port gate four four four you're only
allowed two four four three now in this
warehouse four four two and four four
four were locked shut
anyway so it didn't really provide much
benefit so in this scenario a firewall
doesn't really do very much a firewall
cannot unlock that truck it doesn't have
the keys so it cannot inspect the goods
it can only make sure we go to Bay four
four four so what about wife if we put a
wife in this scenario it would be kind
of like creating a secure zone at bay
four four four where we unpack all the
crates so a wife has the capability of
obviously decrypting the traffic so you
know we can now start to unpack the
crates have a look what's inside and
specifically talking about f5s wife we
have a normalization engine and it's
it's unique to f5 and what this does
it does multiple classes of decoding so
in this analogy packing and unpacking
smaller and smaller boxes kind of like a
Russian doll and only when we get to the
the smallest doll which is the raw HTTP
do we then start to apply our signatures
which means we have a much smaller set
of signatures so you may look and look
at other wife technology and find that
they've got more signatures than we have
but this is the problem for one attack
they all have a signature for the big
doll the next doll the next doll and
then they kind of run out of capacity
whereas we can keep going we can unwrap
these dolls and we only apply the
signature on the
core HTTP underneath actually you can
choose how many dolls you open and if we
reach that limit so if you set four for
example we might do for decoding rounds
and at the end of that if we're still
faced with another doll that you can
open another round of encoding is needed
will just determine that that's an
attack and we will drop the traffic okay
so if we look at other things we could
have done if we'd have sent all of these
parcels to a mailroom that's kind of
analogous to an API gateway where
additional inspection of the addresses
the HTTP headers is done so in the
mailroom they may have certain addresses
that you know are not permitted so you
know they'll been or hopefully recycle
whatever they find and letters to the
CEO would probably be opened by a PA and
in given another level of inspection so
there are lots of things that we could
have done differently or better so
hopefully I've kind of explained that
ingresses is more than just packets
arriving in a kubernetes cluster
actually ingress has or application
ingress has a whole number of
infrastructure components so we've
talked about DNS GSLV routing networking
woth but there's other things DDoS
mitigation and things like health
checking circuit breaking a be testing
service discovery and so on and so and
so on there's there's lots of functions
that are included in this all of these
functions are performed by an
application delivery controller and ago
ingress is actually application delivery
so what I want to do now is oh I meant
to say actually
No so customers have many components
that form their ingress data path and
typically we're talking about I don't
know seven to nine is kind of typical
these are the common ones listed here
and what you'll find is that you talk to
ten customers and they'll have ten
different sets of services with
different vendors no two customers
really are alike
and it's a complex picture and I'm sure
you all have a similar picture to this
in your environment and it gets worse
many customers will have different sets
of Enders for different application
architectures so for the monolithic
applications they may have a different
set of vendors in place different teams
are making decisions and buying
different vendors for micro services and
then you move to public cloud and you've
got another set again and what you tend
to find is that these individual vendors
kind of organizations tend to create
silos around them so you have multiple
silos along this data path and then it
gets even more complex because you know
if you've if you've got you know
multiple environments then you know you
may have even more silos and each of
these vendors have their own management
interfaces their own orchestration
frameworks and it becomes really complex
to be able to manage you know each team
in each silo are comfortable with their
interface other teams maybe maybe not
and and it means that when customers
want to do automation they need to learn
all of these different capabilities and
the peculiarities of each of them and
it's left to the customer really to try
and stay
them all together which we think is a
big problem and I'm sure you've all been
in a position similar to this I mean
I've been at f5 for nine years and
previously when I was a consultant you
know I was on calls till goodness knows
what time at night trying to diagnose
problems and because f5 is always in the
data path
we're always involved in those calls I
like to say rarely are we the cause of
the problem but I guess I would say that
but I like to think that's true trying
to diagnose which of these solutions you
know is the cause of the problem is
really hard work with all these silos
blaming each other you know not
necessarily being as helpful as they
might be it can be really tricky so this
is the the power of the combined f5 and
enginex you can see that we've got a
presence in every step between the code
deployed on the application server all
the way through to the customer with f5
technology we're actually reaching into
the browser even with with JavaScript so
we're literally from end to end we are
the only vendor that has this end-to-end
capability so this is what it kind of
looks like today you can see we've got
some nginx stuff here as big IP stuff
here nginx at the end but between us we
can be deployed in any architecture and
actually we've got many different
consumption models so whether you want
to you know buy your own license or pay
hourly or whatever you want to do
there's a solution for you so what we
what we're doing next and we've already
started on this is that we're going to
start stitching together the control
planes of all of our products because at
the moment they're kind of separate and
one of the things that we're working on
is is project overwatch so this is
providing a
consistent single pane of glass to be
able to manage all of your device's
components and services we're also going
to be adding in capabilities to add
other vendors into that solution and
that's delivered software as a service
in the cloud so that's one of f5 cloud
services new services it's available
today in preview we've also got things
like intelligent threat services so this
is a capability that's being built by
our security team there's there's lots
of capabilities there we'll talk a
little bit about them later and of
course we've got yeah future services so
we're going to expand on this code to
customer story so we're going to be
adding new capabilities in either end
we're working on many of them already
some of these are partially available
already but we're again going to build
on those and I suppose once we've got a
single coherent platform for management
and visibility the next step is to start
creating insights from that building
intelligence centralized intelligence
that can really provide business
benefits out of this fantastic
visibility that we have of your
application end to end
so I was probably a little bit chicken I
was going to do a live demo I thought
actually you know what I'm just going to
build some slides that show the demo
just in case anything went wrong so why
do we need ingress security well I mean
I'm I'm pretty sure you all know better
than I do that you know building
applications and building security into
up locations is not a perfect science
there are things that you can do
obviously having a fantastic engineer is
probably the best of them somebody who
really understands security
but there are tools out there you know
such tools and you know dependency
libraries and stuff like that that will
allow you to identify some of them more
obvious kind of vulnerabilities there
are server-side security tools that you
can deploy but again none of them are
perfect and you know I talk to customers
who tell me that in order to try and
detect all of their vulnerabilities at
the code level and they're using half a
dozen different tools because no one
tool is perfect and can cover all bases
and actually using them all together is
pretty much unworkable now I'd be
interested to hear your views on this
I'm not going to ask you now but if you
disagree with me and you think that
actually it's possible to have excellent
security through the you know the build
process then please come and tell me
because I don't want to be at the next
conference telling people lies so you
know I'm kind of regurgitating what I've
heard from from our customers so how can
you automate security there are a number
of things that you can do and the first
of those the thing on the left is is
negative security and on the right it's
intelligent security and these are the
only two ways I I think that it's
possible to build security into the
ingress into the data path
so negative security is signatures but
if you want to automate a solution that
uses negative security and signatures
then those signatures need to be highly
accurate and f5 we have all of our
signatures are categorized in terms of
their their accuracy so you want to use
our high accuracy signatures we also
have a service called threat campaigns
which allows us to bring in very high
accuracy signatures on demand and in
reaction to what kind of attacks are
actually ongoing in the wild today and
as those attacks modify and changed then
we'll take those signatures out and
replace them with with different ones so
the trick with negative security is the
more accurate your signature the more
computationally expensive it is
so with threat campaigns we have very
high accuracy but we have a low number
of them and they're targeted so that's
really useful we also have bot
signatures so bot signatures are again
really useful a lot of the bots are
quite helpful in that they provide a
user agent so they're easy to identify
bots thing which is very very low false
positive and others that try and emulate
a browser and often fail to get the HTTP
headers in the right order and then some
try and pretend to be good bots but on
so we can do a reverse look-up on the
source address of that bot and determine
whether it really is a good bot or not
so there's lots of things we can do with
negative security but I think far better
is to add some intelligence into the
system and this is something that we're
working on at f5
there's a lot of work going on on
centralized analytics so centralized
understanding and finding fingerprinting
of every single device on earth that's
the goal so that's underway but today
what can we do well positive security
for an application is a much better
place than negative security so I'm
going to show you a little example of
how our
declarative API for our advanced wife
can help with that and of course today
we've got very limited time so there's
only so much we can talk about actually
the most difficult thing has been
actually what do we have to leave out
today so back to this slide that we saw
earlier we're going to kind of focus in
on application security and I hope this
is visible to you all it kind of looks
okay to me so what this is this is
a screenshot of my CI CD pipeline in
gitlab I'm sure yours in reality is
going to be much more complex than this
but it really just kind of proves the
point
and shows that adding positive security
actually can be pretty simple so we've
got some dependency scanning sassed
we're building and deploying to staging
then deploy the wife the wife policy
onto the wife in line in front of the
application in the staging environment
so this is the wife policy its JSON its
declarative so we just post this to the
wife and it will deploy this this policy
so we define the policy give it a name
we define the template that we want to
use so we have a number of templates
built in on the platform but you can
create your own with your own standards
but this is a good suggestion Rapid
Deployment the enforcement mode blocking
or transparent you specify the server
technologies that you're using for your
application in this case we've got my
sequel and unix/linux
and then we've got blocking settings so
what I've got in this case is that I'm
going to block on file types so we have
a default list of file types that we
deem is okay you know pretty safe things
that you would expect for a web
application and because obviously the
screen is not long enough this is a
continuation so signature settings so
I'm not going to put my signatures into
staging and putting them straight into
production so to speak and then I'm
going to for my policy builder I want to
learn from you know testers not not from
bots and then I've got a couple of web
hooks set up so so we now have the
ability to send web hooks so this one is
going to be triggered every time we
apply a wife policy and this one every
time we receive an illegal request so in
my lab this goes to slack but you can
obviously use this to to trigger your
pipeline and then we've got a
modification section and because this is
a base policy there are no modifications
yet so those parts of defining the base
policy and the adjustments so the
adjustments I mean things like you know
making your application specific
so like the server technologies the
blocking settings and so on and then
here we're defining the policy
modifications of which there are none
yet so this is my pipeline so I've now
deployed my wife policy and I've got
some some testing some functional
testing so again in my lab it's just a
few curls to pull different files down
I'm sure you're so way more
sophisticated than that but in this case
my requests were rejected actually
blocked by the wife
so next my pipeline reaches out to the
wife sends a curl and asks for an export
of the suggestions so suggestions in our
wife what the wife provides you when
you're in learning mode so as you're in
your test environment and the wife
policy blocks something and it will give
you a suggestion and say well actually
if you meant that to get through to your
application you need to disable this or
this or this so there are suggestions to
help you loosen the policy to fit the
application so when you send a girl to
to the API this is the response that you
get in there is the suggestions and we
have entity changes that it's
recommending and in this case we've got
two of them I've got space for the rest
of that down there but there are two in
this case and that section we can just
pull that out and we can merge that into
the policy so you can see in the
modifications section I've literally
just merged those straight in there and
I can repost this because it's
declarative back to the wife and then
rerun the pipeline and second time
around it's now successful so I've
deployed a policy I've run some test
traffic the wife told me what I needed
to do to make it better I fixed it I
rerun it and now everything is working
so now I create my production tag and
then I can deploy boom to production
then I can do my dashed testing you can
get your pen testers in and you're on
the road so hopefully that all kind of
makes sense
pretty simple example but I just wanted
to explain how easy it can be so don't
let anybody tell you that automating
security in the ingress path is
difficult so just a quick couple of
minutes on f5 cloud services so this is
the mission the objective I should say
cloud native software as a service
solutions for enhanced application
delivery security and insights so what
we're doing is we're building a whole
set of new services and platforms in AWS
energy or other clouds to follow so some
of those for example we've got global
server load balancing as a service
authoritative DNS we've got overwatch
that I mentioned earlier and essential
at protect is is kind of like a a subset
of wife features and that are available
as a service in the cloud or when you
decide to to purchase one of these
services you login to the portal you
purchase the service and we deploy
containerized instances of our
technology in the region that you want
to deploy in so for AWS for example you
know if you want to deploy in UK sorry
you Wes to you specify that and we will
deploy your service there and we'll
connect with your environment so with
that hopefully I've answered my own
question which is what was ingress we
talked a little bit about what f5 and
nginx are doing together and what we're
doing in the future
and if you've got any questions well
we're just through the door over there
so please come and say hello come on
tell me I'm wrong if if anything I said
didn't make sense to you and of course
yeah any questions come and Sears thank
you very much right sorry I should have
said I thought we were running late so
yeah if you've got questions yeah one
quick question could you provide perhaps
one or two specific actionable takeaways
for your talk that would benefit
attendees regardless of if they buy your
product actionable takeaways so I think
that the biggest challenge we have as a
vendor is that we're trying to build
solutions that will allow you to break
down those barriers between the silos
and organizations so you know devstack
ops I don't know most organizations dev
SEC hops they're not combined and and
that's really my suggestion really is it
you know we can build the tools but you
guys need to build the organization that
can leverage them so we have all these
automation capabilities we've got
fantastic capabilities but it's getting
the development people talking to the
guys that actually probably own the silo
that own f5 in your environment so that
would be the key takeaway go and talk to
them find out who they are try and smash
down those barriers and get automating
because it you know once you've done
that it's easy does that answer the
question no I don't believe so
thank you anyway Costigan what based on
your experiences what can someone do
some effective practical thing someone
can do that's not by your product
like maybe some insights you don't worry
about it
I was gonna say you're not gonna get me
to say don't buy our product don't buy
our product no Dubai product any other
questions
we're good thank you very much as we've
got 20 minute breaks