okay thank you
um so I'm going to talk about the PHP
allocator yes but I'm going to talk
about how you can exploit uh remote
binary bugs onto PHP as well so that's
the important part I'm gonna illustrate
with one zero day maybe one like another
one if we have time but one should be
enough
so we are really quickly we are a French
offensive security company called lex4
we are based in France and we have two
technical blogs one about Canada and
system which is
blood.lexo.fr and mode which is more
about web exploitation which is
ambionics.io blog
um well PHP and I have been feeling with
PHP for another 15 years I really like
the language for exploiting it uh
I've found a lot of bugs on like
standard Frameworks such as Drupal
Magento stuff like this but I'm also
into binary exploitation as I was sure
today uh I've published a few sandbox
Escape bugs you might think that sandbox
Escape in PHP is useless it basically is
but sometimes it's useful because in PHP
you could have like disable disabled
functions so you find a RCA on the
website and you cannot execute any
function so it's pretty annoying so
using a Sandbox Escape bug you can
actually call any function you want
also it's useful to get access to the
process that is executing PHP and if you
get access to this process maybe you can
access the master process that runs as
fruits and this way you can probably get
a local route on Apache or on PHP fpm so
that's why I did a long time ago and
also maintain a PHP GGC which is
basically why so serial but for PHP so
it celebrates payload for entire life
which is php's digitalization function
decoded and serialized for some reason
foreign so a quick history of PHP and
binary bugs
as you know PHP security is pretty
approximative
like the comparison here returns true
it's a hash and a float and it says true
for some reason and there have been like
lots of bugs that are still in patch
because PHP doesn't really care if the
bug has to be exploited locally
so you have many sandbox Escape bugs
over the Internet the thing is you don't
really have remote exploits available in
over the Internet so I'm gonna try and
change this
um so what kind of bugs can we find in
PHP work PHP is a weekly type scripting
language so it needs to type check and
wave count variables properly otherwise
you can have bugs such as type confusion
where for instance an array is used
instead of a string and use after three
bugs where something is free then you
can fill out the memory with something
else and then you get some kind of
primitive right
so it's very easy to export locally
because you're just writing code so that
would be basically the same as writing a
JavaScript renderer exploit you're just
writing PHP so you can set up for the
bug for instance you can like create the
e-player that you want then you can
trigger the bug for instance you create
an object and call some function that is
vulnerable and then you can use the bug
you have your primitive and then you
want to get like called execution with
the bug so locally pretty easy to do
however remotely it gets a little bit
harder one thing is really annoying when
PHP creates a like receives a request it
will create a heap allocate your inputs
so get post cookies stuff like this and
then it will run the code and then
discard the Eep entirely so if you have
a new uif for instance so use after free
well it will be gone uh after the record
the request has been executed so you
have to find a bug you have to find a
CMS or framework that actually uses the
function that has the bug then you have
to find a way to trigger it and then you
have to use the bug afterwards all in
the same request so it gets pretty hard
also you have a few limitations since
it's a data that is sent over HTTP you
have limitations on the size and you
have limitations on the types you can
usually only send like strings or arrays
luckily the those are the two types that
we need to exploit so it's
perfect voice we also have to beat ASL
and buy remotely obviously and we have
one thing going for us uh crashes are
pretty much okay because there's always
been going to be always sorry gonna be
your main process the main process runs
as roots whenever you crash a walker is
going to be respond automatically uh the
main process doesn't really care it just
responds it if it crashes and also that
means that the every worker has the same
aslr and by randomization so if you can
leak the aslr in one worker you're gonna
have the same aslr in the other worker
so to illustrate a little bit when you
do a remote exploit generally you're
going to have a few steps a few
interactions and you're going to set up
the Eep get some kind of leak with some
bug then set up the memory get some kind
of Auto bug and then probably like spray
the Eep to put your object instead and
then get some kind of shell in PHP well
you have to do this in one request so
that's what it's pretty annoying
one thing to note though is that since
we have the same aslr and Pi on
different workers we don't really care
about getting a leak in one request we
can get a leak once and then afterwards
exploit with a second request so let's
say that you get two requests to exploit
so to me it comes on to picking the
right targets like what kind of function
can I look into to find the bug that I
can exploit remotely with PHP
well the go-to candidate has always been
until allies and why it is because it's
basically a way to interact several
times with PHP in one request
and serialized is PHP digitalization
function as you can see in the payload
here invites it describes an array with
two elements and then in this array
there is an object which contains an
attribute and then there is another key
that contains a string so that shows you
that you can basically create any kind
of memory layout then create an object
potentially trigger a bug on this object
and then use the rest of the array to
fill up the Eep or modify the Heap again
and get a really useful primitive so
this is a really good function to find
bugs into if you want to expose remotely
however well entire life is not that
much use anymore because it was pretty
much a way to destroy any PHP website
for I don't know 10 years so
I kind of wanted to look at something
else
and so my idea was I wanted to look at
database driver functions the idea with
this is that when PHP interacts with the
database it's basically a way to
interact several times with PHP all in
one request
also that's a way to use a bug after
you've triggered it for instance you
take you trigger a bug with one SQL
query and then when the second SQL query
comes in you can potentially change the
IFA layout and use the bug that you have
created
the setup phase where you have to like
set up the layout it has to be done
another way but I will describe how you
can do this
so uh I reported two bugs the first one
we're going to talk about a lot and the
other one may be at the end if we have
some time in any case the second one I
couldn't find any useful CMS or
framework that used it so it's basically
a user's bug the other one however it
affects any kind of database management
utility so admin PSP my admin any kind
of share hosting I don't know CMS
stuff like this
so before I talk about the bugs we have
to talk about php's internals and don't
worry it's very very simple and we are
only going to keep it for anything we
need
so obviously PHP is a weekly type
language so it has to store every
variable with a type and then the
representation of the Bible so if your
variable is a string the type is string
and then it's the description of the
data is stored in a Zen swing structure
for an array that would be type array
and then array structure so before being
used every variable is type checked so
PHP will check the type and then it will
reference the complex object
that is instant value and use this
object instead
we don't really care about zverse
because they are mostly allocated on the
stack or at places that we don't really
care about in the Heap but what we care
about are complex types I will describe
only two types these are the only two
types that we need to exploit so then
swing and then array and coincidentally
it's pretty good because this these
those are the only types that we can
send Using get and pass data
so what is this answering well obviously
it stores a string in PHP so if you
create a string with like three
characters PHP is going to create a Zen
string structure and allocate it on the
Eep the elements are a GC which contains
the ref count and some Flags the hash
value we don't really care about this
one then the length of the string and
then right after this the buffer of the
string is not a pointer to the buffer
it's just straight up the buffer as you
can see in the X damp here like you have
the headers so the GC the Ash and the
length and then straight after this you
have your buffer and the final final
null bytes so if I send a string of orix
14 characters it's going to allocate
enough space for the header so ox18 plus
the length of the string of x14 and then
a nude byte
foreign
as an attacker obviously we can control
the length we have a good Advantage
because if we can make PHP think that a
string is way bigger than it really is
we're going to be able to see the memory
that comes after the string and by
seeing I mean writing and reading so
that's a pretty good way to get control
over the in PHP
the second structure that we're going to
look at and that's the last one is
underways so obviously it represents a
PHP array which is more like like it's
more it's closer sorry to a hashmap than
an array and we don't really care about
what's inside it but the last element
which is very strictor the restrictor is
a function pointer which is called
whenever you remove an element from an
array so in the code snippet here the
descriptor will decode on the first
element so one
the good thing about this is that as an
attacker
if we control the restrictor that means
that we control the PC because we can
simply clear an array or wait for the
request to end when the request ends the
arrays are deleted and super respecter
gets called
so now you have enough to understand the
local PHP exploit it's really easy so
you use a bug to correct the length of
some Zen string so the the length is way
bigger than it should be then you get
read write Primitives over the E for
free because you can just use the array
notation
and then you can spray arrays and in the
Apes that you have leaked you can find
the address of a pedestructor you can
just then change display
sorry and then you can insert the array
and the structure will get caught and
you get coexecution very very simple
however to understand remote exploits we
have to go a little bit into the php's
Eep which is the simplest if I've ever
seen so it's very easy to understand
um so two main functions one to allocate
one two three uh to allocate you use
email log n to allocate n bytes and to
free you use E3 of some pointer
the epin PHP is a memory region of two
megabytes is divided in pages so you get
like a five uh 512 Pages the first page
of the Eep is going to be metadata we
don't really care about this one but the
rest is used for storage
so what do you saw in Pages you saw
chunks one page can only store chunks of
the same size so for instance page 10
could store chunks of size 8.
page 11 strength of size 16 of 32
anything and this is all determined by
the heat metadata
if we want to allocate more than a 3072
bytes however the allocation is going to
be straight in pages instead of using
chunks
so how does the allocation and the
allocation work well for each chunk size
PHP will maintain a linked list of three
chunks okay which is called a bin
um
so there's been zero for chunks of size
eight then bin one for size size 16 etc
etc up until 3072.
so when you free your pointer PHP will
just take the pointer address find out
which page it is in then did use from
the eat metadata which bin it should go
into
and then from there it's going to put
the pointer at the beginning of the
episode at the edge of the linked list
when you want to allocate it basically
does the opposite it finds out the bin
for n so for instance I want to allocate
14 bytes it's going to use bin one
because it's chunks for size 16. and
it's going to remove the head of the
list and return it for us so it's a
lethal structure
obviously there is a edge case where if
the bin is empty PHP has to create new
chunks so it will just look at the
metadata if there's nothing in some page
it's going to reserve the page for some
chunks and then you will create the
chunks in the page and add them to the
free list
so quick example to understand it on the
very left there is the Eep with its
Pages let's say let's say that on page
10 you have strength of size Ox 100
those chunks are reside in B9 so if they
are free they are going to go in B9 so
let's say for instance the bin looks
like this at the beginning if I feel an
element it's going to be added on the
beginning of the list and if I allocate
it's going to take the elements from the
beginning of the list right very very
simple it would be like t-cash and see
ellipse for instance
so now we have enough to understand the
the first bug which is a hip overflow in
the MySQL energy
so obviously you need to understand what
is MySQL indeed well it's a PSPs on
MySQL driver so PHP devs developed this
thing
and it's pretty pretty horrible like
I try to fuzz it and like I couldn't
reach any important part of the code it
was just crashing crashing crashing plus
it's super slow because it's VSP
obviously so I was like I hate fuzzing
anyways I'm going to read the code and
that's why I did and so I got this bug
um this bag is pretty easy to spot
actually
when you connect to a database the
database can ask you for several
authentication methods and if the
database tells you to authenticate with
clear text PHP will just send a MySQL
header of size 4 and the clear text of
the password
the thing is if your passcode is big
enough is going to want to allocate your
password with the header but it only
allocates the size for the password
so when it does the mem copy afterwards
you get four bytes word of bound right
so 4 byte overflow so to trigger the bug
you just have to force PHP into
connecting to your database with some
use passwords a new database then says I
want the clear text password and then
PHP allocates the wrong buffer size and
then it gets the Overflow there
so Target of choice for today was
adminer which is a database management
PHP utility we often find this in pen
test because like the Cs admin puts it
there they use it once and then they
forget it exists and then you just go
onto the website type slash adminer.php
and then you get this
so the idea behind admin is very simple
it's one simple PHP file and then you
give a server address username password
you can connect to it you can then issue
queries you can then import data you can
then export data it's basically the same
as phpmyadmin like any kind of database
management utility but you can connect
to whatever you want and for us it's
perfect because we want to connect to a
Vogue MySQL server a server that we
control with a password that we control
as well
okay
so if we go back to the Primitive PHP
will allocate our password on at least
two eight pages because the password has
to be bigger than one page
um so the idea is that we can override
the first four bytes of the next page
right very simple
um what can we override with four bytes
well we could try and override a Zen
swing or as an array but we would only
overwrite part of the wave count so it
doesn't really matter I mean we could
exploit with this but it gets really
complicated so my ID was more to exploit
by overwriting partially the next chunk
the next pointer of a free chunk when
the chunk is free is going to be in the
linked list so it's going to point to
another frame check if we can modify the
address of this free Chunk we can alter
the link list of the bin and when we
allocate for the strings well the linked
list is going to be modified and we're
going to be able to allocate a different
spot so maybe do other things
the standard ID behind this is that we
try and make two chunks overlap when we
control the linked list and then we can
overwrite a structure such as the Zen
string or send away and we are getting
pretty close to well code execution
the only problem with this is that
whenever we use admina the first thing
that PHP will do is connect to the
database but to exploit the bug we
really need to do a Eep setup like a
some kind of if
layout that we want to have to exploit
the bug
so the only way for us to do this is to
use get and post data right on cookies
and whatever but the input so we can
actually do this do this pretty easily
as I'm sure you know there are two
things that you can allocate in PHP
strings uh very simply like page equal
news and ID equals one two three so you
will get news allocated page allocated
ID allocated and one to Fair located all
as then swing objects and you can also
send a raise if you use the bracket
notation you can force PHP to create a
race that's pretty good but that's on
the allocation what we want to do is
free as well uh once we do that we can
simply send the key twice if we send the
key twice PHP will first allocate the
first value so in this example value one
and then you will realize that there is
another key so it will allocate the
second value value 2 and then you will
free value one so this is pretty good
for us because only with get and post
data we can allocate anything
basically anything and free basically
anything as well so this is pretty nice
however there's one thing that is
annoying uh whenever we send a variable
it's going to be duplicated so it gets
allocated twice so when we free it as
well it's going to be free twice as well
but it's not that hard to uh to to
understand and to bypass afterwards so
only with gas and post data we get a
very precise Eep setup so that's pretty
good
uh as a quick example uh as how we can
do this let's say we want to create a
hundred chunks of size 0x100 and we want
to free one in the middle right
so how do we create a chunk of seismic
700 we send the string of size Ox E7 why
because the header of the string is
going to be headed so it's a 1 8 in
hexadecimal plus the null bytes added as
well and so this end up being this ends
up being ox100
um so then we have a string of size 800
what we can do is send it 100 times
because we want 100 100 chunks and we
want to free one in the middle so we
just change the value of some value in
the middle of the array so 49 here and
we get our if setup
so it's very easy
so what is the current state of affairs
we can set up any kind of Eep layout
using only get and pause
um we can trigger the bug by simply
asking adminar to connect to a rogue
mySQL database so the mySQL database
asked for all clear text passwords and
that triggers debug and then we can use
the bug because we can send arbitrary
query results when a PHP sends SQL
queries
so let's try and exploit with this so
that's why I asked for the pointer
and so
first thing that we need to do a good
Eep setup so the idea is to have two
empty pages in which the overflown
buffer is going to be then the Red Zone
which contains uh freed chunks what we
want to do is Overflow here in the
pointer here so they Point somewhere
else and then a use region here which is
one megabyte long which you can do
easily by sending a get and post data
which is one gigabyte long
and and that's it that's a good setup so
then what can we do well we have to beat
a setup first
so gig was to make this pointer here
instead of pointing to one of these
points here if we can make it Point here
we can then control the free list
entirely and then we can allocate
wherever we want which is pretty good
however
we have to buy data SLR so the first
bytes that I care about are these ones
in the middle that those are the like
the highest bytes that we can uh touch
with the Overflow and so this byte and a
half you have
4096 possibilities so you can just put
forces over HTTP is not that long but
there's one question how do we know that
we are indeed pointing to huge well to
do this we can test every address twice
once with the region filled with zeros
so when we actually point to this
address we will get this
pointer which points to nil because we
only have zeros here and so the
allocation will work however
if we fill the region with FF
the free list will be a little bit
and so PSP when it allocates will
simply crash
so this this allows us to determine the
first one and a half bytes
we got a few not a few more to do the
idea is to repeat the process keep the
same address but this time split the
region into on the top zeros on the
bottom FF so I start the exploit again
if it crashes that means I am on the
bottom
if it doesn't I am on the top and so I
can determine very precisely where I am
in this region
there's one more byte to determine this
is the fifth byte byte 5 is not
reachable with the Overflow because we
have a four byte overflow so the only
way to do this is simply since we
control this this region is to create a
fake pointer here remember we we know
these bytes now so we create a fake
pointer here and Brute Force like 256
possibilities and after this we have
beaten the aslr
and we also have a complete control over
some free list
so this is pretty good to exploit
the next thing that we need to do is
disclose the Eep to get information
about the Eep layout and the pointers
that are in the well to do this since we
since we control some free list we can
make it so two chunks overlap and so we
allocate the Chunk on the bottom with
the string and then we allocate the
Chunk on the top to overflow to overflow
into the first one
and from there we can just change the
length of the string and when the string
is displayed well it's going to display
the whole Eep with it so we get a a hip
disclosure and we get a lot of
information from this
one of this information is when we
create a race at some point we're going
to see them in the Eep and so we're
going to find the address of the
descriptor the descriptor's address is
in the php's main program so this way we
beat by because we have the address of
domain program
then afterwards what we can do is simply
continue to use the the free list that
we have modified to go and modify the
whole centralized structure and change
the pedestrator if we change the
password we can just use the stack pivot
or just simply call system or Zip system
the PHP equivalent and when the array
gets destroyed at the end of the request
well it's going to copy the structure
and we get coexecution
so
you've already expect a demo now but I
was actually uh unlucky uh when I tried
to report the bug uh PHP actually
changed the code
um but it wasn't really on purpose uh I
hadn't reported debugger already but I I
saw that the uh they had they added some
patch because I think there was a memory
leak at some point and so they added a
new byte after the end of the MySQL
password so the exportation was dead
because you wanted to control the last
bite of the of the Overflow and if it is
zero then you cannot point to the huge
region
however it made me think that I was very
stupid and there was a way better way to
exploit so I'm going to show it this way
now
um
we have a four bytes overflow yes but
the allocation of the buffer is Page
align so if we send a buffer of size Ox
2000 -3 the Overflow is actually on one
byte so we don't have to deal with four
bytes of overflow we can just use one
byte overflow which is inherently a null
byte to get a new off by one in the if
so this is a kind of exploit that is
pretty standard so it's pretty easy to
get an idea of how to exploit
so the idea is we can change one byte
from anything to zero zero well what we
want to do again is change the next byte
the next pointer in a free list and for
this I will use a chunks of size Ox 70.
the reason is you want to pick chunks
that are not very much used by the
application normally because otherwise
when you do your if setup and then PHP
connects then you're going to have a lot
of new allocations of this size and it's
going to mess up your your setup so it's
annoying so I use this size and also the
good thing about this size that you
actually get useful addresses for
instance here if I override the two last
bytes it gets to zero so it doesn't
change anything if I modify this one
it's actually going to point to this one
again so you have some kind of circular
dependency and it's going to be annoying
again here it points to this one so it's
circular again it sucks what I want is
this one once a zero if I override this
one it points right before 150 so when
150 gets allocated
then this one gets allocated but it's
been modified it points right up right
before this and you get two chunks that
overlap
and then we repeat basically the same
expertise before we have two overlapping
chunks uh we get called execution from
this
so
uh you have to keep in mind this is a
new exploit so we don't have a SLR we
don't have a pi we don't know anything
so how can we do to do this well
basically the same setup as before we
don't need the huge block anyways we
cannot point to it anyways we just do
something like this but in this exploit
we really need to know which pointer is
here so how do we know this well
a good way to know this is simply to
free everything but keep only one that
you are located
if the value that we kept allocated is
on the top of the page it won't crash
but if it is at not the top of the page
PHP will get overflowed here and it will
crash
so here if it's on the top which we just
overflowing the right count and doesn't
crash so this way you can determine uh
the the post index of the value that we
are modifying the thing is I could use
dichotomy here in theory the thing is
well it's not possible because whenever
I send post data that has a different
size well PHP is going to do a lot of
different allocations so it's going to
mess up everything I've did I've done
here simply because I've sent a few more
chunks and so the Eep layout is going to
be and I'm going to in fact as
well so what I do is on this like free
everything and only send one more
element and this way I I don't have the
problem
in any case it's pretty fast I think I
have like 100 requests maximum it gets
done like really really fast
so now it's basically a problem of
setting up the free list
so what we want is we want to allocate
this one first because it's going to be
overlapped with the other one and then
we want this guy two points here why
because this means that
here you're gonna have the pointer to
here and then when we overflow it's
going to modify c0 here so it's not that
hard to do with get on post data you
just have to do a couple of freeze and
allocations if you have two pointers
that are messed up because as I said
when when you allocate with post it also
allocates with request you can just
allocate free and then reallocate and we
just swap the pointers around so it's
not too much of a problem and you end up
with this free list here so this guy
gets allocated first then we don't
really care about it then the guy on the
top of the page here gets uh is in the
free list sorry and it actually points
to the one with byte if we want to
overflow
so this is the setup phase
whenever then I trigger the bug well
the byte changes and so now the free
list has two overlapping checks this one
and this one and so then it's basically
the same expertise before
you make two strings overlap you leak
the Eep then you leak an array and then
from there you can modify an array and
just
call a bit Destructor on this array very
simple
I've got a demo for this
foreign
[Music]
so this is actually adminer but I have
messed up the configuration so there's
no CSS but you can recognize it I guess
and this
is the exploit so live demo so it might
not work obviously but
foreign
so I just created a PHP file at the web
root so that it's easy to understand I
just displayed ID as well here
I lost my mouse
thank you
what is it
oh sorry
[Music]
thank you
is this place strange or is it just me
no it's fine okay
so demons done
um so I actually thought I was on a 30
minute slot so I think I actually have
45 minutes but then we can talk about
the the other bug so quick conclusion
before we talk about the other bug
um php's Eep has no protections but
finding a bug to exploit it actually
requires a lot of
information a luck because you need the
bug then you need the CMS that uses the
bug and then you need to use it
afterwards so my advice if you want to
find remotely exportable bugs is to look
into and serialize maybe maybe there are
steel box in there but you could also
look at things that make PHP interact
several times with
um uh anything basically database maybe
I don't know like five protocols in PHP
you can do a lot of things with them
maybe you should look there stuff like
this or you could also find bugs that do
not disappear with the Eep and this was
supposed to be a teaser but since we
have some time left I'm going to explain
it a little bit
so PG query pumps it basically sets up
the parameters for prepared query for PG
and the idea here is that it will copy a
lot of Zen strings that you have sent
into an array that contains Char
pointers so if I send like threes and
swings as parameters it's going to
convert them into a chart array and then
add them to the array of chart pointers
so even around an error happens during
the conversion PSP will try and free
every pointer there is in the array but
they won't really matter they won't
really care if the array is initialized
or not so that means that if I can
trigger an error in the first element of
the array every other value is going to
be freed but those values weren't
initialized
so the Primitive that we have is a goal
of three on any pointer the thing is
this pointer we can't really control it
because it's on in an initial S memory
but how do we get a valid pointer into
this memory because we know that PHP
removes the Eep on every request the
thing is PHP removed the Eep but it will
use the same memory region to put the
the new Eep so that means that every
data that we have in the old Eep is
going to link the so we have a way of
putting any kind of pointer at any place
using one request and then triggering
the E3 on this pointer using another
request
so that means that for instance if we
are located differently in V class 1 and
request two we can make it so we have a
pointer that points in the middle of
some Zen string and if we have a pointer
that points in the middle of some then
string when we free it it's gonna add
the pointer to the next free chunk into
it and so when we display the string
we're going to have a leak of a pointer
uh same thing for the adverse if they
are allocated on the hip if if we free
the contents of the Z Val instead of
pointing to the original value so then
swing out as an array it's actually
going to point to whichever tank was
freed before so using this we can
actually get a whole execution using
this function but as I said nobody uses
this so it's pretty useless
and I'm done
thanks Charles for this great
presentation
does someone have any question
um thanks for the presentation uh do you
know if uh in php8 they changed the
allocator or something or improved
anything they didn't change much
basically it's more of a change from
php5 to php7 where they change a lot of
things not really in the allocator but
even in like the structures in php5 for
instance the Zen swing there was a
pointer to the Chart buffer so it was
way easier to exploit but in psp8 they
mostly made improvements to the op code
and uh not really to the allocator well
I don't think so I haven't seen anything
regarding this
and so basically the exploits here that
I showed easy you know on php8
other questions
no okay let's thank the speaker again
[Music]