hello guys my name is Roman
um currently I'm independent contractor
my main specialization is side Channel
and fault attacks I also work with
cryptography and let's say low level
attacks
currently I am in contract with Sony so
I'm mostly doing work for Sony
and in Sony I'm working in a team worth
let's say 15 to 12 20 people like being
honest don't remember we are spread all
over the world we are doing different
kind of been testing device when testing
application web services
um and the the main goal is to test Sony
internal products so that's what we do
I also have my small lab here in
Switzerland so where I have oscilloscope
PM fault injection glitches Etc so I
really perform side Channel fault
attacks here in Switzerland in all you
are very welcome to visit my lab if you
wish
I have more than 10 years of experience
I worked at Naga St microelectronics I
hold a PhD but I believe it's boring for
you to listen
so on the agenda for tonight it's very
short so I will try to introduce and to
reason
what which problems I faced and how I
try to solve them
I will show that I implemented an arc
version to gidra support so it's an
instruction set which nowadays
implemented in gindra
and later I will show that how this can
be used in order to emulate small
portions of code
and also how I can emulate faults in
this motion small portions of code and
clearly later I will conclude the the
presentation
so reasoning is very simple
well very simple you probably saw words
false and you probably saw a talk from
Nicola and Sylvan so what what are these
faults
false is something we
inject into the device so we take a
device and we can physically stress it
for example we can have a very short but
super intense electromagnetic pulse
nearby this device and device I speak
about microcontroller or smart cart or
whatever the device will not freeze or
will not mute what happens it will skip
an instruction it will modify some data
internally and an attacker can use this
in order to bypass certain security
measures for example faults they are
very commonly used unfortunately for
sp32 so esp32 is a very common Target
where Faults Are reported uh first it
was used to bypass secure boot then
esp32 fixed it then it was another
problem to bypass encryption and there
are many many problems but the esp32 is
not the only chip I mean all
semiconductor devices uh in a way can be
vulnerable to fault injection and there
are some open Publications from limited
results from failover flow from Thomas
Road and some other people where the
attack stm32 and f52 and many many many
other iot chipsets and smart cards
however
sometimes
when we develop a device so Sony
develops certain devices we want to
protect against faults so we want to
First in which kind of counter measures
we can put in order for example to
secure secure boot
and since the device is still in
production we cannot really work with a
device it's it's in production it's
still physically made but we're already
developing the code and we want to run
it and to help this situation what we
use its emulation
we use emulation in order to run some
portions of code but also we use
simulation to emulate fault injection in
the code for example we can skip
instructions we can modify data and see
how our code will react to this
in my case I ended up with this task
because I was working with a populator
instruction set which is has never been
supported by any reverse engineering
tool and I needed to implement certain
let's say I needed to implement this
instruction set however since I didn't
know which tool would be the best I did
some study to see
which tool I can use in order to
implement relatively fast and reliably
an instruction set so which will be used
for emulation and I ended up with the
three common tools it's gidra but true
and qmu probably heard of all of them I
did some studies
and to study how easy to implement an
instruction set I used Arc version 2.
it's quite a rare CPU Arc version 2 It's
relatively rare that's why it's usually
not very well supported so I did my
studies and I saw for example that gidra
well it's more suitable for me and most
suitable for my goals radar too can also
do the same job as ginra but is it's
less user friendly so and for me it was
very important to share my results with
other units and while other business
departments so I ended up with gidra and
today I'm going to present you the work
I did to support our version 2. I also
would like to show how emulation is done
and how I can do fault emulation with
gidra and gidra just couple of words
it's a very nowadays no one tool it
competes with Eda Pro it competes with
radar 2 it's uh it's nowadays complex
system so it has a disassembly
decompilation emulation and also
debugging facilities in one package it's
user friendly we can develop plugins so
it's it's a nice tool
foreign
once again step back
a couple of words about Arc version 2.
so in my practice I encountered this
device well this instruction set twice
um and since I suck so I am very bad in
reverse engineering and I I I didn't
have back in times nice tools I could
not do anything with Arc version 2
devices
so I started slowly step by step to
implement this version to supporting
gidra
but our version 2 is quite unique CPU
instruction set it's used in very
special purpose devices for example in
solid state driver controllers or I give
another example it's a high resolution
image radar chipset so it's not very
common and you don't see it normally on
the market it's still used in many iot
devices for example I list two of them
as there are some other devices which
are on the market and they're not very
disclosed
so but they're a very very very few
tools that can do reverse engineering of
version 2. nowadays
edible has decompilation facilities for
Arc version 2 but you need to buy it so
you need to buy a special model for this
and up to today the current state of
zart was work done by Nicola
EOS from Ledger dungeon he implemented
Arc compact it's it's slightly different
its predecessor of art version 2 but he
brought this support for gidrat so if
back in times it was the only he
released the the two in 2021 and it was
only
tool that supported sort of Arc reverse
engineering
however in my case Arc compact is
drastically different from Arc version
2. it has different instructions so for
example a version 2 is clearly more rich
in terms of instructions so I could not
use our compact also there are some
other registers which are totally
different different addresses so I could
not use his work in order to do my
reverse engineering
so I started to implement the this Arc
version to support and how easily it
works with Kindra so when you have
the mouse
seems not or whatever so when you have a
binary you take it's just a sequence of
bytes a binary we put it in gidra guidra
parse all the bytes and decode them into
the commands
foreign
bytes into commands guidra uses
so-called Sledge a description of an
instruction
and slate description it's what I'm
going to show you in in the next example
so let's assume you take one instruction
or some some documentation from CPU you
see on the top the table which
shows you how instructions shall be
decoded in our specific case let's say
you take two bytes first five bytes it's
a major opcode which will be used to
understand which instruction is it is
then it falls by three bytes which show
your register another three bytes
register two bytes like two bits sorry
I'm sorry two bits two bits
um show the sub op code so like measure
and sub-up code
answer is an immediate value so if we
want to write this instruction in gidra
what we will do we will declare a filter
token of 16 bits and we say that first
five bits it's a op code and then we
describe the other bits
for each of the fields we assign the
register set since it's only three bit
Fields the maximum number of registers
is 8 so you can see there are eight
registers
and then we simply write the instruction
for example add underscore s
it's followed with two registers and one
immediate value
will appear whenever
yidra will face this constraints in the
in the binary so whenever it finds an
opcode where the first fifth five bits
are equal to zero one one zero one
it will try to understand which
instruction will be decoded and print
out this instruction
for example if we take the value 6B A1
the binary representation of this
instruction is given like this and this
instruction shall be decoded in add
underscore s r13 r301
and I give you
um
explanations why either does this like
that
so if we come back to our binary
I really wish to find my mouse
yeah perfect
so if we come back our binary
we go to the to the instruction
we take these two bytes since it's a
little engine we need to swap them
so then we will decode
and we see that these two bytes will
correspond to this instruction and what
does this instruction do it adds to
register with an immediate value
and everything is done in gidra so this
was written in guindra Sledge uh
description
and it was decoded by the the guitar
correctly and we see
that our well our operations that we
Define to this instruction is really
taken by Gideon so when we will do
emulation
so this is disassembly so we take binary
we disassemble it into the instructions
and then also we can see that our
can decompile those instructions into C
code
now what we want to do is to emulate
those instructions and emulation is done
thanks to this uh descriptive language
slate or B code
and all this is defined in the
let's say in the
in the description language I'm sorry to
come back and hear so all this is
defined
in the instruction definitions
so I wrote
for Arc version 2 I wrote description
for almost all the instructions so
nowadays Giver can disassemble and
decompile Arc version to binaries it
contains module the the things I wrote
contains 5500 lines of code and there
are 380 instructions descriptions but
sometimes I the same instructions is
described twice in order to optimize
some speed
the
the code can be found to this address I
will release code publicly after the
talk
just keep in mind that this work is
still in progress and there are two
classes of instructions that are not
implemented so this
f32x5 class is not implemented because
it's mostly DSP it's signal processing
class and also F32 Apex it's this class
in Arc version 2. it can be only
disassembled because in advance you
don't know how this what this
instruction does a customer who buys
this CPU can put his own functionality
to the instructions
so just to conclude this first small
part
version 2 is quite rare CPU architecture
not very many people I mean very few
people take care about the question too
you could find support in the Pro back
in times but nowadays I hope thanks to
the tool I developed you can also do
reverse engineering of fact version 2.
it's not the ultimate goal of my project
My ultimate goal was to show you how we
can use gindra in order to emulate the
code
and for this
I invite you for the second part of the
talk
when we take our binary we disassemble
it we can decompile we can reverse
engineer it but also we can emulate the
code and how emulation is done
after we disassemble the code we take
our external python script
so it's a very simple python script I
will show you some code examples from it
later
and we jump to a certain address
and ask to execute whatever instruction
this address does so if it's addition it
will just basically execute addition
we will step let's say this instruction
and then we can step next instruction
Etc so we can step all the instructions
in the binary in some small space and
this will emulate our code
so make this emulation happen I wrote a
small
is 128 encryption algorithm it takes a
fixed plain text it encrypts with the
key which is let's say hidden inside
tables and it gets a ciphertext this is
a c code so it could be compiled for any
architecture so I compiled it for x64 I
executed and you see there as a result
B7 C3 Etc so this is the code example
that let's say that the highest API code
that I wrote but the same code I also
compiled for Arc version 2.
and I just assembled it with a tool that
I developed so this is a disassembly and
this is a decompilation of our
is you can actually see that Jesus
decompulation of the test encryption
yeah it's it's quite similar to the
original code
so the compilation really looks like SC
code
and it can only be achieved if we
correctly implemented instructions like
correctly you've described what
instruction does
just keep in mind that if there are some
complex instructions I don't know if
there are let's say there is an
instruction which modifies many
registers and jumps somewhere and does
something else for githra it's very
complicated to do the compilation after
so it can disassemble but the
calculation is pretty hard for Gita
and this how my python script looks like
for emulation it's very simple
so if I want to emulate my binary I
basically
set some stack pointer it can be
whatever value I want I initialize some
memory if it required for example I can
write plain text or I can write
ciphertext to do something else
I also Define registers of the CPU
and also Define some success exit
conditions so whenever I reach certain
point I know I know that my program is
finished
and the emulation is done like a simple
Loop so I go to the address
and I step into instruction so like this
all the emulation is going to happen
it's very simple
and with this simulation
I will show you
for example this is a test test
I don't see it very well on my laptop
yes it's a entry to the test encryption
so this is the first instruction where I
will emulate and on this slide I show
how emulation looks like
so first I print out my instruction
enter s
then I print out the CPU stack which
exact which is exactly at this moment of
instruction which exactly moment of time
I also print out all the CPU registers
and I highlight by Red here
registers that are used by instructions
and also I show the new and all the
values after the instruction execution
I also use for example some CPU flux Etc
so I can print a lot of information from
my emulation for example enter
underscore s what it will do it will
push the register to the stacks to to
registers to a stock
we see that this registers stop push
indeed and also it will decrease the
stack pointer value so indeed we see
that our python script thanks to gidra
can emulate enter underscore s correctly
so like this we can step all other
instructions for example I give another
example a certain moment of time we will
enter
um
and other functions called Cipher
underscore Unit 8
it's it will happen a bit later in the
execution
when it will happen our stock is going
to be already populated and some
registers of the CPU will be different
and that's exactly what we see so when
we will execute entry to this
instruction it's going to happen at
instruction
109 from the beginning so we emulated
109th instruction before
we see that our stock is already
populated with a plain text
and again we can see that the the same
some registers pushed to stock Etc so
like this we will execute step by step
until we get our ciphertext
in the console printing so I take the
ciphertext from the stack and I print it
here so like this we can take
whatever uh exotic CPU architecture we
can find it can be Arc version 2 where
it can be some proprietary architecture
and with gidra we can run the code
inside it so we don't need actual device
I found it's quite nice and Powerful
in addition we can do reverse
engineering and we can understand like
with thanks to the compilation what
exactly is going on
so this I found this very powerful
for example at the end of the
is execution my ciphertext is going to
be written after the plain text which is
very logical and you see it's B7 C3
exactly the same values that we got for
x 64 compilation
so now I would like to switch to The
Fault injection so we saw that gidra can
run certain parts of the code so I could
execute is in gidra without actual
device
now I want to show how we can use it in
order to inject faults
just to give you a bit of insight
so faults can be used to attack
cryptographic algorithms it was shown in
the presentation of Nikola and Sylvan
and I'm using what is called white box
cryptography I'm not going to dip to
dive into details about lightbox crypto
but it's a specific way to implement a
cryptographic algorithms where you hide
the key inside permutations inside
tables so you don't see key and clear
whitebox crypto nowadays quite commonly
used in in ctfs also for example why the
Box crypto is used in um
grms Google white wine using a white box
in the level 3 of the protection
so it's it's let's say used there are
common attacks on White box crypto its
differential fault attacks the one I'm
going to show you but also you can do
reverse engineering against mathematical
tricks and also there is a differential
computation analysis
um the very the basic idea of the attack
so inside is you cannot reverse order of
operations so operations are kind of the
same
so if you inject the fault just before
last mixed column operation of in one
byte this fault is injected in one byte
then this fault will modify only four
bytes on the of the output ciphertext
and by comparing correct and faulty
Cipher text and by redoing some
reversing some mathematical operations
we can find the kitten
so like this we can make an attack
there are very common tools to do it so
most probably you've heard of side
Channel models it's a tool from Philip
toewan and it's one of the most popular
tool to make this kind of operations
it's based on instrumentation Intel pin
or Val grid so it's one of the way of
doing this riskier also released their
own tool based on qmu to do exactly the
same
and you can find it it's based on radar
2 and nowadays with this let's say
support of gibra we can do the same in
general so basically I uh contribute a
bit in this tool sets
when we speak about faults so when we
take a device and we try to inject the
fault electromagnetic power so glitch or
whatever we don't know in advance which
effects we are going to achieve it can
be instruction skipping register
modification or whatever
we don't know so we sometimes we
observed very exotic faults in practice
however very common for CPU we observe
two effects it's an instruction skipping
and a second one it's a register
modification and I'm going to show you
emulation for gidra of these two
specific faults so if in our binary we
want to again my mouse we want to skip
an instruction
basically we will take the current
instruction we will read next
instruction address
we this we will write this address in
the program counter and then we will
continue our Loop without executing
anything Excel without emulating our
current instruction
it spreads as simple I would say
and when I applied this trick to my is
binary
for this is an instruction skipping so
you will see
which instruction is skipped so this
instruction 250 from the beginning of
emulation this instruction is located at
that oh my gosh at this address
and this is a mnemonic of the
instruction and if we skip it actually
nothing happens it can happen I mean if
we inject the fault into device
sometimes it doesn't happen the same for
for for the binary if we skip an
instruction which does nothing
it doesn't affect our final result
however later for example at instruction
700 when we inject instruction skipping
I'm sorry I need to do step back and
explain that this is a correct
ciphertext so this is what we expect to
see this ciphertext is what we obtain
due to a fault injection so we had this
ciphertext before without any fault
injection this ciphertext we get with
the fault injection and this one is the
difference between two draw of them so
it's the next door
so here when we skip instruction at 700
we see that our ciphertext is totally
different xor is totally different let's
say however if we skip instruction in
1250 we see that there is actually an
interesting diagonal and it's exactly
the fault model we are looking for so
there are four bytes modified so go on
to three four so a lying on kind of a
diagonal and this kind of faults can be
used to attack a yes so we can get is
cryptographic thanks to those faults
[Music]
if we want to modify register it's also
very simple we basically take a register
we
write a new value so we extort it with 0
1 for example we write this register
back
and we read it again just to be sure
that it the modification really took
place
and like this we can do again fault
injection I did it exactly in the same
instructions as before
and we can see again that this
instruction doesn't change it doesn't
change anything if we modify registered
this step it will completely corrupt our
Cipher text and here we have a diagonal
but with different values
so it just shows these fault models and
this fault emulation shows how we can
inject faults in the in the binary
however we are not limited with what I'm
presenting for example
you can imagine a situation that you
have a
signature computation over a small part
of the code and then you have a check
which checks if your signature is
correct or not so with default emulation
you can try to bypass this
check and understand at which moment of
time
in the execution of the real device you
need to inject the fault
application of emulation is not limited
to faults
for example there is a nice work which
uses gidra emulation for fuzzing so we
can run our binary and we can use
fuzzing with IFL American fuzzing logic
we can also do attack on whitebox crypto
again but we can use the simulation in
order to optimize our algorithm or in
order to check certain properties
just to conclude this talk
so givera emulation
um
is very useful I find it super useful
um any exotic instruction set for
example Arc version 2 can be relatively
easy added to gidra so we can do reverse
engineering the compilation
and also we can do emulation of this
nowadays gidra will have Arc version to
support so
I I have released it but I'm going to
continue the support of this tool
and this talk presented also how we can
use this simulation in order to attack
is
I give you some couple of useful links
which you can which you can check if you
wish
pretty much that's all for my talk I
would like to show you a couple of
examples like practical emulation like
briefly to show how githra works so I
will try to do it
tick tick tick
do all perfect you see it
so this is exactly the is
binary that I was
using
so on the right you see the
decompilation of my code
and we can jump for example in the side
for you and eight
we can go deeper and observe
how the compilation is done
so on the middle window let's say you
see the disassembly
and we can
show
what every instruction does in reality
for example when we use enter s we need
to push the registers into the stack and
we can read it here
so in order to emulate the code
I have a small
python binary which does the simulation
so what I will do I will go to script
manager and then run this
it will create few files for me to have
them
the logs and it also will play print out
the ciphertext and now if I want to see
the locks they are here
so every single instruction which was
execute executed contains printings of
stock contain printings of the CPU
registers Etc we can we can monitor
every instruction you wish so these are
all of them
if we go to the very end
we see how our stack is populated
now if I want to inject false
simplify I basically will do like this
so now I will inject faults in every
single possible instruction of my is I
think it's an instruction skipping and
then I can analyze whatever I want so
for example if I inject fault
instruction 900 my ciphertext is totally
corrupted but if I go below whatever
here for example
if I go here you see that my fault
injection caused some diagonal
modification which is super nice
this is an instruction skipping and if I
want to to have one
I know this is one bit fold but if I
want to have an instruction skipping I
just basically uncomment
inside my plugin
and again execute the
emulation
and you can see it's relatively fast
so that's pretty much all for my talk
thank you for for your time and I hope
you don't fall asleep