so in this session I'll present our work
on anonymous attestation with subverted
CPMs which is joint effort with young
combination onion laymen so if you if
you look at a computer nowadays and
typically it has a TPM embedded in it a
trusted platform module this is a tamper
resistant piece of hardware designed to
create secure cryptographic keys and
store them in a secure manner and use
them in a secure manner and what it can
also do is it can observe the state of
the host system so the laptop in which
the TPM is embedded and an example of
this is if if the laptop starts up
during the boot sequence then the TPM
can observe which software is being
loaded onto the TPM to end up with sort
of a report of which software the the
laptop started and now it might be
interesting to perform remote at the
station using this so the TPM will
convince a remote verifier that the the
laptop started some certain good
software so it's not running more where
but it's running whatever we expect it's
running for example if we look at a
corporate network you might want to let
laptops first attest that they're
running secure software before you let
them onto the network so this process is
called remote attestation and typically
this is a two-phase process first we
need to do some some registration step
the join phase in which the the platform
so the host and the TPM together talk to
some issuer that this is some Authority
in the system to obtain some one-time
setup it obtains some membership
credential after that the platform can
sign attestation so it can give a
verifier some some cryptographic proof
that that some TPM measurement is is
correct so in our example of the secure
boot sequence the TPM can convince a
remote verifier that the laptop started
the correct software so we can do this
with standard signatures in standard x5
and on credentials but then there will
be one problem and that is that your
linkable so whenever
send such an attestation to to a
verifier he will see the TPM identity
and it's you can you can follow you
around so if you if you do these at the
stations too many different verifiers
then your privacy will be lost so to to
prevent this people came up with direct
anonymous at the station or DAA and this
works the same as a remote at the
station that I described earlier but now
the other stations are anonymous so they
don't reveal anything about the
platforming question so this direct ones
at the station was introduced in 2004 by
breakout combination Chen and that was
made for the TPM 1.2 standard so and
during the time there was also some
privacy concerns about about the effect
of putting some some chip in your
computer that can can see what you're
doing so to address those concerns daa
was also introduced and included in that
standard then later the TPM 2.0 standard
came around and that's included support
for different and almost attestation
schemes but it still supported this and
since then this has been standardized by
ISO and hundreds and millions of TPMS
have been sold so this is quite a large
deployment of a cryptographic scheme and
there's also interest from other angles
for example the phyto Alliance this is
an industry Alliance that's trying to
standardize password list authentication
and they use amongst attestation to
attach that a certain cryptographic key
is securely stored and also Intel SGX
their trusted execution environment is
using a variation on da - as the remote
attestation mechanism and finally you
can see DAA as a special form of
anonymous credentials where you have a
secure device that handles your key so
this is relevant for for many different
different areas so let's look at the
security of da this is a sort of
signature scheme so of course we need a
form of unforgeable ax t and in
particular we we consider a corrupt host
so a corrupt laptop that can talk to a
to an honest TPM and batted in
and it can make many other stations or
messages and then we want to prevent it
from coming up by itself
on an attestation of a new message which
TPM never approved so in our example
about trusted boot this means that if we
have a corrupt laptop running the wrong
software it cannot come up with an
attestation that it's in fact running
the right software and second we need
anonymity this is why we why we're using
da and the anonymity requirement that we
have is that the verifier cannot see
given an attestation does not know to
whom it belongs or more precisely if you
give it to different data stations it
cannot even tell if it's from the same
platform or from two different platforms
and in this this we want this property
to hold even if the issuer so this this
this Authority and the scheme is corrupt
so even if he tries to give us bad
credentials and is colluding with the
verifier even then we want to anonymity
to hold so that's very good but there's
one surprising thing here and that is
that in this in the in all the
definitions of anonymity we trust the
TPM we trust that the TPM follows the
protocol and this is this is not what
you would expect because one of the
reasons to introduce da was to address
the privacy concerns of some chip people
don't trust this chip and but now the
notion of privacy requires us to trust
that chip in the first place and and in
fact also recent revelations have shown
that it's very naive to trust that some
piece of hardware running some crypto to
trust that for your privacy this is
quite naive and it's not what you would
expect from a security definition and so
in in in different fields in
cryptography people looked at sort of
subversion resilience or what what what
security can I have if if I run the
wrong algorithms and we want to do
something here in the same in the same
direction so so in this talk we're going
to look at can we do anonymous
attestation where we have privacy even
if the TPM is corrupt or even if the TPM
is not following protocol
so let's look at the existing security
definition of the a the most recent
definition is in the UC framework so
it's an ideal functionality and I'll
show you how sining works and how it
guarantees anonymity so the host starts
to sign a message so he gives the ideal
functionality the instruction that he
wants to sign a message and then the TPM
must approve the message and if the TPM
approves then the functionality will
perform some checks first it sees
whether this platform has has performed
the registration steps that that I
talked about earlier and then it will
output a signature and if the TPM is
honest it needs to output an anonymous
signature because this is how we defined
anonymity here and to make an anonymous
signature we use local computation in
the functionality so the functionality
has some algorithms and batted in it to
compute something that looks like a
signature and now how we guarantee that
what the signature that we output is
anonymous is by only giving the message
to the algorithm we don't give anything
that depends on the identity of the
platform to this algorithm and that
means that the resulting value cannot
depend on the identity of the platform
so that means the signature will be
distributed equally for regardless of
who is signing at this point and that
guarantees anonymity and of course a
verifier can use it and can use the
functionality to verify and that's where
we guarantee and forge ability but I
won't go into detail there okay so this
this is the existing existing
functionality so this guarantees an
anonymous signature if the TPM is almost
now we want to strengthen this to come
up with a functionality that also
guarantees is when a TPM is corrupt so
on first the first good guess is - we
had this check that we only output an
anonymous signature if a TPM is honest
now we're gonna do that even if the TPM
is corrupt but this is not enough yet
because if we consider the security
model that we're that we're trying to
achieve that means that everybody is
corrupt except the host
pewter and our corruptions are typically
modeled in a way that if a party is
corrupt that means that the adversary
one central adversary controls all the
corrupt parties and you see on the left
that that that the adversary who is who
has corrupted TPM C's with which message
a certain TPM is signing so it knows
exactly which messages the TPM has
signed and now if that if that message
if if we're not all signing the same
message but if the message is somewhat
unique then of course if the verifier if
a corrupt very fired and sees a
signature on that message it knows that
it was me so we don't have privacy
unless we're all signing the same
message so we could we could try to
prevent the adversary so we could
prevent the a valeri from seeing which
messages the TPM is signing by not
giving the message to the to that to the
TPM but this prevents us from having a
meaningful definition of unfor ability
because rumor
remember in in forage ability we need
the TPM to approve the signing of
messages so this does not work and we
cannot we cannot realize a meaningful
definition of privacy here but in fact
the corruption that we're modeling here
is very strong here we model a TPM which
is controlled by central APIs Airy
however in the attack that we more
envision is that a TPM is running bad
algorithms or taking bad randomness but
that is still a local piece of hardware
in my laptop so we need to refine our
corruption model so now we put the
adversary in the TPM in a jail cell we
limit his capabilities here the UC
framework allows us to define
fine-grained
corruption models and what we do here is
that we say that the adversary can
define bad behavior for the TPM but it's
limited to two that it's not controlled
by one central adversary we can do this
using this body shell paradigm that they
use and this way the TPM even though it
approves messages and can have bad
influence there it is not controlled by
the central adversary so the central
adversary does not see every match
that we're signing and we think this is
optimal privacy this is the strongest
privacy more that we could hope for so
we want to achieve this level of privacy
and in the real world we were then in
the same situation so the TPM is a local
corrupt algorithm in my computer but
it's not controlled by the central at
Missouri where the verifier and the
issue are still colluding and corrupt so
this is our this is our new security
model that we want to achieve now we
have to look at how we can achieve this
using protocols so first let's look at
existing protocols and how far we are
and all existing protocols use the same
the same approach of you use the same
common approach that is that the TPM
holds a secret key this is the only key
that the platform has and during this
this setup phase during the join phase
they authenticate to the issuer and the
issuer places a signature on a
commitment to the TPM key this is called
the membership credential after that we
can make such at the stations and at the
station is a zero knowledge proof
proving that a message was signed with a
TPM key that is certified by the issuer
so this is what all all existing schemes
follow and the differences are in which
signature scheme you use to make such a
credential or how you instantiate the
zero knowledge proof but other than that
they're all the same and unfortunately
none of them are good enough to realize
our notion of privacy for two reasons
actually the first reason is that this
zero knowledge proof that is the
attestation is a statement about the TPM
secret key meaning that the TPM and host
must together make a zero knowledge
proof the host cannot do it by himself
because he doesn't know this key and
that means that if we have a corrupt TPM
he might give some malicious
contribution to the zero knowledge proof
rendering the holder launch proof no
longer honestly generated so we cannot
claim any zero knowledge about this
proof and the second is that the
all the key material is stored by the
TPM and if the TPM is malicious that
means that we have no good key material
left and again that that means we cannot
have the anonymity properties that we
want to have so we come up with a new
approach where we address exactly these
two concerns so the first change is that
we no longer only have a TPM secret key
we also have a TPM corresponding public
key and instead of signing the secret
key in this membership credential we put
the public key in there and that means
that the zero knowledge statement that's
that we prove which is the attestation
is no longer a statement about the TPM
secret key
what about TPM public key and the host
knows that so the host can create this
full zero knowledge proof because the
horse is honest we know that we actually
have created a property or knowledge
group the second change is that is that
we split the key of the that we no
longer only have a key of a TPM but we
split that into two parts the host and
the TPM together create the key that
means that even if the TPM is malicious
and creates a bad key the host adds
enough good key to to come up with a
with a proper key of the platform
altogether so this this new approach we
show that we can with this approach we
show that we can realize the the level
of privacy that we that we previously
defined and I'll give you a bit more
detail here so we specify three building
blocks that we need to reflect the the
picture I showed in previous slide and
with those three building blocks if we
give secure instantiations those give us
a security a scheme the first thing is a
split signature this is very similar to
multi signatures or client-server
signatures and allows the TPM and the
host to to make a signature together
with their individual key shares so this
is similar to existing existing notions
of multi signatures but we need some
extra properties the first is that a
signature should not reveal anything
about the
Anna Richards valid because that would
destroy the privacy that we're looking
for and the second is we need some
uniqueness properties we need that the
signature is unique for a certain key in
a message and that given a signature
only one key given a sinker and a
message it can only be valid under one
key and this uniqueness properties limit
the way in in which an adversary can
have malicious influence because there's
not so many choices you can make this
makes it easier to prove the anonymity
that we want to have and in fact we can
we present that we can that we can
efficiently instantiate this based on
pls signatures second we use signatures
on encrypted messages to form the
credential of this of the platform and
here we present an efficient
instantiation based on AGoT structure
preserving signatures on al-jamal cipher
texts and finally we need the zero
knowledge proof or zero knowledge proof
knowledge to glue everything together
and one efficient instantiation is based
on snore proofs possibly with the CRS
trapdoor and so we showed that any
secure initiation of these building
blocks that fulfill the properties that
we need yields the secure DEA protocol
but if you use the efficient
instantiation that we proposed then we
actually get a very efficient
impractical DEA protocol signing only
takes nine exponentiations and ten
pairings for the hosts which can run
rerun in tens of milliseconds and more
importantly the TPM only has to compute
two exponentiation x' to make an
attestation and of course here it's
important to realize that the TPM is
orders of magnitude slower than the host
computer so you want to minimize the
workload for a TPM and this will have
the greatest influence on the efficiency
of the daa scheme and actually this is
the most efficient daa protocol in terms
of the daa of the TPM signing operation
that there is so far so that makes is
actually very practical and verification
only takes for exponentiation x' and 8
bearings so that makes this this
that shows that we can very efficiently
do this so to wrap up we show that that
the anonymity definitions that we have
used over the last decade for DAA are
not what we expected to be even though
the point was to reduce trust in the TPM
we actually still needed it to be to be
honest for any anonymity and now we
showed or now we define that we defined
DAA with optimal privacy so we define
the best privacy we can hope for in the
form of AUC functionality and we show
how to model such a subversion attack on
a TPM in this framework then we define a
new approach to DAA protocols because
the existing schemes are not sufficient
to realize this notion of privacy we
define a new approach that we can use to
realize this that we can really realize
our audio functionality and we give a
very efficient protocol that a very
efficient concrete and sensation that
can actually be used in practice with
that I would like to thank you for your
attention and I'm happy to take
questions
[Applause]