so this talk is about the gap between
selective and adaptive security in
various cryptographic protocols so as we
all know selective security is the
notion of security in which we required
that the adversary commits to some or
all of its choices ahead of time before
seeing either the public parameters or
other features of the of the
construction where is the adaptive
notion allows him to do all his choices
choices adaptively as the protocol
continues this is of course much more
natural but much harder to achieve
usually as an example thick I think of
garbling where the standard notion of
security requires the adversary to
commit on his on his input that he wants
to gamble before seeing the garbled
circuit this is the classical security
notion of Yahoo garbled circuits and of
course the more natural notion the
adaptive one adaptive one in which we
require the adversary not to commit to
his input ahead of time but only after
seeing the garble circuit is much more
natural and harder to achieve there's a
long series of works in the past decade
showing these various protocols that we
only knew how to approve selective
security can be a shown to satisfy some
notion of adaptive security it all
started in the work of conjoining in
2007 where he devised the game he called
the general selective decryption which
is very easy to prove it's selective
security but seems super hard to prove
it's adaptive security the latest work
in this series of works is by Jeff ergo
lien weeks showing that Yahoo's garbled
circuit construction is actually
adaptively secure one downside of all
this works is that whoever knows them
had a feeling that they're all somehow
related this level also all the series
of works they all had the common
features in the proof and the analysis
looked similar but nobody could really
point out what the jury was the main
common thing and the second point is
that the original work of Connie
and some other works are very hard to
understand they're like super
complicated our first main contribution
is a framework that shows that all of
these constructions basically follow the
same framework they have the same
pattern in the proof and we recover all
the results from multiple all these
previous works using our framework our
framework is quite modular it's
basically it takes a problem and it
reduces it to some combinatorial problem
about babbling of graphs and there's a
bonus we also get a new result for the
adaptive security of Yahoo's secret
sharing scheme which I'll talk next in
this talk so these are our results I
would like to spend a couple of slides
about the framework so there is a very
classical way or a very trivial way to
take a selectively secure protocol and
make it adaptable secure and it's called
commits computer a combination of the
hybrid argument and guessing so here's
how it works
think of two games G left and G right G
L and G Raju are there are adaptive
games so keep in mind the adaptive VI
adaptively all garbling as an example
and want to prove that they're
indistinguishable so what we usually do
we just selectively ice them we just
guess the adaptive choice choices of the
adversary ahead of time
define selective games H left a knight
right and now we just apply the
selective proof security which usually
consists of a sequence of hybrids H 1
till HL now the result is that the
original adaptive games are
indistinguishable but the security loss
is huge it's 2 to the N for guessing the
choices of the adversary and there's a
factor of L which is the number of
hybrids we have in the Selective proof
security and this is of course something
not very good that we would like to
avoid the main idea in our framework can
be said in one sentence it's very simple
to say it's basically saying devise a
new sequence of hybrids not the original
ones from the selective security but a
new one and make sure that in order to
move from each hybrid to the following
one you don't need to know the whole set
of choices of the adversary but only
some small fraction of it some H of the
choice of the adversary to my own small
comments that are important you can
choose a different age at any C to
follow two consecutive hybrids so that
allows you to have much more flexibility
and overall overall you might need to
know the whole choice of the nursery but
at any specific point you will need to
know only few bits as an example think
of again that garbling adaptive Yahoo
garbling so if we had a sequence of
reductions in which we could only know
in every two consecutive hybrids only a
few wires not the whole input then we
would be able to devise a much more
efficient reduction so here's a glimpse
of the formalization of our framework so
again we have the adaptive games G left
and G right and we have a hybrid the
selective hybrids h-12 HL but now the
selective hybrids have an additional
property not only there are the
selective iced versions of the adaptive
games but there are as but each to
selective hybrids are the selective iced
versions of something we call les select
advised games that I symbolized by H hat
and the property this less selective
iced games have is that in order to move
from one to the consecutive one you need
to know fewer bits about the choices of
the adversary so that's the
formalization you can have a different
pair for each two consecutive hybrids if
you have this property then you can get
a security reduction in which the loss
is two to the M times L rather than two
to the N times ed and if M the number of
bits you have to know in every two
hybrids is much smaller than n we win we
get a much more efficient reduction so
this is the main idea of the framework
and I'm going to show how it applies to
secretary the news
in the paper so what is the clustering
secret sharing is a very simple game
introduced in the late in the early in
the late 70s by Blakely and Shamir and
the game is described as follows there's
a dealer that has a secret think of the
bit of the secret is a single bit just
the raw one he wants to distribute it
among end players such that there are
qualified sets and there are unqualified
sets the qualified ones should know the
secret and the unqualified ones should
not know the secret so it's just a we
just take the whole set of any inputs
and we split them into two sets one of
which is good inputs and one of them is
it means bad ones and the goal is that
the subsets that all qualified will be
able to recover the secrets while
subsets that are unqualified will not be
able to recover it and cannot can be
formalized in various ways either
information theoretically all
computationally and we know a bunch of
stuff so on each one of them and I'll
talk about in the next slide but now I
want to talk about the security
definition so in the Selective security
definition that the dealer has a secret
it generates a bunch of shares by one
two pi N and that versary commits to his
whole set of parties that he wants to
see their shares I want till I K and
sends them to the dealer the dealer
replies with the set of the set of
shares of the corresponding parties and
then the dresser has to say what what he
his get was his guest for the secret
either a zero or one he wins if he
succeeds in his guess in the adaptive
game the dealer does the same thing he
chooses a secret s at random generates a
set of shares but now that versary
only sends one index out of n to the
dealer and gets back the share of that
dealer of death party and he can do it
multiple times so he can choose the
share of the next party based on the
shares that has seen so far and again
when he decides to finish he choose he
sends the his what he thinks the secret
is and he wins if he
yes correct we say that a scheme is
secure
in either case if the probability the
adversary wins and he chose only and
unqualified set is at most 1/2 plus
something agreeable okay so what do we
know about this notion there's a long
line of works about information
theoretic constructions that achieve
perfect security there's and they're all
perfect but we will focus about the
computational ones in computational
setting we have two main schemes the
first one is the scheme of Yahoo that
I'll talk about more in the rest of this
talk it basically allows us to share a
secret to a set which is described by a
monotone boolean circuit so there is a
book mount on boolean circuit which is
public that tells you who are the
qualified sets and who are the
disqualified Seth there is also another
construction that allows us to share a
secret to every access structure not
only to ones that are described by a
mount on boolean circuits and what we
currently know is that both of these
schemes are only selectively secure we
have no result about their adaptive
security of course you can do what I
said in the beginning hybrid argument in
guessing but lose two to the N factor in
security which is something we would
like to avoid so our result is the
following a based on the access
structure it is described on the on by a
monotone circuit that has various
parameters but basically our result says
that if you are given if the access
structure is described by a monotone
circuit of size s and depth D then there
is a secret then a secret sharing scheme
is adaptively secure and the loss is
only s to the D and not to to the M
which is much better in several cases
one notable example is an access
structure called directly desta
connectivity it's an access structure in
which parties are edges in a graph and
the qualified sets are
that forum a directed path from some
specified vertex s to some specified
vertex T before this work we didn't have
any adaptively secure construction for
this access structure in which the
security loss is less than 2 to the n
with our result it's only the security
loss is only quasi-polynomial it's only
2 to the poly log
ok so I'll continue with the description
of our scheme and then I'll show our
analysis so your scheme works as follows
you give me the boolean circuit which
describes the access structure and I am
going to label each wire in the circuit
with some label the labels of the of the
input wires are going to be the shares
of the parties so we start by labeling
the output wire with the secret and then
we see either an or gate or an end gate
they might have multiple like fan a fan
out larger than 1 and Fannie now
gentlemen let's assume it's just two
bottle number just two so let's say we
see an end gate in which the output
wires are labeled with labeled with l1
and l2 or an or gate with the same
labels so the first thing we do we
sample a fresh encryption key for a
symmetric encryption anyone and we
associate this encryption key with the
gate now if it's an end gate we label
the left input wire with the random
label and the right input wire with
round with cake sort with this random
label so we just one-time pad this key
if it's an or gate we just duplicate it
to both input wires this is the scheme
last thing we do we publish we publish
on some board or just give each party
the encryption of the label l1 and l2
with respect to the key K we do this in
both cases so that's the scheme a
correctness is quite easy to see by just
reversing the process going from the
leaves
to the to the input wire to the output
wire of the circuit and let me talk
about security so in the security proof
of this scheme a the Selective proof of
security which is the classical proof of
security we do a sequence of hybrids
what is the sequence of hybrids what
we're doing is we're replacing the
encryptions that everybody see the
ciphertext we replace them with bogus
ones so instead of encrypting real
labels we are encrypting random stuff or
junk but we can do it for every gate
right because some gates that versary
can know the encryption key and can open
the encryption so we do it only for the
gates for which the for which the
adversary doesn't have the encryption
key but how do we know which ones so we
know because this is where we use the
selective security we know the set of
parties that were sir we opens their
shares ahead of time so we know exactly
which gates that were sir can compute
their key in which the gates who cannot
compute their key and there must be a
path from the input wires to the output
wire in which we can replace all
ciphertext with bogus ones and thus
replacing the output wire with their
bogus one which makes the whole thing
independent of the secret so the skin
becomes secure so this is the high-level
idea of the proof and notice that it
seems in this in this approach using
this approach it seems inherent to know
ahead of time the set of parties that
were sir is going to choose just to know
the path of of gates that we can replace
with bogus ones so what we do we devise
a new sequence of hybrids that that
allow us to use our framework so here's
our sequence of hybrids each hybrid h i
will correspond to a peddling
configuration of the graph meaning that
on every we think of it as as if on
every gate in this circuit we either put
a pebble or
with the pebbles so all gates are either
pebbled or not pebbled gates will
correspond to circuits that have bogus
ciphertext bogus associated ciphertext
and gates without the pebble will
correspond to gates with with the real
ciphertext and our goal will be to start
with the game in which there are no
pebbles so all the cipher texts are
honest and divides the sequence of
hybrids in which in the last Hybrid
there is a single pebble on the output
gate and what it means is that the
ciphertext that corresponds to the
secret will be a bogus one and therefore
the secret is hidden ok so this is the
high level of our high level approach a
let me tell you before showing the
sequence of hybrids how we go from a
hybrid in which there is some set of
pebbles to a hybrid in which we have a
different set of pebbles so this is for
this we use something we call babbling
rules we define - babbling rules that we
allow to make in order to move from
hybrid a chai to a hybrid H I plus 1 the
first rule that we allow is if you have
an end gate in which one of its inputs
is pebbled meaning its corresponding
ciphertext its bogus then you can also
pebble that delegate and you can reverse
it by unpacking it and if you have an or
gate in which both children are pebbled
you can also pebble that one or reverse
it and the idea yhi is indistinguishable
from h I plus 1 is just because just due
to the semantic security of the
encryption so our main idea would be to
find the sequence of hybrids a in which
in every two consecutive hybrids we
apply one of our pedaling rules and in
addition the the number or the
description of the pebble
or the peplum configuration would be
very short and this is what we are going
to guess in our hybrid argument so our
goal now is to find a pedaling strategy
for boolean circuits with not so many
pebbles at any point in time and in
which the number of of hybrids or
babbling configurations is not so big so
this is the goal and our result is a
babbling strategy that requires 2 to the
D moves or babbling steps and in every
step every pebble in configuration
requires only D times log as bits and
here is where our loss as to the D comes
from by by just guessing the description
of the babbling configuration in each
two consecutive steps so the
configuration will consist of two things
it will consist of a sequence of pairs a
of the form a label a label of gate like
a name of a gate and a bit this bit will
just represent either whether the only
the left only the left subtree is
pebbled or the right subtrees beveled or
both of them so if none of the input
wires of a gate is pebbled we will just
not write it if only the left one is
pebbled we will write a zero in the bit
if the both of them are pebbled we will
write a one corresponding to the gate
name and we'll have another bit just for
the just to specify if the route gate is
pebbled or not so this is the
configuration and let's see how we how
we pebbel a circuit so that's what we
are left to wait to do so think that you
have the following circuit there is an
or gate and for example it has two
inputs which are by themselves or gates
and there is a big sub-tree underneath
each of them so we're doing going to do
to recursively a pebble this circuit so
first we pebble the left subtree of this
circuit recursively we put a pebble
we add the we add the pair root Gate
comma zero to the configuration to
symbolize that the left subtree of the
root gate is pebbled then the next step
is to pebble the right subtree and to
update the configuration to contain the
pair that the root Gate comma wine
meaning that both of its children are
pebbled at this point we can wecan
pebble the route gate which is an or
gate so we need both of his children to
be pebbles
so we pebble the route gate and update
the bit corresponding to the road gate
in the configuration and now we reverse
this process by unpublish the right
child updating the configuration and nun
babbling the left child and updating the
configuration and now we're in the
situation we wanted to get to we wanted
that there is only one pebble in the
tree and in the integrand it's on the
route gate so this is what we wanted if
you followed me then what you can show
is that the number of babbling rules has
a recursive equation which is for if you
want to pebble a tree or a circuit of
depth D you need four times whatever you
needed to do with a circuit of depth D
minus one the four comes from the fact
that you need two pebble the left child
and then the right child and then to
reverse everything so that's the four
and the size of the configuration is
just the size of a configuration in the
subtree plus the description size of the
name of the root gate which is log s
bits plus two more bits which are a
minor just this is the bit to specify
whether the root is a pebble or not a
and that's it that basically gives us
whatever we wanted if you solve this
recursion you recover what is written in
the top so I'll conclude what we have is
a framework what I showed you is a
framework a general framework for
proving adaptive security of various
protocols using our framework we
recovered many previous works and
simplify the
proof by in some of them significantly
we have a new result for secret sharing
that I described to you there's a
related framework in a work of finance
total from last year's TCC in the
context of adaptive run delegation which
leads me to the following question of
whether we can find more applications or
more works where that can be phrased in
this framework it's really easy to
define really easy to use of course it
raises questions many questions about
babbling babbling games peppering games
and I think a very nice question is
whether there is a relation in the
opposite direction namely if we can
prove a lower bound for peddling can you
use it to devise the text on the
adaptive security of various protocols
that we're trying to prove and
[Applause]