okay so let's see what an encryption
citrine protocol it's a two party
protocol introduced by cuto with us and
wash well last year a crypto it involved
two amorphic encryption scheme with
threshold decryption one will be
additively obama week with a red color
and one will be multiplicative glioma
Bhavik and we want to have protocols for
switching from an encryption of M with
the additive protocol to an equation of
the same end for the multiplicative
morphic encryption scheme so this switch
protocol will be a two-party protocol
and we want to have the reverse protocol
from the multiplicative encryption to
the additive encryption so for the
torque the red box with the net negative
morphic encryption of M and the blue box
multiplicative one so these kind of
encryption switching protocols gives
naturally wise to secure two-party
repetition to protocol let's see that
with an artificial example we have that
function where a is the secret input of
Alice and be the secret input of Bob so
I send Bob starts to and keep the secret
using the additive encryption scheme and
send the encryption of alien b2 to each
other and then both recent Bob can
compute a negative expression of a plus
B and a minus B and then they use the
switch protocols
from the additive encryption to the
mythical active one and then both can
compute each from decide the encryption
to the power mu and V Bar by additional
explanation algorithm and then sin we
want at that function with a plus we
have to switch back to the additive
protocol and then both can compute the
encrypted raise it and then decrypt it
to refer to party decryption to get the
wizard so yeah we have a constant number
of ones with respect to the expert on U
and V and a log of U and V operation to
compute that power so with this kind of
this is an artificial example but this
give you an idea on the winds kind of
function encryption switching protocols
are efficient both in terms of number
one and computation for two party
computation so let's see in more details
the original constriction of kouto aleni
they for the institution they use the PI
a encryption scheme for the additive
maahox scheme which is defined over the
double and red engine our salient ago
and they use a gavel for the imitative
scheme so the main technical problem is
that a gamma is personally defined for
the square of the world she said you can
define it for the symbol of really the
set of element of Jacobi symbol one
instead of an said but in order to to
extend it to the world group they have
to design a
raishin you know that to not lead the
factorization of n and this give our
complex threshold description for a
gavel and this rigid in a large number
of one and it seems that it makes a
generic approach for designing such
protocol impossible so our tentative is
to use scheme that we designed with
Fabiana give me that we also go at we
say instead of the the poly scheme so
this CL scheme as a message space which
is edible Pisa where piece of pipe so
use that and for the mythical cheese
came with stick with a gavel so we only
have to extend a gavel over the world
group that the world pitted which is a
lot more simple than the case of the
devil and that these give rise to a
natural traceur description and reduce
the number of one of the original
constriction and by looking aspiring by
the co efficient of Kuto at ideally
these give rise to a simple generic
constellation so we see model type
details that constriction
so first let's see some building blocks
so first we use a linearly llamó fits
like a short scheme is that previously
but let's see that in more details so
it's a bit weak encryption scheme and we
suppose that the set of protects is a
ring and if we have an encryption of m
and prime we have a public function that
takes the encryption and the public key
and gives an encryption of the sum of m
and
and we also have an operation
skaara sort of scalar multiplication
there's a typo it should be an 8 here
that take as input the public key the
encryption of M and a and gives
inclusion of a times M where 8 is a
plain text so example of linearity or
more frequency first came out the Garba
thermically scheme with takes which has
and text space said over to that the
scheme that we saw and the scheme with
like you mean that takes said
over P set where C is apart though many
others that's the one that are we used
here we also want to have a two-party
decryption for for was key our spiritual
scheme so this is a special case of
trestle crypto system normally have to
party here so to fix the notation ska
will be just share of the secret key of
a lease we share our pub we do fiction
as usual and so our generic notation we
suppose that the decryption protocol is
in a single one that means that is as a
Christian of AB combine hit with share
of the circuit keys do some computation
and send the result to Bob and Bob
finish the computation with each shell
and output there is no other round and
this is critical to prove the security
of the Geneva conception that there is
only a single one another with the box
that we use is a protocol for
multiplication
for linear encryption and a directive
protocol so we can see this patrol car
in many works from NPC within encryption
for example in a paper of command of
garden listen
so Alice and Bob start with encryption
of X&Y additive Egyptian and they want
to compute an additive encryption of the
product of x and y so I start to to
sample a random and nonzero amount of
the plaintext or group from X and our
she can compute an encryption of mine
use art X she sends this to to Bob she
also compute an encryption of our plus y
and initiate to party decryption with
Bob from that Bob gets our plus wide
multiply I use encryption of X to get
that and subtract this to get the
encryption of x times y so now let's see
the generic restriction so we start with
a generic position without dealing with
the 0 element inspired by the works of
cooter later Ally
so to simplify we need support as a set
of plaintiffs in the feed can be
something that looks like a field like
the dog and said anything away Santa go
but Paquita I so feed we start with our
two encryption protocol the additive one
and a multiplicative Li movie one over
the set of non zero the group of non
zero
Ament and we will suppose that we have a
two-party description for both
cryptosystem in only one one as I said
before this a lot to prove the zero
knowledge of our generic constriction
without any additional properties so
let's see up to switch from the additive
protocol to the multiplicative protocol
so now Alice and Bob have a shelf above
the additive and the manipulative
circuit keys of of the scheme so I start
to sample a random amount ah I don't see
one
she computes an inscription of additive
encryption of M times R and an
encryption of the inverse of oh she sent
that to Bob and initiate and to party
decryption for the other one
Bob gets em Stan are in the in the clear
and encryption of Ferdie in rush of art
it can multiply both to get an
encryption of M and we have the same
protocol in the other way around because
all that we use the error is a property
that we can we have a scalar
multiplication we can we apply a
plaintext by an encryption and we can do
that also with the additive encryption
so we have a simple solution and the
reverse is the easy
so no how can we deal with the zero
element again we we followed the ideas
of Goethe white LED we extend the
multiplicative scheme to deal with the
zero by the in defining this bit B which
is 1 if M is 0 and 0 if M is not you
like this M plus B will be always
nonzero and we can encrypt it with our
multiplicative scheme and then quit we
have to increase B and we want to
preserve the
wafak properties so let's see that if we
look at em the zero element is absorbent
so if we multiply to 2 m where we have
the truth table and for D this means
that we have no an or gate and we want
to design an encryption of B which is
optic with respect to 2 to the or gate
every debate yet from the original
Constitution we will do that with an
additive solution so we will if B is 0
we certainly want to to 0 I think if if
B is 1 we will consider random nonzero
element and like this if he had we had
that truth table which is the same as as
for B because if we had two random
element we get a random relevant 51
nonzero element if the mission space is
sufficiently large so we get that so
Big M is is M plus B we encrypt M plus B
that means is a mean 0 we encrypt 1 and
an additive and picture of all with a
nonzero element and if M is 0 Big M the
M plus B so this will be small m and we
encrypt 0 with the additive scheme and
we can decrypt easily from that so now
let's see how to switch so we still
suppose that this is the notation of the
previous slide in the first slide and to
be able to switch like in the original
construction will suppose that we have
black box and then heated 0 test two
party protocols that form an encryption
and GE encryption of X gives an additive
encryption of the bit B that is 1 if X
is zero and encryption of 0 X is not 0
so this can be shared with gabber check
it for for example but we did that
like black box so now how to switch
wilfer this extension of the
multiplicative scheme that build with 0
and to the additive scheme so we start
for encryption like before
first we switch the first coordinate
like before because M Big M is always
non zero so we can apply the previous
our protocol to get that we keep and
we've shown off Big M and now we have to
see if we our in this case or in this
case and for that we applied the other T
is
the protocol to to up and can be checked
that deceive the an encryption and a
given fiction of the complementarity
bits of the the bid be how we apply our
protocol that compute multiplication
from to additive encryption and we get
an encryption allocation of Bobby times
M and from the formula here can we check
that it is a V additive encryption of AB
so this give our protocol to switch from
the utility side to the at each side and
the reverse way is more like the same we
use on ezt protocol and then super we we
don't need to do a multiplication so the
way aside these are a bit more simple so
now let's talk about Association so now
our mr. space will be said over a period
so as I said before for the additive
protocol we use the CL scam as Kim is an
angular model type 2 system and we
define over class group of politic order
and this case will be another of
discriminant minus P to the third and in
this class group we have the property
that there is a subgroup of order P
where the discrete logarithm problem is
very easy just just a few operation to
to solve it
and this gives negative amalfi by
encrypting M in the exponent in an event
type scheme by equal teen
well we get as to the poor admin e and
this F is a generator of the soup group
where the deal is easy so we get em so
we don't have to restrict to small
messages and we have mo fear over the
world said about pizza for the beatific
ativ scheme we use a variant of a Corral
so we only have to extend that cable to
from the square of the opposite to the
world multiplicative group this can be
done like this we consider sufficient
hyman in that setting minus 1 is not 2
square so here we are diligent
resumption world of of M and times M it
would be always a square so this give M
if M is a square and minus M if M is a
non square and we also anchored the the
symbol like this a bit which is the Rope
for square and one for non square and we
only have to encrypt that that bit to be
a movie cover said that mm we can do
that with the curvature McAleese game so
yeah the German part here and here the
curvature Micheli encryption of the beat
LM so that's it for the to scheme let's
see our result so first we will look at
that we will compare the our one
capacity with the original solution so
first for the the switching protocol
without zero for the the additive to the
rickety we have the same number of wrong
because this is exactly the
the same solution but in the rivers but
we have the is the same protocol as
before so only to want but for the
original solution there was that a camel
complex a camel the Christian step test
lead to more one and for the full movie
the full ESP protocol that is with the
zero for the first line again this is
the same solution so we have the same
number one and for the second line we
have again for for one of gain of that
and the other one comes from the fact
that we entreat additively
the extra bit so now if we look at the
bit complexity so there is tuition one
is with the serial scam that relies on
the DTH and the other one is a variant
which less than our security exemption
and we can see that we are more the less
from the same material there are other
regional solution this comes from the
fact that the CL scheme and there's more
more bits we have more copper element
that in the the police scheme especially
in this case where P is very large so to
conclude the other things the paper so
the ECL scheme use a group of an audio
so there are some technicalities to for
sure in the keys so we include the key
generation by sampling with this
protrusion instead of uniform this
reduce the number of the number of bits
of the keys here we have a solution that
is securing the onus mysterious model
but it's possible to you
stick to against active adversary but
yeah I think zero knowledge proof and
now for the open pearl there is still
room for improvement we saw that there
is this external is it the protocol so
it would be interesting to find a more
adult method to deal with the zero
element and of course we have the
January condition it will be interesting
to find other instance for example based
on the lattices so this is Morris in Z
for the additive mocha skin but less for
the multiplicative one so that's it
thanks for your attention
[Applause]