okay thank you very much so threshold
cryptography dates back to the late 80s
already and a lot of work done in the
90s and the idea was that you would have
a number of parties sharing a private
key for decryption or for signing and
you would need some authorized subsets
in order to carry out any of the
operation any signing operation or any
decryption operation and there are many
applications for a threshold
cryptography you can think of multi
signatory applications so you want to
have some two out of five people in the
company signing on a cheque or or
something to that effect more recently
there's been a lot of interest in this
to do its application to key protection
so you want to keep your secret key safe
you can either put it in dedicated
hardware but that can be problematic in
many situations so you can split it and
put the different key shares on
different machines protect them with
different operating systems in different
environments different administrators
and make it hard for an attacker to get
to all parts of the key and therefore
keep it safe and this is actually now
being deployed in practice and the
number of startups doing this we know
already from a couple of decades ago
that RSA you know gamma EC is which is
again just a few human snore signatures
all of these can be done very very
efficiently even if you have malicious
adversaries who will run any arbitrary
attack strategy to try and break the
protocol it can be we can protect
against that using very efficient zero
knowledge proof see inside these
protocols and and we and this is really
a solve problem we can do this very very
efficiently in contrast DSA and ECDSA
are very expensive by the way I'm going
to talk about ECDSA but it's exactly the
same for DSA because everything here is
just generic in the group in particular
the best two-party protocol takes
numerous seconds for a single signature
and that's a very significant overhead
and it also has an extremely expensive
key generation protocol so it's
problematic to actually deploy such a
solution the question is why why is
ECDSA so much harder than all of these
other all of these other
protocols or these other encryption and
signing schemes the reason is that it
has this strange or unusual feature that
you have to generate this random value k
and and it's inverse and these have to
be secret and not not known to both
parties and it's actually non-trivial in
multi-party computation to generate
shares of a random value and it's
inverse and that makes it actually very
very difficult so just to elaborate a
little bit now let's compare Schnoor
signing to ECDSA signing or what
happened when we try to naturally make a
two party protocol for these for these
signing schemes so in both of these
signing schemes you choose a random cave
from Z Q where Q is the order of the
group and you compute an elliptic curve
point R which is K times G where G is
the base or generator points of the
curve in Schnoor you then hash the
message together with that point and an
easy do you say you do something
different you take the X portion of the
point which anyway has the bulk of the
entropy and you reduce it mod Q and you
get a small R and now you have something
completely different fish nor you have a
linear equation which is just K minus x
times e and in ECDSA you take the
inverse of K and you multiply it by the
hash of the message plus R times X you
do all that mod Q anyway I put R and s
and snorey I put ena so you can see that
Schnoor the whole way through is just
very linear except for the hash function
whereas ECDSA has this K inverse which
which makes things problematic so let's
do two partition or signing so we have
the secret key X and the natural thing
to do is to have each party hold an
additive share of X so P want to hold X
1 P to hold X 2 and and the sum of the
these is they actually the secret key
and of course they're random under that
constraint you need to choose a random K
well that's also pretty easy P 1 will
choose K 1 P 2 will choose K 2 and and
they can even define a local r1 and r2
value by multiplying that by the point
by the base point and then they can
compute our by simply summing those
together ok so this is very very
easy to do in very efficiently once they
know are they can each locally compute e
because it's a hash of the message and
are and then they need to compute this
final equation this s equation so each
one can again locally do this so p1 will
compute s12 equal K 1 minus x1 times e P
tooth likewise and you just sum those
together and you get the signature so
it's all linear or very nice you have to
add some very basic 0 knowledge first
here but it's very very efficient and
everything works very nicely if you try
to do this in ECDSA everything sort of
messes up at this at the stage of trying
to compute s because of the K University
if you have additive shares of K it's
very hard to compute additive shares of
K inverse and you sort of have this
choice either
we have additive shares and then getting
shares of K universe is hard or maybe
we'll try multiplicative shares but then
combining the different values to get s
is going to also be very hard and so
everything sort of breaks down now in
the the mid-90s there was work on these
for the multi-party setting with an
honest majority done by Langford and
then done by gennaro
yaki Kraft chicken and and rubbing but
I'm gonna focus on the two-party setting
and with in that case obviously there's
no honest majority let's just quickly
rewrite ECDSA and and what I want to
notice is just that there's this s pad
has two separate sub equations the
left-hand red side and the right-hand
purple side and we're going to have to
deal with these separately which is why
I've colored them differently I'm gonna
put that up in the top right hand corner
so you can follow the see the the basic
Sonics game the whole way through so
Mackenzie Ryder were the first 16 years
ago here in crypto were the first to
actually provide a protocol for the
two-party case and their approach was as
follows firstly they said additively
sharing is going to be difficult so
let's not typically share the values so
parties the parties hold X 1 and X 2
which are random under the constraint
that the product of X 1 and X 2 equals x
that's not a problem and since we have
to make this consistent throughout
additively sharing kay their
multiplicative multiplicatively share K
as well so P 1 choose K 1 P 2 K 2 and
and K will be k1 times k2 and then our
of course will be K times G and this is
actually just diffie-hellman key
exchange you can see that P 1 will send
K 1 times G P 2 will send K 2 times G
and they can each locally compute K 1
times K 2 times G so this is actually
very easy to do once they have this
value R that lets them go to the next
step and also since the K the sharing of
K is multiplicative they can each
locally compute an inverse of their
portion of K and now they have shares
also of K inverse so we've solved the
problem of K inverse and everything is
OK
and each can also compute this R which
is our X molecule so what becomes now
difficult what's difficult is computing
s because we don't have additive shares
and this is an air linear or this linear
equation or at least of K inverse but
what they do has have is they have R and
they have shares of both K and X and and
and now what McKenzie writers say is
let's use per year which is additively
homomorphic in order to finish this
computation so P 1 generates a PI air
key pair and can then encrypt each part
of this equation separately using its
own values so P 1 will encrypts K 1
inverse times the hash of the message
which is his portion of the left-hand
side and will also encrypt K 1 inverse
times X 1 times out which is again his
own portion of the right-hand side of
the purple side and we'll send that to
Peter now P 2 can use the additively
homomorphic properties of pi air to
finish the signature how can he do that
Multi can multiply the left-hand side by
its own portion of K 2 inverse and
multiply the right-hand side by each
portion of K 2 inverse times X 2 and
what you now get is you get 2 to
encryptions one is of K inverse times
the hash hash of the message and the
second second ciphertext is an
encryption of K inverse times X times R
and all
- do we just add them together luckily
to add it to be homomorphic encryption
so you can add them together Peter you
can then send that back to p1 who will
decrypt and get the signature so
everything is fine just small caveat you
have just have to add noise because
inside higher encryption you're working
over a large ring you're not working mod
Q so you add noise in order to to
distort any difference here so this
seems very good what's the problem the
problem is that in the case of malicious
adversaries when you want to force the
parties to actually behave honest and do
the correct thing it becomes really
really hard to prove that you're
behaving honestly in particular for one
just one example
p1 needs to prove that the encryptions
that it sends contain k1 inverse now
it's true that K the p2 has some
function of k1 which is R 1 which is k1
times g but doesn't have anything which
is a function of k 1 inverse it's very
very hard it's very unclear how you can
even prove such a relation in efficient
way and actually if you look at the
mackenzie write a paper there's zero
knowledge proof go span about a page and
a half of equations of computations and
exponentiations they have to be proven
and it's an auxilary pi air public key
and there's a whole lot of other things
and it's really really really expensive
to do there's been a number of follow-up
works to McKenzie writer they've all
reduced the cost of these your knowledge
proofs but they're still very very
expensive and there's still a very big
bottleneck because proving that you're
behaving correctly here is very very
difficult so what can we do our approach
is we is to try and remove all of these
expensive to our knowledge proofs you
still have
Sam's your knowledge for it's a very
cheap discrete log by proving that you
know the discrete log of something which
is just actually a local Schnoor
signature so that's really really
efficient and the way that we do this is
we still keep to the mackenzie ryder
paradigm so they have the parties have
multiplicative shares of X but we also
assume that P 2 has an encryption of X 1
under par TP ones player public key so
and we could take care of this during
setup so it's just assumed now now that
P 2 has an encryption of X 1 and knows
that it's a valid encryption of X 1 of
course it doesn't know
inside because the key belongs the
private key belongs to 2p1 we can do
this in the setup and we'll see now this
actually makes everything really really
easy and and that's actually the main
observation of that that of this entire
paper
so the first step you can see the bottom
right in yellow will suit will show what
what I'm talking about there which part
of the signing operation we're talking
about
and as you Mackenzie right of the
parties will run a diffie-hellman key
exchange to generate this value art I
call it a simulator will do for my key
exchange it has some zero knowledge
fruits inside for a discrete log it has
some commitments but it's basically just
a key exchange to compute multiplet of
shares of k and to get R which is k1
times k2 times times G and then again
both parties can locally compute R to be
our x mod Q because they both know now
that the relative elliptic curve Point R
and at and this is very efficient and
very simple what's interesting now is
look at what p2 has p2 has the curved
point R has its shares of of the secret
key so you an end case on X 2 and K 2
always arose has K 2 inverse because
it's it's its own share and it also has
an encryption of x1 and if you look
closely here what you see is that
actually p2 can now work completely by
itself to compute what I call an almost
signature and almost signature is a
signature but instead of having K
inverse there it has K 2 inverse but
everything else is a full signature and
it can do this all by itself without
interacting at all with p1 how p2 can
encrypt K 2 inverse times H of M because
these are values that have nose it can
also encrypt K 2 inverse times R times X
2 times X 1 Y cannot do times X 1
because it has the encryption of x1 to
start with so again it's a scalar
multiplication inside additively home
Orphic encryption if you look at what
this is this is actually a the only
difference between this and a full
signature is that you have to multiply
it by K 1 inverse that's the only
difference but
and in fact not only is that the only
difference this is that means that given
a real signature you can actually even
generate this value yourself p1 could
generate this value itself by
multiplying but by multiplying of a k1
so this value reveals nothing to p1 so
Peter can compute this value by itself
which is an almost signature inside the
encryption and just send the ciphertext
to p1 and p1 as in Mackenzie Rider you
add some noise but we're ignoring that
for now and p1 has the curve point R K 1
x1 and the cipher text of which the
decryption of the almost signature just
decrypts multiplies the almost signature
by k1 inverse and it's finished
it now has has completed the signature
and is almost no interaction and mainly
local work done by the parties what then
Hoddy p1 does is just verify this is a
valid signature and we're completely
finished so it's no longer pages of
complex your knowledge proofs and
actually in practice it's not just
efficiency it's also it's also
simplicity the protocol which is
important if you actually want to deploy
this and and this is a diagram of all
you have a simulator will diffie-hellman
key exchange followed by p2 during local
work sing the cypher text of p1 p1 the
crips and and you're done and multiplies
by K what are you person you're done
questions why is this secure and how is
it suddenly magically solved all the
problems of cheating so in order to
understand that let's look at the
security that it's argued security for
this protocol what happens if p1 is
malicious so p1 is malicious wants to
change the only thing that p1 dance is
participate in the simulator will be
free Hellman key exchange and you can't
cheat in this all you get to do is send
your part of the key exchange and you
have to prove that you know the discrete
log but that's again very easy you can't
cheat this nothing that p1 can do p1
just gets a ciphertext from p2 and the
creeps it multiplies it by something and
outputs it it can multiply it by the
wrong value just means you eat itself
we'll get an invalid signature won't
make any difference whatsoever so p1
ambitious p1 can't do anything and we've
saved all of the zero knowledge proof
that p1 had to send the p2 because
there's nothing that p1 is doing here
what about p2 and that's the interesting
question the the observation here is
that we're not computing a general
secure computation function we're
computing a digital signature and what
that means is that when P so what's the
danger the danger that peter can send an
invalid message to p1 because p2 is
malicious so instead of doing this
correct homomorphic operations p2 could
send something some arbitrary garbage or
something which is incorrect and and and
p1 how can P 1 know the answer is very
simply p1 cannot because the digital
signature scheme so in p1 gets the value
decrypts and multiplies it by K 1
inverse p1 can just check that the
signature is correct and that means that
if p2 tries to cheat it's not going to
help because if it's an incorrect value
p1 will know it's an incorrect value
simply by verifying its signature is
correct and you don't need any 0 in each
box or knowledge proofs anymore because
correctness is valid a just by verifying
the signature and that makes it all very
simple and very very efficient there is
one thing that you might have might be
bothering in if it's not it'll bother
you now once I say it may be p2 can
generate a ciphertext that just knowing
whether the ciphertext actually is a
valid result in a valid signature or not
will reduce will reveal information
about the secret key first you should
know you should notice it can only
reveal a single bit because that's the
only information that there is and this
is indeed a problem so we get around
this in two ways and this is all in the
paper one is by using a game based
definition and in game based definition
you can just simply guess the first
point at which the adversary gives you a
bad signature and then and and
everything goes through and we can also
prove it sit under a full simulation
based definition using a very strange
weird assumption so that's in the paper
as well and if you're into weird
assumptions which seems to be very
popular these days anyway then you could
take that and and be happier but
actually the game based definition I
think is very very convincing noise your
knowledge proofs just using the fact
that it's a signature scheme and you can
verify and everything is OK
what about key generation so
the key generation phase like generating
the multiplicative shares of K does a
simulate a little different key exchange
and that's easy we send X 1 times G X 2
times G and you can each locally compute
the public key which is X 1 times X 2
times G that's very very cheap but
remember we needed to have p1 send an
encryption of x1 to p2 under its own
public key and and p2 has to be sure
this is correct
this is a very crucial point if p2 if p1
sends an incorrect value then when p2
sends back the suffix to p1 it may
reveal information about p2 a secret key
to a malicious p1 so we have to be very
very careful about that
so we construct a very specific zero
knowledge proof to prove this this
statement so this is actually not a
difficult statement to prove because
there are no inverses or anything you
have p p2 actually has X 1 times G
because that's sent in as part of the
iam key exchange and you want to prove
that that's actually the value that's
inside the PI air encryption so it's an
interesting zero knowledge proof because
it bridges between two completely
different worlds you're given an
elliptic curve point x1 times G and you
need to prove that x1 is inside this
prior encryption but it turns out to be
not not so difficult to do not not so
expensive to do that but that's the most
involved part of the entire protocol
that's only done a key generation so
what's the performance of our protocol
we implemented and ran it on Azure with
standard just it's very standard
instances on single core and this is
actually inside a product so it's like a
with a full environment and the parties
communicate over TLS and there are no
shortcuts here and key generation takes
between four point eight and eight and
seven point eight seconds I'll explain
this jump in a second that's done only
once so that's actually very reasonable
and and signing actually takes only tens
of milliseconds you can actually sign a
few hundred ECDSA section signatures a
second using just a single core
obviously if you want higher throughput
then you can simply increase the number
of course latency is what you have here
this is actual
eighty to a hundred times faster than
the previous best protocol so that makes
a very very very difference and in terms
of key generation it's actually
thousands of times faster because the
previous best protocol needed
distributed RSA key generation as part
of the protocol and that's very very
very expensive for in key generation now
why does it jump
why does suddenly the the cost jump when
you go from from the 384-bit curve to
the 521 bit curve the reason is that you
actually need because of this noise that
I mentioned you added you need the prior
key to be at least four times the size
of the group order now we're always
taking 2048-bit payer anyway the modulus
is always going to be that size because
that's the mineral size for security so
for P 256 and P 384 it's it's a 2048-bit
key but at 521 x 4 you have to make it a
little bit bigger but because pi is the
real bottleneck unison so I think image
is making it a little bit bigger 80 bits
bigger actually causes this very big
jump in in in running time especially
for for key generation and and a lot of
work is actually we did a lot of work to
reduce the amount of noise you needed to
add in previous protocols you had to
make it eight times or nine times larger
and that would of course kill everything
and slow it down by a lot so in
conclusion we have a new secure ECDSA
protocol for two parties it's much
simpler than previous protocols because
it doesn't have any of these very
complex there are knowledge per so
distributed RSA key generation and so on
and so forth has efficient key
generation and signing it can run on
services we also it also runs between a
mobile and a server very efficiently
without any problem and it's fast enough
for many applications you could think of
Bitcoin signing if you wanted but key
protection in general and it's fast
enough and works very well in all of
those settings thank you very much
you