okay so yeah so this talk is and
security of the future mere paradigm
when apply to statistically sound proof
this is joint work with Ron Roth gloom
in guy rathalu so Ron was supposed to
give this talk he's an amazing speaker
but unfortunately for you guys and for
me he couldn't make it so I'm gonna be
his proxy so okay so let's start so the
future may be errific is a really really
beautiful and elegant way to convert any
three-round ID scheme into a signature
scheme so what is the difference between
an ID scheme and a signature scheme the
main difference is that an ID scheme is
interactive it contains three rounds
wherein signature scheme is a
non-interactive you just sign a message
so what is the idea how do you kind of
reduce this interaction so there is
extremely simple and beautiful so there
is the following
you know what the signer is gonna
produce the entire three messages
denoted twelve the stock by alpha beta
and gamma he will produce this on his
own subject to beta will need to be a
hash of the first message alpha and the
message to be signed em okay so when you
want to sign the message and you
generate alpha like the prover beta will
simply be a hash of alpha in the message
one sign and then you sign you generate
Ghana so alpha beta gamma is a proof and
it's accepted if it's an accepted
transcript by the verifier of the ID
scheme and if beta is indeed the hash of
alpha and the message when this hash is
going to be part of the public key so
that's the transformation it's extremely
simple its elegant it's nice and it's
the great power of it is that typically
signature schemes were extremely complex
and to construct and identification
scheme are extremely simple to construct
so kind of shows you've kind of a very
way very easy way to go from one to the
other and indeed he was extremely
popular both by Tara tissues and more
applied people I'm sure most of you by
the way show of hands who's heard of
this paradigm the future in paradigm
okay so yeah so as you see
and meanwhile heard about it and it's
it's really beautiful and the main
question is is it secure so if you start
with his secure ID scheme do you get a
secure signature scheme and let me give
you the intuition why did secure ok so
what can an impersonator who tries to
photo choose a signature what can he do
he gets the sash now suppose the flash
is really great it's like a
pseudo-random function so it's like
random and moreover suppose that all the
impersonator can do it kind of use this
hashes a black box ok it's an active kid
or something all he can do is kind of
use it as a black box in this case into
generating generating this transcript by
alpha beta gamma by interacting with a
box with random or with this box is
really the same as been trapped in with
a verifier in the ID scheme so they this
can be secure the signature scheme
should also be secure ok so that's the
reason why security should hold and
indeed this was formalized in the random
Oracle model so it was proved that this
asked paradigm is secure in the random
Oracle model if the hash is modeled as a
random Oracle by a series of beautiful
work starting with the work of Pancho
Valens turtle gave a really really
beautiful idea with the lemma of
showing this this security ok so the
main question though the remains is it
secure in the plain model so can we come
up with an actual hash function at
random or cover an actual description of
a hash function for which this paradigm
is secure so in 2003 together with Shafi
we gave a negative result we showed that
no and let me explain to you what what
exactly we showed what we actually did
is we gave a contrived example of an ID
scheme of a secure ID scheme for which
the corresponding signature scheme will
be insecure no matter which hash
functions you use ok so let's say this
game is contrived so definitely say you
know oh don't use the hash onto this
insecure the take home message was from
this work is that
don't try to kind of prove a general
possibility result for the fear to mere
paradigm because we do have counter
examples ok so in general it's not
always secure Oh
actually this fil jamia paradigm
paradigm even though it was originally
defined to convert ID schemes into
signature schemes it's much more general
than that and has a lot of applications
beyond ID to signatures and in
particular it's been used it can be used
to kind of convert to reduce interaction
in any interactive protocol so you can
start with any console on public point
interactive protocol and convert it to
just two rounds using the future mere
paradigm okay how in the first round the
verifier will just send a hash as before
and the second round the prover will
generate the entire transcript on his
own where the random messages of the
verifier he will compute by hashing the
transcript so far okay using the hash
that he got from the verifier so you can
think of it in this extended setting and
again oh and this this is very useful
it's been used a lot one of the staples
examples is McCauley it's very
influential work on CS proofs uses this
paradigm there's been many many works in
the literature that use this paradigm in
the main question as before is it secure
when we look at it in this extended
setting do we get security so one can
very easily one can show that the same
kind of idea to achieve Allen's turn can
be used to argue that this paradigm this
extended paradigm is secure in the
random Oracle model ok so again if we
model H as a random Oracle it is secure
but then to ask is it secure in the
plain model and in 2001 in his seminal
work Baraka gave a negative result
he showed that it's insecure and again
let me explain what a what we mean by
insecure what he actually showed he gave
an example of he showed the existence of
a concerned public coin zero-knowledge
protocol okay this seems very completely
in relay unrelated to the future mere
paradigm
however it was known that the existence
of such a zero knowledge protocol
immediately it immediately implies the
insecurity of this extended Faramir
paradigm why so here is the intuition
the intuition is the following what does
it mean so let's say this protocol here
the interactive proof is zero knowledge
what does it mean by definition of zero
knowledge it means for any cheating
v-fib star there exists an efficient
simulator who can simulate the
interaction right so this simulator
actually can be a cheating prover in the
two-round protocol why think of the V
star the cheating verifier and instead
of doing what he's supposed to he uses a
hash okay so he actually generates the
messages in this interactive protocol
using hash that's a type of a cheating
verifier for this cheating bear fighter
this is simulator by the zero knowledge
property and this simulator given the
hash just generates an a transcript that
is indistinguishable so this was noticed
by work of had a tinactin by docket al
that if we did have a zero knowledge of
protocol that would have made a public
point can surround zero knowledge
protocol it would immediately imply the
insecurities of the future mere paradigm
and since Baraka gave constructed such
as your knowledge protocol we got the
insecurities okay so so far I just gave
you examples why the fear tomatoes
insecure it's in the extended future
meals insecure as was shown by back the
original Fiat Ramirez insecure as later
showed by Shafi and myself as a
follow-up work to Barak and we actually
used many of his ideas but still I
promised you that I'm gonna have a
positive result so where's that positive
result hiding so let's take a closer
look at the negative results if we take
a closer look at these examples of where
the negative result comes we can see
that the initial protocol both our ID
scheme and zero-knowledge protocol have
only half computed
Oh soundless okay there are not
statistically sound okay so the
interactive protocol if you're
all-powerful you can cheat you can break
the protocol so one can ask well what if
we start with an interpretive protocol
that has statistical soundless can you
is the future meal secure in that case
so if you start with an interactive
proof that statistically sound and
convert it to an two round argument
using the Faramir paradigm is their own
any hope is can we prove that it that
it's sound and in a nutshell our result
is yes under strong assumptions so what
do we show we show that the fear to me
or the extended fear to me the focus to
think it'd be easier to think of the
extended future meal throughout the
stock is secure when applied to
statistically sound proofs as a post
argument under strong assumptions such
as IO obfuscation I'll get back to the
assumptions in a minute but before I
explain the assumptions in more detail
let me first talk about prior work and
the security hmm for proofs so we
noticed a long time ago that our
negative results were only for
computationally a sound proof and
there's a lot of work trying to prove or
disprove the future mere paradigm when
applied to statistically sound proof and
let me kind of give you the main results
in the literature that I'm aware of
so on the positive result Barak Lyndon
in vidonne showed that there exists some
property of hash function some kind of
entropy preserving property that I don't
want to define that if your hash
function has this property that when you
apply the fair treatment with this kind
of hash function you will get security
but whether there exists a charge
functions we don't know okay there's no
construction or instantiations a later
Dody set I'll show that there actually
does exist such a hash function that has
this special property but under some
assumption
assuming there's some robust randomness
condensers with the certain properties
and where there are such things with
live we don't know so you know we kind
of know what we're looking for but we
didn't find it yet and there recently
there's a result by middle back and
venturi who actually show gave a
positive result for a special class of
protocols special classify D scheme so
that when you convert them into
signature schemes
you'll get solace but this special class
doesn't contain I don't know really
what's in there but nothing that one of
the ID schemes that were around though
you know we're suggesting the literature
are contained in in this class they also
showed how to kind of convert some ID
schemes with some properties under IO to
kind of fall into this special class in
the crs model so they do have some kind
of a general result as well okay and the
negative result we also know this joint
work with beacons guitar that you cannot
prove soundness of the Faramir paradigm
even for proofs just focusing on proofs
you cannot prove soundness using what's
called kind of a black box reduction to
a falsifiable assumption giving
indicating that using the techniques
that we have we won't be able to prove
soundness based on standard assumption
so falsifiable assumption is a notion I
introduced by now all for those who are
not familiar with this notion just think
of it as standard assumptions okay it's
a notion that should can supposed to
capture all standard assumptions okay so
this is where where we stand and now let
me explain our results in more detail so
what we show in this work we actually
show an explicit hash function right
there - isle of a PRF family such that
if you start with any interactive proof
that statistically sound then your
two-hour round argument will be sound
under some assumptions so let me tell
you our assumptions first assumption
we need to assume that this IO over
there that we use is really secure it
has to be actually subjects financially
secure or in other words its need to be
to to then secure where n is the input
links but just think of it as subjects
financial IO this is kind of an
assumption that often we need to rely on
when we use IO and applications ok
another assumption is that the function
f sub s that will be IO is what's called
a puncture Bo PRF again with Starbucks
financial security and this is known how
to construct based on sub-exponential
one-way function and the third
assumption and this is kind of weird the
third assumption actually has nothing to
do with the construction ok so the age
the hats that I'm using is just IO of a
PRF of a punctual PRF family so a very
secure IO and a very secure puncture
bowl a pseudo-random function but I have
another assumption and the other
assumption is I'm assuming exponential
security of multi bit point function
obfuscation I you know a weak definition
of facin we only need input hiding
obfuscation which is kind of weaker than
BBB but we need exponential security for
this multi bit point function
Association now when you look at this
it's really not clear where does point
function application come into play so
first let me say that this this notion
has been studied and produced what
before and it's been constructed under a
strong variant of the DDH assumption we
do not need auxilary input in this
assumption for those who because
exhuming put it there is a lot of
caveats we do not need observer inputs
for those who are familiar but the
interesting thing this assumption is
only used at keeneland analysis ok so we
were in the analysis if I have time to
show you you'll see we use this
assumption ok so this is a result now
let's pause a minute and try to
understand this result so what's the
take-home message the take-home message
here so maybe maybe some of you in the
audience will say oh is this efficient
so the take-home message is no it's not
efficient should you go and use the
fifth Jameel from now on with this kind
of hash function because you know we
prove soundness no so do not try this at
home
it'll be very inefficient it's not a
good idea so what is the take home
message so there's two ways to think of
this result one is to say look this was
a proof of concept that you can there is
with hash function for which you can
prove security and you can take this as
an invitation to try to you know prove
this for an efficient hash hash family
one can also think of it as you know I
don't know some of us have been trying
to prove negative result for this so it
kind of shows you well in order to prove
a negative result you'll meet disprove
these assumptions or you'll need to
overcome you know serious hurdles in
order to prove a negative result but in
addition I think this theorem has
actually really interesting applications
beyond the Faramir paradigm and let me
give you one corollary so one corner is
that we get out of this theorem is we
prove that there does not exist a glance
around public-owned zero knowledge proof
statistically sound proof so Barak
showed this for an argument for
computationally so Barak Shawn sorry
that there exists a cancer around public
coin argument computationally sound does
there exist a statistically sound zero
knowledge public coin we shall know okay
so this problem is kind of opened and
for the last few decades there was a
very famous work by gold right and
Kartik that shows that there does not
exist accounts around public coin black
box zero knowledge proof so if you
restrict the simulator to use the
cheating vampire the black box then
there does not exist but the question
whether there exists you know any zero
knowledge proof non black box the ultra
booth with Scouts around public Oien
was an open question and a can a
corollary of our main theorem is that
under our assumption there does not
exist and why why is that a corollary
so let's recall the transformation that
we saw earlier that if you had a console
run public point zero knowledge proof
this in itself is a counter example it
demonstrate the insecurity of the future
mere paradigm so okay sorry
so so if you had such a thing you'll get
that the future mere period I won't
apply the proof would be insecure but
what I showed you that under my
assumption this is secure and so this
acure it must imply that there does not
exist a car to run public coins your
knowledge proof and in particular what
this implies is that parallel petition
does not preserve zero knowledge so in
particularly take your favorite
three-round you know zero node Wisconsin
soundness Andrew Blum protocol or
3-coloring
zero knowledge zero for three coloring
all these protocols if any of this if
you want to try to do run them in
parallel zero knowledge will not be
preserved okay so that's a corollary of
our main result another way to view our
result in a different using different
terminology is we can cancel result in
the terminology of correlation
intractable hash functions so this
notion was it's a very beautiful notion
introduced by Kinetico that Hanna Levy
and this property should be thought of
as a proxy to random Oracle so we use
run to random Oracle model a lot and the
question is what property do we really
use from these you know what property of
Hashem does this random Oracle model use
and one the property that was put forth
is correlation and tractability so what
does correlation tractability means so a
hash function is set to be correlation
intractable it's given a hash in the
family it's hard to find X and H of X
that satisfy some rare relation okay
what does it mean so for any relation
that's rare or evasive so what is an
evasive relation a basic relation is one
that for any input X there only neglige
many wise men a fraction of wise
satisfied the relation and age has said
to be correlation tractable is it for
any such rare or evasive relation given
a random hash from the family it is hard
to find X such that X H of X is in the
relation and in the original work of
Canadia time they show that there does
not exist correlation tractable age with
where the description of the hash is
short shorter than the input size
recently there's a very nice work of
kinetic chain and raisin that showed
that there does exist correlation
tractable age but for some relation that
for all evasive relations but rather for
all of its relationships that are
computable in some a priori fixed
polynomial time assuming I own related
assumptions in essential our result what
we show is that this specific hash
function are you applied to this
punctual PRF its correlation intractable
under our assumptions okay so let's just
see kind of a quick summary that's what
we showed is under the assumptions
stated above that the Faramir paradigm
is secure wouldn't apply to proofs which
implies that there does not resolve the
open problem that there does not exist
can't surround public Oien as your
knowledge proof which in turn implies
that peril repetition does not preserve
zero knowledge and also more generally
cast in the language of correlation
tractability we show that there does
exist a correlation and tractable hash
function which kind of can be used maybe
in other settings to try to remove a
random Oracle so in the few minutes I
have left maybe I'll try to give a very
very one-minute brief overview of the
proof so let's just show the proof idea
for the future mere paradigm so why
would it be secure to go from ID
50-round ID to signature so intuitively
so what is our hash it's are you above
pseudo-random function if instead of IO
we used VBB security like virtual black
box we had Oracle and as we said it is
secure that kind of security in the
random Oracle model so that we do we do
know it's secure but we don't have vvb
security so kind of course so let's use
IO the question is I am strong enough is
that type of alpha schedule in which
only promises us in the finish ability
is it strong enough and what we show is
it is strong enough if we start with the
typically sound proof as opposed to
computational sound if we start with the
computation sound this is not strong
enough because we have examples but if
we start with a statistically sound it
is strong enough so why so what a
statistically sound proofs what
properties they have the property they
have is that for any first message for
an X not in the language for every first
message alpha there are very few betas
for which there exists a gamma that will
correspond to an accepting transcript
now if we use a PRF a really strong PRF
here then by the fact by the strength of
this PRF the fact that F of s this is
not had nothing to do with IO just the
fact that the parent is strong enough it
means let's look let's all alpha
baddam if beta which is H of alpha kind
of for that there exists a gamma okay so
you kind of can cheat with that alpha
okay so by the secure because it's a
look like a random function this
property that there exist few good betas
should remain so till one can easily
show that there exists a few bad alphas
so there is a few alphas for which H of
alpha there exists a gamma okay so there
exists a few bad alphas and now the main
part is to show to argue that IO implies
that it's hard to find these bad gammas
these bad alphas
so the ion
alpha okay to prove this is that where
we use the multi bit point functions so
I don't have time but I'll just say that
the main idea is to just plant like
alpha star and beta star that have an
accepting gamma star so we can plant
that in the PRF and we prove that its
heart of that the cheating prover will
find this planted alpha star thousand
from our assumptions and then we get a
contradiction by saying oh this alpha
star that we planted actually there's no
way to find it because we advocated
we're advocating this room using a
really really strong px okay so that's
kind of the high level idea but again
just to summarize fear jameelah secure
for proofs this is very great news for
me I've been working on this problem
since I was a grad student so I'm very
happy to see an a positive result I'll
bite under a very strong assumption and
inefficient would be great to reduce
assumption to gain efficiency and so on
and then we get really interesting
correlation that have nothing to do with
the Faramir paradigm and kind of resolve
just classical open problems relate to
your knowledge correlation trapped
ability and so on okay thank you
[Applause]