so I would present you our IB from code
with Ron Patrick
first the the issue that there is in
every public key cryptosystem is to
distribute securely the key of the users
we have to be sure that we communicate
with the right users so there is several
way to achieve that the first solution
is to use public key infrastructure
which relies on the use of certificates
and we have to trust a lot of authority
and the other way is to use identity
based encryption where the public key of
a new juror is directly linked to with
identity and all the sacred key are
managed by an only Authority which is
called trusted Authority maybe is
technically difficult to achieve er was
invented by a sham here in Haiti for but
the first constriction only appears in
currently there is for families of hobby
we can do I be from elliptic curves
pairing quadratic residues very recently
computational diffie-hellman problem and
from religious-based crypto for the the
three first ib is based on number theory
assumptions so they are not resistant
with quantum computer and only the
fourth can be used in postponed term
cryptography and that's why it's very
important to find other abilities to
construct high B in post partum
cryptography and that's what we achieved
we first have designed a new PKA based
on the Roc metric and on code base
cryptography with the rods metric and
the security of our new PKA is based on
a new
program the DSL problem which I
introduced later and with this with this
new PK we have designed the first code
base I'll be in with the rock with the
rock matrix and we have also used
signature scheme Rock sign so no I will
present you the wrong metric first we
need to define fq linear codes the ff2
subspace of F G 1 power Hannah so
exactly like in Hamming we can represent
a card with matrix but with coefficient
in the field FQ M so FQ a mini Akkad
will be the combination of the rows of G
and we did not we not in NK f qm card f2
a million card comes with another matrix
the rank matrix to define it we first
need about this of fq m / fq and to
every vector of fq m power hand we can
associate a matrix of size M times and
each column of the matrix matrix M X
correspond to the coordinates of the
vector X with respect to the basis and
by definition the wave of record world
is the rank of the matrix and the
distance of two words is the rock of the
difference of two matrices and these
these definitions
don't depend on the choice of the basis
to use the rock network in cryptography
we need some hard problem and here the
natural hard problem is wrong stand room
recording which is the equivalent of the
Sandra medical instrument matrix so we
have a pirate-themed parity check matrix
of certain code and Sandra and we need
to find a vector
II said that H time e equal s with the
condition that the wave of e is equal to
R this problem is difficult because
there is a probabilistic prediction to
the sandworm decoding problem in the new
metric which is a well known np-complete
problem and for the decoding the
complexity of the decoding algorithm is
equal to Q power times the minimum with
K and km over hand so the complexity
depends if M is greater or less than
hell but what is important is that the
exponent is quadratic in n if we choose
all the parameters linear in Hana and of
course there is the decisional version
of this problem and we just need to the
problem is to distinguish sand room H
time e where e is chosen in random from
vector of waves are from completely
random vector Y so what are the
advantages of the right metric first the
fqm in the code are Lynette who with
respect to a large field so that's why
we can have the structured code and we
can add a compact representations so we
can have a small key size for crypto
system and the the fact there is the
complexity of the attack against the
wrong metric code depends on the size of
the field it's not the case for the
running distance was a project or even
doesn't depend on the size of the code
and another advantage is the fact that
the size of the codes for the rocket
weak growth grow smaller slower than for
Hamming metrics for the same complexity
if we
want to solve the rarity problem with
complexity to power lambda the size of
the code will be linear to lambda over
three F but for ramming metrics it would
be linear for lambda square this is true
for random codes so there is several
construction with which use the wrong
metric in cryptography there is public
key encryption there is two family
the first one is based on the McCulloch
scheme and for that we need some family
family cards we can decode so there is a
gap between cards which the equivalent
of the reads element and they are rich
algebraic structure that's why there is
they have been attacked by overbaked and
the other family is the lrpc code which
are the equivalent of the MVP C code in
Hamming and of course we have a asking
or wrong PK and there are signature
schemes like your wrong sign which is
based on the LAPC code
I will repeat rapidly quickly introduce
you the lrpc code first we need subspace
V of fq m of dimension D and we consume
their matrix H with all this coefficient
in V and by definition the matrix H will
will be the parity check matrix of an
end
NK lrpc code so we can decode
analyticity code if we know such a
matrix but if we only have random matrix
a random parity check matrix we cannot
we cannot use the recording algorithm
and that's why we can use this code for
the macula scale such a matrix is called
homogeneous matrix of width D so now I
will present you our new public key
encryption so
first we need to generate the parameter
of our code we need a vector s which is
come off size n minus K which is
completely random and a matrix of size n
minus K times n which has to be a full
round and a vector e of wife our and we
define the vector P equal to as I
proceed we all don't know we also need a
public card we can decouple up to W our
arrow for the the decryption algorithm
the public key will be the triplets AGP
and the secret key is a vector has so to
encrypt the message m we multiply the
matrix a with the vector P below with
the Nomura's matrix U of wife W we add
some matrix with the Metro the message m
is embedded in the public code and we
obtained the ciphertext C X and 2 to
decrypt the cipher text we multiply the
cipher text by the secret key s with
with the coefficient minus 1 and we
obtain the codeword mg plus an error e
you and since we have chosen you as an
emotional matrix of for SW and the waste
of the vector e is how we can bound the
the wrong the weight of the ero EU and
we can then decree compute M by decoding
this this noisy codeword a very
important proper property to use a
crypto system is that there is s and P
are linked because since we have chosen
P equal as april's e is a difference the
rank of the different
between P and si si is is low that's why
H will be useful for the IB so I will
introduce we have introduced a new
problem to prove the security of our
crypto systems with wrong support
learning problem we this problem in this
program we have a matrix a completely
random and the product of a times u
where u is the homogeneous way
emotionals
matrix of weight W and the goal of the
problem is to recover the support of you
by support I mean the subspace generated
by the coordinates of view we can see
this problem as multiple instance of the
rsd problem which c CI can be seen of
the product of a times a vector of
weight the value but the difference is
that all the the support of all the rows
are in the same space V of course we can
we can define the decisional version of
this problem which is to distinguish the
matrix a you from completely random
matrix Y under the assumption that the
era's are dr SL is hard or public-key
encryption is semantically secure so now
i will i will instigate in the
complexity of aerosol so as I said if we
just have one if n prime equal one we
just have one syndrome so aerosol is
equivalent to the era's D problem and
when and when n queen is large enough
this problem become easy so I will
explain it briefly
we just consider the subspace W
generated by the clone of the matrix a
you so fq subspace and if n 3 is greater
than n time W the subspace W correspond
to the walls of space a time leap over
hand so we can check if for any subspace
V of dimension 1 if the subspace 8e
power n is included in W and then we can
recover V this way for our crypto sister
for crypto system we are in the case
where in the intermediate intermediate
case and I will so we will still
consider the subspace W generated by the
column of the matrix a you but this time
we will also consider as a code C which
is the set of the vector X such that a
time X belongs to W it's an FQ linear
code and it has the property that the
small codeword of C are coming a linear
combination of the con of U so if we can
compute this small weight code words we
will able to compute V and then to solve
our problem so we have adapted the
generic decoding algorithm to this code
and we obtain an external shell gain
proportional to Q power n prime over n
time the minimum of K km over n but the
complexity for this attack is still
exponential okay now I can present you
our identity based encryption so there's
two main difficulties for designing an
ID
the first is we need to to have a public
key encryption with dense space for the
public key and the second difficulty is
only the trusted Authority can be able
to compute the secret key of often user
and the problem is in our wrong PK we do
the exact opposite we first generate the
the secret key s and then we compute the
public key as a and the public key
is passed
yes space is passed so we have to do the
opposed to to transform I run TK into an
IDE we need to to add some some trapdoor
in the matrix a in order to to invert
the function so we are we have a which
is a public master key of hobby and any
vector P of length n can be a public key
often a fan user so we need to find a
vector s so that P minus s a is small in
order to to use or to use wrong key K
and this problem is exactly the problem
of the signature in code base
cryptography so we will have the
trapdoor in the master public key a by
using the signature scheme wrong sign
how wrong sign works wrong sign is also
based on the lrpc code
so the problem we consider a matrix h
prime which is in two parts the first
part is the homogeneous matrix of ID so
it defines the lrpc code and we add some
random
in order to hide the structure of the
record and we call such a card not
mounted lrpc
our latissimus and the matrix H prime H
prime will be the secret key of the of
the upfront sign and to hide the
structure we multiply H frame by to run
to invertible matrix P and Q so the
public matrix will be pH P and Q and now
we can we can design our IB him sorry
first yeah the wrong sign has as an
property that the signature are
constitutionally indispensable from the
uniform resolution which is useful for
the album
so our IB works first we generate public
public master key which is generator
matrix of an allopathic code and we also
have metric G like in the wrong decay
and the trap the master secret key will
be the trapdoor of wrong sign the key
derivation to use a key derivation we
need an Oracle H in order to embed any
identity in the space of the of the
signature from sign and to compute the
secret the secret key of an identity the
trusted Authority run the algorithm
wrong sign with the trapdoor T and we
obtain by by definition we obtain s so
that as I'm an SP the rank of si minus P
is below our and since we have this
property we can use wrong PK with the
mattress
a to encrypt and decrypt the any message
em so the the matrix a plays two roles
one you can be it is used as a public
method in public lyrics for the
encryption and the decryption and it is
also used in wrong sign to by the
Transit Authority to compute the secret
key of any users so the security of our
IB is based on on the assumption that a
la PC plus code is indistinguishable
from a random code and under this
assumption the security of a high B II
is reduced to the security of wrong PK
I'll give us some parameters we have
public master key of a few megabytes and
who is very large because of the the
fact that assume that you in wrong sign
are not statistically close to the
uniform but only computationally close
and the bound depend on Q that's why we
need a huge a real app but of course the
goal of article is not to design
optimized algorithm but more to have
maybe a baton of their assumption in
conclusion there is to several open
questions so first one is to find a
social decision to the aerosol problem
because the security of Ron PK is based
on the decision and the decision version
of this problem and for the currently
the best attack again the decision
version of this problem is to solve the
constitutional conclusion L problem but
we don't have
in your addiction and the second
question is how to design an IB in the
in the M in metric because as I said
with the wrong metric we can use the
parameter M of the size of the field in
order to - it is useful to to construct
the wrong PK and we cannot adapt to the
idea to running so if we want to maybe
in Hamming we in ramming metric we need
a completely different idea
thank you for a for attention if there
is any patient
[Applause]