so since I'm going to talk about the
role of memory and cryptographic
reductions I will start with a short
introduction to reductions so usually
when we constructed some cryptographic
scheme and we want to show that it is
secure we use we rely on cryptographic
reductions so suppose we have some hard
problem P what we do is we show that
given any adversary breaking the
security of our scheme can be turned
into an algorithm solving instances of
our problem more precisely the algorithm
we construct will run the adversary as a
subroutine and answer potential Oracle
queries of it and this in particularly
implies that the running time of our
reduction will be at least the running
time of the adversary and the same holds
for the memory consumption now the
tightness of our reduction can be seen
as some sort of measure of its quality
what we usually do there is we compare
the resources used by our algorithm to
the resource resources used by the
adversary it runs as a subroutine and
what we usually compare they're both
running time and success probability and
if both time and success probability
essentially stay the same we say that
the reduction is tight now to see why
the tightness of a reduction matters for
giving concrete security guarantees we
will look at the time success
probability trade-off plot for our
problem P which might for example it
something like this
so we see we have two axis indicating
success probability and running time of
our algorithm and the plot is divided
into two areas label is unbroken and
broken now if a point lies somewhere in
the area labeled as unbroken this means
that according to current cryptanalytic
knowledge they exists no exist is no
algorithm which is able to solve an
instance of our problem in the
corresponding time with at least the
corresponding success probability okay
so now suppose that we want our base
we constructed to be secure against all
adversaries satisfying some constraints
on running time and success probability
by our reduction we know that we can
turn this adversity adversary' into an
algorithm solving instances of our
problem P however if the reductions non
tight
we might actually end up with an
algorithm which runs in considerably
higher time and also succeeds with less
probability so in this example here we
see that we actually ended up with an
algorithm in the area for which our
problem is known to be broken so we
can't conclude anything on the security
of our scheme however if our reduction
was tight the situation would look
different in this case we would see that
given any adversary breaking the
security of our scheme we would be able
to construct an algorithm which
outperforms all the currently best-known
algorithms in solving our problem and
this in this way we gain trust in the
security of our scheme so as just
discussed usually when talking about
tightness we only consider running time
and success probability however if we if
one talks to cryptanalysis they will
probably tell you that actually memory
is also a very important resource and
actually the most expensive one so in
our work we consider the role of memory
in cryptographic reductions and we
conclude that indeed memory can be
crucial when making complete security
statements we also investigate starting
to investigate how to make reductions
memory tight meaning how to obtain
reductions essentially preserving the
same memory requirements as the
algorithms we started with and we do
this by giving a couple of tools which
can be seen as a memory efficient
replacement for typical non memory
efficient steps in reductions we use
those in one concrete application namely
giving a memory tight reduction for the
RSA full domain hash signature scheme
and finally we asked ourselves whether
there also exists reductions which
cannot be both tight and memory tight
and actually found some evidence
pointing in that direction by proving
some lower bounds so now let's look why
memory in reductions matters so for this
we're going to look at time memory
trade-offs so an important observation
here is that for several problems which
are relevant for crypto the best-known
algorithms actually require high memory
or to phrase it differently we are some
problems are harder to solve if less
memory is available and this in
particularly holes for several lattice
or coding based problems and as people
see now this needs to be taken into
account when derived in concrete
security statements and we will look at
a concrete example namely the learning
parity with noise problem so so far we
have looked at time success trade-off
plots now when we add memory we would
actually have to look at a three
dimensional time success memory
trade-off plot however to keep things
simpler in two-dimensional I will only
consider algorithms having a constant
success probability so we will now look
at trade-off plots in this plane so ok
we see that the time memory trade-off
plot again has two axes now the x axis
indicates the memory consumption of
algorithms so now if a point lies in the
area labeled as unbroken this means that
according to current cryptanalytic
knowledge there are no algorithms known
which are able to solve instances of LPM
in the corresponding time and with a
corresponding memory now for LPM this
time memory trade-off plot is
essentially determined by two algorithms
the first one being the gauss algorithm
which we see here so as we can see it's
able to solve instances of LPM given
enough running time but the memory
essentially plays no role here
now the second algorithm would be the B
kW algorithm we see it's able to solve
instances of LP n in considerably faster
time however this comes at the cost of
some increased memory consumption
so overall the time memory trade-off
plot for LP n looks something like that
and actually due to some recent results
by SI L which will also be presented
here at crypto it looks more like this
so now again suppose we constructed some
scheme s and we want to show that when
we want it to be secured against all
adversaries satisfying some time and
memory constraints now in observation we
can make is that even if our reduction
is tight meaning that it preserves
essentially the running time it might
still not be memory tight and actually
have a way higher memory consumption now
we would again now again we would end up
with an algorithm in the area for which
LP n is known to be broken and we can't
derive anything on the security of our
scheme however if the reduction would
also additionally be memory tight
meaning its memory consumption would
essentially be the same as the memory
consumption of the underlying adversary
the situation looks different now we see
that from any algorithm breaking the
security of our scheme we are able to
construct an algorithm outperforming
even the best currently known algorithms
in solving LP m and we gain trust and
security of our scheme so as we have
just seen for some problems which
provide particularly good time memory
trade-offs memory can be crucial when
making concrete security statements so
we call these problems memory sensitive
and they for example include LP n has
just seen the shortest vector problem or
the problem of finding a collision of
three points in a hash function and also
discrete logarithm over finite fields
for example however for other problems
the best known algorithms only require
small memories so in this case while
still a memory tight reduction yields a
stronger result it's harder to measure
its advantage and problems of this type
for example could be to find a collision
or a hash function and preimage
resistance and hash functions or solving
the discrete logarithm problem of an
elliptic curves defined of prime fields
now I want to illustrate that in deeds
typical reductions often contain steps
which result in our algorithms having a
higher memory consumption for this we're
going to look at two examples the first
one being the simulation of a random
Oracle so a random Oracle is an
idealization of a hash function and
works as follows the adversary has
access to an Oracle which it may query
on points and as a in response it's
going to get a union uniformly
distributed its string however since we
are modeling a hash function during the
Oracle on the same point several times
will result in the same answer so this
is usually simulated in reductions using
lazy sampling and this is by keeping
track of a list of query answer pairs so
whenever the adversary Curie's its
Oracle for the Oracle value on some
point we check whether this value has
already been defined and if not we would
sample a fresh round embed string store
it and then return the answer and it's
important to note here that we really
have to stay a store the answers to our
queries since the adversary might worry
it's Oracle several times on the same
point so in the worst case we could
actually have an adversary which
essentially does nothing but query its
random Oracle and in this case we would
end up with a reduction which has to
provide additional memory which is of
the order of the running time of the
underlying adversary
so the second
example occurs when checking for
freshness of messages in the unfortunate
a game for signature schemes so here we
have an adversary which has access to a
signing Oracle which it may query on
messages in order to obtain signatures
on them in the end of the game it's
going to output a forgery attempt
consisting of a message and a signature
and it wins the game if the signature is
valid on that message and what I want to
concentrate on here if the message is
fresh meaning it has not so far not been
queried to the signing Oracle and these
checking for freshness is usually done
by simply keeping track of all messages
query to the signing Oracle so again in
this case we might end up with a
reduction having to provide significant
additional memory so to give a short
recap of what I have discussed so far so
currently at least in most of
theoretical work the memory consumption
is often ignored in reductions and also
many existing reductions contain steps
which result in the constructed
algorithms having highly increased
memory consumption and this seems
particularly problematic problematic for
memory sensitive problems that is for
problems which provide good time memory
trade-offs so how can we achieve memory
tightness to give some examples for that
we are going to revisit the examples
from a minute ago so the first one was
the simulation of a random Oracle via
lazy sampling where we had to keep track
of a list of queries and answers to
queries in order to be able to provide
the adversary with a consistent
simulation of the random Oracle and now
this can be made memory efficient by
using a pseudo-random function this is
actually actually something which was
already noticed by Bernstein in 2011 but
not formally analyzed so here what we
would do is we would sample
a key for a pseudo-random function and
then whenever the adversary creates its
random Oracle on some point we would
derive the answer to this query
deterministically using our pseudo
random function so in this way we don't
have to store the answer anymore to be
able to provide the adversary with the
consistent simulation and it's quite
easy to see that any adversary which is
able to distinguish this simulation of a
random Oracle from a proper random
Oracle would be able to break the
security of a pseudo-random function so
the second example were occurred when
checking for freshness of messages in
the unfortunate e game for signature
schemes so here the adversity had access
to a signing Oracle and in the end
output a forgery attempt consisting of
the message in the signature and we
wanted to check whether the output
message indeed was fresh so this can be
made memory efficient in the following
way so the general idea here is to use
the adversary itself as a memory so what
we would do is we would still answer the
signing queries in the usual way but no
longer store the corresponding messages
and at the end of our reduction when the
adversary outputs its forgery attempt we
would store the message and then we bind
the adversary meaning we would run it a
second time providing it with the exact
same random coins and also answering all
of its signature queries with the same
answers if we do this the sequence of
messages submitted by the adversary to
the signing Oracle will be the same so
now whenever the adversary queries for a
signature we could simply check whether
this message is actually the message it
forges on so in doing this we only have
to store one message however this comes
at the cost of potentially running the
adversary twice and an important thing
to note here is since we want to rewind
yet whether we actually have to store
all the coins provided to the adversary
and used
we derive signatures but this could be
done in a memory efficient way again
using a pseudo-random function so a
final thing I want to talk about is
lower bounds so showing that for some
reductions it seems not possible to
obtain obtained version of the reduction
which is both tight and memory tight for
this we're going to look at two versions
of the unfortunate e game for signature
schemes the first one just being the
usual unfortunate e against chosen
chosen message attack s-- for signature
schemes so in this game the adversary
has access to a public key and a signing
Oracle which it may query on messages in
order to obtain signatures on them and
in the end of the game it's going to
output a forgery attempt consisting of a
message and a signature and it wins the
game if the signature is indeed valid on
this message and if the message is fresh
meaning it has not been carried to the
signing Oracle so far
now the second game we are going to look
at can be seen as a multi forgery
attempt version of the first game so
again the adversary has access to a
public key and a signing Oracle but now
it's no longer restricted to make a
single forgery attempt instead if it's
allowed to make many and can do so at
any point in time and it wins the game
if any of those forgery attempts is
successful meaning that the signature is
valid and the message so far has not
been created to this on e Morricone now
one could argue that this actually
models more realistically what we expect
of a signature scheme since the
restriction to a single forgery attempt
seems somewhat artificial however of
course we would like to use the more
simple version and this also seems
justified since there is a tight
reduction from the multi forge game to
the forge game to see that note that a
forge adversary' can check signatures
itself for validity so the reduction
would essentially boiled down to
checking whether a message is fresh
and this could for example be done by
simply keeping track of all messages
submitted to the signing Oracle however
then the reduction is long tied another
thing we could do is to simply guess
which of the forgery attempts of the
adversary would be on a fresh message
however then we would end up with a
reduction having a lower success
probability and the final thing we could
think of is actually to rewind our
adversary at each point when it makes a
sign inquiry in order to check for
freshness of the message but this will
result in a higher running time so as we
have seen there are several trade offs
for reductions from the m4 to the forge
game but all of them lose a fact factor
or in order of the order of the
adversaries in one of our resources
but since m4 is probably the more
realistic game and Forge the simpler one
we would clearly prefer a reduction
which is about tight and memory tight so
obtains once in all over the row however
this seems not possible and indeed we
are able to show a theorem which
informally looks something like this so
for a certain class of blackbox
reductions from m4 to forge it's not
possible to be both tight and memory
tight so the proof users streaming
algorithms which are algorithms which
have to process a large input would only
have a small working memory so they can
only process its input as a ordered
stream of small chunks but make several
passes over those stream and so the
restrictions on our reductions
essentially forced them to behave as a
streaming algorithm where the single
chunks will correspond to the signing
and forgery queries and in this way we
are able to use a lower bound on the
amounts of passes a streaming algorithm
has to make over its input in order to
compute certain functions so to give a
very sharp conclusion memory in
cryptographic reductions does matter and
it should be addressed when coming up
with reduction
also it seems possible for many
reductions to at a simple fix but there
also are reductions which seem to be
inherent memory loose thank you
[Applause]