good morning everybody so I'm going to
talk about the our work on quantum
security of an net and this is a joint
work with fans own and this is my
attempt at illustrating and Mac under
contract proposed Pirie and so what I'm
going to do is this I'm going to first
talk about briefly about quantum
security in general and then as a
warm-up I'm going to talk about cascade
construction and then finally I'm going
to talk about and mech so about quantum
security we in a sense we can say that
quantum security is a stronger version
of post quantum cryptography where the
adversary not only has a quantum
computation or capability but also the
quantum computation and quantum
communication capability with this
environment of course there can be
formalized as adversaries ability to
make quantum super post series to its
Oracle so like a light classical case
instead of making a query X and
receiving Oracle answer who acts the
adversary can prepare its curry as a
superposition of different messages X
and getting the again superposed answers
so perhaps one motivation for this is
from the quantum random Oracle model so
if we regard a random Oracle as a I
really shouldn't health hash function
then we can see that any quantum
adversary can evaluate the such hash
function in superposition why well maybe
perhaps in order to do a reverse search
for anyway in that case we can think
that the traditional formulation of the
random Oracle model doesn't do justice
in formulating the adversary or
capability of quantum adversary in such
steady
so therefore the correct notion seems to
be the quantum random Oracle model where
the adversary can make quantum
superposed theories to the random Oracle
in a sense the quantum security is the
full generalization of the quantum
random Oracle model and then now the
adversary can make quantum superboost
here is to all of its Oracles for
example when you are talking about
encryption schemes than
a Christian Oracle and for district
Easter signature therapy signing fairies
so despite this is a relatively recent
area there are already many interesting
results both positive and negative and
so now there are some constructions
involving quantum random Oracle's and
there are some PRF max encryption
schemes and signature schemes and so on
and on the other end there are also many
interesting or texts these or texts are
especially interesting because they are
successful quantum attacks on the
classically secure schemes
examples include Evan master cypher
Mubarak of cipher and cbc Meg and other
block cipher based perhaps and
especially we all these works are based
on quantum algorithm called Simon's
algorithm in clever way and especially
the last work about CBC Megan others are
the more present in crypto last year and
that actually partially answers the
question posed by Bonnie and sundry can
we construct a quantum secure PRF for a
large domain from a quantum secure PRF
for a small domain in particular to the
cbc-mac where I make instructions give
quantum secure perhaps in other words
can we do care of domain extension in
the quantum setting and so well they say
that this force in EC max case the
answer is no but you know since our work
is complementary to that so that we have
proved that an Mac HTML a Mac and some
other schemes are quantum secure of
course if the underlying small key F is
quantum secure the main ingredients we
have used for this our first oracle
indistinguishability of functions and a
notion we call cure of security and the
random leakage so I'm going to first
talk about cascade construction the
Cascade construction is I start with a
small PRF where the key space is equals
the codomain and we can build a larger
PRF simply by processing iteratively
process each message block one by one
the result is the Cascade construction
here I'll illustrating the three-block
case
and classically the cascade construction
is known to be secure if the number of
message blocks are fixed and the result
is done by paleri Canadian Krawczyk in
1996 and the proof uses a two-level
hybrid argument in one level one level
it's over the message blocks and another
level is over the Curie's and I'll
briefly illustrate I'll really show the
outline of the proof so the proof
consists of a successive games
indistinguishable games and each all of
them are identical except how the Oracle
is prepared of course in the original
original game we have the Cascade
construction and we move to the next
game where the first PRF instance is
switched to a uniform random function of
course this change is indistinguishable
due to the PRF security and in the next
game we are going to eliminate one more
PRF instance by a uniform random
function and you are going to do this
once more and we finally arrive at the
game where the Oracle is uniform random
function but in order that this outline
works each successive games should be
indistinguishable from the previous one
so we can see that the each Oracle
theory to the left hand side part should
be indistinguishable no Oracle carry to
the right hand side part to allow this
switch but we can if you look at this
carefully then we can see that this does
not involve just single care of instance
but actually many care of instances
because whenever the adversary makes a
theory of Z of X that'll produce a
randomly chosen PRF key role of Z so
therefore if the adversary makes put our
true queries then there are two keys are
involved so there are Q PRF instances to
handle this situation
in the classical proof a notion called
multi or occur security was given so
this is not complicated it simply says
that if you have polynomial number of
independent PRF instances that will be
indistinguishable from the same number
of
independent uniform random functions and
of course that can be proved by a simple
hybrid argument so now the multi Oracle
setting is ready now we can do argue
that we can carry out the outline that I
have explained
so whenever the adversary makes total
two queries then we can prepare your
queue instances and then using this
multi Oracle indistinguishability we can
simulate the transition from this Oracle
to that Oracle so that allows the that's
more or less the outline of the class
for security proof of the cascade
construction unfortunately that doesn't
really work for the quantum setting
because obviously if you look at this
proof then it is assumed that each
individual queries are on superposed and
of course that's not true in the quantum
security setting so but one interesting
thing is that at least one special case
of the Cascade construction was already
proved to be quantum secure and that is
in fact the ggm construction given by
called Reichhold Wasser and Macaulay
this is a way to construct a PRF out of
a length doubling PRG Andi 2012 xandrie
showed that ggm is quantum secure if the
underlying PRG is quantum secure quantum
secure so let me so one of sort of a
simple observation we can make is this
if we modify the notation a little bit
we can immediately see that GCM is in
fact a special case of the Cascade
construction when the underlying Calif
can process only one single bit so in
fact that can be readily extended to the
case if the underlying PRF has a
polynomial size domain because such a
PRF is in fact PRG so what we need to do
is to remove this restriction to the
general case so to do that let me
briefly review under this approach for
proving
quantum security of GGN so first step is
to repackaging the classical ggm
security using a new notion called
indistinguishability and then he proved
the Oracle indistinguishability using
new techniques suitable for a quantum
setting and so let's talk about worker
indistinguishability suppose we have our
true probability distributions is 0 and
d1 and of course we know what do you
mean that these two are
indistinguishable so one it is hard to
distinguish one sample of d0 from the
other sample from d1 in that case we say
that these two are indistinguishable
then we can say that the 0 and the 1 are
all indistinguishable if it is hard to
distinguish arbitrarily sized indexed
family of independent and identically
distributed samples from B 0 and from
the same kind of samples from d1 and we
are going to eventually applies to PRF
so we need to talk about iid samples of
functions so let's be a little bit more
for now suppose is an index set and
suppose G is a function distribution
here this notation Y to the X is a very
important function space from X to Y and
imagine Y and X are like the bit strings
space of meat strings and then I'm going
to define this e to the I this is a
distribution of random functions of type
I to D Y to the X so how do you define
it
each image F of I is chosen
independently according to the
distribution T remember that this
distribution is a function distribution
so therefore each fi is in fact a random
function from X to Y and in fact we can
take a slightly different but equivalent
point of view by regard considering the
whoring isomorphism so simply Y to the X
to the I is isomorphic to the Y to the I
times X Y because as I told you before
fi is a function from X to Y so this can
be evaluated on any people what happened
ok any point X so but the effect is that
it
in fact this gives you a function of INX
together because these two viewpoints
are completely interchangeable we can
regard this DDI as a distribution of
random functions from I times X to I
okay so now we are ready to talk about
Oracle indistinguishability of functions
suppose I is an index set and we have we
are given two function distributions and
I'm going to define that they are Oracle
indistinguishable if it is hard to
distinguish one iid sample of d0 from
another iid sample of t1 by any quantum
adversary who can make quantum furies so
and also we can talk about or occur
security of Kiev's using this we say
that PRF is Oracle secure if it is a
rockery indistinguishable from a uniform
random function in impact that turns out
to be exactly the notion required for
carrying out security proof for the
Cascade construction let me show you I
so here we have a indexer I and for each
index I we need to pick a uniform random
instance independent random instance of
PRF and to do that we need to pick a
secret key for this particular I that in
fact gives us a uniform random function
kappa from the indexer i to the key
space of F and we need to compare this
Oracle with another Oracle chosen by
choosing a uniform independent random
function for each index but if you think
about it that's simply a uniform random
function of I and X together
so in fact Oracle security gives us this
in indistinguishability which exactly is
the right shape for carrying out the
security proof for the Cascade
construction so the only remaining
problem is so is the PRF F or a curse
secure the answer is yes in fact it can
be more slightly more general and if we
have to efficiently sample in this to
visual function distributions then we
can prove that easy row and you honor
indistinguishable in the class car
setting the proof would be even easier
so it can be done by simple hybrid
argument over Curie's but of course in
the quantum setting that is not possible
but again we can rely on a technique
developed by sundry for the context of
the ggm security that's we can switch to
small range distribution
so unlike the iid distribution in the
small range distribution each image fi
are not chosen independently instead
we've fixed a small number R and we are
going to first choose our number of
independent samples and each F eyes are
chosen to be unit for me one of those
are samples so there will be necessarily
lots of duplicates and only there are
only our genuine independent copies and
what sundry showed in the security of
ggm setting is that it is
indistinguishable from switching from
the iid distribution to the small ranges
distribution so here what I need to do
is to compare small range distributions
of d0 and d1 and in fact now we are can
do is to we can do the hybrid argument
over those are independent copies so
gradually one by one we can switch from
[Music]
switch those are samples from d0 and d1
to finish the proof further or
indistinguishability well now we are
ready everything's done essentially done
for cascade so if FP is a secure PRF
then according to previous argument F
who is Oracle secure then using the
worker security we can carry out the
hybrid argument for the Cascade
construction which proves the quantum
security of cascade cascade construction
ok let's move on to the N Mac n Meg is
simply cascade construction with
additional post-processing by additional
independent PRF instance and so it
requires two keys one for the Cascade
and another for the post-processing and
that post-processing prevents the
extension attack so unlike the case of
the Cascade construction you know
processing variable-length messages and
classically of course the security of an
Mecca is proven and when you try to
adapt those classical proofs to the
quantum setting we were not able to do
that so we have devised a direct hybrid
argument using an extended version of
Oracle indistinguishability and for do
this we need an additional property of a
secure PRF so but before that the first
step in our proof is to replace this
outer PRF instance with a random Oracle
H of course this is possible due to the
PRF security and so from now on I'm
going to pretend that so here is an
illustration again for a three-block
case and from now on I'm going to
pretend that this is the definition of n
there okay so this post-processing
random Oracle is very helpful because it
prevents the extension attack but on the
other end this is not helpful because it
prevents using PRF security
the reason is this the adversary can
make different message block theories so
if the adversary makes zero block URI
then the Cascade will simply output the
secret key K and which will be post
processed by H and the adversary now has
access to H of K of course this is
problematic because what is peer of
security after all that's simply ability
to substitute one pair of instance with
the random function but in order to
guarantee that the cyclic case should be
well completely secret
and so now adversary knows H of K this
is an information leakage however small
this might be so what you need is that
this purif instance should remain
pseudo-random even when H K is leaked
when for a random RH so now we can
expect that because the amount of
information leakage is too small
intuitively it is almost clear that if F
is secure F should be again secure even
on the random leakage and in fact that
I'm going to say that and so anyway I
have a file
this notion formalized this notion
security and the random licorice as
follows so imagine two games in one game
the adversary is given correct instance
a random Oracle and a hash of the secret
key K and in another game we are
adversary's given a uniform random
function and a random Oracle and a fake
hash value and if true these two games
are indistinguishable then we say that
sheriff is secure on the random wreckage
and of course so classically it is not
that hard at all
to show that a secure PRF is secure on
the random negation and we were able to
do the same in the quantum setting and
the techniques we have used our
dominicanos innate hiding lemma and also
care of security against here recovery
ok so by invoking a 1-8 hiding lemma we
were able to pound any advantage of the
adversary attack on the under random
leakage by this right hand side term so
you can see that basically if the
function f is secure then the right hand
side is negligible well this is a very
weak bound but still as enough to prove
security on the random location well but
what about the I mentioned security
against key recovery but what about key
recovery isn't it obvious
so if he is recovered than all that's
all off but ultra positively if your
scheme is secure then it should be very
hard to recover the key
and of course in class car setting there
is a very easy proof and let's briefly
see how it works so if you have a key
recovery attacker then using a you can
build a distinguishing attacker P runs
this key recovery attacker until it
outputs a candidate key K and what be
next does is to very fair very check if
this answer is right or not by verifying
this key and an on period point Z so if
you see if this equation holds or not
and this P will output 1 if and only if
this verification checks out and in fact
this is fine in the classical case
because if this Oracle is a PRF instance
then B will output 1
with non-negligible probability as large
as the success probability of a and on
the other end this is a crucial part if
oh is a uniform random function this all
Z because Z sorry this all Z is uncured
so all this left hand side will be
independent from the right hand side and
this is really from random so therefore
the variation may check out only with a
negligible probability so that's how
classical proof goes but as you can see
in the quantum setting the problem is
that even one single theory may be
potentially plot all the points in the
superposition so in other words there
may not exist any point Z in the domain
where was he is independent from the
right hand side FK of Z so the classical
argument doesn't hold here so of course
the obvious way out is to instead of
verifying at an unclear at the point Z
we can verify a random point and
intuitively we can see that this should
obviously work but still analyzing this
may not be completely trivial and in
fact we were able to prove that if the
PRF is secure then it is secure against
key recovery by reusing to a variant of
quantum search problem so now we know
that PRF F is secure under under
medication and this can be looked in a
slightly different way equivalent way so
consider to function distributions in a
one function distribution key is chosen
and HK is concatenated by a PRF instance
so in this function the first part is
essentially random constant and in D 1
again a random w is chosen which is
concatenated by a uniform random
function so what PRF security on the
random linkage says is that these two
distributions are independent
indistinguishable if F is secure the
question is are they what are
indistinguishable
well almost but not so fast look at the
definition of D 0 this construction
depends on H and the auto bursary also
has access to H so therefore we need
actually one more update to the
of worker indistinguishability so in
fact that's possible and now we can say
that D zero and the owner or occur in
this usual relative to H and we can
essentially say the similar things so
now these two distributions are all in
distinguishable what do they mean so
given any index Zi and any index I we
can pick a random key couple of I so due
to this or occurring distinguishability
in short we can safely pretend that H of
a random function Kappa of I and F of
Kappa I and X are can be swapped with
the independent uniform random functions
of ini X respectively actually this
substitution is enough to prove quantum
securio mmm so I'm going to show you
briefly so I'm going to illustrate this
by the blocks up to three and again all
the games are identical except how the
Oracle is prepared of course in the
original Oracle B we have an net and
first thing we are going to do is to
substitute this random key syntactically
with a random function of a single tone
domain of course they are the same thing
it's only a syntactical change and now
that's done let's look at this so this
part is H of random function and F of
random from stains having the same
random function and the argument and so
on so from the Oracle security we can
see that we can substitute these two
parts independently to arrive at this
and of course we can do one more same
substitution so again this is H of a
random function and F of the same random
function and some odd room argument and
again we can substitute piece with two
independent random functions once more
and of course we can repeat this until
we get rid of all of PR F's and finally
we arrive at again where
the Oracle is uniform and non function
and essentially that proves the quantum
security your van back and so I have
shown you the proof that cascade
construction and n neck are quantum
secure and using some additional
assumption the the quantum secure of H
mag follows immediately and using
similar techniques we were able to also
prove quantum security of our guaranteed
cascade and a Mac thank you for your
attention
[Applause]