because given a talk hi thanks
so this is joint work with my advisor
and Yanique we are hanging around all
the conference during the whole
conference over free to talk to any of
us
so me moving bow is a cryptocurrency
that allows you to make private payments
without having to download the entire
the entire block chain without having to
download 200 gigabytes of data when you
start a new client it was proposed in
2016 by an anonymous person going by the
name of Tom Elvis Schuster which is the
name of all the Mort in the French
version of Harry Potter and it was built
on the top of three main ideas it's a
standalone cryptocurrency but it was
built on three main ideas that were
initially envisioned for Bitcoin and
that for which reverie Maxwell should be
credited namely confidential
transactions which adds a privacy on the
top of Bitcoin go and join which adds up
anonymity and transaction cut through
which adds up scalability after this
publication the author disappeared never
to be found again and some people to
cover this work mostly angry poultra and
a couple of months later another
anonymous person going by the name of
pig not to several in your four friends
develop an implementation and is now
luncheon so in other words what happened
is that Gregory Maxwell put some forum
blog put some forum posts on Bitcoin
talk and this random guy appears puts
this text file and three years later our
cryptocurrencies lunch it potentially
worth billions of dollars and there is
no proof of security so what we did
together with the girl in unique was
proof that these cryptocurrency
satisfies some security notions and we
try to see if we could improve it by
means of abstraction even before talking
about mobile itself can I get a show of
end of how many of you know what is a
utx oh wow okay so in
in in Bitcoin at some point you have to
inject money into the system and the way
you do it is that you create a
transaction that only specify some
outputs you put a value and you
associate this value discredit to some
verification key and if you know the
signing key associated this verification
key then you can spend the money and the
way that you do it is that you create a
new transaction where you're specifying
the outputs how much of this money you
are giving to which verification key and
you would sign this transaction with
your signing key now you would have the
transaction to be balanced if I forget
about fees and stuff like that I would
have that the sum of the output should
be equal to the value associated to this
input and then it goes on and on like
that so for example if I want to send if
I have one Bitcoin and I want to send
you to you two bitcoins I would have to
create a transaction and I would have to
find two verification key was value adds
up to the amount that I want to send you
okay and there is no reason for which in
the output the output should be only the
recipient it could be for example a
change that I want to keep for myself
now on the other side when I receive a
payment I how to avoid that double
spending how do I avoid that these are
signing he has not been used twice the
way that I do so is that I construct a
list of verification key together with
the Associated values that can spend the
money and the way that I do so is that I
look at the world transaction history
and I see the outputs and I check that
they have not been spent so again if I
start if I download if I have a new
Bitcoin client the way that I should
accept new transaction is I don't load
the world transaction history which a
few days ago amounted to more than 200
EAGA bytes I verify all the transactions
and then I construct this list and there
is a great deal of difference between
downloading this world transaction
history and unloading only the list of
unspent transaction output this UT
exocet dimension and which right now
amounts to more or less four gigabytes
and there is no reason for which I would
have to download the entire transaction
history rather than this set and this is
what's very difficult to achieve
and at the same time we're what in some
form at least may move in water achieves
now back to the improvements that I
wanted to mention so the first improving
that dimension is conjoined which is
adds up anonymity and the way it does so
is by noticing that in the inputs there
is no reason for which all the signature
should belong to the same person so if I
were to get together with other friends
that are making other transactions at
the same time instead of signing only my
little transaction we could construct
together by coordination a bigger
transaction the specifying the outputs
all our outputs and we would sign and
said this bigger transaction and I means
of shuffling this will destroy the link
that we have between the sender and the
recipient now if there it's there are
some contribution which are bit more
complicated than that for example if I
want to hide to the other participant
how much money which are my recipients
but the bottom line of this is that with
cooperation I can achieve some form of
annuity and and that is always good to
have friends cut through it's not really
possible in Bitcoin but the fundamental
idea is that if at some point I'm
creating some money and attributing it
to Bob and then Bob send this to Charlie
the ledger itself has no need to record
the fact that Bob at some point had some
money this can easily be forgotten and
the way we call it this is Kathryn
finally the last feature privacy feature
that was initially envisioned for
Bitcoin it's called confidential
transactions and is the most
cryptographically consistent and the
basic idea is that if you want to hide
the value in a Bitcoin transaction you
can replace them with commitments if you
don't know what commitment schemes are
you can think of them as encryption if
you don't know what encryption is
whatever but the basic idea is that
commitments are really what we want they
are in the case of penderson commitment
they are perfectly adding so they
perfectly hide the values and they are
binding in the sense that once I
selected this commitment they can all
really change my mind about how
much value were put in there and at this
point one problem would be how do I
check that that transaction is balanced
that the sum of the outputs minus sum of
the inputs is equal to zero
and the way that I would do it is that
the day transaction the person that's
creating the transaction would select
the opening so that they are sum up to
zero and at this point if the sum of
their commitments in the outputs minus
the inputs is the identity element it
would mean necessarily that the values
add up to zero and therefore the
transaction is balanced now it's a
little bit more complicated than that
because implicitly these values are not
natural elements they are elements in a
finite field so for example I could have
as input P minus 1 and 1 on the other
side and I don't really want to did have
this problem of wraparound so I for in
order to to fix that I have to add a
range proof simulation extractable
journal is proof that says that these
values is for example 32 bit long and
this is sort of the starting point for
me moving more so if I were to take back
confidential transactions in the way
they explained it before I would have
instead of these values again these
commitments and I will have some sort of
opening associated to them and a
transaction would have again the
signature and then values were placed by
commitments now there is another way
which I can check that this transaction
is balanced and is not to force the
person to put the openings to be equal
to zero but to put - to let define the
access what the code will call the
access as the sum of the outputs minus
sum of the inputs and and notice that
this is a our group element and we can
see this as a public key of which only
the sender which has the input and the
recipient which has the outputs know the
respective secret key so in theory they
could get together and prove to anybody
knowledge of these secret key by making
a signature for example on the empty
element and this in some sense would
prove that they know the discrete log of
this group element and therefore that it
was a commitment to zero and if it was a
commitment to zero it was a trellis
transaction the sort of the way it works
and and the crazy idea be moving world
what what makes it beautiful is that the
it actually says well right now when I
want to make a transaction I have true
secret keys I have a opening to the
commitment and I have also assigning
here what if I just get rid of the
signing keys
what if the this signature that I'm
making would be sufficient both for
proving that a transaction is balanced
and for proving that I really know the
openings to this commitment there is no
a priori reason for which this would
work and this is what we try to prove so
using this if I were to go back to the
initial slide where we saw the flow of
transactions how do I create some money
I would have to create a new transaction
where the value is replace it with the
commitments again and I would have to
specify in something that I call the
supply how much value I'm creating and
the signature would be valid under that
commit the commitment in doubt - the
commitment with zero binding factor to
the to the value that's being declared
and it was sort of proved that this
commitment is really creating this value
and then the secret key for him how once
I created this this commitment how do I
spend it and the way that they do it is
that I would create again a transaction
I would put as input a commitment I
would declare the change how much value
I want to take for myself and on the
other side the recipient would create a
commitment to the value of the reminder
the value that we agreed upon and
together using our respective openings
we would create this signature right so
actually what we do in the paper is we
show the way in which these you can do
it not interactively so here when me
moving most sort of starts to shine and
if I have one if I have two transactions
and again this transaction are just true
lists of commitments which have can be
verified with the signature and the
signature is valid again under the sum
of the outputs - some of the inputs I
can also consider what is called an
aggregated transaction and what does it
mean the addition
here it means that I take the inputs of
the true transaction and I concatenate
them and I put it in on your transaction
I take their outputs and I concatenate
them I consider the union of the two and
now what is the access of this
transaction while the inputs get added
together and the outputs get added
together so it's the addition of the
true accesses of the two previous
accesses and we know of a primitive
namely aggregated signatures which allow
me without knowing the signing key of
any of the two transaction to squash
together these two signatures and have
only one which accounts for both at the
same time and and the beautiful thing
about this is that it gives me some I
can then shuffle the transaction and I
would destroy the link that was between
the true transaction individually and
also I can do this any time I do not
have to I do not need to wait for any
party to be online I can do it is known
interactively and what I want and there
is another thing that is interesting to
notice and it is that and this is the
scalability feature of me moving more is
that if I have a transaction where the
output goes back as input the
intermediate thing that we talked about
before well at this point the final
transaction what do we have we have that
the same coin the same commitment will
appear both as input and as output and
therefore it does not contribute to the
final sum what does this mean it means
that what if what if we think a
cut-through is the way in the way we
thought about this before what if we
just remove these commitments then the
signature will still be valid because
the access again has these terms
cancelling out each other so they don't
really contribute so I can really get
rid of them and still have a transaction
which is valid so in a way they only
price them paying for aggregating two
transaction is adding these group
element over here and in the meantime I
get rid of all the intermediate things
and the way that we sort this sort of
fits together is beautiful and very
simple at the same time and we move in
bold they used to say that everything is
a transaction even the ledger at this
point you can think of it just as a list
of coins that have been generated at
some point and then squash together so
it has only output
and the supply the money that has been
generated accounts for the total amount
of money that is available in the system
and the signature is accounts for all
the past transactions so instead of
downloading if you remember the picture
of before if I want to have some
cryptographic notion of validity of the
UT X I just have to download this verify
this signature and all the range proofs
when I'm done I don't have to download
to you 200 gigabytes of data so what did
we do what we took minimal limbo we
abstracted away the notion of homework
commitments simulation extractable
non-interactive general knowledge proofs
and arguments and and aggregate
signatures we provide some security
notion that we believe describe the
security properties that we want from a
moving ball namely it is not possible to
spend more money than is available in
the system which protects the system it
is not possible to steal money from
honest users we want to protect the
users and the amounts are hidden we are
protecting the transfers of money from
user to user and then we prove these the
security of member raynbow and in order
to do so we have to introduce new
security assumptions of compatibility
between the signature scheme and the
commitment scheme this comes from the
fact that as you saw before a commitment
to zero acts as a public key for signing
a transaction and we gave also examples
of our commitment and signature scheme
that satisfy this property namely
paterson commitments and nor signatures
which is what has been used in a green
implementation of a moving ball right
now and we give another example
penderson commitments and VLS signature
which which acts better in terms of
aggregation because in BLS signature
aggregation of signature is only one
group element more formally what did we
prove is that inflation again protects
the system it says that it is very
difficult for an adversary to create a
ledger and the transaction which is
consuming more money than was available
in the system and intuitively you can
say that this can happen in two ways
either that
three is breaking something in the
cryptographic primitives using the
ledger for example the commitment the
binding property of the commitment
scheme or the affordability notion for
the signature or the range proofs or
it's creating a transaction which is not
balanced and in order to create a
transaction translating a transaction
which is not balanced
means that the signature is valid under
a commitment that is nonzero and again
you see that there is this sort of
relation between commitments and
signature which needs to be put in place
and formalized then we prove that it is
not possible for an adversary that is
observing honest user interacting and is
interacting itself with the ledger to
steal at any point in time one coin that
belongs to an honest users this is a
much more difficult to prove
finally we prove transaction
indistinguishability and it basically
says that if we have two transactions of
the same length then they you cannot
really distinguish one from the other in
the sort of NCPA game and actually these
are over a week notion of privacy and
we're working on a stronger notion that
we're going to predict in integrating
the full version because in fact if you
consider two transactions and this true
transaction I have nothing in common
then when you aggregate them these two
accesses the public keys sort of
uniquely identify the true constituting
transactions of this aggregated
transaction because they are the subset
sum of some of these commitments so I
can in some sense derive back which
construction made it and this is a
property that I will that implicitly I I
do not want to be there and there is
there was a proposal namely kernel
offset from Andrew poultra that is now
integrated into cream that prevents this
and this is something we will put in a
full version strengthening the the
privacy game for transaction
indistinguishability this is basically
all I have to say so far and I'd like to
add that I am at the end of my PhD and I
am looking for a postdoc
so if you're looking for somebody that
can tell you that your roof system is is
secure and I can go all the way down to
implementing ashing into the curve or
hashing into a field element and maybe
I'm the right person to talk
[Applause]
questions for our Mackellar so this
notion of transaction or link ability is
what what exactly does it cover like
does it also cover like user earn link
ability like when I spend like it goes
from a user to another user and so on is
it like something like same same level
as the cash or is it like weaker or now
it covers the fact that if I created if
I created some money and then I sent it
some other user and I squash together
all these transactions then this
transaction are indistinguishable okay
so it's really for a particular
transaction the the money the amount of
money because so but what what about
could this money be traced okay so the
money can be traced later unless you add
these criminal offsetting okay and that
this is something that we will put soon
in their full version this relation
between commitments and signature is
that look is that standard notion or is
this like something that you need on top
of like when you do when you do
implement your blockchain you actually
need to take care of that or it's
something that this proper of me moving
body to be introduced so it's proper so
does that require like can it be do you
need started standard commitments a
signature yes but it is a property that
you need to prove on a pair of cough a
commitment and signature you need to
prove that this pair commitment
signature satisfy a property namely for
example the at least the fact that a
commitment to zero is a valid
verification key or can be mapped to a
valid verification key all right thank
you let's technically
[Applause]