so I'm going to talk about maliciously
secure private set intersection
I'd say joint work with Tobias so so
specifically I'm going to we are going
to realize this functionality of psi
where both the parties will get the
output of the protocol so AF and we have
this say it's a say an SV and the the
functionality will give the intersection
of this SA and SB nothing else to both
the parties so we are in the settings
where the set size are same or similar
you can pat it to make it same and also
we are considering security against
malicious adversary
so why psi so as already which I
mentioned that this is a really
practically motivated problem and it's
app it comes in many real-life scenarios
for example he mentioned about this
measuring ad conversion rate but there
are also many other applications like
private contact discovery matchmaking
ride-sharing secure skates and many
other things and there actually many
work has been done on this to party psi
primitive and specifically also on
actively seek EO to party psi primitive
but very few were considered the
multi-party settings so in this work
specifically like actively secure
multi-party setting so in this work we
try to construct more efficient
multi-party psi protocol which is secure
against a malicious adversary so in this
process we actually find propose several
secure psi protocol based on one
primitive which is called oblivious
linear function evaluation so
specifically we propose a to PFS
proposed a to psi protocol with optimal
communication complexity like which is
linear in the set size and the
computational complexity is dominated by
order of M log M field multiplication
and then we generalize this to psi
protocol to multi by D psi protocol with
communication complexity of n square
plus n MK where n is the number of
parties so usually this n is much
smaller than the set size M so we kind
of get almost linear communication
complexity for actively secure
multi-party psi protocol and for the
computational complexity is it is order
of n M log M basic field multiplication
we also give a protocol for threshold
multi-party psi with same communication
and completely computational complexity
and threshold multi-party psi means
every party will learn the intersection
when the size of the intersection is
greater than some threshold value and
all these protocols are information
theoretically secure in le hybrid model
and so we can say like in comparison
with other in psi protocol our protocol
kind of asymptotically beats all the
existing maliciously secure psi
protocols and this is the first
instantiation of a threshold multi-party
psi protocol which has your active
security and also almost linear
communication over it and note that for
the two party threshold psi protocol it
actually achieved the linear
communication over it because this is
kind of in minus 1 whole square so it's
just go away so we find this result in
le hybrid model now the question is what
is Whaley so this is a primitive called
oblivious linear function evaluation
where to part it is a two-party
primitive where one party the sender
holds this linear function ax plus B and
the other party holds this evaluation
point alpha and at the end of the
protocol receiver will lani alpha plus b
and sender will learn nothing so there
are many available construction
passively secure or actively secure it
cetera but for our specific instance
ation of the PSI protocol we use a
maliciously secure oily protocol from GN
n 17 which also achieve constant
communication over it
now how to do psi from Willie so from
Whaley we define a functionality
restrictive functionality really Plus
which actually I don't allow the
receiver to input 0 valleys in the oily
functionality and then from that we
define a functionality called oblivious
polynomial ever addition so we define
this Opia functionality which
essentially take two polynomial
randomized it and add it and from this
opa functionality we get this our
two-party PSI protocol and from this
two-party psi protocol we get this
multi-party psi protocol and I note that
like if you don't want active security
you can go from this oily directly to
this OPA functionality and then to the
PSI and multi-party psi so it's a nice
background so how to do this to psi from
Whaley so the idea is simple first you
encode your Paulino sets into polynomial
such that each element of the set
represent the root of the polynomial so
alleys encode is set SI to PA of X in
this way Bob encode is said his be to PB
of X and this way and then observe this
PA of X plus P V of X the roots of this
polynomial the roots of this polynomial
you can actually detect the intersection
of two sets but obviously this is not
secure because given this PA of X plus P
V of X one can remove this P V of X and
learn the input of the other party
totally so how to resolve this issue so
the simple thing what we can do is just
randomize this polynomials and add them
and so and we call it the intersection
polynomial which is PA into r1 plus PB
into r2 and so if you see closely again
the roots of this polynomial actually
gives the intersection of these two sets
SA and SB so actually this is already
shown by Krishna and so
that this ran linear randomized
polynomial can be written as like GCD of
P a comma P B into some uniform random
polynomial of some of the matching
degree and the roots of this GCD of P NP
B already gives the intersection and
this roots from this uniform polynomial
actually gives no information about the
other parties input so we use this fact
so in this paper actually they kind of
encrypt this polynomial with additively
home Orphic encryption and then for
maliciously say a malicious security
they use zero knowledge proof so that's
why using this heavy cryptographic
machinery they they lose the concrete
efficiency of the protocol so instead
what we use we use this primitive Whaley
to do this randomized addition so so
first we I define this functionality
which is called OPA of Livia's
polynomial addition and this
functionality Alice give input his input
polynomial PA and some random polynomial
R and Bob give his input polynomial PB
and at the end of the protocols Bob will
learn this PA plus PB into R so in other
terms actually Alice randomized Bob's
input polynomial and add his polynomial
to that so how we can realize this
functionality we can realize it from
Whaley in a simple manner so the so note
that the input of a and B is this PA and
PB polynomial which are of degree M and
now a choose random polynomial r1 and r2
of degree m and randomize his own
polynomial PA with this r1 well so we I
call it P which is equal to PA into R of
1 and then Alys evaluate his polynomial
P and this random polynomial R versa
publicly known index like alpha 1 to
alpha to him and Bob will also do the
same thing with his input polynomial PB
and then they invoked like
- Emily's where Alice's input is P of
alpha I and r2 of alpha and Bob's input
is PB of alpha so now from each
invocation of this oily Bob will learn
this PB into r2 plus P of like
evaluation of PB into r2 plus P and you
can see that degree of this PB a degree
of this r2 is M so the total degree of
this polynomial is 2m so from 2m
evolution points Bob can reconstruct the
polynomial PA into r1 plus PB into r2 so
that's the functionality with order of M
really calls you can actually randomize
and add two polynomials it's interesting
to note that it's already this function
leader already gives a one sided to psi
protocol with passive security because
this randomized polynomial all already
contains the encoding of the
intersection so but with passive
security and yeah this protocol is
definitely information theoretic in F
willy hybrid model and the communication
complexity is like order of M field
elements even if you implement this F we
using that Whaley protocol from gene and
seventeen because that has a constant
communication or it and it's coming back
okay
okay so we are done with this opa
functionality so from Whaley we designed
this opa functionality with passive
security but what about active security
for active security we have to use
actively security box in place of
assembly securely but that's not enough
we have to ensure that receiver cannot
input a zero value to all the early
invocations because otherwise the
receiver can learn the polynomial of the
sender fully so we define a
functionality core Willy plus we do that
task for us and which requests only two
Oh Ellie calls and and then at the end
we need a consistency check and we are
working with the polynomials and
whenever working with polynomials that's
nice because you have the input and
output polynomials you pick a random
point and check the consistency of the
polynomial so that's a simple check we
do at the end of the protocol and so we
are done with actively secure OPA
protocol now from this I will show that
how we achieve the actively secure to
psi when both the party will get the
output so the idea is that Alice now
choose this random polynomial UA which
has some degree to him and some random
polynomial re and are a prime with the
with power degree M and they in Alice
and Bob invoke the if OPA functionality
where Alice input this UA and Ra and Bob
input is polynomial PV as a result the
Bob will get this is V which is PB into
RA plus u a this actually can be seen as
a secret sharing of this randomized to
polynomial PB into re where a sphere is
minus UA and B's share is SB so given
that like Bob will also do the same
thing yield to some UB and RB and sacred
share the is polynomial PA into RB so
once they're done with that Alice and
Bob will dynamize these things in a way
and add the
in such a way such that it will result
in this polynomial which is PA into some
random polynomial plus PB into some
random polynomial and this is this
already gives the intersection so and
then at the end they will run the
similar consistency check like
evaluating their input and output
polynomial in a random point and check
whether the relation holds now if you
see closely like this part of this
protocol don't leak any information
because this PB into RA is masked by a
random to M degree polynomial UA and
this PA into RB is a random to M degree
polynomial UV so the up to this point
this is totally secure but a malicious
adversary can try to Duran demise it in
many different ways but that leads to
the wrong polynomial because this EA and
UV are chosen totally in random and if
they say wrong polynomial then the check
will fail and then the both the party
can about so that's the whole protocol
and the communication complexity is
order of M field elements because this
opa can be implemented with order of M
fill elements and for D randomization
again you have to transfer of him field
elements and computational complexity is
dominated by order of in law game field
multiplication because of the to detect
the intersection you have to do the
multi point evaluation of this this
final polynomial and that requires this
first one will transform which requires
the same login filled multiplications so
we are done with this two psi and now
how we I will show I will give the
intuition that how we can get this multi
by D psi from this two psi kind of
directly so so we use the star topology
like from front paper by mu-2 and kermit
for 2017 so
here I take a toy example of three-party
a case where three parties a B and C
they have their polynomial P a P B and P
C now C will say compute the
intersection and then C you learn to two
party protocol FRA with a and B to learn
the intersection polynomial P a
intersection C and P B intersection C
now if you see like he defined this
intersection polynomial as PA
intersection C plus P B intersection C
and root of this polynomial already give
a intersection B intersection C okay so
we are done but unfortunately no because
here the central body can learn the
intermediate intersection so we can
learn intersection between a and C and
the intersection between B and C which
is not allowed in the ideal
functionality so we have to do something
about that so what we do is like we
allow a and B to run a set of phase
where they can talk to each other and
make some random mask like RA and RB
after they're done with that then C
start talking with a and B and run the
two party psi protocol and where a use
the random masquerade minus RB and be
used random mask minus RA minus RB so at
the end of the protocol DC will learn
this the same polynomial masked with
some value and from this instance you'll
learn some P B intersection C learnt
with the negative of that same
polynomial so now if we add both of them
you will get the same intersection
polynomial and thus can detect the
intersection but in this case C cannot
learn and this intermediate intersection
due to this random masking so yeah
that's a protocol and that can be
definitely extended to multi-party case
and for malicious security we have to
add a check similar check as the two
party psi protocol at the end of the
protocol so in terms of come
vacation for the setup phase so you can
a and B can actually exchange some PhD
seeds and then extend it to form this RA
and RB so it's like like in square
communication and then for this in
instances of 2 psi that is like in M
communication so the total communication
is like N squared plus n M into K and
computationally the central party have
to do in two psi instances so this is
dominated by n into M log in
multiplication so that's it does a
multi-party psi protocol for the full
protocol you can look into the paper
there are some many details so we are
done with the small T by D psi now I'll
give an intuition about how we can get
threshold multi by D psi from this multi
party psi protocol so let us consider a
two party one-sided PSI case the first
thing that would be a protocol so what
actually what's happening here so here
actually Bob learns this intersection
polynomial which is PA into r1 plus PB
into r2 and Bob evaluates this
intersection polynomial over its points
and get these outputs and whenever this
bi belongs to the intersection he will
get this white box which is zero output
and otherwise he will get some random
evaluation random points over the field
and from these zero outputs Bob can
detect the intersection so that's what's
happening in all the protocols now the
idea is to make it threshold use a
different encoding use the encoding says
that this PA prime of alpha evaluates to
1 instead of 0 when this alpha is in
from the set and similarly Bob can
encode his say it is V 2 PB prime such
that like when PB prime alpha is
evaluate to 1 if alpha belongs to this
SB so if you do that and we choose these
random polynomials not in a random way
but in a certain way such that this like
this r1 prime and r2 prime
of alpha gives a share of some LM robust
secret sharing scheme which like share
of the values of s1 and s2 where we want
to achieve this ill threshold so now if
we run the previous protocol like before
Bob will learn this polynomial which and
call that P intersection prime which is
P a prime into r1 prime plus PB prime
into R 2 prime and evolution of this
polynomial now give him something like
that where this for the B is for the BI
belongs to the intersection he will get
share of this s1 plus s2 because at
least PA Prime and P V prime evaluates
to 1 for this encoding
and this r1 prime alpha in R 2 prime
alpha gives in s1 plus s2 so he'll get
one share of s1 plus s2 and in the
similar way if we get like kind of ill
shares of s1 plus s2 from that ill sheis
he can really reconstruct this s1 plus
s2 and thus can detect the intersection
but there is a problem because now the
other evolution points are not random
because this r1 prime and r2 prime are
not random polynomial of degree m so
that might leak some information about
the other parties input so to resolve
that issue so one way to resolve that
issue is to use p intersection like
where you encode the polynomial like the
previous m PSI protocol and then use the
new encoding and define this p
intersection + p intersection prime as
the intersection polynomial so if you do
that then Bob will evaluate this
polynomial over his input so you'll get
something like that so first we get
these random points for the BI which
belongs to the intersection you will get
some 0 some random point 0 and so on and
from this thing he'll get something like
this where he gives the secret share of
s1 plus s2 whenever bi belongs to the
intersection
otherwise he will get something else we
don't care but now if you add those
things so this this gives like in the in
the position where bi actually belongs
to the intersection you will get the
share of s1 plus s2 and for the other
case the evolution points looks random
so we have to take care that in the
protocol we take care of the fact that
Bob ultimately will learn just this
polynomial not any like just not P
intersection or P intersection prime
separately so if so and then we are done
because from the here Bob can compute
this s 1 plus s 2 and then detect the
intersection and that's the and that can
be definitely extended to multi-party
case I just give an example for two
party case and it has a same
communication and computational
complexity as the multi party psi
protocol so with that I'm done so in
summary we give a very simple protocol
for actively secure two psi you know le
hybrid model we generalize it to from 2
psi to M psi this is the most efficient
I'm actively securing psi tilde and this
is also the first actively secure
threshold M psi protocol so in the paper
we also give a estimation of the
concrete performance we don't have an
implementation but we just estimate the
communication over rate of the paper and
so for the details you can look into
that paper actually surprisingly the
performance like at least communication
over rate of our to psi protocol is
comparable and in fact in some cases
it's better than the most efficient 2psi
actively secure to psi protocol and
future direction obviously you can use
the more optimization which is already
exist in the psi literature and then
implement this only PSI protocols to see
the actual concrete efficiency of these
protocols and one of the important thing
is that performance in offline and
online paradigm so all these things are
in early hybrid model so you can
- like in the offline phase you know you
can do all the Whaley's with random
input and then in the online phase you
can durán demise this oil is to get the
actual output and that actually
drastically improves the communication
overhead of the protocol and so that's
something to look into and then another
question is so we get a threshold psi
protocol with linear communication
complexity so we can look can we do
better so actually we have a protocol
with of threshold psi with sub linear
communication complexity and so maybe
I'll going to explain that in crypto
this year and so this is a print link
and thank you
Thank You satrajit for the talk and for
the expert handling of the glitch any
questions all right then let's thank all
the speakers in the session and thank
Lorenzo for expertly handling the glitch
[Applause]