thank you for the introduction so my
talk today will be about how to suppress
volume leakage in structure the
encryption using conventional
assumptions this is a joint work with
cynic Amara ok let's start with first
recording what structure the encryption
or AC for short so AC is a cryptographic
primitive that was introduced by chase
and camera in 2010 that allows the user
to encrypt the data structure in such a
way that it can privately create later
on and in particular there is a set of
algorithm that takes as input a security
parameter and the data structure and
output a key and an encrypted data
structure and the encrypted data
actually sent to the server and as query
time the user will run a token algorithm
that takes as input a key and the query
and we'll also put a token the token is
sent to the server and once the server
receives the token it will run a query
algorithm that takes as inputs the token
and encrypted data structure and outputs
an answer and the answer is sent to the
to the user okay so we call the
information that the server learns a set
up time the set up leakage and it may
include for example the size of the data
structure and we call the information
that the server learns at query time the
query leakage and it may include for
example the search pattern or the access
path and at very high level we say that
a SCE scheme is smq secure if for one it
doesn't reveal any information about the
data structure which beyond the set up
leakage and for - it doesn't reveal any
information about the data structure and
queries beyond the query leakage and for
more detailed security definition please
refer to to the secret and paper okay so
when designing or analyzing structure
the encryption schemes there are three
main dimensions that one should pay
attention to which are efficiency
security and expressiveness and in fact
structure the encryption has greatly
evolved during the last two decades and
there are a lot of works that have
investigated for example how to design
efficient scheme or how to design more
expressive schemes
or how to attack or design more secure
schemes however one aspect that was that
didn't receive a lot of attention or and
is poorly understood is leakage and
actually there are three main directions
that one can reason about leakage and
can help us to better understand it
which are crypt analysis measure and
separation I'm going to detail each of
these directions in the following slides
so so what do we mean by crypt analysis
in encrypted search so it means the
following so given a leakage profile we
want to design attacks that recover
either the queries or and the data under
some assumptions and the goal of crypt
analysis is that we want to empirically
learn the impact of a specific leakage
profile in the real world however the
main limitations of crypt analysis is
that the gap between the assumptions and
reality can get white okay so the second
direction is a measure and what do we
mean by this is that given a leakage
profile we want to somehow quantify for
example in bits the specific leakage
pattern and the goal here is that we
want to theoretically compare between
leakage patterns but the main
limitations of this approach is maybe
there is no meaning for a total order
and this is something that we are
currently working on and the third
dimension which is suppression which we
believe it's one of the most important
direction means the following
so given a leakage profile we want to
design a compiler or transform that will
suppress a specific leakage fashion and
the goal here is we want to design these
tools that will suppress various leakage
patterns however the main limitations of
this approach is that it will incur some
overhead okay and as the as this orc is
about ticket suppression i will recall
two main approaches that were introduced
by that we introduced last year as
crypto which are compilation and data
structure transformations so let's start
with compilation so computation is a
mechanism that takes a structure
encryption scheme as input with the
leakage profile
such that the query leakage is equal to
two passions person one and pattern two
and the computation will output a new
structure the encryption scheme with a
new leakage profile and a prime such
that the query leakage is equal only to
pattern one so that is we have
suppressed pattern 2
so the second approach is the data
structure transformation which works as
follows so given a data structure ok we
will apply our transform that will also
put a new data structure the star that
we will give as input to a structural
encryption scheme and itself it will
output an encrypted data structure and
the structure of the encryption scheme
here has a leakage profile and a-- but
the resulting scheme that does include
the transform inside will have leakage
profile lambda Prime's such that the
query leakage is only equal to person 1
so we have suppressed a person potential
so a valid question to ask is that are
there any other approaches actually to
suppress leakage and the answer is yes
there are and as I have just discussed
the kmo paper introduced two approaches
the blackbox compilation and data
structure transformation where the
deepest raster transformation actually
suppresses a leakage pattern against an
unbounded adversary so in this work we
will consider a new data structure
transformation that will suppress
leakage against a bounded adversary so
this this is actually important and one
of the major findings in our work stems
from the question of whether actually it
is possible to design structural
encryption scheme that actually do leak
something such that an unbounded
adversity can still learn the leakage
pattern but an abounded adversity cannot
and if we go back to our data structure
transformation slide this new transform
is very similar actually a chart so
there is a data structure there is a
transform that will output a data
structure that's given as input a
structure the encryption scheme which
itself outputs an encrypted data
structure but now the resulting
structure the encryption scheme does Li
Kui leak is sill composed of two
patterns pattern 1 and patterns star
where patterns are now in the eyes of a
bounded adversary is actually equivalent
to Nasik okay
and in the remaining parts of this talk
I will show how to leverage this new
capability to designs SCE schemes that
will hide the response length I will
detail what the response length means in
the next two slides that I'm the
dedication actually to some brief
background so let's start by a simple
yet from the model data structure recap
what we mean by a dictionary data
structure is a data structure that Maps
a label to a value here we map the
keyword to a file identifier and there
is a gate operation that's given a label
it will output the corresponding value a
Meucci map data structure is a data
structure that map's a label to a tuple
of values for example here we map a
keyword to a tuple of file identifiers
similarly there is a gate operation
that's given a label it will output the
corresponding tuple so the response
length pattern is known in searchable
symmetric encryption volume pattern and
it's very simple it's a pattern that
occurs at query time which is simply
equal to the length of the response or
the answer
so how the respondent is actually very
challenging especially if we want to
preserve efficiency and what I'm going
to do in this slide or the upcoming
slides is to show two ways to actually
hide the the volume pattern but as you
can see there will be very inefficient
so the first approach we call the knife
padding approach so we take a multi map
data structure and we will just pad it
add dummies to all tuples in such a way
that our respondents will have the same
the same all the tuples will have the
same length sorry and then we take this
transform data structure mm Prime and we
will feed it to a multi map encryption
scheme any standard multi map encryption
scheme that does actually leak the
response length and the query quality
here qAQ refers to the search pattern in
SS silat sociable symmetric encryption
literature so the resulting scheme SC e
prime is a multi map encryption scheme
that actually hides the response and is
actually easy to verify this so in terms
of asan projects the cool complexity of
such a approach is not it's not that
good the query complexity is actually
linear in the maximum response laugh
and the storage complexity actually is
terrible it's actually linear in the
number of labels I'm the maximum
response length but the good thing about
this approach is that it's non
interactive and as I'm going to detail
the second approach which is actually
interactive this is actually a plus so
the second approach that we call through
a free dictionary approach we will start
again with a multi map data structure
and we will transform it to a dictionary
and then we take this dictionary
structure and we will add dummies to it
and the number of them is that we will
add to this dictionary data structure is
equal to the maximum response length
minus one and then we will feed this
dictionary data structure to a
dictionary encryption scheme that has
the property of being leakage free and
we can instantiate such such primitive
using oblivious Ram in such a way that
the resulting structure the encryption
scheme will hide the response length as
long as whenever we fetch a tuple we fit
along with it a number of dummies in
such a way that the total number of
values with which is equal to the
maximum response length so in terms of
asymptotic this naive approach is also
actually it's worse in terms of query
complexity compared to the naive padding
but it has great storage complexity but
it's also interactive which can be bad
for some scenarios ok
so a right question to ask is can we
actually achieve the best of both worlds
and the answer to this question is
easiest and in the remaining parts of
this talk I will detail the pseudo
random transform or PRT for source which
is a data structure transformation that
has better query complexity and storage
complexity when compared to the knife
padding approach but it has the
disadvantage of being lossy I won't have
time to talk about vlh which is the
structure the encryption that's Dutch
builds on top of of PRT that hides the
response times but it's actually
straight forward from the PRG
given the slide that I have presented on
the data structure transformation I will
detail though the the density sub graph
transform or DSC for source which is a
data structure transformation that
actually it's non lossy that has better
actually storage overhead but it has
quite
worse query complexity compared to the
to the PRT I won't have time
unfortunately to talk about AVL H which
is the structural encryption that we
build on top of the of the of DSC and
also I won't have time to talk about how
to make village and a village dynamic
but please refer to our paper to learn
more about these three parts that I'm
not covering okay so let's start with
PRT so please don't pay attention to the
formalism for now as I'm going to
describe this transform through the
following illustration so we have two
parameters lambda and mu where lambda is
the minimum response length and nu is
the output size of a PRF so we take our
mu Qi map and the PRC will output a new
multi map data structure such that the
new response length is equal to lambda
to which we add a PRF evaluation on the
keyword concatenated to the old response
length and given this sum we will make
the decision whether to pad or truncate
a specific tube so let's get an example
so for keyword 1 W 1 the response length
is equal to tree ID 1 ID 3 ID 4 okay so
we will evaluate the PRF on keyword 1
concatenate it to tree which is here for
example is equal to 0 it's just for a
second of an example and we take this 0
and we add it to 1 where 1 here is the
the value that we we we set for lambda
and the result is 1 so we compare 1 to 3
which is the old response length and we
see that it's smaller and actually we
have to truncate the tuple with with two
values so and this is why we have
removed two values from in the new
medium for keyword two however so we
will apply we do the same we apply the
PRF the result now is 2 we added 2 1 is
3 and we know that tree is actually
larger than 1 so we have two paths
so we pad we add dummies and for qhv we
do the same and we in PR T we also have
this ranking function which is basically
ranking the file identifier within a
tuple and the purpose of this of this
ranking function is that it will allow
us to lose only the less significant
file identifiers and we will preserve
the most significant which is
important from a practical point of view
so well commissioned to ask us about the
number of truncation and was about
storage overhead and for this analysis
we had to assume a special type of Milky
maps that we call Z distributed Milky
maps that I'm going to detail now so
what do we mean by this so as if
distributed Mickey map has a response
lands that are as if distributed where
the ARF
response land is equal to to this
formula it's not important to parse it
actually the illustration gives you an
idea about how the response lands are
distributed so the choice of zips
distribution was not arbitrary actually
that it is very common to finds if
distributed data sets in in practice and
actually we have run a neuron just to
check the response land distribution a
neuron is a data set composite of half a
million roughly emails and as you can
see the the graph here the response
length distribution is a power law or as
if distribution with some distribution
sorry with some parameter okay so this
slide basically summarized our main
finding it's not I don't want you to be
distracted with the details but the main
takeaway from this slide is we were able
to show that the storage overhead of PRT
is actually alpha times the storage
overhead of the naive approach where
alpha is strictly smaller than one and
you can think of alpha as the storage
with a reduction multiplicative factor
with respect to truncations we were able
to show that truncations are actually
sub linear in the number of labels equal
to this this this formula here I just
want to note that this analysis is not
tied specifically to use if it can be we
can do the same analysis for power law
distribution and most probably we will
have the same results but just to give
you an idea so as you can see that we
have some strong occasions avoid
question to ask how can we get rid of
this truncation is it possible to have a
data structure transformation that does
not actually incur truncations and this
is what we are going to cover with the
DSC or density sub graph transform so
the name will make sense
I promise at the end of this talk so so
we take a museum up data structure
we view the museum up inside as a
bipartite graph where the top vertices
are are the key words in the multi map
or the labels in the Meucci maps and the
bottom vertices are actually bins we
have here for the sake of example four
bins we do all actually instance eh also
as states data structure think of it as
a dictionary data structure that we will
keep at the client side and you will see
how how to transform work works so we
take our first keyword and we will
randomly pick three bins uniformly at
random and so why three three is the
maximum response length and actually
something that I forgot to mention is
that through this bipartite graph what
we are trying to do is want to simulate
an aldose around emeritus rainy graph so
and once we select these bins we take
our file identifies in the tuple and we
will just insert them in the bins that
we have selected each in every single
bin and in the state what we do is that
we will map the keyword
choose all file identifiers sorry bin
zayed bin identifiers that we have
selected end up in the previous step we
do the same for keyword two so here the
difference is the key words to has only
a response length equal to one but still
we will have a number of edges equal to
three because as I have said we want to
have a random air those Iranian graph so
but we will just put a single file I
don't if are in one of the of the 3
selected bins we will also update the
state similarly where we are so we where
we map the keyword to the bin
identifiers we do the same for the for
the third keyword and we will just
finish by padding all the bins to have
the same load so something that we that
you you may have already noticed is the
size of this state actually is terrible
is actually linear is actually equal to
the knife padding approach so how can we
remove this this downside or this
restriction so we use the following
trick at very high level we replace the
random generation of edges by a
pseudo-random generation where we take
our so how does it work we we first
sample a random value and
we have a PRF and that will that we will
evaluate on this random value
concatenated two counters one counter
one two three and three here is the the
response length and they will the PRF
will output something and that something
is actually the bin identifier and as
you can notice here we have a collision
so what we should do is that so what we
should do is we will have we will repeat
this process until no collision will be
found so here we we didn't have a
collision and then we will just insert
the the file identifiers in the in the
bins now in the state instead of storing
and mapping between the keyword and all
of the bin identifiers we just store the
keyword that map's to the random value
that we have used for the edge
generation and we do the same for for
keyword two we will put the ID and we
will update State similarly for keyword
3 and so on and so forth we will pad and
then now you can notice that the size of
the state is way better
it's just linear in the number of
keywords instead of being actually
linear in or equal to the size of the of
the naive padding approach great so what
is the output of this da DSC is that we
will output three things a key and the
state that we will keep on the client
side and the dictionary basically data
structure that will map the bin
identifier to its content and when we
want to perform a get the client will
follow on a key word w1 the the the
client will first retrieve the
corresponding randomness from the state
and then generate prick recompute the
the bit identifies by evaluating the PRF
three times and then it will just fetch
from the dictionary to corresponding bin
contents and will find the result okay
so one natural question is how about the
load of the bin this is like the most
important question that we need to
asking for this transform to understand
how how it does in terms of of storage
so we were able to show that the load of
the bin is equal to some 2d to this
formula but the takeaway here is that we
were able to show with high probability
that the transforming team
has a Big O of n which n is the number
of pairs which is actually the same size
of the the Mickey map that we have given
us input so there it is as some sort as
some practically no additional overhead
the size of the states as I have
mentioned is linear in the linear in the
number of labels which is actually
dominated by the number of pairs which
is great all right so when we were
working on this we have noticed
something which is very nice actually we
can actually further reduce the storage
overhead if we leverage some
computational assumption and what we
leverage here is an assumption called
planted dance sub graph which is an
assumption that has been already used in
public key to design public key
cryptography by Appelbaum Baraka and
anderson and also into studying the
computational complexity of financial
products by aurora at all and at a very
high level the assumption is as follows
so you have on one hand a random
erdos-renyi graph on the other hand you
have a random Erdos ringing graph into
which we plant a dense sub graph and an
adversary and bound adversity cannot
distinguish between the two so we
leverage this assumption in this work
which is quite nice because it's an
another application in cryptography so
how does it work
and as I have said maybe I forgot to say
this but this this storage gain will
only work for a specific type of Meucci
maps that does some detail in here so
the Moochie map i have changed a little
bit so this will work if we have some
labels or some tuples that they have
some non-empty intersection and here you
can notice that keyword 1 and Q 3 they
have a non-empty intersection where ID 2
ID 4 appear actually appear in both and
this is what we call a concentrated
multi map and this is what we have said
so how the DSC works now so we will have
our our our bipartite graph or the top
vertices our keyword and the and the
bottom vertices are actually bins so
what we start with we will first put the
concentrated part in the into the bins
and then so we do it reverse actually
you can think of it as we are doing
actually rivers and we just we then
generate the edges that will map the
keywords W 1 and W 3 to actually to this
concentrated
part and then we will continue by
generating as I have explained it before
for the DSC the the other edges say for
keyword 2 and here the idea is that we
as you can notice we are we have added
only the concentrated part only once out
of time only once and this is basically
the results we are reducing the load of
the pins as this is a contrived example
but as you can see the bins now only
contain all of the bins only contain one
value while in the previous example they
do contain two and this is basically
just a concise example to show that we
are we are getting something and
actually we can show asymptotically that
the load of the bin is actually reduced
by this concentrated part that we have
identified and it's better than the
previous load of the bin all right
so to conclude what are the takeaways so
I want to first start with something
that I want to emphasize so volume
pattern is an important pattern that has
been recently leveraged to perform some
attacks by calories at all and by grabs
at all true attack structured encryption
or and because it is just based on the
volume so this is an important work that
shows how to design structured
encryption schemes that they are not
prone to these attacks and as I as you
can see you know hopefully this talk
have shown that it's not actually
trivial to to to to suppress the volume
passion we have seen the trivial
approaches they are terrible in terms of
efficiency and I want also to stress
that this line of work
hiding the volume or hiding other
pattern is a very important research
direction in structural encryption and
encrypted search in general so we have
started this in 2018 by the because
suppression work and this work is
actually another step into this
direction hopefully you didn't fall
asleep and you remember that we have
seen the PRC and the DSC transform
something that I want also to to to
emphasize here is that if we go back a
little bit and if you think about
suppressing the volume pattern
intuitively you you might think that
hiding volume information theoretically
is not possible without padding but we
goes around this using computational
assumptions which is kind of the first
work that actually do this for any
pattern and for volume in power in
particular and hopefully this line
work will help us actually to suppress
other passions in structural encryption
and encrypted search in general another
point that we introduced in this work is
that there is this new trade of between
correctness and security and I will I
will finish by mentioning that this line
of work will actually help us to thwart
mini if not all actually existing
attacks that we know of in the
literature ikkc GPR and so on and so
forth thank you so we we don't have time
for questions let's take the question of
Lai