hello everyone my name is Ethan song
today I'm honored to introduce our
recent work choristers instructors and
the cryptography is called his random
tips course always professor we pocoyo
randomness is crucial for cryptography
based on several previous results
without randomness several basic tasks
are impossible to realize for example
the knowledge encryption and so on so in
this work we would like to get a better
understanding on the extent to which
randomness is necessary to be more clear
we consider the following question
suppose that a party uses correlated
tapes in multiple executions of a
cryptographic algorithm can the security
still be preserved this question can be
motivated by for example a defective
random number generator which outputs
correlated tapes under multiple
occasions so we will non line of
research of reset for security where a
party uses the same random tape across
multiple executions can be seen as a
special case of our general problem for
example reset both your knowledge reset
the security mutation and so on in this
work we need to initiate a systematic
study of the above question as an
example let us first have a close look
at correlated tapes to knowledge we
model correlations among the random
tapes by considering anniversary which
may have limited control over the random
tapes of the analyst party to be more
clear a malicious very fair is allowed
to specify T tampering functions a 1 to
a T then the random number generator in
the first execution is replaced by a 1
and in the second execution by 2 and so
on
after that a string exodus sampled a
uniformly this axe can be seen as the
original random random tape which is
unknown to either the prover or the
verifier in the first execution the
prover uses a 1 X as this random tape
and a 2 ax in the second execution and
so on the prover is stateless well the
very very state flow across all
executions we point out that using a 1 X
280 X is a very natural way to model
Tico his strings one can see that if the
very fair truth is altering functions to
be the identity function then this
becomes reset does your knowledge
however correlated tapes your knowledge
is impossible to realize even if T is 1
and a 1 actually is guaranteed to have
enough me entropy this is based on the
work of toadies and his closers
therefore we consider to use a small
random seed in the shared random stream
model which is a weaker model than the
Sierras model in our work we further
show that if the timing functions can
depend on the seriouser as a seed so it
is still impossible therefore we require
that the terminal functions should be
independent of the seed other notions
like correlatives multi-party
computation as are correlated tape
multiple accommodation curried tapes
secure encryption can be defined in an
analogous way the central object in our
work is a new notion of randomness
detractors which we call : source
instructors very informally a seeded
correlative random choristers destructor
an input a seed s
and a source X produces a uniform output
which is independent of the temporal
results generated by the same seed s but
the temperature source is ax we require
that for every tempering function a I
should not alter the same string as his
input when we think that it is the to
notion of nom instructors as phenomena
instructors there is only one source but
multiple tamper disease nominal
structures were introduced in 2009 by
the design which they have played an
important role in cryptography and the
complexity for example in prep the
amplification designing mm structures
and designing nominal codes in our work
we define the corythosaurus attractors
and another notion we call his those
instructors the me entropy requirements
of both notions is the point Nami ok
which takes the number of the executions
T the length of the output M and the
seedlings D as input the error rates is
the malarial function of the security
parameter Kappa the difference between
these two notions is the requirements of
the sibilants Icefall choristers
instructors the students only depends on
the security parameter which means the
number of ask executions is independent
of the seedlings for Vic course
instructors the seedlings can't growth
control with the number of the
executions so we would like to point out
the connection between Whitaker is
correlated source attractors and 2001
structures where the latter notion was
introduced in 2014 by Kiev tree and the
cross for me and
most constructive was first constructed
in 2016 by telepathy I go Yan Li so it
is actually a stronger notion because
the better the rosary is allowed to
temper posters is separately 2000
illegal structures implies the existence
of weak choristers instructors by
considering the second source why has
the seed and there's no term rings on
the second source however the second is
the length of the second source grows
with the number of the executions which
means little note implies the existence
of corythosaurus instructors our result
gives an explicit construction of a
chorus of instructor with the volume
parameter so we simply set the secure
perimeter sorry we simply set the
seedlings as the security parameter
recall that K is the entropy requirement
epsilon is the error rate T is the
number of executions and M is the length
of the output we also give existential
results of corridors instructors we note
that the me entropy requirement is
almost a necessary condition
imagine that all tamron functions are
chosen as different permutations so in
this case I Riyadh put should be uniform
and independent with others so it
requires that the original source to
have at least three times M me entropy
now let us first see how this new notion
could help us construct kora T tapes
your knowledge we first require that for
every temple function AI
area I should have enough me entropy now
under the constraint set for every two
tampering funk
AI and AJ civil not all to the same
string and Irene puts in the prover can
simply apply a coroner's instructor on
the random tape and the seed then use
the result as a new random tape in this
execution the property of course
instructors guarantee stats the prover
will use independent and run independent
random tapes in different executions and
therefore the security is preserved to
relax the second constraint will rely on
the technique from reset was your
knowledge in general reset with your
knowledge allows us to handle the case
where the prover uses the same random
tape across multiple executions
correlated source instructors allow us
to handle the case where each random
tape differs from every other one
therefore we can combine these two
notions to handle all possible tampering
functions however there's the subtle
leakage issue with this approach imagine
that some tampering function AI just
outputs the same as a 1 with probability
1/2 then learning whether these two
executions use the same random tape
leaked further information about X to
the adversary
fortunately this amount of leakage can
be upper bounded to show security
we simply leak this information about
which to thermal functions will be off
of the same string to the other was Ray
we differ a pattern of X to be a vector
as 1/2 as T where each element is an
integer between 1 to T so it satisfies
that if as I equals 2 as J then it means
that the random tape in the X execution
is the same as that in the JZ iteration
you
in the yeah now the number of patterns
is bounded by T 30 which means leaking
the patterning information only leaks T
log T which is bounded by T times T
piece of X given the pattern I read two
terminal functions sorry I read to
tempura tempura random tips are either
always the same which can be handled by
the result both your knowledge are
always different which can be handled by
choristers instructors therefore our
panel construction of courage' tips your
knowledge is the following
he actually each execution the prover
first applies a curry sauce instructor
on its random tape and the seed to use
the result as a new random tape in this
execution and invoke a reset both the
knowledge protocol with the verifier now
we give an overview of our construction
there are three steps so first we
generate an otherwise verges otherwise
we'll get the extraction process later
then we prick the original source acts
into to our limited color hit parts the
resulting sauces are paired up and our
extraction process starts from the first
pair X 1 X 2 to the last pair X 2 L
minus 1 and X 2 L in the first step till
the wise is generated by using the
source and a fresh piece from the seed
it satisfies that with high probability
this otherwise is different from arid
tempered 1 so this idea is not new and
has been widely used in the construction
of normal voice tractors soon to break
the sauce into several limited career
parts we use the strong city destructor
with fresh seeds each time and here is
the case for tempura sauce now we have
to our times t plus 1000 in total they
are paired up in the following manner
each column of sauces are denoted by a
set Chi we not set the sources in
different sets are generated by using
different and independent seeds
therefore for our J XJ is a uniform even
given all the sauces except those in the
same set as XJ now our instructions
precise start from the first pair to the
last pair in the GC the region X 2j
minus 1 and X 2 G will be used depending
on the J speeds of the otherwise one of
the source is chosen then we apply
instructor on the children source and
afresh as our end result in the last
division to get W J finally we apply
another extractor on w g and a fresh
piece from the seed GG will be the final
result in this iteration a general
picture of our extraction process is the
following so the first seed c0 comes
from the seed because there is no inter
vision 0 and the final result CL will be
the output of the instructor
now to show that our construction is
indeed a carissa tractor it is
sufficient to show the following two
properties first if the J's bits of the
otherwise is different from that of a
temper one then we should be able to
break the correlations between them in
the jzt region once we break the
correlations we should be able to make
sure this independence remain till the
end of the extraction process so we
first point out two important effects of
extractors for two stars is X and X
prime if given X from X Q has enough me
entropy then the result of extracting X
using the seed of Y is independent of
the results of extracting explain using
the same seed Y to see this when we
first fix the second source X front and
in this case X still has enough me
entropy then the result of extracting X
using the city of Y is independent of
the seed Y and also the second source X
from and therefore the second result now
for mm X and X from if X itself has
enough me entropy then the result of
extracting X using the seed Y one is
independent of death of extracting X
from using another state Y 2 this is
because when we first fix the second
results and in this case X still has
enough the entropy to use the instructor
with a uniform seed
now for the first property we compare
the extraction processes in the JC
duration we note sets in the second
level of abstraction to use the same
random seed white g2
therefore if we can show that given wji
WJ still has enough me entropy then we
are done w3 is determined by two parts a
temporal source and the J minus 1 I so
we set the length of C to be much
shorter than the length of W that means
fixing C only fixes a small amounts of W
therefore it is okay to fix the Jamis
one I as for the temperature source
note that the J's piece of the other
wises are different which means these
two sources come from different sets so
when we first fix the tempura sources in
the beginning and if you will not
influence the extraction process of the
original one
now for the second property by induction
we have C G prime minus 1 and the 3
premise 1 I are independent therefore by
the second effect about instructor the
result WJ Prem is independent of W 3
prime i and also we have g g prime x r
ett frame is in lebanon of DT prime i
finally we would like to point out to
future directions so one direction is to
discover more applications of corridors
instructors we believe curry sauce
instructor is a very natural notion and
we will have many other applications and
the other direction is to construct a
curry sauce instructor to match our
existence is the essential results
that's all thank you
[Applause]
yeah so well of our goal is to construct
a choristers instructor starts that the
seedlings does not grow with the number
of the executions but for to 2011
structures both sources grow with the
number of the executions so like in our
application we only need a very short
seat which is independent of the
executions but if we use 2002
instructors soon we need to first know
the number of executions in the
beginning to generate the seep yeah have
you tried to use like college to
extractors to construct to source
extractor the other direction no we
didn't consider this case because so for
carita stores instructor a big advantage
in designing is that we can break the
seeds into several parts and each part
is still uniform but for 2011 structures
that is not the case
yeah ok thank you so let's thank the
speaker again and
[Applause]