yeah thank you for the introduction so
this is joint work with Benny Applebaum
it's Rika Bukowski and I will talk about
the creature is complete for the wrong
complexity of malicious NPC so in
multi-party computation we have multiple
parties and they have private
communication channels between them and
each of them has some private input and
their goal is to mutually conclude some
functionality F over all the inputs in
such a way that each of them only learns
an output without learning everything
else anything else about the inputs now
there are many different security
notions that were defined for NPC so for
example there is the semi honest setting
where the parties must follow the
protocol and all they can do is just
observe all of the information that they
get and try to learn something out of it
and there is the malicious setting where
they can actively are differently than
what they supposed to do and send
arbitrary messages and you can consider
perfect security versus computational
security and there are other notions
such as the threshold and whether we
allow abort or not and there are also
many different sorry many different
combinations of those settings now you
can also measure protocols according to
their efficiency so you can consider the
computational complexity and the
communication complexity of protocols
and you can also consider the number of
France and in many classic results that
the number of rounds is correlated with
the degree of the function to be
computed so our goal in this work is to
reduce the number of rounds in a generic
way that is independent of the security
notion so the high-level idea is to show
a non-interactive reduction from any
function to function of degree two so in
in that way once you have a protocol
that computes this degree to function we
have a protocol that computes any factor
okay so what is a non-interactive
reduction so let's say we have this
function that the parties want to
compute but now we say that instead of
communicating with each other there is
some Oracle that computes a
functionality age and the only thing
that the parties can do is query wants
this Oracle so now the reduction has a
very specific structure so in the first
step each party can do can do some local
pre-processing over its input and then
they all perform an Oracle query sending
sending their processed inputs they all
get a response and eventually each of
them can do false processing and derive
the final output now notice when we
consider the militia setting then the
only chance of the parties to deviate
from the protocol is in the
pre-processing phase so that fact will
be important for us later and why this
primitive is so strong because if we
have a non-interactive
reduction to a function H then given any
weight to compute this functionality H
we don't get a way to compute F in the
same number of France so it can be
either a protocol that computes age or
thrusted party or even some physical
device okay so let's go over some
previous results so many classic
protocols are actually implicitly
non-interactive reductions so for
example Yuans protocol is a
non-interactive reduction in the two
parties and myoma setting and in the
multi party setting we have reductions
to degree three functions and usually
the they use something that is called
randomized encoding and then a natural
question is whether there is a reduction
to the degree two in the multi-party
setting so there were a few breakthrough
results in the last year that
the protocols that have only two rounds
in the multi party setting but they
don't show a general reduction so they
face each security option
separately and try to solve the problem
in in the independent steps and recently
in TCC there were two words that showed
an underactive reduction but only in the
semi honest setting so the natural
follow-up question is whether there is a
such reduction in the multi-party
setting for a degree 2 but with
malicious security and this is a the the
question that we solve and our answer is
yes ok so we do so by proving main
theorem that we see as our main result
so we call this the master theorem and
it says the following so if we have a
protocol that computes F we can use it
in order to define a non-interactive
reduction from F to a function of degree
2 so what is nice about this master is
it's not sensitive to the to the
security setting so it preserves the
security guarantee that will help from
the protocol that we started from and
the the price that you have to pay for
that is that the the complexity grows
exponentially with the depth of the
protocol that we started from now you
can plug in many protocols and try the
master theorem on them and then as a
corollary you get reductions so we get
completeness theorem that says that
every function is maliciously reducible
to a degree two function and we can get
it either in the information theoretic
setting or in the computational setting
and if we do so in their constitutional
setting then we can save the the
exponential growth okay so now
finally after having this reduction we
can use various protocol to implement
the degree to function and then we end
up with explicit protocols and some of
them improve known results so in the
last slide I will give concrete examples
okay so now I'm gonna give the truth
layout of the master theorem which is
the main technical part so as I said
most words that show a reduction to
degree 3 is something that is called
randomized encoding so they showed that
if you have a function f you can compute
an encoding of it and the encoding will
be of degree 3 and our idea is instead
of computing and coding on a function
then we first look at a protocol that
computes this function and then we
compute something that is not exactly
randomized encoding but it's inspired by
it but because we know that now our
input is not an arbitrary function but
description of a protocol that we can
exploit it or benefit and and and define
the encoding in such a way that now it
is of degree 2 instead of degree 3 and
also that the reduction has they're
exactly the same security guarantees of
the protocol that we started from and I
want to mention that the idea to start
with the protocol and reduce its number
of rounds is inspired by the works from
last year approved by a band for
modeling and they go against Universal
ok so now the question is how how will
we define this encoding in such a way
that we can get degree 2 instead of
degree 3 so the first step would be to
take the protocol that we start and
describe it is one large circuit so
every local computation that each of the
parties do can can be described by some
secrets and then we glue them together
and I will in a minute show how and we
get one large circuits to describe the
entire computation that should be done
by all parties in the protocol so we do
so by defining two types of gates or
local gates
correspond to local computations and
then there are transmission gates that
correspond to communication between the
parties so by defining this structure we
can then associate everyone with one of
the parties so for local computation
gates we associate off the wires with
the party that should perform this
computation and winter swishing gates
the input wire is belongs to the party
the sends the message and the output
wires belongs to the receivers of the
message and now the idea that we had the
the work that showed security and the
semi on the setting was that because now
every gate has the property that all of
its input wires are always associated
with a single party then we can let that
specific party perform some local tree
processing and in that way we save one
degree so then we and we ended up with
degree two instead of degree one and now
the problem that we had to face in this
work in order to generalize it to the
malicious security is how to handle at
parties that hit in the in the
pre-processing so a priori it's not even
clear that when they don't do the
pre-processing honestly they even end up
with something that looks like some sort
of randomized encoding but what we deal
in this works to slightly changed the
way the encoding is defined in such a
way that no matter which malicious
strategy they choose for the
pre-processing it ends up looking like
changing the local computation that was
supposed to be done in that specific
gate so in that way even if a party
sends any arbitrary value instead of
performing the pre-processing we can
translate it to a malicious strategy in
the protocol that we started from
so we preserve the security guarantee
of the of the protocol that we started
from okay
so to summarize the results we have the
completeness theorem which we derive by
plugging in protocols so first of all we
get perfect security for threshold and
over three four functions in NC one and
we can get a sophistical security if we
want security in there honest majority
setting and if we want to support any
function in P then we have a
computational solution assuming blackbox
one-way function for any honest majority
and now we can use many different
protocols to implement the degree to
function but we give her we given the in
the paper a few examples and we derive
the following results so as I said in
the work from TCC we have a semi honest
protocol from any honest majority in two
rounds and now in this work we have a
protocol with malicious security with
selective awards and the improvement
here is now this is for any honest
majority and there is a similar result
in the work by unanswered all that you
will hear about in the next talk and our
next new contribution is the is in the
guaranteed output delivery model so that
we also improved the threshold to n over
4 and we get the number of rounds to be
3 which is optimal so for NC 1 we have
perfect security and if we want
polynomial functions we can do so
assuming one with factions so yeah
that's it
[Applause]