came in good morning everyone I'm
Karthik naka and today I will be talking
about a book on locality preserving
abuse now we're joined to work with
Gillard Gilbert truffling and Elaine
so let me start off by quickly defining
an oblivious Ram so in general in a
computation you have a request sequence
I and the request sequence will claim
the following I want to read memory
location a 1 followed by write something
to memory location a 2 and so on and so
forth and the CPU actually executes this
access pattern and sends a response back
the problem we are trying to solve with
an omnibus Ram is to hide which
addresses are accessed in this request
sequence so we assume that you have an
adversary which is snooping on your
address bus but it cannot look into the
contents of the CPU for example or the
actual contents of the data in the
memory for instance you can think of
your data is being encrypted so what you
want is to convert this logical access
sequence into a sequence let's call it
or MFI in such a way that the adversary
does not learn what is so for security
you want for any to access patterns ini
prime of the same length that or ramify
is indistinguishable from or Amma Phi
prime so typically when you are trying
to office gate these accesses you will
end up accessing more memory locations
than you would do in a logical sequence
and that is why one important metric
that you're trying to reduce is
bandwidth or the number of memory
locations you access for every logical
access so separately in systems another
notion that is very important is the
notion of data locality so what is data
locality if a memory location is
accessed a nearby memory location will
be accessed soon enough for instance if
you are if you have a file server in
such a way that let's say a file spans
five blocks then if you're accessing the
entire file after accessing the first
block you will end up accessing the next
five block the next four blocks as well
and you will have a similar observation
if for example if you have range queries
and this notion of locality has
motivated the design of hard disks and
SSDs that we have today in
that when you're accessing the first
block that is expensive and accessing
the subsequent nearby blocks are cheaper
so at this point I would like to
distinguish between this notion of
locality which is spatial locality and
temporal locality so temporal locality
says if I access a memory location soon
enough
I will access the same memory location
again and that has motivated design of
memory hierarchy and caches and so on
and so forth but over here we are only
concerned with spatial locality so the
problem is that with an oblivious
serum.this this office feature of
accesses inherently break locality so in
an overtime scheme let's say if I'm
accessing memory location five I end up
accessing five and some more spurious
memory accesses but more importantly
after performing this axis I end up
shuffling my data around and this such
shuffling inherently break in early
breaks data locality so the question we
ask in this work is the following can we
construct a bandwidth efficient a ramp
that preserves data locality so this
notion of bandwidth efficient is
important over here but before we
understand this question let us first
define what I mean by locality so at a
very high level locality is just the
number of head seeks or the head jumps
or the number of discontinuous regions
that I'm going to access so if I'm
making 100 maxes and let's say your head
moves in the following fashion where I
have accessed three blocks this
contributes three to bandwidth and one
to locality and let's say then the head
performs a jump and what makes another
set of accesses then correspondingly my
locality and my bandwidth would increase
so at a high level I'm just trying to
reduce the number of head seeks or head
jumps so if reducing locality was my
only goal then the following simple
solution would just work I'll just scan
the entire memory and then I'll get a
locality of one which is great but the
problem is that your bandwidth is going
to be very high so in that sense I'm
trying to reduce both locality and
bandwidth together and intuitively I am
trying to get both of them to be pollen
McKinnon so the first question is can I
actually get this turns out we show a
lower bond that you cannot have
something like this and in general we
show that we show a lower bond which
says if you want sub-linear locality
then that implies linear band well this
is not great but the on the flip side we
show that if you have some leakage
perhaps something is possible so the
next question we ask us whether we can
construct a bandwidth efficient over AM
scheme that preserves data locality
while only leaking the lengths of the
contiguous regions that are accessed and
under such a leakage we show the first
Aram scheme with data locality so
specifically if your access sequence is
making T requests in such a way that it
spans K discontinuous regions then we
show an over AM scheme which has a
bandwidth which is T times poly
logarithmic in n so if you know the
overrun literature this is something
similar to what all Aram schemes do but
the main part of the result is that we
have locality that only depends on the
number of discontinuous regions and the
blow up is a factor of Paulino gardna
Canyon specifically it does not depend
on the number of memory locations T that
is accessed
we achieve this while using a client
storage by using a constant plant
storage and interestingly for some part
of a computation we end up using two
disks instead of one and that is
essential to in a scheme to achieve
locality so and as I mentioned earlier
we end up leaking the lengths of the K
regions that we are accessing so in a
nutshell we have this upper bound and
lower bound and for the rest of this
talk I'm going to focus on the upper
bound result so before I explain how to
achieve this for a standard orem let me
simplify the problem and show it show
how it works for a simplified scheme or
a simplified input pardon me
so in general my request pattern can
look like the following I want to read
memory locations 2 3 4
and then write to memory location seven
and eight so T equals 5 and K equals 2
over here
so the first simplification I'm going to
make is that instead of these requests
coming one by one I know my ranges of
life so I'm going to read know ahead of
time that and the accesses is going to
be four ranges to come before and seven
to eight and a second simplification I'm
going to make as that I will only allow
reads for now so let us see how we can
achieve this for the simple scenario and
the high-level idea is to use what we
call read only range of ROM and the idea
is very simple instead of storing data
in 1 over m I'm going to store data in
log and different neurons or am 0 to a
ROM login or log and +1 different terms
so over m 0 stores my primitive data
blocks the way you would think of
storing data in Y over on or a month
stores n over two blocks but each block
is now a super block which is a
concatenation of two block to primitive
blocks so block one is block 1 comma 2
the second block is 3 comma 4 and and so
on and so forth so you have n over two
super blocks of size two and in general
over m is has n over 2 to the I super
blocks each of size two design so the
important invariant that we have over
here is that all our arms should store
identical information so if I'm
accessing some block I in orem 0 should
be the same as the the primitive block I
in any of the log inner arms or log and
plus 1 or ops so let's say now I want to
access a range of size 2 to the J if
it's something smaller than 2 to the J I
can pad it to the nearest power of 2
the observation is very simple a range
of size to the J is covered by two super
blocks of size 2 the 2 to the chain and
if you think about this for 10 seconds
you'll realize that the system and which
to superblocks
I can evaluate this by some simple math
so now if I want to access a block of
size tilde J I'll just go to o Ramji and
perform my axis
so that will have a bandwidth of two to
the J Pauline Logan the Orem has a
blow-up of Polly Logan and each block
has size two to the J in terms of
locality observe that this is
independent of two to the J because
whenever I'm accessing these chunks they
are of size to the J together so the
reason why this is a read-only Aram is
because we want this invariant which
says all over amps should store
identical information and if I were to
update this array engine or MJ I need to
do it in all of the other over amps and
that breaks either bandwidth or locality
so in order to support writes we use a
size slightly generalized data structure
which we call a range tree and a range
tree is the following tree where again
leaves are the primitive blocks and they
are sorted by addresses the distinction
from what we were doing in the last
slide is that over here these leaves
could contain discontinuous blocks for
example over here it's 1 2 5 & 6 blocks
3 & 4 are not there and every internal
node has super blocks which are a
concatenation of its children and they
are again replicated and so on and so
forth and and looking ahead each of
these levels will be stored in different
Durham's and in order to support so if
you think about what we did for
read-only in your arms it is this full
range tree consisting of all n elements
so if you were to support writes I'm
going to use a hierarchy of range trees
so we're the largest tree contains all
of my data and then I'm going to have
many smaller range trees and I'm going
to maintain these two invariants the
first invariant us the range tree
invariant which says within a tree
blocks are consistent that is if I'm
looking for a primitive block it will be
stored at all of these different heights
and each of them will have the same
information information and the second
invariant that we maintain is that
smaller trees of fresher that is across
these ranges blocks may not be
consistent but
whenever I have two blocks across trees
the smaller one will be the fresher one
or smaller trees act as a cache or a
stash for a larger tree so let us see
with this data structure how we can
perform an axis at a high level B then
Aram each axis consists of two parts
first I fed some data and store it on
some contagious locations on the server
and then I engage in a maintain or a
rebuild process where I'm going to write
this data back into the Orang data
structure so let us see how to do each
of these in power let's say I have a
request which says read some locations
as kamati so for range trees which have
a root size smaller than this range all
I'm going to do is access the root for
range trees but that are larger and I
now need to find two super blocks that
store this range s comma T so earlier
with the read-only range or and this was
easy because I could use some simple
math and figure out where these two to
where these two super blocks are stored
but now it turns out I cannot do that
because my data need not be a set of all
n memory locations so in order to
actually find which two these blocks are
we will use a separate auxiliary data
structure which would be oblivious at a
high level if you use if you perform
some sort of a binary search on top of a
know Ram that data structure should be
sufficient to obtain these two blocks
and then I'm going to access these
appropriate blocks from Orange a where
AM J where J is log of t minus s plus
1.so and at the end of this I have data
from each of these ramps all written to
a server and the same log can be
repeated multiple times and I need to
perform some sort of deduplication to
get freshest range s comma T so let us
try to analyze the locality of this
algorithm and again remember locality is
the number of disk on teachers accesses
or the number
of jumps so for the first step we have
they just making up to log and
discontinuous accesses of size of of the
size of the range for the second step
for accessing the oblivious data
structure and we are again making poly
logarithmic accesses but this is of size
one because all we are accessing in the
data structure is some index for the
next step when I'm actually performing
this axis again I'm making poly
logarithmic number of discontinuous
accesses of the size of the range and
finally in order to perform
deduplication we'll use some sort of a
locality of friendly oublie with certain
so for now I'm going to punt on W sort
I'll revisit it when we reach the
maintain phase but for now if you would
observe all of these points or all of
them do not depend on the range in terms
of locality or localities independent of
size of the range so with that let us
see how we can perform a maintain
operation or a rebuild operation and the
goal over here is to write this access
data back into the data structure so
updating arrange tree is hard and it is
because we want to store consistent
values across different heights so if
you think of accessing the range of size
K and now I have to update it across all
Heights for accessing the root I'm going
to incur a large bandwidth because I'll
have to download the entire data and
similarly for accessing the leaves I'm
going to incur a large locality because
I'm going to do it I need to do it one
by one and the fix over here is to
actually write in a smaller range tree
and rebuild range trees if if you take a
bird's eye view and see what we are
doing over here this is something
similar to what rebuild operations how
rebuild operations are performed in
hierarchical or arms in general but the
important constraint that we need to
maintain over here is locality so we
require over arms that have a locality
friendly initialization and a locality
friendly rebuild procedure
specifically I cannot initialize an over
on by saying I start with an empty
and add blocks one by one I need to do
it as a batch and an important
ingredient turns out is a locality
friendly oblivious sort and over here we
use baton exert and we show that if you
have two disks then Botanic sort can be
implemented with order log square and
locality and n log square and bandwidth
and this is where the notion of two
disks come in in a final result all
right so we spoke about how to do
read-only in your arms using a very
specific range tree how to do read and
write using the hierarchy of range trees
let us try to see how we can move from
offline to online again the idea over
here is simple
I have requests coming one by one all
I'll do is some sort of a predictive
prefetching whenever I see my request
sequence if I see that the request
sequence is discontinuous I just access
a block of size one on the other hand if
requests are contagious then I'm going
to prefetch a larger super block of
double the size of what I did earlier so
if I have so it just grows it's
geometrically so if I have requests
which are which looks like two three
four five six for every 1 comma 4 first
I'll access a block of size one then a
block of size two then a block of size
four and then I observe that localities
not maintained when request sequence one
who comes in and then I'll start all
over again and as we can easily see a
range of length L just requires up to
log L accesses so I can move from
offline to online by throwing in another
log and factor in terms of both locality
environment so to summarize here are our
contributions I discussed the upper
bound over here now in the presentation
for the lower bound I would urge you to
read our paper but before ending my talk
I would quickly discuss whether such a
length leakage in an over amis
reasonable and I would first make a
number law statement that this largely
depends on the application
if lengths are already public knowledge
Ranger hands are useful and then they'll
give you efficiency because because of
locality however on the flip side I'll
also mention that range or a monastic
generalization of a regular era I can
always turn off the locality feature by
just not using predictive prefetching
and finally in recently people have
considered trying to hide the access
pattern length using differential
privacy perhaps something like this can
be used over here
to hide the length of ranges let me end
my talk by posing some open questions
the first open question and to me this
is the most interesting open question is
can we actually preserve the number of
disks while achieving obliviousness for
instance our solution uses two disks and
that stems from using a bionic sort it
turns out that there have been some
partial progress through a subsequent
work which was published in NDS 2019 and
over there they assume a larger client
storage and they are able to do this
using a single disk and the client
storage that they assume is the size of
the range that you have accessed a
second interesting open question over
here is can we have a locality
preserving a pram or an oblivious parent
run and finally until now I have
discussed everything in terms of poly
low poly login and so an interesting
question is can we get actual asymptotic
efficiency in fact a previous draft of
our own work discusses better
asymptotics for the same scheme that I
described and this work in in DSS 19
also talks about the actual asymptotics
so the interesting part of this work is
that they use a tree based over m
instead of a hierarchical Aram to
achieve locality thank you and I'd be
happy to take questions
so yeah questions if a question please
come to the mic
all right thank you okay let's thank the
speaker
[Applause]