we the slides will hold together enough
for me to actually give this talk thank
you for the introduction as said I'm
Ariel Hamlin and today I will be
presenting our work on private anonymous
data access this is a joint work with
Raphael Ostrovsky more Weiss and Daniel
Wix so without further ado let's
consider a setting where we have a
server a single server storing some
database in this case a medical database
and we have a set of clients who want to
make queries into this database to get
information about flu symptoms
especially given the flu symptoms we've
had or flu season we've had here in the
States you might have someone who is
concerned about their headache or
headache causes but for other clients
they may be concerned about sort of
their queries and their identities being
linked to those queries so in this
setting they want maybe both privacy for
those queries and anonymity for their
identity so this is the setting that we
consider within panda essentially a
single server with multiple clients and
we want to be able to provide privacy
and anonymity for the clients asking
queries so as with all works we have an
acronym namely private anonymous data
access or as we like to call it panda
because who doesn't like cute adorable
fuzzy creatures so for the rest of the
talk I'll be referring to our system as
panda so without further ado what does
panda actually consist of we have a
setup for a protocol that takes in
database and generates for each of our
clients essentially a unique client key
and gives the server and encoded
database so in this case both the client
and the server is our stateful we also
support writing or sorry
reading so a client may have a value
that they want to read within the
particular database using their client
key they interact with the server and
get the value back at that particular
database location we also do support
rights in panda but in this talk I will
be talking primarily about our read-only
Panda scheme if you're interested in
rights we do present the sort of
high-level work but I would encourage
you to refer to the paper or track me
down after this session so now that we
sort of established the syntax let's
talk about what we want sort of in the
setting in this definition as I
mentioned in our motivating example we
want security against a server who may
be trying to learn clients queries and
their identities namely what we want
privacy of access patterns against the
server and we want anonymity of the
clients identities meaning the server
cannot cross correlate clients
identities between different queries we
want this not only against a server who
might be observing these actions and
interactions with the clients but also
with a server who is allowed to collude
with some number of clients and gain
access to both their sort of actions and
their secret key and we set at setup
time an i priori bound on the number of
clients that the server may collude with
and we call this number T as our
collusion that we also want a single
server scheme so not necessarily
something that relies on multiple
servers especially not servers that
don't collude and finally we want
efficiency goals namely we want the
client and server read or write if we're
talking about it complexity to be
sublinear in this collusion threshold T
or sorry in the number of clients and
and the database size and we want it to
be linear in the collusion threshold so
it's this combination of privacy and
anonymity for with bounded collusion and
these certain efficiency goals that we
call the panda setting so without
further ado this may sound fairly
similar to some of the primitives that
have come
for me in this session namely oblivious
RAM and another primitive called private
information retrieval so I want to spend
the next part of the talk sort of
comparing and contrasting the Panda
setting and whether Oh RAM and Pierre
are things that actually work to solve
our problem spoilers they don't so I
think previous talked an excellent job
motivating and explaining Oh Ram so at a
high level we have our single server we
have a single client who wants to make
access paths or queries into a database
that the server storing well hiding
their access patterns Oh Ram itself
there's a huge asterisks on this know up
here but is not inherently multi-client
there are schemes that attempt to
support it but most of the common
schemes do not run time is going to be
poly log in the database size and we
have setup assumed and the server has
states and we're able to build a ram
essentially from one way functions we
also have a primitive called private
information retrieval we're talking here
about the single server pure
constructions and in this again when you
have a single server and multiple
clients who want to be able to make
queries and hide their sort of access
patterns unlike a Ram peer is inherently
multi-client namely the client does not
need a secret queue to make a query so
anyone can come along and sort of query
and is not needed to be defined at setup
time unfortunately this requires linear
server-side work for any read accesses
and we're able to get peer from public
key crypto so how we compare with panda
particularly a ram we are able to get
multi client and unlike peer were able
to achieve poly log performance in terms
of our database size we do allow for
setup and sort of States and we're able
to construct panda schemes from fhe
so these are common primitives that you
might compare panda against but there's
actually a third one that I want to talk
about a little bit and that's deadly
efficient pure or deep here this was
first introduced by the malla doll in
2000 as a multi server scheme and
basically what it does is deep here
allows for pre-processing unlike typical
pure and what you get as a trade-off
there is that you can now achieve a poly
log runtime for server access complexity
during reads and essentially what I want
to compare against is the more recent
work by caneta at all and boil at all in
2017 that reduces the multi server DPR
down to a single server and namely their
public key deeper variants as with pure
we have a single server and sort of any
person can come along and make queries
against this sort of database the server
is storing we are as I said able to get
multi-client poly log runtime we allow
for setup and state or pure with
pre-processing is it's also called
however in order to achieve this we
require or it requires new coding
assumptions and virtual black box off
you station
so public key deep here does in fact
solve our penned a problem but it does
so with some fairly heavy assumptions or
you know heavy-duty tools and we were
wondering is it possible to get a
construction that relies on sort of less
onerous assumptions and yes because my
talk isn't ending and I have 14 more
minutes to talk at you guys so without
further ado I want to go into our
results so we're able to achieve a
read-only Panda scheme relying only on
fhe with TR collusion bound poly log L
our database size client read complexity
we also support two variants of panda
that supports writes we have a public
rights panda where we essentially have a
public database that everyone writes to
and we have a secret rights panda where
everyone essentially has their own
personal database I want to spend most
of the rest of the talk talking about
how we construct our read
panda ski so without further ado our
main starting idea here is the original
multi-server de pere scheme introduced
by bemol and in this scheme we have
multiple servers and in fact we have que
servers and sort of they're all involved
and for setup we have essentially
trusted setup that takes in a database
and outputs and encoded database and it
gives essentially this encoded database
to each of the K servers it is the same
copy there is no difference between the
databases that each of these servers
gets when someone wants to come along
and make a query what they do is
essentially send out K unique indices
into this encoded database for codeword
symbols that they want to read the
servers then go ahead and return the
codeword symbols at that particular
location and the client is able to
decode them and get the message symbol
that it wanted to read at that
particular address in the database we
say for correctness that the client must
issue these K queries to the server and
we say that privacy holds in essentially
multi server deep here if less than s of
the server s of the servers collude and
in that case when they have less than s
indices that they're comparing these
indices appear to be uniformly
distributed so that's what when I say
multi server deep here privacy further
in the talk is what I'm alluding to so
obviously if you'll remember we had a
sort of a list of requirements that we
wanted for for panda one of them which
is we wanted to use only a single server
so how do we move essentially a single
server scheme or a multi server scheme
to a single server and we do this by
essentially having one server emulate
all of our K servers as virtual machines
or virtual servers now we're down to a
single server but obviously in this case
privacy is not preserved as the single
machine is emulating all of these
virtual servers it gets to see the
access
turns into these encoded database so
when we're considering access patterns
and the sort of wanting to hide them the
primitive that jumps to mind that we
want to use this might be something like
oblivious RAM or Oh Ram and so what if
we did instead of essentially encoding
the same copy and sort of handing this
out to all of our virtual servers before
we did that we essentially put these in
coded databases into K unique a Rams and
each of these o Rams now would have
their own secret key the question is now
how do we query these our M's when a
client wants to come along and make
their sort of K accesses to these
virtual servers so we now have to give
each of the clients essentially all of
the Oh RAM secret keys so this would
seem to work except if we remember that
panda allows for collusion between
clients and servers so as soon as this
collusion happens the server gets access
to the client secret keys which is all
of them and any notion of privacy
provided by this Oh Ram is now lost so I
even put it in a no Ram in the first
place
so we need to now essentially have that
each client has some unique or unique
secret state that is not shared with all
of the other clients so when collusion
happens we still have some notion of
secrecy so what we do here is to
introduce the idea of committees so what
instead of getting all of the secret
keys for the sort of a Rams instead
clients get the keys for virtual servers
on their assigned committee and this is
don''t setup and they essentially get
assigned some subset of the servers k of
them essentially that they can now make
their queries - so in this case in this
example client one gets access to the
first and case virtual server client
number two is going to be given access
to the first and the second virtual
server so on and so forth as you'll note
we actually have to use more than K
virtual servers in this case because we
do want some additional servers so we
don't have sort of entire overlap on all
of our virtual committees because we
want those committees to be unique for
each client so what happens now when
collusion happens the server only gets
the keys for the committee of the
cluding clients which means that it only
gets to see some accesses in plaintext
only for those where there is an overlap
between your committee and occluding
clients committee so essentially we can
say that the server because the overlap
between your committee and the cluding
client committees is going to be less
than s based on how these committees are
generated we can say that the multi
server dear privacy still holds because
the server only sees less than s
accesses essentially in the plaintext
the rest of the access patterns are now
going to be hidden by oh Ram so privacy
holds so we have single server we have
privacy but if we remember in panda we
also want anonymity for clients but now
clients essentially have some unique
information namely they have a unique
committee associated with them so
servers can tell quick sort of clients
apart based on which virtual servers
they access as they have been assigned
to their committee so we lose anonymity
so how can we fix this one could say
well when we query the things on our
committee we can simulate sort of random
accesses into the Oh Rams that are not
on our committee and the server excuse
me
won't be able to tell the difference
however this comes down to the
fundamental problem we don't actually
know how to simulate these accesses into
the ORM because you remember we don't
actually have the secret keys for those
grants and what's even worse our
adversary the server might even in fact
have the secret keys if it's colluding
with a client that has that server on
its committee
so essentially what we need is this
ability to make smart dummy accesses the
ability to simulate a random access
without the secret key and this seems a
property that most AI Rams outside of
trivial ones don't necessarily have so
instead what we do is we try and get the
next best thing we get a ram like
behavior up to a certain number of
queries and what we do to achieve this
is introduced the idea of instead of
dropping our encoded database into an
OEM we instead simply permute it based
on a pseudo-random permutation
essentially so instead of each encoded
database in these virtual servers being
dropped in a no RAM instead it is
uniquely permeated as defined by a
permutation key and these keys are given
to the clients and LU of the Oh RAM keys
so when we want to make a query a client
simply gets the index that it wants to
query sort of in the unpermitted
database it permits it according to its
permutation key and ask those queries
two things to the virtual servers on its
committee for things that are not on its
committee it simply asks for a random
index in the encoded database because
now it can simulate a totally random
access and the server even if it has the
key can't tell the difference between
that or sort of an actual legitimate
access so for things that are not on my
committee I have sort of uniform queries
by definition
I'm just asking things randomly for
things that are on my committee but the
server doesn't have sort of access to it
we say that for a certain number of
bounded number of queries excuse me that
essentially it gives an oem like hiding
of access patterns thanks to a lemma
from Kennedy atolls 2017 paper and for
things that are on my committee and that
the server does have the key for it is
going to appear to be random
based on the multi-server deep your
privacy so we're kind of covered in all
three of our cases so we're able to
achieve essentially up to a certain
number of queries and how do we move
beyond this bount and this is where our
reliance on fhe comes in essentially for
every B reads where B's are bound the
server is capable of regenerating the
permutations on its own because instead
of having them sort of specified by a
sort of a pseudo-random permutation we
have them defined by a PRF and this PRF
key is essentially encrypted under FH
fhe
allowing the server to essentially
evaluate the permutation on its own and
refresh it for worst-case sufficiency I
think that it's telling me that y'all
are hungry for lunch and that I should
hurry up but we can say that for
efficiency we can amaura ties this
action across our bounds or are
essentially our epoch in order to obtain
sort of reasonable worst-case efficiency
so this is how we achieve unbounded read
only panda we also have as I alluded to
previously panda that supports writes
namely a public rights panda with a
public database where essentially rights
are public so both their content and
where you're writing it to but the
identity of the writer is still hidden
so we still have anonymity reads of
course are still private and anonymous
we also have a construction for secret
rights panda where essentially each
client has their own database that they
can write to and in that database
privacy and anonymity of rights is
maintained
obviously reads are also still private
and an anonymous the cost of this
however is that performance where we
have database size
namely L now scales with the total
number of Rights
across the entire system I that's not
the end of my talk hello
it really doesn't want me to show you
guys performance numbers I'm almost at
the end so I can finish up if we have to
without I don't necessarily this one try
this one enjoy beautiful seals this was
taken that crypto in Santa Barbara so
anyhow uh while they were fighting with
that I'll simply sort of finish off so
we're able to achieve public rights
Panda with the same read complexity and
secret rights panda with the same read
complexity as read only panda all you
have to do is hit I think it's just
start and it should nope all right this
is going to be actually my second to
last slide so you guys will bear with me
so client right complexity is simply
going to be a vlog L where L is database
size for client right complexity secret
panda achieves the same sort of
complexity as reads and server right
complexity has a reliance on both the
number of colluding clients and our
database size and here epsilon is for
any epsilon greater than zero so that's
what we achieve for panda with rights in
summary we're able to achieve a read
only panda scheme from fhe where clients
and server complexity is poly log and
database size and linear in the
collusion bounds we support two forms of
rights
and public and we are interested in
pursuing the panda problem sort of in
other directions namely it would be
interesting to see if we can remove this
bounded collusion aspect of Panda and
have performance scale independent of
sort of the number of collisions or
corruptions and to remove this reliance
on fhe in favor of more efficient
primitives so thank you for sitting
through this before lunch with all the
technical difficulties and at this point
I am happy to take any questions thank
you very much any question is about
panda yes they're adorable