so this talk is going to basically be
concerned about no cloning so what is no
cloning or quantum no-cloning well what
we can consider is a hypothetical device
that takes as input an arbitrary unknown
quantum state and turns it into two cop
identical copies of the original state
classically this is easy so if you're
you know classical state is this a
string of ones and zeros you can just
read it and write it down twice but it
turns out with quantum information this
is actually impossible if you if you
truly know nothing about the input
quantum state there is no way to
actually create two copies so as a
cryptographer you know what I think of
when I think of no cloning is quantum
money so quantum money is basically the
you know the cryptographic application
of this and what it is is the following
so the the mint is going to basically
generate a random quantum state that's
going to be the bank note they're going
to keep a classical description of this
bank note privately to themselves and
then they'll they'll give out the
quantum state right so you know by
no-cloning when when you get this
quantum state you can't copy it so you
know it seems like we have a good a good
unforgeable money from this but the
problem is is that this plain quantum
money that I've described so far is
maybe not super useful in practice and
the reason is is that in order to let's
say you know mr. moneybags here has a
quantum bank note they want to go buy a
car they're going to give the bank note
to the dealership and the dealership is
going to say hey you know this is a
arbitrary quantum state how do I know
that this is the quantum state that came
from the mint versus you just came up
with your own arbitrary state so what
the dealership has to do is actually go
to the mint send them the bank note the
mint says you know yes this is this is
the bank note corresponding to the
private State if you know the actual
classical description of the state you
can verify and so then they'll send the
money back and say yeah it was the right
so with with this concept of quantum
money we don't have an analogue of you
know holding the note up to the light
and making sure there's a strip in there
and all the other features that we have
so what we really want out of a quantum
money scheme is public verifiability so
you know the analog of just holding the
bill up to the light so what we really
want is that a scheme where the serial
number can actually be made public and
so broadcast to everyone I know you just
verify relative to this serial number
and the hope is that security remains
that you know mr. mr. moneybags here he
knows the serial number he has a quantum
state that even then he still cannot
copy the quantum state
unfortunately the sort of original
proposal for quantum money is totally
insecure here if you know the serial
number it immediately tells you how to
construct arbitrarily many copies at the
quantum state but we can hypothesize
about the existence of of this better
object so really you know this notion of
public key quantum money is just it's no
cloning plus a verifiability aspect in
this talk I consider something maybe
even a little stronger
and to motivate this you know I had a
thrown blockchain or Bitcoin somewhere
so if we imagine a typical
cryptocurrency application the thing is
that with cryptocurrencies the the
people minting money are the same as the
people spending money and if you think
about it this presents a very big
problem that it you know how is the
person who's minting money going to be
how are we gonna prevent them from you
know just s-- minting multiple copies of
their money you know the cryptocurrency
solve this by keeping a public ledger of
all transactions but maybe we can use no
cloning in some way to to avoid this but
you see that what we need here is that
the we actually need security against
the person who makes the banknote in the
first place and so this is sort of the
motivation for the title of my talk
let me explain what the title of the
talk actually means so you know we have
this old adage about lightning never
strikes the same place twice let's
pretend it's actually true
Early's true in nature well we we know
actually it's not true if you tamper
with nature say by erecting a tall
building so this is the tallest building
in Europe it's somewhere in Russia and
we can see you know four pictures of
different lightning bolts striking the
buildings so you know clearly if we
tamper with nature lightning will strike
the same place twice so what does
quantum lightning it's a hypothetical
digital version of lightning that is
secure in the sense that no matter how
you tamper with the procedure for
generating the lightning in your wreck
the tall building when you know
essentially a lightning rod or whatever
you do to tamper with the procedure it
will still always output different
outputs every time and this is
impossible classically if you think
about it for a moment because you know
if you basically you can control the
initial conditions if you're thinking
about digital things you know just
always feed in the same randomness if
you're thinking about physical processes
you can control the initial conditions
in a laboratory environment so that
every time you carry out the process you
get the same result with quantum
information though maybe we can hope to
avoid this
as a sidenote so when I give this talk
in the u.s. I use the World Trade Center
the tallest building in the US so for
here I wanted to find the tallest
building in Germany and show four
pictures of lightning striking it
unfortunately I could only find one so
maybe Germany actually already is
invented quantum lightning I don't know
any case so quantum Lightning has
applications maybe public key quantum
money is a trivial one maybe it can give
decentralized currency without a without
the blockchain and also another
interesting application is that it
actually gives a way to certify that a
particular value has entropy basically
the the bolt is a proof that its serial
number has entropy and there's a
easy reduction showing this okay
so let's turn to constructions well
they're very few and far between
unfortunately there have been a few
constructions in the literature most of
which has been mostly which have been
broken and all of which are basically
the the underlying computational
assumption is we don't know how to break
this scheme and nothing really more
interesting than that no nothing based
on standard assumptions or even like a
nice simple to state assumption that can
be analyzed by cryptographers so the
purpose of this work is to try to remedy
the situation and give some new
constructions of quantum money quantum
Lightning that are maybe a little easier
to analyze and along the way we'll see
some interesting connections to post
quantum security which is security of
classical crypto in a quantum world so
yes let me take that detour now so a
seemingly completely unrelated topic is
is the following
so consider commitment scheme in
particular bit commitments you know we
all know that this these consists of a
commit phase in a reveal phase where in
the commit phase after the commit phase
Bob learns nothing about the message but
in some sense we want that Alice is
bound to a particular message and then
only in the reveal phase does she does
she reveal what the message is so I'm
not gonna care about the hiding property
for this talk but the more interesting
case for us is binding so what we want
is that an adversarial Alice who engages
in the commit phase at least the the
classical way we define security is that
after Alice carries out the commit phase
she can then what she has to do is try
to commit simultaneously to both 0 and 1
so but I we need to take a moment tack
to think about this definition so the
security goal is that Alice after the
commit phase has there's a unique
message that she at most a unique
message that she can possibly de commit
but the way we typically formalize this
is we say that once Alice Dee commits
she could not simultaneously / sorry
once I was commit she cannot
simultaneously D commit to both 0 & 1
classically who cares these are these
are equivalent definitions you can
basically if Alice can be commit to
either 0 or 1 you first D commit her to
0 you rewind her on and then D commit
her to 1 and now you have both a D
commitment to 0 and 1 so classically
these two goals were the same but
quantumly
maybe maybe not and here's the intuition
so a quantum Alice engages in the commit
phase and the commit the the messages
are still classical but you know Alice
is running a quantum computer on her
side maybe after the commit phase she's
left with some quantum state and this
quantum state lets her D commit to 0 or
it lets her D commit to 1 but she can't
do both and why is that
well once she D commits to 0 she needs
to produce 0 and a classical D
commitment which is sent to Bob right
remember we're insisting all the
communication is classical but in order
to do so she has to measure her quantum
state and to extract this you know
classical D commitment just a measure of
quantum state causing a collapse and now
when she tries to rewind and then D
commit to 1
she'll find when she rewinds her her
quantum state is completely messed up
and when she tries to D commit to one
she's going to get garbage so this is
this is the intuition there's a solution
to this given by une rue in 2016 for the
purpose of this talk actually it doesn't
really matter though so I won't spend
any time here so the one question that
you might ask is this really a problem
and it turns out maybe so here's a
result by in Venus and others that
doesn't give a concrete separation
between the the classical notion of
simultaneously D committing to 0 & 1 and
this better quantum notion
but they give a construction relative to
some Oracle but basically what they show
is relative to this Oracle there is a
scheme a classical scheme that is
binding in the classical sense even
against quantum adversaries so the
adversary is always quantum here but
we're considering this classical notion
of security where they D commit to 0 and
1 simultaneously however even though
it's binding in the classical sense it's
insecure in the quantum sense in that an
adversary can be commit to either 0 or 1
okay but at the moment you know there's
we don't know of any actual concrete
instantiations of the separation and
they kind of left it at that
so now let's segue back to our
discussion of no cloning and I guess the
question is what does all this have to
do with no cloning and there's this here
we come to the first set of results of
this paper
where we actually show that if the
commitment scheme and you're able to
certify that it's binding in the
classical sense but somehow security
breaks and you actually get this bad
thing in the quantum setting then
actually you get quantum money from this
and moreover if your commitment scheme
is not interactive you get this better
notion of quantum lightning and we show
an analogous results for signatures and
hash functions as well so here's the
intuition so suppose for the moment that
actually we could take the adversary
state after the commit phase their
quantum state and suppose we could clone
it well if we could clone it then
actually the two definitions of security
are equivalent right because then we can
just take the one the one state and D
commit use it to D commit to zero
potentially destroying it so you know we
just throw it away and then we take the
other state and use it to D commit to
one so if there was somehow a way to D
commit sorry to clone the adversary
state post commitment then we could
actually prove the
equivalence of the two definitions and
so what this means is that any
separation between the two definitions
inherently uses no cloning and the way
and so we can try to take advantage of
this constructively to build quantum
money or quantum lightning so basically
what we are what we'll do is we'll set
the bank node or bolt to be the
adversary state post commitment and then
the way you verify is you more or less
just check that the adversary is able to
break the the quantum security notion
all right and and that's you know that's
the intuition of course there's a bunch
of messy details in order to actually
make sure this works okay so what are
the takeaways from this well there's two
possible interpretations one is hey
these these stronger quantum notions I
don't need to worry about them when I'm
designing schemes because hey look
people have tried for a while to build
quantum money and lightning and it's not
done a very good job it's very hard to
build so maybe you know you could
conjecture that you could probably
reasonably conjecture that a given
scheme that's secure in the classical
sense is also secure in the quantum
sense because otherwise you would have
just solved this hard problem and the
other interpretation is maybe this is a
route tor provides a route towards
building quantum money or lightning
basically take a commitment scheme and
somehow try to show that it's broken in
the quantum sense right and the second
route is what we will try to do in the
latter half of the talk okay so next
let's turn to actually giving new
constructions of these objects so the
first construction of quantum money is
going to use something called program
office Kishin
what is this basically it just takes a
program scrambles it the goal is to hide
all the implementation details while
maintaining functionality as you all
probably know this has recently we've
been given a lot of attention and many
you have conjectured to be crypto
completes in the sense that it seems
like any task that you want to solve you
can solve using office keishon and well
you know so I show that this actually
does hold true at least for quantum
so if you have indistinguishability
obfuscation is a usual way we formalize
things then you can actually get public
key quantum money and this this lemma or
this theorem is composed of two lemmas
one says that this other notion of
office occasionally hiding off the
station implies quantum money and then
shows that then the second lemma is
indistinguishable the obfuscation
implies this other notion of obfuscation
and this second lemma here is rather
easy from non techniques the more
interesting one is the first one I'm not
going to go into the proof of either of
these but I do just want to explain what
the security notion is so that you can
try to come up with other constructions
of subspace hiding office caters to
build quantum money so here's here's
what sub-sites hiding office Kishin is
so basically the office cater the the
input programs are just going to be
identified I'm going to be the functions
that I'll put one on a particular
subspace and I'll put zero everywhere
else and so what we're going for the
security property we need is we're going
to imagine two spaces being chosen at
random as larger subspace T and a
smaller subspace s that's contained in T
and what the adversary sees is they're
going to see s the smaller subspace and
they're either going to see an
occupation the program that computes s
or they're going to see an obfuscation
in the program that computes T and the
security requirement that we need is
that these two are indistinguishable
right so if you can if you can build a
subspace hiding off you skater with you
know the right parameters then you would
immediately good public key quantum
money and solve this apparently
difficult problem okay so for the other
set of the other result is for
constructing quantum lining
unfortunately I don't know how to
construct this from subspace hiding off
East occation or even the you know the
stronger notion of indistinguishability
off you station here's all what I'm
going to try to do is construct quantum
lining from learning with errors I don't
know how to do this what I what you
and show is that this this is not
something that I formally define in the
paper but you can show something that
I'll call for this talk at Gap lwe is
good enough to build quantum lightning
so what is what does gap lwe firstly the
graphics got messed up here but what
we're going to imagine is that we have
some distribution on and what this
distribution is going to output is a
tall matrix a and some auxilary
information now the auxiliary and all a
and the auxiliary information are going
to be given to the adversary and now
what we want is three things so the
first thing is we want that cyst or the
short integer solution is hard relative
to this matrix a with the auxiliary
information so if the adversary is given
a they're given the exhibitor
information that they can't find a short
vector X in the left kernel of a this is
the this problem it turns out that
there's a quantum reduction more or less
due to rev that shows that if this is
hard
another problem is hard which is called
the search lwe problem and here what
you're given is you're you're given a
dot s for a random random vector s so
this is basically a random element in
the column span of a now of course if I
gave you that you could easily recover s
using linear algebra but you know you
add noise and then this presumably
becomes hard but the the goal so what is
hard is taking a sample of a des plus E
and recovering s so we need both of
these problems to be hard you know so
far this is this is this is normal you
can use if a is just a random matrix
this corresponds to the usual assists
and search lwe assumption which are
known to be hard based on worst case
lattice problems the the wrinkle here is
that we want decisional lwe problem to
be easy so what is decisional lwe it
just says that given one of these LWT
samples you can't tell whether was an LW
simple or a uniform random vector and
here we actually want we want this to be
easy now normally if you just if your
matrix is just uniformly random the same
reductions that work force a search lwe
also can be used to show that decision
llw is hard so we want to wait basically
to preserve the hardness we want to you
know break the matrix a in a way that
preserves the search lwe hardness and
preserves assist hardness but somehow
allows the decisional problem to be easy
and and i call this a gap lwe because
there's sort of an analogy here to gap
diffie-hellman where you can think of
maybe sis is the analog of discrete log
search LW is the analog of CDH and
decisional other beauties the analog OD
d h and a gap tiffy Hellman group you
know has has two of those being hard and
the other one being easy right so in any
case if you can find such a matrix with
like Ziller information such that the
three of these are true then you
immediately get quantum lightning now
unfortunately I don't know how to
instantiate this what I do in the paper
is I give a candidate modification where
we basically change the notion of
shortness to news it normally shortness
is l 2-norm I'm gonna change the notion
to rank norm basically what happens is
you interpret the vector as a matrix and
insist that it's rank is small this
actually doesn't really work because
rank nor the Syst version and for rank
norm is actually easy but you can kind
of massage things to get something that
looks that looks reasonable yeah
unfortunately it has been broken in some
settings but I don't know maybe there's
some some hardness here that can be
verified but clearly much more work
needs to be done
yeah and that that basically concludes
my talk so you know please work on these
problems I think they're very
interesting and and hopefully I've made
it clear like some some things you can
think about without no having to know
anything about quantum
to make progress on building quantum
money and lightning so with that I'll
end thank you
[Applause]
great questions
that's one going
we know that the naive version of
quantum becoming man doesn't work
because you can do a gentle measurement
to get back last day so can you go on
little detail about what's your
definition of the become meme and to
make it possible
what's used to make it possible to do
what exactly what again so to make it
actually binding because if the binding
has a high probability of a success
there but it's got higher incidence
gentlemen German lemma you can get
bigger the contest day Oh
[Music]
what why can't you just always rewind
Yeah right the problem is that this when
you act well when you dekum it you're
not just sending you're not just sending
the bit 0 or 1 but you're sending the
proof right in this okay so the
intuition is basically what you might
hope to have is that the proof is
actually a superposition of proofs but
once you classical eyes it by measuring
so that you're actually sending what's
the right slide to show once you're
actually sending a classical D
commitment to Bob so you have to you
have to take the superposition over
proofs measure it and that's going to
force a collapse on that you can't then
undo okay
does that make sense
so I I have a question about this sub
subspace of whose Cashen problem so is
is that like a related notion of like
what should be publicly viewable from
like for I don't know for program
obfuscation we have a notion of
computation of input and output and for
the subspace of obfuscation what's that
is that is there something publicly
publicly no so the only thing that's
probably so the I mean the algorithm
froggy skating is is of course public
but the only other thing that's made
public is the subspace s so just s you
know you wrote you know and all the
obfuscation literature you always assume
that the obfuscation algorithm is public
but nothing nothing else is public that
answer your question
okay so there's just subspaces random
with no like is there a notion of size
or of structure of those subspaces or
does no I mean I I've gloss over some
details but yeah the you know basically
the S will be of a given dimension T
will be of a given dimension but
otherwise are uniformly random and you
have a fairly maybe fairly basic
question regarding the the quantum money
application so if I verify the proof
this does not collapse the state or like
so if I like verify the proof is the
money then destroyed or how does this
sort of work conceptually so yeah a you
know you usually you would insist that
verification does not destroy the state
but there's there's actually generically
you can take any verification algorithm
even one that does destroy the state as
long as it succeeds with overwhelming
probability on honest banknotes you can
modify it so that it will also actually
preserve the original state Thanks hi so
when you when you look at quantum money
so I understand correctly that if you do
the verification interactively with the
with the mint basically what the mean
would do would the
stroy the quantum token verified that
it's actually correct regenerate another
one and send it back with a certificate
of authenticity this is more or less
what happens correctly sure I guess I
mean I mean you can you can interpret
what the mint does differently but more
more or less that's right okay
and now the goal would be to do it
actually public key verification right
exactly this sounds a little bit like
verifying the digital signature or on a
quantum state correct verifying a what
protocol a digital signature on a
quantum state it's it's related except
so the the the thing is if you could
imagine like a I mean the problem with
signatures is that depending on how you
actually define things signing a quantum
state is actually impossible yeah but
yeah it is related okay so that exactly
so I was wondering what was the
intuition that allows to circumvent this
impossibility result let's say I mean I
guess I guess the intuition is is we're
not quantum money is more is a more
general that's more general the right
word no it's it's more restrictive of a
concept than signing a quantum state and
intuitively the the impossibility for
signing a quantum state is just that
authentication of quantum states implies
encryption and you know normally the way
you would formalize signatures is it
always leaves the message in the clear
here there's there's sort of no message
that needs to be in the clear so you
know we don't care if things are secret
okay I see thank you okay we'll end the
session here thank Mike again
[Applause]