alright thanks let me start by comparing
I sahjhan II based public key encryption
to diffie-hellman what both of these
give us is non-interactive key exchange
so the setup here is that you have Alice
generating some public key a times GG is
some standard that everybody knows in
the space of public keys Alice has her
own secret a and multiplies that by G to
get a G and Bob does the same thing to
make his public key be G from his own
independently generated secret B and
that lets them both agree on some shared
secret which you can write in several
ways you can say Alice takes Bob's
public key BG and multiplies it by her
secret a to get a times B times G which
is the same as a times B times G which
is the same as B times a times G which
is the same as what Bob gets by
multiplying his secret B times Alice's
public key a times G so they've agreed
on the same element of the public key
space some shared secret which they can
then hash and use as an AAS GCM key to
authenticate and encrypt all their
communications there's lots of names for
the different mathematical equations
that are being used here like a times B
being B times a okay that's
commutativity of the multiplication in
the semigroup of secret keys which is
maybe a group there's the associativity
at the beginning here well sometimes
mathematicians have so much fun coming
up with names that they have multiple
names for the same thing so this is when
you're multiplying secret keys by public
keys to get public keys then that's not
called multiplication anymore with
associativity it's called an action
which just means okay you've got
associativity when you multiply the
secret Keys and then multiply the result
by a public key it's the same as
multiplying the second secret key first
by the public key and then multiplying
by the other secret key all right
this gives us a shared secret between
Alice and Bob which traditionally we do
by maybe not the original diffie-hellman
protocol we use elliptic curve
diffie-hellman going back to Miller and
Co blitz in the mid-80s and both of
these both the original diffie-hellman
with multiplicative groups and elliptic
curve diffie-hellman have some
polynomial cost in lambda to achieve a
security level of 2 to the lambda of
course to figure out what exactly
polynomial is you have to start by
saying well okay what are the attacks
how can some attacker figure out
something about the shared secret
starting from the public information a G
and B G and then once you know how fast
the attacks are which is different
between this is why we like elliptic
curves is that the attacks are a lot
harder I once you've figured out how
fast the attacks are then you have to
figure out the constructive side of it
how fast are the algorithms to compute
the action to multiply a times G to
multiply a times B G etc if the attacks
get better than we know then well the
amount of key material that you might
need the key size might go up
dramatically it could even be totally
broken which is why the word pre quantum
is important here the pre quantum
security level to to lambda gives us
some polynomial cost in lambda but once
you switch to post quantum cryptography
then diffie-hellman and elliptic curve
diffie-hellman are broken if you look at
what Shor's algorithm needs to break
diffie-hellman and elliptic curve
diffie-hellman then it's basically using
exactly the features that were used up
at the top the commutativity of
multiplying the secrets and the
associativity but it's actually using a
little bit more algebraically it's using
that you can add public keys
what you do ensures algorithm you set up
some well there's some lattice of care
say x and y such that x times g plus y
times i a times G is 0 and that's some
two-dimensional lattice which sure finds
you
elements of and well end up in what I
just said there was a plus you can add
elements of the public key space which
is exactly the wedge that I saw Janee
based crypto uses to make a post quantum
version of the same thing at first
glance the the story is just like the
elliptic curve diffie-hellman story that
well there's some constructions due to
some people with some sort of details
where you analyze the attack cost of the
crs system goes back to covina and wrath
of stevia and sobinov and then much more
recently the seaside system went from
asia crypt 2018 that's from while some
of the authors of this paper but more
people so castro can read us i and maybe
i should say everything else i'm going
to say is going to be the same between
saris and seaside except for the details
of the costs where it's
besides I don't know a thousand million
times faster than CRS so you definitely
want to use seaside instead of CRS but
the aside from that the the basic
picture of what I'm talking about is the
same both of these just like
diffie-hellman elliptic curve
diffie-hellman have some polynomial cost
to resist all known attacks pre quantum
and the advantage is post quantum they
also have some polynomial cost to resist
all known attacks that take time less
than two to the lambda all right so this
is one reason people are interested in
nice OG&E based cryptography it gives us
non interactive key exchange just like
the original diffie-hellman but
apparently surviving quantum computers
there's another reason that people are
interested in I saw Jenny based crypto
even if they don't want non interactive
key exchange which seems it's kind of
hard to achieve non interactive key
exchange post quantum we don't have very
many proposals for that but we have a
lot more proposals for just doing public
key encryption and then within that
space of public key encryption systems
well there's a lot of interest in how
small the public keys can be and in
general how low the cost can be let me
emphasize you don't need to do the work
of coming up with non-interactive key
exchange in order to have a public key
encryption system for instance the best
known example of iso geneva-based crypto
the SI d h super singular i saw Jenny
diffie-hellman it's kind of misleading
because it doesn't do what
diffie-hellman does it's it's just a
public encryption system you need
communication to agree on a key but okay
it's now as a NIST submission for the
post quantum competition it's called
psych super singular isogen e key
exchange this is a perfectly reasonable
public key encryption system which is
well known for having small public keys
and let me compare this to various other
options for the public key sizes that
you might get and let's get a little
more quantitative than just polynomial
in lambda maybe I'll start down at the
bottom left here so pre quantum suppose
you want to to the lambda security where
security here is you want every attack
to take two to the lambda operations in
this talk I'm not going to be precise
about what exactly an operation is I'm
also going to ignore things like
communication cost so let's just say two
to the lambdas some simple operations
and you have to look at attack papers to
see the details
to curve diffie-hellman if you want
security level 2 to the lambda you need
something like 2 to the 2 lambda
possible keys because there's some
square root attack taking advantage of
the attack against the lifted curve
diffie-hellman exploits the well-known
worst case 2 average case reduction for
elliptic curve diffie-hellman and does
that in a way that reduces your security
level for 2 to the 2 lambda keys down to
only 2 to the lambda security and then
to transmit they 2 to the 2 lambda keys
you need about 2 lambda bits to
communicate
unfortunately post quantum that's broken
by Shor's algorithm but we have lots
more options and that's what gives us
while psych and seaside and again CRS is
very much like seaside except for being
quite a few orders of magnitude slower
let me just focus on seaside seaside is
twice as big keys as traditional
elliptic curve diffie-hellman for the
same security level instead of say a 256
bit 32 byte key you need say a 64 byte
key psych is quite a bit bigger now here
there's two variations you can do a
compressed psych which is only what is
that seven have seven times bigger than
elliptic curve diffie-hellman or seven
halves times bigger 3.5 times bigger
than seaside or an uncompressed version
which I don't think is going to last
long term because the compressed version
is getting faster and faster if you look
post quantum then well if you just count
at a cost naively then psych and
compress psych get somewhat bigger i if
you look at elliptic curve
diffie-hellman again that's completely
broken and then well what about seaside
that's somewhere in the middle because
there's a sub exponential time attack
against CRS and seaside this goes back
to 2010 tchodson Joensuu carve used
cooper burg sub exponential time hidden
shift algorithm or reg oves follow-up
algorithm or there's another follow-up
algorithm by cooper burg i same Cooper
burg but better than the first paper
actually also better than the second
paper I don't know how many people were
at the quack workshop over the weekend
but you heard that Cooper burg 2.0 is
better than Cooper burg 1.0 and better
than reg EV I anyway that is a sub
exponential time attack against CRS and
seaside which means that you need super
linear key sizes
in order to resist the attack and now
you can ask natural questions of what
exactly the superlinear is when does it
cross beyond the 21 lambda I mean it's
super linear so it has to be bigger than
21 lambda at some point how big this
lambda have to be is that of
cryptographic interest and so this
starts me on my list of questions if you
have a particular value of lambda say
you want to to the 64 quantum operations
to break your system or even more to to
the 96 to to the 128 quantum operations
to break your system what key size do
you need for seaside to achieve that
security level and this breaks up into
lots of separate questions because
there's there's actually a bunch of
different attacks and then these sub
exponential attacks in particular
involve quite a few layers they involve
first of all some bunch of queries that
if you look at how Cooper Berg's
algorithm finds a hidden shift it's not
as powerful as Shor's algorithm it's not
as fast it has some rapidly increasing
number of queries but well it doesn't
increase as exponentially it's just sub
exponential and what exactly is that
number of queries well even knowing that
Cooper Berg's 2011 paper is better than
the previous ones
doesn't help you figure out a concrete
answer to this because he just does
asymptotics and it takes a lot of work
to figure out what exactly the the costs
are another question when you start
digging down into the lower levels of
the algorithm you see that it's not
actually convenient you don't get the
fastest attack under reasonable
assumptions by generating a uniform
random element of the group of secret
keys it's much faster to generate
something which is not exactly uniform
but what does that do to Cooper Burke's
algorithm it's not clear and similarly
the computations get significantly
faster if you allow some errors you can
do everything error-free but if you
allow some errors it makes everything
faster too I'll get a little more into
that in a moment
and what effect does that have on Cooper
Berg's algorithm again not clear neither
of these questions is what this paper is
about this papers about the third item
on my list which is how expensive are
each of the queries so these algorithms
are doing a bunch of the attack
algorithms are doing a bunch of queries
which means evaluate the ice ogyny
action
on a superposition of all the possible
secret keys and then how expensive for
those queries how long does it take to
compute nice ogyny
on a quantum computer in superposition
over all the secret keys and this is
something where well we have 56 page
paper which is what I'm not going to try
to completely tell you about in the 20
minutes that I have I so look online on
quantum dot I saw Jenny org to see all
the details of that I will tell you a
little bit about the results try to get
you interested in reading the paper
another question that's not addressed in
this paper is what if you look at
communication costs or in general you
look at how much Hardware you're using
and how expensive is it really to run
that hardware for the amount of time you
need
which for a quantum computer means
you're constantly doing error correction
on all of your qubits how expensive is
that actual quantum computation and
that's that'll be another 50 pages to to
figure out in detail maybe the biggest
takeaway message that I want you to
remember and before I get into the
details of what kind of results we get
is that you can check these quantum
algorithms there's a lot of mistakes in
the algorithms literature generally and
maybe they pile up specially in the
quantum algorithms literature because
people don't have to actually verify
their results people don't have a
quantum computer and so they say I'm
sorry I didn't run the algorithm I've
just proven it's correct or maybe even
not that it seems like it's correct and
sorry I can't try it out I think that's
a cheap way out there's actually a bunch
of quantum algorithms that we can check
very confidently on our current
computers so what I want you to remember
is that you can verify the cost of a
quantum computation using your laptop
for instance in the particular quantum
computation that this paper is about we
have software go again to quantum
dodging or you can just download
software what exactly is it doing well
it's running at a quantum misogyny
computation well forget the quantum it's
running a nice arginine computation
using a sequence of bit operations and
xan doors and X ORS and nots and it also
counts how many nonlinear operations and
linear operations there are people
usually
with these because the costs are
different in traditional hardware the
linear operations are actually a little
more expensive in quantum hardware the
nonlinear operations are much more
expensive but anyway all of that is
tallied automatically by the software
and then what does this have to do with
a quantum computation well there's some
standard translations which say if you
can do bit operations for your
computation if you have a directed
acyclic graph of bit operations and then
you want to do a reversible computation
which constrains your bit operations you
can no longer create bits and erase bits
a reversible computation you can do
things like take 3 bits X Y Z and
replace them by X Y Z plus x times y so
override Z with Z plus the like Z X or
the end of X&Y and that's a reversible
operation that's called the toughly
operation and that is something that if
you do it again you get back to the
original input and there's a few of
these operations where those are the
basic operations you're allowed to use
in a reversible circuit instead of and
and/or an X or not and there's a
completely generic way to take the bit
operations and turn that into it most to
be reversible bit operations at the cost
of using a whole bunch of space I'll say
a bit more about that in a moment
once you have reversible operations then
you automatically get a bunch of quantum
operations to do the same computation on
a superposition of inputs and the factor
there is at most a factor of 7 for each
tally gate turning into what are called
T gates in quantum computation and you
can also look at the cost of the linear
operations and you get some smaller
factor for those and you can also try to
optimize these these you don't always
need seven times as many t gates it's
awfully gates you don't always need
twice as many toefl ease as ands and ORS
when you try to optimize these you might
save a well two or three bits in the in
the final runtime but we're much more
concerned with the big picture of 40
bits or 80 bits of or 128 bits of
security so okay there's some limited
factor there between the number of bit
operations you need and the number of
quantum gates you need there's more you
have to verify than just the operation
counts like maybe you care whether the
computation actually works whether it
computes lysogeny and that's something
where we have some sage scripts compare
to the output of these bid operations
it's really helpful to have your
computer running these computations so
you can just try and check we also have
some errors to speed up the computation
we limit the computation time to the
point where we have a noticeable number
of errors and that's something where we
had to do some generating function
computations to figure out what the
error rate should be and check that by
pumping up the error rate to something
we can measure by trying out the
computation and seeing how often it
works all right
case study to finish things off in last
4 minutes let me focus on Seaside 512 so
this is with 512 bit 64 byte public keys
how secure is this pre quantum it's
reasonably clear that all the algorithms
we know it's similar security to 256 bit
elliptic curves what about with this sub
exponential time attack well there's
some assumptions here about what the
group elements are that's this -5
through 574 integers between minus 5 3 5
and what error rate we're tolerating
where 2 to the minus 30 to might be good
enough for running Cupra Berg's
algorithm probably is good enough for
running Cooper Berg's algorithm and
under these assumptions if you count the
number of nonlinear bit operations
there's another paper which
independently had an algorithm for this
and we counted the number of bit
operations for that it's about 2 to the
50 bit operations which we optimized a
ton out of and got down to a 2 to the 40
and then well okay with even a little
more work our best result in the paper
zero point seven times two to the forty
bit operations nonlinear bit operations
to compute one seaside 512 group action
under these assumptions about how many
errors we're tolerating and how big the
inputs are all right if you translate
that from bit operations on the laptop
to what is the quantum computer going to
take then there's that factor of x 2 and
x 7 from the previous slide using a
whole bunch of qubits I said if you have
B but bit operations you suddenly need B
bits which means if you start with 2 to
the 40 bit operations you have about 2
to the 40 bits which turned into 2 to
the 40 cubits if you think that's a
crazy number of qubits you're probably
happier with you can at the expense of a
factor of 4 in the run time you can get
the number
it's down to two to the twenty which is
much more reasonable and actually even
if you can afford to to the 40 cubits
it's much more cost-effective to use a
bunch of separate two to the twenty
cubits for doing this four times as many
operations computation if you care about
the total gates which some of the papers
on this look at in quantum computations
the T gates are about a hundred times
more expensive than the linear gates but
we counted the total as well and it's a
little more than they two to the forty
five point three there it's up to two to
the forty six point nine all right if
you want variations in all these numbers
of course the paper gives lots of other
examples and all the software's you can
try different sizes yourself what does
this mean for the complete attack
against Eastside 512 this is my last
slide well one issue is how big those
inputs have to be issues of how you can
get a uniform group element it's hard to
do that inside the attack at least it
doesn't seem that the attack works if
you just use the minus five through five
the reason that we chose them is five
through five is an example is that's
what the seaside user does normally but
the attacker doesn't seem to get a work
in Cooper burg algorithm with that
there's another paper from bonito and
wrote lower which claims that you get
about a factor of four slow down from
dealing with us and they also claim that
you need about two to the thirty two
point five queries using about a billion
two billion cubits in order to do the
Cooper burg layer of the computation so
two to the thirty two point five times
two squared times the two to the forty
six point nine from the previous slide
gives you two to the 81.4 total gates
assuming that the the two claims here
are correct
maybe those are overly optimistic or
maybe there's some faster algorithms
than what they were talking about this
paper is just focusing on the the ratio
between like how expensive is each query
and then you also have to figure out the
number of queries etc if you count
communication costs then while this is
still using a huge number of qubits and
that's definitely going to make
everything more expensive because you
have to be error-correcting all those
qubits but we did not figure that out in
this paper finally let me comment on in
the bow Natasha wrote lowered paper they
say under the same assumptions that
actually it's only two to the seventy
Gate which comes from their being a
thousand times too optimistic about the
cost of doing the queries and we
identify where the basic points of
optimism are and save well this too to
the 71 is not something that with any
algorithm that we know it's possible to
achieve of course if you come up with
something better than maybe you can get
the two to the eighty-one down somewhat
below two to the eighty try to get even
below two to the 70 maybe it's possible
and then with your quantum computer and
2 to the 70 qubit operations on two to
the 31 or maybe even fewer qubits you
can break the 64 byte public key seaside
512 I hope I've gotten you interested in
the paper
if so look at quantum that I saw Jenny
org and take a look at the details
that's it thank you for your time
any questions so then you mentioned that
you didn't do the fault tolerant stuff
when you need 50 pages for that so
actually you don't need so much like we
we did this for char and and so on so
it's pretty straightforward
if you have the gate counts and I did it
now basically it for for you so I can
tell you some comfort well so let me be
clear about what the hard part is so I
agree that it's it's reasonably well
understood what the costs are for
instance doing the surface code if you
know what your error rate is at the
lowest level the problem is that all the
higher levels of the computation we have
not looked at what depth we need for
doing any of these computations so the
ISO Janee computations have some chunks
where we can parallelize it and some
chunks where it seems to be that we need
to do stuff serially and doing stuff
serially means that well you can figure
out with this number of qubits how long
you have to go but it's much more than
you want if we can find any sort of
parallelization then it makes it much
more effective when you do the while the
quantum volume the area times at the
time for your computation I agree that
the lowest level things are increasingly
well understood but at the higher levels
we did not try to optimize what the
depth is of the ice ogyny computation
for reversible or equivalently quantum
computation and that would be necessary
to really understand what the cost is if
you just do something naive and base it
on what's understood
levels that I think you'll be
overestimating the security Thanks
any other questions ok well let's thank
the speaker again
[Applause]