speaker yeah so now I'm going to talk
about some strengthening of what your
fault is this crime so decision work
with Andrew supplement Daniel weeks so
I'm going to look back at what I talked
before and what so pretty much what we
built is a design engineer for an Isaac
so just to take a step back we have a
proven every failure but now summer is
approaching so they remove their hat on
shaved so that's how they look now and
pretty much so so then there's a serious
in the sky and even this year as the
prover using your witness for first
eight months
there's only proved to be very fire and
then very very are using some special
verification key then decide to accept
all of the proof so what I'll be many
interested in during the sport is the
setup assumption that we make in
particular the setup solution that we
make that there is a magical entity that
both publishes a series in the sky but
also gives this secret it should verify
so in particular the setup is kind of
complex in the sense that the first
party has to interact with every
verifier that participates in protocol
and portrayal if there's many pairs of
say prove a verifier that wants to
participate then the trust setup has to
talk to every verifier so natural
question is to realize distress that our
assumption and to have something that is
much simpler and possible it would be
nice if we could make sense merchants
simply by using simple to set up a
vanity so what do i mean by that
so that actually defines someone
actually the notion of many shoes design
interior furnishings where the setup is
really just saris so there's a magic
arts restaurant easy that publishes a
series in the sky and after that can go
offline after that any verifier can just
look at this at the CRS and pick himself
a secret key so that will be his
verification key but now in some sense
the proof produced by the prover has in
different in some sense should this
verification key so what the Verena
she also picks a public key that depends
on this verification key and that's in
the sky so now given this yearís and
this public key any proven looking at
both can publish a proof and so generate
a pie and now the verify or dependent is
a verification he can decide to whether
accept or reject the proof so in popular
only the only chance we make it's
raining some in the setup in the setup
phase in some sense so the protocol
still has a strong flavor disunity
prefer an easy in the sense that for
incentive proof our privately verifiable
and there's no hope that this will be
easier to restrict Dianetics but at the
same time we don't want to shift the
threat of the trusted party to be very
fire and popular the very far would be
malicious for you know so what we want
is really to ensure that whenever the
very failure is malicious then security
holds on so in this case your knowledge
and popular the verifier can pick his
pair of keys maliciously but actually
from the point of view of the prover
it's not even clear that even any secret
key associated so what we really want is
that the 0h property holds given
arbitrary malashri generated public keys
and in that sense the security that we
get is much closer to the music and also
the setup in the sense that the only
thing we trust is really
that's a magical entity put a serious in
this guy just just a quick remark so
this is the notion of distinctive
measures isn't even for an easy core MTV
music and if I just reward our own
another way you can look at that is read
that we have some kind of true round a
zero knowledge protocol but what makes
it really interesting is that the first
the first message is reversible so that
really what gives this non interactivity
flavor oh yeah so now the natural
question is how do we build that so the
wrong map will follow pretty much
closely what Rafa talked about so Joe
Hodges showed that if we start with a V
porcinis
and if you start with a designated
verifier version of pure cheese you get
a divinization so naturally what I'll
focus here on words is to focus on
measures version of that and show that
pretty much that so fast is fun isak
sign how to build my MVP RG okay
so recall how do we use a TV PR g to
implement an easy engine
so here the prover which was a scene the
seed along with the service we define a
mini many random bits and the prover
will also have generate proofs that bits
are generated correctly so now to
implement the hidden beats the prover
was simply sent a short commitment to
the scene along with hidden bits and
local proofs that those bits are
generated honestly so this translates
directly to the malicious flavor were
the verifier now picks himself whiskey
and gives him gives publishes of public
in the sky oh yeah so now the only thing
that changes if the magic if the very
very honest everything is the same as
before
the only thing that changes is when the
profiles man issues and what we used for
charge with zero knowledge of the
designer forensic in the end is really
that when the prover give a local
opening through some bits the other bits
still remains hidden that's really what
makes the hidden bits journal go through
so we want that naturally to how it even
maliciously generated public keys and
it's not too hard to show that pretty
much the syntactical I think didn't
change the proof on meditatively PRG
implies maltose divinities so now we
reduce the problem of constructing MDV
disease through the program of
construction
Malchus so mtv PR geez so the natural
step is how do you construct that so let
me recall briefly the you know like side
you rephrase the construction of roof oh
and a natural question is to check
whether the confession we gave before
natively satisfies the property
so again you have a seed like a
commitment receipt that will just just
be a creeper element and s will be the
seed that is chosen by the by the
approver and this is the same as a in
Reverse dog so in the series there's a
lot of different group elements tráfico
that GGI and pretty much you define
those hidden piece to simply be those
group elements in the series raised yes
so now there's also another part in a
series that allows you to check whether
those bits have been generated quietly
and part even or you have some group
elements that that help you prove that
pretty much s1 and G have the same
discrete log in some sense so from far
talked about the dirt twinsies - shake
another which we see is that we actually
have a design intent very failure newzik
for kind of digital age and that's
exactly crime ership so that just
another way to look at it oh yeah so now
we can directly change we can daringly
change the syntax to handle verifier
that picked up a blue key that will be
the part that allows them to prove out
of the prover to prove whether the bits
are correct and now what we want is that
some kind of resilience whenever those
group elements are generated maliciously
so say the the failure wants to attack
the first hidden beats well a natural
thing to do so in patchwork you won't
get the proof for the first beat but a
very easy thing to do is to simply
rewire so in fact you are given the
Sierras you can just set the last
elements of office public it should be
the Seminole man as the first bit of the
Sierras
not even how the profits actually just
receiving the proof directly reveals the
first bit so it seems like very easy we
broke it pretty easily so is a hop
lowest well it turns out we can fit that
so much easily and how do we fix that
will simply make all the hidden bits
depend on many more group elements
so what do I mean by that now we will
have many many more group elements that
the number of hidden bits that we want
in the end and what we will do is simply
to pitch some random graph and now every
every hidden bit with dependent many
random different basically elements okay
so how well and also like to check the
proofs now we need to give the quite
appropriate krupa demonstrated yes so
how does it help us well I was supposed
to again that the verifier wants to
learn something about the first hidden
beads now with high probability over the
graph well so first she has to actually
recover if we procure some your favorite
hardcore B's let's recover all those
groupie remonstrated yes if you want to
do anything meaningful and in particular
over the randomness of the graph there's
at least some group elements that does
not appear anywhere in the other hidden
beads that the very first to learn if
you want to learn anything about the
hidden bit so in particular for the
simple mix-and-match attack that I
described before you can also argue that
for sufficiently high number of group
based group elements that was that's
also happen so if the very firm manage
is true this to do anything meaningful
with the first hidden beats you will she
can actually compute some hods like by
itself so that sounds we made progress
but again that's us simply for very a
very restricted class of attacks so what
we show is that actually if we pick this
run on graphene especially careful way
you can actually prove security against
any any other sort strategy for the any
malicious very failure under a stronger
assumption let's go to one more
situation sumption so it's like you're
one more version of CH and that will
directly give the militia dignity prefer
an Isaac from one message so next shoe
is going to talk about compact
processing is it says so