thank you go I'm good morning my name is
Katia to Emma of from entity and she is
chica yoshimura from ATT communications
and as you know ntt communications are
providing the global internet services
with various and also Oh in Japan we are
providing the internet services called
ocn and as a basic service and as a
basic infrastructure we provide the DNS
cache servers for our content for our
customers about these days we have
sometimes we have an experiences of a
heavy load of the of those cache servers
so today we would like to talk about our
experiences of the heavy load of the cat
suburb and result of the analysis and
lessons learned okay and as you know the
DNS world oh there there are several
players these players and categorized
into the 30 the application or operating
system on the user devices and on the
user side and it is a code and stop
resolve odd sometimes and secondly the
authoritative servers including DNS
servers TLD servers and go as you know
the DNS cache servers provided by ISPs
or universities and I was a kind of book
impact how do to a DNS anomalies or
people are focusing on the DNS resolvers
button as I'd mentioned also the DNS
cache servers or sometimes suffers that
kind of a burden opted heavy low okay so
the burden of the DNS cache servers
sometimes caused by misconfigured dls
authoritative servers the length
delegation is well known but other
factors exist as well so today we would
like to talk about our two experiences a
one lesson the coast by one is that
caused by viruses warm activities and
the other is a large resource step and
the TCP filling the first first is
presented by me and the second part will
be presented by a scuffle so let's go
into the first part of the presentation
and in the United States and in the
globally the my Duke was oh that was my
do one of the one person the war okay
the my dog attacks SEO website and some
species attacks Microsoft website when
my room is activated our it got it all
it's going to resolve that this name of
the website into an IP address and we
also have Antony in Japan which attacks
attacks Oh hccs JP we call xjp the
website the arts DB is abbreviated up
from association of a copyright or
computer software and this organization
is watching that illegal copy of the
computer software an acne is a word that
is an effect of famous Japanese p2p
software waiting and some Swiss
subspaces subspecies of Antony attacks
xdp website on the first monday of the
month and when trying when they try to
connect a website it resolved
fqdn double double double axe JP or JP
so when the Anthony is activated of
course you know the details attacks
going through her or the ESPYs network
and the target website is under attack
and access line is filled with Adidas
packets and the backbone is also
sometimes L filled with the dealer's
packet and indeed in this case the order
of the website Oh removes the a record
of the target website ok to avoid the
attack from the affected users and in
April the kwenda and when Anthony attack
the odor of the website remove the a
record from authoritative server at the
time the query is sent to a DSS cache
servers and return of the NX domain from
the authoritative server and the ants
the Edisto mate is also return to what
what the user but there is no IP address
so the worms cannot attack the website
so that the order of the website is
can't escape from the dealer's attack
but the query because then they cannot
get the IP address of the target website
they repeat it that clearing to the camp
our cache servers so therefore the DHS
our DNS servers the so-called heavy load
ok so the Y dns guess overall it a
result record removed from author david
solvers and NH domain was returned and
it's TTL was short and 60
and as I mentioned warmth repeatedly
said carries even if they could not
solve resolve the name the highest was
approximately 700 queries per second
from a one IP address this seems to us
that the negative cash did not to be did
not a negative cash are not effective in
some operating system or application so
someone how they can- just disabled at
any time I don't know that exactly so
but we have to fix it quickly because
then our DNS cache servers are on a
heavy load okay so we prepared a fake
zone and forth to the forward to for the
queries to that to devote to this sobber
ok so the query not going to an author
JD summer and this wakes all return the
black hole IP address and also we
prepare the routers which which had a
black hole in our network so the packets
destined to the back hole IP address or
discarded at the robert at our routers
so the target of website l can escape
from the dealers attack and also we can
get our BS cache servers will reduce the
load and this worked very well in an
april attack so we decided to use this
attack this method again in May and this
graphs show the total queries at our DNS
cache hoppers and the top graph is that
every attack and the bottom is an attack
in May and Wendy this began and the
order of the website removes the areas
a record the number of the number of the
oil eclairisse are increased very
dramatically but then when returning the
black hole address the number of the
clearest are reduced to an ANOVA and at
the time we we capture the DNS package
and I like those packets personally and
this was a graph of the may attack and
please be careful about an y axis y axis
is an logarithm scale so the spite of
this too despite indicates an extremely
large number of queries and during the
day made third oh we had a much more
curious than usual okay and we arised
the correspondence between the answer of
the DNS and number of the queries hello
to that to read the result that fqdn of
the italian west harbor this graph shows
when an S domain returned the number of
the queries to resolve the fdd n is
dramatically increasing and after
returning the black hole address that
navajo the queries are becomes known
exactly normal okay and i'll skip the
side and in april and in May we have
this we have succeeded to reduce the DNS
servers so we collaborate other ISPs in
June to defend this attack we prepared
our own black hole address and
encourage high speeds to use the black
hole address and also encourage eyes
peas to set the black hole of that
outlet in their national network and we
also asked the owner of the website to
return the black hole addressed we
prepared so the queries to our cache
servers and return the black hole
address robin DNS authoritative servers
and were going to attack to the black
hole address button those maggots were
discarded at the at the router of the
participating ISPs ok so the lessons
learned from this attack is removing a
resource record is not a good method the
combination of behavior warrants stop
live elbows user and author the
discovers or sometimes cause DNA DNS
cache server to collapse and the
collaboration between victims and isp is
required ok and if we can have if we
have the generate black hole addresses
and isp said the derrick black hole
addresses to their routers the the owner
of the author daily server has only to
do return the generate black hole
address to escape from the details
attack so I think we think that then
some kind of generic black hole address
is necessary ok so oh this is the first
part of the presentation so next going
to a thicker part syllogism please
good morning everyone I'm chica
yoshimura working at ntt communications
cooperation in Japan and we operate
operate ocl an ISP in japan in june we
found that they might have been in
adequate setup of an authoritative dns
server which meant our cash dns server
overloaded in order to alleviate the
overload on our server we took a couple
of approaches in this presentation I am
going to briefly explain what the
program was what causes what causes the
program and how we solve it the program
here when we say overloaded women high
cpu utilization caused by an MD Damon
recently one of our cash DNS servers
suddenly became terribly overloaded we
found that observer tried to establish
tcp sessions with an authoritative dns
server which failed three day handshake
at the scene center state why did our
server try to establish TCP session with
also native server as you know dns
servers try to communicate with other
DNS servers for UDP except in special
cases at that point we didn't know why
our server came up against this
situation usually the number of DC
positions is around five in our church
server but in this case we found around
120 outstanding connection attempts the
numbers too
compared to the usual from investigation
we concluded that the package is
kissable caused the increase of TCP
sessions as you can see in these
brothels they seemed to synchronize with
each other as you know TC or truncated
truncated bit is set to in responses
when entire set of resource records can
be accommodated in one UD be pocket now
what happened to our server let's look
at the next slide and the users directed
queries to our cache server then the
server perform the recursion and finally
asked the oh sweet eight observer this
auction is described ro it described
with other one but in this situation
because the answers from the
authoritative server didn't fit in the
512 octaves payload size limit the
entire unser couldn't be accommodated in
one UDP packet the server returned the
pocket with kiss a bit and required I'll
cache server to ask again using TCP this
auction is this action is described with
autotune consequently our cache server
queried the authoritative server to get
unsub HTTP pockets however they also
taking salvors seemed to reject the tcp
queries this action are indicated by
arrow 3 although the cancer but right
justjust server try to retransmit
queries by tcp our server could not get
any answers from the authoritative
server the cache server waited for about
seven
five seconds and ended up with time out
for you if there are five authoritative
server or with one domain a cache server
repeated the same operation five times
even if one of authoritative server is
able to accept TCP queries al-sabah can
get the answer from the authoritative
server the reason for increased infinity
suppositions was that our server kept
bleach retransmitting queries by tcp
despite the fact that these accesses
were rejected by other side while our
selves are rated for the responses it
kept returns maintained query it was
meeting TCP queries as a result our
server was overloaded an example all
contents on packets is shown in the next
slide but I will skip detailed
explanation and going to talk about all
of our work ground after the trouble we
took some actions to attenuate the
impact of these suppositions also we
amend several times the administrator of
the domain to accept TCP connections or
reduce the name recalls the rain recalls
to fit and 512 octet they still have not
answered our request until today while
we waited while we waited for their
action our server was gradually getting
overloaded and battery affecting all our
internet users using oracle server to
avoid this situation to become worse we
used the option block
hole on the cache server in order to
reject the queries from the users that
caused our cache server to be overloaded
if our goal is just to keep the server
low load level there is another possible
approach we could modify buying the code
on our server so that it won't send a
query bug when truncation of course
meanwhile it attains a survey response
back to end users both this approach and
the action we took which was the black
hole use of queries are effectively 208
the overload on chest server however
this approaches do not our cache server
to solve its own purposes akasava should
a cache server should respond to queries
with right information and also negative
Sarah is expected to configured as
suggested an RFC in order to avoid
future occurrences of the same problem
with suggests that every DNS
administrators reveal their dns servers
configuration regarding this program
there seem to be the three level in
points we think one open tcp port 53 for
tcp queries RFC 1123 recommends
answering tcp queries it's not possible
to open tcp port 53 and because of some
special reasons we strongly recommend
that are stl reset the packet should be
returned and to when possible set the
size of answer to be smaller than
512 all stats or three support ed nl0 on
your dns server you support this we can
get answer over 512 upstairs from what
they also entail give dns server result
tcp connections thank you so the record
oh yeah Oh through our experiences oh
please feed friendly to a DNS cache
servers so Adam these traitors please
check then modify the settings of the
authoritative service and instead of
using removing air whistles record in
case of details please use some black
hole address and ave and from the second
experiences please configuration should
be a compilation should be consistent
oversized result sets or no ed n 0 and
cross tcp port is not good but we can
often see this same thing ok thank you
very much
we we have time for a few questions I'm
going to ask Phillip Phillip Phillip has
oh I thought you had left the building
are you are you prepared okay we will
take a few questions my name is Spencer
donk inside a question about the TCP
filtering with a large are are set that
query would have failed for anyone
trying to be okay I guess what I'm
asking is you had your you were talking
to an ad man who wouldn't reduce the
size of the ya-ya are sad but would it
was that was that query working for
anyone oh yeah oh wait boy past Dora Oh
Adam is ready to reduce or open the tcp
port and oh it may it may affect all of
the users I think the answer is at the
other side now you just did oh yeah okay
so okay just like like holding was the
right thing to do yeah
hi I'm Sam Wyler many Rob Thomas is in
the room because you may want to get up
and answer this for your proposal that
you use a well-known black hole address
I'm wondering what happens if you play
that out a few more steps do the
miscreants change their code to detect
your black hole address and just have
their coat fall over and die do they
quit using the DNS entirely where does
that play out oh you mean that the oh
you think of Derek black hole address
cause another attack for when you use a
well known address the attacker will
know that also another site
hi Bill hi this is me speaking Japanese
or not as the case may be yeah using
well known addresses is a bad idea don't
do it if you can get away with it if you
can't get away with it you're you're in
trouble having honey pots and other
other such things to catch people is you
know it it's part of the arsenal of
things that you have so if you have a
quote unquote well-known black hole
address and people find it you're going
to have to move it eventually because
they will know people will find it out
but this is a technique one at one
technique that has been demonstrated to
work in today's environment will it work
five years from now probably not or at
least it won't be as effective but there
are i mean the IAB and the IETF people
have come out and said use of well known
addresses this is probably a bad idea so
this one works now thank you see more
questions
um okay thank you very much thank you
very much