right thank you very much so it is the
the universally applied rule of thumb
that the buffer of a router needs to be
2t times C where 2t is the two-way
propagation delay of a flow through the
router and C is the capacity of the
bottleneck Lane
often we don't know exactly what the
wrong hood time go through Robert is so
what people will do is they'll simply
assume it's 150 milliseconds this rule
is mandated in many RFPs for backbone
and edge routers there's at least one
hour seat from the ITF it's usually the
reference where this rule comes from is
usually a paper we will own a siren song
called highest performance TCP and
am-ness net high performance at that
time and about 40 megabits per second
and up to 4 flows so times have changed
a little since then this rule of thumb
also has major consequences for router
design and let me just give a very
simple example if today your router
manufacturer and you want to build a 10
megabit line card the rule of thumb
tells you that you need about 300
megabytes worth of buffering and what's
worse yeah to this memory you have to
read and write from into this memory to
read and write a packet every 32
nanoseconds now the amount of memory
alone is not a problem 300 megabytes you
can go to the local electronics store
and buy that for approximately hundred
dollars the problem is the normal DRAM
that you can buy there is much too slow
to be accessed at these feeds you could
instead trying to use SRAM with astron
you need about 80 devices which will
pretty much cover most of the space on
your own your light heart and it'll also
cost about $2,000 and worst of all it'll
generate about one kilowatt worth of
heat one kilowatt per line card is
probably more than your local data
center can anticipate so you can't sort
of need either of the two approaches
worked and this is a 10 gigabits per
second so if you go to 40 gigabits per
second the problem it becomes much
charter people that proposed a variety
of solutions are LTR mfc ram funneling
architectures with extremely wide buses
but I think it's safe to say that for
today's of our vendors building the
memory architectures for these high-end
line carts remains a major challenge so
in this talk I want to convince you that
the rule of thumb for sizing Rado
buffers that is universally applied is
wrong and that is wrong by about a
factor of 100 I'll first tell you where
originally the rule of thumb came from
and then why for a robbery the core of
the Internet today no longer holds so
the reason for the rule of thumb is the
congestion control mechanism of TCP so
I'll briefly sort of recap TCP which
many of you might might know by heart
but for those who don't how it works and
then sort of explain and drive to go at
them TCP controls it's sending rate by a
congestion window W and it has a very
simple rule that says at any given time
I may send W packets but then I have to
wait for acknowledgments before I can
send any additional packets at any given
time I may only have W packets
outstanding so if W is 3 I can send 3
packets then I wait until
acknowledgments come in it also has a
rule for updating the window size and a
congestion avoidance mode which is the
most part which should be the mode of
long live TCP flows this rule for
updating W is that whenever I receive an
acknowledgment that a packet was
successfully transmitted to the
destination I may increase my window
size by 1 over W so if my window size is
3 I increase my window size by 1/3 if a
packet is lost I have my window size so
if I win the previous owner size is 10 I
go down to window size file the result
of that is the TCP sawtooth shown at the
bottom here which I think everyone is
familiar with now let's have a look how
this works in practice so what we have
here is a TCP flow from a sender to the
left to receiver on the right through a
router in this case this router does not
have any buffering
the the link to the right of the router
is our bottleneck link and one of the
goals we have for router is to fully
utilize this bottleneck link so that's
why I'm showing the utilization there
keep an eye on that utilization
currently a window size is one which is
successfully transmitted one packet we
increase our window size by 1 over 1 so
by one and now I have a window size of 2
so we're sending out 2 packets and here
at the bottom you can see the plot of
the current window size let me eat this
up a little bit here we now have two
packets outstanding both are
successfully transmitted so the window
size is increased to 3 if you look at
the utilization the utilization is less
than 100% and it's immediately clear why
this is the case currently we just don't
have enough packets in flight here to
fully utilize this link all of the time
so this is an important observation that
the window size of TCP sender must have
a certain minimum value in order to
fully saturate a link I'm going to speed
this up now and let's see what happens
when we have actually enough pattern in
a large enough window size to fully
utilize the link so window sizes 7
window size 8 so if window size 8 we now
have the link is fully utilized all of
the time
it still shows utilization 95 percent
but this is just because it's almost
raining a little bit now the problem is
that what will happen the next time my
sender increases its window size by 1
when huge pieces has window size by 1
it'll send this one extra packet this
packet can no longer fit anywhere on the
link because visibly all the link is not
occupied with packets it also can't fit
in the router buffer because there is no
auto Parker so here comes the extra
packet it gets dropped as expected this
drop information in the form of a
missing sequence number is now traveling
to the recipient and then back to the
sender and we know what the what the
sender will do and it receives the drop
information it will have its window size
and when it has its window size from 10
to 5 it'll now have more packets
outstanding than it made so stop sending
for swath while and then start with
resume sending again but only with 5
packets outstanding so here's the drop
window size gets reduced to 5 now has 10
packets I'll send you it may only have 5
parts and stop sending for a while
and after a short while just start
sending again here we go so but now it's
ending with windows science 5 which
again is insufficient to fully utilize
the bottleneck link and this will
basically repeat itself again and again
again we get this we get a sawtooth to
summarize if we have an unbuffered link
our window size will below the threshold
that's necessary in order to maintain
full utilization of the bottleneck link
most of the time whenever it touches
that point where actually the link is
fully utilized it'll scale down again
and the link will not be utilized you
can actually run the map here and it
turns out they can still get 75% link
utilization without any buffering but
you cannot move with a single TCP flow
75% of utilization is the maximum you
can get now let's look what happens if I
have a router that has a sufficient
amount of buffering so we have the same
experiment as before but this time we
have a buffer in the router and as you
can see the queue fills with packets and
then the packets get sent out one by one
we start with the window size of 5 and
as we've seen before 5 is not sufficient
to fully utilize the bottleneck link so
let's speed this up and see what happens
when a window size is large enough to
fully utilize link if utilization 70%
80% 90% at this point the link is fully
utilized all of the time what happens
when the window sizes increase when this
extra packet isn't here's one of these
extra packets this extra Packer could
not be put anywhere on the link so it
gets stored in the router in in the
router buffer so the role of the router
buffer here really is to absorb these
occasional extra packets which which no
longer fit on the link and prevent the
window from scaling down because of the
packet drop prematurely so here we see
another here's another extra packet and
again the queue length and water
increases by 1 because of the extra
packet this will continue to be that way
until the the buffer queue the the
ridiculous hole so we have about two
spaces remaining one space remaining
and now the buffer queue is full so the
next time an extra packet is sent by the
sender will see a drop and the the
sender will will have its window size so
at sixteen point eight sixteen point
nine here's the extra packet extra
packets is also it gets dropped the drop
information again as a missing sequence
number travels through the queue to the
recipient and back to the sender what
the sender will do is the sender will
again half its window size stop sending
for short period of time because now it
has more packets outstanding than it may
and then resume sending but on with with
half the window size that it had before
so here it stopped sending but during
the time that stopped sending the link
is still serviced by the packet from the
from the router queue and basically just
from the first packet from the from the
sender arrives at the router again the
queue is empty so we have hundred
percent utilization all of the time also
our minimal window size so the window
size after the drop was about eight
point five which is sufficient to fully
utilize the link so we have 100% link
utilization all of the time so to
summarize the case of a buffered link on
a fully buffered link the window size is
always above the threshold that is
necessary to fully fill the link with
packets at any given time so we have a
hundred percent link utilization all the
time the reason why the window size is
high enough is that when the window
grows above the threshold that is that
is necessary has the link full with
packets the extra packets get buffered
by the router buffer so the role of the
router buffer here is as you can see in
the upper graph to basically absorb
these fluctuations in the window size of
TCP so how much buffering do we need we
need enough to buffer in order to fit
the sawtooth of TCP if TCP wouldn't have
a sawtooth we wouldn't need
buffering and router or we need at least
much much less power and this is the
origin of the rule of thumb you plug in
the numbers and if you're interested in
the math there's a signal publication
from this year that has the equations it
actually turns out that you need exactly
two T times C that the the height of the
Sawtooth is exactly is exactly two T
times C
so to summarize the rule of thumb makes
sense for one flow now the routers that
you here in the room are all operating
have more than one flow they typically
have the thousands or ten thousands of
close so the question is if we go up by
four orders of magnitude does the rule
of thumb still hold the answer is if the
Falls are perfectly synchronized then
the rule of thumb still holds it's a
falsity synchronized then the rule of
thumb doesn't hold this brings me to the
second part which is what is the correct
amount of buffering that's needed for
router for congested bottom and the
result will be that it's to G times C so
are all rule of thumb divided by the
square root of the number of drugs so if
we have more than one flow going through
a router the role of the rather buffer
is to absorb the fluctuation in the
total number of outstanding jackets so
instead of absorbing one single sort
that now has to visibly absorb the sum
of all these salty if the flows are
perfectly synchronized we basically hit
a small salty that add up to one large
sort hood so we have exactly the same
dynamics of the Alpha of the number of
outstanding packets that we have for
single flow we also have the same buffer
occupancy that we have for single flow
so the rule of thumb steroids if those
are not synchronized it is more
complicated here we have the bottom
shown two clothes that are not
synchronized so basically we now have a
slightly randomized I'm sorry and the
sum of these randomized salty what we
expect to see is some kind of
statistical multiplexing we can make a
very simple quantitative argument here
and I'll spare you the math again if
you're interested it's in the paper but
if we assume that each of the window
sizes the window size of each flow is an
independent random variable then the
central limit theorem tells us if we
take the sum of independent random
variables
it should converge to loss the Gaussian
distribution does anyone remember that
so that's something which you can very
easily verify so we taken a network
simulation mode with NS tool we plot the
probability distribution of the sum of
the window sizes
and we did that and what you actually
get is something that looks pretty much
like a boss so in this case this will
just was for a hundred mega building
with it with a thousands of those well
about a thousand applause so how much
buffering do we need in this case we
said the role of the buffer is to absorb
these fluctuations in the total number
of outstanding packets the probability
distribution of these out saying a
number of packets is dislodged so we
presently want to pick a buffer that
will bracket our gosh
so that'll busily big enough to fit the
Gaussian most of the time so the
probability of so many packets being
outstanding that we're above our buffer
and we get drops as small and the
probability of so Q the packets
outstanding that we below the buffer and
effectively don't under percent
utilization is also small and the the
central limit theorem also tells us that
the the more variables we have the more
statistical multiplexing and the
narrower the portion gets the width of
the Gaussian decreases the one over
square root of n as you can look up in
most math books so the the buffer size
which is necessary to to bracket the
width of this dorsum also decreases of 1
over the square root of n we know the
battle for single flow was 2t times C
we've seen before that for single flow
the rule of thumb still holds so the
amount of buffering required for for n
flows should be 2t times C divided by
the square root of n so what I'm saying
here is that actually the more flows you
have the less buffer you need things is
about the only thing and networking that
gets better the more the more clients
here at your serving and again there's
something which you can very easily
verify using an NS 2 simulation we have
on the x-axis here the the number of
flows and on the y-axis the minimum
buffer that we found basically
iteratively so we just rerun the
experiment until we found the buffer
size that would guarantee as 95% quickly
we can see that the the red dots which
is our simulation fit very well on our
model of 2t times C over square root of
n which is the Green Line so to
summarize for congested router
flows in the coffin
or argue synchronized there's plenty of
experimental evidence for that and also
if you run a network simulation once you
get enough flows they do synchronize and
for disorganized long will it flows you
need only buffers of 2t times C over
square root of n now we said before n is
something like 10,000 so what I'm
telling you here is that if you take
your current Robert today and switched
off 99% of the buffering it'll run
better you don't need to change anything
the protocols any other external network
parameters but basically this will still
be sufficient in order to absorb
fluctuations in the total number of
outstanding packets it'll also reduce
your over the overall latency of flows
through the router in case of congestion
and then we have later some experiments
to back up that claim now so far we were
assuming that we have a congested router
with long live flows you might wonder
what happens if we have flows a slow
start
the majority of flows in the network
actually are typically short-lived flows
for example web traffic that only sends
a few packets before the flow terminates
these flows never get out of slows I've
never get into this congestion avoidance
mode and do in that case buffer
requirements differ and the answer is
yes you actually need even less power
unfortunately if you mix long live flows
and short-lived flows as you have it in
a real network the effect from the long
live flows dominates and even if only
10% in a typical Network today probably
something like 80 90 percent of your
packets are from long live flows in the
congestion avoidance mode even if it was
only 10% still the long live flows what
dominates was the very very small
percentage of long live flows is
sufficient in order to to have the long
live law affect dominate your buffer
requirements but if you have a router
where you know this part has never
congested you never have any long live
flows then you can actually get away
with even smaller buffers so in slow
start TCP has a different way of
updating its congestion window it'll
start out with a congestion window of
two and then basically double this
congestion window for each window worth
of data that was successfully
transmitted so TCP world's first sent
two packets and four packets eight
packets sixteen packets
two packets the distance between these
bursts being one RTT I'll spare you the
the mathematical model that that sort of
the to model these smart close
especially a human theoretical model we
can with this model calculate things
like loss rate average queue length or
the flow completion time so the time
from starting in flow to ending on flow
the complete models in the paper here's
just a brief overview what the what the
result means what we've plotted here is
the average queue length you're gonna
see in your router if you only have
short clothes and at the bottom we have
the flow length and packets so assume we
have only flows of length 20 20 packets
which would be probably be like a small
web page then the the queue the average
queue length you would see is only ten
packets this depends on what load you
have near entre this is assuming a load
of 80% which is already fell behind the
important thing to take away here is not
so much what the exact quantitative
relationship is but 15 or 20 or 30
packets worth of buffering is all an
extremely small buffer you today robbers
took we have thousands of 10,000 packets
high in progress
other results from the Swart flow model
most importantly the buffering
requirements only depend on the length
of the bursts and in the load they do
not depend on the line speed and the rtt
to give an example if you have bursts of
up to size 16 and a lot of 80% for 1%
loss probability mu 115 packets worth of
buffering if you double that buffer you
get another factor of hundred smaller
loss probability so there's can edit if
increase here and amount of buffering
will give you an exponential decrease in
the amount of probability versus of size
16 might seem small at a first glance
but for example Windows XP usually
doesn't scale it's a window size above
12 packets so this is actually a fairly
realistic number but the most important
takeaway is that all this doesn't does
the the amount of buffering put of these
short clothes that you need does not
scale with the line speed so if you
build a Mon megabit router or 40 gigabit
router
as long as it serves the same type of
traffic and just more of it the amount
of buffering you need does not change
and what this means is that the amount
of buffering you get you need for the
long flows which increases with the
bandwidth usually dominate is the
dominant of the of the two effects so I
now want to show you what happens if you
actually try this out with simulation
and real physical networks so this is a
comparison of three things the model of
a simulating our model with a bow first
of all our quantitative model supposedly
just using the formula that I just
presented simulation is of a network
using ns2 and experiment on the real
physical assist code GSR auto with OC OC
3 line parts that's a very old place the
engine 0 so the we have um we repeated
this line this experiment for us 400
flows and for 400 flows and then we
picked router buffer sizes of 2t times C
over square root of n half of that two
times that and three times that's just
to get an idea for sort of the
elasticity how exactly does it depend on
the amount of traffic that you have you
can see in the the numbers to the right
that there's probably good agreement
between model simulation and experiments
about two things a LED with two T times
C over square root of n sized buffers
you can achieve very close to hundred
percent utilization if you have four
hundred flows actually a hundred percent
utilization then 99.9 the experiment is
probably a statistical error it also
shows that the model roughly predicts
correctly at which point utilization
will drop from hundred percent to
something below hundred percent so this
formula of 2t times G over square root
of n in a laboratory experiment with
traffic that we generated ourselves does
actually work we also tested our short
flow model so this shows the probability
distribution that the Q exceeds a
certain length on a router so we have
the probability on the on the y axis in
logarithmic scale and the the cooling
on the x-axis and we can see that the
model which is the blue line fits very
well with two sets of experimental data
which is the red and the green line that
is if you shift the data by 42 packets
and at first this puzzle does lock there
was no we didn't see any good reason why
we would always underestimate the queue
length divided by 40 two packets but
then we started running numbers and 42
packets or forty three packets
corresponds to 65 kilobytes of data and
so we were thinking maybe there
somewhere is a hidden memory here of 65
kilobytes that we that is not documented
the router documentation that we can't
measure if there's some additional
buffering of that size would explain
what we always measure a queue length
that's all okay so we actually I
contacted the manufacturer and find
found the person who who build the wine
cart and they told us yes it's actually
true in the end the interface management
chip there's a 64 kilobyte buffer and
with this offset the the theory in the
experiment
I imagine extremely well so we decided
to go one step further and try this out
with with live traffic with real users
so so far the experiment the exponent of
the GSR that we did was basically an
idealized set up in the laboratory so we
only had long lived clothes we had very
controlled traffic we only had TCP but
we have we had real pc's with real TCP
stacks in this experiment we took a live
production network while it was running
throttled the bandwidth until we got
congestion and then we'd use the buffer
size to see when utilization would fall
below hundred-percent and big thanks to
Leah Roberts sunayana Gunsan from
Stanford for allowing us to do that and
it turns out that with small multiples
of 2 T times cos square root of n which
is shown here in there in the second
column we can get in the experiment
there so the rightmost column on
utilizations that are very close to 100%
so even for traffic that's a mix of
long-lived flows short-lived flows UDP
traffic probably occasional denial of
service attack or something like that
even the sort of this is much more
diverse traffic makes this rule still
holds fairly well we also tried this on
on the Internet to research network so
the we took the link from Indianapolis
to Kansas this is a ten gigabits per
second link served by a PI to Juniper T
six 40s on each end the default buffer
of the Juniper is about one second we
and on this link we have occasional test
wells of one gigabit per second for TCP
flow of one gigabit per second with
normal TCP we need very very small loss
probabilities some somewhere in the
order of ten to the minus eight
so this is extremely stringent and have
loss criteria we have to fulfill here so
the the first experiment a buffer size
to ten millisecond or one percent of the
default nothing happened five
milliseconds still nothing happened the
next step is two milliseconds or so the
experiment is ongoing but so far there
was basically nothing that there was to
observe the test flows would still have
the full utilization we would not see
any packet drops on the link even with
these with these small buffers and
thanks to just a special enough and ok
arm so it helped make that happen
so to summarize the old rule of thumb
for how much buffer a router needs is
one delay bandwidth product and there's
still certain cases which this rule
holds first of all if you have a single
flow that should be able to saturate
your router at full speed then you still
need a buffer of twenty times see if for
a single flow you can live with 75% of
the utilization then actually you can
you can use much smaller buffers so if
you want to set for example a new speed
record
large buffers might might still be
necessary however if you're serving many
flows even if you have congestion then
you only need buffers of 2 T times C
over square root of N and we believe
this is applicable for the core and the
edge of the network today if you have
one or many flows and you have no
congestion and you know there never will
be congestion on this router then you
can actually get away with even smaller
buffers something the order of hundred
maybe 200 packets it's fairly
independent of line speed it just
depends on how close you want to get
your load to to a one I mean again this
is only for include gestured routers so
if your load goes above one you'd busily
be back in the upper case but this only
works if you know your honor will never
be congested and which probably for for
real network is not putting particularly
sensible architectural and design
guidelines so the link goes down or
something like that you you might get
fantastic so this change has a fairly
large impact on router design if you
have a 10 gigabit link line card serving
200,000 modem flows which sort of is the
last generation of line cards then the
rule of thumb tells you you need two
point five gigabits worth of buffer
memory which would it require external
slow d ram with a new rule of thumb this
buffer now becomes 6 megabits 6 megabits
you can easily put not only in SRAM but
put an on-chip SRAM so you don't need
any external RAM devices for buffering
anymore at all for 40 Gigabit LAN card
with 40,000 a broadband flows we still
need the the reductions from 10 gigabits
to 50 megabits of buffer memory 50
megabits today is just slightly too
large to put it on ship but the people
who understand how to build these things
tell me that in the next generation of
of chip design it should be possible to
fit something that order of magnitude on
the chips directly I think currently you
can do 30 2 megabits on SRAM chip but
the next generation you will be able to
do 64 so that buffer also puts go back
on the rocket ship and with that I thank
you if anyone wants to know once you
have more information we have a lot more
experimental data and and all the math
there's paper on our homepage and I have
a question over here
have you noticed in your experiments any
any reduction in latency along with
reducing the length of the queue and it
or the buffer and is that significant
enough to be another good argument for
doing this yes absolutely um I didn't
touch on that but the if you have
buffers of one delay bandwidth product
right your your maximum queuing delay is
the amount of buffering you have divided
by a line speed so if it's two T times C
divided by C so your maximum queuing
delay is 2t which means in case of
congestion the latency through the
router will just be twice what it is
without congestion so effectively the
the existing rule of thumb sort of
doubles doubles latency in case of
congestion with a new rule of thumb you
get to the the increases percent or
something like that over the the latency
with without congestion so we have a
much much smaller increase even more
interestingly me one of the questions
that came up is with if we have smaller
buffers we might get a little bit more
loss so for example does this perch it's
a short flows in mixes of course if we
have long flows and short close to short
posts suffer from smaller buffers and
turns out no they actually because the
the much shorter RTT through the through
the router outweighs any any longer for
long to turn due to losses or timeouts
by an order of magnitude so if you have
short the smaller buffers basically in
case of congestion your shot flows will
take half the time or or close to half
the time to complete thank you
it's very interesting hi Scott Marcus
the very interesting piece of work
I was curious since in the comparisons
between the the theoretical simulated
and actual results all the numbers are
pretty close to unity I assume your
sample sizes were probably pretty large
I was wondering about the confidence
intervals so let me see which which of
the slides were you referring to it's
different for different ones so for the
for the Stanford experiments the biggest
problem was estimating the number of
concurrent flows so busy hour N and n is
only in a square root so we're not
particularly sensitive to miss
estimating that although there we we're
not particularly precise we
be off by as much as a factor of 1.5 or
two okay thank you in the in the other
experiment here we're much much more
precise because we could could control
the setup so here would say we're
probably within dot one percent or two
percent okay so your confidence interval
on each of the individual percentages
you're saying is probably within one
without one or two percent yes that's
great okay thank you did you give any
consideration to how routers
prioritizing cues for example weighted
fair queuing or a class of service
impact says does this model apply to
that or does that is that a totally
different experiment to factor that in
we thought about a little bit I mean for
the experiments in here we just assumed
that we have one output queue right
which is slight oversimplification or
what do you have in a in a real network
and if you have multiple virtual output
queues that are completely separate then
basically you would have to each each
output queue would have by itself would
need to have this amount of buffering
you can well okay this is a slight
overestimate you can get some with some
others using multiplexing between them
and it would be less than if you just
have one queue John Lee I had a question
about what packet sizes you were using
and did you have variable packet sizes
in your flows in our simulations as well
as the experiments we we just had long
flow sending a maximum rate sending
infinite amount of data so they would
always have maximum length TCP packets
one-way in X going back so that was
1,500 or was that jumbo packet in the
for the Stanford experiment we had a
wide range that you know what is typical
for for a production network today so we
had some short short flows we had some
streaming applications with like 300 to
700 my packet lengths we had something
we still had probably around a third or
half max maximum thousand five or five
habits okay thank you
wanted to ask you if the cost factor by
increasing the buffer size decreasing
the buffer size by a factor of 100 how
much does it is a like what what's the
net result in terms of the overall
reduction in cost of the router so I
guess we have a lot people in the room
here who can probably answer that better
than I could so what I've heard from
from router manufacturers is first of
all the RAM chips themselves I mean
typically today for all you have to use
the RAM at the end of the day because
that's the only only RAM chips that'll
give you enough amount of buffering
because of the DRAM is negligible it's
in the order of hundreds of dollars
however the the architecture you that
you need in order to access this DRAM so
typically these sort of staged hard SRAM
part DRAM very wide bus architectures
they tend to make the line cards both
more expensive as well as much more
power hungry so estimates I've heard and
this is I can sort of just pass this on
where that between 30 and 40 percent of
the cost and complexity of a line card
today is the buffering architecture so
if you could all move it back on chip
you might be able to reduce it by
roughly that amount thank you quick
question have you considered the effect
of correlations like if you have on off
sources with long gone periods it's well
known that the superposition of such
sources is highly correlated going into
the buffer and the way they interact in
the buffer have you considered that
effect of the other type of correlation
so in our models know the the trace data
that I've seen for sort of core links in
the network typically show data that is
that is fairly a fairly well behaved in
terms of its overall behavior so there's
no strong synchronization at any time
scale at any time scale relevant for the
for sort of the analysis that we do
between flows so I guess my answer would
be in the traces of the network that
I've seen I didn't see that effect and
so we didn't look at it in more detail
if if you have a network where this
plays a major role that you'd have to
look at this
two quick questions first is did you
monitor test any topologies involving
multiple serialized routers some with
regular sized buffers and others with
the new model buffering and especially
at different speeds okay so we looked at
topologies where we have for example
access links that are that are slower or
somewhere in the path we have routers
that are links that are slower than our
bottleneck link right which is typically
the case in the core of the network if
you have a 10 gig of a link in the core
of the network hardly anyone who's in
tanki would access link to the core and
in that case so generally slow access
links smooth out traffic I mean because
basically if a quick burst will space
the out as individual packets and arrive
at the Kaurava as individual packets and
this is beneficial and we did not look
at scenarios where you have multiple
points of congestion in the network that
is I guess my question was really even
in the if there was only one congestion
point would it matter where the
buffering was actually reduced so the
answers we looked at we looked at some
scenarios there we think that that sort
of covers most topologies but the single
point of congestion and what I've
presented here is a worst case estimate
so if you have the other topologies
there might need less buffering because
basically traffic is smoothed out in the
access does that answer your question
incredible I'll follow up afterwards ok
the other question is for the internet
speed land record stuff would that not
be a case of it would have make not more
sense for them to have modified versions
of TCP that don't do the window in half
and absolutely I mean because once
you've got the small buffers then they
need to work around you yeah no question
absolutely no question for you does your
data include admittedly have not read
your AC on paper so perhaps it does does
your data include
kinds of simulations with tests in which
you had a combination of conformant to
loss like tcp of course and non
conformal foils like voice over IP or
TDM over IP that kind of things so we
did we do combinations of short live
flows and the long live flows and well
Charlotte flows they still in theory
adapt to to congestion they lose a
packet in in practice they are so much
more aggressive than the long live those
because they have smaller window size
and just double every time but you can
almost treat them as a sort of
concentrate sender or something like
that and that doesn't change the results
I guess the the one question or more
concern I would have in my mind is for
example on a network that we we know is
going to carry large the RTP traffic
what would those non-conforming flows
tend to exaggerate the capture effect if
you had less and less buffer at
congestion points so forth
okay we should maybe take that offline
sometimes yes sometimes no thank you if
you change one little thing to say in a
cube root of ten did you have some
sample I'm sorry I didn't get the first
part of the question okay yeah it's two
T by C but you defended you could you
comment on that change yeah
so the if you mean the the fundamental
question there is what happens if you
pick a size is too small or too big
right if you sort of if you look at the
shape of the Gaussian all right it's
it's a family sense sort of your it's
fairly sensitive to if you pick much too
small about for your media gonna rely
recognize it because your losses just
will become huge right and you're not
gonna go anywhere near hundred percent
utilization anymore if you think a
buffer size that's too large
you'll still get hundred percent
utilization but with a larger latency
and these sort of this this transition
is actually fairly sharp so if you would
take I don't know - TT MC over Q like
the cubic root of N or some
like that you wouldn't you would get mad
you would get a much less than hundred
percent utilization and set the
significant losses is that does answer
your question yeah I was looking at some
you know done in this so so that there's
some in the the extended version of the
second paper that's in our home page
there's some data on that that compares
sort of how varying your amount of
buffering effects utilization so if you
know if you get ninety nine point five
versus 98 or you know ninety-nine point
nine you might want to have a look at
that or okay one quick question did you
was there any investigation of red or
other similar discard mechanisms of the
pintail drop yes the the key effect of
red is that it D synchronizers flows
which for I mean my whole analysis here
is if you have synchronized flows then
you need to lead a large buffers because
GCM can I suppose you don't need a large
buffers I don't claim to fully
understand when flows are synchronized
and whether or not the big problem is
that the NS two which is the standard
tool who the academic community to to to
simulate networks tends to overestimate
synchronization so if n is two shows of
synchronization that doesn't mean you
necessarily have some translational real
network rat if you have synchronization
you use red it will definitely help you
to decent cognize the pulse and get to
your lower buffer requirements earlier
for a very large number of flows flows
tend to be synchronized with red or drop
tail or any other scheme so it doesn't
really matter what you use I mean if you
have like more than 5,000 flows you use
whatever you want it
thank you