okay my name is Lori Blanc I'm project
leaf for the RIT be serviced at merit
and this will just be a brief update on
our PS LNG see curious how many of you
are familiar with the RPS L standard not
a whole lot okay well I'm not going to
go into the details of our psl so our PS
LNG is is an update to the rbs.l
standard to support ipv6 and multicast
and it's been a work in progress for
about the last three and a half four
years or so so it's taking a bit of time
it's taken longer than we had hoped for
so we had several goals while we wanted
to maintain backward compatibility with
our psl so we didn't have like a flag
day type situation where people had to
switch over to a new server it was also
important to try to limit the number of
new attributes and classes in our psl
and to maintain readability and
understandability so people don't get
confused when trying to figure out
policy and trying to create policy in
our psl so we pretty much finalized the
standard at this point there is a
mailing list where you can look at the
archives or you can submit comments but
at this point I think we're pretty much
done so a brief summary of changes there
was one new class that was created the
route 6 class which is equivalent to the
route class accepted it supports ipv6
prefixes the other significant change is
with the autonomic class which is used
to express a s policy so there were
three new attributes created there a
multi-protocol import export and default
and there was a an AFI keyword added to
support address-family specification and
several other new attributes were added
to dip to various set classes and I
won't go into those in any real detail
so here's just a couple of brief
examples the first one is route 6
s that I mentioned so you see there ipv6
prefix and the origin is pretty simple
example and and with the autonome object
again you have the AFI specification and
there's several different types shown
here this was taken from the right test
database they have a test server which
implements RPS LNG so there's some
actual policy they are real policy as
far as the standard status the internet
draft was brought to before the iief ITF
operations and management working group
chairs we started not to reconstitute
the RPS working group since the standard
was it's pretty minor update to the
existing standard and we didn't really
want to go through all that work so the
working group chairs agreed to Shepherd
it through the isg and it's actually
been approved by the isg and so at this
point we're just waiting on the RFC
editor to provide their comments or
approval and so you can find an HTML
version of the draft on the ra DB
website as far as implementations there
are two implementations in who is server
software both merit and ripe ncc have
implemented support marriage has their
version available on the ird net web
site and we just released the 2.2
version today which is consistent with
the latest draft our ripe NCC has also
updated the ar-ar-ar-ar-ar tool set with
RPS LNG compliance and they are actually
turning this code over to ISC for
long-term maintenance at this point they
don't they don't really want to be in
provide maintenance and they felt ISC
was a better place to maintain it
however they will continue to to
incorporate patches and updates it will
just be a is you will maintain the CVS
repository so as of today Marik has
implemented our pathology in the
production are a DB registry and you can
now register route 6 objects and I
b6 and multicast policy and we actually
actually had a couple people today who
were so so excited that they went ahead
and registered a couple route 6 objects
and RIT be ripe is planning deployment
in November at some point they need to
roll out their software get it all
committed into CBS to make a release
they do have a test server that's up
right now on our PS LNG right Pat net
250 300 one as far as the other
registries like ap Nick or a number of
providers have their own registries um
I'm not currently aware of any
deployment plans so this is sort of a
little bit different topic but since the
RPS LNG work is pretty much finalized we
thought it would be good to try to do
better coordination among the IRR
operators so we've set up a mailing list
at Merritt that we're hosting and we'd
like to address several issues such as
actually getting deployment among the
various registries with rps lng support
and to address other issues like
authority issues in hierarchy marine and
replication issues and also looking at
new standards like the crisp work in
IETF as well as new working on in
routing security bgp security so we'd
like to encourage people to join this
mailing list if they have any opinions
or comments and that's it any questions
thank you