I'm Salman over here is chip chip Ryan
have you work both in the cisco systems
and basically for I've been with Cisco
for almost nine years working with the
high-speed customers and large
enterprise customers and for last two
years are so working quite a bit with
ipv6 deployments and designs Jeffrey and
over here also you know we work in
pretty much the same team working with
ipv6 deployments and designs and
related by pv6
so the idea is that today's the
presentation we just kind of share with
you bring some of the
what's going on out there what are the
main deployments what are the different
ways of doing things what are some of
the things to keep and to look out for
by the way how many of you over here are
currently testing or doing something
with ipv6
these are like
you have done any anybody has done any
tended to fall
or in the lab environment okay
says it is this something related your
any broadband ice here
sure sure
so
um
maybe you know for some of you some some
information will be redundant so just
kind of bear with us and for some of you
these things will be more
um
most of you have his slider
he slides already available
so
you have like quite a bit of slides over
here and we have 90 minutes to cover
them so
me and shipping only might gonna skip
some slice but because they are more for
your reference later on and after the
presentation if you still have any
questions we'd be around here so you can
come and ask questions and
so first thing you know click update
that what is
ipv6 address looks like rice is like 128
bits so the first three best tells me
that you know this is a golden unicast
rally with addressed by 2012
followed by 45 days so the first fully
asbestos the provider part followed by
the subnet ID
then the fixed interface ID which is 64
bits
some of the basic things I'm not going
to go into details because our main goal
is you know to get you into the
deployment section and talk about more
the deployments we have basically put
together three case studies one is for
native ipv6 deployment then one is 46 PE
and then one for deployment in the
broadband area papi what people are
doing in the broadway near area because
one of the things like what we are
working on right now is the activity
more related to ipv6 is in northern us
you know it's more in asia-pacific
region and ripe ncc like in some
European countries first since in
Switzerland Netherlands and Germany
France these are all broadband when the
search providers who are providing using
ipv6 to provide broadband
for their varmint customers also the
biggest customers biggest faces which
ipv6 is being the point is Japan and the
customer who is doing it in the
commercial deployment it's also in
broadband and so we'll also talk about
one of the case studies that how they
are doing it
so the address allocation policy is
pretty much you know they they have this
hurricane ipv6 so dope
the top with the classic scenes that we
have all of these different registries
which fire gives like fresh 20
they're the different registries they
assigned / 32 to the ice piece I feel
fine / 48 to the customers to the sites
so if you remember in the previous
slides the flat foldability plastics
before we have this 16 bits over there
Frank so depending on like you the the
ice P doesn't have to give / 48 to their
customers this is where basically they
would be making their revenues also
depending on how many bits they give to
the customers right they could give a /
64 / 56 or / 50 depending on the number
of bits because more bits a site a site
would have they can have you no more
room to play with the bits that do more
things
so this is how
summarize so in this particular example
we have two thousand one which is a
global unicast Charlotte with a / 23
which is a registry registry assigns a /
32 to an ISP I've see signs of / 48 and
then from / 48 to / 64 those 16 bits are
basically in if I'm a farmer site if I
get a / 48 I have these 16 bits rank 5
to the power 16 I could have this many
subnet occurrences
so in this one you know keeping the
party in mind
we have the ipv6 internet / 16 then we
have the in this example two different
IP and of course these are from the same
registry so
you have / 30 tues over here in the ice
cream is finalized 48 so why advertising
the routes you know these customers only
announcer default route to the upstream
i speak the ice visa announce the / to
reach into the
one thing you know I haven't we haven't
covered and this you'll notice that you
know some of you might think about what
happens when the when the customers are
doing home right what happens with the
multi horny right so the multi-homing
right now it's it's not anything
different what we do in ipv4 when we
leak the more specific this is some a
major like a known problem in the in the
working group and their eight different
drafts which are being worked on to
resolve this particular problem that
what will happen keeping this hierarchy
in mind when you have multi home
environment and you're going to differ
nice piece how you're going to do it so
that's something you know if you go to
the ipv6 working group you will see like
different drafts which are being worked
on right now that there's nothing like
solid solution that you just do this you
know so there are several different
options and and for instance like right
now people what they're doing that they
just leave the more specific you know
when they do the multi-homing this is a
interesting slide like what i was saying
for that more activities in the
asia-pacific region and the ripe NCC is
Europe and all day shifts of the country
and the rest is 50 Erin
those knowledge
not that much activity but not picking
up quite a bit one of the reason was
that the department of defense announced
last year that they want to go to ipv6
by 2007 you know so that can accelerate
the whole thing and I'm not sure that
how many of you are aware of the
applications but the things that I was
in Santa Barbara when they was ipv6
forum conference and that's where they
made the announcement so the
applications they were talking about is
like pretty advanced and things what
they want to do you know so right now
you cannot go into all of those details
but if you just look up you know on the
internet you will find out some details
on that
as far as the routing is concerned
nothing has changed you know you're
still doing this the longest prefix
match nothing has changed all the
routing protocols which are their price
EV for you have support for ipv6 also
there are some minor changes which are
done in the protocols that as far as the
protocol the way it behaves is pretty
much same and all the protocols except
ospf right ospf is some other more than
minor changes the way it behaves you
know because now you have more certain
number of more LSAs introduced and
summer some of them are renamed some of
them are merged you know so the
functionality is a little bit different
than only just doing the nlr I or doing
some longest prefixes support for
longest prefixes is more than that
okay so all the as far as you get most
of you know that rep ng is the for ipv6
based on based on rip version 2 and then
we have a igrp for ipv6 hosts
differently and integrated is is that I
said you know for ospf you have quite a
bit of changes which are the way the
protocol behaves it's a little bit
different now but when we first started
to support ipv6 the first thing of
course was a riff and G because it was
easier to implement but after that was I
sayest history's most of the vendors
started to support because the way is is
worse and the the whole TLD concept you
know if you remember that initially when
thy the ISS came Tuesday 5tl v's right
and then when we added ipv4 we added
five mokey Elvis but when we added ipv6
we added two more clearly said was
pretty much ready to support ipv6 that
was one of one of the reasons that when
they started to support ipv6 for link
state protocols it was i sighs before
ospf because ospf needed more work to be
done
you could have a basically concept of
shipping the knife for CF where you have
ospf version 2 and 0 spea version 3 are
running at that time you know you have
basically two different SPFs running so
once you're doing that you have to keep
just saying this you know that you can
do it it's just isn't easy thing to say
but once you really deploy that you know
you have to keep a lot of things in mind
for instance you know yet you'll have to
make sure when you make these routers
seduced a crowd or supporting out there
version 2 and version free you got to
make sure that you know you have the
enough memory enough processing power
because now you'll be have you have to
this robber basically running two
different SPS right you'll have two
different routing tables so the package
will come in for coming for v4 you go
look into the oil ospf version 2
forwarding table and then for version 3
will be different right so it'll be
double the capacity hour and everything
so you have to once you kind of we have
customers right now who are doing this
but you have to make sure that you're
needing the doctor all the guidelines
right so there's no easy we like to just
put like you know ten pounds of sugar
and a five-pound bag so we have to get
to be follow all the guidelines the
other thing is that I sighs as you know
that it's being supported right now but
the other concept is I size multi
topology which is also being supported
right now so you could have you know two
different topologies two different SPS
because right now with is I is the
current weight the way it works could
only have a single topology for both
leave v
and v6 but much its polish you could
have separate apologies which is also
supported right now then you have V GPA
right so VDP was easy right for v 60 day
they using multi protocol bgp now they
have another address-family fi to which
is for ipv6 of course all the sub
adverse families are same in all the
edges families
there was like a very quick update
what's going on around the world what's
water things some related to ipv6
so SP deployments right activities
basically you have several market
segments the internet exchanges the
transit carriers we philosophy is the
wireless mobile operators and each of
them you know they could be doing things
a little bit differently than others but
as far as
as far as the mean
if I fall
so basically
but mainly you know for ipv6 there's no
you know cookie cutter approach or there
is no you know deadline or anything that
you know this has to happen by this
dated all around the world because
you're running out of something or
there's some deadlines a y2k or
something nothing like that so it's all
going to depend on the requirements
coming from the customers Frank and what
what they want to do what they're asking
for if all this investment that whatever
we are doing making sense or not so
depending on different countries regions
you know even in countries different
cities all that sort of stuff like
you're working with one customer in
malaysia in kuala lumpur you know
they're doing something you know with
wireless and ipv6 they have these
waterfalls they want to do this thing in
kale and for longer so it's all depends
you know where you are what are the
requirements purses in Japan basically
they're deploying ipv6 that's one of the
biggest departments and the work and
they're doing focusing on all the all
the broadband customers right and so to
keep in mind that you know like your
kind of shifting from that this dial up
environment to a broadband environment
right where you have always all the
connectivity and there's no more you
know you go there you dial up you get
the address and once you're done you
release it someone else use it now it's
like broadband environment things are
pretty much of all the time and the
address is going to be needed all the
time right and then another big
application for you know ipv6 which is
being evaluated and also a lot of things
are going on in that part of the work is
in the mobile right so if you see what
where we live right now in this part of
the world or you know even in the Europe
you get pretty much you know the
landlines and all these things are no
problem but if you see if you pick up
like the four or five big countries in
the world right Jimmy Indonesia India
China Pakistan Bangladesh these five
countries we have more than half of the
world's population and even to this day
and majority of the cases you know if
you go if not get the landline very
easily right takes time you know that
part of part of the world there's
you know their job that you know if i
apply for four to get a landline maybe
my kids will get it takes cut quite a
bit yeah and but at the same time you
know even I'm originally from Pakistan
you know and when I go there to my
village somewhere a person can they
won't have a landline anything but if
you know they go to town center or
somewhere they can still get mobile
phone rang and they can get connected
right they can make phone calls all over
the world so the applications people are
thinking and in that part of the world
things are being tested that let's say
on this mobile phone you have a IP step
right and if you have IP stack of this
mobile phone or
whatever it is right now you can get
this guy connected on the internet as
well right so this thing is basically
connects to if you know about the 3g
right the 3g gets you 2 megabits rates
right and 3gp p which is the body for
for all the standards they have chosen
ipv6 as the de facto stack on all the
devices which are going to be built in
future like which are billions right so
basically that if you have this PDA or
mobile phone or whatever it is you know
with ipv6 tag the opportunities are
pretty much a pretty big because that
this guy can get connected on the
internet at the same time if you have
some local provider who's providing some
kind of stream of the interest of those
people right if it's like cricket
highlights or you know anything and need
movies or whatever the songs or whatever
the things people like you know they
could put a spot a local server at
people most of time they could watch on
this you know this PDA or whatever in
smaller lies they have they could do
quite a bit and also you know when we
work in that part of the world and you
know things doesn't have to be big like
over here things
even have smaller things people are
happy with it so those are some of the
things people are evaluating right now
as far as the v6 and this whole market
is concerned
sure right now we can do it but you'll
have to do next
no privacy
your ledger system at
I'll just maybe you know some skip some
slides in
as far as the
performance in areas are concerned for
the core of the network you know
you could have
native right when I say native it's not
it means that you're not going to have
any ipv4 you're going to have a dual
stack environment right so you have all
of these devices which are groups like
they're supporting IP v4 and v6 right so
you have two different folding tables
remember the things I talked about all
the limitations all the guidelines you
have to meet the crossing power to all
the the memory and em all gotta have
Hardware forwarding and all those things
you have to keep in mind or you could
have in the core you could have maybe
you're running and pls right so as we
know that you have two camps over here
so if you're doing mpls you could do
still 6p and you could you can deploy
ipv6 very in a pretty nice way which in
fact for this particular case we have a
case study and we'll go in details about
how you can do that as far as the excess
is concerned towards the customers you
could either do tunneling between your
access points and the customers or you
could also do a native when I say native
again these two points a goose tag and
you're doing some kind of you know rip
ng or something routing protocol for v6
and exchanging routes so all of these
things are this basically right now
being done you know I'm different like
some people are doing one thing
in something with the other thing
and one thing to keep in mind you know
that
decnet was not very popular than
it's compared to ipv4 but we still find
decnet right in the kisser networks so I
pc war is like big crisis it's pretty
much deployed everywhere so it's going
to take time you know to get towards
ipv6 s and it's not again it's all going
to depend on how what people are asking
for and the applications comes along and
the farmers come along as far as the the
deployment is concerned you know for
enterprise and I skis you know things
what they have to look for is pretty
much saying you know as far as it could
take you know the it could vary in
little bit of cases but as far as the
major components are pretty much saying
that they have to make sure that you
know they have to do all the addressing
part and then they have to choose the
routing protocol right and then they
have to make sure that the DNS
environment is ready for that right so
bien esta you just look into that really
quick but basically you have the air
records and for v6 we have the party
records right so its dns is ready for
that to support that and also the
transport is also available okay so
before we 6 transfer is also there and
about the management how these ipv6
devices are going to be managed right
now to this day right now we do all the
management the transport is v4 right so
how are you going to do it are you going
these things to keep in mind what would
be the security who
the
one thing about you know choosing the
routing protocol that you have to kind
of keep things in mind and from the
frost from the point of view that let's
say you have a OSP version to running in
the network right now from point A to
point B rank and and you you plan to
deploy oh sweet version 3 so you have to
kind of make sure that you know you know
all the details about the person
fermentation what I mean that you know
you have to make sure that the person
who deployed it like lesson that in the
past you know they be played with the
matrix right so point from point A to
point B let's say you have a fat a the
preferred path but it's not the past
which is being taken because they played
with the metrics right so now you deploy
OSP a version 3 so now that will be
taking the pre the most optimal path so
let's say you run into some kind of
issues right some problems and when you
troubleshooting that will be a pretty
big problem because the customer the
end-user you're going to say that you
know with before things are working okay
but musics not working things are not
working okay because you know at the end
of the day you have to kind of make sure
that you know all the details while
deploying this thing
as far as the transition in integrations
concern of ipv6
most of the things are you know there
you have these customer networks lots of
them you know you have these islands of
ipv6 right now and these islands are
being connected by doing certain things
like I said in the previous slide you
could do tunneling you could do mpls 6pe
those sort of things right there are
certain things which you could do
there's no expectation right now that
people would just rip off their ipv4
networks and put in ipv6 in there right
so you have to just kind of work and get
the integration going you know in a
little even if you know you're not going
into like big deployment or something
you could still start you know have
these little islands of v6 and get them
connected and start playing with it or
something to get used to and get early
start
that's right
right
the PE routers we deduced
and for this particular exam 16 you have
a whole case study so we'll go into more
details that all the whole process is
eager
I'm trying to you know yeah that'll be a
really interesting part for a lot of new
folks over here so as far as the for the
integration the transition and for
existence is concerned you have you know
you have dual stack you have tunneling
and you have translated like dual stack
I talked about what's the dual stack
that soon as you have you know by
default robber is a you notice is
sporting ipv4 packets route and I
shouldn't say that because for cisco you
know we were doing IP and Ethel talk and
all the stuff there were like three four
stacks so this is just a mission but but
why they use dual stack that usually
routers do I q equal so they they
basically once they start doing ipv6
they the dual stack right so or you
could do tunneling right and this point
of when you do tunneling only the tunnel
endpoints that will be doing stat right
then everything in between is going to
be whatever it is and then you'll have
some translation going in certain part
of the network because what's going to
happen
ok so in fact I have some slides on this
particular thing but as far as what
funding is you know
lesser your life in network
absolute saw prices with the two tunnel
endpoints detect epson salt packets a
month
right with the talent starts
encapsulated mm to ipv4 password or the
ipv4 network that lands on the other
parks other side that tunnel endpoint
that d capsulate
puts the intensity I mean that to talk
to that confront
courses
so so do stack approaches little bit
when more siren visit
you have
crane protocol ID for ipv6 right so
which is Bureau x86 DV
so basically depending on this is the
preferred approach right so the panic
you can make your you know devices
dual-stack and depending on the
applications when they start to come
along they can choose whatever you know
IP v4 or v6 they can do whatever needs
to be done as long as it's there because
there's only going to be API which is
needs to be written and they can so they
can recognize this thing protocol IP
okay
this is some you know reference slice
for DNS but as far as you know the DNS
part is concerned that this is one of
the good slide that a record what you do
right you do from domain name to IP
address and from quad a records you do
basically from your name to ipv6 address
mapping and then you have the PTR
records the reverse of that right from
this is basically part you have to kind
of make sure that your you're supporting
that one thing to keep things in mind
that for when you're doing you're
deploying DNS right you have to make
sure that it's not only you have to make
sure that the dns server is ready to
support like a and the quality records
right and at the same time the transport
is also available the root servers you
know we're sitting is not like your ipv4
environment and goof server sitting at
the v6 environment is not going to work
right or if you're in the week before
environment and the roots are sitting at
the v6 environment it's not going to
work so the Transport has to be
supported as well with the DNS like a
records and party records whatever the
cases in this particular example you
know if it if I want to go to a calm
right so I send a request you know how
that basically works this up some
basically reference lights I could also
do an extra cry so
if i send that request i'm going to get
a wreck v4 and v6 addresses and based on
the application and go get connected to
whatever wherever it likes to
this is that what I was talking about
that you know let's say you have an ipv6
environment and you send a request and
it goes to the dance to the roof install
over that's ipv4 it's not going to work
ok and on the other case ok I wasn't
aware of this animation sorry about that
so in this particular case that if you
have ipv4 environment you send it in a
refresh to an open
so where does this rule
the this particular example
calm and sausages
intercom
hey by the way the deli
this comes back over here espn.com
the delegation for this is sitting at
this suture right and then when it comes
over here it's only supposed ipv6 right
it's not going to work for you so this
passport has to be available also these
are some of the things to just kind of
keep in mind when you deploying the DNS
for ipv6
the Duelist AG infrastructure we talked
about you know as long as you're meeting
then mark the requirements you have the
enough family enough processing power
all of these things are being taken care
of you should be pretty much fine but
there's no way in search provide an
environment that without meeting the
guidelines you'll basically jeopardize
you're going to jeopardize your current
ipv4 network which certainly we don't
want to do you know it's been i've been
with cisco for you know almost nine
years and I started to start my work and
the tech you know and I was there for
five years and with the pager all the
time so but now things are pretty good
you know because it took time for people
to stabilize those networks so we
certainly don't want to tell people to
take out before and put the OSP a
version 3 right but it's but it's going
to be more of a integration in a way
that you know start from a little bit of
sites and then you know you analyze and
you expand from there based on the needs
this is you know some basically very
some basic slides that how what do you
do on the router to make it a dual spec
these are some tunneling they're
different kind of funding mechanisms
which are available to terminal ipv6
packets into ipv4 over ipv4 environment
they're manually configured towns
semi-automatic and automatic you know
this almost sounds like you know
different kind of guns you know and I'm
just at the wrong place you know to talk
about these things so in fact you know I
come from Pakistan and we just grow up
with these things and it just happens to
be this way you know manual semi
automatic automatic so so man oh man
when you configure tells it took it took
you guys a while to understand ooh ok ok
so you have we have this manually
right so you have basically two nail
tunnels right pretty easy source
destination source destination on both
sides and you turn the traffic right
then you have GRE tunnel which is
exactly the same nail tunnels but
remember these nail tunnels you know if
you can expand the more sites you have
it's not not going to be scalable right
why would you want to do one or the
other manual or GRE they're pretty much
same nail tongues but only some of the
cases when you do GRE like in certain
cases let's say you have these islands
of is is right and you know the ice is
also sends these layer two messages
right so GRE is only turning mechanism
which can also tell you the nursery
information the Milky messages right so
if you have these islands of is is and
you're trying to do manually configure
towns it's not going to work for you
because the manual configure terms is
not going to pass any of the lyric you
information ok so in that case you
you'll end up doing GRE instead then you
have this concept of semi-automatic
tunnel vocal concept which is you know I
think I have a slider I have slides on
that i'll show you in the picture then
you have automatic tunneling mechanisms
the two of them which are pretty popular
624 and iso tab 64 is automatic because
you know you'll see in the configuration
that you do not configure any
destination the destination is found on
the fly you know so lonely configure a
source address and the destination so
it's basically a point-to-multipoint out
just much more scalable and then
you have isotype isotype is again
automatic funding mechanism we saw is
more used in a enterprise environment
okay let's say I'm i work for cisco
right so Cisco I he provides ice except
you know handling I could do it my cisco
environment is all i teased before let's
say about your fiber and windows XP
machine and running ipv6 i want to get
connected to the ipv6 for so what I do I
just basically make sure that I can
figure my part lies the tab tunnel point
on my part and the society has put up
isotype router which is just what a goof
stack router okay so i can make a tunnel
over ipv4 infrastructure from my point
to the isotope router and that i set a
browser has a little bit it's basically
a gateway you can get me connected to
anywhere on the ipv6 internet okay so
that's the idea
so if you know somebody asks about the
tunneling so this is a good example and
you can just keep it you know just kind
of see because the only the tunnel
endpoints are dual stack in this case
just
all you're doing
encapsulating into ipv4 header it could
be done between the robbers or you know
the the hosts since this is all
operational you know people who work
with the network I have just a quick
question that lets say 52 I have a
simple tunnel you know point-to-point
tunnel and this tunnel is not coming up
you know I check the configuration
everything is ok right and I'm handling
ipv6 over ipv4 ok network
what would be what should be the case in
things let's say look
you know one of the you know in fact
there was one time I just troubleshoot
this thing remember that when the slide
I said that tunneling is the IP protocol
time when you turn the packets ipv6
packet into V 4 is 4 p-1 right so this
is you could have a point to point on
which is a warm towel there was a router
in between somewhere which was what it
was doing it was blocking protocols I 41
right so everything was ok but this town
wasn't coming up and then took us a
while to just get to that thing that
that rather in the bed middle it was
blocking that protocol 41 this is an
example of you know manual channel
configure configuration right here
pretty central power source destination
Fahrenheit ipv6 IP you know nothing else
nail tunnels on both sides GRE exactly
the same only
all you when would be that some of the
cases when you want to use GRE and not
that manually configure tells they're
both the same if the network is big or
something or you want to do tunneling
it's not very scalable this is the
tunnel vocal concept that these are some
of the services which are available
right now on the internet so a person
you know let's say if I if I'm you're
not connected from isp which is on ipv4
and I have a windows XP machine at home
and I want to get connected on like
these go get connected to the ipv6
internet I can basically go to this
website you know some whoever's
providing the standard local services
and I can fill out all this information
and that time the broker server
basically pull push all that information
to a blue stack router and the time of
the storm between the du sac router and
my machine at home right over the ipv4
intimate and that
to get to the ipv6 internet right so
this is these are some of the services
which are available right now in fact
right now you can if you go to six bone
dotnet these services are available for
free you know so if you have the fewer
at home all ipv4 if you have a Windows
XP machine or something dual stack
machine you can get connected on ipv6
internet this is the automatic tunneling
the 64 64 telling for this particular
type of tunneling you have a reserved
address space which just starts with two
2002 so the first 16 bits are always
going to the 2002 by the way this
particular tunneling type is you know
it's for people who are who never got a
chance you know to get ipv6 address a
global unicast audible address right
they could just use 2002 and then put
icv for public ipv4 address and though
bits and they can they can make that
dress look like a global unicast article
address because it starts with two right
but only use for the environment you
know for the large environment put the
enterprise environment as well where
people want to get their sites connected
on ipv4 and they want a case where what
you know the test they want to test the
whole environment and you know get used
to it but obviously you know they wanna
the the main thing is the everybody
should try to go to 2001 address range
not 2002 which is only fixed 464
tunneling you can
ok so this too much information here and
a lot of it you know I'm going to skip
the 64 paneling type in the
configuration 64 relay services is
basically just really quick to tell you
that people what they're doing that they
can the truth the 624 connects the two
thousand two sides together but what if
a two thousand two sides want to go to a
2001 or internet ipv6 internet or
somewhere else for that you'll have to
have 624 relay services at six to four
real a router again is a dual stack
router which is a gateway between a 2002
and the rest of the world okay then you
have Matt PT which is again what it's
doing and brief what you're doing that
right now dot ten-dollar addresses to
the global addresses same thing is
happening between v6 and v4 I'm going to
again animation sorry well there and I'm
going to skip some of this because we
really want to get you you know to some
deployment parts in the
ok so lets you know what we
chip will cover the deployment part to
what the idea was that we both do 45
minutes but I'll cover that part in 45
minutes so it was impossible so since
this is like I think this is the last
section right last session so I would
really encourage that if even if going
over 90 minutes just kind of stick
around because this part is going to
interest you even more okay
a lot
he said about it
just a few points I wanted to start with
making some notes while Stalin was just
pretending
the rule of the information is actually
available in the slides I definite ID
so first of all as an argument why tv6
and
addresses building
at the larger Addison space building
driver
however what we noticed is that in the
process of trying to come up with
business cases
to justify the expense of
which in some parts of the world is
encouraged by legislation or
backstage so on so forth people try to
find new ways to deploy services so you
feel like to be for network nice you
tried to squeeze
the last drop out of it 30 foot on top
of it all
that are possibly BP
gasps all kind of SLA that's a lace of
supporting services so
but sometimes the way you started that
big network and a big investment might
not be the best way that you could have
done it and you learn that
ipv6 sometimes can offer you
of second opportunity the second chance
to squeeze some more out of your network
and this time maybe
so besides looking at the large letters
in space
you might see I be single
the other observation that i wanted to
make obviously we're just going to start
talking about the point
you have to balance investment versus
and often times is going to be driven by
your customer
whole idea is if you have two customers
and you don't want to put too much money
up front then it might be worth what if
you fight you do as little as possible
conservatives because however if you
look on the long run with the current
state of ipv6 and with the current
support of ipv6 by the Mexican
it might be worth
picking a second thought and
going for full scale long term before
and I'm saying this because the question
of tunneling came
and everybody internally
and everybody 96 world was interested in
tunneling and developed Connelly
in order to help people for encourage
people to
esri investment as possible
so we are getting to a point where it
might be worth it to consider go
the world's back
okay so that will be my first speech
production
oh you discussed
case scenarios one would be
more stack
dual stack refers to the fact that we
are trying to look at both ipv4 and ipv6
in coexistence obviously when you're
going to eat when you're going to be 4i
can be six besides all the discussion
about money and
the cost and how much going to get back
you have to make sure like someone was
mentioning you have to make sure that
during impact on itv4 is not significant
so that's why along the way we will talk
about 4 mg 60 power now
it's very tempting
c4 to take your approach on developing
guide on at one
six in the same way you before it I can
be for make sense
the same philosophy my good
with whoever you think
most times that works but sometimes
things
so talking about dual stack that means
that your neck
we turn on ipv6
along side by side without people so on
on your interfaces you have ipv6 in a
on top of life or next to I
now obviously when you do that you
better be sure of the consequent better
be short of the memory style that you
have you met the people brothers
education
routing information for ideas
make sure that you have the jarada has
the ability to process to build erotica
I let us know this case pain in which we
are willing to do that
both of them both these campuses are
connected to a next-generation Internet
service provider that in turn can take
you out for either exchange
so this company applies for prefixes so
they want to get their own pee fixes
that people to design our / 48 allocated
by the service provider as someone
pointed out we're talking only about one
service provider will be home in we just
want to get there so we have the fantasy
move aside
maybe power
along the router
there is provided a link to the okapi
office
now someone was talking about the two
local unicast addresses that are family
being a star
this is a little bit of an older slide
that has a three FF II
address that
but still works concept of the same
slide a slight difference in in the
hottest-ever start now as you can see we
decided to choose
prefixes the to pretty Cesaro
highlighted down at the bottom flat for
needed for entire company but we decide
this to a sinus / 56 on one
/ 56 on the other campus
then we go ahead and start configuring
each campus with with the addressing
scheme that we first plan if we thought
about as you can see the three daughters
they have the links configure with / 64
and then also the links that provide
access to users also configure with / 6
before all cut out of the three FS e v 0
0 FF @ / 56 then we have one link the s
the cereal foods
the architect
configuration wise rather simple we are
looking at first and most important step
is enabling the writing process on the
routers ipv6 unique and routing
obviously found that terminology is
obvious that we are talking about unit
class process is not a booty gasps and
then found interfaces we enable ipv6
these interfaces most likely have ipv4
on them as well but here we're just
showing the ipv6 addresses
there are several ways in which you can
you can do this but this is one way in
which we did we show clearly how the
interface ID is defined in this case for
example for Fast Ethernet 0 / 2 on
router r1 the prefix is pfft be 00 FFF
to interface ID is one statically
configured we could have led the router
choose its own interface ID with you
if I'm using some terminology if it is
not familiar because maybe you didn't
work that much like in your sixties let
me know
once we set up all the ipv6 address
saying you can ping between the routers
you want obvious if you turn on the
routing the choice cause is is you're
going to have two areas one in our ep
one in samples in enabling is is on the
router start the ISS process we define
the ipv6 address family define the area
and enable is I ask
RTP side configured sim in a similar way
we have a different he takes here we
assign the prefix with a lagoon / 64
throughout the routers and enable gonna
enable a sales as well in between the
two sides we took you have a link that
runs is is a little Q as you can see we
enable the the circuit type on the CD 02
/ 0
now
a song mentioned
we want to have at one point or another
in our net we want to have sort of an
interface if you
in the p4 world right because as you can
see he's 6 and before we don't talk to
each other in this case no paneling
this is that we even used before in
order to transfer this traffic but there
is no window between the two worlds so
net PT is going to be your wing
and if you have within an island devices
you want to talk all within a dual stack
Island the best one is called talk only
before or only be six then
you have net PP
and on this particular router we have
met be enabled for such v4 hold it is
not using ipv6
you
to set up
provided an IBD be between the two sides
in terms of configuration again just
briefly going over the vtp configuration
we have the process enabled and we
defined it the two guesses for the
campus and for the ISP what I wanted to
show is P much configuration why is
something that is similar to what you
are familiar with night ed for the
neighbor definition however as you can
see in the neighbor defined is your next
up identified with the link
the local addresses
but basically our addresses that are
used only for the local lane to exchange
information and why do we use that as an
ex-cop well ipv6 can do a lot of can do
some portion of the numbering very easy
to router advertisement addresses can
change between their RS global unicast
addresses can change between routers on
the same length but the link local
addresses typically do not change so
this way using the link local as your
next stop is a very easy way to nail
down that neighbor lake is very you know
for the long run but you want to make
sure that when you're going to advertise
for send information about your browser
you are not going to point to provide
the link local as an ex-cop why because
there are is specifically told to not
for traffic to be local
okay so that's why we have that drop map
down at the bottom that says whenever
you're going to advertise your prefixes
make sure that you put your next up will
be your global address not your link
local
and this this is the link between
customer sideways
pretty much configuration why's
everything everything stays the same
don't think I need to talk
and this is the ibgp connection same
concept the same way defining that the
neighbor
network the network definition over
there is just basically
making their order to advertisers prefix
and then the route map down at the
bottom again to make sure that if your
honor advertise the prefixes with the
right its global unicast addresses the
next hop another load
there is another there is another
statement that should be in the b2b
configuration that is going to show up
in our six key example which basically
will tell the router to not consume that
I sweetie for is the only
profile abilities rent
then to complete this example we want to
make sure that the traffic that gets to
die speed and goes out to the internet
and connect to connect output to other
sites on the v6 world so for that
particular segment we chose to just set
up a static panel to the Internet's
chain and it's a typical example of
manual tunnel
any questions
so far
and just clear something to be run in
the election
so maybe a little bit more interesting
6p
p is a migration in technology McMahon's
strategy you have ipv6 all right
and it's actually very powerful thing
knowledge
it allows you to do that with minimal
impact on your fourth that was that that
was the goal of six
and leverages that all the experience in
all the knowledge that we gain with
running mpls VPN and summer so forth so
if you look at this network
and you have your PE devices
the idea of 60
on the edge devices where you have
customers and only their
and then information ipv6 packets are
going to be tagged with a v6
then tagged with a v4 tag
to cross the poor the packets are going
to be switched based on the default back
all the way to the next half to the next
60 router that tack strip and then
switching done or the destination of the
pattern being identified based on 36
times
so we're going to go through the packet
forwarding information
in terms of how protocols are being
distributed across your network well we
have your gooseneck Island over there
you're going to have all your v6 world
stuff now your v6 addressing and you're
going to have your v6 igp or
you can use vgp because we know
though bc silence in the 6p router
in the core you're going to be left with
whatever before hat so you're going to
have your before addressing going to
have your default igp you're going to
have all the mechanisms that you're
using to exchange that the tags with
beef ldp rsvp-te
you're bgp multiple robdd sessions
between the pier are
so how exactly 60
in this diagram we're going to we
have
routers that advertise for that post
that post to pkt the left hand side you
have two thousand 10 for 20
and on the right-hand side you have
2,000 104
each one topped by an IDP a v6 igb
they talk native to the 60 router so 61
and 62
interface is facing those routers are
enabled phonee
2 diabetes
advise 60
hey I know about two-thousand 10 4 21
and if you want to reach it you just go
to the ipv6 math ipv4
and 17
along with this information
saying when are we going to send packets
for that guy for 2,000 10 41 please also
attach this ipv6 tag to the package so I
so I know how to deal with it okay
now when we move
one
61 will have the following information I
know how to get to two-thousand 10 4 21
my next hop is going to be the address
Colin problem ffff column 192 dr. 5417
that is the ipv6 map ipv4 address by
build an ipv6 address out of my out of
that I TV for Eddie that will be my next
hop I also know that if I'm going to
send this out I have to attach an ipv6
label it will advertise typing
and I also know that if I want
made with my health might
I learned how
and I know the tag that was explained by
a el de or I RSVP so
ok so now here is in you know with some
animation to say
two thousand one is advertised two
thousand on 0 for 2 10 size matter I PPP
advertising is all
in the ipv4 world
but then byah
the advertising 2001 yo
along with
the neck top well is not just before the
ipv6 math packet before
and a label
never deliver these v6 by GPS to his
client so now let's see how the packet
traveled with that
most laps routers into 10 96 packet
plenum server
it loads why I by his own igp that he
can
p 1 in north union two-thousand 10 41
6 p-1 picks up the packet loops
up in his own writing table and sees
that each if you want to reach 2,000
1421 the next hop is going to be at Town
Hall of FFF 190 2054 that end up 17
which is
this means that I'll have to encapsulate
this packet we did tag with ipv6 tag and
then with an ipv4 that to do 6p
so he's going to go and add beside the
MPEG he learn label the physical able to
the yellow one
we're also going to add the LDP late
label for 192
hold the packet along now the core of
the network has no clue what's in that
packet all they care all those are
hear about is the top little late
the LGBT so the next one
he's going to do the swap a typical mpls
stuff so happily swapping let and swap
swapping labels the router gets all the
way to the penultimate are so adept
another half
I pop the label now this is the reason
why we need a night to be six pack in
order to make sure that this mechanism
works with an open on top if my internet
network
the top of an ultimate
I
inside
Oh
yet this I think is
so
system that ipv6 label now
that he can he still can process it he
looks at the label instead of looking in
the 936 packet now he against that I
that label packet doesn't look up on the
label sees what that means that pointing
to his v6
first that particular label
the yellow table
and then thousand ipv6 look up
Paquette wherever it has to be forwarded
just a point of interest here what we
noticed was well
you look up on this label right on the
yellow
these are rather small entities compare
with the actual address so you two can
actually
so much faster look up by looking up a
very small label and binding it to your
alban's urban interface then actually do
a look up
so our for example our original
implementation use aggregate labels 2
u16 labels and we just assign them round
robin people
your family League label too discreet
look up as much fat
saves you a lot of fine lot of resources
alright 6p is that is a matter between
three and six
first of all I'm not sure why we would
not
why we go
if you have a tu tunnel or just pls
the idea would be I didn't want
Jason now obviously
what we are talking about here is 60
there are other mechanisms that
boy you
but not
you can feel
and the other tunnel
and then you can set up your own
but then that's different you don't have
the dynamic aspect
some information on standardization i'm
going to skip over this some of the
benefits of 6p
is
actually it's be good
works very well to scale
it's a very
you're familiar with VPN
what you have to do
is sort of a glow it curve provides the
global
what will connect you to be for
everybody in your map
it doesn't differentiate between and use
so
p offers you a one
I uses cloud on top of your network
everybody sees every time
so it's a few eq would 60 you can make
an analogy with it
if as if you have one big thing here
you
actually I'll show them the
configuration wise and just drawing an
analogy and just drawing a parallel if
you're familiar with VPNs that's how you
should look at deep at six
one big DRS but that handle Tony
so let's go over this configuration and
that that will make things a little bit
more clear mini how the configuration is
done but bottom line is the idea is that
this is pretty simple it's pretty
straightforward to implement doesn't
affect your core which is a big factor
it's very dynamic it scales folding
performance is excellent they're holding
is done hardware to out so you know it's
going to have little impact on your on
your performance of the network the only
thing that you have to look is some of
the hardware resources but other than
that is it ok of the cons you don't want
to do 6p if you don't run mpls don't
turn on mpls just put 60 you need to
understand mpls MV GP
most of the people do nowadays and
requires an upgrade at the edge so your
6p devices your PR that hacked the new
duties people have to be able to have
the picture nado
yep
you can do ldp RSVP and over t college
and there is one more comment I want to
make on puns I think I'm going to talk a
little bit about it no multicast so you
look on the long run multicast is part
of your service that you plan to turn on
as a service for multicast at 86
unfortunately no multicast for work 6p
at this time but work being done on it
configuration there are two commands
that are relevant neighbor send label is
under under btp you advise the advisor
vtp process to send the aggregate labels
and you have a global configuration use
NPOs ipv6 or interface explain down
there in its
some of the few show commands that are
interesting and work worth looking at
when you enable troubleshooting show bgp
ipv6 neighbors in order to see the
capabilities show bgp ipv6 unicast
porcelain prefix ipv6 route mpls folding
table this will show you the ipv4 side
of things the ipv4 tag that are going to
be show bgp ipv6 unicast label that's
going to show you the inner leg you
exchanged by an EVP
and show ipv6 set that will show you the
two labels together in the stack
configuration wise on our diagram we had
the seats to succeed you are left mode
native ipv6 hooks are good
ok
routers never mind about it it's 90 by
Pegasus
worry about it talks over Center 19
protocols
v router
6pr is where most of the action yeah
first amended we mentioned
d configuration is relatively simple
just have to
11 per minute was I mentioned earlier
there was not in the example for VT
one commander you should keep in mind is
local
called ipv6 heavy before you
has to be there on bgp nor too
thing that is not be for all
well I'm his family I keep six
going to have the neighbor
for next hop right foot speed
we are looking at the people
so did you
next up be4 address
some of the commands I'm going to go
really fast to some of the show commands
show BTW kappa v6 neighbor what you want
to see there is you want to see that the
address family i think is securely
fastened negotiated and you want to see
that their state the capability is
received advertised and receive later
I was talking about that ipv6 Matt ipv4
address as you found my configuration
the next hop will stand off hand of 21
right well via MP bgp i'm going to
advertise the v6 prefix is behind me
next up is this ipv6
why build an ipv6 address out of my own
so then that there are over there
he's rotting table the max cops for the
ipv6
is this we're
show ipv6 drop I think being advertised
bad
the next have to be
ibc smash
show mpls folding table here we have the
tags are the the prefixes that are the
ipv6 prefix is listed and they are all
they're listed with aggregate untagged
one is a network that health that is
directly connected to do
there are
show bgp ipv6 unique as label here
you're going to see all the labels that
i learn along with the PX so i've been
the neighbor relationship with Vicki
that guy send me
the following information
he said that he knows about 2003
own lawn column 1
if I want to get over there my next stop
is
people that I should use the
send a packet classic speed
to be 124
ok
now
ah
okay there is a little bit of a small
piece missing them
okay if I do a show ipv6 sad
as I said I'm able to see the stack of
late
as you can see
next hop is again an ipv6
Zach we saw auto than advertised
I got it quietly
which in turn
deploying when Glen to the point 16 what
you do is you want to start up the edge
and then maybe add a few dollars if you
don't want to mess with your production
orders add a small router over there at
the edge make it at PE router turn on
six PE and sort of if you want isolate a
little bit that way resources but then
as your customers grow and grow and grow
and they go so fast amazing just move
towards towards the poor enable the
major routers for 60 more smooth work
accord and then turn on services want
you to have six fee you have the unique
as connectivity turn on services like
multicast not so much right not over six
feet we talked about an alternative but
you can turn on POS for 60 you can turn
on
so here is an example you had your own
network
where you have before
devices doing their own TV they're on
the small water there at the edge the
beach before degrees
and you have the 60 hours off to some
route reflectors you won't use
reflectors exact like you do with VPNs
for scalability purposes
you have no more pop
you are
maybe one your data set
to provide services and then as your
customers number of customers grows then
you start to move your devices you
increase the size of your ipv6 island
the device closer
and it burns its key
Sam scalability
there is a small slide here on interests
which is you use three labels here i'm
not going to go into this but i'm really
out of time but i can definitely talk
about it you won't get their ass or
carrier supporting carrier just a quick
note on load balancing it works just for
reference it for reference purposes you
look at the load balancing a few areas
but the 6p router is done based on
hashing source destination and on a few
outer now is supported on so just making
a control works
these are even better now ipv6 multicast
like I said there is no way to do it
over 6
and if the old right is the old problem
then pls you know all together we all
know that mpls does not really support
so they are all kind of work around same
thing with 16 work is being done
supported in the future but for now you
might want to consider an overload if
your customer really really want to do
multicast then you might consider an
overlay with some that that also
leverage mpls like um pls Donald Fraser
or multicast traffic
qsr is on the roadmap not supported at
this time beat the ends on the other
hand are supported we call this feature
6bp you have it on our routers and same
concept it's going to be pretty much
going to divide this big ipv6 cloud that
6p put together is going to divide it
into smaller clouds that are private and
I used for customers so now here is an
interesting thing why in the first place
really need VPNs now right i mean these
six is the next thing right we have all
the addresses in the world we don't need
private addressing you don't need to
hide our addressing scheme from other
etc security purposes of
big
but so why do we need to be B ends well
we need me for the fact that we are
usually at the ends network
administrators are used to running
and we still have the security problem
in fillmore
Weeden our network and four other people
can see them
but the question then is
how do you get out of this VPN right I
mean how do you get
ipv6 VPN
and connect with somebody else
to another network
highest esteem casa said said we d
you really want VPN
but then the question now is you have
your VPN you have your own world how you
get out of there so we have EP ends now
we have to work on the next step trying
to get out of that is not being done yet
that does that make sense or not
so just food for thought one way one
thing that you could do is we'd be sick
since we support so many addresses on
the same interface
what you might want to do with a VPN
deployment
v6
you might want to have to add the skins
on your network one address scheme that
goes out to the Internet so goes on over
a leaky VPN out late at night and one
addressing scheme that you use inside
your VPN for inside your enterprise
inside your domain
and then you let you let SAS to do the
job for you and hopefully does the right
job of selecting the right source
address whenever you send the traffic
I pretty much talked about the slide as
you can see 6p has traffic for all
clouds yellow and green six vp instead
yields similar type same way as in ipv6
and ipv4 different routing table
different polling tables and so on and
so forth configuration wise if you did I
p is equal to VPN on our rs6 VP is
exactly the same thing as a matter of
fact it was just a change in the VPN
code to support this
well I'm out of time so I'm not sure
here we go
one of the things that we notice was
service provider Sarah friends were
interested in in using ipv6 for
broadband access why well because
broadband access offers you the
opportunity to get more money out of
your customers right you can offer them
more services like video channels audio
channels and so on and so forth as an
example in in Japan cable TV is not such
a popular thing so why not use some of
the broadband channels to actually
deliver hktv can speckle this
so broadband employing I BGC seen in the
broadband environment he got a lot of
input so that's why we decided to
actually cover this example of discuss a
little bit about broadband access so in
principle ipv6 you really need not be
concerned about the layer to stop right
whether it is dsl well there is fiber to
the home cable and so on and so forth
well things are almost true for most of
these access media types that's the case
IP just practically six on it regardless
of the media things are a little bit
different in cable docsis the kind the
conversion of dots that is being
implement as being used is not really
conducive to ipv6 does not have all the
elements necessary for the table pieces
to support ipv6 so if you're thinking
about doing ipv6 over table right now
you're you're not best bet you're only
bad is tunneling everything else goes
away all the way you can do your
stagnated with all the other media and
actually salmon and colleague of ours
and myself we wrote a draft about
broadband access if you are interested
in more information on the cable side
and the problems that we face there and
the work that needs to be done there
encourage you to do Robredo we can
answer the other question
adsl and ftp access so when are we going
to have one of these media we chose 80s
and an FPT does the example you have
several ways in which your customers can
have can gain ipv6 connectivity they can
just have layer 3 connectivity dual
stack enable ipv6 natively between the
customer as a pc or as a customer
premise router and your access rather
the one that you manages the provider or
what you can do is you can use some form
of total of PPP than a connect so here
it's just a discussion on how this
protocol back up we show two models one
model is paint PPP so you just take your
ipv6 packet send over PPP
the two routers not necessarily have to
have a TV six natively enabled
that would be sort of a like a
point-to-point model and then we have an
aggregation model which is the second
one we're actually what you do is see in
the first case the VPP session is coming
the demands take it out of PTP the
package is taken out of TBC and then it
goes into the ipv6 cloud second example
you might want to do aggregation so you
might want to aggregate sum of this PPP
session hold the way to an aggregating
router to an LMS so you take all the
complete instructions bundle them up
into ELQ apt take it over take them over
an M 50 people to the LMS well you
unwrap the whole thing
traffic into the ipv6 world
and here is just protocol back in you
know
for detail for this for
dsl access configuration wise in this
case what we're looking at is we are
looking at obviously the interfaith
force under 80 important but then we're
looking at the PvP session configuration
is on a dollar and beside them besides
the TPP connectivity we put one
statement if it's relevant there which
is the ipv6 address auto-configuration
which advises the router how to get its
address from the Nance and also we have
to have a static route that says the
people because
says all your traffic send them out of a
pilot one and then the termination side
on the net
we support all the extensions for the
degree for ipv6 in radius they are all
listed here for for your reference and
racequip skip real quick over this
addressing allocation obviously when
you're going to start to build this
business case for your broadband access
I pcs runner access you want to think
about addressing now there is plenty of
addressing out there but you still want
to make money out of it maybe like
someone was mentioning the policy is
nowadays are us a service provider you
take your / 30 cube you might want to
assign your customer / 48 if they have a
small site over there or / 64 preferably
you don't cheat the customer and don't
go lord I mean higher than 64 you don't
know like 70-something or so on and so
forth but you know you as a certified
might choose to take some of the bits
and ask the customer for money you want
if you want to get all 48
but i but policies the recommendations
would be go / 48 or / 64
the one thing also to keep in mind with
this slide pretty much stays what what I
just said but one thing to keep in mind
is we'd be six we've sort of try to
stick to our promise that we will give
customers and address to keep for the
long run not like we'd be four we were
so stingy and we say all right here's an
address use it for two hours or three
hours then I'm going to take it back and
I'm going to reuse it so that in itself
might help in some situation it might
help with the with the management of the
addressing and might help the customer
with his configuration of the site
simplified but it might introduce some
some small complications in in how you
do things in your own metal versus
respire especially when you do
aggregation to give you an example if
you have in one of our discussions if
you have to terminating points for your
tunnel weather
or they are your lttp columns and you
have your customer that they can connect
to any of these Ellen asses or lazard's
right if I'm always going to leave my
customer the same prefix and you can end
up in any of these routers then it's
time to put holes in the prefixes that
each router can advertise so now i'm
going to have mixes of / 64th here
instead of being able to summarize them
too / 48 for example so policies or or
some thought has to be putting that in
this process we have a smallest amount
on the drop in in this you have to you
might want to put some policies in terms
of how customers can connect this
location if this customer will always
keep the same address but like in before
you might also choose you might also
choose to give your customers temporary
in this first third example here this is
an example where my customer is doing
always going to get the prefix 3ff pc00
and it's going to always get that
particular ID it's just the TC 0 0 0 1
but then the next few examples give you
some situations where you might want to
get short-lived addresses / 128 from a
pool or / 64
but one of the really cool things that
we have in ipv6 anyone talk about is
another means to actually provide
customers with P fixes and let them
dynamically manage those prefixes and
distribute them within their network and
that particular mechanism is called the
fce in six ed I'm not sure how many
room are familiar with it but the idea
would be that me as a customer whether
I'm a toll I have a reasonable level but
I'm a small enterprise
I can actually go to my provider and
dynamically ask for the prefix for my /
48 that I'm supposedly entitled to and
then won one time getting that / 48 I'm
going to intern go ahead and distribute
it cut it up and distribute to my
internal users or my internal interfaces
so let's see how this works let's say
that I'm have I have my here's my ISP
router and I have my cpu router which is
the Aurora that is on the cusp of it the
capital of credit
and protocol wise
on the customer side i'm using neighbor
discovery i'm using my DCP all the good
things that ipv6 uses for the users for
to exchange any information that they
need to get a real address get dhcp
formation get dns info
cpe in turn talks about whatever link
was established between it and Iran talk
dhcp
the PT router used to play to
authenticate or as a song get
information that he needs for his
customer from the radius
now first of all there is a one step
that was missed here in that TP comes up
the CPR owner comes up establishing the
link between
and the pina daughter
and basically since is the sensor a pack
of the request saying hey i'm looking
for a i'm looking for a rather the can
vp of prefix can give me a network
address the PE roller receives that
packet and authenticates talk to the
radius server authenticates this
customer
and gets on the radio the information
that it needs whatever prefix it can
hear that pasta
then the cpe router the pirata tells the
CPI hey I'm a DC tpd router i can give
you a prefix the 6p era let the Sun the
cpe roller comes back ok fine how about
you give me a prefect
saying that he's looking for a fit for
prefix delegation the PE router based on
the information that if God from the
radius server is going to send a DC to
reply saying okay here is your prefix
that you can use a / 48 for example the
60 router
the cpe router takes a prefix that's
left 48 and then we cut it in pieces
however it decides to and assigns those
pieces we own interfaces so each of each
interface you will now get a slice of
that / 48 or whatever world that PVC
from the ISP
wanted it assigned one of those
past seven Radha ever
okay it's
okay it starts to send out a router
advertisement saying here's the prefix
that you can use the host can advertise
can auto configure itself is in the
regular idealistic auto configuration
and then it can continue with the
process of getting in South table while
talking on the v6 world by sending a
request for DNS services and so on and
so forth configuration wise real quick
i nibble the varsity
on my valuated face so we could
be applied for the Nasdaq scan
provide him with the people
and any precinct
that def speaker
then in turn once he got that prefix
he's going to go to his own interface
fast ethernet
that those extra bits of kislev 64
plus my interface IP
I decided to be
EU ice
any questions on that sub vc DVD
here is some information on draft that
we mentioned encourage you
and that that will be
vcp works great
actually it's actually it's in fact is
using in production as being is the
production httpd
it's very practical
especially for customers
well one of the customers that we were
working with for example they plan for
each one of these for forming networks
or you know like small business networks
they just give them a staff 48
and then the customer slashes that is
left 64 and the science plastics before
to each interface
as you typical you don't want on that
clients that you don't go below the old
loudoun and in less than 60 for because
you just want to keep the UI
thank you