(modem dial-up sounds)
(funky music)
(television static noise)
- Well thank you guys for coming,
welcome to CypherCon,
my name is Joe Grand.
This talk is pretty interesting to me
because I normally give technical talks
and we'll go a little
bit into my background
but when Michael invited
me and the theme was
the '80s retro telephreaking
historical sort of nostalgia,
I was like okay well
let's think of something
a little bit differently than
I've spoken about in the past
'cause I'm normally a computer engineer,
I'm a hardware hacker,
I've been doing this
for my entire life as you'll see.
I'm a runner, I'm a daddy.
But I was like what if I put together
a presentation that talks
about the time where nobody
knows about except for maybe a few stories
that my wife knows, but most people don't.
So this presentation is something
that's not really meant to be a bio,
but it talks about some
tales of the olden days,
of the '80s and the '90s
of hacking and phreaking
and juvenile delinquency and sort of
messing around and exploring in a time
where there weren't a lot of rules,
or I guess there were, but I
just didn't listen to them.
So it's really goes along with the theme
as you'll see with the
hacking and the phreaking
and like Michael says in
the conference program
about nostalgia, like it's great to hear
all these old stories,
but then it's important
to take those old stories and say okay
well what can you apply to newer stuff
so my goal is not to just stand up here
and tell you how bad I was as a kid,
which is pretty
embarrassing, but to get you
to be inspired of like okay
well maybe I can still do this
even though things are different now
and there's new laws and new things,
there's also new technology
and there's new villages
and there's new opportunities
to do this stuff
where I didn't have the
same opportunities early on.
So it's still using that hacker mindset
just in a way that isn't
gonna get you thrown in jail.
So my story really I don't
think is that much different
from people that grew up
in the early '80s and,
or mid '80s and early '90s who
were involved in computers.
I got my first computer
when I was seven years old
in 1982 and was just infatuated with it.
And I think it's important
that people share these stories
and that's, again, why I'm doing this
because that's sort of this
lost era of the hacker world
before it became what it is now.
And a lot of, everyone has a past, right?
Everybody has stories
but not a lot of people
actually want to admit what
they've done in the past
and I think that's an important thing to,
first of all because it's fun,
second of all because I finally
wanted to say this stuff
but just so everybody can have a say
in what that history was really like.
So pretty much everything
you're gonna see has never
been shown before and some
of it's very embarrassing.
But I just found this stuff
and I was like this is cool.
So like I said, I got my
first computer in 1982,
I have an older brother
who's six years older than me
and he was involved in
computers, so he was 13
and he had an Atari 400 and
we basically would play games
and collect games and use
bulletin board systems
to talk to other people, but
he decided to become a musician
and gave all of his computer
stuff to me which is awesome.
Around that same time, he was
also involved in electronics
and, for me, I would
like do a chore for him,
I would clean his room or
bring his laundry upstairs
or whatever it was and
he would let me pick
a piece of electronics from his junk box,
so it was like this amazing
thing and really without him
I would never have been
exposed to this world at all.
So yeah, this is me in
let's see I was eight
so I guess second grade
or something like that
and already, that's an Atari
400 for those who don't know,
the retro gaming village in that room,
I don't know if it has an Atari
but it has this era of stuff
so imagine a bunch of kids
using that stuff in that room.
I was a latchkey kid, I had a
normal middle class upbringing
so a lot of you might wonder
as we start going through this
like how did he get over there?
He had normal parents,
normal school and everything
but something just clicked
with the hacker world
and as you'll see with some other stuff.
So I spent a lot of time with my computer,
it was a way for me to just
discover lots of things
on my own and it was
really fun, and back then
if you had a computer it
was something where you
were either really lucky
like I was or your parents
maybe were involved in
some academia or research
or something that required a computer,
it wasn't like it was today.
And it was really something
where if you had a computer
like you were sort of a weirdo already.
This one was age 10 so around 1985,
I still have that computer
and yeah so television,
I have a terminal program
running on here, XE Term,
which was the terminal
program, my modem you can't see
but I'm guessing by '85 I
had a 1200 baud modem maybe.
Most of my early days
were using a 300 baud
acoustic coupler modem, which
there's an acoustic coupler
in the other room also which is awesome.
And this was an age where
I was doing a lot of
game collecting and playing games
and that's really why I used the computer.
What ended up happening is
when you're collecting games,
and I've heard this story
from other people too,
is you're collecting games,
you want to then find
other games that are
outside of your region.
So I could call local calls
within the Boston area
where I'm from, but I wanted to connect
to other bulletin board systems,
'cause places in California
or New York like they had cooler games,
or at least that was sort
of the thought process.
So we had to call those numbers.
I originally was just
dialing long distance
and had to pay for it,
but being a 10 year old
like that wasn't a very useful thing to do
because I wasn't making that much money,
I think I just was getting allowance.
But I found a code written
on one of my brother's
floppy disks that was one of the codes
that you could use from various services
that actually would let
you use to place calls.
So sort of like a corporate
code, you have an 800 number
that you would dial, you'd
enter some six digit pin
and then you could get access and call
long distance wherever
you wanted in the country,
which it turns out is illegal.
(crowd laughing)
What did I know?
Actually I probably already
knew, but I didn't care.
The quest was to get the games
and connect to other
bulletin board systems.
So it just happened, just
like I never would have been
introduced to electronics
and computers if it wasn't
for my brother, I wouldn't
have gotten into the phreaking
side of things either so
it's really all his fault.
So I found one on his, on the floppy disk
and that sort of set the
stage of things to come.
Once I realized that I could go to other
bulletin board systems
and start communicating
with other people, the
hacker world at that time
was still very localized,
so you had groups of people
in Boston, in New York, in
California, in the Midwest,
in Texas, but there wasn't
this real connection
but then with bulletin
board systems everybody was
using codes to get access
for free long distance,
it's just what it was and I
think some of the older guys
at the time were like
we're gonna fight the man,
the telephone shouldn't be so expensive,
we're gonna do it for free,
but I think most of us
were just doing it
'cause it was convenient.
So I got a little bit into software
for a very brief second,
I'll tell you one story
that sort of pushed me back into hardware.
Back into hardware for
good, did we just lose this?
Oh, okay.
So this is a program that I
wrote when I was seven or eight
and some of you might
recognize what it is,
it's called electric dog,
I found this program,
it's in BASIC and so here it
is, little loading screen.
(electronic beeping)
Can anyone guess what that is?
It was on the label, which
you might not be able to see,
that was K9 from Doctor Who,
and it looks just like him
for a eight year old or whatever.
So I did a little bit of programming
and actually taught myself
hexidecimal by hacking
or modifying the binary of
somebody else's cracked game,
because you know they have
the crack screens on there
that says cracked by
whatever, I would change that
and make it say Joey Grand or Black Ninja
which is what I was at the time.
So just sort of experimenting, I was like
oh if I just change these values
in this hex editor program,
it changes the thing
so it was pretty cool.
I never got into software cracking because
most of my kinda passion was in hardware.
I found this just the other
day looking for pictures
and stuff, my first handle was
Black Ninja when I was seven,
which is hilarious because
when my son turned seven,
the first name he gave himself
was Black Ninja and I realized huh,
I think every seven year old likes ninjas,
and if they're black
ninjas it's even cooler
'cause they're more
mysterious or something.
So it sounded cool, but this was my list
of all the games that
I'd collected over time
and they were all numbered
and very anally organized.
I had other names too,
Astro Zombie, Auto Von,
FBI Agent, and ultimately
settled on Kingpin.
So at the time, besides
being involved with computers
which was a bad thing to be at the time,
I got involved in punk rock and hardcore,
woo hoo, so this was
1989, I was 13 years old
and so I would basically
spend either all of my time
using the computer and
the rest of the time
just being a complete mischievous whatever
you wanna call it outside of that.
And this is what's sort of interesting,
I still haven't been
able to figure this out.
I'm 42 now and this was a long time ago
and I'm still drawn to that
sort of subculture of music
and the counterculture of everything,
and I still haven't figured out like
I had a normal upbringing,
we didn't have the struggles
that a lot of people that
get into punk rock do,
but I'm still attracted to
that world so I don't know.
This combination was dangerous.
And this is when I sort
of knew, I'm normal,
everyone else is not normal,
that's how I sort of took it.
Also at the time, which
I think is important
to sort of see this
progression kind of happen
is after discovering punk rock which was
all about fuck everything
up, I started in high school
there's a lot of peer
pressure to drink, right?
And do drugs and go to
parties and all of this stuff
and I was like this is stupid,
I just wanna use my computer.
I don't wanna do that stuff,
so I rebelled against that
as well and discovered
straight edge which really
was my kind of direction for a long time,
which was involved in the
kind of punk and hardcore
music scene of like I'm not gonna drink,
I'm not gonna smoke,
I'm not gonna do drugs,
I'm gonna be a vegetarian, I'm gonna have
this clean, positive kind
of mindset and clean mind.
So while I was like this
very almost, people would
make fun of me for being
like a goody two shoes,
they had no idea what I was
doing with my sober clean mind
when I wasn't around other people.
And I'll show you some examples.
And then skateboarding also,
so this was like the trifecta
of things you didn't
want to be in the '80s
because you would get your ass kicked.
And this was something where
I was tormented emotionally
so people would make
fun of me all the time,
whatever it was, I had friends
that I would skateboard with
and stuff who were not technical people
so we'd go into Boston
and we'd get made fun of
and we'd get into fights
and we'd get beat up.
It was just like this really weird thing
and then having a computer
was the same thing,
like people in school
would be like oh you nerd,
fat whatever, like all of
these things that really hurt
and my sort of response
to that was like okay
well that gave me this thick
skin of like well I'm gonna do
whatever I want to do and I
don't care what anyone says
and that has sort of
followed on for a long time,
so that's a theme actually
of this whole thing is like
do what you wanna do no
matter what other people say.
And I think that ended up being both good
and bad for me, as you'll probably see.
So some of these stories
I talk about phreaking,
I talk about kind of credit card fraud
and stuff that seemed
normal to me at the time,
actually it still seems normal
to me, as bad as that is.
But I have to sort of
preface it with I was sort of
just one generation of
hacker, so before me,
of course, people have been
exploring technology way before.
I was just one piece of that lineage.
So I thought this one was cool, this was a
picture of Marconi in his
lab in 1903 and he had given
a demonstration to show off the first
Morse code transmission,
so wireless, I don't know
if it was a spark gap
transmitter or whatever it was,
but he was saying to the
press and tell me how,
this is so relevant to
today in infosec even,
he said I have this new
system, I'm gonna show you
that we can wirelessly communicate data,
totally insecure, nobody can hack it.
And there was a guy, Italian
guy, I don't know how
to say his name, Meville Maskelyne,
who was a magician and he
was like that's bullshit,
I know how this system
works, I'm gonna hack it.
So he ended up, when Marconi
was giving his demonstration,
he sent his own messages over Morse code
to the receiver saying like
he was saying rats, R-A-T-S,
rats rats and then he said some poem
making fun of Marconi,
which was like so awesome.
Just that hacker ethic from 1903, right?
So it's like anything we do
that we think is interesting,
we're just standing on the
shoulders of other people,
so that was really pretty cool.
Oh yeah, so actually the
story that he started with
it says there was a young fellow of Italy
who diddled the public quite prettily.
(crowd laughing)
So there have been trolls
for a long time also.
Other stuff, too, so Esquire
Magazine October 1971
was an article that inspired
a whole generation of people
and before this, people had been exploring
telephone networks through MIT,
through other universities,
y'know making free phone
calls and phone phreaks,
or phone pranks, calling
people using the blue box
to gain access to the phone
network and travel around
using multifrequency
tones and stuff like that,
so there was already this
culture of telephone exploration
by the time I got involved and sort of
just took advantage of all of it.
There was actually a letter to the editor
that I found from this article
and this guy says it says so
much about our relationship
to our technology, the
union of isolated spirits
through electronics, the
computerized craziness of our times
and that was 1971, so
just you can already see
that similarity even to this
day where everyone's like
there's too much technology but technology
brings us together
still, but that paranoia
was there earlier so I just
think that's really interesting.
But I think also that Marconi example
is like what we do at hacker conferences,
we'll find vulnerabilities
and talk about them
and it's what, 115 years later
and we're still doing the same thing.
And then I would be remiss to not mention
the 414s being in Milwaukee.
Are there any 414s here?
'Cause I heard there
were last year, right?
Okay, I was hoping there would be.
So yeah, this was a group,
and there's actually
some Wisconsin history section over there
at the conference, they were
a group that actually met
through IBM's Explorer
Club which was hosted
by the Boy Scouts to let
people explore computers.
And they ended up breaking into all sorts
of computer systems that
were connected over the modem
and really were the first,
I would say the first
publicly known hacker
group and it was just
a group of 16 to 22 year old kids.
But that was like a
really interesting time
and then Wargames came out
and that inspired more people.
We had like the Legion of Doom, LoD,
Masters of Deception, MoD,
hacker groups sometimes warring
with each other trying to
one up each other of like
can we listen on people's
cell phone, normal phone,
landline calls, can we
hack the whatever ESS,
I don't remember what version,
can we hack the ESS switch
to listen in on phone calls
and do all of this stuff.
Kevin Mitnick, of course,
Kevin Poulsen who had hacked
various radio stations, hacked phone lines
so he could be the only person to dial in
to win the Porsche, so
people were doing this stuff.
So I definitely wasn't that
first generation of hackers
but I will say I think that I was part
of the last generation
that got to do what we did
before the mainstream got involved in it
and a lot of the laws
changed, it was a little bit
like yes it was illegal
at the time but it wasn't
totally enforced and I knew
people that got in trouble,
myself included, but it wasn't
like it is today, the
world is much different.
Okay, so let's see some stories.
So one of the, besides collecting games,
what ended up happening
is after collecting games
that sort of evolved into,
as I got older I was like
okay well playing games
is alright, I realized
I'm not a good game player,
but I still loved technology
and I loved communicating
with other people
and I loved the bulletin board systems.
What I ended up doing is a
lot more of like war dialing,
so saying okay I know these phone numbers
are known BBS's, what if
I use a war dialer program
to try every single number of this prefix
and so I would dial
10,000 different numbers,
usually you'd let the
program run overnight,
you needed a direct dial
modem, you couldn't do it
with an acoustic coupler, and
you wake up in the morning
and you have a list of
phones that phone numbers
that were modems, so then you
could go through and connect
to things and it was really
such an easy process.
It's sort of like if
you have your badge now,
there's actually a war
dialer program in your badge
so you can connect up to this USB port,
hook it up to the phone line and war dial
the telephone network that's
up in the other room too
and sort of get that
feeling of what it's like.
And you can do it manually as well,
'cause you could just sit there
and dial, y'know 555-0000,
555-0001, over and over
again and see what you get.
You'd hang up on a lot of people,
but then if you connected to a modem
then it would keep track of that
so that's how you would discover systems
and even if they were passworded,
that's just the next step right?
Just finding the computers,
it's like a scan now
on the internet, see what ports are open
of different things using Shodan to see
what IOT devices are connected.
This was just slower.
So it sort of evolved
into not the trading games
but trading codes and
trading phone numbers
of things that I had war
dialed with somebody else
that would war dial something else
and it just became this
gathering of information,
I was like a hoarder of information.
Not necessarily to use it
all, but just to have it.
And I thought that was really neat.
Some bulletin board systems,
too, also had secret sections
so you had like the game trading sections,
if you could get to
those, but there was also
other sections sometimes that
would be like the hacker side,
and then you could trade codes
and do all of this other stuff.
Inside of the book, this was
the first page of my first book
which was the red one,
there's three of them.
They get more and more
nefarious as the years go on,
but this I was not even
15 when I started this,
so I was just fascinated
with what phone numbers
could you call and what could they do
and log in usernames and
passwords for various systems.
I didn't even know what the systems were
but just to be able to go and
explore and connect to them,
it's sort of like with
lockpicking now, right?
Lockpicking village is huge
because having that power
to unlock something,
even if you never use it
to break into something,
it's just like really cool.
Except I did end up using that
stuff to break into things.
So let's see, some of the early stuff,
y'know bulletin board
systems, trading information,
I did a lot of telephone kind
of centric goofing around
so I did connect to
various computer systems
that I shouldn't have, I'll
talk about one of them later.
But I just loved using the phone
and you could really fuck
with people on the phone.
So I actually found a
recording of my first,
not my first but one of my
earliest recorded prank calls,
I had just turned 14, some of
you guys might get insulted,
so sorry (laughing), so
it was christmas time
and being who I am, said
well christmas is what?
It's like Jesus' birthday right?
So I'm gonna look up people
named Jesus in the white pages
and then call them up and
wish them happy birthday.
(crowd laughing)
So let's see, I'll try to play
it, see if you can hear it.
(phone ringing)
Is Jesus there?
- [Jesus] Yeah?
- [Joe] Is this Jesus?
- [Jesus] Yeah.
- [Joe] Happy birthday.
- [Jesus] Good.
(crowd laughing)
So my voice hadn't changed yet,
did you hear it in the back?
Yeah okay, so just stuff
like that, that was fun.
What we would also trade
are voicemail systems,
so one way that hackers
would exchange information
back in the day before the internet,
besides bulletin board systems
and besides meeting in person
which once in a while
happened, mostly around
trading games and stuff, is
through hacked voicemails.
And you would find the
voicemail box somewhere,
call an 800 number or somebody might say
hey this is a voicemail for my dad's work,
so you'd call that and you'd
hack somebody's voicemail
password, which normally is
gonna be like 0000 or 1234,
actually not that much
different than today,
except this was 30 years ago.
So you would hack their voicemail system,
you would use that as a
way to share information
with other people, you'd say
okay here's my list of stuff
that I know, leave a
message with stuff you know,
I'll go share that, that
gets relayed over here,
and you have this network
of people communicating
over other people's
voicemail and then you get
the legitimate user after
the weekend or something
comes back and says wait a
second someone's hacked my thing
so they change the password
and they leave a voicemail
like this number, you
can't use this anymore,
it's my voicemail, and then
you'd just go find another voicemail.
So this recording, I ended up
finding a whole bunch of tapes
that Whisker from the toy
makers digitized for me,
all of them are now up on archive.org,
if you search for Kingpin
voicemail collection,
there's a whole list of voicemail systems,
I'll just play one
that's one of my favorite
that's sort of a short
one and you can just
sorta get a feeling of
like what types of stuff
were out there and you
can tell by his voice
that he was just another
kid doing this stuff,
so really cool so here we go.
- [Operator] Please enter your
three digit extension number now.
(numbers dialing)
- [Mike] Hello Mike Hunt
here with a 1-800-458-5035,
also a 193187, next 206085,
next 209649 I think that is,
maybe a seven, so 3215, next 205309,
net two fucking place here's more codes.
Same number 715132, next 715248,
next 715632, next 715964.
All those would have to be freshly hacked
by a crow fly, okay
here goes the Mastercard
at 5329 0217 8301 3120
expiration date is 8/90.
Okay to the guy who gave that to me,
you said you want Mastercards
with names and shit,
I can get a lot of those but give me
a number where I can
reach you or a BnB okay?
See what else I got, here's
on if this still works,
474-2010, um okay guys,
leave what you want.
Message, fuckin messages
on here are pretty long
we got actually three minutes
so just slow the fuck down
when you say your shit, okay?
That's all I can say
right now, this is Mike
oh wait here's one 1-800-234-5095,
codes are 590447 and 8148870.
Okay and this is Mike Hunt, later on.
Oh shit, keep on having more shit.
Okay here's a calling
card, 8919 938 7824 2403,
next 919 938, oh shit fuck that one.
Sorry about that, leave what you want,
call my other box if you
wanna leave shit too,
it's 1-800-284-2337 box
number is 2125, okay?
This is Mike Hunt, later.
- So you can see he started
off with a bunch of codes
for doing free long distance
and then threw a credit card
in there, which of course if
a bunch of hackers get that,
that's gonna be used very quickly,
I'll talk a little bit
about credit card stuff.
And then another voicemail box to call to
so it was like this web and
I don't know who that guy is,
I would love to meet
him 'cause that was like
when I recorded that I was
like this guy is so cool
'cause I was even younger than that
and I was like this guy is
awesome, I wonder where he lives.
But I had no idea.
Because of using the
codes that I was using
which were 1-800 numbers
and I don't exactly know
how traceable those were at
the time and all of that,
doing prank calls and voicemail
hacking and everything,
I was really paranoid about
who was calling my house.
And so I created a board
which I'll show you later on
that was called ring busy
device, and it was a resistor,
just a single resistor
that would go in line
between the ring and the
tip of the telephone line
and that would still let you dial out
so my parents could use the phone,
but if somebody tried to call the house,
they would get a busy signal,
actually it would ring once
and then be a busy signal.
So that would prevent these companies
from calling and complaining
and having my teachers
call and complain about
whatever I did that day.
And it actually worked, I
used it for a long time,
I don't actually know
if my parents know that,
so now you do 'cause
they wanna watch this.
I warned them they probably shouldn't
watch this presentation
but I think they will.
So I got a phone call one day and I always
recorded every phone call which
is also illegal by the way.
But I recorded this one,
so see if you can notice what's going on.
(phone ringing)
- [Joe] Hello.
- [Man] Hey you're busted, man.
You ain't got long distance service.
- [Joe] Excuse me?
- [Man] Yeah.
Who's this, who's calling please?
- [Man] Huh?
- [Joe] Who's calling please?
- [Man] Secret Service,
federal department.
- [Joe] Uh can I please have your name?
I think you might have the wrong number.
- [Man] No we show this number 617 (beep)
- [Joe] That's my phone number.
Yes that is the number.
- [Man] Okay, thank you,
we're just confirming that.
- So that was sort of hard to hear
but this guy called me out of the blue
and he's like you're
busted, but he was obviously
also pretending to be somebody else
because Secret Service doesn't
have a federal department,
they are a federal department.
But it still freaked me
out, and you can hear like,
what I did a lot of times
too is people called me
Mickey Mouse growing up
because my voice was so high
like you heard in that other
video, so I would try to be
like hello this is, I'm sorry
you have the wrong number,
but I still had a high
voice so that was me trying
to sound older, which you'll
hear on the next one too
which I don't understand
how people even believed
this stuff, especially
when I started actually
ordering things with
credit cards and I'm like
hello I would like to order
this video camera to my house.
Yeah so having a high voice
didn't work out too well.
So one of the things also
that a lot of hackers did
was do what are called
alliance teleconferences,
and these were teleconference
systems that were run
by AT&T and businesses would use them,
sort of like a conference call
now or whatever people use,
Skype or I don't even know what people use
for conference calls,
Slack, no you can't do voice
with Slack, I don't know, whatever it is,
three-way calling for lots of people.
So it was a conference
call system I think it was
$5 per minute per line that
was on the conference call.
A lot of these, actually a
lot of alliance teleconference
recordings, I had some but
they were inappropriate
to post to archive.org and
inappropriate to play here
but some of them are on
archive.org from other people
that you hear all these
hackers, like legendary hackers
on the phone messing with
people 'cause you basically have
a giant group conference,
it's like IRC for voice.
And the way you would start these systems
is whoever calls in to start
the teleconference pays the fee
pays the money so you werent'
gonna do that from your house,
you might be able to do
it through other ways
of getting access to
some, like through PBX
to get access to an outdial
that would call out.
But what I would do
since I lived in Boston,
I would hop on my bike,
ride down into the city
into like an alleyway, I
had my lineman handset,
take off the cover of one
of the phone junction boxes
that covered like all the
apartments in the back,
clip on to one of those,
hope no one was on the phone
at the time, I'd get a
dialtone, start the conference,
and then transfer control of
the conference to a friend
of mine and then unclip,
ride my bike home,
and the conference would be
running for 12 hours at a time.
And we'd call everybody,
people from around the,
usually local but also other places too
because like I had my
friends and then they
might know somebody in
New York, let's call him.
This guy likes a girl in California
that they met at camp, let's call her
and it was like this
totally ridiculous thing
that would go on for
hours and hours and hours
and for those of you who
remember having phones,
like I'm sure everybody
in here who's my age
or maybe slightly younger
and definitely older
like spent time on the phone
with like somebody you liked
and you'd lie in bed and you'd
talk on the phone for awhile
and you would do that for hours and hours
and like my ear would turn
red and it was just so fun.
So we would call party
lines like at the time
there were actually
legitimate party lines going,
1-900 whatever and you would call those
and it would be like a,
I don't even know what
a good example is, a
forum for whatever sex
or I don't know whatever stuff.
So we would call those
and then like just screw
with whatever, we'd pretend
to be that type of person
or whatever which was
just totally horrible.
We would also call girls that we liked
and sometimes prank
call girls that we liked
because we didn't know how
to actually communicate
with people that we liked at the time.
So we would call them or we
would have somebody call up
and be like hey is this Samantha?
And they'd be like yeah Samantha,
uh Joe says hi click,
just stuff like that,
and then sometimes we'd just
bring on, we'd call people
and the thing is like
there was no caller ID,
your house phone would
just ring and so someone's
parent would answer, hello,
it's like is Bill there,
and we'd talk to Bill for
four hours, it was just chaos.
One time I remember I
was in New York working
and got a phone call
from one of my friends
who was on a conference,
we decided to connect
directory assistance operators
from all over the country
together, 'cause you
know you would call 411
to get directory assistance
but you could also call
a local number for each
of those areas to connect
to directory assistance,
so we brought them all
into the conference and
then we all stopped talking.
(crowd laughing)
And they at first they
were like hello Kentucky
directory assistance, how can I help you?
And someone else was like
California directory assistance,
and they're like what's going
on, this is really weird
and then they just all start talking.
So it's like we're
bringing people together
by screwing with them and
I don't remember how long
they were on the phone
for but it was hilarious.
So imagine 20 people on
the phone for eight hours,
12 hours at a time, $5 a
minute, it was not cheap
and companies did not like that.
Also AT&T did not like
that so they started
doing their own investigations
into misuse of stuff,
so I got a phone call one day,
okay and another reason why
the ring busy device was good,
my parents weren't home during the day
so I could turn it off and
see who was gonna call me.
I got a phone call and the
person on the other end
started naming every single
name and phone number,
or every single name of people that were
on the conference call, and
there were names of people
I didn't even know because
we were all using handles,
but it was every name
and I was like oh my god,
we're so screwed, so you can hear me
trying to act very like oh very innocent.
- [Woman] June 18th at
9:56 in the evening.
- [Joe] June 18th, um,
yeah I don't have any idea.
- [Woman] It was a conference call.
- [Joe] Conference call.
- [Woman] Involving a
bunch of different numbers
so that not a lot of people
would be on the same call.
- [Joe] Um no I have no idea,
I don't have triple on though.
- [Woman] No something originated
from your phone number,
it was originated from a number
in Clarksville, Tennessee
and they, y'know, included
all the other numbers.
So that the charges weren't
on your bill at all.
- [Joe] Um, hmm, I don't
know anyone from Tennessee.
Is this, do you know if this
is some kind of mistake, or?
- [Woman] Well the calls
weren't billed to your phone
and they won't be because
you're not responsible
in any way, I'm just trying to find out
who initiated the call,
if I give you names,
can you tell me if you recognize them?
- [Joe] Um okay yeah, I'll try.
I'll see what I can do.
(beep)
Uh nope.
- [Woman] (beep) In California
- [Joe] Uh no.
- [Woman] (beep) In Tennessee.
- [Woman] (beep) in Boston, Massachusetts.
- [Joe] Nope.
- [Woman] (beep) one of the parties
call from Sterling Heights, Michigan.
- [Joe] Hm, yeah none
of these sound familiar.
(beep)
Uh, nope.
- [Woman] (beep) Sterling Heights.
- [Joe] Uh nope.
- [Woman] And the last one, (beep).
- [Joe] Uh no.
(beep)
Nope, nope.
- [Woman] (beep) Memphis.
- [Joe] Nope.
- [Woman] (beep) Cordova, Tennessee.
- [Woman] (beep) Oldford, Massachusetts.
- [Joe] Uh no I don't know any of them.
- [Woman] Alright, are you the only one
that would answer the phone there?
- [Joe] Um yeah.
- [Woman] Okay thank you very much.
- [Joe] Okay, bye.
So you can imagine my fear after that lady
just naming every single
person that was on
the conference call, asking
if I was the only person
to answer that phone,
so I went ahead and then
started calling people and were like
I just got a call from
the alliance operator.
But that was sort of the kind of
stress you lived under doing this stuff.
And ultimately, I never got in trouble
for alliance stuff which was good.
So here's one that was a friend of mine
was war dialing and apparently
somebody answered the phone
and war dialing you normally do at night,
while you're sleeping, so
somebody answered the phone
and she got pretty angry
and left a message for him.
So here, this one might be a little loud,
so just I tried to turn it
down, she was really angry.
(crowd laughing)
But so you'll see this.
- [Angry Lady] For some reason
you're calling my number,
I don't know who own that,
we might need a new number.
Please don't call that number again
because I will have
the police calling you.
Don't you dare call my
telephone number tonight
and call on nine or
whatever, wherever you are.
I don't care who you are,
that's no reason to call me
in the middle of the night
and I'm gonna have the curb or something
and I will have them come on you.
If you a killer, or whatever, I don't know
who the hell you are but
you don't call me tonight
and wake me up in the middle
of the night, you hear me?
- So I can imagine that
happening all over the country
all the time because the war dialers
were going and people would answer.
Makes me nervous just hearing it.
So yeah were indirectly effecting people,
not that I feel bad about
it but it was sort of funny.
So this one's a little
bit of RF radio hacking,
so this is something, we have
software-defined radios now,
we have lots of methods of
manipulating wireless systems,
what we used to do back in the day,
this was November, around November 1992,
is we had HAM radios, and
HAM radios will transmit
in a defined range, so I
had a two meter HAM radio,
I think it was 144 to 146 or something,
HAM people will know, but
I had modified my radio,
it was in Icom 2SRA to
transmit at a wider band
so I could transmit from 138
to 174 megahertz or something
which violates the FCC
rules and I'll probably
get my HAM radio license taken away now
'cause I'm admitting to doing it.
But we would modify the
transmit frequency outside
of that range and it just so happens
that maybe even still to
this day I'm not sure,
that the fast food drive through windows,
the speakers were all wireless,
which meant you could
transmit to the people
inside wearing the headsets
that are taking your order
or you could transmit out the speaker
and really screw with people.
So this is one where I was in
the car with a friend of mine,
this one's really hard to
hear so I'll sort of explain
at the end but we're
sitting in the parking lot
a little further away, we
see a guy come up and he
starts his order, and then we
jump in and sort of harass.
So here we go.
- [Man] Yeah can I have two
quarter pounders with cheese?
- [Joe] He'll eat 20 Big Macs please.
That was us.
- [Drive Thru] Can you
hold on for one second?
Alright, can I take your order?
- [Man] Medium cheeseburger
- [Joe] I'd just like 10 in a bag please,
just 10 in the bag, we're next.
- [Man] I'd still like a
quarter pounder with cheese,
three cheeseburgers and two large Cokes.
- [Drive Thru] Can you pull around
to the second window for me please?
- [Joe] And also in a brown paper bag,
I want 10 bags I'm really
hungry, I'm really hungry.
- [Woman] Please pull around.
- [Joe] I can't, my tires are slashed.
Wait a second, wait okay.
Can I have hot dogs delivered?
I guess I can't, I'll just park my car.
- [Woman] Hey, is anyone at the speaker?
- [Joe] Yeah just hand me that.
- [Woman] Who's ordering 10 Big Macs?
Who's ordering 10 Big Macs?
Mike, are you hearing anything?
- [Mike] He's gone.
- [Woman] Just me?
Mike are you hearing anything but me?
Okay if you hear it again, I want you to
let me know 'cause I'm
gonna call the police.
- So the loud voice obviously was us
transmitting over the
radio and at the beginning
there's a guy that's like I
want three quarter pounders
with cheese and we're
like we want 20 Big Macs
and you can hear him go no not that many.
(crowd laughing)
And then he drives away and
we're still harassing them
and we're not even there,
and we got the point
where we would do it and it's like
can you come to the window,
who's at the window?
And it's like I don't
have any arms or legs,
I can't get it was just horrible.
So anyway, that was just
some of the mischief
that we did, and like
I said like this stuff
just felt normal, it was
playing around with stuff
and just being a punk
juvenile delinquent kid.
What I also got into
was cloning cellphones,
and this was later on but
because of my fascination
with technology and with electronics,
cellphones at the time that
were on the Amp'd network
would use ESN and MIN pairs,
electronic serial number
and a mobile identification number.
If you had that pair,
you could program that
into other phones and then use that
and then those phone
calls would get billed
to the ESN MIN account, so it was actually
really easy with certain types of phones
to load your own ESN and MIN pairs in
and then you could use
that for a day or two,
call 900 porn numbers
and call your friends
and everything and not get billed
and then change to another one.
I ended up selling those in high school,
which was a good way to make money
but I found myself in like
really sketchy areas of town,
in like projects and I'm like
this sorta chubby white kid
and selling phones to people
that were friends of friends
of other people, but it
was actually sorta fun
and a good way to get
money that I could then
go buy electronics and other stuff with.
So that's sort of a side thing,
but just another example of this sort of
craziness that came out
of this hacker world.
I do have one request that
a friend of mine requested
I tell this story that isn't
exactly technical related,
but a little bit of physical security.
So I grew up in Boston, the
public transit system there
is called the MBTA, so
the train system there
where besides just hanging
on the back of the train
to get free train rides, which was fun,
it wasn't very safe so
one of the other things
that we would do, especially
if the train was full,
the train is like, I don't
know how to explain it,
it's like a bi-directional train
so you have the conductor's
booth at both ends
so when the train turns
around, the conductor goes
to the other side and
gets to the other track
and keeps going so the
conductor's in the front
of the train driving the train,
that means the back conductor
booth is open and empty.
And when the train is
full and you're surrounded
by Bostonians who are just
naturally mean anyway,
myself included, I wanted a nice plush,
comfortable seat to sit in.
It turns out that the locks on those doors
were one type of skeleton key,
I don't remember what type
but I grew up in an
old house that had lots
of skeleton keys so I just took a bunch
and tried each one until it worked.
If you didn't have a
skeleton key, you could just
use a credit card as a shim to push
the latch out of the way to get in.
So then you'd go and
sit, you'd push everyone
out of the way you'd go sit in the back
of the train and get your ride in comfort.
But then that was sort of boring
'cause now you're sitting there
just looking out the back of the train
so what we decided to do was
oh, we can control everything
from the back of the train also.
We didn't try to drive it or anything,
which now that I'm thinking about it
would have been actually really funny,
but you could do like the
bell, like the warning
as they cross over the
tracks, ding ding ding.
So we would do that, we'd
sometimes honk the horn
and then we'd see the button
for PA, it's like oh yeah.
So what we would do is
like we'd use the PA
and you'd be like next
stop is the last stop
on this train, sorry
everybody has to get out
and then you'd hear everyone go ugh,
and then the train would go
err, the driver would stop,
and like we're in the
middle of the train tracks,
and then run down the
thing to try to get in.
Sometimes we had friends on the inside
and friends on the outside
to see what the conductors
would do trying to get
to the back of the train,
so we knew that they
were gonna come after us
but it was just so funny and we would say
all sorts of different stuff, as kids do.
So what we'd end up doing is we'd do that,
we'd honk the horn, we'd use the PA,
the train would stop, the
conductor would come down
and we would open a
window and just jump out
the window of the train and
run off down the tracks.
So that was a story by request.
Sorry mom and dad.
(group laughing)
So I mentioned earlier
that I don't normally deal
with software, and I do low
level programming and stuff
but that doesn't really
count, I was experimenting
at one time with
keyloggers on UNIX systems
which are still very common, right?
People hack UNIX systems all the time.
I had a keylogger and I think
I had written something,
I had some piece of code and I modified it
to try to log people's keystrokes.
I went to a very prestigious
technical university,
I didn't go there, I mean I
went there, I didn't attend.
Went to this place and
one of their laboratories
had computers for the students
to use and computer labs.
This particular institution
had a known root password,
like it was a public thing,
so this was still a time
where like sharing root
access on systems was okay
because it's all about
trust and somebody not
shitting in their own backyard.
But being me, I said
oh I have root access,
I'm gonna install keyloggers
on all these machines
then I can get legitimate credentials
from all of the students there.
So I rode my bike down
to this institution,
ran these keyloggers
on all these computers,
and said okay I'll come back
tomorrow and grab the log files
'cause I didn't really have a lot of skill
in like network side of
things so I'm like alright
I'll come back and physically
get them off the computers.
Come back the next day,
the entire lab room
where I had installed the keyloggers,
all the computers were down,
like I had crashed them all.
And I'm like okay maybe I
should just stick to hardware.
And I never got any of the accounts.
So I was involved in a hacker
group called Renegade Legion
in my teenage years and this was a group,
we released a bunch of text
files, so we were a group
but it was like let's
try to share information.
The information we were sharing, though,
wasn't like it is today where
like trying to fix things,
it was mostly like here's
how you steal credit cards,
here's how you break into
credit bureau systems,
here's how you there's
actually one on creating
a master key for master lock,
here's how different types
of systems worked so it was
all hacker related info files.
We did some pretty crazy stuff
and I'll mention one thing later.
There was also another
group that I was involved in
called Lost which was
really just making fun
of one of our friends, that
was Renegade Legion guys
but we already had
handles, we had fake names
of doing our hacker normal
hacker stuff and then this
was like we would just fuck
with anybody, it was really bad.
New hacker kids that would
come in and everything.
We were just a mess.
You can probably guess which
one was me based on the names
here but I'll give you a
hint, it says Skateboard Joe.
Okay so this, like I mentioned,
the mischief didn't just
take place on phone
lines or around the city,
I got involved in credit
card fraud as well.
And just like phones and free phone calls,
like it didn't seem weird
because it was this faceless,
the way I justified it
was like a faceless crime,
like these big banks,
the credit card owners
didn't get in trouble so I
mean they didn't have to pay,
they weren't responsible,
just a big evil companies
would front the cost so
it seemed to make sense.
And this was before like
now identity theft and fraud
like it's a much bigger deal now
because of organized crime involved
and people that are have their
whole goal is to screw you
and get as much
information, this was still
even though a lot of people were doing it,
it was still very
localized and sorta small.
But I had access to credit card numbers
like through the voicemail
systems and one other way
that we would do it is through our modems
since we had access to credit bureaus,
dial up the credit bureau
and in those little books
I had passwords of the credit
bureaus as they changed
and you would hack the
passwords and guess them.
There was a certain
string you had to enter
to query records, so we would
look through the white pages
and say okay who would
have a large credit rating?
Or a large credit on their cards?
Doctors, lawyers,
dentists, so we would look
through the white pages,
that book with names in it,
which I don't even know
does that exist anymore?
I don't know.
We would look through
those, find the names
of those people, pull their credit record,
get all the information about
them, get their name whatever
their maiden name,
whatever stuff was in there
and then we would call
the credit card company
and say uh my name is Dr. whatever Smith,
I'm going on vacation and
I seem to have misplaced
my credit card, can you
mail it to this address?
So they would mail a new
credit card to my dropsite,
my abandoned house or a
neighbor who I knew was away.
I'd get the credit card and
then we'd go on a shopping spree
or we'd use it online, or not online
but use it over the
phone, get stuff delivered
to the same dropsite so the
billing address matched,
or at least they knew that
we were at this location
for some amount of time on vacation
and then we would get rid of the card.
And it's something where
people can still do that,
and like it shouldn't happen still anymore
because I feel like the banks
maybe should have learned
30 years ago or 20 years
ago when mischievous kids
were doing it, maybe we
should make it harder.
Maybe a maiden name
shouldn't be an identifier,
maybe we shouldn't use
a social security number
for everything, maybe we shouldn't
just send out credit
cards, but really the banks
don't actually give a
shit because they want you
to spend money and they
want you to be in debt
so they're gonna happily
issue you cards and then if,
for some reason, somebody
notices new credit card charges
and they complain, they
just eat those costs.
It's still a winning
battle, it's like a casino
where sometimes they have to pay out
but they're gonna make money in the end.
So it was just too easy
to have that happen.
This was, took place in
one area I was 15 or 16
or something, I can't believe
how young I actually look
there where this was an
area that I hang out a lot
and we started recording
our exploits and instead of
having phones we had
to have a video camera,
how do you get the video camera?
You use a credit card and you order one.
I remember being on the
phone with some video audio
video place and I had really
loved this Sony camera,
it was like this beautiful,
box looking Sony camera
from the '90s I don't
remember the name of it
so I went to order one over
the phone and the guy said
you know we have this
new one, it's a whatever
this company is, this
one's way better so he
upsold me to a more expensive one
and I'm like sure I'll take that one.
So I ended up with this video camera
so I think it's sort of
funny where I was obviously
defrauding him but then he was
sort of trying to defraud me
by upseling me and I guess he got screwed,
no actually he didn't get screwed anyway,
it was the credit card company.
Anyway so I got this video camera,
we started filming stuff, this guy,
I'm gonna call him Robert because
he looks like Robert Plant
that wasn't his name, wasn't his handle,
we would spend a lot of time together.
Usually credit card types of stuff.
We would hang out in this
one location in Boston
where we would hang out in
this store as you can see
and really annoy the
people that work there,
we'd just talk with them all
the time, hours at a time.
Across from this location
was a bank of payphones
which was great for us to do all of our
various types of calling
people and harassing people.
There was a little store that
sold like Moroccan trinkets
from Morocco that this Moroccan guy owned
and he saw us messing
around with the phone
and one day he came up to us
and like what are you doing?
I'm like oh making some phone calls
so we ended up working out a deal
where I would trade him free
international phone calls
to Morocco to get like Moroccan stuff.
So my room had like all this
Moroccan incense holders
and the bells and the
hands and all this stuff,
it was super cool but that's
sort of where I learned
early on that's like oh
I can barter with people,
I can trade my skills
for other people's skills
which actually still happens today.
Let's see, one other story, oh yeah.
So I ordered a laptop
once from a well-known
computer company and shipped
it to a friend of mine
in a different state
because he had good access
to like a dropsite, so he,
we had it delivered there,
he was gonna test it
before he sent it to me
and I talked to him on
the phone he was like
I couldn't believe how
long it took to test
all the RAM when I powered it
up, it had eight megs of RAM.
Eight megabytes of RAM,
that was a huge thing.
He ended up actually getting arrested
for credit card stuff, too bad.
And then speaking of
being awkward with girls,
so Robert here had a crush
on somebody who worked
at a record store across
the hall from here.
So instead of just like
going and being yourself
and communicating, he said
let's order 12 dozen roses
to her at work, so we used a credit card
and ordered 144 roses and the delivery guy
was walking with one dozen
at a time up the ramp
to put them all on the counter
of the checkout counter
and it was like, it was awesome.
I wish I had pictures of it.
So anyway, this is all ridiculous stuff.
So being into hardware,
this thing up here,
this is the that's the ring busy device.
When I was messing around with cellphones,
I needed a way to extract the
memory contents from the phone
where the ESN and MIN were
stored so I could figure out
how I could change those,
so I didn't have access
to a device programmer which
is like a general type of tool
you can get now to do it so I built my own
and I would just manually cycle through
every single address of
the contents of the memory.
Down here was sort of some experimenting
with creating a multi-frequency generator
because with a lot of the
phone phreaking stuff,
you need to generate certain
tones, you your DTMF tones
but then you had your
multi-frequency just MF tones
that were the ones that you would use
for the in-band signaling to
control where you're going
in the system so blue
box type of stuff here.
Here's one of my little
beige boxes I would use
as my lineman handset,
so instead of having
a legitimate orange lineman handset,
I could just plug a
normal phone into this,
connect these to two
phone lines in this case,
this was a little conference call system
so I could have little
conference call on my own
just clipping onto phone lines.
This one down here, who had
a pager back in the day?
Yeah, few people.
This was a red box in
a pager, and a red box
is a device that would generate the tones
that a coin would generate when
you put it into a payphone.
So I don't know if you
remember, like you put a dime
in a payphone it would go beep beep
or you put a quarter in and
it would go beep beep beep
and do five beeps so this
just created those tones
and because all that
signaling was called in-band,
all you had to do was have your red box,
hold it up to the phone when it said
please enter, please deposit
75 cents, you would hold
this thing up, you'd push
the buttons corresponding
to 75 cents and then you
would get your phone call.
I sold those a lot, too, that
was also very profitable.
Oh I should mention, I've
always been into buying
and selling stuff at my parents
just reminded me of this.
So when I was a little
bit older I discovered
that AT&T dumpster, a
junkyard that was all
discarded AT&T equipment and
I pulled out all the EPROMs
from the different types
of telephone equipment,
and EPROMs at the time, they're
programmable memory devices
and they're used in all
sorts of arcade games
and stuff like that,
not anymore 'cause it's
an older technology but
I had dozens and dozens
of those that I would sell on usenet,
so selling stuff has
always been kinda popular.
When I was younger, when I was about 10
I discovered like an adult
bulletin board system
and that was a local number
so of course I signed up
with a friend of mine,
we pretended to be older
and we said our birth dates
at something that seemed
really old and you could download
ASCII art of naked women.
There were probably naked men
too, but I didn't see that.
So I'd have these printouts
and it was dot matrix printout,
ASCII dot matrix on a piece
of paper with the paper
on the sides, whatever
it's called, tracker feed.
So I had these printouts of naked ladies,
I'd hide 'em under my bed,
but I ended up selling those at school
which was one of my first
endeavors of selling things.
Which was awesome, yeah.
What else?
This one here is a
universal garage door opener
so this system is just based
on it has 10 DIP switches
that you would set for
your transmit password
that would match the
receiver and I said well wait
what if I just replaced
that with a circuit
that would cycle through
all of them automatically,
so you just hold the button down
and it will open any garage
door that uses that system.
Which is like a precursor
to doing it with wireless
exploits through software-defined radio
which Samm Kamkar did something recently
that basically emulated this
attack plus a whole bunch
of other ones of other systems to have
this universal garage door opener system,
so just because you could do
it doesn't mean it's legal.
I didn't actually take advantage of that,
I ended up showing it to my parents
and they said okay good job,
then they moved their bikes
out of the garage, so at
least that was a good thing.
And then other mischievous stuff like this
generated a really high frequency sound
which high frequency
bounces all over the place
so I would bring this in
to school in high school,
turn it on, close it, it was a Sucrets box
so like an Altoid sort of
thing, leave it on the desk
and have some tissues
to pretend I was sick
and the teacher'd be
like what is that sound?
And look all over the place and
I'd just sit there, it was awesome.
This is a laser listener that I thought
would be cool to spy on people
and so I created this to
try and spy on people,
this was a credit card
copier and of course
with all of this stuff
something was bound to happen.
So eventually the hammer came down on me
and I ended up getting arrested,
this picture by the way
like I normally smile a lot
if you haven't noticed, the police told me
not to smile because it wasn't
funny when I got arrested.
So this was not the first
picture that they took.
So it was actually I got very lucky,
this was a turning point for me
and I ended up flying
to Michigan to hang out
with some of the guys from Renegade Legion
so hacker group that normally we'd
mess around on the phones,
now we're in person.
Being a parent now, I have
no idea why my parents
let me do that, they were very
open with what I was doing,
and so I ended up going
to Michigan, we thought it
would be fun to break into a Michigan Bell
telephone facility to steal
information and it was all,
again, about that
information of having like
how can we do things
on the phone networks,
how can we have hardware that
we're not supposed to have?
We ultimately were charged
with six felonies each,
they dropped the charges
on me because I was
the only juvenile, so this was the point
where I was like shit I should
probably stop doing this.
The other guys, not so lucky.
I ended up going back about
a year ago I was doing
some work out there and stopped
by the telephone company,
took a picture and it was
really eerie to be back there
25 years later and then
it was so cold in Detroit
that my cellphone died,
so I was like shit,
so I just followed the
signs to the police station
and I was like this is
where I got arrested,
went into the police
station, my palms got sweaty,
I'm like oh my god
they're gonna recognize me
'cause I had to ask for directions
to get back to the
airport, and they didn't.
So anyway, I only have a few minutes
and this is really like all that bad stuff
were experiences that kind
of paved where I ended up
and I had to do a sport or get
a job according to my parents
and so I ended up running which became
a saving grace for me because now I would
I could kind of that was my
balance of using computers
and then running so that was really good.
I ended up joining The Lopht
which is a hacker group
in Boston with a bunch
of older guys that were
really focused on sharing
information in a good way
and using the hacker name
to spread the good side
of what we could do, the positivity of it
without breaking the law, so I had
known them beforehand,
there's a lot of history
about The Lopht that's already online.
I had known them before
that, but they're like
we don't want him to join until he's done
doing his dumb shit and they
were right so I got in trouble,
joined The Lopht, I won't play the video,
you can see it online
'cause we don't have time
but it was a hacker hangout to mess around
with stuff not unlike
maker's spaces today.
So we got a lot of media
coverage about trying to
share what hackers can
do for the good side,
which you should all understand
being at a hacker conference.
We ended up testifying in
front of Senate in 1998
about the state of computer
security in government,
that is of course not real.
That was in the White
House press room though.
I do want to play this as
sort of the final thing
because it's pretty funny,
this was Conan O'Brien
the day after our Senate testimony
and he had heard about it
and said okay let's make fun
of hackers 'cause who
doesn't make fun of hackers?
- I found this, talk
about something that's
a little frightening I read
this in the news yesterday.
A group of computer hackers told Congress
that hackers are now capable
of shutting down the internet,
redirecting commercial
flights, and transferring
millions of Wall Street
dollars around the world.
It's weird, yeah, which
means the only thing hackers
still aren't capable of doing
is losing their virginity.
(audience laughing)
There's a guy with thick black glasses
crying right now in the third row.
- And moving all the money out of
your account.
- Yeah right.
I'm completely screwed.
I'll show that red-haired freak.
I don't fear nerds.
(audience laughing)
That's the bravest stand I ever took.
I'm sorry, I might be going out
on a limb here but I don't fear the nerds.
- Yeah okay so that I
should mention that this
was 1998 so this is just when the internet
was becoming common, people were starting
to discover technology, and
we were really at that point
trying to show how bad computer
security was at the time
and has it changed since then?
No, I'm gonna skip through this,
I also ended up doing a TV
show called Prototype This
which was an opportunity
now to share my love
of electronics without fucking
with people but teaching them
how to do it and how
to build crazy projects
so it really is something
that ended up being positive.
Of course, designing the Defcon badges,
the first electronic
badges at conferences,
other sorts of stuff,
Chumby was like the first
open source hackable
hardware thing, so it's again
just turning that energy
into something positive
ended up being my career,
like this is what I do.
I live it, I've lived it my whole life.
The technology has changed
but like I still am always
thinking about things
and always questioning
and always trying to find a
way to push somebody's buttons
and how can I teach people
things and like it really
is just something that I've done.
So yeah, even though
technology has changed,
now there is this technical criminal more
organized criminal element to it,
but there's still plenty
of stuff to hack, right?
Like we're doing retro stuff here
but even with the newer
things, there's stuff
you can do and just not
hopefully get arrested for it.
I would say like the hacker
mindset is still here
where the most important
thing that we can do
is kind of use our passion
so do what we love to do
but I think teach critical thinking skills
and teach the facts of
questioning our world to kids,
to this next generation
because we sort of already have
our minds kind of made up
but a lot of kids these days,
I have two of them, and
they're in the school system
and I can see that they need to learn
to not trust everything that they read,
they need to learn to not
trust everything they see,
they need to question on
their own and then experiment
so I feel like that's
our main responsibility
as hackers is to learn stuff on our own
but then teach other
people to question stuff.
Because that's gonna be
the most important thing.
'Cause I know that I
want my kids to be able
to critically think about
stuff and not go down
the path I did but learn
that okay I don't really
trust what this guy's
saying, I want to learn
on my own or I want to
figure it out and like
I think that's really
important and that's what
the hacker community is, to me, all about.
The history, I feel like
everybody has a story.
I just saw Hamilton
recently and there was like
one song at the end,
everyone's bawling at the end
'cause it was so sad but it's the song
is called Who Lives, Who
Dies, Who Tells Your Story
and Hamilton had this amazing story
and his wife spent like
50 years after his death
documenting everything and sharing
and if we don't document our history
of these early days it's gonna be lost
because it was before our data
was harvested by everybody.
It was like this time where
it almost doesn't exist
unless people talk about it,
so please tell your stories
in other conferences and
sort of share this stuff.
And of course this is
all my these are mistakes
from my past, I maybe some
of them were mistakes,
the carelessness of youth I guess
but I wouldn't have changed anything
because it sort of got me where I am,
I just have to apologize to my parents
for dragging them through this.
So yes thank you again,
sorry I'm a little over
so we'll take questions
elsewhere but thank you
for coming and enjoy the
rest of the conference.
(group applauding)
(dial up modem sounds)
(television static)