that please oh stop
okay so I'm going to be talking about
return oh I'm pin track for those that
didn't come into the hardware hacking oh
it's going it still is
so I can't walk around it's probably
better that way
so I'm panda tracks oh yeah I know I
know and I'm going to be talking about
return-oriented programming this morning
and which is a great topic first thing
on a Sunday did you guys just wake up
that's awesome okay now yeah well there
you go that that probably is what I
should have done so return-oriented
programming first - am i i'm pen tracks
i like to tear things apart i don't
build things but they asked me to write
the code for the badges and you get what
you paid for right my god because i
don't build things I also teach an
exploit develop development class which
it you know some people seem to a lot of
people seem to like so check me out on
Twitter what's that oh thank you Ray
yeah Thank You Man
I appreciate it yeah I just taught my
intermediate class for the first time
and I think I finished the material like
at four o'clock in the morning the day
before maybe okay so today we're going
to talk about rock and the reason why
that we want to use something something
called rock which is return oriented
programming is because we have new
exploit mitigations in place on
operating systems in our applications
and normally whenever you take or look
at any type of you know exploit writing
course you're starting out and you're
writing an exploit where you are
executing code on the stack without
having to do anything right pretty much
you're going to find it jump ESP or
something like that you put the shell
code on the stack
you know you run your spoi execute its
code on the stack and you're like yeah
I'm done right but in the real world
these days that's not really the way
things are right
there's mitigation techniques they're in
play that prevents you from doing such
things so you know whenever you do that
type of an example you're talking about
you know the way the world was back in
and out 50 years ago or I don't know
1988 something like that so what is back
prevent stack execution prevention it
takes advantage of the cpu and there's a
flag in the CPU that tells the CPU that
areas of memory are not executable right
so if you put code there and try to
execute it it's just not going to do
anything it's actually going to seg
fault the application it's going to
crash because it can't execute that
memory so when the application like sets
up its memory different areas get set
this way non-executable one of the areas
of memory that gets set this way is the
stack right because you shouldn't be
executing code off the stack amen
so there's different ways that you know
this mitigation technique has been
implemented over different os's right
hat as exact shield other Linux has had
pax open BSD has you know whatever that
is and then Windows has dint and
everybody seem you know everybody's
heard of death right because that's how
Microsoft saved the world okay and we're
going to talk about you know how we can
get around death and execute our code
anyway so this is going to be pretty
much a demo so I did not pray to the
demo gods this morning so I am sure them
my Windows VM is going to
crash or reboot right in the middle of
this that this is fine if you can't read
any that hex either it's okay because
you probably don't care but or you might
want to care and move forward because I
can't make this any bigger because of
the resolution okay so I've got a
machine here and oh yeah my machine
rebooted so let's see how to setup
I had this all set up beforehand and of
course it had to reboot because I've got
like an unlicensed copy of Windows so
here what I've done is I've told Windows
I want to turn DEP on for everything
except for the application that I'm
allowed to execute right now by by
default Windows seven came with turn-on
depth for essential Windows programs and
services only which meant every other
application that was running on your
machine didn't have that turned out good
job Microsoft right so you actually have
to go in this and which is funny because
I don't know if you saw what I just did
but I went into like I right clicked on
computer I got into the system settings
I hit advanced system settings that kind
of makes sense and then I went to the
Advanced tab and then I went to
performance settings I've never really
understanding where we're going right
because I'm trying to keep code from
executing on the stack and then I find
over here in this tab that's kind of
hidden you know data execution
prevention and then I have to turn it on
then I have to reboot my machine yeah go
ahead I mean it's completely different
but I think that you can have em at turn
turn death on on the application yeah
yep yeah yeah you want death on because
you don't want people to send exploits
to your application and execute off the
stack and I'll show that show you that
happening in a minute so for my pony
server and I think I spelled the name
wrong but whatever I turned deaf off
okay so I checked the box I had to
reboot my machine to get this to work
right good job
Microsoft and I'm going to now that's
turned on I'm going to go and start up
my service so I wrote this service it's
got tons of vulnerabilities in it it's
for my a class right and I'm going to
take as Floyd and send it to the
application
and then if I go and look at my machine
or my machine my server hasn't crashed
yet but if I go into and connect to the
gear let me connect to the server right
and see and I think it was 4 4 4 4 let's
do that I've got a shell ok
and all I did so for those that can't
see it this is a window show I just
connected to the port on the Box on 4 4
4 4 and I opened up a bind show right in
the way I did it if I look at my script
let's stop that let's look at the script
all I did was here I have a jump DSP
right there's jump ESPs all over your
application I overwrite the save the IP
to then go to the jump PSP in it jumps
back to where my coat my shellcode is on
the stack it executes it so depth is not
turned on and it's a pretty simple
script I mean that's pretty much it and
I exploit my my script my application so
Deb what came out and you know they were
like we're going to make it so that that
doesn't happen right so let's let's go
in and turn it off and see if it works
performance settings up yep execution
prevention and check this these boxes
okay now Deb has been turned off from my
application so I'm going to start
anything that's been turned down right
so it's going to keep me from executing
code up side so if I go in execute that
again get out of that though not not too
if you change the bullet to make it so
that def turn on for all your apps you
don't have to reboot but once you have
it turned on then you can turn on and
off debt for individual applications
right so now I'm going to run the
non-drop again right and I just lost my
window and I'm going to execute or try
actually let's go back to the Windows
machine and we see that crashed right so
now if I go back to my netcat and try to
connect to the listener that I opened up
just a minute ago
it shouldn't connect right nothing
happens because they bought the bind
port didn't like open up so I pushed the
shell code onto the stack but then when
I use my jump ESB it jumped onto the
stack and then the code was prevented
from executing so let's look at that in
the debugger so I'm going to start up
the app
connect immunity to it and I'm going to
oh man I keep doing that sorry and I'm
going to set a breakpoint at my jumpy SP
so here's my jumpy SP right so I'm going
to set a breakpoint there and then start
the application backup gun now when I go
and execute my script we're going to
stop and see what happens so back in the
debugger our application is crashed we
can see that the debugger pause done in
the bottom and we can see in the status
bar at the bottom that we hit that pit
or bug point in the brain point is jumpy
SP if we look at the stack over in the
bottom what is it for you guys right
hand right we see that ESP is pointing
at the button ship X 90s right those are
no ops so it's kind of like a no ops log
if I hit it it's just going to slide
down and then below the 90s is my
shellcode before I turned up on I would
be able to go and just execute those 90s
until I hit my shellcode but if I go and
jump right now right now you can see the
instruction pane where it's changed and
I have my no ups in the upper left hand
corner for you guys right and of if it
depth was turned off I'd start executing
those instructions but now whenever I
hit I step through it I get access
violations down below DEP is working
right see how that is if I had turn this
off I'll just execute those and execute
my shell and that's how I was able to
bind to the support previously but now I
can't right it's broken so how do we get
around it let's go back to Who am I
talks about right so we observed for
this slide we observe the access
violation so what is return-oriented
programming it is a way of chaining sets
of instructions there in the application
already
and to do what you want to do so in the
application
there's sets of instructions which we
will call gadgets right and they are all
followed up by a return right when you
overwrite yeah II I P the safety IP and
make it so like I was going to the jump
TSP what's happening is is you're
returning out of a function right and
then that memory address is executed so
I find a jump ESP whenever that return
hits I go to that that instruction and
execute the instruction in Rob we're
kind of doing that type of thing yep
oh I'll get there yep yep so whatever I
oh I completely lost my train of thought
thank you very much so before I can't
hit that I was at City this morning I
have to say this morning I'm sipping my
coffee trying to wake up my head hurts
like something fierce and Jennifer sits
down in front of me with her oatmeal
right and she's like I'm going to heckle
you today right here so thanks I
appreciate that because I completely
threw me off
I keep going good this is fine okay so
I'll answer your here question because I
have no idea what I was talking about
so turing-complete means with gadgets if
you have enough gadgets and we'll talk
about what they are in a minute you can
pretty much write any application right
if you have enough gadgets to work with
you can pretty much write at you know an
application based on all the gadgets
that you find in the application okay
and the nice thing about using Rob is
you're not executing code off the stack
all you're doing is you're pushing
instructions onto the stack and then
utilizing the the behavior of
right to jump to these sets of
instructions to execute what you want
but the sets of instructions are
actually in executable space of memory
right and then at the very end there's a
rag well what a ret does if all it does
is it pops a memory address off the
stack and then it jumps to it right
that's all it does so if you put a bunch
of memory addresses onto the stack that
lead to a read at some point you're
going to hit the rack and then pop off
the next memory address off the stack
and then jump to that and I'll have you
know examples in a minute so what is a
gadget pretty much kind of went through
it it's like it's all over in your
instruction space and they're just sets
of instructions followed by your read
right there's other types of gadgets
that end in other instructions what
we're going to only talk about the ones
that end in the rest so you'll have
instruction instruction and instruction
instruction and then a rat okay now the
nice thing about x86 is it's a variable
length instruction set so a no op is one
byte in size it's a hex 90 but then an
ADD ESP like add 92 ESP is a longer
instruction it might be for 6 bytes long
this allows us to find even more gadgets
in the instruction space because of the
way you can jump to the memory addresses
in the middle of may be existing
instructions and I'll show you that in a
minute
like I was saying I was getting ahead of
myself as far as the gadgets normally a
program has all the instructions set up
in memory based on a four byte you know
boundary right but if you jump into the
middle of the instruction then what gets
executed might look very different from
what the real instructions are
so that adds the number of gadgets that
you might end up using being able to use
and you're the application that you're
targeting one note due to popularity of
Rob there's been a lot of research into
trying to keep this from happening I
know that there's a couple universities
have been working very hard to figure
out ways to keep people from using raw
to execute show code on on their in
application space so here's a really
good example of gadgets that are hidden
within the instructions in an
application so in the top example I had
the original instructions I have an or
instruction and it starts with 80 83 0 D
0 C yada yada yada right and then
there's a test EDX right now if I jump
to where the zero D is right and start
executing from there I get a completely
different set of instructions here right
so the the or instruction turns into a
different or instruction it becomes an
or EAX and a number and then the next
instruction after that is an ADD al so
if you look at the top you have 0 d and
then this part right here then the
hidden gadget down below that's my first
instruction you see how that is and then
the second instruction is 0 4 and then
this f7 down here right and that becomes
the add and then my return becomes this
here this c2 and the bus a bunch of
zeros you see how that is so I just
created new gadgets or instructions by
jumping to the address of the in the
middle of an existing instruction any
questions about that yeah go ahead
yep
it's more it's sort of like that it's
more like you had let's say you have a
function and there's a bunch of
instructions inside the function right
first thing that a function will do is
save EVP right so there is a move you
know push EBP on stack and then you move
ESP to EBP every function has those
instructions and then the instruction
has since the function has the
instructions to do whatever it's
supposed to do right so what I'm talking
about is if there is any Rex in that you
know ret opcodes in that function then
what we're doing is we're building
backwards from that C to spot and seeing
if there's any valid instructions that
we could utilize yes yes in this example
yep does that make sense okay so what
are gadgets you ask so a gadget can be
anything like let's say I need to pop
something off the stack and put it into
a register I can have a poppy ax a poppy
DX and then we return it's a pop pop
right you probably hear about pop up
Brett's
when you're doing SCH exploitation right
in this example maybe I need to put
something into EDX like you know a
memory address or a number or something
I'll put it under the the memory address
for this gadget and then whenever I go
and execute it the next thing that will
be on the stack is the value I want to
pop into ETA X right and then I might
not care what I put into EDX and then
you know I'll put some junk in my
exploring and then whenever this gadget
executes it will pop what the value that
I want to put into EAX and it will do
that and then we'll just pop junk into
EDX because I don't care and then it
will return on my stack I'll have
another memory address for the next
gadget it's going to pop that off into
yeah
P and then execute the next gadget the
next example is a little bit different
let's say that I need to pop or add you
know 10 to ESP this is a bad example
because you know normally you don't add
something to ESP but let's pretend
that's like I had just put a negative
number into EAX and I want to make it
seven if I add earth you know nine if I
add 10 to EAX instead of the ESP in this
slide and that would give me my nine men
looking forward and then I have to deal
with these pops right I have to put junk
into EBX in the SI after that and then I
get my return I have my next memory and
my next gadget that you need to execute
it'll get popped off off the second I'm
off to the races
does that make sense any questions cool
so you're probably wondering Doug how do
you how do you build rap chains or how
do you find gadgets right there's tools
for that right Mona is a really good
tool for finding gadgets in a building
rap chains and on the Windows platform
there's a bunch of Python scripts like
lot gadget that you can down from
download from github to build rap chains
and fun gadgets on the Linux platform so
what we want to do is we've got all
these gadgets that are in our memory
space and we want to start creating
chains of different gadgets to do the
things that we want to do right we want
to we have a destination in mind but we
have to get there right for example
depp's turned on in this case right I
want to turn that off right I want to
execute stuff on the stack why don't we
just turn that off for the memory space
that we put the shellcode in right that
would be cool right so I'm going to
build a rock chain to go and turn turn
off that great job mitigation techniques
or hate
another thing that we have to deal with
is SLR a SLR is the randomization of
memory space right this stack is
normally under our control so things are
always changing at the memory addresses
are always changing on the stack we want
to make sure that that's not happening
with our gadgets right because when I
write my spoi if the memory address for
um you know my first gadgets 1 2 3 4 5 6
7 8 right and the next time I start up
the application SLR is under control
yeah is in play it randomizes the memory
addresses then it's 9 8 7 6 5 4 3 2 1
I'm kind of screwed because then I can't
execute my my gadget and you have to
have control over ESP right because ESP
is where we are putting away we're
putting these gadgets out in the stack
and we have to be able to point ESP to
our gadgets or I mean our chain to be
able to do the rats right because the
rent is just popping you know popping
that value off the stack for us so
here's an example I need to put 2 C into
EAX and hex zero zero is a bad character
right so I can't just put zero zero zero
zero zero zero to C into my exploit
because the first four six zeros are
going to just break my spoiler right
because hex 0 0 is a bad character so
what I do is I build a chain first thing
I'm going to do is I'm going to find a
pop EAX right that's at the top of the
chain and I'm going to pop a value into
the X register I'm going to choose ffff
ffff anybody know what value that is in
decimal okay minus 1 yep it's negative 1
I didn't have to use any zeros put that
into the register as soon as I execute
that pop you can take that value of s
put it into EAX and now have - one in
EAX so how do you think I might get - to
see I just find an ad right a gadget
that has an a Dax and then I just start
executed executing them until I get to
that value - to see and then it's
followed up by a rat because all gadgets
are followed up by a rat or something
that's similar right some type of jump
whatever you see what's going on so now
I have to see in EAX and I didn't have
to use my bad character which was X zero
zero which would would it broke my
gadget so now I have a chain of gadgets
that did what I needed it to do make
sense
cool yeah yeah we can do it again let's
let's just rewind wait who's awake right
now because I think that Bill was
falling asleep oh good there's a couple
hands could I'm glad that's good I'm not
sure if I'm awake so that's good okay so
I said that Mona would be a good tool to
find gadgets on the Windows platform
right so I'm just gonna go into hey Mona
rock for me right and she's going to go
out and find gadgets she's also going to
go out and build you know try to build
chains for me she would tell me about
interesting gadgets that I might be in
trip you might be able to use she'll get
all done that you can find right in the
app application and she'll put them in
files for me so like rock text will have
all the rot sets you found right very
cool if you go and do this and you have
a big application like let's say
Wireshark right and you say just rock it
motor wrong right sometimes Monet
doesn't look and see which libraries it
might need to use and it will go and try
to find Roth's fullerene gadgets for all
the libraries that are being loaded into
Wireshark and when that happens your VM
is going to lock up really hard and your
machine is going to lock up really hard
and you're going to be like I need
coffee and I won't be able to use my
machine for hours right so if you do
that just be aware of what you're doing
and just tell Mona I'm interested in
looking for gadgets in these yellows and
just you know zero down but unless you
want your machine to get real hot and
you know not be able to use it for a
long time okay but oh I've done it
plenty of times yeah it's aggravating
that's why I'm warning you okay so you
might be thinking okay Doug you just
said let's turn rap off right well on
Windows there is a bunch of functions
but we're going to pick on virtual
protect right now they'll be able to
help us turn death off in a specific
area of memory virtual will protect
modifies the permissions of memory right
and Mona is really nice because she will
try to create a chain utilizing virtual
product so she does the work for you
sometimes she might not be able to find
the correct gadgets that she needs to be
able to turn you know Deb off of that
area so you're going to have to go and
fix fix the chain but she does a really
good job of setting things up for you so
here you can kind of see an example of
this down below it kind of took a
snippet out of the beginning of the
chain and you can see how the very first
thing that she does is she finds a
pointer to virtual to protect in the
application itself right and then what
she does is she figures out a way so
that you can pivot on the pointer and
then call virtual protect directly from
the kernel to disable that virtual
protect is so cool because you can go
you know I've got this area of memory
like the stack and right now it's only
read right and I want to be able to
execute off the sack Vergil protect can
you like take these 100 bytes and just
make make it executable for me
sure we'll do that that's cool we can do
that right thanks Microsoft so here's a
bunch of different functions that we
could use let's say virtual protect
isn't available in the application but
virtual virtual Alec is there's
different ways to do it
but we're going to pick out virtual
protect right now normally virtual
protect is very reliable right we're
talking about Windows here if you're
looking at Linux if you like to pick on
Linux and protect it a good thing to do
yeah that's that's a function you might
want to do man on ok
so virtual product is a kernel function
is it whit I have to say when XP was
awesome I loved when XP because
everything was static there was no ASL
are turned on and a lot of the OS
libraries right including the kernel
right so you could just say you know
call virtual protect directly from the
kernel because there's no ASLR there's
no randomization there you could always
reliably use that function well Windows
7 came along to galuwa smarter and now
you know a SLR is turned on on those OS
dll's
so we all we do is we look for the
pointer that is being used within our
application to point to it because it's
always going to be dynamically created
every time that application runs and
then we can just pivot off that pointer
good job a SLR right thank you for
protecting me
awesome yeah so here we are we have the
layout of how to call virtual protect in
a function all right I mean the virtual
production so on the stack I need to
have the address of virtual to protect
at the top right because I'm going to
call them get a return to it remember we
were we need to return to our gadgets
and stuff we're going to do the same
thing with virtual to protect so the
first thing that's going to happen is
we're going to return to that you know
the memory address of
virtual product then the nice thing
that's on the stack is going to be the
address that we go to after the function
is done right we're kind of taking
advantage of how functions are called
especially on the x86 architecture here
right because when in whenever functions
really get called and you're not messing
around with it with a boy the last thing
that gets pushed onto the stack when we
call a function is the address that
we're going to return to right so in
this case we're going to put the address
of the shellcode that we want to jump to
after virtual protect turns off the
error turns on execution for that you
know area of memory then we're going to
tell it how many bytes we want to you
know change the permissions for so you
know we might how big is our shellcode
100 bytes maybe on on a linux ploy maybe
like 500 to 700 pipes for Windows shell
code right we were going to have to tell
virtual protect we want this much space
that has the executable bit turned on
let's say okay and then um we want to
tell it you know what the new
permissions are right so hex for 0 on
windows is you know the value you want
you just have to remember that or take a
picture of this slide whatever on Linux
it's going to be pretty easy everybody
knows about schmod right how do you make
something executable in Linux you say to
mod 7 whatever right it's the same thing
we need some m protect on Linux to
change the permissions set to 7 right so
we get read write execute and then it's
something really weird about virtual
product and I am NOT a developer I said
that at the beginning is that you have
to take the permissions of the page that
you're making the change to and then
apply that the
current permissions to some other area
of memory so you just choose something
randomly that's in the address space of
the application and just say do it to
that and I don't really know why virtual
protect has that in its parameters but
you just have to deal with it so you
just choose something randomly and it
goes and makes it read right I don't
know okay so let's let's test this out
let's check it out
let's go back to demo and hope that my
Windows machine just didn't reboot on it
oh good it's back okay that's that's
always good and what we're going to do
is instead of instead of using my
regular spoil you exploit where I was
using the jump ESP I'm going to now
utilize a chain that Mona created so
first thing I'm going to do is I'm going
to fire up my application fire up
immunity I'm going to bot you know
attached to the running process I'm
going to start it up stop it and then
I'm going to say Mona right Mona please
find Rob for me right and oh wait while
you're doing it I want to make sure that
let's see - yep make sure that you don't
find any addresses with hex zero zero in
it this route this is small I'm sorry
but I'm telling Mona to ignore any a
memory addresses with a hex zero zero
okay because heck zero zero will break
my exploit remember in my example I said
that this application has a problem with
hex zero zero so she's going to go off
she's going to go find it and she didn't
hang my machine right because this is a
really small application I wrote it and
then as a developer so it's even smaller
okay and if I go into where Mona's
writing her logs I can go and look and
sure enough here's my rot file right if
you can see that small here's my Rob
chains and then she has gives me Rob's
suggestions that's pretty cool
so if I don't want to dig through every
single Rob I mean gadget I can at least
look at the suggestions to see
what she thinks is good or not right but
let's look at the change see what's in
there so if I scroll down a little bit
you will see that the first thing that
she does is tried to make a chain for
virtual product let me just move that
over so you can see it and what she's
going to do is she's going to use a
method of that utilizes push a deed
anybody know what push ad does on an
Intel processor it takes the registers
and pushes them onto the stack so all
that Mona needs to do is put all the
values that she needs to call virtual
protect and put them in the right
registers and then one push ad is called
it's going to take all that stuff and
push it onto the stack and then she's
going to turn around and call you know
the function just like we just talked
about the way it will be set up exactly
the way we were just you know talking
about and then if you scroll down a
little bit and I'm going to have to move
this over again because my windows too
vague she gives an example in Ruby the
example and C and my favorite the
example in Python right so I can take
this gadget or chain of gadgets and
copying them into my script and utilize
that so let's let's look at my script if
I scroll down here's my chain the same
chain that we just saw sorry for those
in the back I trust me there's stuff
here because somebody said highlight it
I was again I can highlight it there you
go can you see it better yeah yeah
that's good this is fine okay so this is
the chain that she made for me I was
really lucky well kind of that she was
able to create a chain to do everything
she needed some applications like this
application before I started
like developing it had a lot of parts of
the chain that she can figure out so
what did I do
I went and started creating these
gadgets I was like okay I need a pop EBP
I'll just create one put it into the
code and then recompile and then all the
Sun goes there and Mona was like hey I
just felt a change for you that's
awesome okay but then down below instead
of my jumpy SP remember here I'm going
to put my chain in in there instead
right so I'm replacing the jumpy SP so
because I can't jump back to the stack
it's not executable and putting my chain
there of gadgets but my entire script
the rest of it is exactly the same the
shellcode is afterwards the script is
the same except for the fact that I'm
using wrap to turn off debt in that area
instead of you know just jumping to the
code at the shellcode itself really
really cool right nice okay cool so
let's let's see what happens in the
debugger just you know see exactly how
the chain is working so I'm going to
fire I'm going to be able to you know
try to figure out how to use gin now
that I do I'm going to start this back
up and I'm going to take the first
memory address actually let's look at
this real quick the first memory address
is of the chain is I know you guys can
read it back there can somebody read it
it's six yeah whatever I don't care
I'm just getting copy it whatever and
I'm going to set a breakpoint in the
debugger so
area so the first thing that happens is
it I want to pop EAX
so that's the first gadget in the chain
so I'm going to set a breakpoint there
in it the instruction just turned light
blue right so I know that there is a
breakpoint there and I'm going to go
back to my I'm going to fire up the
application again f9 and now I'm going
to send my spoiied
so Rob okay I just sent my exploit okay
if I go back and look at my debugger
sure now it's down in the bottom I know
you can see it it says break a hit a
breakpoint it's the number of the
address that I said so it's that poppy
ax so if we look at the stack over on
the left hand side we see I don't know
if you can see it I'll make this a
little bit bigger that there's the
pointer to virtual protect on the top of
the stack I put that there
oh wait I didn't look right there Mona
put that there right I didn't put it
that third I put it in my script so now
if you look if you compare the stack
from that point down all the values
there on the stack are the stacks
they're in my chain right now we're
going to start executing these at
gadgets based on my chain do we know how
we got here anybody know just just so
that we cover that yeah go ahead
yep
other stuff yeah yeah perfect yeah
exactly
the other thing to know is I over wrote
so I have a function that has I've on a
Rodian right this one has a stack of
buffer overflow vulnerability in it some
string copy doesn't have bounds on it
right and I can overflow the buffer I
over every every function when it's done
it returns back like we said to specific
you know that to the calling function
right it needs to know how to get back
there that rat i over row you know that
i overwrote the say VIP and that rat is
executing my my first gadget that's how
I got here just so that I'm clear about
that so now I'm about to execute my
first gadget so I need to take the
memory address of the pointer to virtual
would protect and put it in EAX so if I
step through look at EAX it just changed
it's now got the pro tool of protect
address in EAX right the next thing that
Moana is going to do is it's going to do
some trickery to switch it so that it's
not the pointer anymore but it's the
actual memory address of virtual protect
in the kernel okay so we're going to
just step through that quick oh I just
executed the return if you noticed at
the top of the stack the memory address
for the pointer of virtual protect is
gone because it's been popped off right
and we've gone in return to a different
gadget so now we have a move a gadget
that has a move instruction in it and
this is the trickery that's going on by
now in a place where there's a new
gadget being executed so I execute the
first instruction which is the move and
then here I'm at the return it's going
to pop that memory address I have on the
stack next off and jump to it so it's
some other gadget that we're going to
jump to alright so now we have a pop up
Brett
right she wants to pop the next values
off the stack and put them in the
different registers
sometimes you have to deal with gadgets
they have junk instructions in it so
more than likely she needs to push yeah
do the push this might be a bad example
but she needs to let's get back to that
because this is actually good these are
all good instructions what she's doing
here is she's going to push EAX onto the
stack which is that pointer and then
she's going to pop it into ESI because
that's where she really needs it right
so when we push it onto the stack it's
going to push my chain down right so now
that value is now back onto the stack
and then what she's going to do is pop
it into ESI right it didn't affect my
chain at all in my class I tried to do
this example right and I think I might
throw my back out if I try to do it here
but I like said pretend that you are you
have painted lines on the road right and
those are your your if that's your chain
right and every time you want to execute
a new gadget you just freshly painted
right so every time you jump on a new
line you're going to get like footprints
in your new line right and pretend that
every time you execute a new gadget you
kind of jump this way I'm going to go
right through this stage and put your
foot on the next line right but then if
you need to move things around with push
pops it's kind of like jumping backwards
right you're not every time that you
jump on a new line you're kind of
utilizing the next gadget in the chain
but if you're doing something like this
where you're pushing and popping you're
kind of jumping backwards onto lines
that you've already jumped on and I
would love to do that right now but I'm
really scared that goes right through
the floor here and then whenever you're
ready to start X you know executing new
gadgets you have to make sure that on
the stack you're back to the next gadget
that you want to execute
a stack right so if you do a couple pops
or I mean a couple pushes right you're
pushing data onto the stack like this
one is doing one you have to have the
same number of pops to get back to where
you were to get to the next gadget does
that make sense
I would love to jump back and forth but
I oh yeah I can jump down there after
after okay so then we have a bunch of
other things that she's doing this
trickery to be able to you know figure
out you know where virtual protect is
and I just went to pass the gadget but
if you look in EAX right now the value
has changed for virtual product to the
kernel all right she did her trickery
now she's in the the mode of trying to
set a specific number probably you know
the permissions is I think it x40 was
permissions right she's going to go I
think that she just pushed a value into
EBX
what is a ffffff DFS right and now we're
going to negate that kind of like what I
did before I had at negative 1 which is
FF FF FF FF and then I added to it right
to get a number that had nose in it
she's doing the same type of thing but
she hasn't nagged instruction to be able
to just do two's complement to that
value to get the positive number without
putting hex 0 0 into the floyd make
sense and if you look at EDX right now
and then execute that instruction we now
have 201 so 201 is the size of our
shellcode must be right it's hex tool
whatnot 201 just be aware that ok so now
if I just keep on stepping through you
can see that she's putting different
things into each register right and
here's our push ID so now if we look at
the registers and we go back to that
slide that I had before right they
should line up we have in EDX hex for 0
right we have
have in EBX hex 201 before zero is the
permissions the 201 is the size of the
page that's going to be you know changed
make sense she's doing that using
gadgets she has not executed anything
off the stack yet now we're about to
execute virtual protect so the next
thing that we're going to do is we're
going to use push ad push all those
values onto the stack let's do that now
now if you look at the stack down in the
lower right hand corner you can kind of
see in through here right there's our
virtual protect this is the memory
address that we wanted to jump back to
here's our value of the size of the area
that we're going to change and this is
the permission right here make sense
that's pretty cool right yeah
thanks Mona I mean you can build these
change yourself and it's great exercise
by you you like the rubik's cube this is
just like the rubik's cube right or
maybe worse or i don't know i I'm
horrible at the rubik's cube when my son
can do it in a minute and I'm like what
just happened he's like I did it and I'm
like yeah but how like I don't even know
how you can look at it fat and like know
what's going on I don't know so maybe
it's a little bit harder than the
rubik's cube for some people okay so
then what I need to do now is I am going
to Mona's going to set it up now so now
we are ready to call virtual production
you can kind of see it on the stack
immunity is kind of trying to figure out
oh we have a function that's about to be
called right and you can see how it says
called a virtual protect and then the
address equals it knows immunity knows
what the virtual protect parameters are
and she's like helping me out she's like
oh yeah look at this your immunity is
like yeah you're going to call virtual
protect and these are all the parameters
for
that good job and I can look and I'm
like oh yeah look at that the address
and the size the new protection yeah
like you eat right yeah that's cool in
the old protect which I don't understand
right next thing I do is I'm going to
call it there's a there's a bunch of
little things that happens I'm kind of
stepping through like virtual Pracht and
some other things right but let's get to
the point where oh here's there's the
actual called virtual tracked right and
now whenever we return we have a jump
PSP this is this is a memory address
that Mona found and she put onto into
her chain and we're back to the
beginning this is back where we started
right before we started talking about
Rob we're ready to jump to ESD and
execute code the shell code if you look
on the stack there's a bunch of hex 90s
right hex 90 is that no up so you have a
little bit of a no ops lot sled there
slide whatever right and we're going to
see remember what happened here when we
had depth turned down at this point we
couldn't we got an access violation
right let's see what happens
oh no ops on the in the staff I mean
executions through right let's see if we
get the access violation nope
I'm executing no ops right now oh yeah
that's excellent right I'm getting
really excited now look really really oh
there's my shell cut oh okay
do you see what happened we just turned
off that that mitigation is no longer in
play right so let's see this in reality
like let's see if it really works this
is where I should have like prayed to
the demo gods right and said please work
just do it please
and I'm guessing that when I am about to
do this Microsoft is going to give me
the finger and
say and like reboot windows on me or
something like that I don't know but
let's see let's see if it works
oh and let's make sure I wasn't messing
with you and had virtual yep I have it I
have it turned off good or I mean turned
on so Debbie's turned out good I just
want to make sure okay so now I'm going
to execute this drop right
did anything happen I don't know if I
look at the running process it's still
running so I didn't crash you remember
before when I did this it crashed the
process the only thing I did was then
turn step on a crash my process but now
he didn't so let's go back and just
double check and see what's going on
here I have my neck neck cat - poor 404
connect to it boom here's her felt okay
thank you very much so I'll go back to
my slides and go away to the end any
questions yeah yeah go ahead
no no so I turn deaf right now on my
machine jet designed for all running
processes so it that will not there's
nothing else I mean oh if you turn it
off yeah so I think that's that's a good
question if you turned up off yeah yeah
Rolly yeah I'd love it right right I
wouldn't have my show anymore but if you
have depth turned off I've had certain
situations where this bullet won't work
because virtual protects is like I think
it might throw an error and say I can't
do this because it's already executable
right or something like that so
sometimes your target might be
vulnerable anyway and then when you go
to the user op it might not work because
you're trying to do you know turn
something off that's already off so it's
yeah maybe you have to play around with
it but then you can just go back to my
first script right and just execute that
done dang any other questions
yeah yeah I guess she does a good
question I like that nice so that's my
talk hope you liked it hope they woke
you up thank you