thanks al welcome back after lunch
everybody get something to eat or you've
not started yet that doesn't look like
you guys are too hungover really they're
hungover people are still sleeping maybe
but yeah so this this slide is not going
to help with anybody that's hungover you
see those sweet sweet graphics I made
this before you really start mandatory
disclaimer this is my stuff it is really
difficult to do a disclaimer because I
know what to put in one but yeah don't
do stupid stuff with anything I say and
it may not be accurate I don't know we
cover this we hit talk about fun stuff
more specifically on the voice over IP
and more modern phone systems I've
talked before on the history with
Patrick so we're not going to go there
will be a few slides of history but
that's going to be I'm going to try and
keep it to a minimum not repeat myself
and bore you
yeah and then we go on the health test
focusing on like if somebody said I need
to test my phone system I'm going to
give you a phone number can you test it
there's going to be some overlap when I
try and map the vulnerabilities to the
OS top ten because people are familiar
with that but it will be loosely map
because it doesn't quite relate probably
and then there'll be some fun tricks
stuff that I worked on the slides on
github or SlideShare at the moment but I
will put them up at some point Sam
you're going to covered this this is
about me is the acronym super kind of
that have a day job I really enjoy it
it's basically I'm an offensive team I
get messed up it's really fun but for
outside of work fun I like to ride
bicycles I do a little bit of road
biking but I like riding in the
mountains more because now turns out
that trees don't try and run you over
especially North Carolina D yeah had
some close calls yeah I did presentation
in 2005 here on wardriving anybody see
that
you didn't you weren't here one two
people I'm sorry that was probably the
worst presentation I've ever given
my entire life there's like five slides
yeah then it is hacking with the iPhone
in 2007 that was right when the iPhone
came out their votes in 2009 and then
what 2015 me and Patrick did some fun
stuff sorry wrong number pony pony they
become Vegas and then gettin busy with
his last year did anyone see that it's
really the longest I've ever talked
about one topic normally I would do it
want to look at that because it's so
much stuff to do with phone systems that
you just keep going and going there's so
much to learn I find it really
interesting so this slide we get some of
the buzzword bingo if they're doing it
out of the way I'm an 80s kid I guess or
is a 90s kid we had radios as VCRs all
that stuff I don't know what marvin is
for the other two TV shows I was
familiar with Fresh Prince and Saved by
the Bell
I did ride in cars about airbags or
seatbelts really gore not and we didn't
have cellphones or the only thing we
have was a telephone or hammer in
letters maybe that's why I like phones a
lot we didn't have myspace Facebook
there's no profiles or likes so you're
as popular as you are in person it's
really had the best of all times right I
don't know the nineties kind of stuck
they want to know that great anyone
having a good thing about 90s now they
say you played multiplayer games anybody
do that so much fun is that a really
good time or you have to sit next to
somebody when you're playing a game this
is how people cook selfies I didn't have
that I was unfortunate I had the Gameboy
but didn't didn't have the funds for the
for the printer probably worth more now
than it was absolutely time let's how
you block someone you had a apt
unless you had two phone lines than you
you just screwed sir how many people
remember that first telephone number
good number of you now anyone want to
tell me what it is it's a great a great
way of you know posted on social media
and maybe someone will tell you that
first phone line where you can answer
the security question people kept phone
numbers forever right it didn't really
change that's cool I do remember mine
who uses telephones who doesn't use a
telephone who doesn't know what a
telephone is I believe you anyone else
that so everybody right every industry
uses a telephone of some sort on it did
say scary where it said interesting but
I changed it because you don't want to
like those are the really interesting
industries anyone have any other
industries that could be could be
relevant now
anybody want a jello shot if you have
some feedback or something as yellow out
here for the perfect afternoon snack we
can get started now drinking because
it's afternoon
so smokey you want one mode you will run
it back there
you got it you've got to contribute or
answer questions any other industries
academics I work yeah I yeah give him
one why not
academics is kid oh absolutely that was
one of my examples by redacted at yeah
you can Gil
but we're we go on say is the history
exploding the phone if you're
interesting that read that book and
what's the other presentation we gave
like I said this is more on a digital
side I don't know how loud this next
slide is going to be so let's give it a
shot anybody remember that a lot of
people remember that so I'm not going to
the worst sound of its mystique rings
wait for it wait for it
there you go that diagram explains
what's going on and there's no way
you're going to be able to do that yeah
anybody is get off the internet I need
to use the phone that was a thing yeah I
grew up with telephones this is kind of
a flow chart or loads our time line of
the technology I've seen other than
telephone IRC a CQ aim all of those came
around 90s 96 you had net meeting but
who actually really used net meeting I
guess people that may have been a little
bit older than me
we had 96 SMS Palm Pilot Sony Vaio was
released and things kind of started
picking up your Yahoo Messenger all of
those through Yahoo Messenger added
video chat when was that I don't know
it's 2002 T it wasn't down till there
that you have video chat or really I get
teamspeak secret or crown asterisk isn't
really related to that but it's related
the whole presentations 2002 yahoo
messenger with the video was I mean that
was 15 years ago right Facebook was
released to the public in down there and
then 2007 you've got the iPhone so I say
what the bots took over for it so I go
quiz so prior to the iPhone what do all
of those tech not even the open what do
all those technologies with the
exception of asterisk have in common
they what yeah I'll take that I was
thinking uh they're all closed source
right everybody was trying to do that
thing make money like the dot-com boom
anyone know what the first camera phone
in 2000 was called oh who made it now
yeah you could just cut start saying
names you get it right eventually maybe
nope now getting closer with Sony and
Samsung is thoughts of an S ah
they teach me Joe had to be sharp made
it yeah whoever said the other one you
grabbed a drink I know who it was he
said communication yeah you got to put
your hand up so recent history you got
all of this stuff everybody's familiar
with this screen sharing livestream and
whatsapp snapchat kick all of that is
just taking off everything to go camera
on it everything is recording all the
time like Alexa you can mess up a few
and I'm not getting that smart mirrors
where I don't know why you want a mirror
on your camera on your mirror to take
the motion but some people may be into
that terminology this can be a pop quiz
all right this pot PSTN is your easy
once lingo all right you can have a
jello shot even though you've been on
that CEO line CEO yay PBX that's an easy
one hopefully now DTMF there you go now
about some protocols sip
there you go i okay you guys fit into IX
it's not really used MIT more there you
go XMPP XMPP that's a mouthful
anyway I know you know extensible
multimedia and that's it you I think
maybe ami a re this is elastic so we we
just skip that because we start a bit
late so those are all of them and if
anybody said anything wants to come grab
this planet yellow shells left yes so
what do they all do the protocol is
obviously facilitate communication PSD
ends all relate for the old telephone
network the PBX and asterisk that's kind
of like when you dial your phone it's
going to handle the calls
gateway is just another word for a line
out AGI is the gateway interface which I
said before it's like the CGI of
asterisk like the arm pit masters am i a
Ras management interfaces how you can
manage stuff within asterisk a ra is a
restful interface which is kind of more
modern gateway interface and extensions
to anyone no extensions are within a PBX
yeah so it's not an extension of
asterisk is like what you dial once
you've got a line 1 1 1 whatever
drunk-dial plant channels the channel is
the session of the core so you guys know
that codecs I'm not a huge codec nerd I
find them pretty interesting but that is
why is people can I'll give these all
day I'm not going to go into too much
detail bound but three major ones you
need to be worried about or know about
PCM I guess for a law you law versions
of PCM in the TSM then you got some high
def stuff
in 1972 7.11 was was approved and played
a toot for acronyms of things that's on
the right of the screen is all of the
codecs that I had in school for my
asterisks and there's a ton of them
they'll have their own little quirks
DTMF like jewel tone multi-frequency two
times played at once different
frequencies that's how that works
so you know that when you press number
on the phone OOP that's right that is
what happens why do people run PB X's
you don't have to have somebody sitting
there plugging stuff in can reduce your
costs if they keep calling and have your
apps within PBX that your voicemail may
be considered an app or conferencing
call queues directories basically people
also run them because everybody runs
them now right who doesn't have a PBX or
company
I know maybe small ones so we go over
the anatomy go internally boy somebody
runs their own externally or cloud
deployed and third-party managed like
ringcentral something maybe that's one
the basic deployment I even tried the
data
I made diagrams PBX in center you have a
couple of clients going this one soft
phone tip and then a TA which is an
analog telephone adapter which is going
to convert your old-school telephone not
the rotary won't do that but just a
regular telephone will we there's pretty
common a bigger deployment for like a
business would look kind of like that
you can tell this one's better because
it has two stacks on the PBX and there's
voicemail there is a maybe SMS inferring
in there video conferencing you kind of
see the link between the two providers
how you can skip through and they cause
from one location to the other
basically more calm more technologies
being added on maybe they've run a call
center or they do other stuff of that
they would do reporting on
cause and stuff maybe they do some
mobile stuff this is what Enterprise are
large I found this image I think this is
a Cisco's image may look like we're
going to spend like an hour on this now
that's really what it looks like nobody
knows they just keep on piling stuff on
basically more technology to factor off
it might be used for that like
somebody's dialing you back for
verification on sewing I'm not going to
read it you want a second yeah
just more and more more more
technologies getting piled on top until
nobody knows what the diagram looks like
or where something sits in the network
so we kind of took a low bun how test
like I said earlier when someone says we
want to test that one system how first
thing is what are you actually testing
right a lot of things test so it's only
more you can test is a really good first
step I can't cover everything to do with
like voice and phones because there's
just so much but I try and get through
some of it like mobile I'm not going to
be able tell you how to tear apart
mobile apps and how that works but never
agree that it's crazy cool cool I mean
seriously you've got hardware software
PBX cell phones apps verticals
codex is own beast because there's a lot
of issues with codecs like VLC if anyone
uses that video player always has a lot
of buffer player is going to come
through media codecs processing those
signals on each type is going to require
its own set of skills and yes a lot of
this so once you kind of figured out
what you're testing inside is that black
box white box like do you have
information or do you have to go out and
do extra work find stuff are you trying
to be stealthy are you trying to you
know duo's in you trying to avoid being
detected and see what would happen if
you've dialed something 10,000 times
what's going to figure out what's our
limit
yeah so there's some other stuff
Osen in grab phone numbers from the web
with directories look for patterns and
people's because sometimes companies are
going to buy a block of numbers maybe
you do port scans to try and find PBX
answer now they're showdown you can use
it try and identify MAC addresses or use
the web I use the web is kind of
different from web directories like you
go into a company's website trying to
browse through to find the phone numbers
they're using the web there's tons of
resources the who lists people's
information a free carrier lookup comm
with a carrier of a number see maybe you
can use the information and good source
find a phone number entry points who is
they list the technical context phone
number step there is that let's see
hey good
so when your that's been how do you test
right you can dial up through pots with
a regular telephone and press buttons
that sounds really exciting in front
just what you want to do is sit there
all day pressing buttons you can use
modems with 80 commands maybe get a
little bit more into it soft phones any
of the major one you can use it just
like a regular telephone or you can try
some of the automated of scriptable
stuff that's there's a ton of those out
there there's a steep learning curve to
that chip jsj s if MJ sip some of those
I didn't like any of the idea because
these kind of phones tend to go in and
out some of the older ones aren't
maintained anymore I have bugs so I
figured well I just use a PBX to just
write stuff in that this is my setup
it's a little like a Raspberry Pi it's
is anyone familiar with the orange PI's
anyone seem nice
or I know the Charlotte guys house
anymore even a bomb yeah it's like a
Raspberry Pi quad core it's got two gigs
around I think 16 gigs of NAND flash on
board it's really portable
giggy and basically yeah it's good
little board it's portable you can take
it with you somewhere if somebody wants
something shiny to look at because
you're testing a phone system and you
must show them something you put it in
the box take it we can say this is what
it's $20 this is what did fun stuff so
yeah
because I didn't want to pay for eyes
replay now it's a friend of mine that
has onboard flash so you don't need a SD
card or anything
the Gigabit Ethernet is also separated
from the USB bus so you get a little bit
more traffic throughput with it and yeah
that they were really cheap I think 20
25 30 bucks something like that and it
just seemed one of the things I wanted
try yeah
the software is I ambien which is a
derivative debian asterisk and bunch of
scripting utilities
I'm getting a little bit into that more
later I'll show you some of the other
stuff go into the issue types so now we
can do can anybody name the OWASP top 10
of the heads now can anyone name
anything from the OWASP top 10 a one
well located towards a one an injection
you can have a jealousy I know you want
one a to close it
broken authentication of session mode
there on the next slide okay
yeah with yeah okay you get two drinks
now that was huh as to jello shots for
fish so yeah this is them yeah they're
just coming out of a new one I'm not
sure when it was but this is 2013 so say
what no trolling me back there is you're
out now when did that come out not for a
release right release candidate yeah
yeah in August year so everybody goes by
2013 still that injection to improving
the phone system you've got web voice
sip or DTMF is going to be your
injection points and you're basically
going to come up with either cross-site
scripting buffer overflow or log
contaminant sure there's many other
things you can do if you haven't find a
valid injection I really wanted to have
i recently within past month asterisk
had a buffer overflow they would have
loved to a demo but I'm not good at
buffer overflows and it causes for it
was you have to have this module in this
module they stand on a mister it will
take a longer to configure it and but
yeah so no demo for that broken open
session management we've thought about
mostly authentication people will not
implement an SSL TLS sip for the
transport in general yeah if you're
external is not really much you can do
with that unless you can get in the
middle to do that what you need to do to
be in the middle and capture that
traffic that the authorization I guess
technically will fall into exists broken
but we talked about that a little bit
later but good things in the perspective
TLS was added in one point the asterisk
one point six which was released a
really long time ago people just really
slow to implement that so I'm going to
speed up block its cross-site scripting
we know what this is it could get really
interesting with some of the SIP
frameworks sip yes
if you can make a payload to deploy to
somebody which can then connect to their
PBX where you figured out where it sits
what it talks that could be really
really fun but yeah unsecured or very
object references this was a really hard
slope for me to come up with because
it's hard to map this to it but then I
got thinking I mean other than this in a
big disappointment so far up to four and
not really anything covered it's just
what it would look like right
somebody doesn't have access to their
account they just take the Victoria
Secret thing where you could see other
people's orders you could change the
order number and see what they had
ordered so this could maybe translate
into you down into a phone system and
then you dial an extension that is an
external phone number maybe it's
basically translates into a bag config
or it could be from a gateway interface
or from the app configuration related to
a5 does anyone there were a five is we
already went over this 2013 now and you
guys are quiet after lunch let's get
someone
so yeah it was a great album has a grey
album so this configuration this is
really common ship configured to allow
people that used to be the default word
so yeah anybody can connect and then
just people with misconfigure their
style plans so you could perform cause
as anyone sitting in the desk mine has
once been misconfigured accidentally and
I may have made some calls to some
places they probably shouldn't have its
audited passwords that I mean would you
call that miss configuration probably if
you can have like a 10 character
password or a 6 is how many combinations
of passwords there were four characters
versus six or however many on an
arbitrary length
efore weak passwords for portals
voicemails zip clients a six
these are easy turn see a pattern
everything's kind of related somehow
it's kind of a convoluted do it so your
voicemail Krampus calls any of these I
mean sensitive information is what it is
credit condoms count numbers
verification pins call information that
kind of stuff on system is going to be a
logs function level access control so
this is interesting so caller ID spoof
if you've ever called somewhere and
smoothed your call already and notice
that you've got a different response
because your phone number said something
different it's kind of a functional
level access control right because
you're trusting the youth the call
coming in facing your whole trust honor
string that can be changed the other one
user logs in to change username password
fails they can try another one if they
can just do that sit there all day long
I mean that's the functional level
access control because you're not
checking say hey this guy's been sitting
on my phone line for 10 hours pressing
buttons yeah
that that one anyone want any more
information on that
I mean basically reasonable use rate
comes down to that make sure you use
this dial in on them camping on your
phone line eight eight is
cross-site request forgery some vendors
are going to be more susceptible to this
because they care about their products
maybe but are they going to do the
fences because oh this is internal only
nobody's going to get that kind of thing
but when it's paired with exercise is
pretty good have some bad results we've
seen a lot of them recently with like
Netgear look at Negi the home routers
having that cross-site request forgery
where they were basically reconfiguring
the routers for people through posting
links online that was great yeah if you
did your enumeration properly it's not
going to be difficult to find out who
the vendor of a system is and we get
into situations similar to see Cerf a
bit later on so a nine components with
known vulnerabilities everybody uses if
these fag can't cover every PBX out
there and or then I did want to have
like a really cool chart but I ended up
doing more content instead of making
pretty pictures yeah so here's an
example of a component with a known
vulnerability that's the ATA we saw
earlier he'll nata made by Cisco I think
it was 2002 that came out and they still
so on people still use them that's what
it looks like when you find go to the
page it's like you've made in 96 right
something like I would break that's what
it looks like when you log in exam
tastic doesn't it
it turns out there was a bog list for
this where you could bypass the
authentication by entering a one-bite or
someone character and a poster question
would just let you in and then you can
reconfigure the the ata to do whatever
it wanted and that's what it looks like
when you turn connect with SSL so that's
not cool
that's the what is that a Cisco state
some when they stopped selling it I
can't even see on this screen but
basically the end of life did before
they stopped selling it is that I'm
seeing mm-hmm that's with why would you
do that
so how I'm pretty sure see set up for
work on that portal if you really wanted
to target those but how does it relate
yeah it's pretty related and you'll
remember
c2fo s number of 2013 taking to make
sure you paying attention
oh come on it's a jello shot good tons
of you've got to get up and take them
close you can go on just the same number
nine just like that it was a right yeah
everyone doesn't want those jello shots
say let's go then how long we got twenty
minutes we're good see I'm doing good on
time normally I try a go way too fast
and then I get upset because they're
finished contentment I'm Bella debris
these are really common on the web
everybody seen these some people usually
deliver malware and use some trick
people on a PBX IV is maybe trickier
it's going to have a bit more of a
higher impact maybe you do loops you tie
up some functionality by Pascack use
there's a whole bunch of fraud stuff
that can be done if you have a doubt
into a call center and you're waitin on
the line you hear the beep beep maybe
you can use those tones to replay into
that next time you call back and you
won't have to sit in the line maybe you
can do that sometimes it's very similar
to a free which I didn't write down on
my notes what number a3 is so I guess I
should get a jello shot that a man
sleeping
so another potential vector for this is
somebody calls the call center and as a
bad phone number and they call me back
you dials that phone number not jegging
and it's fraud the bonus slides for the
overstuffed and the really boring part
of the presentation unless it's all
boring is insufficient and insufficient
and the automation that's related to a 5
a 6 a 10 kind of brute forcing
everything extensions voicemail
conference codes leader codes counts
called directories passwords ATM and
related to that by long session timeouts
many we ID set that way so this is how I
would map it if I was going to map
friend systems to the OS stuff and I
took a little while thinking about this
and trying to go through it there's no
research behind it I would like to kind
of do some more in the map what happens
with them and see if this matches up but
that would be my take on totally up the
debate and it probably could be if you
moved around set anyone have any ideas
think phone systems what they would what
order they will put in maybe injection
could be higher I know everybody's bored
out of their minds
no I did search all right that's for my
lady
I put the slides online news they know
you're an idiot this one should go up
there and this one should go down there
because this happened or something I
know we should debate it and make a good
one so once you've installed asterisk
and I am got that far on it yet because
every year these conferences kind of
sneak up on me some reason I so I did
say made a vagrant VM I'm making a
vagrant VM for everybody that kind of
takes everything you don't need out of
asterisk and setting it up because there
is so much stuff like you can configure
it is just overwhelming I'm trying to me
cut it down to a slimmer version so you
can get in that and like use a soft
phone or start scripting
so the console is pretty easy to use so
you can use it like Metasploit or any
other console once you've got it
installed that's how you show the help
prep also help call share help which is
great that's really fun but maybe it's
just me that I have issues with the
interface because I don't understand
phone systems that much but it's it's
pretty difficult to use but trying to
make it easy there we get to the fun
stuff now so yeah I have a job and I
like it a lot and I had the opportunity
to test our phone system I was secondary
on it somebody else picked up from from
the kid and I was getting nowhere with
menu sitting there like dialing I think
I did it maybe for a hour or more and I
got really bored of just listening to
the same voice over and over I was
really gained the role of it so I had
this idea like social engineering was
out scope so I couldn't do anything talk
to anybody what I could do is sit there
and go through the Thank You group had
this idea to write a man-in-the-middle
call and see if it would work I had no
idea if it would work and there's some
pictures and stuff you know try and if
it worked there's a grand scheme to see
how he is a bad person to target either
clients or internal employees customers
whatever there's nothing new from a tax
payer an attack perspective I think I've
seen some old hacker movies that may
have done the same kind of thing but I'm
trying to make try to do with more
modern systems like with a computer
instead of a tape recorder basically
there's two vectors for it I like to
call the first one the fat finger squat
and the second one is this brutal target
of itch
yeah those are the vectors so the fat
fingers squat is this is how I would do
a diagram for it like the bad guys there
he stood the Grim Reaper in this cape I
guess that's Grim Reaper but he's got a
telephone on his stuff and you have this
poor guy on the Left I mean he's got a
hook for a hand he conned I was phone
properly how's it going to hit the
buttons and he dies on wrong number
and goes to the Grim Reaper but the Grim
Reaper's just sitting there and he's
gonna create call to the good guy the
guy this guy originally intended to call
but just sit there and record the line
and pass that fruit so that was the
concept it worked great in the end the
tons out because when this guy calls
this guy and this guy four words to call
before it forwards the caller ID so
company didn't know that it wasn't the
original guy
maybe so I have a little demo of this we
can see if it'll work maybe I have a
live demo but then I have a backup plans
there
we do it light first we don't my going
to take the aux out in my pop let's do
it live so I call my home phone number
maybe home phone number is sandal how
loud it basically there we go
see your answers Merry Christmas
as with all huge whoa-oh
so I was going to use the ambling I just
press five probably listen to us at the
moment
okay it records everything you'd say I
was going to use it company but I
decided not to because it's not fair to
target one company or because I mean
anybody can do that to any companies
there it's just going to be invisible so
the second leg there is very similar to
the first one except instead of doing it
waiting somebody to dial in you would
have somebody actively engaging say I
wanted to target Anubis in the front row
I'll call and say hey I saw you tweeted
about your account you have an issues
right and oh yeah thanks coin and then
basically you dues you would forward or
no Jenna call to the call center and say
nothing you just sit there
okay I'm transferring you to the call
center now and beep you're sitting there
recording it you can record those tones
I think this diagram kind of explains
that you spoof caller ID calling the guy
with the hook hand and he has no idea
because he's a guy then you record and
you could even have contacts or you
could just have no context if you wanted
yeah I mean if you see you can I guess
write a botton Twitter that just wait
for people to complain and you've
already harvested their information so
you just go ahead and send them a call
maybe you could do that so yeah it
flushes it in through the call center
how can I help so that was the fun I got
they have
I have no demo for that because if I was
trying to hand
how do I do this I've got so many things
going on but it's pretty much the same
as the first factor so yeah it's the
same except not a little bit different
so what can you do with that what would
anybody do with that goes in there and
I've recorded somebody's phone session
anything don't care none of you care
security questions bank information
right tones yeah so well it might
contain what we talked about at the
beginning maybe maybe some DTMF it
really depends on the target system who
you're testing as to what it would
contain so but generally you're going to
get some kind of voice some kind of
tones or response that yeah from the
beginning all set sound what does this
look like those DTMF so you can decode
that if you get used to right codecs and
stuff and it comes through properly
I can have an issues of it recently the
first time I difficult to set up but the
first time I said it up it was working
then I tried it again and it features
it's wrong for my attended there so the
reliability is not 100% we're kind of
working on that to figure out why maybe
I need a hardware decoder that I mean
that maybe it's a software maybe it's
somewhere in between got to figure that
out but basically you can decode the
tones since you have a recording of the
voice session so I guess this entry I've
been working on this for a while freaka
me started out kind of as a joke and
then moved into more of Doc's I did
bunch of changes last year get a REST
API ID there or Patrick wrote the sap
module so you could make calls and do
social engineering preset and added a
web there's been not very many changes
to this it's going to be more to come
whenever get time the welcome end people
want to actually do stuff some as
interesting but I want to re-engineer
everything do some more continuity write
some multi-step from because I think now
be cool
if you can and somebody does instead of
hanging up I said that last year that I
wanted to do the stuff but instead they
did stuff for work which is a lot of fun
so I think I can use a lot of this and
add those two vectors to it and I plan
on doing that so people can use those
and maybe in their engagements if they
want to test some phone stuff just so
many ideas if anybody has any ideas
I have loved theorem yeah that's about
it we were right on time that's about it
so yeah I'd like to see people from 2600
you know get back into phone systems
that's kind of the roots I was trying to
get with the whole presentation at the
evolution of stuff so seeing things grow
like super quickly I don't as far as I'm
concerned like when 97 you never it
again a stranger's car now you summon
strangers from the internet and get in
their cars
that's I can't take credit for that yeah
it's pretty crazy Sam yeah phone systems
are still relevant phone numbers aren't
going away right you with Illinois
recently had something where people do
not want to get rid of their landlines
because their medical devices are
connected to them so they may be around
for a while and they've been around this
long so hopefully it was useful maybe
somebody's stuff I think I covered
everything that I promised to cover is
there any questions or anything any want
no jello shot questions now and silence
all right I didn't have to use this
slide
the whole thing yeah how could that
together this I'm there is a project
online there's got some stuff but you
want more of a written guide at how I
yeah I should have actually put them my
slow that was one of the last changes I
can do to github.com and it's just freak
me I believe we can verify that
afterwards because they really should
have included that but yeah that's it
any more questions those