so as we get started on this it's not an
oversized crowd so if you have any
questions I think we'd probably work
them in I don't have a lot of slides
just basically some introduction in some
areas this is very demo intensive so the
number area the number of things I want
to cover one we're going to go ahead and
let's see if I get the right one on here
we're going to go over some basics on
using a logic analyzer so that's always
that's always kind of cool if I can get
it hooked up properly when we get to
that point if we can't then I get a
video I always have videos because you
never know when shits gonna go to hell
in a handbasket so so I've been working
on this presentation on and off and
there's a few things that aren't 100%
perfect I apologize for that it's kind
of a work in progress and kind of worked
out in a way of some stuff but we're
gonna get all the basics covered and
give you guys some stuff that you can go
out of here with and hopefully do some
cool and break some hardware and I
know I got tons of broken hardware so
nothing wrong with destroying it that's
why they make garbage cans so the
presentation today is you boot two
routes so obviously we're going to cover
some concepts around you boot some
methods on some IOT to actually get into
the u-boot console and then we're going
to cover a couple of interesting things
you can do I have two different videos
accessing you boots very similar and
then I'm going to do something outside
of the u-boot also it's something you
often deserve when you get a console on
a better hardware a consumer grace one
that often shows up and I want to show
that also so hopefully this works out
and we get through all the demos without
any major glitches so let's start off
with getting new batteries well
it's first one so the first thing we
want to cover what is what is you boot
so you boot you boot is a in the United
States you boot is not a submarine in
Germany you put is submarine so a
universal boot loader is what we're
talking about and it's used a low it's
loaded from flash memory and it loads up
and it calls another storage area or
maybe the same storage area and loads
the operating system or kernel in the
memory and executed to move from there
you can often access this via serial
connections so that's why we're going to
use the logic analyzer to dig in to
identify a serial connection and then we
get into it has a very minimal command
set so you're going to see all the
command set you're going to see looking
at the environment we're going to alter
environment variables on the device
we're going to write them back to the
device so we get it to do certain things
that we want to do so why do you want to
attack you boot other than because you
can freaking do it often you want to
gain root access why do I want to gain
root access typically there's two
reasons for that if I gain root access I
can actually monitor the running
application running code on the system
it gives me more insight and what's
going on if we want to do further
testing looking for bugs vulnerabilities
and things like that it's also great for
extracting firmware if I want to get a
firmware off the device there's a number
of ways to do it I could pull the chip
off the device I may be able to use a
reader on the device or if I can get
root level access and there's an
expiration means either USB or our
network we can go ahead and make calls
right too often the block devices on the
on the system and actually do dd copies
off and with DD copies we can also alter
that data even if it's a non writable
filesystem bring them back in we're not
going to do this but bring them back in
unload the filesystem rewrite the actual
chip the block device with DD and alter
the device which is what we did last
year was kind of the hard way if anyone
was in that presentation we actually
pulled an embedded multimedia controller
and we actually did that here showing
how to do that so you can alter firmware
you install your own perform for
firmware if you want to alter the device
and use it for some other purpose I
don't wanna keep using that damn it so
so in the beginning understanding and
identifying so before if you're gonna
get into hardware the first thing you
want to do is start understanding
hardware and often one of the best ways
to do that is literally tear the devices
down let's start looking at them so we
have a number on this one happens to be
a luma luma is a mesh device it does
Wi-Fi and Bluetooth I use this example
because I had a number of
characteristics that I wanted to show
and demo this evening so we can easily
look into that so I always encourage
people to go out and get your hands on
hardware just by any hard work go to go
to a secondhand store buy junk off eBay
and before you start hooking stuff up to
it and doing all this crazy stuff just
learn what's there open the device up
and look at it let's get into
identifying is there a place where
there's a header where it can
potentially connect our tools into the
system to identify what's going on there
where are the memory chips this happens
to be a NAND flash chip it's a SPI
serial peripheral interface type device
this over here is a controller for the
Ethernet this here being an arm ipq 4018
is a Wi-Fi chip you can go out and pull
down the data sheets on all these
particular devices and look at it before
you put power to it before you do
anything understand what's going on
behind the scenes learn to identify that
because it's often very similar in
nature as you start digging into these
devices and there's structure of the
chipsets the type of data things you're
looking at so you want to be able to do
that pop off these shields the only
thing you need these shields for is to
meet FCC regulations and we know where
that's going
so pop all these shields off often often
I'll pop the shields off I think we have
I think this one actually has me pull
this off here this has a jumper wire on
just ignore that pass it around so you
can look in you can look into the device
and underneath here happens to be the
RAM chips one of the easiest way to
identify the RAM chips is you see all
these squiggly lines there's no straight
hole shot lines going to the actual chip
they're all squiggly communication the
RAM chip is in parallel that all has to
get there at the same time thus they
actually function as delay functionality
to be able to read and write to the RAM
chip so if you actually look at this
underneath that I'll pass it around you
can actually see all those squiggly
lines so it's a quick way to identify
standard RAM chips on a device so we're
at a point where we're getting into
basics there's a number of tools that
you can use to actually identify serial
communications which is a console you
want to get on the device and it's you
are universal asynchronous receive
transmit there's a number of tools of
doing that you can go out by jtagulator
160 bucks or something like that but
this has other means to you can use this
for testing for JTAG so what it does is
you hook this up to all the pins and
I'll go through a series of sequences
and it'll send data to those and try to
get a response back and it'll do it with
all the different pins at all the
different ball rate speeds to try to
identify which ones read which ones
right and what the ball rate is so it's
it's it's somewhat convenient and it
works pretty good you can also use a
multimeter and actually measure voltage
on it and I've seen people talk about
that I actually think that sucks
come on there's a lot better ways of
actually doing it that is the cheapest
way for sure but it's not a guarantee of
what you're actually looking for another
way is a logic analyzer now you can get
these in different price ranges this one
here is like a $700 one it's eight
channels 100 mega psych 100 megahertz
sampling rate so it's pretty pretty high
in this one unfortunately they quit
making this was a there for I don't
remember what the sampling rate is it's
a four connector one this used to be
like 99 bucks so it used to be cheap I'm
not sure but sale a when they quit
producing this told me they had a
freaking pile of these things
in the warehouse because I contacted and
bitching about them because I want to
teach for training purposes so they sold
me six of them for like 50 bucks so that
is an option to reach out and say hey do
you still have that I'm trying to learn
and I'm looking to use your product this
is one of the better products but
there's a number of cheap ones out there
that work pretty good and I'd recommend
this is the best way for doing analysis
looking for UART connections also using
the tool we're gonna show and I'll show
some of the stuff in it there's like 20
different decode protocols in the
application that you can actually use
everything from CANbus spi uart
the list goes on and on and on it comes
in really handy for doing various other
circuit analysis on the device but it's
great for figuring out what you are if
it's UART and what the pinout is and
what the bald rate is fairly quick with
very little effort so the first thing
you want to do is do a demo and let's
see if this will actually work any
questions while I'm fumbling around here
Universal asynchronous received transmit
it's a serial console
I'll use the expensive one because
that's why serial interface when you're
looking for serial interfaces you can
often find those on a lot of the MC use
or the processors you also saw find you
aren't used for internship
communications like if you have a
Bluetooth chip on a board and you have a
processor whether it's a Wi-Fi processor
or a standalone microcontroller they
actually communicate to each other over
UART and that seems to be the standard
and that's internship communication so
you can look at that and decode that
information there but it's often on a
lot of the microcontrollers and
controllers either by default or can be
defined via GPIO general purpose input
output and that's usually done
programmatically on devices and a lot of
vendors will do that they'll have
consoles almost most of the devices I
open up have some form of console if
especially if they have a full operating
system some type you know some full
embedded operating system you're able to
do that ok let's come over here and it's
all about time I'm gonna get through
this in time we're not going to get
through this a talk okay so on the four
channel one let's go ahead and wrong and
let me jump over here to this right here
so you can see the device so hopefully
everyone can see that does it look good
behind me can you see it okay so maybe a
little focus issues I like this camera
but it has its own little issues okay
it's good enough
so everything's gonna be backwards from
what I'm looking at so we can see right
here is the actual pins these are kind
of high pins where we've actually
soldered the board we'll just have four
holes in it it'll be typically 2.5 4
millimeters so you can buy strips of
those you can break off stick them in
and solder min to get the headers
working and then what we need to do is I
know that the first one on here the very
first one right here is a ground pin and
the way we do that is we
a multimeter and we check it against
like in this case these ground lugs that
go to the ground plane on the device we
checked to see does it ring out with a
multimeter so it's actually ground so
once you identify ground you want to
actually hook the ground ones to it so
in this case here the lower wires on
these rigs all black on the bottom of
course they made the first line black
too which sucks but the head on it's
actually black so that's a ground line
so if we can get my blindness to
actually see this thing dark and of
course watch old man fumble around here
and we got black brown black brown and
red we got four channels we're gonna
look at three channels on this thing I
wouldn't really typically worry about
the order you can figure that out once
you're seeing the communications so so
what we're looking for a serial and off
to check these not all of the headers
that you find will have a UART on it
they could easily be a JTAG connection
or some other in circa serial program
connection so we have that hooked up so
that what we want to do is jump over
here to I believe this one and it did
detect it my device so we know that's
good and this program is called logic
sail a logic this varenka probably needs
updated it's 1.2 but if we come over
here we can actually set things so we
can set the sampling rates and how long
we want this to runs so we go ahead and
set this for 20 seconds on mine I can
have up to eight channels on this one so
once we get that set at 20 seconds you
get a power plug over here and we're
going to go ahead and start this once it
started I'm going to put power to it
so if I had a power strip on and
apparently I don't have the power strip
on so let's turn it on okay so now we
got all the balloonists on the backside
of this and it's running and we should
capture some stuff here
so once it's done running you can use up
and down arrow keys to look at this
stuff and we can see we have
communication on channel zero usually
when I see this and I only see one
channel doing that and not like all four
of them with similar communications on
it
now you usually quickly identify that
this happens to be potentially you are
so what we can do is and as I mentioned
with the analyzers you have a number of
different analyzers let's see if we can
show all the different analyzers let's
see get this up so you guys can see it
so we can see all the different
analyzers have happened to be available
for decoding so it's a fairly decent set
sometimes you can actually pick up other
decoders available as kind of plug-in
type functionality come back down here
and what we're gonna do is we are going
to set up an async of course I managed
to lose my freaking glasses okay
and we know it's channel 1 so we're
going to go ahead and set to channel 1
the next thing is the bold rate so how
do you determine the bald rate there's a
number of ways to doing it one way is we
can blow this thing out and logic gives
you ability to take a measurement so you
can take a measurement of the shortest
pulse in there take what that
measurement is in microseconds and
divide it into one you're gonna come up
with a number that's going to be
basically the ball rate are close it's
not 100% accurate it's close you're
gonna land mostly at one of the
standards so you have a whole bunch of
standards so you can Google standard
Baldrige so you're gonna get a list up
and running from 9600 up to 200 I
believe or 200 and something but IOT
typically falls into two general areas
90% of the time or more and that is
and the other one is 1 1 5 200 so I just
pick you know it's guess it didn't work
change it there's only so many options
and if none of those work then you may
have to dig a little do do a little math
if somebody's some vendor decided he
wanted to get weird and play with you
head by creating weird things I had one
device as an example it actually changed
a number of these other settings so
let's expand this out so you can see it
so you have eight bits one stop no
parity I had one vendor that as the
system booted up you can see the whole
boot process and when it loaded kernel
it changed the parity bit that took me
freaking a whole day to figure out what
the hell was going on I'm like this
makes absolutely no sense I know this is
UART I know what's going on why is this
changing I'm I'm getting gibberish all
of a sudden but I eventually got that
figured out so we're going to go ahead
and set this to 1 1 5 200 and we're
going to go ahead and save that out and
it should decode so if we go ahead and
we expand this out and we see that line
up there we can see that we've actually
decode this data so we have these
characters if we come over to the right
hand side we can see it all over here so
we can see it's saying format so format
logic and we can see that now we do have
a true serial connection and we've
actually decoded it as you are standard
async communication any questions I
would recommend if you're interested in
hardware get one either try to track
down to use sale a I love these they're
great devices I do not own stock in the
company you're not quite sure the
cheapest one right now is around 300 so
it's a fairly heavy cost point our price
point but I think you could probably
track down one of the smaller force and
you could always contact them and say
hey you know I'm trying to learn this
stuff and I'm really entry-level they
may sell you one at ninety bucks they
may actually go cheaper I don't know if
they happen to still have them so I
would not pass up that opportunity to
give that a try so the next thing we
want to do is now that we've done that
let's go ahead and disconnect that and
then what we're going to do is we're
going to go over to a chakra chakra
to get here so here's a Chikara shikre
is a small device and you could do a
number of different things with this you
can do spi you can do some JTAG stuff
you use an open OCD I don't use it for
none of those because I'm lazy so I buy
the right tools but this thing is
actually great for UART
communication it's simple it's easy and
there's a number of FTD FTDI 232 devices
all different brands out there just pick
one for this type of stuff there's even
a board that will actually have four of
them built right into it so then you
want to go ahead and look at that well
if I have a cable here and I do
so go ahead this up plug it in here so
the things you need to be concerned with
as we as we looked at this and we
connect it to this particular device we
also we notice where the ground was so
that's easy enough pen eighteens the
ground and then they have receive or
transmit the rule of thumb is if this
pin happens to be transmitted okay
because we receiving data from it if
it's a received channel you're not gonna
see nothing on it's gonna be zero
voltage on it so it's going to be on one
side or the other
both of those are zero it's 50/50 plug
it in if it doesn't work plug it in the
other side and the goal is is you have
to go from transmit to receive and from
receive to transmit you know what I mean
so that they crossover or you won't get
communication again I usually don't give
this much thought I just plug it in if
it doesn't work I swap the wires makes
it fairly easy so I'm gonna power this
off so don't mess it up and we're gonna
go ahead and hook how are we on time and
run a little longer than I thought
either way we should get through this if
push comes to shove on presentations I
can run through some of the other videos
and it's lighting that's rough in here
okay I think you got it and we're gonna
give it a whirl and see if I got it
right so I use and you can use a number
of different serial consoles this
particular one that I'm using is it's
cool term
I like cool term I just run it on my Mac
comes and easy so now we have to come
over here to options so we want to see
if we actually see our device if we do
there is the us B serial connection we
have we know what the bald rate is it's
one one five two hundred the data bits
were all the same there's no parity 1
stop bit only thing left was some
terminal settings so my terminal works
right handle this and you can play
around this find out what works best
from a terminal standpoint you go ok you
connect to the device I like that tick
mark that make me and I actually got it
right the first time it maybe not so
let's find out I think maybe not ok love
these swap these around here real quick
and of course it was always a chance my
thing is going bad oh gosh come on up
here and go in oh good one of the things
about shipping stuff and throwing it
around in your bag is you like Jam
up so we're going to start over and I'm
going to use another one that's kind of
little less mangled ya know watching
watching Darrell plug things in is kind
of boring just don't throw up my
head
okay a little garbage they're not sure
why we'll find out now this is another
50/50 whether I plugged it in right
because I wasn't paying attention hoping
I got these things plugged in right
wonders of live demos yeah because if
this part fails then the next part can't
be done of course I forgot to do
something like actually check to see if
oh gosh yeah cancel let's disconnect
Cory that's probably why it's not
working there we go I got that okay
connect let's try one more time damn it
this doesn't work I need to check my
other connectors yeah I'm having some
problems here sorry about that guys any
questions why fumble of course I haven't
given you anything to ask questions
about yet have I
what's that I think the bus pirates a
piece of but that's my opinion
yeah here we go
okay so we're booting up it was just
some connection issues hit any key -
ought to be okay there we go okay
of course this device is messed up so we
have to I apologise apparently I grabbed
the wrong device where's that devices
going around anyone still have that
bring it here real quick yeah the reason
why is one of these was used for another
demo so it wasn't reset properly
so the bus part has its traits but and
it probably worked pretty good on cereal
to be honest with you my experience with
it was trying to use it to pull flash
memory out and it has a tendency to run
a little slow and definitely if you're
in a VM environment has serious problems
with the USB bus on timing issues I
actually took the one that I had and
reprogrammed it as an SDK 500 to do
connections to atmega chips to be able
to rule pull the firmware off this and
that it works really good at give me
me why is this in playing with me I
apologize dammit this is crazy
should you just rewrote the other one
could have done that okay so it's
already booting up so you can get to the
whole idea of the boot okay so we get a
logon on this thing apologize for that
that's kind of kind of screwed up on my
part I had them all plug together
plugged into use and of course they got
unplugged in the bag being bouncing
around into one the pins were all
mangled and it was actually a couple
shorted out to each other so that's why
I pulled that out there so it wouldn't
be any more problems and this thing will
come up as as Illuma we don't know the
password I've got the hash off of it we
weren't able to crack that which is not
uncommon for a lot of number of these
devices so one of the things we want to
do and let me jump over now that we're
at this point let's go ahead and while
that's running up let's go ahead and
step over here breaking in console
methods for gaining access so there's a
number of different methods but you want
to be able to get into you boo you boot
has what's known as a boot delay
so you can fire up a device and you can
actually see it count down from three to
one that means it has a boot delay in
place most of the board's you're gonna
run into that's going to be set to zero
that means you're not going to be able
to halt it and go into you boot mode so
and it can be set in seconds but you
have to get into you boot console to be
able to set that so we want to be able
to do that so the way we're going to
actually do that is an attack we know
and refer to as a ping glitch for know
better terms and the way that works is
we have we have a memory chip in this
case this is much easier to do on this
way there's two memory chips there's one
on the other side of the board happens
to be an 8-pin SOI c spi flash chip that
actually holds you bit the chip on the
upper side happens to be a nan spi chip
this one this is a w saw and socket it's
like five by air six by seven or five by
six millimeters pretty small and that's
the actual pin out so the ultimate goal
is as you boot loads up what you want to
do is prevent it from after it's loaded
you don't want to do anything while
floating just load it you want to
actually stop it from me actually being
able to read the kernel by default you
boot will fell into a console when you
actually do that so so and here we have
the actual pin house so the pin you want
to take the ground happens to be the
slave out for the spi this is the
outgoing data now as I show this to you
don't go out and go hey let's just start
shorting out and see what happens
because you will find out quickly what
will happen and it won't go good for you
number of times this attack works a lot
of times doesn't work all the times I
was doing an engagement for a customer
we had a similar layout like this but
they were reading everything from one
chip so big timing issue there because
it's just literally milliseconds so you
have to try like 4050 times before you
get it to fail into you boot console all
I managed to do is have it to fail in by
wiping out the u-boot somehow it was
kind of weird so in the demo what we're
going to do is we're actually going to
ground this out as the device is booting
up and as presentation has been going so
far this level to go to hell
handbasket - but I hope not
I usually put a lot of time into working
through these demos so that we can that
we can have good demos live demos and
make sense so we have this device so
we're gonna actually going to power this
device off and then we're gonna go ahead
I don't want that document camera we
don't want that we actually want the USB
microscope okay so we get into the
microscope here this USB microscope and
we kind of bring this thing down bring
it in focus a little bit here happens to
be the actual chip so I've already
hooked to the ground plane of this wire
here to the ground plane and a goal is
as soon as you power this thing up you
want to be able to ground out pin two
which happens to be this pin right here
okay and while you're doing that you
don't want to short out other
because that's not good so we're gonna
cry do this and we got to be able to
watch the console on the other side so
let's shorten this up a little bit let's
bring this over so we can see some kind
of traffic taking place over here let's
clear this data hopefully we'll get this
the first time I was doing it the other
day for some reason like this is really
easy it took me like four times I'm like
well you're not even in front of people
Darrell you're not supposed to screw
this up when you're in your lab by
yourself
yep nope too quick powered off boom so
now there's there's a number of
different commands there is a print
environment print EMV and we can see the
can everyone see that good I try to make
it big enough so UK so we're actually
able to see the environment variables so
we can walk up through here and there's
a couple of interesting environment
variables right here right here we have
let's see if this laser pointer works
dan this thing's like sheep oh that's
why I didn't have it turned on what a
dumbass so so I'm a real comedian today
so if we come over here we have we have
boot delay so we have boot delay boot
delay right here so we can actually set
that so the first thing we're going to
do is we're gonna set boot delay to a
number and then we're gonna power it off
and back on again and you can see how we
can actually halter it so let's go ahead
and do that first and see if we can get
through that without blowing my leg off
and the way we do that is we want to set
E and V boot delay and we're gonna set
it at 5 put that out there let's go
ahead and scroll our print environment
see if that will actually look right so
we have boot delay set to 5 and then
what we want to do is we want to save
the environment variables out there so
now we've written an entire environment
variables back to the system things that
are weird
this should normally work you should be
able to write back to the chip no
problem I did actually encounter a piece
of hardware we were actually at this
level here I was changing environment
variables and I said say V and V
and it literally wiped the entire flash
chip blank I have yet to figure out why
the saving grace was and this was a gig
for a customer the saving grace was and
they had no idea why it did it either I
actually made a copy of the firmware by
pulling the chip off and pulling the
firmware and putting the chip back go on
so all I did was pull a chip off reflash
the firmware I typically pull chips if
it's like an SPI because if you're
actually going to read and write to an
SPI chip to pull flash memory you have
to actually take the main processor
reset and you have to take the CPU in
the reset mode or it'll interfere with
that communication
I typically notice if it's an i2c chip
ITC is a bus protocol so if you hook up
to that you will actually put a request
on the bus to communicate with it and
typically you can do those in circuit
just a couple quick notes there so from
here there's a command let's look at the
commands real quick so a dollar here a
question mark you can actually see the
commands you boot will be will be
compiled different for every product
with different functions so you can see
a massive amount of different
functionality that may be there or not
be there I've seen the command structure
to be really minimal and I've seen it be
very intense so here's the command
instructions and you can do all kinds of
things you can read from memory you can
boot a boot from TFTP which we're
actually going to do to get some level
of access to the device
so once we've saved that out one of the
commands is reset which actually cause
the CPU to go reset mode and it should
reboot for us and it should come up at
one point and actually prompt us so we
no longer have the glitch so then you
just hit the enter key and there we've
broken out of it because we put that
delay function in there so at this point
some of the things we want to do is the
ultimate goal is to actually get root
access to the actual device so at this
point with the delay put in only with
that delay set other than zero the
function called boot command will
actually work okay so at this point you
can actually put specific boot commands
in there in our case I am actually
going to just cut and paste to be able
to do that because I don't want to type
all this stuff and we're not going to
write it in there what we're going to do
is we're gonna run it from the console
run it from the u-boot console so what
we're gonna do here based on the system
booting up we know where everything is
in memory typically I have to check one
more thing before we run this is gonna
go to hell on us a couple things to to
mention we have this device actually has
server IP this happens to be the IP
address of the TFTP server so before we
get started let's go ahead and cancel
out of that
let me check real quick here we have a
VM running here and I'm just going to go
ahead and what was that it was 182 so we
need to set it to 11 . 182 wrong 1182 so
I'm going to go ahead and just do this
under edit connections our connection
chain just a medial add one not to 182
did I type that in right okay okay and
then we want to have out of there and
then we want to go ahead and save that
out and then we have Ethernet connected
up
and my wiring mess and we're gonna plug
the ethernet into this luckily this
thing had a couple Ethernet ports I
wasn't sure how long these videos would
take or these demos would take so we're
still making good time we won't be able
to go through all of them but I can run
a quick video and talk to you through
some of the other stuff so at this point
let's see if we can actually ping it
ping 192.168.1.1 82 using Ethernet and
of course it's not there okay we went to
split-screen my screen got even smaller
so I'm like going blind here okay now
it's up in live so at this point we can
actually do TFTP it's gonna take the
TFTP variables that are actually in this
particular boot which is the actual
server it's going to go out and what I
did was I went out since this is an IP Q
4018 chip there was there was some open
wrt projects out there for it so we're
actually able to compile one we didn't
get all the pieces work in one of the
reasons one of the reasons is is that
secondary chip on here happens to be a
very non-standard chip so I ran out of
time the process would be to actually
rebuild the kernel with the new device
tree where I define all the variables
for that particular chip into a DTS file
which was we just walked
that process recently so I didn't get it
actually into the system yet so we're
gonna go ahead and run this and if it
works out it's starting to load so at
this point it's actually loading over
TFTP server but it does give us a level
of access so the next phase of it would
be get to recompile for the right DTS
for the right device tree that would
give us more access to other pieces of
the actual device
and there we actually got root level
access to the device so we're able to
actually see some of the stuff so oh
gosh
everything's not working now oh don't
tell me this thing's decided to
with me it's not disconnected it's there
tree you should play back in case you
can't read document tree damn it
go hell in a handbasket quick
doesn't it but you see we came up with
root level access from there you can go
ahead and go into proc and proc in and
request a dump of the MT DS and identify
all of the actual partitions that are
actually lined out on the actual chips
any questions we're gonna go over
something else here in a minute
hopefully it goes good too
any questions any concerns any beer
bottles to throw at my head yeah
it's usually set to nothing what it's
going to do in this case it's going to
pull from boot ipq which is going to
pull from the flash memory just to find
in you boot in this particular case
there's a number of different ways you
can actually to break into this some of
the other examples is in the you boot
arguments the environment area called
boot args in boot args you can often at
the end of the line there's a couple
things you do it doesn't work on this
one but works on some of them you can
actually put a one in there which tells
booted in single user mode you can
actually put single in there it varies
or you can put emergency and that will
often give it to boot into that one of
the other things I was going to show
before I managed to disable myself
somehow there we go so just disconnect
and reconnect it here let me show this
cat /proc MTD and we can actually see
partitions on the initial chip there's a
secondary chip that contains some other
file system data that would be where we
often want to get in this case but it's
again it's about how the chipsets are
lined out what's available and actually
building those DTS files to actually put
that into the device tree which would be
one of the next steps so one of the
things I want to do now is just to show
this to you there's other functions that
often show up when you're in these
consoles so let's go ahead and go yeah
my serial ports act do not connect
reboot so we're gonna go ahead and we're
gonna let this let this come back up I
think I keep bumping these wires all I
know exactly why it's doing it this
thing was actually shorty not over here
so we're gonna let this come up and what
we're looking for is an F switch show up
gotta be quick or not be quick I miss it
I must have missed it there we go
that F switch and see if we can screw up
so you can actually see that I see this
a lot and there's a lot of cool stuff
you can do from here because this F
switch will actually put the device in
single user mode if they compiled it to
actually be able to do that the
difference is is now that we're in here
if we go if we try to read any-any we
can actually do and see the actual
devices under proc MTD and you can see
the few that we actually missed down
toward the bottom that are on that other
chipset so we're able to get into this
but now we're in this single user mode
and literally none of the drivers none
of the functions none of the pieces are
actually in place to actually
communicate over Ethernet or communicate
over USB I actually try to enable the
Wi-Fi on this thing and it literally
just kicked my ass and nothing would
work so I got Wi-Fi Ethernet neither one
of those was I able to actually
communicate with or get fully
functioning so then I circled around to
the usb seen this thing come up and it
says USB and it says all this data here
but you still can't address the USB
there's no device in the system even
though it recognized I plug something in
there's no device so one of the methods
that I have is I found out that you have
to actually build the device from
scratch so we're actually able to
shithead sucked I don't work come on an
errand control
get ready wrong there we go so you use
make note and a generally way to make
note works is we have to define some
variables with make note we set this is
just the Linux rewrite rewrite rewrite
we have to define the device when where
we want to put it
and this be switch lets us define two
things which is the major and minor the
major in this particular case that
number require replies to an SD device
one of the block devices that you can
actually configure into a system the one
from what I understand is actually the
sequence of device if I had multiples on
there they would be numbered differently
as I'm setting them up so it'd be eight
one eight two eight three and then and
it would be s DASD bsd C whatever the
case may be and you have to set the
miner to be appropriate that to actually
communicate that so we're gonna go ahead
and we're gonna put that in there one of
the next ones we had to do was check the
device let's make sure we can actually
see it I like to put that in there don't
do that so we actually do run a check on
the device and it comes up and I don't
actually see any errors on it which is
kind of cool the ultimate goal in this
case here is I want to get the firmware
off and I want to get it off
other than pulling it from a flash pull
it from a flash I get a blob so all the
pieces all the parts trying to separate
it out very difficult at this point I
have all the mounted partitions I can DD
all of them off and get the individual
partition structure so the next thing we
want to do and I always do this is
format the device so we're actually
going to format SDA so this will take is
take a second so any questions
no because they could come from
literally anywhere it's kind of amazing
a lot of them come obviously from China
the sources in China are like kind of
iffy so you usually have to screen
through a whole bunch of sales crap a
lot of times to drill down into it some
of the bigger manufacturers have better
resources to actually go to the sites
for of those particular chips you know
Texas Instruments and and things like
that are much easier to track you down
you still run into a lot of cases where
you're dealing with OM devices and you
know you have to sell your firstborn
child to actually get your hands on them
yes sir
yeah I guess if you could determine that
timing cycle you know it's yeah it's I
mean you can still very random because
you don't know where it's gonna be
but once is there a way to identify that
yeah that would be an interesting
project I'd love to see be able to do
that and maybe hook it up to something
where it just restarts a system and
keeps going until it figures out what
that is but again as an example you
never know with power off island off on
off on off on what will happen I've seen
some strange things happen where the
device just says screw you and doesn't
come up anymore we had one where we use
them for training and end up getting
cycled the u-boot and barrett varmint
variables went away so okay so that came
up so at this point one of the things we
can do is we want to go ahead and mount
the device so we have to make a
directory so now we're on a device and
all of the directory structure is only
read-only so the one way around that is
all these devices boot up and put a lot
of stuff in temp temp will be rewritable
on these embedded tech so we're actually
able to create that there the next
option is let's go ahead and second
I'm going to go ahead and we're going to
mount it so we're going to mount the USB
yeah it mount it's mounted okay it goes
through says I don't know what this I
don't know what this is all yeah I know
what this is and it mounts it up the
next thing we want to do is now that
we've done that let's start grabbing
crap off this thing
and since we knew the partitions let me
see you 1210 let's look at these
petitions again so cat /proc slash MTD
so we see these partitions here running
out of time but the interesting thing
when you're dealing with embedded
systems you're actually going to have to
ubi repo systems or - root systems these
are typically the the main root file
system structure you're actually going
to see the reason why you have two of
these and two kernels
it's upgrade that's how you do upgrades
on the system if you look into you boot
there'll be an environment variable it
tells what structure to actually use on
that boot up so what happens is when the
system does an update it receives the
update what it'll do is do DDD to the
one it's offline because they're not
amounted they're not they can unmount
them dd write to those and then what
it'll do is they'll change the
environment variable switch is part of
this it'll boot back up so if the whole
firmware update fails fails back to the
valid structure and that's why they do
that versus you know how many times
power cycle in your house happens to do
upgrade what's going on you'd be killing
devices all over the place it wasn't for
that so the next thing we want to do is
we're going to go ahead and DD partition
MTD MTD 10 over to the device and this
process here works pretty good and now
we can get it off now we have the actual
file system partition running out of
time so I'm not going to show it but
what you would do is you can easily take
that now they have it and actually to
unscrew sure so you can well you can do
you can do been walk you don't even need
to been walk on it cuz it's just gonna
be a squash filesystem so you just
basically unscrew it out and now you got
it blowing out into a writable format
you can go in and create your own user
names passwords everything all into this
file system and then go back and make
squash and then take that image
deedy it right back onto the device
right into that location make sure the
environment variable set to point to
that particular one and you boot it up
or you can be risky like I did last year
when I did the demo when I initially did
that when we're talking about the
embedded multimedia controller I just
wrote the image into both um it's either
gonna work or it's going in the trash so
it's kind of still it's kind of still
running here so one of the things I
wanted to show and I'm gonna be around
tomorrow if anyone wants to see it or
actually do one of these attacks I have
some hew devices or had some hew devices
oh here we are
these is what we used it at RSA sandbox
village and also we use these at the DEF
CON IOT village for hands-on training
which we're going to be back this year
doing some stuff but you can do that
glitching on here the cool thing with
this the manufacturer actually put the
root password hash as an environment
variable so ya you connect into there
and you go you just delete it you know
you do set environment security and -
tick marks it wipes it out you write it
back to the system you reboot it and
your root game over it's a really it's a
really funny example I was hoping to
show that so as you see we kind of
finished up here we're able to actually
write that out out to the actual USB now
that we built the environment very all
environment for it and now we can pull
off all the partitions on that disk and
do analysis and it's much easier than
trying to explode it out from an actual
blob dump er a flash dump and I got one
minute and then they're gonna drag me
out of here
so any questions real quick so we got
through all the press all the demos yes
yeah you can mount this up if you wanted
to no yeah yeah when you pull you pull
the flash ROM off I've never been able
to mount that up straight up not in that
that environment I've never been
successful in doing it I've gone through
and I've tried to do that I have
actually taken him off
I've taken the objects off that way and
was successful in one case to actually
didi the whole flash onto is this was
kind of weird the whole flash it wasn't
an SPI but the whole flash block onto a
USB and cut it to mount up when I
plugged it in and booted and mounted it
up and it actually mounted up as a
filesystem on another device I had but
no I hadn't been successful in that so
that kind of finishes everything up I
hope you enjoyed it we got through all
the demos except for the hue in spite of
the the blind old man glitches so I hope
you enjoyed that I'm going to be here
through tomorrow please talk to me
if you have any questions catch me or
reach out to me online I'm always online
so thank you very much
[Applause]