thank you Olga thank you everybody it is
great and kind of weird to be in a room
with so many people again
um particularly having such a tough act
to follow uh Ben Nemo for those of you
who don't know me I haven't learned yet
not to slap my chest when I'm wearing a
mic so apologies if you just went there
um I am the global lead for threat
intelligence at meta
um formerly from the ocean Community my
background is in exposing influence
operations and now I'm at meta and we
kind of work on all kinds of weird stuff
on the internet which which still hasn't
gone away
and good morning I'm Eric Hutchins I'm a
security engineer investigator on our
influence operations team at Meadow and
like then it's a delight to be here to
see all of you in person and connect
with some old friends and make some new
ones
and to share the stage with so many
other great presenters so thank you to
the Cyber work on uh for inviting us
here
our team on at meta has a responsibility
for a number of online harm types not
only covert influence operations but
also Espionage scams and brigading and
many many other types our responsibility
is to detect disrupt and expose these
operations
now when the team started this work the
first job was obvious just to understand
what was going on and what the Bad
actors were doing so it was really about
analyze break them down and then take
them down and we started off working in
these lots of different areas
um but what we saw increasingly was
there were the more we understood these
threat actors the more there were
commonalities between them there would
be commonalities between different
operations of the same type but there
would also be common analysis between
very very different operations and so
over the last 18 months what we've been
doing is we've come up with a framework
that really allows us to break down and
tabulate analyze those commonalities
across all type all the different types
of operation that we deal with
so it's our pleasure today to present
this framework that we're using in
method to analyze these operations
next chart please
so those who know me might know that I
am a sucker for a good analytical
framework this morning when Jen used
really kicked us off and was talking
about 2007. one I was angry to realize
that was 15 years ago but two that is
coincidentally the time frame which my
colleagues at Lockheed Martin and I were
first generating the ideas around the
intrusion kill chain it was through that
collaboration uh at the time of the Air
Force that sparked the ideas and The
Crucible of the APT era uh for how to
think differently about these compromise
and so one I am the the Twitter handle
kill chain but I'm also on Mastodon so
you can follow me there too where I'm
doing most of my commenting today
uh so after 19 years the infosec world
and getting a chance to work with so
many brilliant people I made the switch
to thinking I'm doing something totally
different in IO but you know the more
things change the more they stay the
same and uh in that fashion as well the
chance to work with so many billion
people many are in the audience today
and here on stage with me as well
thank you um and yeah so so my
background is I come from the open
source World
um my main specialty was always
analyzing influence operations I moved
to meta just under two years ago
um and one of the fascinating things of
being an i o nerd was talking with all
the different colleagues many of whom
are here I'm sorry I can't shout you all
out but I'm a little short-sighted so I
can't actually see you
um but it was talking with the
colleagues and saying wait what your bad
guys do the same thing and this kept on
happening in more and more areas right
Espionage uh fraud scams brigading we
were all seeing the same kind of things
and so about a year and a half ago we
started saying right we should be able
to tabulize tabulate this right break
them down and take him down and so we
started working on a kill chain
um Hutch joined us and you know the guy
who got there first on the Twitter
handle I am not jealous at all
um but we started building up a kill
chain to allow us to to analyze all
these different operations and we and
it's been fascinating to learn from so
many experts in so many different fields
and think we really are all seeing the
same behaviors time and again here so
first off huge thanks to all the experts
here who've actually made this possible
next slide please we also have thanks to
a gentleman who can't be here today
because you've been dead for a thousand
years called William the Conqueror and
we will be illustrating the kill chain
with the help of William the Conqueror
and the Bayer tapestry because I used to
be a medievalist and some things you
just can't quite shake off
next slides
so why are we actually here why are we
talking we all know largely thanks to
Hutch there are many Kill chains out
there there are many ways to understand
and analyze cyber intrusion right it's
kill chain miter attack Diamond model
pyramid of pain same thing's happening
in the i o space there are different
kill chains out there there are
Frameworks like Amit and Rich data there
are kill chains out there for scams and
frauds and account takeovers what we
don't have as Olga said is one chain to
rule them all we don't have one
intellectual framework which is designed
in the first instance to describe
analyze and break down all those
different sorts of operation equally and
so what we've been working on for the
last 18 months is that one chain to bind
them all I will not quote too much
Tolkien because then I'll be going on
forever but it is that idea of having
one kill chain which we can apply
equally to lots of different operations
and therefore compare them speaking the
same language and breaking us all out of
silos
the big part of that challenge that the
operations that we see are very improved
we might align ourselves into particular
teams of focusing on Espionage versus IO
the actors in the course don't adhere to
our terms of the rules right so a great
example here of a blended operation is
the Ghost Rider campaign an operation
that uses both account takeovers and
compromises but once those accounts are
compromised use them to conduct an
influence operation
and so a classic intrusion kill chain
might describe part of the corporation
but might miss some of the aspects of
the other department
s
and taking away compromises all together
and talking about authentic accounts
another aspect that we deal with
significantly and here we can think of
the the operation VV which was an
extremist anti-vaccination group based
in Italy France we took them down last
year and so they coupled two different
Farm types the first was print gaming so
they were coordinating coordinating on
Telegram and and organizing these Mass
online harassments they were also
training people on how to disrupt things
like vaccination scheduling systems
these accounts were also then using
spreading harmful helpless information
and so again we have two different arm
types that we would deal with no
compromises here whatsoever but another
example one in types of adversaries
next slide please
so we design the online operations kill
chain to bridge that Gap we've designed
it for any kind of operation where if
you like there's a human at both ends of
the chain there's an actor who is trying
to achieve an effect and there is some
kind of human being that they are
targeting
um and so we've designed it as widely as
possible right we can use it for we can
use it for Espionage particularly in
sort of the the spear fishing and social
engineering side influence operations
brigading Nigerian scams right the good
old-fashioned email scam we have
designed a kill chain that it would
actually be applicable to that as well
we use it at meta to systematize and
analyze our understanding and compare it
across all the different teams we have
dealing with different arms but because
we both believe in open source that's
where we come from is where our hearts
are we've designed it with the open
source community in mind and as we're
talking through the examples everything
we're quoting today is stuff that has
been reported by open source and it is
amazing and again shout out to everybody
here it's amazing how much stuff you can
actually see through open source and
we're trying to leverage that in the
kill chain to be able to describe all
the different steps that an actor will
go through
it is inspired by by Hutch as we all are
um and it's based on the principle that
fundamentally if you're running an
online operation doesn't matter what
you're planning to do with it some
commonalities are going to apply like
you need to be able to get online if
you're going to be operating on social
media you probably need social media
accounts if you're smart you're probably
going to disguise them
regardless of what you're then planning
to do with them
there are going to be commonalities that
we can see detect share describe deal
with and so that is the basis of this
approach it's looking for those common
analysis and trying to make them into a
single framework
next slide please
[Music]
and so how we use the kill chain is the
same you know mindset that we've always
had first and foremost it's a way to
organize your analysis to break down an
operation into a sequence of phases
identify detection opportunities and
disruption opportunities early as
possible
second we can use it to compare multiple
applications we can take an adversary
look at them over time and see how
they've changed see their TTP shifts
over time we can take two operations of
completely different harm types and find
those commonalities and realize that
they can prioritize investment
disruptions and capabilities because it
covers all of these operations and third
I've been just pointing out the power of
the element we share
looking back on what really took the
intrusion cyber kill chain from just an
idea into this incredible thing Beyond
anybody's imagination was that it was
used as a community to share and I think
that's the really important thing that
we can across our own teams and as we're
advocating across the community be able
to collaborate
and so allow us to present the 10 phases
of the online operations kill shape or
the double kill
uh we'll get into each of the 10 phases
uh momentarily but I also want to point
out the other premise that That Remains
the Same two other premises everything
the same first we want to be left that's
the idea that the earliest that we can
detect and disrupt an operation the more
effective we can have the more friction
we can throw at the adversaries
second as an analyst we want to be
complete as much as possible we want to
identify these uh as many phases of
these of this campaign and bringing that
Defender mindset that anytime these
adversaries are coming online they are
revealing themselves and they are
revealing some of their ttps to the
extent that we can take everything they
reveal and turn it into a countermeasure
we are most effective against them
and a brief comment about you know 10
phases and the the size of it I do want
to point out that the majority of the
online operations that we're dealing
with are meant to be seen they are not
meant to be hidden and so there's a lot
of emphasis on how these accounts and
operations are set up to be seen
and I also point out that I think these
phases are really important to us
because these are the ones in which we
see the adversaries focusing their time
and their ttps and so that's my workflow
next slide please
so we're not going to talk you through
the 10 phases of the kale chain just
describing briefly what you see in each
one all the examples we're going to give
are come from come from uh public
reporting most of it's open source and
if you think at the start we talked
about the common analysis right if you
want to do an online operation you've
got to get online there's only a number
of ways you can do that so the kind of
things that an operation is going to
need they're going to have to start by
acquiring assets that could be getting
hold of an IP address email addresses
phone numbers it could be if they're
going to be operating on social media
social media accounts
we're applying this to a large range of
operations right so they might be
getting hold of crypto wallets we saw a
wonderful Russian operation earlier this
year where they appear to have bought a
whole lot of bean bag chairs for their
operators to slump on and if you think
our lives are hard imagine being a troll
sitting like this for 12 hours a day on
your phone it's almost like being a
teenager again
um so
most of the examples we'll be talking
about are from the i o and and the the
intrusion worlds because those are the
ones we know best those are the ones who
are best documented but always please
bear in mind we have tried to design
this to be as widely applicable as
possible and to prove it we are also
going to apply it to not exactly online
operation but but if we can have the
next slide
uh the Norman conquest of England in the
year 1066. believe it or not this is a
really really good template for using
the online operations kill chain uh here
is stage one for example you can see
this is the Norman Army acquiring all
their assets before they're going on
board to go and try and find England and
invade it so here we have guys with like
suits of armor they've got spheres
they've got helmets and if we can just
click again please
they're even bringing a barrel of wine
because they're French
next slide please
and so now you know what it's like to
work with Ben Nema step two uh phase two
of the kill chain is disguising the
assets how they are making them look
real provide that authenticity aspect of
them you know this is a really important
step as I said because these operations
are meant to be seen
how they are masquerading as different
organizations how they're creating their
fake personas a lot of emphasis on this
my first experience my first case of
working in an i o operation we announced
earlier this year was taking down one in
Brazil it was individuals associated
with the Brazilian military who are
conducting an environmentally themed
information operation the first time
we've encountered that and these
individuals were masquerading as ngos
copying legitimate content from
Greenpeace and other environmental
entities
they were also using Gan faces a classic
TTP the very first TTP that Ben taught
me and the i o space was how to
recognize a game face this is and we see
across across many harm types is a very
common one still today I do want to
shout out since I know they're both here
to people to give thanks to Louise
Alonso for setting up this i o case for
me on the silver platter and Matt
Richard MJR former metamate who's doing
some amazing analysis on detecting the
end faces and we've been following that
with the key interest so thank you both
[Applause]
mixture
and my attempt to be a medievalist so
here's the classic camouflage put on the
armor put on the uniform of an adversary
disguise
you go then absolutely right and in fact
if you think about it you know romance
scams today are still doing this pretend
to be a soldier get money off people uh
next slide please
so the next stage in the kill chain is
gathering information this is the Recon
phase
um probably more familiar term we think
about this as anything the operation is
doing to get information about the
environment that it's working in or
about the target the targets that it's
working on and there's a really good
detailed description of this in the
Department of Justice indictment of the
gru operation from 2016. because this is
an area where
almost by definition lots of different
people are going to have lots of little
nuggets of insights it's a very very
large jigsaw and we all have small
puzzle pieces so this is the kind of
archetype of where it's really important
to be able to share what we're seeing to
put together a bigger picture for
example if you look at the um the gru
indictment they were searching for their
targets on social media they were then
searching for vulnerabilities in the
servers that they were using
um they were doing a whole range of
search activity to try and pinpoint not
just who but how and where and when lots
of different platforms and so getting
information that Recon phase is probably
I would think the most important where
if we can systematize our sharing and
actually talk the same language on what
we're seeing and where that would really
be a benefit to try and understand what
the heck is going on back in 1066 it was
a little bit easier right the challenges
were a bit different so if we can see
the next slide
um if you're trying to invade England
the first Challenge from France is
finding England so what do you do you
want to research the environment you
climb the Mast and you look around this
is what the Normans did back in 1066
full color imagery to prove it next
slide please
step four is the coordination and
planning
in our field in the i o field the first
term I learned is coordinated
inauthentic Behavior key term of art to
describe what we're trying to identify
inauthentic we just described about the
disguise in the assets the coordination
is also key to show the the network that
there exists and so how do these assets
direct and organize themselves
uh in the vbe case we had organization
along telegram they were using uh to to
organize and like a
more public to get as many
uh first while allies to harass uh
individuals but of course that
coordination very much could happen in
private off-platform places where we
might not be able to see that and where
we have to might use our imagination to
see what signals might apply what
signals might we see I always like to
think about what it's like in those
troll Farms of how they're measuring
their effectiveness what's the
management how do they do the
performance assessment to see whose
trolls are doing the best what signals
that might look like when they're
collecting those stats
if we look back a thousand years into
Williams leadership style and his
performance management next chart please
he's a lead from the back with a big
stick yelling at people
just for the real medieval nerds in the
room which is probably me
um if you read the Icelandic sagas he's
not known as William the Conqueror he's
known as villamarin bastardi
which means William the bastard
um looking at that picture you can
probably understand why
next slide please
so next up we're halfway through the
kill chain so don't panic um testing
defenses a b testing right if you're a
sophisticated adversary you're not just
going to throw everything out there and
see what happens you're probably going
to try and work out what's going to
happen so this is where all the a b
testing all the penetration testing
comes into play this is the phase where
an operation is just I'm going to try
this and this see what happens we know
the gru were doing this in 2016 for
example they were testing different
exfiltration
um methods they were testing access to
servers but you might also see it in in
the influence operations world or in the
um in the harassment world right post
the same thing on two different
platforms does it go down on Facebook
and stay up on telegram
um it's anything where you've got that
that slightly trial test phase on the
next slide
again we can see the medieval equivalent
right your whole Army is attacking a
wooden Castle two guys run up with what
look like torches on the end of Spears
try and set fire to the castle testing
the defenses see if it works
next slide please
step 6 is beating detection
so this is a dynamic action that the
adversaries are doing to evade detection
or sort of sort of the visual
recognition of these campaigns as well
as our our pivots to find them so this
thinking that this is not so much
changing the the paint Scheme on an
airplane or changing its tail number but
this is literally flying below the radar
kind of aspect
and
two examples that come to mind here
going back to the VV case uh they were
constantly changing their their sort of
symbology of using VV to using emojis to
using different Unicode characters
Etc and so thinking about if we're just
doing naive searches for keywords we're
going to miss some of that activity you
think you're finding the whole operation
you're missing something that's one
aspect
and credit to Graphica for recording
that that aspect of that operation
another example is geofencing websites
so just in September this year we took
down an announcement operation
russian-based Operation that is making
these doppelganger websites to look like
German news websites hundreds and
hundreds of these domains
pointed out that some of these domains
were geofenced that depending on where
you browse them from you would get
different content again if it can make
you look at something and say is this in
or is this out of the campaign or the
operation that's the idea when we use
the term covert influence operation I
think the covertness is what really is
coming into play here
next chart and here the the live to
fight another day kind of aspect is
simply to swing around and obey the back
side of the castle
next slide please
next up indiscriminate engagement
originally when we were working on this
on this kill chain we just had
engagement as a pillar on its own and it
just just got too big right there's so
many different ways to engage so we
divide this into two we'll talk about
targeted engagement but before that you
get indiscriminate engagement that's the
classic just throw it at the wall and
see if it sticks um a lot of spam
campaigns tend to do this it's generally
the less sophisticated end of the
spectrum but this is anything where
you're throwing out content and just
hoping that somebody will pick up on it
spamouflage that Wonderful Chinese
network of which is like frankly it's a
gift to investigators when you feel you
can't find anything else at all you can
still find spamouflage it's really
relief
um but spamouflage does this a lot right
they'll post stuff on three different
platforms no hashtags no kind of attempt
to engage people and then they use fake
accounts to like make it look like
people are engaging
um operation secondary infection which
is the Russian operation that was
planting forgeries all over the Internet
did the same thing right they'd create a
forgery in Swedish about the Swedish
prime minister they drop it on a forum
for the Pakistan civil service in
Islamabad and they'd leave it there like
how are you expecting people to pick up
on that
um in the case of 1066 if we can see the
next slide look at these archers here
they're not even aiming right this guy
on the left is going to shoot his own
man in the back it's just
don't even point and shoot just just
like pointed or wave it around and then
let go that is the indiscriminate
engagement side very unsophisticated by
contrast
we have the targeted engagement so
coming again from the infostatic
intrusions world this one very much you
know feels familiar to uh to us in terms
of how individuals can be targeted I
think we can think about this also not
only in a one-to-one situation of one
actor or one operation targeting one
individual we can also think of of a
one-to-many so the the Z team that we've
been alluded to earlier would comment on
on German politician Facebook pages and
Twitter pages with their Z iconography
and his Linsky messages it was turned
into a specific audience but it was it
was vast in terms of the audience
let's also think though about the many
to one and that's where the brigading
comes into play that online harassment
again many people to flood vile comments
and things to one individual is a really
important part about Target engagement
I also want to take the opportunity to
remind all of us here in this room that
we are not only just reporters and
researchers of this activity we may well
be a Target sometime I think it's very
important to keep in mind
whether it's a journalist being on the
receiving end of influence campaign
trying to launder sort of that influence
through a legitimate media or as our
friends at Google pointed out a few
years ago of North Korean actors
infiltrating vulnerability research
community
so I think it's very important to
remember we're not just in an ivory
Tower researchers but may well be
targets of this from time to time
next slide these yeah uh and so while
we're at uh step eight of ten of our
kill chain this is the end of the kill
chain for poor King Herald and his
targeted engagement
next slide please
so we're nearly there nine out of ten is
compromising assets for for the Cyber
intrusion part this is when it gets
really serious right
you to take over assets that the target
is using a lot of this will fall into
the cyberspace so if you think about
using malware using social engineering
phishing trying to get hold of
somebody's account credentials and but
you might also see this in the influence
operations space or in brigading right
if you socially engineer somebody to
give you access if the threat actor does
it to get access to somebody else's
social media account or website and then
locks out the original owner changes the
password that is the same kind of thing
compromising assets is getting anything
that an operation does to get the keys
to somebody else's Treasure Chest
um which is an opposite phrase not that
I was planning that for ages because if
we have the next slide
this is one of my favorite images from
the Bayer tapestry how do you surrender
a castle you put the keys on a spear
wave it over the wall and you wait for
the other guy to pick it up compromising
Assets in 1066.
next slide
yeah and then finally we have enabling
persistence this is uh when the when the
adversary first encounters disruption
what do they do to respond to that you
know no good plan can respond uh to uh
it's first encounter with the Enemy this
is the operations first encounter with
us as Defenders
so what do they do to to last the uh the
Russian operation with the German news
websites I mentioned they just keep
cranking these websites out so they're
learning the same Playbook over and over
again and and trying to make us find
them the most durable way to block them
looking back on the on the gru activity
I think there's some really interesting
examples
one is the Persona Alice Donovan which
was being used as an author to publish
uh various uh content and would switch
to Hillary themed content just before
the election
and what happened was once that
operation was revealed they removed the
byline from
so then the content kind of Remains the
Same
but maybe the linkage to connected
that's the idea for how they can do
and of course the other key thing is
moving to different platforms
which next chart would be our view of an
ideal day when we do such a good job of
disrupting it they all fled to telegram
to do it
[Music]
over the next turn
so there you have it the online
operations coaching and some caveats
again coming from the experience of
these types of mindsets and sharing
those types of Frameworks over the years
first and foremost it is modular not all
operations are going to use All Phases
in the same way you're going to have a
mix and match and that's okay
I often use the phrase the quotation all
models are wrong but some are useful and
the idea is to be useful and when it's
not useful we have to change
second and then this is what really
convinced me that this was the right
kind of approach is that these
operations that we're dealing with are
focused at a human to human level we're
not looking so much at the exploits of a
browser or an email server or the
behaviors of a malware implant but
rather on the behaviors of people both
on the targeting side as well as in the
receiving side of an operation
and then as we mentioned from the outset
on our team we deal with a whole variety
of harm types
and while certain Frameworks will be
more precise with given harm types and
within that one domain we see so much
blending and overlaps across our
organization that having the generality
and that commonality has been really
important to identify
opportunities where we can share both
analytical tradecraft as well as build
better detection
please but I used to be a journalist and
the question for a journalist is always
so what
as such said we designed this to be
useful and there's a couple of ways that
we can see this being useful both
internally and externally internally it
allows us to compare lots of different
sorts of operation according to a common
language in a common framework so let's
imagine for example that you're an
organization which has three different
teams focused on Espionage i o and the
scams and frauds if each of those is
using a different framework maybe three
different kill chains or ones using
Mitra attack one's using a kill chain
one's using something else
what happens if threat actors are all
doing the same thing let's say they're
all downloading faces from this person
does not exist which is what I did for
this slide
what are the chances that they're
actually going to sit down and say hey
we're all saying the same thing and
that's disguising assets the second link
out of 10 in the kill chain that's a
really early phase maybe we should be
working together actually to detect this
and disrupt it whereas if they're all
using the same framework it's going to
be much easier to compare notes and say
across all these different violation
types Bad actors are doing the same
thing so maybe we should be getting
ahead of them so that's the internal use
and then next slide please
externally this is a screenshot from one
of my favorite operations ever which is
secondary infection Uh Russian operation
planted fakes all across the internet
tried to interfere in the UK general
election in 2019.
the exposure of secondary infection is
all about sharing there's folks here
from dfr Lab there's Adam ronsley's here
I know the Graphica team are here and
the guys from meta who originally
discovered this damn thing are here the
way secondary infection got exposed
Facebook found 16 accounts they shared
it with dfr lab dfr Lab built it out to
about 200 accounts over 40 different
platforms they shared that with the
platform s Graphica went further found
about two and a half thousand accounts
on 326 different platforms shared
information Reddit found the same stuff
it shared it back this was all about
info sharing I remember being at the
heart of that we had calls with like 20
different teams
every team had its own way of
understanding they had their own
questions and it took a while to work at
hand you're asking the same thing as the
question that a guy got asked yesterday
you're just using completely different
words
if we had had a single framework that we
all recognized to be able to say here's
how we break down this operation here's
how they're creating their single-use
burner accounts it would have been so
much easier
to share information and let everybody
know here's what we're seeing and it
would have made it easier to share back
next slide please
in the name where we started same
mindset identify the complete phases of
the kill chain understand opportunities
to detect and disrupt at the earliest as
possible use it as a framework to
measure your effectiveness of moving
earlier in the kill chain identifying
those commonalities of seeing the end
phases across the entire organization
training the entire team building new
detections to find them and disrupt them
ourselves and then share as a community
provide that context
and uh and the the the means of which to
use the same language to share and put
together those pieces too
it's been an honor thank you very much
and if we have time we'd love to take a
question too
thank you for the uh presentation I was
just curious if there's anywhere we can
read like a white paper on the specific
kill chain yep we're working on a paper
on this
if we can quote you to like the internal
teams to say hey there's interest for
this externally that would make life a
lot
recognizing that this is ultimately uh
an information sharing kill chain intent
I was wondering if you could tell us any
steps that you're taking to socialize
this new kill chain not only amongst
threat intelligence teams but also with
Executives who will be then trying to
put forward the idea of this
boosting the information sharing not
only within the Tactical level but also
at the Strategic level so any any
information on your socialization of
cherry with what was the other audience
that you mentioned so you have how are
you socializing this not only among CTI
teams but also Executives I was
wondering if you could speak
speak well I'll say from historically
that was a crucial aspect for the
intrusion kill chain was that we did at
Lockheed Martin use it to guide the
executive notifications team further
down the kill chain you did a notify
increasing higher executive so from that
standpoint I think from a
decision-making aspect it is very much
in there we're using it one we talked
about prioritizing investment for
detections that's one way in which we're
looking to an organizational level say
this is what we got to focus on because
here's all the things that's going to
detect
and then secondly we do very much
measure how much we share with our
partners and how much we are relying our
detections from leads from our trusted
communities both amongst the big tech
companies but also from researchers open
source and other communities as well so
being able to measure that sharing
Community is another key metric that we
use
um thanks very much for what seems like
a very clear explanation of the model
I'm curious it seems like part of this
isn't simply descriptive but also
anticipatory
um the last example you had was a bunch
of stuff being shown across a number of
different items but I'm curious if
you've had any examples of a tactic or a
movement between stages that you've only
seen for let's say fraud or Espionage
but that has anticipated something that
then gets seen across one of the other
items
so so the way we're thinking about this
is
um initially this this is this is a
post-hoc system right you you have to
have the operation before you can break
it down before you can understand what
it's doing
um but the way we think of it is once
you can identify
what the threat actors are doing in one
area you can actually start to look
ahead and say okay well if they're doing
that here then we want to be building
detection here here and here to get
ahead of them the next time they're
doing that
um a really interesting example is
actually again you know again faces and
shout out to MJR here that I from off
the top of my head late December 20 late
2019 was the first time we saw an
influence operation that was using a lot
of faces created by stylegan too and at
that point those of us who are a
Graphica and dfr Labs spent just days
looking at these these Profile Pics onto
our eyeballs watered but there was no
kind of scale detection going on
but what happened was then the whole
Community started working on this I mean
again shout out to MJR shout out to some
of the early ocean Specialists who are
doing this and working out just by
eyeball what are the ways that you can
identify these and then increasingly
what we'll see is folks are going to
build scale detection which allows you
to do that and so it goes from this
individual detection through to working
out okay that is how we can identify
this and once you can once you can
systematize your identification of it
then you can move on to the to the
anticipatory model and the more we can
share information about that the more we
can do it anywhere in the system right
so Gan faces came into the public eye
through influence operations but again
faces again face it doesn't matter what
the threat actor is going to be doing
with it if you can detect that thing you
can apply it to any of the threat spaces
we're working on
thank you very much thank you
thank you