my name is Dakota I'm with Craig Stamos
group where I'm a China consultant I'm
also a non-resident fellow with the
United Council and I'm the first talk
after lunch so you're awake you're full
and you're paying attention and I'm
going to talk about China's cyber
security policies that bolster its
Talent Pipeline and its capability
development
so I'm going to paint the picture of
when Xi Jinping comes into office in
2013. at this point we know that code
can slow down Iranian centrifuges
Snowden has leaked a bunch of secrets to
the press That's influenced how people
think about this issue and China's own
Security Services have dismantled a
network of U.S informants who are using
website websites to communicate with
their handlers Xi Jinping comes into
office in 2013 and sets cyber security
policy as one of his top priorities he
stands up a leading small group in 2014.
this is promoted to a committee of the
Chinese Communist Party Central
Committee one of about 28 committees at
this level within the organization it
signals that it's a very significant
issue and that the provincial and
Municipal governments and party leaders
should respond to this political demand
signal at the same time in 2016 that
this leading small group is elevated to
a committee he stands up the cyberspace
administration of China this is a
public-facing government bureaucracy
that matches the Chinese Communist Party
Central Committee for cyber security and
informatization both in address and
personnel and in actual offices and so
when we hear about
investigations against tech companies
from the CAC it is actually the same
political body as a committee within the
Chinese Communist party next slide
so they start to focus on Talent
policies in 2015. uh this is after the
committee's been stood up and people
start to focus on this issue and China
has recognized that the United States
has done very well in its cyber power up
until this point owing to a focus on
education so in 2015 China begins a
review of cyber security degree
curriculums this is based on the United
States's National Initiative for cyber
security education in 2016 they begin
building a national cyber security
talent and Innovation base in Wuhan and
then in 2017 they launched a program
that mirrors the United States is
centers of academic excellence and cyber
operations in 2017 they've certified
nine schools as these world-class cyber
security schools and then two years
later they certify four more bringing
that total up to 11. and then in the
same time in 2017 they've stood up uh
this like academic infrastructure for
degree curriculums the ones that are the
best but they need students to attend
these institutions and they need people
to be attracted to the cyber security
field and so this dual-handed approach
to making this happen occurs through
this very impressive you can't go abroad
and you can't do International software
vulnerability competitions anymore next
slide
so Xi Jinping is trying to change this
attitude of
um seeing hackers as flowers in this
field of wheat that are meant to be
found by policy makers and then later
utilize her purposes uh for for a
hacking Target so like if we look at the
apt-40 group and the doj indictment and
the intrusion truth information around
that or we look at the anthem Insurance
hack and its overlap with Southeast
University there are actually students
competing in cyber security competitions
who are later drafted into hacking
operations of the state they are meant
to find software vulnerabilities for use
by the state it's very haphazard it's
not how a mature bureaucracy functions
particularly when considering
intelligence collection and so changing
this attitude is a critical part of this
Talent pipeline in order to do that they
need to get students and people
interested in this job they hold back
their best security researchers from
traveling abroad they launch a program
called the uh let's see infosec
Triathlon it's a joint I jointly
operated I capture the flag program that
runs across China it's run by the
ministry of State Securities 13th Bureau
the China Information Technology
security and evaluation center and the
Ministry of Education and the goal is
specifically to promote people's
interest in pursuing this as a career
field and then in 2018 tianfu cup gets
stood up as kind of this replacement for
you can't go to pone to own but we're
still going to compensate you for these
vulnerabilities and of course charges of
these vulnerabilities being used in
internal hacking campaigns emerge a
couple years later thanks for reporting
from MIT technology review next slide
but that's not to ignore the fact that
they are interested in the software
vulnerabilities that are created by
researchers and then you know released
to the public at these competitions so
in 2017 there's a quote from the head of
chihu 360 where he can pairs software
vulnerabilities to a national resource
on par with things like coal and Timber
and this attitude typifies one of the
two reasons that these security
researchers are not allowed to travel
abroad you can see the same interest in
in harvesting collecting and utilizing
software vulnerabilities and the 2017
robot hacking games which is replication
of darpa's 2016 cyber Grand Challenge to
promote Research into automated software
vulnerability Discovery exploitation and
patching those competitions the robot
hacking games still run in China they've
held at least seven as part of my last
look and they're run by the People's
liberations Army equipment Development
Department so this is the branch of the
military specifically responsible for
procuring and finding capabilities that
are necessary for military operations
and then in 2021 they codify their
interest in tapping into this software
security pipeline by making it a rule
that you have to disclose software
vulnerabilities uh found conducting
research within 48 hours to the ministry
of industry and information technology
and this is a recreation of an operation
that we saw in 2017 thanks to research
at recorded future that showed the
Chinese intelligence Services were
collecting vulnerabilities that were
reported to their National Database
using these vulnerabilities and
operations and then only reporting them
publicly after those operations had been
busted by folks in this room and so that
lends itself to a policy environment
where we get to the 2022 Microsoft
defense report where guess what they're
using a bunch of zero days and they have
them because they've invested in the
capabilities to create them they've
withheld Talent from traveling abroad
and they facilitated an ecosystem within
China That's focused on doing this
research and they've started basically
this Pipeline and they're not allowed it
to go overseas next slide
so all along the way they are creating
physical infrastructure to support uh
the the research that's being conducted
on attacking both regular computer
networks and then operational technology
networks uh and so China builds its
first cyber range in 2010 uh it's
mentioned in a couple places and then I
can't find any record of it and then a
couple years later in 2015 uh one gets
stood up in guayong the national
government likes what it does and what
it's doing they commend it for
supporting uh offensive and defensive
National exercises and it's got a bunch
of uh ICS and operational technology
equipment and soar they do the same
thing and with chengdu's Peak geek
competition in 2019 which is meant to
create NATO's
NATO cyber defense exercise
in Guangdong Province there's pongchang
Labs where they're putting a bunch of
computational power into determine
whether or not reinforcement learning
can improve how cyber operations are run
specifically looking at a track yes and
then state-owned Enterprises also run
cyber ranges in this case Kasich which
does military missile development and
satellite operations has their own cyber
range focused specifically on these
assets next slide
so uh like all good researchers I find
the best stuff before I'm supposed to
come up and talk on stage within about
36 hours of doing so
um so I find this document online it's
the cyber security Talent actual combat
abilities white paper attack and defense
capabilities Edition very cool name very
mundane report it's 85 pages long and a
lot of it is demographic information uh
just like scissogen came up on stage and
talked about an interest in promoting
diversity within the U.S ecosystem the
first graph in this report from China is
a breakdown by gender uh it's 85 percent
male and the remainder is women it's not
great
um next slide
what I like most about this report is
they basically said I was right that the
world-class cyber security schools are
meant to copy the NSA DHS programs for
centers of academic Excellence next
slide
but what I found most interesting about
this report uh and it's 85 Pages which
to be clear I have skimmed okay there is
a translation coming out from the center
of security and information technology
at Georgetown
but the three needs that they found and
most president in these focus groups was
the need for people who are competent
penetration testers people who are good
reverse engineers and people who
specialize in software vulnerability
Discovery and exploitation last slide
but the real point of the report is to
summarize basically what I presented to
you today they have a development model
for their China hacking capabilities
pipeline uh both from a talent
development and a capabilities
development and they call it the four
plus three model and they think that
people who are coming out of this town
pipeline should be competent in the four
abilities and they should demonstrate
them in the three ways that they've
articulated here
this is an issue we're all going to have
to deal with China has gone from finding
flowers in a field of wheat to
cultivating an entire Harvest of people
who go to work in those bureaucracies
and that we all have to deal with thank
you