so uh my name is John Bateman I'm with
the Carnegie Endowment for International
Peace formerly in the U.S intelligence
community in the Pentagon I want to talk
to you today about whether Russia's
cyber operations in Ukraine were
actually militarily effective we already
had a great talk about some of the
technical pieces of these operations but
what has actually been accomplished in
terms of the war as a whole a lot of
people are trying to get after this
question and I have a forthcoming paper
that attempts to Analyze This now I
could spend my entire allotted time
talking about all the caveats about our
limited data the conceptual problems I'm
just going to say that this talk is kind
of a rough first order approximation
that I think can still be useful now if
you were to try to answer this question
how militarily effective has Russia been
in its cyber operations you might want
to break it down further you might want
to make some sub questions out of that
so the first thing that you might do is
you might try to make a one-for-one
comparison between cyber effects
operations or what the US military might
call fires and kinetic operations
envisioning cyber as a weapon system
what have been the comparative effects
of each next slide
uh Nick yeah thanks
um so this chart tries to go through
different categories of Ukrainian
targets of interest to Russia and
Compares some publicly available data
about what we know of the effects of
each so let's just start at the top uh
dog that didn't mark here is that
there's no known information that any
Russian cyber operation has compromised
or destroyed any piece of Ukrainian
military equipment whether Western
provided or otherwise well what about
military Communications what about the
Via snap hack is this still a very
debated event and I think the best that
you could say about the Via sat hack
from Russia's perspective is that it
plausibly contributed to some of the
communication problems that Ukraine had
in the earliest days of the war but
really the true cause of those problems
was very effective jam and electronic
warfare that Russia was doing and Russia
has continued to do that throughout the
war whereas the ViaSat hack was a
one-time event you could continue on
going down the line here
um no known actual takedown of uh
Ukrainian electricity via cyber means
meanwhile right now there are actually
millions of ukrainians that lack power
due to kinetic strikes uh I think this
final row is actually my favorite
because if you want to think about the
general purpose cyber weapons that
Russia has this would be destructive
cyber attacks and we saw a historically
unprecedented Spate of these Microsoft
counted about 50 in the first four
months of the war well during that same
period Russia launched over 3 000
missile strikes and at one point was uh
using uh 20 000 artillery rounds a day
so I think it's very clear that on a
one-to-one basis cyber has been far less
consequential than anything on the
battlefield now you might be saying John
okay but this is very simplistic cyber
weapons are not like kinetic weapons
they can have tailored reversible
effects they can have cascading effects
okay let's look at that next slide
so my argument is that the unique
benefits of cyber really haven't been
leveraged by Russia either
um so Russia really has never had a
strategy in Ukraine maybe other than the
first few weeks of the war for limiting
the actual effects so the idea of having
tailored effects that limit permanent or
collateral damage really is not part of
Russia's strategy
um the same thing about geographic reach
deniability these have really been kind
of beside the point for Russia Russia is
able to reach anywhere it needs within
Ukraine
um and uh deniability is not worth that
much when much of the world thinks of
you as kind of the modern face of evil
now so hiding behind some apt Persona is
kind of pointless a lot of people look
at Cyber operations as cost effective
and that's true to an extent but once
you're in a wartime environment there
are tremendous fixed costs on the
kinetic side and so for example Russia
has huge stalks of ammunition and it can
launch thousands of missiles and
hundreds of thousands of artillery
rounds it actually actually hasn't been
able to scale its cyber effects
operations to anywhere near the same
degree next slide now you might be
saying yourself okay but what about all
the intelligence operations hasn't that
been effective well there's really two
problems with the use of cyber as an
intelligence operation in Wartime uh one
problem is that you need to generate
intelligence That's Unique that can't be
gotten from other sources so if you want
to think about Russia's kinetic strikes
satellite imagery can tell you a lot of
what you need to know in order to Define
that airport find the aim points confirm
its importance really the idea of using
a cyber penetration on that airport to
somehow refine your targeting of that it
doesn't really make a lot of sense
the other thing that is really a
limitation is that Russian institutions
actually need to be limber and objective
and coherent and honest enough to
actually ingest and use any cyber
operations intelligence that they get
and we've seen throughout the world that
uh throughout the war that the Russia
way of war is very very crude very
brutal very violent very indiscriminate
it's not the type of person Precision
Warfare that really benefits from a
cyber intelligence
um so I'm going to hand it over to my
colleague Gavin now who will talk about
a few more pieces of this yeah so uh
next slide and one more first slide
so one of the questions we had is okay
so how would Russia Marshal its cyber
capabilities towards a military end next
slide
let's rewind to 2008. in Moscow there
was a lot of consternation in the
aftermath of the Russo Georgian War
about the fact that Georgia proved so
resilient to cyber and information
operations during the course of that war
and the idea started percolating that we
need to somehow consolidate some of our
uh capacities
in 2012 then Deputy Prime Minister
Dimitri ragozan who oversaw the defense
industrial base raised the idea of a
unified command to shape the information
environment next slide
he beat the drum that social media was a
key element of cyber warfare in this new
era that we find ourselves and
incidentally by early 2015 the general
staff 8th directorate which is in charge
of cryptography and and protecting
information and communication networks
for the military
uh issued a 26 million dollar tender for
Network defense services
next slide
so by the end of 2015 a command called
the information operations troop so the
Vio was stood up and bear in mind as
Gabby outlined before information
operations in the Russian conception
entails both Technical and psychological
um and its initial focus seems to have
been information assurance but
subsequent leaks and then U.S sanctions
later on indicate that they were heavily
involved in cyber opera or psychological
operations as well and in fact the
Russian defense minister in his very
limited public commentary about this new
unit mentioned their remit to match or
exceed
soviet-era counterpropaganda next slide
now recently we've learned a little bit
more about this unit the Vio number one
the gru unit 5477 which ran the info
Ross and other fake Outlets is
subordinate to Vio we learned that its
director was formerly detailed to GRU
unit 26165 otherwise known as fancy
Bearer apt-28 and the deputy director
had been made a an advisor to the
security Council now bear in mind the
Security Council is where some experts
such as Irina borgon and Andre soldotov
assess that major Russian cyber
campaigns are coordinated primarily at
that level
next slide
so what does all this mean the core
competencies of the Vio the information
operations troops uh appear thus far
based on available public information to
be primarily more dedicated to defensive
information information assurance
psychological operations but there's
precious little to indicate that they're
engaged in or have any capability to
perform offensive cyber operations and
what this also conjures is a lot of
questions about the degree to which the
Vio is separate and distinct from the
gru or whether it is merely a
alternative command structure that is
called upon during periods of War as
some of these slides noted they have
exercised with the Russian military in
particular in 2016 in the kafka's
exercises reportedly but we don't really
understand how they operate
independently of Gru capacities and as
you'll also note on the U.S side up
until 2 2016 we kind of conceptualized
cyber command's role as primarily a
defensive one it wasn't until after 2016
there was really a push for offensive
capacity so in a lot of ways Russia
appears to be struggling with the same
uh issues that the United States and
other West Western Nations do in putting
together a command unit that is coherent
enough and has the capacity to Surge
towards military objectives uh when
called upon and that's something as
author Max Smith recently wrote most
countries with sophisticated cyber
capabilities are currently struggling
with and will continue to struggle with
so
um it remains to be seen whether Vio is
a wartime command structure or merely an
amalgam of extant Gru capacity but
that's open-ended question for everyone
here we'd certainly be pleased to talk
with you more about all of these issues
and with that that's our time
foreign