zuzana autumn soda please welcome her
thank you everybody
[Applause]
okay hi everyone
thanks for coming so I'm Susanna I work
for yourself oh okay you already see the
slides so I work in easy as a malware
analyst and today I'd like to talk about
an espionage platform that we discovered
we named it at all but just before I
start I want to ask you a question how
many of you remember 80 comments please
raise your hand okay some of you
remember so for those of you who know
you will know that these comments were
created in the 80s and they were used
subsequently and maybe you will not be
so surprised to learn that I'm too young
to remember these commands I wasn't even
born in the 80s so when I first seen
these strings in some malware sample I
didn't really know what was going on it
didn't really ring a bell but of course
I have some older colleagues who did
recognize these commands and even they
were wondering what are these commands
doing in some malware sample this is not
something you are seeing every day right
so we started to looking to look into it
and we started to analyze this malware
and then we realized that the fact that
something is old doesn't necessarily
mean it cannot be used today or in this
case surprise misused so let's meet at
or so just a start when we started
looking into the after our malware we
were able to trace it back to 2013 so it
has been undercover for quite some time
now we have analyzed several different
versions but the most important one was
released in 2018 when the developers of
atour released some new improvements
some more structured architecture and
really just more professional code and
this version is the fact that one that
is still used nowadays we detected two
last samples in July this year so this
is the one we are going to talk about
today because it called our attention
with its functionality and complexity
and this is what we are going to talk
about so this dog will be first about
the espionage campaign itself we are
going to look into what a tor is spying
on and who is spying on and then of
course we'll talk about how its
implemented because that's interesting
about it and then we will talk about two
notable features that gave a tour its
name and that's the elaborate network
communication using tor and then the AP
commands used for GSM fingerprinting so
let's start with the targets the first
thing we knew about at all is that it's
highly targeted we only had some
twenty-something targets detected and
among these targets there were some
high-profile users in Eastern Europe of
course this is only our telemetry we're
likely only seeing some part of the
picture so that's why we had to look
further and we wanted to know more about
other targets that we do not see so we
analyze the code of this malware and we
were actually able to learn something
more about the intended targets of a
Thor
so I'm going to talk something about how
the platform looks like so that you can
understand how we were going with this
discovery so first thing you need to
know is that this platform consists of a
dispatcher about 32 and 64-bit version
and then it comes with the series of
plugins with some additional
functionality so how do this platform
comes to life is that first dispatcher
is injected into all running processes
and subsequently it loads all the
plugins into these processes and the
thing about ether is that each of these
individual plugins then decides in which
of the processes it will be activated so
for example the plugins that are
responsible for network communication
are only activated in applications that
already communicate over the Internet
this is a clear attempt to hide the
malicious communication within a regular
stream or network traffic so similarly
for example the plug-in responsible for
audio recording is activated in
applications like Skype
or some VoIP applications again these
applications are likely already using
the microphone so this is also saying
for other and other plugins what we are
concerned about here is the plugin that
is responsible for taking screenshots of
individual applications in which it is
activated and then to be able to report
on victims activities so this cling
grabbing plugin is again
not activated in all of the processes
just some applications of interest and
we are going to look further into it you
just need to know that this plug-in
contains a list of some strings which
are then of being looked for in process
names and windows titles and if these
strings are found then this plugin is
activated and is taking screenshots of
these apps so first when you look at the
list of these apps no surprise here what
you'd expect some social networks email
services and maybe some office apps but
when you look further you can find
strings like big lashing it through
sheet or Yandex pasta and all these
strings are actually associated with
some applications that are used in
Russia and they include the two most
popular Russian social networks or a
VoIP app that is provided by Russian
telecom operator so our conclusion here
is that after is specifically searching
for users that are russian-speaking
and this conclusion is further supported
by our telemetry indeed most of the
targets were located in Russia so
further about the targets we are looking
at the strings in the same plugin and we
discovered it was interested in some
other applications like digital
signature creation applications or VPN
application secure email or TrueCrypt so
it seems like a tour is also concerned
about privacy concerned users and
actually when we looked further in the
code we see some other traces of a tour
being interested in through crypt
so this is a part of the code where
author is trying to detect a true crypt
driver
on the compromised computer and then
some control send some control codes to
the driver and when you look at these
control codes these are not standard
codes they are TrueCrypt specific so and
these are used to recover the actual
version of TrueCrypt installed on the
computer and this case say two things
first of all indeed it seems like a Thor
is interested in privacy concerned users
on the other hand we can see something
about the skills of the authors of this
malware because this is not a very usual
technique it's actually pretty rare so
as to recap we have seen the others is
pretty highly targeted it has some
targets in Eastern Europe which I which
are high profile users also it targets
individual russian-speaking privacy
concerned users we are also seeing that
a tour is using quite some interesting
tricks to do this Spang and this is
actually what the next part of the
presentation will be about we are going
to talk about how these platform is
implemented how it works
and what's interesting about it so as I
already mentioned the core of the other
platform is the dispatcher which is a
DLL first loaded and then it works with
the other plugins but there are also
some other notable features and parts of
the platform the inter process
communication between all these
components is done via some shared local
folders meaning that some of the
components write files to these folders
other reads from them and this is how
they can all communicate so these are
the four folders that were used by the
plugins and then now for the plugins
there is a installer plugging that takes
care of the persistence of the whole
platform and there is a set of some say
espionage plugins that collect sensitive
information and store this information
in the upload folder and now you could
imagine that all these information
should be ultimately exfiltrated to a
remote server
but none of these plugins actually
communicate with this server directly
they're all offline
there is another infrastructure full for
talking to the server as you can see
it's a tourist service so it cannot be
done directly so what happens here is
that a file uploader plugin monitors the
upload folder and if there's some new
information some new data it then
prepares the data for exfiltration and
to be able to reach out to the remote
server it uses two other plugins this is
just simplified graphics but basically
it uses a tour client to be able to
resolve the onion domain and of course
to choose the circuit and crypt the data
and then relay the communication so this
is one part of how a tower communicates
with the C&C server but of course
there's there is the other part of the
communication where the server wants to
reach back to the platform and to the
compromised computer and maybe send some
additional instructions or tools that
are to be deployed on the machine so
again it uses the same infrastructure
with Thor but the data is a relay to it
another plug-in which we called command
dispatcher and then this plug-in can
interpret the instructions and if there
are any new files or updates and these
files get stored in these shared folders
and how it works then is that the
dispatcher then can monitor these
folders and if there is some new plugin
then this plug-in will get loaded so
that you can always have your malware
platform up-to-date so this is how it
works I would just like to point out
that none of these plugins on the Left
communicate with the internet directly
they just use these shared folders so
that they can communicate with the
actual plugins that are responsible for
the network communication so if we just
concentrate on these plugins we can see
the communication is split into four
components each of them is implementing
a different layer and these components
communicate with each other these two
create or local servers that the other
components can then connect to and only
some of them are communicating with the
control server directly using FTP
protocol in passive mode I already
mentioned that these plugins are only
activated in applications that already
communicate with the internet which is
one of the tricks that Atari uses
another trick is of course that it uses
audience service protocol for its CNC
server aiming for anonymity and and
traceability so this is how Network
communication works in a tour now let's
look closer at how the individual
plugins are implemented so when you look
at some of the plugins of a tour you can
see that it's not so easy to analyze
them without having some further context
because there are a lot of calls to some
mysterious function that you don't know
anything about but if you have access to
all the other components you can
actually see that this function is
implemented in the dispatcher so the
main part of the platform and it serves
like as a proxy for Windows API
functions for cryptographic functions
etc so instead of calling these
functions directly the plugins will call
the function of the dispatcher and then
use some indices to tell the dispatcher
which functions should be used and then
the dispatcher can then translate the
function to some meaningful code and
only if you have access to all of these
components you are able to tell what
these plugins are actually doing so an
important thing here is that remember
that all these plugins are injected into
the same process as the dispatcher
itself which means that they share the
same address space and that's why it's
possible to call these functions like
that to reference each other's functions
and the reference to this function is
passed to the plugins onload by the
dispatcher and this is how it looks like
when you look at the plugins it's also
dll's
nothing special at the first site they
use these export names that are pretty
common but when you look at this expert
DLL getclass object
the most important one so what it does
here as I said this petrol pass is a
pointer to the most important function
and then the plug-in stores reference to
this function in global variable and
another thing which happens here is that
the plug-in then returns it's bugging ID
and the actual version back to the
dispatcher
so the dispatcher can keep track of all
the plugins that are loaded and if there
is some update it can decide whether
this is a newer version or not so this
is how it looks like all the plugins
have this kind of exported function so
it was the same for all the plugins that
we analyzed and these are all the planes
that we are able to collect to recover
you can see all the IDS and versions and
maybe an interesting thing here is that
the IDS seem to be continuous and you
can see that we probably don't have all
the versions it's not surprising at all
because these after campaign is highly
targeted so probably the attackers use
different sets of plugins per victim so
we didn't see all the victims of course
we don't have all the plugins and
another thing is that it's pretty
complicated to collect these plugins
because they are DLLs but they are
encrypted on disk isometrically and if
you don't have access to the dispatcher
which has the decryption key you can
really recover the plugins so they are
only fully recovered in memory if you
also have the dispatcher so this is just
another complication that the developers
of after created for us so these are
other plugins that we recovered and
we're going to talk about the key logger
and the screen grabber and plugins like
that exciting you've seen quite a lot of
these but let's just focus this one
plug-in that we call device monitor for
some reasons for example it has plug-in
ID number one and this is a prominent
spot right so maybe this is some plug-in
of importance for the other form
again it has a version number 14 which
means that there were quite a few
versions of this plugin
it's the highest number that we have
seen among all the versions so maybe it
means that the developers behind a Thor
boots some effort into developing this
plugin so I not look closer and the most
important reason why we are going to
look into this device monitor plugin is
that it's responsible for the most
important functionality that we have
seen in a tour the GSM fingerprinting
so let's look closer you have already
seen this flight these strings now let's
put some meaning to these strings so as
some of you know these correspond to
commands from so-called haste command
set or 80 comments and they were created
in the 1980s to communicate with modems
or some older phones and to be able to
change connection settings or to dial-up
but later there were other comments
added the set was extended both by some
proprietary commands and some
standardized so there are quite a few 80
commands now and what this actually
means these are the commands that the
actor was using so this command is used
when you want to start a communication
with a device that is connected to the
computer ad for attention and if you
want to use the extended commands as
well then you use this command and the
other commands are used for querying
some data from the device such as the
model number or the device manufacturer
or the software version and then there
are more important or more interesting
commands for example this one which is
requesting the IMEI number from the
device this is a unique identifier of
the device further it requests I am si
number which can identify this device
subscriber or it's the owner of the SIM
card that is put into the device and
also it's asking for the
msisdn number this is a number which is
responsible for mapping
between the identity of the owner and
detail a phone number so this is the
kind of information that a tour is after
let's just quickly recap what I saw does
is that when it detects a device
connected to the computer it starts
sending 80 comments and then by these 80
comments it is able to learn information
about both the device and the subscriber
of the device so the owner of the SIM
card now you may have noticed that I
mentioned the word device quite a few
times but I never said mean when I say
device and this is actually a question
that we were asking what kind of device
is at or looking for is it some old
modems because first the IP commands
were used for communication with modems
so maybe this is the case or is it some
older false these also have support for
80 commands and SIM cards so maybe this
is what authority but then we're
thinking maybe it's also some more
modern devices which also use SIM cards
such as smart cameras smart worksheets
or even modern smartphones so is it
possible that 80 commands are still
supported by these devices and is it
possible that this is what a tour is
after so we were looking and we found
this paper which was published last year
and give us some answer so actually the
80 commands are still supported on
modern smartphones there are thousands
of these commands supported different
for different manufacturers and firmware
but more importantly and more
disturbingly it still poses a security
risk if you are connecting your device
by an USB interface to the computer and
then sending 80 comments you are able to
change the device firmware inject touch
events or quick query some interesting
data from the device so actually this
paper showed us that it's still possible
to communicate with the modern
smartphones just via the 80 commands so
we were really interested in what
this is what adores after so we look at
the code and this is a code for checking
whether a third be sending the eighty
commands to the connected devices and we
can see that it checks the friend the
name of the device and it should have
come substring in the name well if you
connect a smartphone to your computer
usually use a USB port and what you see
in the name is some strings like USB
vite or maybe the name of the smartphone
so unless you are connecting your
smartphone via some serial cable or some
USB to comm adapter or some special set
up probably this is not what usually
happens so come is probably just after
some device is connected to the serial
port or virtual serial port so it seems
like maybe this is not the main focus of
the utters after authors maybe just in
some special configurations so we had to
think of some more explanations and we
actually considered the totally opposite
in explanation maybe this code is just
some residual from some older versions
we have seen that this platform has been
around since 2013 maybe even older so
maybe if you look at the code it only
target the serial port and you can
remember that the modems and some older
phones support 80 commands so maybe it's
just all that it's about but then when
we look at our telemetry we learned that
actually this plugin is still included
in the newest version that was released
in 2018 and we never seen an old version
of this plug-in and also we have seen a
64-bit version of this plugin detected
in this year so to us it seems like the
developers of out otter know what they
are doing it doesn't seem like they are
just releasing 64-bit versions of some
old plugin
so we had to look in some more
explanations and another hypothesis is
that there is actually a device that can
be both connected to a serial port or a
virtual serial port and can answer 280
comments maybe it's some device that the
victims organization or the victim
itself is using maybe we don't know
about this kind of devices but we can
assume that the actors behind a tor
could learn about these devices via some
other techniques of reconnaissance we
don't know but what we can tell is that
if this is true then this is just the
beginning
because there are further 80 comments
that we haven't seen used in a tour as
you can remember the commands that were
used or only used for queer acquiring
some basic information such as device ID
manufacturer subscriber ID and stuff
like that so it seems like some
fingerprinting of these connected
devices but when you look at all the
other commands that are supported in all
the different devices there are
thousands of under specific 80 comments
and if the actors behind author learn
about what kind of device is connected
to the computer of the victim then they
can create other customized plugins and
push them back to the victims computer
we have seen that there are mechanisms
in place so that these plugins can be
downloaded and used and this can be
actually used as a base for further data
theft so this was about the GSM
fingerprinting now let's wrap it all up
we were just talking about an espionage
platform that we called a tour we have
seen that this malware is targeting both
high profile targets in Eastern Europe
and privacy concerned individual
russian-speaking users now we don't know
who is behind at all but what we can say
is that it was professionally written it
had some unusual functionality and
there must have been invested substance
substantial resources into developing
this kind of malware another thing as
usual with a PT's we don't have all the
pieces of the puzzle so we don't know
everything but what we can tell from
what we see is that at or malware is
worth further tracking and it could be
interesting to collect the other
remaining planes and to see what else it
has as its tricks so this was for my
presentation today I would like to know
that this was a last minute talk so if
you're interested in more details there
won't be a paper in the conference
proceedings but we are going to publish
a comprehensive white paper with more
details so stay tuned and that's it
thanks for your attention there are any
questions I will be happy to answer them
[Applause]