it's my pleasure to introduce young Sean
and Lou Jean sorry Luigi no come Astra
from have asked her going to talk to us
about a relatively new malware family
called reach spoof hello everybody
before we start I'd like to say feel
free to take as much pictures as
possible
as you want but please make sure we both
look slim and nice today
oh sorry first I'd like to address
myself my name is Elam are working in
our software a small resistant me and I
work in field of security for over 10
years and my colleague Luigi you know
chemistry and I work for a bust as a
male model researcher and I'm still
students at the CTO and in Prague and we
had a colleague that helped with us with
our research it's autostrada is amol
researcher - he's working for a stand
yeah there's also thank you so the race
pool this is the malware loader we
discover last year and we'd like to
share with you as much information as
possible so please join us in spoofing
in the rate with the rate spoof so what
we are going to speak about today at
first we will show you the origin of
infection when we discover a smaller
what happened during a time trap and we
look on the infection change will go in
the deep with each of the stages you'll
start with the stage one which is a
Microsoft Word then stage two which is
visual basic script stage three cap file
and then two more stages four or five
which are both execute files one is a
drop bot which communicate with C&C
server and the last one is a door odor
at the beginning of this year we
released a blog post for the detail
about a rich poof and few days later we
discovered something early change so we
will look what happened after we
released our blog post and of course at
the end your projects of summary and
maybe they're gonna be time for
questions and hope maybe some answers
it's not like starboard to original
fiction this was the right interesting
for each modern family so there is proof
we discovered his mother older and all
this 2018 the first versions was obvious
that the first version were probably the
death files homeland or test files
because there was no application at all
it was really easy readable each thing
was invisible etc before January 2019
there was like an average one new
version per month
they started in confiscation they
starting some more stuff doing that but
the biggest boom was in the January till
the end of February 2019 the public
gardens changed almost daily updates
with smaller or bigger changes this
Marvel or is more likely malicious
loader communicate with us
IP range only with its CNC server so we
know this is targeted to us after all
data bias we were able to discover the
samples were share through the Skype
insta messages and emails go it's really
target attack
so let's look on the process tree I'll
just in Rauscher tell you what's going
on during the whole attack it's all
stars we do merge with a spam email
which contains the malicious windows
word document this work has a dropper an
executor for the visual basic scripts it
changed I'm slightly or more but
basically the BBS then drop the cup file
unpack up file and run the drop bot with
just a simple file at the beginning
which communicate with the C&C server
has ability to download some additional
stuff so I started with the Microsoft
Word this Microsoft or actually it's
pretty common these days the malware is
spread to spam emails so it's not so
surprised so same way here they usually
come on social engineer it was really
stupid just okay
please run amok arose and
we'll see something girls and in war as
a doper and runner for the VBS what was
interesting when Numa co-star running
the first thing for the date it changed
the value of show hidden tech to true
and the emergency exit map text appear
to victim it sure this is some
similarity maybe you know for example
the gun crap was shared with the
Microsoft Word documents which also try
to use the emergency exit map but
although I will reverse a lot of
Microsoft words related to gun crap we
were not able to find any relation
between the read spoof and can crop and
in this case the document contained the
visual basic script we just embedded a
64 bit string and code it in hex
he was just encoded no it was just
decoded drop and run through we script
dot exe during our investigation we
discover many a probably fake loose
because there are some really messy for
example in the Microsoft where they use
the French Wars for the error but it
really seems like only the fake loose so
let's move to do with your basic script
what is interesting actually each
version even the diff files test files
where digitally sign is the same for the
VBS and for all next stages
everything was signed with the new
certificates and they were paying
attention you don't know why they spied
provide a lot of time lot of money to
sign everything even it was just a
diphthong but once we found something
very interesting
this digital signature if you look on
the email it contains some random
Russian no not random but the Russian
name which is brought against a clue
it's I to at email a true but what's
more interesting if you check the name
spices say ok why they are using this 9
and we probably get a clue we take the
author's play a lot of this game do you
know it yeah I see someone guys know it
sure is really good game or if they
don't play it
they maybe write a lot from Frank
Herbert and maybe they hope that he who
controls the spice control the universe
but fortunately did not happen yet so we
hope it won't change well and I started
the digital signatures actually what was
interesting to issuer in this case were
just two companies was the Komodo and
sexy go reaching the reason why they are
using these two companies because
certificates are not really pricey and
it took them a long time even if we
report the certificate using malicious
stuff to revoke that so I guess that
occurs a lot of time to work this
digital signature with a bit before it's
revoke Baidu sure the main purpose of
the visual basic script in this attack
is to drop an expand cap file so if
there is just a simple function you
start reading itself from define offset
and to the core it decode the cap file
which is then dropped into the into the
target computer and through the built-in
tool which is expanded to xe8
unpack with a simple parameter and it
unpack this cup file into the execute
file they use the random names but in
each case is they add the number of
processor number into the name and of
course when the excel file is dropped
the Visual Basic executed at first
what's happened there will be a script
check if you use race admin it's not my
party I was bit surprised it's so easy
to check if the users add line you can
just try to read this register key it's
accessible only for admin so there was
it was so easy for them to define if you
use this up man and they say ok user is
admin that first
cool well they call next function say
the current name into the server
variables and then they change the day
to the first of the January 2100 or nine
in the later versions it was 2199 this
probably too broke some sand boxes and
stuff like that why it's not really
something what drive work good but let's
say and then they spawn the server
command lines
and through that they run the drop both
and after it they just change the date
back to so nothing is going on I don't
think this is really something which can
really break some behaviors actions but
maybe they hope it will but in case the
user is not admin they try to use
something else
so again spawn of several common lines
with your arguments and it spawned
scheduled tasks DXE with the parameter
which say after one minute run the
microscope windows don't object helper
which is in fact the drop bot this is
the way how they can break some again to
be here on the behavior detection or the
chain the whole chain they can break
sometimes and we also find in few
versions they try to use the simple link
file which was dropped and then executed
to run to drop both they were a tested
some stuff like that to mate we probably
stay under the radar
what is not working much so the cup file
you mention it many times
the cup was in effect use in each of the
versions but with the cap we have like
two hypotheses why they are using the
cap file it may be anti behavior like
maybe against the behavior detection
because when you are of the BBS
we should Rob executable file you do
something let's B color right if we drop
the zip file maybe but the benefit of
cap file it's really easy to expand it
with the built-in tools in Windows and
now I would like to ask Lou you to
please yeah thank you
so as my colleague said the vbscript
dropped the ball as you can see on the
slide here there is a really simple call
graph of sorry graph that the it's
describing the functionality of the drug
bought it first connect to the CNC
servers the since is the under sample
all the samples that we analyzed all IP
addresses of the CNC server was
hard-coded on the sample and starts to
communicate there there is a den
handshake with the CNC server this
handshake it's it's a good really simple
after the handshake it start it start
the communication where encrypted there
is a client hello to the C&C server just
the pink if CNC server is alive then
infected bought sends the some ID to the
C&C server and this ID is a MAC address
of the infected bot and this MAC address
is then hashed by md5 and sure CNC
server can respond with the come a bit
okay or can respond with the more
powerful commands it that means that it
can download all files gather piece
informations start processes or
self-destruct it's self insert it
self-destruct itself or delete the
specific file it has gone fencing based
IP addresses that means that it worked
just on American IP ranges so as I said
we analyzed a lot of samples and we saw
lot of modifications so I will divide it
and two main modification that will the
the difference between this modification
is the communication protocol so then we
see
a commercial application in some version
were not and some that there was
discussion then some commands were
scrapped so it there wasn't there and
this is a timeline where I will tell you
about the main modification really the
malware out all the modificated of
modification he it the mottos the tried
a lot of lot of stuff and so but let's
say that this was the daily
modifications so this is a main timeline
and we first we saw January 15 there as
you can see there was a application
placeholders but it for me it doesn't
make sense you know you see modification
placeholders there there but the the
command which is run in this situation
is is not obfuscated so then in this
this version they use the communication
protocol version one about the
communication protocol versions I will
describe it later so then we saw January
17 as you can see here there is a very
simple application the string
obfuscation it Delphis cade the the
bytes with the EXR then he had as a
service it means that the mouth the
vbscript can actually with the right
parameters can execute the bot as a
service so so yeah and then he had the
communication protocol version 2
then on 22 January he he added the
scheduled tasks so as a my colleague
said in the first case he had on the
vbscript
and this case is its it he they it add
to the eggs of file and yeah it can
start with the scheduled tasks if the
Maurer doesn't have admitting privileges
it will run as a scheduled task and and
so on
so in 23 January the obfuscation were
scrapped as you can see here there is a
clear string clear commands you can see
and they in this version they just use
few commands so I think it was four
commands there instead of eight and they
return again to the communication
protocol version one now I'm going to
I'm going to tell you about the
difference between communication
protocol version one and two so in
communication protocol version one it's
it was very simple they communicate over
TCP socket they were a handshake
the handshake was quite simple - so the
the client and the server they generate
the random bytes and then send to each
other generated the random bytes and
generated the random bytes their doctor
and they hashed by shot - and this how
it was created the key about
initialization vector after after the
key the disk is hashed by md5 and that's
how they created a suggestion vector so
this was the parameter for AAC CBC for
secure communication so from now the
hello were
and as I said clients client sense to
the C&C server the the commands ID that
contained the MAC address dashed by md5
now communication protocol over root 2
so it communicates over HTTP protocol in
this case they avoids a handshake so it
it's all samples that we analyzed the
the they had just this hard-coded string
from this hard-coded string it's hashed
by a two and created the key and about
any session vector they're all really
simple there we'll just sort two
constant bytes in the sample and they
say is used a a CCBC for secure
communication the the bots and get
requests to the census server so as you
can see there is a content md5 where the
message or outside the command it's
encrypted by AAC and then decode encoded
by base64 but there was still one thing
that in all bots that we saw there used
communication protocol version 2 but
there will still present communication
protocol version 1 he is still present
therefore case when the HTTP proxy is
used in the infected
PC so now the bot which you saw it was
very simple it downloads the other stage
which is the downloader these downloader
starts to any initiate the interim
protocol it's a protocol just to enter
authenticate with the C&C server it
first so it starts first to that they
it was the security t2 dll then it finds
out the security function table
structure is a dispatch table that
contains the pointer to the functions
related to the entire API functions yes
in this case two it has IP address
hard-coded in all sample in that all
centers that we analyzed all hard call
it a paralysis
then after success initiate interim
protocol it starts communicate through
the credit channel and and the ball
received from the C&C server the the
payload and the payload were executed
wirelessly so it worked it was quite
let's say interesting in some cases that
actually it's created the pipe and he
wrote the all the receive data from C&C
server he wrote to the pipe and from the
pipe he created the process and that
process is a finite payload now my
colleague will tell you about what
happened when we published our block
eulogy so we get all these data and we
cite of course to publish visitor to
share our information but raise
awareness to everyone he was a bit
happened at the 16 February we published
a blog post was our surprise that few
days later the 21st of February we
receive completely new version alexei
was not completely new version because
first step first time the game starts we
do some email warrior cumin VBS cup file
it was the same
what was our surprise that from the cup
file as usual was not unpack the exit
Google file
but the VBS script it was wrong through
scheduled tasks they just get rid of
some functionalities Sara
well sure that those guys they really
care was going in the world of the
security because the traction was really
fast
I was interesting you expanded VBS
actually not all the functionality of
the drop boat and the downloader at
first is get information about the
targeted computer so yeah computer and
I'm processing defier username HP's
information to the md5 get the first
four bytes and use it with the computer
name as a parameter for communication of
the C&C server as identifiers the CNC
several others was again hard-coded they
didn't really make much try to do you
some DG or something like that really
hard code it was probably written
because they changed it a lot etc this
VBS crepe also had a function to delete
everything or wipe out everything from
the target computer just just stay safe
a bit or delete the samples from
computer and the second function
it was the same function as was before
able to do the unloader
it was the download and run file so it
just received from the C&C server the
two part to command download with the
URL and the file name and just to the
simple get you don't load the file save
the file into the time and run it this
show has the guys behind they are really
skilled with VBS because they were able
to rewrite the function of the P files
into the VBS really fast and they really
react was going on the security so let
me do summarize or talk a bit i was the
low activity in 2018 and when we
discovered his mother and activity has
sped up in january 2000 ID till the end
of february was like we say it was from
monthly updates to daily updates
what is it Earl interesting that after
we were able to block it
even with the new VBS file since then
there is no activity behind the read
spoof maybe we were able to piss them
off enough to stop using this malicious
payload loader or they are working on
something more interesting or they are
stay under the radar but we open up
because we are able to track them since
early do deaf files till the production
version 3 poof usually five stages mono
loader for droppers one with the boot
functionality and as I mention is what's
very interesting that every single file
even the Deaf files and theft's tests
files were digitally signed so you can
see those guys behind they rely spent a
lot of time they invest some money into
it so that's why we are bit aware that
we don't see nothing these days also the
communication protocol was extended in
me to generic which is not so come on
and especially when they keep default by
communication protocol one in some
special cases like the HTTP proxy is on
the target computer and again we we
speak a lot on conferences that sharing
is caring but sometimes we can see that
Marvin altars are really watching was
going on they checking the blog post
probably the checking maybe the Twitter
because they can react really fast when
the security companies release this
information so thank you very much first
time and now I hope you have some