okay wait ladies and gentlemen we
continue in the afternoon with
boris tomasz
on the acceptable use of internet
and categorizing the web at scale thank
you
yeah hey everyone thank you very much
for attending our talk acceptable use of
the internet categorizing the valetsky
my name is tameshwaresh and i'm a data
scientist with surface ai
first let's go through the agenda of the
talk it will have me
four main components first we will go
through the motivation
why we are doing this project uh within
sofa ci
in a nutshell we think that the
security profile of our organization is
heavily dependent of the content
their employees browse so we find it
really important to understand that
content to best of our capabilities
to do this we propose a machine learning
model for url classification for
downstream
systems so this will be a defensive
application of emma
we we propose to use amazon to do this
because the internet is huge and highly
volatile so
it will be a invisible task for a human
to to do
also even though
the
url is not tightly
related to the content the page is
serving it still holds valuable signal
and it's a very lightweight artifact
that can be used more easily than a html
or a portable executable file
then we will go through the model that
we are proposing to solve this problem
and we will go through the architecture
of the model and the intuition why we
propose to use this and finally we will
go through the is that
in terms of accuracy and coverage
and finally we will hand inspect some of
the samples
let's look at the problem
more closely
let's say i'm a sys admin at my
organization and i go in monday
and i see
three urls in the telemetry of my
organization so i essentially realized
that my colleagues looked up so on the
x-axis we have the urs that my
colleagues looked up and y-axis we have
my happiness level about those urs
so when i see the first url it's a
security playbook pdf from microsoft.com
so that's like fantastic kudos to my
colleague
i'm over the top happy about that the
second one is
less known domain it's called
tricks for winning the lottery pdf like
i'm not that happy like i guess i'm not
judging
but whatever and finally i can see in
the logs that someone looked at pirate
bay and downloading uh or trying to
download the pdf
now
parity is a
torrent site so that's intellectual
theft at best or maybe that's not even a
pdf so that's how i get run somewhere
so it's just me but what will i do i
will just simply bloat that url in my
firewall or my utm
now next day i go in again
i see the winning the lottery pdf so
it might not work uh but more
importantly
i can see that
same pdf is still being still being
downloaded from piratebay except it's
from a slightly different url
so this is an issue
so that's it i had it i blocked the
whole domain the pirate bay
next day i go in again and i can see
that it is being downloaded from a
different torrent site so it looks like
with a
bit of a cat and mouse game on our hands
and the question that we are trying to
answer is that
is this a game that we can win or is
this a game that we should be playing at
all
so let's do one more exercise um
here we have a plot which says bin
domains by lookup count on the x-axis
and on the y-axis we have lookups
covered in telemetry so let's unfold
what this means
this is a bar plot it has bars so if we
look at the very first bar it's produced
by taking a sample from our customer
telemetry
uh taking all the url all the lookups
from the customer telemetry grouping the
lookups by the domain and taking the
first
100 domain by this
kind of popularity so if we sum up other
lookups from the top 100 most popular
domains
and if i have some kind of information
about those domains it will and
and i block it in the utm allowance
block list in the utm then i'm it's
really good news i covered a lot really
a lot of of the telemetry of my customer
base
so if i do this exercise for the next
next
bin or next bar
for the same amount of work hand
labeling 100
domains or urls i get significantly
lower return of investment and we can
see there is an exponential decay so at
one point i will just simply
run out of time or permissions i will
just give this process up because it's
simply not worth it to
unlabel stuff
so let's say i i give up and labeling or
blocking stuff in my firewall after the
first i believe these are for
40 bars so that's 4 000 domains most
popular domains
is that
yeah
and the question is will i be surprised
the next day i i go into the office will
i see any other funky uh passing this
kind of block list like this approach
now the answer to that is that probably
yes
because if i take the rest of the
telemetry and sum it up as the last
column there it turns out that the long
tail of the url lookup distribution is
actually really long
so it's simply infeasible to take the
most popular domains and and just assign
some kind of label or knowledge to them
how does it translate to our actual
coverage this exercise um
this will be a plot that you will be
seeing
more after this but on the x-axis it has
the time so for every day this plot
represents for every day how many unique
urs were looked at by our customers
for for this 100k sample
and the solid range color means that
that we had some kind of information
about those urls and the dashed one
means that we we have no clue what the
customers are browsing which is clearly
not good so that's a blind spot
so this is this is not as not
necessarily one to one map to the
top and domains but it's not a bad
strategy after all
so
what do we mean by labels uh internally
with suppose we track 80 labels um i
track i i show nine examples of that
eight labels here
these labels or urls belonging to these
classes could have impact on the
organization along multiple dimensions
or aspects so there is one important
which is the security aspect so there
are
trusted at this sites like microsoft.com
or search engines google
or there is stack overflow which is
something that
probably you are not going to get
infected from or less likely
and to the bit right of that there are
the social networking sites you can
argue how risky it is but it's more
likely that you will get infected from a
facebook link or a dropbox link
than uh
then from a trusted update site and then
on the far right we have the
extreme categories which is pornography
or drugs so
those are just simply infested with
malicious content so you might want to
pay
more attention to those urs
and then there is the other aspect of
all this which is called which is we
call the
negative impact of productivity or
negative legal
impact or ethical impact
so there are these law sites which have
no product negative productive impact
because we need to need those to do our
everyday job but then it's up to an
organization whether it wants to allow
its employees to browse social network
sites
during workouts or dating sites and for
sure no company wants to allow employees
to browse pornography or or buying
village drugs during work hours so
this is sort of the motivation but
why we are tracking these classes
so just to recap the motivation part
what we are
trying to do is we want to use our
machine learning in contrast to the
standard approach which is having
analysts hand labeling a few sites that
cover a good chunk of the telemetry but
not all because it leaves a lot of
unknown data
this this manual labeling approach we
want to replace it because it's really
slow it's expensive
manual work doesn't scale at all and we
want to use a ml instead of that
specifically to provide extra labels for
our long tear that manual labelers
couldn't
cover
this project
has additional like side effects but it
reduces time for about new sites i i
mean whenever you deploy the model it
will be instantly there
so you don't have to wait for the whole
pipeline to get to the analysts and
it could also highlight conflicting
labels but
that's for another day
generally if you use emma you would want
to split your data into two or three
groups
the first group being the training data
that will be used to
train your machine learning model
and the other
two or three is the test of validation
data where you will evaluate your model
how well
it was trained
we use the so-called time split
with which we want to emulate the
deployment scenario meaning that we
pick a point in time which is roughly
end of january for this scenario
and we take everything before that time
as training data and everything after
that has test data
we use 200 million urs is our training
data
and one
one detail to highlight is that there
are no duplications between the training
and test data which will be still a
realistic scenario because people still
can look up urls from the past but we
are not really interested in
how well the model can generalize
between url caps but
sorry not interested how well it can
memorize but we are interested how well
it can generalize for new caps
but domain revisions are allowed but not
not for urs
so
now that we have our data and our labels
the only thing we need is our model
uh we propose to use a 1d convolutional
neural network
for this task
there is the on the left we have the
architecture of the model it has
fundamentally three main blocks one is
the character embedding then the feature
detection part
and finally the classification so just a
few quick words about it
the input to the model is a url as a
string so
it needs to be the ml operates over
numbers not on strings
so we need to convert that in strings
into numeric representation
we choose a 1d
character level embedding to do this um
it's a it's an existing concept there
are many ways to do this we choose to go
with that so what that does it takes
every character of the input url and it
maps it to a numeric vector
every every character to a about numeric
vector in a way that
characters that occur in a replaceable
fashion so like
numbers are like in a url so it's not
necessarily changing the number it's not
necessarily changing the meaning of the
url
and then then those
similar characters similar characters
with similar rows would be mapped to
similar numeric representations so
that's probably enough about the input
part
but this this makes it
makes this more robust to obfuscation
attempts if you just want to type more
and more numbers at the end of the url
and and then the most interesting part
of the key part of the model is the
feature detection part which consists of
1d convolutional layers
what convolutional layer does on a high
level it operates a sliding window on
top of input
strings are fundamentally one
dimensional so there is an example on
the right for that
we have the casino bethlehem.net
as a input url
it is converted into its numeric
representation by the embedding layer
and then we set a
we pick a convolutional window that we
slide over this string so essentially if
we set out the key equals three so a
three line convolutional window it from
the beginning with the step size when it
will slide over
the url so it will capture the numeric
representation of class rc c and so on
so essentially it will capture all the
three length substrings of the url
now
we do this with
window lines two three four five so for
example window length four it will
capture
the every four length substring of the
url
but with that rank three it will capture
bat and with length four it will also
capture game so these are important
because with the human eye these are the
very birds or subwords that drive the
human eye that's saying hey this is a
gambling site so among the other
substrings these will be captured too
and all these features will be fed into
the classification layer
and it will assign baits to these
specific features in a way so it
it gets the best possible probability or
accuracy at the end
so how to evaluate the model as such um
there are many ways to do that i'm
showing one this is called rap curve
uh recur shows a trade-off between
between the first positive rate and the
true positive rate
this plot has three lines on it
three curves
so for example if we look at
the orange line
there is a dot at 10 to the minus third
false positive rate
what it means that for every one in a
thousand urs that are not in the
healthcare side we will make a mistake
and say it's a
healthcare
healthcare site
which is not good but it is a price that
we have to pay that we get a decent true
positive rate uh roughly on
roughly on the 90 percent mark
which is a pretty good result
uh we are doing well for example with
the pornograph pornography
category as well so these urls turns out
they have current pornography something
that are really explicit even in the url
but but but they will be hosting and of
course there are more generic categories
like personal cloud apps which is
hard to
hard to decide what they are about but
it's still a okay result
but how does this uh translate into into
the actual deployment so we had this uh
plot before
with the covered and uncovered data so
first let's see how the tracker
translates to the
labeled part
so it turns out if we apply our model
uh for each
each label for
each labeled part we get the
corresponding model predictions but we
can evaluate our model
the solid blue is the urls that we got
correctly and the libraries that we got
incorrectly which is
this this is our right reset
but this is not where the that we would
expect this model to gain value from
because this is something that we
already knew
so let's see how we do on the
on the unknown part
and it turns out we can
roughly have
the amount of
unknown data that we had in our
telemetry before just by deploying this
model
and it picking up specific
subwords
looking at the ratio with which the
model got the urs right
it kind of gives hope that the pink one
the additional again from this model
will be
also
uh could a bit good good accuracy even
though it's a harder problem
these deep learning models are
fundamentally black box so as of now we
don't really know why they make the
decisions that they make
there are multiple tools to
post-op models
that
are used after the model training to
explain the first modals these decision
decisions
one is called lime so we are showing
results here from uh from a positive
mode called lime
um
on this plot we have two set of urls one
is the
[Music]
high scoring previously unknown examples
so that's that's the net gain from this
model and then the high scoring missed
labels which is the failure mode of this
model
first let's go with the high scoring
unknown examples so
the first url is movie 7.8
series and it was predicted by the model
to be an intellectual piracy site
now with lime if we feed this url into
lime with our model and its predictions
what lime
high level does
it splits the input into tokens
permutes the tokens and it assigns
probabilities for
to each token like how
how much the contribution of that
specific token is to a specific class so
the deeper the color is on on that uh
right picture
uh the tokens
contribution to the class intellectual
paradise is higher so
the highest contribution is that movie
samantha cam which is i would say it's a
fair fair
token to pick up as a
marker of the intellectual piracy side
also the series one is highlighted so
it seems like this convolutional concept
is working out and then we have the
democratic strategy.org which is likely
to be politics and finally the
pokerstars.tm which is obviously a
gambling site
and
there we have the other set where where
we made the mistakes with the mother so
the first url is for solarknives.net
so on the right we can see that the
model looked at the burn knives and
immediately said it was a weapons site
whereas in in reality it was food and
dining so i would say this is a fair
mistake to make
then we have the word cancer day
which was uh predicted to be ngos
in truth it was a healthcare site so
this should have been caught sometimes
it it just not capturing the proper uh
subwords
and finally this is the
mode where you would expect a url based
mode and not perform so well is the
study.com where the url has not no
no
no signal whatsoever but it will host so
unless you knew that study.com was a
hosting site you you stood no chance
with this modal predict that it was a
hosting site
so that would probably explain why we
still have uncovered data in our
telemetry even after
uh utilizing the moda but even with that
we we get
we get nice looking urs extra coverage
yeah
and with that
thank you for your attention and please
if you have questions asked
[Applause]
do we have any
yep so i was thinking what is the next
step
to fine-tune this
what
how would you be able to fine-tune
because you are focusing now only on the
urls
do you want to focus or or add more
content based on the
words pictures on the
web pages or so the main next step is
that
this system access every filter so
obviously there
are methods that we won't try want to
try like different models but i would
say if we are looking at that as a
system as a whole the next step would be
implementing a model that takes in html
from the url then that would provide
more so that's the trade-off so
downloading and scanning on the html and
predicting on the html it's way more
pricey
but
uh using this model as a pre-filter then
feeding that to an html
that's the next step for this project
thank you
so thank you for the presentation i
would like to ask a quite practical
question because
i'm working with content filtering
softwares and testing it and so on and
what i see so far that even with this
kind of ai introduction
it is still not real still not near how
the
human people
trying to interpret the page so i would
like to ask
your opinion when we will get to the
point that instead of classifying
any domain saying this is a
nature side this is a gambling site
instead of that the classification
software downloads the page
interprets the text with machine
learning
interprets the pictures
audio files video files on the page and
it actually you can say that for example
this download this part of the the
of the parent-based site is a free
textbook therefore you can download it
and it's it's a completely fine but for
what is content it says it's highly uh
inoperate therefore it is classified as
a torrent side so you are not allowed to
open this url in your browser when you
are working in a corporate environment
thank you
so i would say
machine learning is there but there are
more aspects to machine learning than
just the model
so
there are two key other aspects so one
is the data that you use to classify
so my answer would be first that if you
think as an model as a compiler and the
data as the code the compiler executes
then then we need better code we need
better data
so that's one part and the other part is
that
the hardware is not there
yet so there are models that are pretty
good at uh
at uh at classifying all these things
that you asked
it's just pricey to get the data for it
and to run it for everything but i would
say the argo is there
and i think
maybe 10 years
but it's not really for me to say that's
just my personal i guess
uh
i have a simple practical question why
three is the magic number because i
realized that in another product they
also
took every three consecutive characters
and and build their model based on that
why not four characters no uh we
we have uh actually four four of those
layers so we take every two three four
and five substrings
and by that it's empirically so someone
tried six and someone tried one and we
arrived at the solution okay this this
is where it made sense
but no
practical reasoning just we tried it all
okay that seems to be it thomas again
thank you very much
[Applause]
you