guys
hello everybody good morning we are ilya
and alex from cyclode
and in the next 45 minutes we will
present our research
on github actions internals
including how we discovered and
disclosed critical vulnerabilities in
popular open source projects that were
using those actions
so on the agenda we will talk about what
are github actions and why it's such a
powerful build system which kind of
misconfiguration it can have we will
understand the consequences by exploring
its internals and we will speak about
possible mitigations
so my name is ilya i previously worked
as a developer and are in the team
leader on the ips product in checkpoint
i later on moved
to fireglass a security startup which
created the first
web isolation solution and currently i'm
working as a back-end technology lead at
cycle
and i'm alex silgaiv i'm a senior
security researcher at cyclode
previously i were investigating malwares
at checkpoint research a reverse
engineer with some interesting piece of
malware both
crimewares and apts
and at the moment i'm
searching vulnerabilities and
researching mitigations for the software
supply chain
security that's it
okay so you all know github
and its code storing capabilities
and in 2018 they stepped up their game
and decided to create a cicd platform
called github actions
which allowed its developers to automate
their development workflows
it really became very popular
quite fast
and
mainly due to its rich marketplace
and currently it holds more than 2 000
public actions on it marketplace
and also provides free
free ci cd for public repositories
according to the their numbers github
currently has more than 73 million
developers
and
stores more than 200 million
repositories
so what are the possible usage of github
actions the main usage is cicd as i
mentioned
for example running
tests on open pull requests or static
analysis
you can
build your code into containers and
upload them to a chosen registry such as
docker hub or ecr
you can schedule tasks that will scan
vulnerabilities in your code you can use
it to automatically label issues and
pull requests you can send issues to
ticket handling systems and much much
more
so here's an example of a github action
as you can see it is just a yaml file
that contains
when and what to run
so
in the you can see their own
uh
keyword which means that this action
should run upon every push every new
push to the
repository and it contains a single job
in the single step just to print hello
world
to create this workflow you simply need
to put this code inside dot github slash
workflows
and that's it
every next push will trigger that
workflow
so let's speak about a little bit about
how it works
so github runner is an open source
project that what it connects to the
github action service fetches the jobs
and then executes them
it can run on a github hosted machine
which is the popular use case and you
can also run it on your self-hosted
environment
the gita boasted runners will run as a
thermal environment which means they're
created upon a workflow triggering and
will be destroyed after it ends and for
each workflow a new temporary github
token is created for the possible api
interactions
so be
before we talk about
the github token itself a few words
about access tokens in general so in
order to access and modify github assets
you need to provide an authentication
token that details your permissions
so as you can see here when creating a
token a developer can choose which
permission the token will have which are
basically a subset of the user's
permissions uh inside that specific
token so i as a user can have access to
many organizations and many repositories
and this this token will basically
provide those permissions when i use
them
another thing you can see that these
tokens can be created uh
with with or without
expiration which makes them a lot more
strong
meaning that these tokens have a
privilege to do a lot of damage and it
can even not expire at all
so github when they designed their
github actions they really wanted that
developers would not use those personal
access tokens inside their workflows
so to overcome this they created
something called github token
and the github token is provided for
every workflow that that starts running
its default permissions are read and
write for most of the events and the
permissions are only for the repository
in which the github actions is currently
running
the token is valid during its action the
action execution period
or 24 24 hours at most
and it uses a default parameter in many
actions
and is this is the preferred method to
invoke github api
functionalities
an important note are forked pull
requests
which which are basically used when uh
contributors want to contribute to some
open source project they fork the
repository and create a pull request
with the suggested changes
and if you think about it if that
specific repository has a github
workflow which for example runs the cic
test or static analysis
this
the developer
can basically use that github token with
the right permissions to modify the
content of the repository by committing
via api or stuff like that so github has
different
mitigations for forked pull requests but
the basic one
is in those scenarios the github token
receives at most read permissions
so these scenarios won't be possible
another core mechanism in github are the
secrets so any meaningful
cicd workflow will need to use some
secrets for example aws access tokens or
or passwords for registries
and gita
gives us the option to store secrets
they save it in a well encrypted manner
and if the workflow wants to use them it
decrypts and adds it to the to the
payload of the workflow there are
several options on how to create secrets
some of them are on the
organization scope on a repository scope
or even a repository environment which
we will talk about a bit later
and here's
the first example of a vulnerable action
so the sample workflow you can see that
the
keyword is on
issue created on opened this means that
this work will run every time i will
open an issue in github for a github
repository you can see that it has a
single step which runs a script
and an important note here are the curly
braces that are used throughout the
script
which allows
developers to use dynamic parameters in
their workflows so github provides
parameters on the event triggered for
example the issue title and the issue
url and also the github token that we
discussed previously
and this specific workflow basically
checks if the title contains the word
bug
and if so it performs an api call and
adds a new label of type bug to that
issue
so this looks innocent enough
but let's see how it can be exploited
on the right you can see an issue title
that we provided
for that workflow and on the left you
can see what happens when it is actually
executed
this title is planted inside the curly
braces that we saw before and you see
here that the if statement is is not
non-existent it's it jumps over the if
and then
runs a code on the runner itself this
example just prints cycle to the screen
and
the fact that this crafted issue uh
knows how the workflow looks and it
knows how to start the if and how to
finish the if in in a way that the
syntax is
is valid and the workflow runs
so is it a bug or a feature
according to github's best practice
papers it is well known
and they cite when creating workflows
you should always consider whether your
code might execute untrusted input from
attackers
which is very nice and very friendly
but i'm not sure that all developers in
the world start by reading the best
practices documents before they start
using the platform itself
so we wanted to know how how popular
the usage of these batters are
we used a tool called github search
and which is currently in beta but it's
a very nice tool you can just add
keywords to the search here and it will
search all public repositories in github
and will return the results you can sign
up and try it out it's really fast and
really nice
and you see that we search for the
github event issue in curly braces and
also
the keyword run
as you see we have
two hits here
in which
we find workflows that indeed can be
exploited in the way i just showed
so is it widespread
we saw we found many many a
popular open source projects such as
liquid base
which is a
tool for
handling
database schema changes wire which is an
open communication platform and many
more
and
we can see that according to the
downloads of those open source projects
and the their usage
these vulnerabilities are are
potentially affecting millions of users
so here let's dive a bit into one of the
use cases of the wire specific one and
here you can see a part of their
workflow you can see that it is
triggered upon any issue comment
and an important note here is that
an issue comment is used when you add a
comment to an issue and also when you
add a comment to a pull request so
github
users are using the same event for both
of these scenarios and you can see
several steps the first step is
basically checking that the github
that the command body contains some
keywords zenkin's review so if we add a
pull request comment with the word
zenkins review we will go past we will
pass this if we go to the next one and
here it just checks that whether the
comment is on the pull request or not so
if it is we continue to the next if
here it checks whether the title starts
with some keyword then end with some
keyword and if it doesn't
you can see the two echo commands and
the second one is
basically printing out the issue title
for debug purposes and this is exactly
what can be used to exploit this very
popular workflow
on the right you can see that after we
disclosed this issue to wire they were
very fast in patching the problem and it
was very simple you simply need to use
an environment variable so you see the
end
at the top
storing the issue title in that
environment variable and then you can
just use that and it is already escaped
and the code will not run when you use
it in this format
so what are the consequences of a build
compromise
you can expose secrets as we mentioned
in order to create a meaningful cicd
pipeline you are probably using secrets
so in this way once we we have code that
is running on the runner we can use it
to expose the secrets to the sensitive
assets
we can also use the github token the one
we discussed before to commit to the
repository as i mentioned
by default you have read write
permissions to that repository so we can
create a workflow an inject code that
uses github api with that token to
commit code that is not really part of
the pull request inside that repository
in such a way an attacker can really
create critical supply chain incidents
without being really reviewed or
approved in that manner and the much
smaller risk would be the malicious
active ability to run botnets or crypto
miners using runner infrastructure
so in this point i will allow alex to
dive a little bit deeper to the
vulnerabilities and the mitigations
[Applause]
yeah
so
so thank you very much ilya
let's dive a bit deeper
technically deeper
so ilia explained what could be the
the consequences of such build
compromise
and will soon explore how an attacker
could actually reach these consequences
from technical perspective
so for that we created this intentional
vulnerable workflow which we'll explore
through our example
so this workflow first
will be triggered whenever a new issue
is created
it defines the new environment variable
for demonstration purposes soon we'll
see while we're doing that
and it has a three steps
it has three steps the first one
doing checkout
this is an external action it's using
the checkout command which basically
does git clone to the code into the
runner environment
very simple and it has two additional
run commands the first one just prints
the issue title and description and the
second one is run runs a
c url
to the github api to update
this issue a label with a new issue
so as
ilia showed previously this echo
is susceptible to injection attack
because they are not sanitizing the
the
the title and the body so an attacker a
malicious attacker could potentially
run
his code at this point exactly this
exact point so what could he who is
fetching in this uh in this sample he
could get on the one side connect this
this github token
and use it for his malicious purposes or
he could get this additional bot token
which comes later in the strong command
and see how we how he does that
first in order to er
to ease the testing of this random
infrastructure instead of creating
workflows and testing
each workflow when he runs we created
some lab environment
in which we
[Music]
made a reverse shell from the runner
environment to our personal computer
for that we use the popular tool called
ngrok which does basically a
tcp or http tunneling
even if you're behind firewall or not so
it's really a really cool tool we just
run the ngrok with the we installed the
tool on our computer we run android tcp
10000 tcp is the mode it could be run in
each http also and ten thousand is the
port in which we want to to listen
after running it we received from a
android android cloud received this end
point
which will use it later in their
exploitation
and then we just create a simple
netcat
listener on port 10000
and at the end we created this
simple bash script
which does the the reversal it's you
could find the script easily in google
so combining all together
when we were sending this issue title
this
looks quite complex but we explained how
it really combined when we when we send
this to the github repository and while
we get our reversal
we have a control on our computer on to
the runner infrastructure so we can
explore it and find it any interesting
stuff in there so
we won't overload you with all the
reconnaissance with it on that machine
you are welcome to check our full blog
for that
but we found some interesting
pieces of data which we'll use later as
we as we will show in this in the slides
so let's go back to our previous example
so first
very simple thing an attacker could do
if if we have a code execution
capability
is to print environment variable this
simple command and find for some
interesting
stuff in the environment variable for
example we have this github token
defined
as an environment variable which the
attacker could
just print the variable and get it and
use it
very simple
it also happens in real world scenarios
not in only our
our sample
a second scenario that attacker could do
is
use the checkout command
as i said this command just does a git
clone to the to the code
but it also sends a default parameter
which we are not seeing here but it
sends the github token as a default
parameter to the external checkout
this github token is also used as a
terminal authorization token
for the git clone
so wherever we're using a git
the git set tooling also know that
whenever you're doing git clone with
some token it also saves that token in a
that git slash config file
so because we are running as an attacker
after that checkout was made
we can access this dot git slash config
file
find the authorization line in that file
and just pipe it through base64 decoding
and we get our github token which it
will use which was sent to that action
and used to
to clone the code so as an attacker we
have another
method to to fetch this
sensitive token
this was the second scenario
the first scenario is a a bit more
complex and
during a reconnaissance of the runner
environment we noticed that each run
command we have two of these here
each one of this before it's been
executed it's also is saved on the file
system as a shell file
and the runner saves it and then
executes it
so why it is interesting
because in our case where
as an attacker we have code execution at
this point we didn't receive the second
command yet so we have only this
single run command you could see here as
a
as we're printing the directory the
render type directory which saves this
shell file we have a single shell file
that contains the same content as this
one but instead of the
curly brackets placeholders we have the
real values which were inserted
as the action
triggered so if we'll
get this second-round comment somehow
it contains also this secret the secret
bot token which will be placed as a
as a real value which as an attacker
want to grab
so if we get a foothold on this run
comment we also
get this bot token this secret
but as i explained the attacker have
caused execution at this point
so how
can we
fetch the the next one that hasn't been
executed yet
we have many methods to do that a simple
method either thought well off was just
putting some persistent script on the
runner
uh what does it mean it means a simple
uh
you know our case was python script that
was monitoring this directory
and whenever a new shell file is written
to the directory this file would be
immediately sent to some control server
as me as i'm simulating an attacker so i
created the server and whenever the new
file will be there it will be sent to me
so
what will be the steps
creating a some server that records all
the all requests creating some python
script that records modified shell
script in that directory
i packaged it all into some docker
container to ease the deployment and i
run that container on the runner in a
detached mode
mapping the volume and
and indicating the url which you would
send the file to
uh
we'll soon see in demo how it works all
together
so these were the three scenarios we
showed how to fetch secrets but there
are many many more they were really
simple and more sophisticated attackers
applied sophisticated methods
which we won't include in this
in this slides or in the article
additional methods could be inspecting
the the memory layout of the process
inside the runner try to extract some in
sensitive information from within the
memory it could be a
monitoring created processes so maybe
the secrets were sent through
environment variables to the processes
so we can
fetch maybe interesting information
there
and there are many many more methods for
further
research
so let's start with the demos uh for the
first demo we'll show how can we
exfiltrate secrets we will do it
in two steps the first step will just
send our simple github token as we
explained through the environment
variable and the second phase of the
situation we'll put some persistent
script on the machine and wait for the
second command that will be sent
also to our server
so
let's see
first we
set up the server
our control server and we're sending the
malicious issue to the repository
this issue contains several commands if
first it will
call the github token
which is the first phase and the second
one will run the
the docker run as you can see we got
already the first token
which were very simple through the
environment variable and
and we got also the second phase with
the exfiltration you could see we have
here
i don't know if you remember but
wherever the complete script that was
the third step for in the sample
workflow we have the conflict complete
the best script including the
token
contained in that script
so actually we managed to get it
so for the second
demo we'll show how we're able to commit
malicious code into the repository
without the knowing of the maintainer of
that repository
for that we have we provided is really
simple a bash script that contains
it that receives two parameters the
first one is the the file that we want
to commit is a url from where we
fetching that file and the second
parameter is the path in the in the
directory where we want to commit the
file to
it's a really simple script it fetches
the file
and the does
some several git commands like adding
the file configuring the
the code the committer we can put here
whatever we want we want we can impart
impersonate other committers and then we
commit it and push the code
so on the runner side we just
we will
fetch the script and write it with some
a simple malicious file with simulated
so let's see that in action
you can see as a demo repository with a
directory and a file
then we we are adding a new issue
this issue is previously show contains
several comments
first it fetches the script which uh
which we saw previously it gives the
proper permissions
uh to run on the runner and then he runs
it with the malicious file
some some simple file
uh
so we we're going back to the repository
we can see we have additional file added
to the repository
you also you could also
notice that the latest commit was made
by maintainer name with innocent commit
message we have complete control over
this data
and the fir the third demo will be a bit
more complex we are showing an
additional concept
for a for attack vector
up at two to this point
we show that we are
exfiltrating secrets that were in that
specific workflow
but uh there are additional secrets that
could be defined that weren't used in
that workflow there could be it could be
secrets defined on the repository level
on organization level they could be used
in other workflows not specifically that
one
it maybe we have some method to fetch
them as well
how can we do that we show that we have
the ability to commit to the to the
repository so let's commit a new
workflow that all his always doing will
be to exfiltrate all possible secrets
that he is exposed to
so how we do it we'll define this this
workflow
that
that all it does is
is a taking all the secrets is supposed
to writing it to that secrets file and
then
run c url to our some control server
but we have some minor issue because we
need to trigger this workflow somehow
from within our
runner
github has some
it's not security mitigation but they're
denying the
the activation of workflows within other
workflows it's to deny a circle of
triggering
so we already come with the idea with
we're using workflow run which tells
this workflow to run after another
workflow that called vol will be will be
finished uh running and this is the one
that we injected in the first place
so we are injected as a workflow and
we're committing an additional one and
when this one is over the one we created
will be triggered automatically by
github
so this solves us our issue and also on
the
on the runner side we're just going to
run this simple command invoking github
api this comment contains the
the commit message
the email the content this content will
be this workflow base64 encoded
and we're
telling the path in which we want to
commit this file to
so let's see how this works
first we're set up in the server of
course
now we're running the malicious issue
command it's quite long because it has
has the complete workflow as a base
base64
data and it uh as we said running serial
command with put
i mean with using the github token which
we as an attacker previously fetched
to to invoke github api
we using the contents api of github and
adding the path of the file together
with a commit message committer the
email
and
everything
so let's see what we have received in
our server we received the the bot token
which we previously
get in our first demo from that
for the second run command we received a
github token for that specific
uh repository
for the specific run and we also got the
two additional
secrets that could be either defined in
a repository level used for other
workflows or in organization level and
this is additional tokens called
additional sensitive assets could be aws
tokens could be azure tokens and etc
this is pretty cool
so
now we'll show possible attacks and
exploitation let's see how can we
mitigate it
the first mitigation is to avoid avoid
any run steps possible
for example instead of using this
command that is susceptible to injection
attack
we could use an external action it's
called labeler
that does exactly the same as this
command
it also received the title but it's not
susceptible to injection
it's not always possible but whenever
possible it's really recommended to do
that
the second method to mitigate this is to
sanitizing the input which is probably
the most effective method to mitigate
this specific attack is instead of
using the curly brackets
inside the run
you just define them outside in the
environment variable and use that
variable inside the
inside the command
this is
this the this mitigation exactly as wire
did as elias showed previously is very
effective because
we have uh the stronghold just simple
best script
which does this and it is sanitation uh
for us
another method for a post exploitation
mitigation is to limit the token
permissions we can add inside the
workflow this permission tag that will
define the maximum level of permissions
that the github token will receive
so
even if will the attacker manage to uh
to exploit and run code on our build you
won't be able to do whatever you want
because you will he will be limited for
example in our case we have a
we need only read permissions for
contents we need to clone the code
and we need right permission to issue
because we need to update a label so
this will
be sufficient for our sample workflow
another method that's uh effective for
the third
demo that we showed is to limit secret
secret exposure every secret define
secret defined organization level could
be defined
for what repository he could be exposed
to so even if an attacker would be able
to
to expose it to ex filtered every second
as possible you won't be able uh
if this mitigation will be applied
um and i another minor mitigation will
be to require approval for outside
collaborative collaborators it's
additional mitigation by github
the default parameter is to require
approval for first-time contributors
it's mainly applies for public
repositories each if a contributor
haven't committed
code yet to the repository he should be
allowed the manual by maintainers to run
his code
and the last one will be to use the
environment in branch protections it's a
second
yeah
it's a
[Music]
rather new mitigation by github that the
only enterprises
github enterprise allows it that
gives you the ability to define secrets
on environment level
so
what will be the takeaway from this talk
first of all
um
even when github does
most of the security
for you for example it gives you a
github hosted runners it gives you
ephemeral environments it gives you vm
based isolation etc
we are wanted to to understand that your
build
pipeline still could be compromised and
you should you should know that
the second one is as we've seen in
github best practices
it does
most of it's that some of the the it
delegates some of the security to the
developer
i myself a developer and i know the
developers do make mistakes so this
should be handled carefully
the third one is the the consequences
that we've seen in the demo of such
build co promise could be
a really disastrous could be it could
cause potential supply chain attack for
that vendor it could attack many many
clients
and the the last one is that securing a
pipeline isn't a matter of faith
in we'll show that github as an example
it supplies many security mitigations
that
all could be applied
and we wrongly suggest you to use this
as well
and
that's it
thank you very much you are welcome to
check the
full technical blog in the cycled blog
and thank you very much besides for
hosting us here a really great
conference
that's it
good question
thank you alex and elia do we have any
uh questions at this time
yeah yeah
okay here we go
hey so yeah just one thing came to my
mind that what what options do you have
to check for attacks happened in the
past like does github do any logging or
you just search for
like tickets with very strange names or
like whatever do you asking how to check
if you were attacked yeah kinda
yeah
unfortunately github doesn't supports
many editing it has some but it's not
very verbose and
this entire like ecosystem of ci cd
security it's really it
hasn't developed yet like other standard
security
industry
so the you know there isn't much of you
to to
to know that but that's why we're what
we suggest like to to mitigate it from
the start not to allow it in the first
place and and of course for big
organizations this is exactly what our
company does it monitors automatically
your commits your pull request
looks for
vulnerabilities such as this one and
alerts the maintainers automatically
anybody else at this time
okay one more
hello uh so my question is why the hell
is github not sanitizing these uh like
input fields like
it should be shouldn't they
yeah this is a terrible question yeah i
was waiting for that
um
[Music]
no i had this talking several times
they're all asking it
because they actually they can't
i mean they're allowing you it's code
execution as a service
they can do that it's not really
possible they're allowing you to run
bash script they can't do that for you
thank you but they can do other various
stuff like
warning you like telling me something
alerting you or something like and they
do don't do that unfortunately
just as a note uh it's it started like
very raw and people were starting to um
approve pull requests from inside
workflows so they added configuration
whether you can or can't approve uh pull
custom workflows and then the open
source tools where people just were
running
the for pull request just running and
using the token and then they understand
there's a problem and added this
mitigation to for the maintainer to
manually approve one and then to
manually prove everyone so
as you can see they learn
they they step up their security posture
on the github actions but yeah they
can't do it like
anybody else
well
in our case alex
thank you very much
[Applause]
you