yeah my company
ladies and gentlemen uh our next speaker
is mark modly he'll be asking questions
regarding injections
all right everybody i hope that we are
not that tired so we could pay a little
attention today as well at the end of
the day
so
injections uh i believe that we've heard
quite a lot
of injections in the past two years i
would say i guess i read more articles
in the two years
uh than ever before about injections but
today we should not really talk about
these kind of induction injections
and have a little bit of talk
about the ovus category injection so my
name is mark moodley i really love to
teach
and
before the actual presentation they told
me that good presentation has got three
key ingredients one of them that it is
short the other one it is not really
long and the third one that it ends soon
so i'm going to start uh by saying that
or promising that that i'm going to
shorten
my presentation in order to fit the time
frame that we've got over here
so
i do not really like to talk about
myself in these kind of situations the
people who met me during lunch big day
know that i'm quite talkative so after
the
little presentation feel free to reach
out we could have a little talk and
after midnight we can leave as well so
uh besides us uh
besides pun intended uh there is another
company or
i would say organization which is quite
fond of injections and this logo should
help us out as well
so uh
what is this organization
this is called the ovas the open web
application security project and
they
have quite a few
projects i would say which i really
adore and one of those is the overstock
10. i really like the thread dragon
which is a threat modeling tool provided
by august completely free and the zed
attack proxy codes up as well but i
really like this project because it sums
up the
most recent vulnerabilities i would say
uh and therefore
it is always a good point to have a
picture about the current stance of the
i.t security or the web word i would say
so in the most recent of us top 10
release it was actually last year in
we've got a completely new uh topic
which is called injection nobody ever
heard about it right
no that's right who said no
may
the duck bee video please
give it a so uh
it wasn't introduced last year but it
was introduced the year before right
where is there was the other note coming
from
all right i've got a few of them so be
prepared
all right so it wasn't introduced in
what year was it introduced
uh
no we are getting closer and closer but
it still wasn't uh introduced in this
year and i believe it wasn't introduced
in this year as well but in the meantime
you've got your duck as well so
let's see
uh
was it introduced this year
we are getting tougher and tougher
and the answer to that is still freaking
no so basically the injection uh was
introduced in
is there anybody in the audience who was
born after this date
ahead
so
as you can see if a vulnerability is
freaking older than some of the audience
there is something clearly going on
right
yeah i heard it right
so uh
we could talk about a lot of kinds of
injections and
i brought here a few
but to be more current today we had
pretty amazing
actually quite amazing
uh talks and two of them stood out for
me uh because of the mentions of
injections one of those was with our arp
injection
basically route injection and that's
quite amazing that we talked about and
it is still not on the slide
the other topic that we've had
was the first github issues
do we remember what the issue was with
the github i guess pipeline or runners
what injection was there
it was a command injection
all right so uh we've got quite a lot
of injections around us
what the hell is on the screen is there
anybody who could tell me
go ahead
it is actually a tree injection
or it is called a trunk injection in
sometimes
so
is there anybody who's got closer to the
definition what injection is at freaking
over
i'm not surprised by the lack of fans
over over there in the audience
so
what on earth are injections at all so
basically we start to say everything is
an injection right
i believe that
we do not really have
any clear-cut definition on injection
itself so i've came up or actually
with the team we've came up
with two
those two definitions which could shed
some light on what we call injections
like data escaping to the contour
control flow that's something that we
would say that's right
basically if we are talking about for
example gpqr java persistence query
language injections that's mostly true
as well we could talk about unexpected
input
content or with side effects on the
application or inside the application
itself
i'm
quite all right with these definitions
the ovus
foundation
uses kind of a different
explanation
to this topic which is injection occurs
when untrusted data is sent to an
interpreter as part of a command or a
query well
i honestly do not really like like this
definition uh because sometimes there
are no actual
parser that's involved in that as we've
seen today in the arp uh poisoning or
the our crowd injection there is no
actual processing there which is
i would say different or would be
different if we sanitize that data that
is completely changed
so uh
let's agree that
i do not really want to define injection
itself but just last and let's agree
that it has to do
something at least
with the unexpectedness of the input
that we are working on or
yeah it has at least side effects
so
of us
uh ovas is merging topics into injection
in the most recent change if you uh take
a look at that i know that it is blurry
uh but
if you are familiar
with the ovus topics that in that now
you should know that basically
cross-site scripting got merged into
injection as well
for me that's ca that's kind of a
strange
behavior or decision and let me tell you
a little story
in
2002 i believe
i i created
a content management system because
their php was all the rage and web 2 was
something that everyone was like quite
looking into and uh we were taking a
look at that wow this new web thing is
shiny and everything i know i'm old as
hell and i was running with the
dinosaurs at one point i can see from
the eyes of the audience but yeah
basically uh that point we were creating
the web and we were quite fond of that
stuff
one day my created content management
system was hacked by none else but my
close friend and he told me that he's
done that
in a way that he was able to embed
javascript in one of the uh codes that
he was allowed to written because it was
so sophisticated that it had different
privilege levels uh administers
administrators and content creators and
he was able to stall the contents of my
cookies
and i was like all right
back then there was no csp and
http only cookies
such fancy things didn't really exist
then and basically uh we wouldn't even
uh
mention that
cross site resource sharing
who heard about those things back then
basically those were non-existent
and
for me this is
the point where i start to believe that
injection is way broader than it should
be so
in 2003 the very first ovasp
the very first over stockton uh
mentioned the command injection flow
the next year in 2004
it got renamed the category post
homelessly
to injection flows
because they broadened it in that year
as well
so
in 2021
it got just the category of injection
and you could believe anything that's
what's in there your application needs
to be checked against the overstopped
and issues because sometimes that's the
criteria which is dumb in itself not to
mention that but uh injection contains
now almost everything that you could
imagine we've heard today at least three
or four topics that we're considering uh
that could be considered as injection i
would say so
i've developed software quite a lot in
my life and
what ovasp is doing right now is similar
when you've got a project manager who is
unable to say no
to new feature requests and basically
like a snowball our injection is getting
bigger and bigger and bigger we do not
even know right now what injection
consists of on on the slide we've seen
like i don't know 10 20 or something
like that of injections and we still
haven't written everything over there
there are quite a lot of things so this
got me thinking
what else could be considered as an
injection which was on the overstocked
and list quite
recently
and i would argue that
what you can do you can consider
uh xml external entity attacks as
injections as well but of course we need
to rename that topic into dtd injection
because
you are injecting
document type definitions into that
that's a point to that
i would not really merge this topic into
injection as well but
yeah you could do so
have you ever heard about request
smuggling
nice a few hands up
all right would we rename request
muggling into packet injection
or something like that
not that freaking all right
i think this tendency really has to stop
uh because over is just
over populating i would say the
injection space and i do not really like
that
so
quite a while ago i was working
with
atelco company
and
they had
different vendors to choose from
and how do you choose a vendor in i.t
security sometimes uh if you are
constricted really you do not have the
choice to choose because the space is so
limited at the moment that basically if
you uh get a paper that says
that you've done the oscp then you are
considered an expert and every word of
yours is true no matter what
do not blame me
it is still a good certification and
some certifications are pretty good but
uh just because you've got a
certification it does not matter uh in
terms of real life work because
sometimes you do not even know uh what
you should be looking for and in this
vendor selection process we've created
fake
sites
and it wasn't for the taco company it
was a previous project
we created fake sites and
basically we ordered penetration tests
for the from the vendors and we told
them that all right bring us everything
from that site which is missing which is
problematic
and uh sadly
but surely uh we haven't got everything
back back that's expectable it was a
10-day time frame and we hit so many
bugs in there even the creators we did
not know how many were there uh but
there were some intentionally hidden uh
features which were not really recovered
then so
i'm
gonna take just a few minutes uh from
your time and share you
really just a few
not so common injections
so
anybody
does we recognize do we recognize what
this is for or what payloads are these
have you got the dock
now you do
all right so uh it's template injections
what we
have here better to be said it is
server-side template injection because
uh it is better to execute code or do
anything on the server side because
that's where the key that's where the
data is and that's where the real value
hides
so how do we do the server side template
injection uh with the abbreviation of
ssdi
so first of all we just send
an input which should be
rendered
on any page or in pdf documents for
example i really love when sites have
pdf exports because most of them is
using the free marker uh template engine
and therefore if you are
looking up
the
free marker template engine codes or
exploits there is quite a bunch of them
and you are able to execute system
commands in there which is quite a win i
would say
so then just invoke the requested
resource and when the template is
injected basically in most of the cases
uh we've got code execution but uh what
we always have we are able to exfiltrate
data from the server itself
so
uh
yeah i would say that's something that
need to be considered on and if you are
working as a penetration tester or uh do
you do bug bounties or even have
some experience in like capture the
flags ctf games i would advise
looking on those i believe that the lead
boys are here
aren't they
all right so uh please do your ctf
chores and start your ctf team
basically as far as i know the hungarian
ctf teams are quite behind in the words
order if i could say so and we need to
work those up
those are rocky numbers we need to pump
that up so
what is our next injection topic
that i would like to talk about only
just a little bit because it is not
really something that most of the vap
penetration testers would be interested
in
so
have we ever heard about dln injections
i should have gotten more ducks honestly
this is my last lonely duck so uh be
prepared for her
so
um
we heard about dln injections before so
uh
dll injections is uh
more likely
a tool for malware harvard and in or
privilege escalation world what you've
used for and not like the web
applications so
what you do is you get the handler of a
process and basically modify the memory
of the process i'm not really getting
into the details of it you are modifying
the memory of the process and later on
uh you are basically able to take over
from that process or create fork a new
process from there where
you could work with the
rights of the original process meaning
that it is a tool uh which could be used
for
privileged pre-village escalation
purposes sorry it is getting long for me
as well so
i just want to say that reflective
loading is another topic if you are into
dll injections it is uh getting more
clever and clever because we need to
avoid antiviruses and stuff
so we do not really write on the disk
and therefore
we could fly under the radar uh for a
little bit
uh in the talk description that i've
gave
there is one question
why do people dismiss
the category of injection or injection
as a topic any guesses
i believe
they do not dismiss it at all have you
got a doc
oh then someone is still
obligated to have a duck in the at the
end of the talk
so
people do not really dismiss
the injection as a topic
it just got so bright
and basically there are
a few hundred i would say that if we
came together with amex injections and
log injections and cookie injections and
stuff that it is impossible to handle it
as a single entity uh let me share you
one story
so
a friend of mine
uh wrote
oh my god that was in the early days so
even before some of the audience was
born uh
we had the browser engine conqueror do
we remember that
it's it's not a fresh one i would say uh
you you have so basically one of my
friend modified the browser engine and
with each http request
he created or sent a cookie to the
server which contained nothing else than
admin equals one
so
it's laughable it is so dumb to do
really it it is so dumb but the results
were
out of this world honestly i haven't
seen so many pages broken into by one
odd equal or sorry a cookie by administ
was one
and uh the fun thing that he created uh
i i told him that i'm going to give this
talk and i really like this example and
he told me that
just for fun service he basically
created an extension to chrome as well
uh which does the same exact thing
and
he told me that
he was able to get
it was last week or some sum around that
uh he was able to get an administration
panel without logging into the system uh
of a hungarian web shop i do not
recommend to get around and test out
hungary and web shops with this
technique but well yeah
we are here with injection topics so you
could get administrator rights on web
shops basically
with a joke like this
so
we learned
that
actually
we are really really
behind
in terms of understanding injection we
do not really have a commonly acceptable
i would say
definition for it
and
right now i think the key takeaway is
that we should not generalize
the topics to the point of obviation is
there any question i should answer
if there is none i just hope that this
talk will end the generalization of
injection uh topics in the overstock
then and so there will be no sequel to
it
mark thank you very much
[Applause]
i hope you've enjoyed
who's the youngest member of the
audience
yeah the other extreme is also nice
so if you've got any question or just
want to hear some fun stories about
injection feel free to uh reach me out
i'm still at the conference and enjoy
the rest of it there is one talk left as
far as i know