or that our scar
okay
so now i think you can
hear me even better so
i'm guessing it's gonna be a bit hard to
get your attraction at this time of the
day because you're probably tired and
not going to be long but first of all
i'm going to be introducing myself my
name is adeda delawaskar and i'm a
senior threat hunter in palo alto
networks unit 42 for the past two and a
half years now before that i used to be
a checkpoint to stock manager and
and today i'm going to be discussing
with you an insider threat
uh use cases that we managed to find on
our customers environment
we're going to be discussing and i will
be showing you how can you use your edr
logs your endpoint detection and
response logs in order to target those
two frequently seen use cases and
i'd say at least 60 or 70 percent of
our customer base
so
without further ado let's just start
um so on the agenda today we're gonna
start with defining the insider threat
we're gonna give you some
at least try to set the grounds for this
entire conversation
then we're gonna share with you a few
real
real world use cases that i'm pretty
sure you're all familiar with at least
one of them
we're gonna deep dive into how and what
we can do in order to spot them using
your edr logs
uh q a and we're going to wrap up the
session with a few recommendations
to everyone so let's just begin
so a little bit about the team we're a
managed hunting team that's providing
on threat hunting for our customers that
is based on
practically anywhere in the world and
this is done on top of 46 dr logs which
is palo alto's edr obviously you can do
those type of hunting on any type of edr
that you own and it doesn't it is not
limited to cortex xdr
so first of all
let's um deep dive into who is he who is
the insider and let's try to define him
so
when you're thinking about a bluetooth
whatever is in our mind all the time is
rats and ransomwares and apts and
vulnerabilities and those type of things
are usually occupying the socks in the
blue teams the entire time now there's
also one thing that is always floating
in the back of our head and it's called
the insider threat
and
i feel as personally as a previous stock
manager that we always come short in
detecting those insiders throughout our
days
and in this use cases that i'm going to
share with you i hope
that
maybe some more blue teams around the
world are going to are going to be
utilizing those specific use cases in
order to find those insider threats
so
i'll give you a couple of examples why
insider threats are a really big problem
to organizations worldwide and
essentially why they are so hard to
detect and essentially they're so hard
to detect because they're part of organ
our organizations it's we that gave them
the credentials and it's we that gave
them the legitimate access to those
systems and to those data types of data
that they need to interact with in order
to do their job
and when you think about an insider
threat or an insider it can virtually be
anyone it can be
um a careless employee that sends an
email mistakenly but it can be much much
worse
with a rogue business partner that knit
that sets sorry right next to you and
decides to turn against the same
organization that he is working for
so we'll start with a couple of examples
and i'm pretty sure that
everyone in here probably recognizes the
person in this picture
on the left so this is edward snowden
and this is the famous case of eder
snowden versus the nsa and the story
begins on 2013 when edward snowden is
getting hired by the nsa as an external
contractor
and throughout his service in the nsa he
decides after 15 months of employment
to steal a lot of data from the nsa top
secret documents
approximately 1.7 million documents were
alleged to be licked by edward snowden
and obviously this caused a whole lot of
embarrassment to the national security
agency of the united states
how did he do it you ask
he essentially had domain admin
credentials and he connected an external
usb drive to one of the servers which he
then
leaked a lot of documents from this
specific server
another example before we dig into the
technicalities
um the anatom and the urible affair
i'm guessing that this is one probably
one of the most uses that is less known
here in the crowd but this is a really
famous uh case in israel
and in 2005 anatkam was assigned to work
as a clerk in the israeli command office
center
she was just a regular soldier and
uriblau is an israeli rs newspaper that
is specialized in military affairs
throughout his throughout her
military service anotcom has decided to
copy thousands of classified
documents including many uh confidential
documents also
to us an external cd drive this time
this was quite a while ago where usbs
were not as popular and then after she
finished
her um
her service she took that specific usb
with her later on linked it to
the journalist uriblau
which eventually uh published some of
the documents in harris newspaper
later on on january
2010 anatka was indicted with espionage
and she actually uh served and was
sentenced to four and a half years in
prison in prison and 18 months of
probation
so with all this background being laid
out
let's start with the first use case that
i'm going to be sharing with you and the
first one is going to be called living
somewhere
um
so
let's just
read and go through the life cycle of an
ins of a classic insider threat it all
begins with a new employees being
recruited to the team and he is assigned
with a legitimate account to perform its
daily tasks later on as time moves on
the employees granted with more and more
permissions
to different types of systems and
various data types that he needs to do
you know because he's participating in
some more project or some
new uh
teams that he's engaging with and this
is something that happens essentially to
all of you i'm guessing as well
later on comes the termination phase and
this can be a dual part termination can
either be the employee's pending to
leave the company because he decided to
move on to another to another company or
he's or this is the company's decision
to fire him
and this is exactly where the data
expectation takes place
a few days prior to the last day of the
employee
he moves on to connect a personal usb
drive to his or her machine and copy
internal data to this specific disk
drive
now let's do an anonymous survey
i wanted you to raise your hand if you
ever copied
data from your own
and fast employer when you left
all right so
there's some courage people in here
because
so first of all i'm guessing that no one
has actually fell into this because when
we were doing it internally in palo alto
a couple of people were actually raising
their hand and we were saying is someone
taking notes i mean we should be kind of
taking notes for the next time that
they're going to leave
so no one's going to admit it but i'm
guessing that if we're really honest
probably a lot of us have probably did
that a longer along the way
so what i'm going to be providing with
you first of all is
some example of reports every obviously
everything that is customer related is
obfuscated in here
but just i'll give you a high level of
what is this report is all about so the
managed threat hunting team has managed
to find over the past three months three
users that have copied excessive amount
of data to an external usb drive you can
see one and a half gigabytes of data 5.1
gigabytes of data and 15 gigabytes of
data
the key
finding in this specific report is not
the amount of data that was copied but
the fact that for the last 90 days
for the last 45 days story no login
event was was spotted for this specific
user and this may hint that this user is
no longer part of the organization
the second part of this
report is followed by highlighting to
the customer
what is the type of data that was being
linked so we can see a couple of really
interesting
named directories like
clients which contains 5000 suspected
internal company documents my appeals
again a lot of company documents alleged
that are containing in this specific
directory and ipdump now this was a
really big law firm company
which later on confirmed to us that
indeed
those directories were containing
internal documents
another example
another user that has copied 1.8
gigabytes worth of data to an external
usb drive from a directory that is
called
fda submission this was a really large
pharmaceutical company and again when
looking through the copy event obviously
fda submission is highly suspicious when
we're looking at this event
so how do we create those type of
reports
so we're going to use two queries and
in this specific um screenshot what you
can see is is a
is this
it's a screenshot of an xql query xql is
a proprietary language of uh palo alto
networks but you can use it at any ed r
that you own it could be either splunk
or any or crowdstrike or anything
similar to that and with that query
we're doing a couple of things we have
the first query that is going to get a
list of all the users
that copied data to an external usb
drive and were and did not observe login
for the last 45 or 90 days you can just
adapt it to any um
duration of time that you would like
this is what we call the lead generation
query
we're going to get all the leads to our
further hunting efforts based on query
number one
then we're gonna go to query number two
and query number two is all about
getting an idea on interesting files or
folders
that were spotted throughout the copy
event
so this is query number one and this is
the lead generation query
and we're going to use the following
output columns in order to make our life
easier
let's login when was the last time stamp
where the user has logged into any
systems in the system that we actually
have logs for
usb connecting number of days this is
the unique amount of days that this
specific user has connected
i use a usb drive to his machine
throughout the query period and this is
just to show you how often
is this user is prone to connect usb
drive to his machine part of his regular
job or not
total amount of emails that were copied
throughout the event total amount of
documents amount of images total amount
of code and
total amount of gigabytes and count of
the unique files that were copied
throughout the event
all of this columns are designed in
order to generate and make our life
easier in picking those
highly suspicious leads where we're
gonna run the second query on top
and this is the exam this is an example
of the output of the query i know it's
in uh
it's in dark mode so it's really hard to
see i hope that you can see it but
you have the query highlights right
above so the user's last login was july
13th and this was actually this was a
query that was executed around um
december 2021
so for quite a while the user did not
log into any system of the specific
customers environment
over the past 90 days the following usb
properties were spotted so the user has
connected only
on one day i mean for only one day the
user connected a usb device to his
machine
a total a total amount of 1.8 gigabyte
was copied
over 1.1 k unique files
and the file type breakdown says that
two email file types are copied 85
file type 85 images sorry 102 code files
and 646
documents
so following this
really good line and you can see
the output in here this is the drive
letter the username which is math and
all of this type of data that is like on
the query itself
this is where we're gonna pivot to query
number two and query number two is
analyzing the copy and again the columns
are here to help us understand better
what was copied out throughout this
event so one of them is the timestamp
which is obviously the time step of the
copy the full path of the file that was
copied the username the drive letter
the host name and the file size which
are all
which are all pretty straightforward
this is an output of the second query
and this is related to the first query
that we just saw with the fda submission
so you can see that the drive
that a directory called fda submission
was copied to a usb drive a few days
prior to the user's termination
so while we're experiencing the feedback
that we got we send a lot of um
those type of reports to customers and
it essentially happens on every
environment that doesn't block usb drive
so one thing that we recommend to our
customers is maybe enforce a usb block
and just open the usb to those people
who need it to be part of their actual
work
and if this is something that you will
not be able to enforce in your
organization so we highly recommend you
to have those queries or those similar
type of queries running in your
environment regularly
just spot them even if it happens after
the users get is getting terminated i
mean for us
as blue teams
when a specific file leaves our
environment and it doesn't matter if
it's physical copy or an online copy it
usually means game over in a way
but then again we had a lot of customers
that were reaching out to users after
their termination
and
starting
kind of a legal actions against them
because they took and they violated
company policy with doing that
okay so this is something that's really
key and while you're all reading the
feedback do you have any questions while
i'm drinking some water
awesome
so the second uses is called uploading
somewhere and this is very similar to
the first use case you can see that the
lifecycle that is laid out in front of
you is extremely similar to the first
one with one exception
instead of connecting
a usb drive to your host you're going to
link it to one of the online drives and
the third-party vendors that are aligned
that are allowing external storage for
people that are gonna use it
so
a couple one two report examples with
two key differences which i'm gonna
highlight for you so one of them you can
see that over the past three months a
user was spotted to upload 5.7 gigabytes
to one drive
and again
the last login for that user was spotted
45 days in earlier now notable
directories that were spotted throughout
the copy event is
archive.pst a psd file is
probably microsoft outlook's
internal
mailbox file and it probably copied and
contains an internal copy of the user's
email backup including a lot of stuff
that we probably don't want to leave the
organization
so this is the output of the copy again
now highlighting the
uh process that actually initiated this
specific upload towards the cloud in
this case we have onedrive.exe
another example
is
when you're when when you're hunting for
customers or essentially in your
environment you have an idea on what is
the allowed third-party software that
this specific organization allows their
users in order to use for cloud storage
so for example in palo alto networks
we're using google drive
and in this specific company we saw that
onedrive
is
something that is fairly used by in this
specific organization which made us to
believe that onedrive was the authorized
third party vendor that this specific
company has chosen not to mention that
the remote host
that this the onedrive is uploading the
data to
is the domain is called sharepoint.com
but luckily enough for us microsoft also
um
registers a sub domain
which is masked in here which you will
be which is which is owned by this
specific company so in here for example
if palo alto was to use one drive in
order to store their file it would have
been palo alto.my.sharepoint.com
and when to me as a threat hunter this
is a really key
and important investigation point
because i can whitelist everything that
goes out to
this specific subdomain
i'm guessing that this is allowed
an allowed connection that is done by
onedrive but in here you can see at this
specific account that google drive
dropbox were used throughout the
organization not to mention
that using this technique of the remote
host you'll be able to determine if a
user is connected with his personal
onedrive
because when you're going to be
connecting with your user with your
personal onedrive your data get is
getting uploaded to a different domain
and not the company owned domain
so again this is an example
of the query and you can see that those
processes that are responsible for
uploading a lot of data
towards uh
both.dropbox.com and google apis
google apis dot com which
belongs to google drive sync and
dropbox.exe
so how to create the report
so again we're going to use two queries
really similar to our first assumptions
getting a list of all the users this
time who uploaded data the third party
vendors and their last again was set to
back in the past
the second query is gonna
help us in understanding what are the
type of files that are being executed so
again very very similar i'm not going to
bore you with again but last login date
number of unique uh uploaded days where
the user is actually uploading stuff to
the cloud total amount of emails
documents images code total amount of
gigabytes and unique files that were
spotted the query number two is to help
you analyze the copy again
and this is where the q a comes and if
you do want to do the q a at the end
because i have a wrap up all right so
i'm going to jump straight to the
wrapping up
so wrapping up
so blue jeans it's really easy to focus
on the on the outside i mean if i would
have an enormous survey in here and ask
you if you're a member on the on a blue
team what concerns it the most i'm
guessing that ransomware would be number
one
followed by
i guess crypto miners and some uh
botnets and
and rats but nobody would have mentioned
the inside of france
now
there's a real if you're gonna
google some
really interesting cases over the past
few few months even there are a lot of
cases where insiders from really popular
companies like
even google and tesla
there were a lot of cases where it
really affected the company and made
them pay millions of dollars
to just
counteract those activities that are
made by the insider threats
one another thing and this comes from me
to you
in a data-driven world where everything
essentially we're doing is being
documented
don't borrow stuff with you when you
when you leave a company because
essentially we can see everything
and again if you would like a copy of
the queries again this is xql based so
if you have all follow auto networks
cortex xtr you'll be able to use them
out of the box but if not it's just a
general idea on how to build them then
you can adapt into your
own edr language so please don't don't
hesitate to reach to reach out i'm
pretty sure you'll be able to do so on
linkedin twitter or
anything similar
that you feel free to so thank you very
much for having me
and the q a
thank you uh
[Applause]
yeah i was wondering whether waiting for
45 or 90 days isn't too late
is it
by informing the customers in real time
about these events is it too false
positive
of an approach
so that's actually an excellent question
the problem is when you have third-party
hunters is that we don't have the
ability to know who's spending to leave
the company so for some of the customers
that we actually reported it to
we build a process that actually
they're gonna send us the people that
are pending to leave and we would run
those queries before the alleged date of
this specific user that is going to be
leaving
if you are working for a company and
you're um
threat hunting for a company for your
internal company then you don't have the
you have the ability to contact your hr
and have them send you all the employees
that are pending to leave or even worse
ones that are getting terminated soon so
this is going to be uh but this this
this is a good a good comment because
you when you're sending something that
happened three months ago
it's usually a little bit problematic in
terms of the customer
uh
thanks for the for the talk really great
talk
just out of curiosity you said that when
your clients like received the report
they could maybe sue that
that employee that stole their data
um
i don't know if maybe if you know the
answer but is like the data from your
report is applicable at court for them
to sue but maybe they didn't record the
all the data that is transferred
so again an excellent question and thank
you
so
the thing is i'm not sure they will be
able to utilize our report but our
reporting also includes the queries
themselves and the query squares their
data that they're saving on
on palo alto's cloud
and if they're gonna use those queries
in order to get the output from the
apollo's cloud it's it's applicable to
court i mean
it aligns with all the data regulations
that are needed and they can just
provide the output query and i'm
guessing it stands in court i guess
thank you
anybody else
okay in that case
once again thank you to odd and his
young assistant
thank you
[Applause]
you