hi there everyone
good morning good afternoon or good
evening depending on where you're
joining us from
thank you so much for coming my name is
max hunter
and i work as an engineering director at
the electronic frontier foundation
primarily focused on software projects
to encrypt the internet
so eff is a non-profit organization that
works to protect
privacy freedom of expression and
innovation for all users of technology
you may have heard of some of eff's
legal victories over the years
we've had some landmark wins for example
we helped in bernstein v department of
justice to establish
that first amendment protections apply
to programming code
we ensured that free speech and privacy
protections in cda230 remained intact
through
numerous legal challenges and
we were helping to ensure that fourth
amendment protections apply to cell
phone location data
through our support in amicus briefs and
carpenter v the united states
these are just some of the wins that
we've had there have been
hundreds of high impact cases throughout
the years
eff has also worked on software projects
that you may be familiar with
we have browser extensions like privacy
badger which is a
an extension that helps to protect the
privacy of millions by stopping
advertisers and
other third-party trackers from secretly
monitoring users behavior
as they browse the web we also maintain
https everywhere
this is a browser add-on that helps to
ensure that your client
defaults to the encrypted connection
with many major websites
making your browsing more secure when
site swaps or
offer both http and https connections
we also build and maintain sertbot
that's the project that i work on
a free open source software tool that
fetches and configures let's encrypt
certificates
to encrypt web traffic surpod is used to
secure traffic to
tens of millions of sites in the process
helping to protect the privacy of
hundreds of millions of visitors
eff also works to push back on harmful
technology policy ideas
we do this through a combination of
legislative
activism and policy work both
online and offline that's what i'll be
talking a little bit more about today
today we'll be exploring two cases that
eff is working on to push back against
bad legislation
as i said we've got quite a long history
of doing this
since the 1990s eff has worked to
fight to protect users ability to use
strong encryption
encryption that's uncompromised by the
tampering of governments that are
interested
in enabling mass surveillance
in the 1990s we worked with leading
cryptographers from academia
civil society and industry around the
world to
fight back against the clinton
administration's disastrous clippership
proposal
which would have required companies to
create mechanisms to defeat commercial
encryption
we won this campaign we also defended
against export restrictions that would
have regulated development
and distribution of strong encryption
more recently you might have seen that
we launched a campaign with hundreds of
thousands of
supporters successfully pressuring the
obama administration to drop their plans
to explore mandates for cryptographic
backdoors
and that was the end of the crypto wars
with no more bad policy suggestions ever
and we can
close this talk out and move to
questions
that is what i would love to say of
course but of course these conversations
continue to this day
and 2020 has brought us a host of new
threats to encryption
this debate is very much still ongoing
and the greatest of these threats within
the united states has been a legislative
battle over the earn it act
now earn it will strip away section 230
protections
for any website or service provider that
doesn't follow a list of best practices
leaving those companies exposed to
liability that would most likely lead to
bankruptcy
this best practices list and air quotes
would be created by a government
commission and this commission would be
headed by attorney general barr
barr has a long history of pressuring
commercial security providers
to break the encryption of their users
in the name of lawful access
just two weeks ago the earned act passed
the senate judiciary committee
and has now been introduced to the house
of representatives
so to really get a feel for the
potential implications of earn it
you need to imagine an internet where
the law requires that every encrypted
message
that sent be read by government-approved
scanning software
companies that handle such messages
wouldn't be allowed to protect the
privacy of their users
or they'd risk losing the legal
protections that's
uh they have under cda230 which are
responsible essentially for their
freedom to operate
you can't have an internet where
messengers like this are scanned on mass
and also
have end-to-end encryption any more than
you can create back doors that can only
be used by law enforcement
any mechanism that is used by lawful
authorities to gain access to private
messages
or otherwise infer the content of those
has the potential for abuse
third-party access like this commission
would likely recommend
to encrypted communications is
impossible
it's built into the definition of
end-to-end encryption
concepts like client-side scanning are
not a method to circumvent this
client-side scanning is just another
method of breaking end-to-end encryption
either a message that is sent remains
private to everyone
but the sender and its intended
recipients or it is no longer end to end
encrypted
it's a fairly simple concept that no one
but you and your intended recipients
should be able to read your private
messages or otherwise
analyze or make inferences about the
content of what you're talking about
this is the fundamental promise that
encrypted messaging services
make to their users requirements that
earn it could put forward like
client-side scanning
would break that promise
so recently an amendment was put forward
by senator patrick leahy
a democrat from vermont it was voted
into the bill and
purports to protect encryption from
being the state's focus
it is definitely an improvement but
we're still concerned that the amended
earn it bill
could be used to attack encryption
senator leahy's amendment prohibits
companies uh from being held viable
because they use
end-to-end encryption device encryption
or other encryption services
but the bill still encourages state
lawmakers to look for loopholes
it allows the states to undermine
end-to-end encryption by doing things
like demanding that messengers be
scanned on a local device
before they're encrypted and sent along
to the recipient
we think that would violate the spirit
of senator leahy's amendment certainly
the intentions were positive
but the bill as it is currently written
opens the door for that question to be
litigated
over and over again in courts across the
country
the newly revised earned act would allow
all 50 state legislatures
as well as the u.s territories and
washington dc
to pass laws that would regulate the
internet that would
bring about new regulations for
encrypted messaging as well
by breaking section 230 of the
communications decency act
the earn it bill would allow large
messaging services
and small website owners alike to be
sued
or prosecuted under state laws
i believe an eff believes that offering
strong privacy protections
to users shouldn't make messaging
services liable for prosecution
even with the new revisions for senator
leahy
ernit would do just that so
if you're a u.s citizen we encourage you
to contact your representatives to
speak out against the threat to user
privacy and earn it
we've created a number of online
activism tools that users can use to
find their representatives
and share their feelings about strong
encryption
however the us earned act is not the
only ongoing legislative threat to
privacy
in 2020 two legislative efforts in both
india and brazil
pose serious threats to privacy of
encrypted messaging services
both efforts are aimed towards
determining the originator of
misinformation
and in both cases the legislation will
not help
with the problem of misinformation but
they will
significantly weaken the privacy
protecting properties of end-to-end
encrypted messaging services
now my colleagues katico rodriguez and
verdiana alemante
have analyzed the privacy implications
of the brazilian legislation
along with my former colleague seth
shone
and i'll be sharing some of the research
that the three of them have done
now
so whatsapp is the most popular
encrypted messaging tool used in brazil
and as such has been the focus of the
pls 2630-2020 bill
the legislation seeks to compel
messaging services to be able to
determine the originator of forwarded
messages
or like earn it would threaten their
liability
threaten them with liability there's
been
minimal discussion relatively on the
impact that this legislation
would have on other tools and services
like telegram
signal and imessage that offer privacy
protecting and
encryption although these tools are
conspicuously absent from the public
discourse they would almost certainly be
impacted
by the traceability mandate that the
legislators are considering
whatsapp has faced widespread
international pressure to
curb the flow of misinformation on the
platform
in brazil this pressure was refocused
during the 2018 presidential election
where bolsonaro's supporters used the
platform
to spread misinformation about his
opponents
now whatsapp's forwarding feature is
implemented using
privacy by design on the server side
forwarded messages are designed to be
completely indistinguishable from other
forms of communication
so when a whatsapp message is forwarded
by a user
using the forwarding arrow the forwarded
status
is appended to the message on the client
side entirely
and the forwarded count is incremented
towards
uh the five limit uh so after five
forwards a message is considered
mass-forwarded but nothing about this
forwarding status
is returned to whatsapp's infrastructure
the messaging platform
gains no additional knowledge about the
message's contents
this is sound design for privacy
if a messaging service were to comply
with this traceability mandate that's
being considered
they would be required to move away from
the privacy by design
implementation for counting forwards
they would need to move information
about the number of times a message has
been forwarded
from the client to the server gaining
additional knowledge
about the content of the message it is a
core tenant of privacy-centric systems
design
to only gather and retain the minimum
information
required for the functionality of a
particular feature
requiring encrypted messaging services
to retain this information
violates this tenant and it undermines
the user's trust in privacy-centric
software
fundamentally also message traceability
mandates like
pls 2630 2020 misunderstand the level of
centralization
in the secure messaging ecosystem
though the messaging apps might not
appear to be decentralized like email is
the idea of tracking when a user
forwards a message may depend on control
over client applications that simply
doesn't exist within this ecosystem
you can't have any way of guaranteeing
that all client applications
some of which are developed and
maintained by third parties
will comply with restrictions and
limitations in the same way or even
that it's technically feasible for them
to do so
some systems are simply too
decentralized
that is to say there's no central
organization
maintaining them responsible for
compliance
so this mandate assumes that application
providers are always
able to identify and distinguish between
forwarded
and non-forwarded content and also that
they're able to identify the origin of
the forwarded message
this in practice however depends on the
architecture of the service and
the relationship between the application
and the service
when the two are fully independent like
you see with email
it is common for the service not to be
able to differentiate between forwarded
and non-forwarded content
and that the application does not store
the forwarding history except for on the
user's device as
in the whatsapp design that we
previously discussed
this architectural separation is very
traditional in internet services
and while it's less common in modern
private messaging
applications the obligation would limit
the use of
xmpp and jabber or other similar
solutions like that
those this could also negatively impact
other open source messaging solutions
so some might make the argument that
these are acceptable privacy compromises
in the name of combating rumors and
disinformation
some people might say that it's worth
retaining additional information
if it can assist law enforcement with
ident with identifying the
originator of uh illegal messages
but this is not the case not only
will these traceability mandates
compromise user privacy
they won't effectively assist law
enforcement in identifying the
originator of content
attempting to do so by collecting
additional information
about message forwarding fundamentally
misunderstands the way the content is
shared on social media
secure messaging apps all the time users
will share content
which is originated on other platforms
entirely
for example a signal user might take a
screenshot
of a tweet or a facebook post distribute
it to a large group of encrypted
messaging users
in that case implementing traceability
would both weaken the privacy
protections of the messaging service
and only allow users or only allow
authorities rather to identify the user
who created the screenshot
there are certainly software design
solutions that can improve
the issue of mastery forward and
misinformation
we've explored a few of those already
such as limiting the number of
recipients for a forwarded message
or labeling viral messages
as viral indicating that they didn't
come from a user's
close contact however undermining the
privacy and security of millions of
people
is not a viable solution
so you might be asking what you as an
individual
can get can do to get involved with
these campaigns
and if you live either in the us or
brazil we would encourage you to contact
policy makers
to push back on these bad policy ideas
you can also you can do that by getting
involved with some of the organizations
that are leading the work to push back
on these proposals generators digitalis
uh
is leading some of the work in brazil uh
you can join them at derrish's
digitalis.org
participa or eff eff.org
join
finally thank you all for your time and
support
none of the work that is done to protect
user privacy from overreach would be
possible
without your involvement and support
thank you all very much and let's move
on to questions