hi folks
today we're going to be assessing
privacy risk with the ipa triad
before we begin my name's mark i could
describe myself as a few different
things but largely i've just worked on a
huge variety of projects
coming from a decade of software
engineering before my shift in focus to
security and privacy
today i run a small consultancy called
obscure group
and before that i was a privacy engineer
at google
providing consulting to their hardware
product teams and marketing groups
and before then i was a doing product
security at square
working with all their products before
that i was working on squares blue team
building detection tools and incident
response pipelines
and before then i was a founding member
of the square capital product team
now before all of that i was working at
a variety of small to medium-sized tech
companies building products and services
in advertising social networking
e-commerce
collaboration tools etc overall i built
up a skill set that's been really
helpful for jumping into complex new
spaces
assessing what needs to be done and
moving on to the next problem
so today i wanted to share a few tools
that will hopefully help you
when you're jumping into complex privacy
problems so that you can address them
and similarly move on
so we have a few different sections
today i'm just going to dive right into
the introduction
and i want to give you a different
perspective on privacy
but first let's learn from our
colleagues in security
what does it mean to be secure or not
secure well there's a concept known as
the cia triad which is considered one of
the key concepts
used to describe what qualities must be
protected in order to consider the
information
wholly secure in principle in summary
confidentiality is about exposure risk
integrity is about tamper risk
availability is about resource denial
risk
and having these different properties
has been really helpful
in having more nuanced risk discussions
and analysis
rather than just saying something is
secure or not secure
so great but what does it mean to be
private or
not private well there's a bunch of
different approaches to this depending
on where you're coming from
um you can jump into data protection
concepts like collection
processing transparency consent and
control
but sometimes it feels like rushing to
standard solutions when you don't really
have a bigger picture of what you're
trying to protect
you can talk about what users care about
and what they personally find
creepy or clearly compromising their own
privacy but these assumptions really
vary
a lot between individuals and
communities and user expectations are
also highly subject to their lived
experiences
technical literacy and access to
meaningful data about how their
information is used
we can consider the motives and means
various attackers would seek to
compromise others privacy
but attack surfaces and techniques are
constantly changing
and that can make it really difficult to
maintain a collective understanding and
language to describe privacy this way
so coming from security i wanted a way
to describe
properties of privacy and what i ended
up with was
identity presence
and activity let's just dive right into
these
identity is about data that reveals who
it's about
um so things like a full name a date of
birth social security number
can be attributed to an individual or
when you're talking about a group
it could be a member of a household
employee of a company
being part of a social circle of some
sort
or whether you're talking about some
larger population like a nationality
gender age group religion
now for presence this is really about
data that reveals
um where someone has been not
necessarily who they are but just that a
human was there at some point
and here's an example of some things
that can return data
that indicate human presence at a given
point in time
now activity is about data that reveals
what
happened at a given point in time and so
here are some examples below
that show um you know data
about you know what somebody was doing
while they wore
an activity monitor or maybe as they
used an app or made a purchase what
behavioral data they generated
or what hardware can sense the
environment around them
to detect activities in some unique
interesting way
hmm you may have spotted something now
from the previous examples it's actually
rare to find data that doesn't involve
multiple properties or expose another
property via inferences
and that's pretty similar to how the cia
triad works in practice too
for example if an attacker subverts the
confidentiality of a credential
they could use it to log into a system
and modify and delete data
which could affect integrity and
availability
here's a venn diagram of various subsets
of how
data can be of multiple properties um
when you're smack dab in the middle
it kind of means that you're seen from
all sides
it's about who you are what you're doing
and where you are
a good example of this is a video camera
they're all around us these days
um and they're pretty high sensitivity
on all
three um scales so um
yeah you see them in doorbells security
cameras in your phone
uh all over the place authenticated
interactions
now before when i talked about
behavioral data
um describing um various activities you
might do
a lot of time they're tied to your
identity explicitly
via some user identifier or some session
that you have
in that context and in this case
somebody is making a payment
which is linked to your identity and
often
a place in the real world so this is
also
all three um at least in theory
badge entry systems are also an
authenticated interaction
which encompass a couple different
properties
let's dive into how we perform
risk assessments using a qualitative
approach
there's a general methodology i'm just
going to introduce here
it's about averaging three things
severity scope and likelihood
and the impact becomes the shorthand for
the overall negative privacy effect to
be avoided
severity it's informed by sensitivity or
the damage potential
i.e what is the harm experienced in this
picture a squirt gun is shown
and this might be considered a mild
annoyance to most people
maybe less so if you're replacing a
circuit breaker or operating heavy
machinery
but that's out of scope in more extreme
cases of severity
the outcome might be injury or death
now scope is about a pool of a
population or users or systems
or whatever you're trying to protect
and here i'm showing a drop of water but
to you this might mean a handful of
users
using a subset of your application
in more extreme examples the scope could
be every single user
past and present moving on to likelihood
it's informed by the number of steps or
the complexity for the risk to be
realized
the practice of threat modeling is
extremely useful for determining
likelihood
since it involves deeper knowledge of
the design the implementation or the
operation details
now in this example you can interpret
the baby puzzle metaphor
either way if this if solving it means
the risk is realized then you could
consider the likelihood pretty high
now if you interpret the design more
literally and that a baby puzzle is
harder to lose pieces
break during use or accidentally swallow
a piece
then you might consider the risk
likelihood being low
in a complex system the metaphor can
also be taken in a couple directions
for example if realizing the risk
requires highly specialized knowledge
tools preconditions then the likelihood
might be considered low
alternatively if you consider to be to
have the overall system be complex
various prone to various types of
failures
and have a larger attack surface then
you might actually consider the
likelihood high
so what does using this methodology look
like
as a bunch of potential outcomes well
for those who are more visual learners
here is basically a table of all the
potential outputs
and if you find the intersect here with
low severity
medium scope and high likelihood we find
that we have a medium impact
with a little bit of practice you can
pretty much do this in your head
and if the impact ever feels overstated
or understated
it's a good indicator that one of your
inputs was improperly assessed
but sometimes risks are more complicated
and in those cases it's important to
contextualize your risk impact
and state the assumptions you've made as
a side note
if your severity scope or likelihood is
none
your impact is always none
so here's how i suggest you use the ipa
triad properties
um i suggest you use them to inform risk
severity
via the infrared data sensitivity
um this should be somewhat intuitive
here but an example of something i would
consider to be a
high identity sensitivity could be like
biometrics
uh video footage that sort of thing um
i'll move on for time's sake though
let's go into some exact use cases
where i found the ipa triad to be
helpful
developer apis so
there is a lot of different ways to
authorize users
i'm going to loosely describe what it
means to be an oauth provider
but i'll let you know the same
principles can be applied elsewhere
now developer apis basically provide
third-party access to user data and
typically through resources that allow
you to either create
read update or delete records
and historically at least from what i've
seen most companies usually consider
read to be the least sensitive
permission since create
update and delete are really the primary
targets for attackers to cause
operational disruption to you for your
users
um these would be like integrity or
availability attacks
um but this laid-back approach is how
you get yourself into a cambridge
analytica situation where attackers are
actually using your
read apis to silently slurp up user data
for their own malicious uses and when
you're not careful in this regard
it's really hard to walk back from
without thoughtful assessments and
long-term api deprecation roadmaps
where users end up at risk until the
apis change
which can take a while so it's better to
design it right up front
this is what the typical authorization
process looks like
but the important thing to note is that
a user can grant multiple permissions
in addition each permission can grant
access to numerous developer api
resources
each with varying sensitivity
so what i recommend you do if you're
building out your own developer apis
is that you really assess the resources
that you're providing
using the risk assessment methodology i
described to better understand the
privacy risk to your users
and this is a great opportunity to
review other risks as well like
financial or operational
or abuse and once you've done that
you can pretty much just generate a
spreadsheet formula to
calculate your aggregate risk
sensitivity
across resources to really tell you what
a permission scope's risk is
but i do stress that it's important to
take a step back
and look at the bigger picture revealed
by all the data
does one resource have a low identity
sensitivity
but another one have a high identity
and together do they allow really strong
correlations
that now expose a strongly identified
individual's presence or activities
these can be really useful insights as
well
then i recommend you de-risk your
platform by applying the principle of
least privilege to your users data
um you can take a permission scope that
gives you access to way too many
sensitive resources
and break it into useful sub permissions
and what's really important is even if
you can't meaningfully change your
permission structure what you should
really stress
to do is to make sure that you're
communicating the sensitivity of
permissions
to your users when they are granting
other parties access to them
because a lot of times um users just
click yeah sure i'll allow it i want the
thing to happen
and they don't really understand what
what data access they're providing
let's talk about device sensors another
use case
but before we do that let's borrow
another security concept
side channel attacks and this is where
you can use
information to make inferences about
sensitive data based on
how you understand the device to work
so let's take a look at a few examples
to see what kinds of information we can
glean from raw
high fidelity sensor data well
smart watch style heart rate monitors
from an identity perspective
they don't really return a lot of unique
interesting information
like something that would directly
measure the heart
so that you can't really tell if anybody
has like a heart abnormality like a
murmur etc
but from a presence perspective the fact
that you have a pulse is a pretty high
sign that there is uh
somebody on the other end of that device
and also during physical exertion heart
rate is known to go
up so a lot of these things are
advertised as activity monitors and so
yes you you can get the activity
information from these readings
gps um if these are on all the time
chances are the owner is going to return
to their home
so that's a pretty identifiable piece of
information
sometimes addresses are listed in public
records
um if the device hasn't moved in a while
it may not actually be
a good signal of whether or not there's
a human present
but if it's moving chances are there's a
human attached to it
now if the device is known to be
somewhere
like a restaurant a gym a shopping mall
a place of worship maybe an adult
bookstore
or a healthcare clinic you might be able
to infer some kind of activities of that
person
so from an activity perspective this
data is interesting as well
air quality sensors well these ones are
interesting because they don't tell you
a whole lot about someone's identity
maybe a stretch but maybe someone with a
lot of perfume
might trip the volatile organic compound
sensors
but i think that's you know who can say
without actual testing
um depending on placement they can
actually pick up human movements pretty
well
based on like an unusual disturbance of
patterns
um in what you're seeing in the ambient
environment
otherwise you might have to infer
presence via other activity
now air quality sensors are interesting
in that they can react significantly to
activities like
opening a door or window or cooking a
meal on the stove
or taking a shower or lighting a
cigarette so
they do expose some information that i
think most people wouldn't guess
so what do we do to protect sensor data
well
you get creative and you you think about
what you could possibly do with the raw
information
there's a lot of research out there
about how you can use
hardware sensors for various purposes
check it out even if the implications
haven't reached your product domain yet
so the most important thing i think you
can do
is to isolate processing so the data
never leaves the device
that way you fully minimize your data
exposure risk
but what's also important too is that
the user knows
under what circumstances data does leave
their device
and give them control over it i think
there's a lot of people who don't trust
microphone
embedded devices and perceive them to be
always recording
even if they're just keeping a local
stored buffer
and occasionally sending relevant pieces
to the cloud
i think that there's a lot of
expectations users have about
stuff that stays on devices that just
isn't fully there yet
um if you can't do everything on device
the
the next best thing you can do is
degrade the signals much as
usably possible to minimize inferences
of other activities or important
information
so going back to something like a radar
sensor like
wi-fi that's really interesting because
you can basically get a good
3d picture of the world around you and
so something you can do that's helpful
is you can instead of returning
continuous data
maybe you return information at more
discrete intervals
that make it harder to tell exact
movements
and so that can decrease your activity
sensitivity from that data
um other things you can do is you can
let's say
return less precise data so can
something like um a radar sensor um
be sent at like a lower resolution
or some less precise amount um and that
way you couldn't see someone's body
shape
which might be an indicator of their
identity if you already know that about
them
so yeah you can definitely minimize
identity sensitivity from that data as
well by
by obfuscating these characteristics
through introducing noise or removing
precision
um one example i'm just blown away with
uh
how location tracking still works today
when it comes to gps in particular
um so many people don't really need to
share anything beyond their zip code
in order for apps to localize but for
the most part
when people consent to share their
location it's giving very precise
coordinates and
risk has not been minimized yet in the
degree it should be
well what else can we do with this data
that's all the time we have for today
but there's probably a bunch of projects
where applying the ipa triad might be
helpful for you
if you end up doing something really
interesting let me know it would really
make my day
if you have a question about these
slides or a project you want to discuss
feel free to reach out and thank you