hi
my name is nicole fern i'm a senior
hardware security engineer for tortuga
logic
and i'm really excited to be here
virtually with all of you to talk about
how hardware can be a double-edged sword
for security
one of the main messages of this talk is
that hardware now more than ever
is essential to consider in the context
of security
if you plot the number of cves that
have the word hardware in them over the
years you'll see
a definite trend of increasing focus
on hardware as a place where attackers
are looking for vulnerabilities
and this is because hardware is truly a
double-edged sword
it's relied upon as a trust anchor but
also can open systems up to
attack
a key question in all of this is who
wields the sword
whose responsibility is it to secure
hardware
hardware is not designed in a vacuum the
hardware system is global
it's complex it involves many different
countries and organizations and all of
them have different motivations when it
comes to
hardware security and this is what makes
securing hardware incredibly challenging
so to start with i want to talk a little
bit more in detail
about how hardware can be used to
protect a system
and over the course of the next few
slides we'll see that
while hardware security features are
fantastic
to include as protection for a larger
system
to provide any security at all these
security features have to be implemented
configured and used correctly
which is not always straightforward
hardware is a natural choice to be used
as a trust anchor
because hardware can provide services
such as cryptographic acceleration
secure storage in the form of one-time
programmable memory
and a whole host of other things that
are difficult if not impossible to
provide using just software alone
we're seeing a definite trend towards
using
hardware subsystems that consolidate
all of these security services and
security functionality
into into one ip core that's that's can
be sold to
anyone developing a system on chip
commonly abbreviated as
soc these roots of trust are subsystems
focused exclusively on security
and what they provide to in an soc
designer
is the ability to kind of optimize the
security subsystem for security
and then leave the remaining portions of
the system
open to being optimized for things like
performance
and so while this is you know great that
we have dedicated
ip being sold for security specifically
um one thing to keep in mind is that you
know it's not enough just to buy one of
these hardware routes of trust from for
example rambus
or synopsis and just instantiate it in
your design and assume
you are secure
purchasing and using security ip is kind
of
like buying a gate to secure your house
in this picture shown on the slide you
know
the gate isn't providing any security
because you can just walk through the
lawn and circumvent it
but that's not to say that in a
different system in a different house in
a different context that same gate
might provide adequate security in a
lawn with for example a fence or a wall
surrounding it
and this is similar to what what
has to be true to secure an soc of
course the security of an soc depends on
the security of the hardware logic
itself specifically the the root of
trust logic
but additionally it's highly dependent
on the
hardware configuration and integration
of
of that ip into the larger system and
also it's dependent on how software
uses and configures security features
and this is can be complex to analyze in
the context of an entire system because
vulnerabilities hide in design
complexity
and interaction between different system
components
the cisco secure boot hardware tampering
vulnerability is a great example
of a route of trust that was improperly
integrated into a larger system
cisco used an fpga to provide
you know the trust anchor for their
entire device the entire router
however the bitstream fpga the fpga
bitstream
which completely controls the
functionality of the fpga
was stored unprotected in spyflash and
could be modified by an attacker
the flash region was not protected from
privileged software rights
from the application cpu and it also
wasn't encrypted so it's fairly
easy for an attacker to you know
overwrite
the bitstream to accomplish their own
functionality which had the consequence
of
completely bypassing secure boot or
defeating
secure boot which is one of the main
security services
this route of trust was providing for
the router
earlier i mentioned complexity and one
thing that
makes hardware complex is that it's
highly configurable
hardware needs to be configurable for
both flexibility reasons and also
fixability reasons
if you can imagine once once a hardware
design
enters the physical world as silicon
it's really really difficult
almost impossible to edit that that
functionality
right once once the um silicon you know
is
taped out then that's it if you find a
problem or a security vulnerability
with the hardware design itself you have
to work around it
using things like microcode patches or
firmware patches
another option for providing
configurability and hardware
is is registers one common design
practice is to use something called
chicken bits chicken bits are kind of a
special type of configuration register
they are undocumented bits on a device
that can be able
then that can be used to disable certain
functional security features
or more generally any feature
so why would someone include chicken
bits in their design
it provides the hardware designer
the opportunity to chicken out of using
a particular feature if a bug in the
silicon
in that feature is later discovered
but clearly this has security
implications
and ramifications
so the configuration space of hardware
grows exponentially with design
size and this can make it really
difficult to determine the impact of
a specific configuration on security
you know imagine you're trying to write
the firmware for
a hardware component that has 100
configuration bits
it's it's really difficult to determine
okay which bits
influence security which bits influence
functionality and to get it right
and it's made even harder if the default
values
for those configuration bits and the
registers
lead to an insecure configuration and
that's exactly what happened in this bmc
vulnerability
and that the default configuration
resulted in
the host cpu having arbitrary access to
the bmc's entire memory space
so to mitigate this vulnerability the
firmware had to be updated to
change the default configuration and
secure
the device
the debug infrastructure is another
example of
hardware that's typically configurable
and also has an
impact on the overall security posture
of the device
nail gun is a vulnerability that
shows how certain insecure
configurations of arm's multi-core debug
infrastructure can lead to
privilege escalation that doesn't
require physical access to the device so
in
arm's multi-core debug model one core
can be used as a debug host for another
core
and so that's in contrast to the
traditional debug model where
the debug host is always an external
debugger
connected physically to the chip
this vulnerability can be prevented by
setting these four configuration signals
correctly
but how however the authors of the nail
gun paper they noticed or
they noted that a lot of devices that
they looked at
were set in the insecure configuration
and
they guessed this is because it severely
restricts the
debug functionality if you put it in the
secure configuration so a lot of
device vendors chose to just make it
more flexible
more usable more convenient but
ultimately
insecure another important point
that this paper brings up is that there
are a lot of different
parties involved that make decisions
that influence security so for this
specific example
arm provides the four signals in the
architecture the debug architecture
but then it's up to the soc vendor
such as qualcomm who buys processors
from arm and incorporates them
into their chip they control how
their customers set these
for debug signals whether they're
through fuses or through configuration
registers or just hard coded that's up
to the soc manufacturer
and so their customers in the mobile
device ecosystem this would be the
people making mobile phones such as
samsung or google they buy
chip from qualcomm and then it's up to
them to set
fuses at the factory to the correct
values or
in their firmware stack write secure
values to
the configuration registers
so it's pretty clear that security
requires alignment across
many stakeholders many companies and
countries are involved in creating and
using silicon chips and it's not easy to
point to
any individual stakeholder and say you
know you
are solely responsible for security
so we've talked about how hardware
security features have to be configured
and used correctly to provide security
but now i want to shift gears and talk
about
other hardware features that have
nothing to do with security
but make systems vulnerable to attacks
i like to call this class of this class
of issue
when functional features become security
problems
there's a lot of complexity in modern
hardware designs
which comes from you know really
really demanding requirements for
performance from
consumers we expect our devices to
be extremely energy efficient responsive
and always connected and to do this
you know hardware designers have had to
innovate a lot and that's where you
you get things like direct memory access
speculation
etc etc and unfortunately these
these functional performance features
aren't always designed with security in
mind
a great example of this is dynamic
voltage and frequency scaling
dvfs is ubiquitous it's critical for
energy efficiency
what it is essentially is it's you know
mechanism that allows software to manage
the power consumption of the device so
it can both
modify and monitor power consumption and
it's good to do this because the the
operating system
especially knows the workloads running
on the device they know what
applications are running and how much
power they need so it's ideal for the
operating system to
control power consumption but this has
the consequence that an operating
the operating system can lower the
voltage increase the frequency and
inject
faults during computation this is
extremely relevant
if you are relying on a trusted
execution environment such as intel
sgx or arm trust zone to protect you
against a potentially malicious
operating system
being able to monitor power consumption
from software also
has implications for security the
platypus attacks showed
that using the interfaces for
monitoring power that are available to
unprivileged software
you can perform a power side channel
attack capable
of recovering aes keys kernel as their
offsets
with no physical device access required
and
and that's that's pretty significant
because typically when you think of
fault injection
and power side channel attacks you
assume that the attacker has to have
physical access to your device
speculative and out of order execution
is another great example
of functionality added for performance
reasons
that is not transparent at all
to the programmer's view of the
processor
which that was you know that was okay
until the discovery of spectre and
meltdown
and then speculative execution
micro architectural features were front
and center with respect to
security and you know it's unfortunate
that those features are
so opaque because
you know not only addressing spectre and
meltdown didn't
involve only the processor vendors it
didn't involve
only companies like intel amd
and arm it required a lot of
a lot of involvement and contribution
from the software community as well
especially people developing compiler
tool chains and operating systems
all of these groups had to work together
to come up with mitigations in a timely
manner for
spectre and meltdown
so now that i've talked about all of the
issues in hardware security all of the
challenges in
in the final few moments of this talk i
want to present some solutions
the first of which is industry-wide
hardware security initiatives this
category of solutions
really is to address the challenge that
security requires alignment between all
the different stakeholders in the
hardware ecosystem
and so to foster alignment and
communication
you know you need these public
initiatives that
involve dozens and dozens of companies
that are all contributing and working
together
and i've listed a few of these on this
slide if you're interested
another solution that can be implemented
by an individual company or organization
is something called a
hardware security development lifecycle
so this is for people who are designing
hardware
and this addresses the challenge that
security issues can arise at different
design stages so the idea is that you're
going to
as an organization dedicate resources to
addressing security throughout
the entire hardware development life
cycle and by addressing it early on and
consistently you're going to reduce risk
and this is a good idea for
organizations to
implement but it's it's easier said than
done there's a lot of technical
challenges
and this is where i believe that
technical solutions can really play a
major role in making this
feasible for companies to implement
under really intense
time to market pressure and resource
constraints
so one technical solution to this
problem
i would like to bring up is hardware
information flow analysis
this is the technology that i work with
on
a daily basis so if you have any
questions or this is something of
interest to you please come and speak
with me
after the session a major
problem that i see when people try to do
security verification pre-silicon
is that information flow is not a
first-class concept in the existing
tools
which makes it really really awkward and
really high effort
to first off capture confidentiality and
integrity requirements which are so
central to security
it's hard to capture those requirements
in a way
that you can actually verify in the
context of your design implementation
so if you employ something like hardware
information flow tracking
this streamlines the whole process and
just makes it easier to specify and
verify
security requirements and hardware and
again i'd be happy to talk with anyone
after the session about this
so we've seen that there are a lot of
requirements for securing hardware
you know first because hardware is a
double edged sword
if you have security features
implemented in hardware that's great but
these features have to be
implemented configured and used
correctly
the other side of the coin is that
features
added in hardware to increase
performance and usability
really need to be considered from a
security perspective
you you can't just design functionality
and assume that
it's isolated from security because it's
you know hard to really argue that
anything is really isolated from
from security and lastly security
requires alignment across
many different stakeholders and there's
just many different groups of people
involved in securing hardware besides
just the people
designing the hardware
and so with that i would like to leave
all of these different groups and
stakeholders with some questions to
think about after the talk
if you're an ip provider or soc vendor
you know what is your security strategy
do you have a security strategy
are you applying the same methodologies
from functional verification to security
and are you struggling you know so
please come and talk with me after the
session
also how are you communicating security
with those using your hardware or ip
is it easy for your customers to use
your
your hardware in a secure way or do they
have to read through
500 pages of documentation to get it
right
if you are an oem or systems builder do
you understand how hardware can affect
your threat model
and do you know how to configure and use
the hardware in your device correctly
and lastly if you're a software
developer
you should be asking yourself are you
considering hardware in your threat
model do you need to be considering
hardware in your threat model
and this is because you know in the
the past few years we've seen attacks
that were thought to require physical
access to the device for example
fault injection and side channel
analysis these attacks are being
performed
from software which has imp implications
if
for example you are deploying something
in the public cloud
where there can be other tenants that
share the hardware at the same time
that your software is running so with
that
you know i'll leave you with the the
parting message that
you know hardware is truly a
double-edged sword and we
all wield it together and i would be
happy to take questions now
you