hi everyone my name is sophia silly and
i'm a researcher and implementer of
cryptography and classroom
my job focuses on implementing and
theoretically thinking about
cryptography and computer science
but i also think about intersection
between privacy and security
and what users actually face as a threat
in the real world
today i'm going to be precisely talking
about a topic related to the latter
in the sense that the topic that i'm
going to be speaking about is how
digital tools i use to enhance
gender-based violence this is indeed a
pro topics that covers many axioms
but has mainly been talked about from a
global north perspective
today my aim is to bring you the global
cell perspective
specifically the latin american
perspective as the way digital tools are
used to harm people should not be
thought of as it is applied equally to
all but rather as a phenomenon that
is intersected by many other factors the
way that it is not truly used to enhance
gender-based violence in the global
north
is not the same as what happens in the
global south
a small disclaimer for this talk i will
be talking about
instances of domestic abuse sexual
violence
and discrimination in general if at any
point you feel uncomfortable during the
talk
please feel free to stop the video or
leave the video
in general please reach out to someone
and make yourself feel safe
your mental health is important so
please take care of it
we'll also like to say that this talk is
dedicated to anyone who has experienced
gender-based violence
in general and it's a call to action for
us all who make digital tools to think
about it when we design
systems or applications for us to build
a digital world where this does not
happen
or at least it's not enhanced
this talk is also a remanded reminder
that we can work together to change the
situation
if it sounds difficult or it sounds too
sad
in latin america we have achieved change
by working together and asking for this
change
we as women have united and that's what
exchange we have not been aided by
governments of big corporations or big
organizations
we have actually achieved change by
protesting together by marching together
and by actually achieving the change
together so if we can do it as women in
latin america you can also
you can also ask for this change and
actually make it happen
so how can we start this talk where does
one begin
one of the things that i didn't realize
more than a year ago when this research
is started
is that there's not so much research
around the mother as there is research
on other topics
the reasons for this could be many but
one of the top ones could be that the
thinking that digital tools are used to
enhance gender-based violence
is not approved they think that this is
not a pervasive phenomenon
or because the bibles appear to not
appear so publicly
this is not to shame that survivor
should appear more publicly but actually
to note that maybe that is one of the
reasons why research
is not so focused on this area for me
this research came from a personal
experience because i was suffering from
gender-based violence that was aided by
digital tools from this personal
experience it became a shared experience
because friends of mine were actually
experiencing the same
it became their community experience
because the local organizations i reach
out to all the women's organizations
that i reach out to
were actually experiencing the same and
i later found out that this is a global
situation because it happens in every
country
and in every region of the world and in
many countries it has actually been
declared as a pandemic as it happened in
mexico
in my case it was a recruit usage of
digital tools to enhance gender-based
violence
as i was warned that my ex-father might
try to saw more in my devices
but it was a subtle one as well as he's
revealed my social media posts to try to
find any hidden meaning
that could be used to discredit me or
harm my reputation
through this he managed to make me lose
my job indeed
and it is in this way we should take
notice digital jews used enhanced
gender-based violence are not
technologically sophisticated most of
the times
there are sort of in the realm that they
we think that is not so much of a big of
a deal
but it is indeed
gender-based violence is the first cause
of death of women all over the world
in countries like mine because i come
from ecuador in ecuador every 71 minutes
a woman is killed for being a woman
we like to emphasize here that they are
killed actually for being a woman
because most of the times when i speak
about this sentence or
or people read this sentence they think
that women are killed because they were
trying to get mocked or any other reason
but indeed they are keen because they
are women and i would like to emphasize
here that this is not a problem that
only exists in the global north
but also exists in the global south must
be even more pervasive in the global
south
i would like to say here also that
digital tool was used to enhance
gender-based violence
it's not a problem only of the global
nodes even though in a global node of
course people
may be using more digital tools than
your global cell
but gender but digital tools used to
enhance gender-based violence
it's also happening in the global cell
with differences yes
but it's also happen
i said there is research around how
digital tools are used to enhance
gender-based violence
but it mostly focuses in global north
and scenarios what he focuses on and has
found is that gender-based violence
through digital tools happens
by the usage of mobile and social
engineering it is well noted in the
social engineering part
it is a sort of social engineer in the
sense that is not rampant on
active cohesion but rather the gathering
of information to guest passwords or any
kind of way that they can
think about to access the accounts of
survivors for example
we will compare this later point to how
it actually happens in the global south
so what is the state in the global south
specifically in latin america
after briefly listening to what the
research has already done in the global
north
will we find the same results with the
same techniques applied
to the latin american region
the first thing to know around this
question is that there are not so much
research
there is local research from local
organizations or what can be gathered
from the experience of our blessed
bibles themselves
this is our main source for our ongoing
research what we find out is that there
are specific ways in which digital tools
are used
and we try to come up with a methodology
ways to classify them in order to
further explain them
why we try to come up with a methodology
because when we actually start
researching about this we found out that
there was not so much
literature around how to actually
classify the different ways in which
digital tools and used to
enhance gender-based violence actually
expressed
this is what we will explore through the
next slides from the tears of the
survivors themselves
the first classification is of course
sexual violence as this is the most
prevalent use of violence
aided by digital tools a 22 years old
woman recollected
they sent photos of me intimate photos
to the whatsapp that we have as a group
at the university they took those photos
without
me wanting them to i have attached here
also the spanish text
because most of the times people think
that these things do not actually
actually exist so they don't think the
digital tools are used to enhance in
their base balance
at all so i'm actually attaching here
actual tales from actual survival
so you all think that this indeed is
happening
in this tale we see here two instances
of digital tools
an instance of taking a photo in a
non-consensual way and an instance of
massively sharing it over social media
this situation can be thought of as a
trivial one as is often referred to
but it is not taking a photo in a
violent way and later saying it is
reenacting
the violent act gets committed again
every time the photo is shared
another woman tells and at first on this
slide i have attached the spanish text i
will see here in the next
slide the english text the translation
she says
i don't know who's read me i don't know
who it was they sent me messages threats
against my family they say they were
going to talk
about me that they were going to tell
them who i really was
they asked me for explicit photos and
videos and i sent them to them
the photos and the video reached out
everyone everyone at my school
i felt bad and i can't talk to anyone
she was at the time a 15 years old
student
this tale plays into many aspects of the
region the first thing is of course the
cohesion
the survivor was not sharing something
willingly but was forced to
because society in general is disforcing
the attacker knew quite well that she
would not want to tell her family about
her private life
because it is shameful to be found as a
woman that you have any kind of sexual
desire
whether you are a sexual being at all
therefore she complace
she complied because it was easier than
facing the misogynistic society
there's a common stereotype that women
in latin america are hot
or sexually liberated or dressed
provocatively in a free way
the reality could not be further from
the truth that in american societies
could be very misdemestics
and play into the idea that women's
sexuality is private
and if it becomes public it is the cause
of shame
abusers use this notion to cohese women
in a blatant way
in the sense that if a relationship
lends for example
they will share any photo over social
media they use this to punish women for
leaving a man
to publicly suppose that she's a sexual
being one of the tactics that we use
with women that we work with
that experience this is to tell them
that having the photos
bus maybe it's not such a bad thing and
that maybe the best thing is that if
they own that narrative
this of course is just a band-aid of a
huge problem a problem of misogyny aided
by the massive way in which private
borders can be leaked a woman that
committed suicide in brazil after having
the photos leaked
said excuse me if i wasn't the perfect
daughter
the school paseo now fearfully perfecter
to her parents she said this after
having her photos were
publicly exposed she said it's not
because she was being irreverent
but because she was sad of the shame
that she was putting her family
on a shame that she'd not wanted nor she
intended nor she cost
this quote is taken from a study that is
linked later on talk
the natural question to ask here is then
how is this media share how are these
videos and photos actually share
there's a prevalence in latin american
facebook and whatsapp groups where these
photos are actually shared
and actively shared men's groups or
matching clubs in a way where men rang
themselves around how many photos they
can share
or who has the best video who has the
best photo
on the other hand sexual violence is
also prevalent
and is also used to intimidate women
that are public it is a common thing
that photos of male genitalia are sent
to public figures that are women
it is also a common thing the creational
hashtags that instigate violence against
women such as
sinata golpiano diamond if he doesn't
beat you he doesn't love you
you might being a misogynistic beautiful
golfer when you're your woman if she's a
what happens when women are public and
own their narratives their sexuality
their feminism
their struggle we have seen a little bit
already on how attacks
actually happened then but let's explore
them more in depth right now
a woman recollects they have advised me
not to be a feminist so public
this is a common unwanted advice that is
often given
when a woman is open about a struggle or
about being a feminist or about in
general just being public at all
and this advice means that if you're
public you are the subject of shame
you're the subject of violent acts
so how does this shame happen women get
shamed by targeted social media messages
by head speech by sending up sexual
imagery
and by much more in many instances we
have even discovered that there are
groups that teach
how to do this and how regular meetings
about this
they have worshipped with these this
worship that actually
they actually list who kind of public
profiles
women they have they should actually
target and what is the best strategy to
actually target this women
in the case of moa mobile is only used
by vms in the case of a high public
profile figure that is a woman
as governments are the ones who know how
to buy the broadway
and have the economic prostitution to
actually buy the kind of malware
we have seen this in almost any latin
american government that has actually
bought
more way from finfisher or the hacking
team
the results of these threats that are
actually more public and happening over
social media or by the usage of malware
actually escalate physical violence that
can be
um it can result in physical violence of
the death of the victim in this case
this is different to what happens in the
global now
not because the situation of escalation
to actually physical violence and not so
common in the global north as it is so
common in the global salt
what happens in the private sphere in
the private sphere the scene is not so
different
as what we have already seen the usage
of digital tools to enhance gender-based
violence is again not a solar one
it is one that is on the face abusers
here in this region do not try to guess
the passwords but
actively ask for the victims of
survivors
to actually say the passwords themselves
because men feel entitled to be asking
for these kind of things
or they take the devices for victims to
isolate them
which denies them the access to
communication to education or to have
digital literacy
during the covet 19 pandemic most of the
latin american governments chose to
solve the education problem
by using digital tools it was deeply
ineffective as many households do not
have access to several devices that can
be used in order to access education
or to access to remote work but it was
really worse in the case of women
because it was
prioritized that manchester us should
have the access to people but these
devices are not women
which is better the the gap of women are
actually achieving the status of being
digital literate
latin america is one of the regions that
have the lowest rate of
of people being digital literate it is
the lowest among women as handling
technology is often thought of a
commercial
and women are often discouraged from
having devices or even attending
computer related events
such as attending university studies or
workshops or in general attending a new
workshop
any kind of event that focuses on
teaching women
how to operate devices or computers or
being safe or
online in the case
in this case specifically women do not
often realize that many of these
tactics that men use are actually
violence because
being in a misogynistic society if you
think that this is the normal way that
men should act they think that men
should be listened to
that this is what normally happens but
this is how a relationship should be
when a man in a relationship takes the
devices from the woman from her partner
from her panel in their relationship
they think that this is a common ground
and the men
actually are entitled to do this they
think this because they think that they
are aiding a man that they are being
strong with a complicated person
that they are helping a man that might
have any other psychological problems so
therefore should be listened to
this is what actually happens and it
happened also in my case
so what is the future what can we
actually do
the first thing is that we should
actually
change the way in which we think about
research we need research that takes
into account the scenarios from
different countries
and from different regions and that
research that does not only focus on
more malware
i know that more that they actually
study on mobile is actually
fascinating because it could be
technologically more challenging than
only thinking about how to solve social
media
but more well as we have seen is
actually not the main problem in many
places we should also ask social media
platforms
to do better in other countries besides
the global north because what actually
happens is that when we raise concern
to certain social media organizations
about an
ongoing attack against women or a
survivor who is right now
facing some kind of violence in her
usage of social media
is that these concerns are not actively
listened to well in the global know
sometimes this
is actually listened to because accounts
do take do
do get taken down or social medias get
actually or social media accounts can
actually get
shut down well when this happens from
some countries from the global south
this actually does not happen
when i was researching about this we i
also researched around
the state of the privacy laws in
different latin american countries
and i was really surprised that most of
the privacy laws that actually exist in
these countries
do not take into account experiences of
women of what they are actually
experiencing online
and this should actually be we actually
compare we should actually compel them
to actually
include in the privacy laws because this
is an experience that is actually
actively happening in
at least half of the population
we should actually rethink how the
sharing of intimate media
should be actually happening over social
media
or over any other kind of media we
should actively
create platforms platforms that actually
allow users to securely and privately be
sharing this
intimate image
and with this i would like to end this
talk with a little bit more a happy note
in the sense that i would like to
encourage again as i study this talk by
saying that if we act together we can
actually share
we can actually change this situation um
i put this up here a photo of the
of the women's march in argentina in
which one of the
main slogans were juntas which means
together in spanish this means that if
we act together we should we can
actually change
the status of what is right now
happening because this is something that
as a society and as a community that
actually develops digital tools should
be taken
into account so we together can change
things and
this not only to say that this is the
scenario and it is sad
but actually to actually ask you that
please work together and change the
situation
here are some of the resources that i
have used to actually give this talk
that you're encouraged to read
this is actually organizations that are
working around thinking about how
digital tools are used in
transgender-based violence
the first one from ecuador the
the leather one is from brazil another
one is from mexico
and here i have also attached a blog
post of my experience on how
actually i was facing the usage of
digital tools to actually enhance
gender-based violence and with this i
would like to thank you all for
listening to me
and i'm open to any questions if you
have any
so thank you
you