no data no problem
giving nuclear inspectors better tools
without revealing state secrets
twenty years ago this september two
planes flew into the twin towers in new
york city
almost eight years ago two homemade
bombs were detonated at the finish line
of the boston marathon
only a bit more than 26.2 miles away
from my own front door
both of these events were horrible acts
of terrorism but were tremendously
fortunate that neither involved a
nuclear explosive
in fact we've never had an act of
nuclear terrorism and a big part of that
is due to international cooperation to
safeguard the incredibly potent nuclear
materials
at the heart of these weapons but even
though a nuclear terror catastrophe has
never occurred
we can't stop being vigilant
the role of inspectors from the
international atomic energy agency
the iaea is always to stay ahead of
those looking to divert and misuse
nuclear material
for whatever sinister purposes they can
come up with not just nukes but also
things like dirty bombs
most of the time this is straightforward
treaties and agreements with the iaea
dictate who
what where and when the iaea can inspect
states that do not comply with these
rules risk running afoul of
international law
like the treaty on the non-proliferation
of nuclear weapons
all but four countries have signed the
treaty and on this map they're shaded in
red
signatories possessing nuclear weapons
are shaded in blue and
those without them are shaded in green
for better or worse
as sophisticated data analytics become
ubiquitous it's anticipated that states
will also be increasingly reluctant to
share anything more than the minimum
amount
of information that's required under
their safeguards agreement the iaea
this is not generally because they
intend to act illegally or make a
nuclear weapon
but rather because they wish to protect
proprietary business advantages
or sensitive state information still
while these protective stances aren't
necessarily a bad thing when it comes to
individual national security
for the vast majority of states at least
they may pose an impediment to the iaea
detecting a diversion
somewhere and that could lead to a
catastrophe
so can we devise a system that appeases
both parties
one that lets states retain high levels
of privacy while the iaea inspectors can
be notified about real deviations from
expected practice
well we're looking at the intersection
of privacy and security
where the cryptographic subfield of
secure multi-party computation becomes
applicable
if you aren't familiar with the field
secure multi-party computation
or mpc for short allows two or more
parties to jointly compute some function
of all their inputs together
while none of the parties learns
anything about the input of any other
party
beyond what's implied by the result it
sounds a bit like magic
but i assure you it's computationally
sound
the idea of npc has its roots in the
late 1970s and early 1980s and i'll
largely be focusing here on one class of
npc algorithms called garbled circuits
credited to the cryptographer andrew yao
in the 1980s
yao presented what he called the
millionaires problem two millionaires go
out to dinner
agreeing that the richer one covers the
meal neither wishes to disclose their
true net worth
so they devise an algorithm to indicate
who's paying and nothing else
there was more formulation in
mathematical theory that was developed
through the 1990s
and by the early 2000s software was
being written to actually implement
these algorithms
as computing power has grown the
abilities of software implementations
have grown with them
with mpc really only entering the scene
as a practical technology in the past
decade
a couple examples are privacy preserving
cryptocurrencies like zcash
or an anonymous study on gender wage
gaps by boston university in 2015.
covet 19 contact tracing has also
recently spiked an interest in these
algorithms too and so with all this
development
we decided to try applying npc to our
own safeguards problem
at the most basic level we were asking
the following questions
what can we actually do with mpc which
specific safeguards problems would
lend themselves to it what types of data
could we analyze
and why isn't this already being
deployed
let's start with this first question the
key insight about yao's garbled circuits
and subsequent evolutions of them is
that they can handle literally
any calculation that might be performed
by multiple parties
if you can program a computer to do it
you can build a circuit to do it too
and i'll come back to this in a bit as
far as what data we could use well we
decided that an interesting exercise
would be using mpc to analyze the output
of detectors like
those relied on by iaea inspectors
since every radioactive isotope think
flavor of an element
produces a unique radiation signature
measuring these emitted radioactive
particles
can tell an inspector exactly how much
nuclear material
and what types are in a location this
plot of the spectra produced by uranium
ore
serves as a good illustration you can
see the distinct spectral peaks
each one where the detector measured
many radioactive particles with the same
energy
and while none of these peaks actually
corresponds to the radiation from
uranium itself
they do come from a cocktail of
radioactive particles that's really only
produced in this observed ratio
by uranium ore taking this idea further
perhaps if we could watch the output of
a detector over time we could flag
measurements with radioactive signatures
for nuclear materials that are
proliferation risks
this is what the iaea inspectors and
data analysts already do
but with mpc we could do it obliviously
we'd learn nothing else about the
material compositions that are picked up
by the detector
which brings us back to the third
question
why hasn't anyone done this yet well
on one hand the technical requirements
of npc mean that only very recently have
off-the-shelf computer systems been able
to handle privacy-preserving
computations
of what i would truly consider data
analytics
additionally the iaea is necessarily
incredibly risk-averse
you can't ride the cutting edge without
taking risks
and when it comes to nuclear security
losing bets are not acceptable
the iea has to ensure that every
technology put into practice
is guaranteed to work often times this
also means deployed technologies are
customized to be extra secure
and extra resilient the ieee's
technology tends to be tried and true
not latest and greatest and finally
nuclear safeguards is a small field on a
constrained budget
the pool of expertise is pretty limited
and unlike a lot of tech fields
nuclear safeguards isn't a money maker
that means that the technical overlap
between nuclear fields and
the latest in cryptography is just
pretty small
now before i show you what we
accomplished i want to take a few
minutes to explain how npc actually
works
it's super cool but i told you it wasn't
magic and so i'm going to have to back
that up
you may have learned at some point that
any calculation your computer can do can
be performed
using a digital logic circuit this
circuit here
shows a simple calculation is bit a
the circuit's input wire on the top left
greater than
less than or equal to bit b the input
wire on the bottom left
by adding gates the circuit can be
scaled up to do almost anything
real numbers are reduced to binary and
every addition subtraction
multiplication division square root
modulus exponential you name it
is represented using a complex system of
logic gates
not and or and the like
garbled circuits build on this
foundation let's look at the two-party
case
to keep the focus on safeguards we'll
say one party is a nuclear facility
and the other is the iaea our two
parties agree on a function to compute
for simplicity let's imagine a function
that tells us if the two parties have
picked different numbers
from just the small set of integers 0
through 3.
since our circuit will work in binary we
convert our integer possibilities to
base 2
and get 0 0 0 1 1 0
and 1 1. we see that we have two bit
inputs
for each party each party has two
input wires to the circuit and the
party's integers are only the same if
each bit
in each input is the same the gate that
gives a one
only when the bits are identical is the
xnor gate
you can see that on this truth table
here we have two of these xnor gates one
for each pair of bits
then since both pairs of bits have to be
the same
an and gate gives us an output value of
1 only when both of the xnor gates
confirm a match
now this is all relatively
straightforward and we can see all the
bits clear as day
however we need the circuit to be
garbled
let's imagine that the facility goes
through this circuit and replaces the
two values on each wire with two random
strings that only they know
starting with the first xnor gate we
replace the 0
and 1 on the first input wire then 0 and
1 on the second input wire
and finally zero and one on the output
wire
we repeat this process for the second
xnor gate
and finally one last time for the and
gate
after the labels are added we can still
see the pattern from before
but that's the only thing that tells us
whether a label corresponds to a zero or
a one
next the facility uses the input wire
labels for each gate to symmetrically
encrypt the gate's output wire label
we start in the first table encrypting
the first row
then the second third and fourth the
process is the same in the other two
this produces four encrypted tokens for
each gate
one for each row in the truth table if
the facility
were to hand you one token for each of
the input wires to a gate
you could only successfully decrypt one
of the four outputs
and the only thing indicating now which
encrypted token belongs to which row
is the fact that they haven't moved from
where they started
so let's change that
now remember up until this point every
step we've seen
was performed by one party the facility
the facility knows all the labels and
what values they represent
and so they can give the labels matching
their own input values to the iaea
since the other party hasn't seen any of
this yet they don't know which random
label matches which wire value
that label is just a random string to
them
now the iaea needs to get the labels for
its own input wire values
but this presents a dilemma it can't
directly ask the facility for the label
corresponding to its bit choice
because then the facility knows that the
ieee's input is whichever one it asked
for
likewise the iaea can't be shown both
labels and the matching values because
then it will be able to
decrypt more than just one of the
encrypted rows in the truth table
we solved this using something called
oblivious transfer we'll treat it as a
black box
where the generator party can put both
labels into the box
and through an interactive process of
encryption and decryption
the iaea gets only one label of its
choice
i'll reiterate that the iaea learns only
one label and the generator
learns nothing
after executing oblivious transfer the
ieea has all the labels it needs
labels matching its own known values and
labels matching the facility's
unknown values the iaea can start
walking through the circuit
successfully decrypting only one token
for each gate
this decrypted token reveals the label
on that gate's output wire
which can then be used as a decryption
key for the next gate
again this process repeats for each gate
in the circuit
finally once the iaea has the computed
label on the circuit's output wire
it can share that label back to the
facility so that the computation result
becomes public
so now that we've covered the
fundamental cryptography let's get back
to real implementations
i told you before that we wanted to be
able to identify anomalies in radiation
spectra
effectively demonstrating that mpc
worked on safeguards data
at the same time knowing our audience of
safeguards inspectors and data analysts
we recognized that if this was ever
going to be more than just a fun idea
we needed to be able to do it in a way
that was clear and convincing
especially the folks at the iaea who
might not be at the forefront of
cryptographic research
we surveyed available npc software
frameworks and found a pretty wide range
of options available which is great
these were codes that satisfied our
obvious criteria
of being able to perform calculations
correctly while keeping data private
but all of them presented other
challenges
some were too limited in their ability
to handle a challenge of this scope
some are no longer maintained others are
commercial and
so while potentially great for a
contract down the line they're not so
great for a highly tailored demo with
full transparency
but most often the codes where
state-of-the-art research codes
designed to showcase the latest
development in the field and were just
too sophisticated for building a demo
aimed at a budget constrained inspector
with a relatively limited base of
expertise
for perspective on this last point there
was a fantastic systemization of
knowledge study
published in 2019 by researchers at the
university of pennsylvania
surveying a selection of mpc frameworks
and related tools
it estimated that learning building and
testing their selection
took 750 person hours and even then they
didn't always succeed
that's a computer science phd candidate
working for a month straight
no breaks no weekends no sleeping
and so we built a prototype of our own a
python package called cipher circuit
now i confess i'm not a cryptographer
just a nuclear engineer with a passion
for reproducible computing
our prototype evaluates circuits
successfully and securely
and while it's admittedly slow it is
highly accessible
here's a quick snapshot showing how the
whole process we just walked through
can be encapsulated in just a few lines
of python
the package is designed to be used by
anyone who understands the fundamentals
of garbled circuits
installed without any headaches and
inspected thoroughly at
every step of the circuit evaluation
process
but finally after development the time
came to begin testing garbled circuits
on
real world time series anomaly detection
data sets
now the radiation spectra that we were
looking at before
tend to be large sets of data at each
point in time one may monitor hundreds
or thousands of channels
each giving a count of how many
radioactive particles are measured in
some energy range
as you saw earlier we started smaller
looking to find a univariate time
series that we could analyze first as a
test and we settled on something outside
the safeguards realm but which i hope is
easily relatable to you all in the
audience
an electrocardiogram signal a heartbeat
here i've shown a sample of heartbeat
data sourced from the beth israel
deaconess congestive heart failure
database
it's pretty obvious just by looking at
it to see where the anomaly is
but for privacy preserving computation
we can't look at it
instead we coded up a garbled circuit to
analyze the cardiogram
one party inputs their cardiogram data
the other party inputs parameters of the
anomaly detection algorithm
and the result the garbled circuit
identified the exact location of the
anomaly
but never revealed the actual cardiogram
heartbeat
and so with this successful result we've
pushed on to something far more relevant
to nuclear safeguards
using a selection of data that was
generously shared by a team at oak ridge
national lab
working on the modeling urban scenarios
and experiments project
or muse for short we began applying
garbled circuits to time series of
radiation spectra
during february 2019 the muse team
collected radiation data from along a
stretch of road between a research
reactor and another facility inside the
lab
we knew that at some point during the
month a metal drum containing a mixture
that included a specific izotope of
protectinium
that's elemental simple pa and it has
233 protons and neutrons
was moved past a roadside detector
now this protectinium isotope decays
fairly quickly into an isotope of
uranium that could be used to build a
nuclear weapon
that uranium isotope is exceedingly rare
in the natural environment
so creating other materials that decay
into it is the only viable means of
production
so watching for the radiation signature
of the short-lived protectinium
is comparable to what an inspector might
be interested in
and so begin our blind treasure hunt
could we identify the exact date and
time when the protectinium passed the
detector
without ever actually looking at the
detector's output
i'll show you here's an animation of
just a few minutes of data collection on
one morning in late february
the animation is sped up so you won't
have to stay still quite that long
on the left is the view that a facility
might have the plot gives the radiation
spectra that was actually measured
in this case the muse data you can
hopefully see the jitter at the bottom
of the plot
that's background radiation it's
everywhere all the time
including around you right now it's low
enough that it has almost
no impact on your life but the detectors
see it
and so our algorithms must filter it out
then on the right is the view an
inspector might have using a garbled
circuit
at the top is a rough example of the
radiation signature of the protactinium
you can see a large peak at around 300
kilo electron volts
kev and a smaller peak at around 400 kev
that's what we've built the garbled
circuit to look for the lower energy
peak is less likely to show up reliably
on the detector so we're ignoring that
one
at the bottom is an indicator of whether
the data input by the facility
shows hints of pro-titanium green is
good to go
and red is an anomaly here detected at 9
19 am
it's a success now as i mentioned before
our package is fairly slow and so our
goal is to speed this up to something
approaching real time
after that ideally we move to implement
the package as a language in and of
itself
akin to most of the existing frameworks
available today where circuits can be
built as computer code
not wire by wire gate by gate like i
showed before that gets tedious
there are also some other obvious
challenges that lay in front of us
how will we deal with malicious
adversaries these participants who might
try to subvert the calculation by
not following the rules of garbled
circuits and
fortunately this is a problem that's
actually generally been solved in the
literature and so we just need to build
it into our own methods
perhaps more importantly can we prevent
parties from
spoofing their input data garbage in
garbage out as the saying goes
but adding techniques like commitment
schemes to the procedure could ensure
that when a party enters data
it becomes immutable enabling the
inspector to return and verify its
authenticity at some point in the future
if it's deemed necessary
despite these challenges i believe that
this technology is needed now more than
ever
as international relationships are
becoming increasingly strained
the ability to use trustless
privacy-preserving systems may allow us
to maintain relationships
and international cooperation around to
nuclear safeguards
hopefully they even present the
opportunity to rebuild trust between
nations that may not currently see
eye-to-eye
and so for all you nuclear inspectors in
the audience let's consider where npc
might fit into the iaea's future
operations shall we
and for anyone who's left i believe that
npc could have applications in
almost every aspect of modern life and
so i challenge you to think about where
and when you might desire privacy
preserving computation
in your own daily routine and then
i hope you'll push for mpc to go
mainstream
you