hi everyone
i'm patrick gage kelly a privacy
security
and anti-abuse researcher at google and
a person in my line of work
hears all the time that privacy is
dead you too have probably heard privacy
is dead
or at least you've heard this question
is
privacy dead in mainstream publications
and advice from ceos from venture
funders even in the academic press
but you know it isn't every time you
tell someone a secret
particularly if you expect them not to
repeat it or use it in a way that might
embarrass you
every time you write something down in a
diary or a journal
which you know a family member or a
partner could read
every time you have a thought inside
your own mind and then catch yourself
and say don't think that these are
moments
moments of privacy is trust or secrecy
or freedom and we all have them these
moments are part of being human
and the protection of these moments
where we express privacy
is part of what allows us to flourish
and yet we hear too often about how
privacy is dead
or dying enough that an idea i don't
give credence to
is something that we're going to spend
today working to understand
to explore what it would mean for
privacy to actually be dead
and deconstruct this specifically in a
quantitative way
using data from over 90 000 respondents
that we at google
have been working to understand over the
last few years
specifically we've been working with a
series of public opinion polling firms
including gfk ipsos and most recently
gallup
we did this to get the highest gold
standard sets of responses
we could from people around the world we
began in 2015 with just a few countries
and we now have responses from 29
countries on six continents
and are beginning to see often very
stable trends
year over year our survey instrument
that is the specific questions we ask
our participants
has also evolved over time with a core
of 60 items about privacy and technology
these questions range from far-reaching
opinions to their current attitudes and
to self-reported behaviors on their
engagement with specific privacy
technologies
for example let's start with a question
that we asked our respondents
i want you to think to yourself and
answer this
to think about the amount of privacy
you'll have 10 years from now
in 2031 will it be
more less or the same amount of privacy
that you have today
from the data we have we think that 49
of people expect to have more privacy in
10 years
18 expect about the same and 33
expect less privacy than they have today
that's half of the population expecting
more privacy
about one in five expecting the same and
just a third
expecting less maybe the third that
might think privacy is dead
now assuming you all the attendees of
enigma are
similar to the populations across the
couple of dozen
countries we studied you might have
thought similar responses
but we'll come back to why the enigma
audience might be a little bit different
a little bit later now
these results might seem optimistic
it might be hope that privacy regulation
can provide more data protection
it might be hope that new technologies
will keep our information
safe from unwanted and inappropriate
data use
it might just be pure optimism
even if you considered that privacy
could be more protected in some ways but
at greater risk in
others even if you tried to balance
these concerns
many of our participants data that
implies millions or billions of people
around the world
are choosing to believe that they will
have a future with privacy
this along with much of the rest of our
data confirms that people
haven't yet given up on privacy
so that's our first point today that
people are
optimistic about the privacy they will
have in 10 years
and for the rest of today's talk i'd
like to take us on a journey
through five more interesting findings
in our data
the second is that people just straight
up say
privacy is important while asking people
to forecast how much privacy
they expect to have in a decade is
interesting and a fun thought experiment
it's not the most direct measure of
how people feel about privacy today
so our first measure here is doing just
that
when we asked participants directly
saying how important is the following to
you
people told us that privacy is important
to them
very important actually we asked our
respondents this question
on a five point likert scale that means
our participants had five options
in this case extremely important very
important
moderately important slightly important
or not at all important
those last two slightly and not at all
important
are those two thin gray lines on the
right side of the bar graph
totaling just about three percent of our
global respondents
what this means is almost no one thinks
privacy isn't important to them
and across the last six years we
regularly see that these top two
categories
very and extremely important are the
choices an
overwhelming majority select that's
about 9 in 10 of our respondents
near universal support the type of
support across
countries demographics and time that we
see for
very few of our measures simply when we
ask people
if privacy is important they say it is
it's very important but of course
they're just telling us that they
believe it's important
this brings us into our first set of
sort of methodological notes about how
we do this
large survey work and these results come
with
all the caveats that are contained in
doing survey work
that means the data we're covering today
is self-reported
just like how people tell us how privacy
is important to them
to execute these global surveys means we
wrote the questions
we provided the answers and people had
to answer the questions within the
bounds of the responses we offered them
they couldn't tell us that privacy was
important in some
different or nuanced way they had to
answer it on our scale
similarly there was no way to specify
that if you think you will have privacy
more in some ways in 10 years and less
in others
you can't tell us that do you average it
and say it will be the same do you weigh
these differently
we aren't giving participants a way to
tell us more
well we built our survey instrument
iteratively over multiple years and
began with a selection of items from pew
euro barometer gallup ipsos and other
public opinion polling tools
no survey question is perfect in terms
of how respondents will read
understand and answer it or how stable
it is over time
additionally we've asked our
participants to fill out a 20-minute
survey of privacy attitudes
that may have been more time than they
normally spend thinking about privacy in
the course of a month
this may have framed their answers to
questions as they worked their way
through the survey
but even with these caveats in mind
we think these results really show how
people
are engaging with privacy our third
highlight today
is that people have a range of negative
experiences online
thinking back to our last two questions
the future
or the importance of privacy these can
feel very
abstract very opinion based but we've
also included items
that attempt to measure people's lived
experiences and the impacts of privacy
directly on people's lives one type of
impact that privacy
or most often a lack or compromise of
privacy
can have are negative experiences we've
asked our participants if they've
experienced a wide variety of negative
experiences while online
with 7 in 10 respondents across all of
the countries we surveyed
telling us they'd experienced viruses
malware or some other form of hacking
that they'd been exposed to unwanted
explicit content that they'd been the
target of a scam
phishing or some other form of identity
theft and more
on this chart we're showing a selection
of the negative experiences that people
globally have faced
and while some are relatively infrequent
i don't want to minimize the potentially
severe impacts that some of these events
can have
while not all of these may seem directly
related to privacy
in the ways we think about it within
this community our participants often
think of these events
and other events online in relationship
with how they consider the use of their
data
and their ideas of safety and privacy
also the range and forms of the negative
experiences
change based on the country as well as
demographics
particularly the participants gender
but again i just want to emphasize that
seven in ten of our respondents globally
have directly and personally felt how
their privacy and safety
have been threatened online
now i just mentioned that the negative
experiences that people have online
change based on the country
and we see that difference on several
metrics i've glossed over a lot of the
details here
and while i'm going to keep doing that
to keep this talk at a very high level
i've shown various global summaries and
the story isn't that simple even the
method of taking a global
average or reporting a single global
metric is not straightforward
we can't take this data and encapsulate
it down into a single number
that represents how people feel about
privacy around the entire world
with privacy as with most
socio-technical problems
this is a complex and nuanced space and
i don't want you to leave
this talk believing that every person or
that every group or community think of
privacy similarly
we see some very big divides between
some countries and on
certain metrics and some questions and
so now we're going to revisit the
a few of the questions we've already
explored today to see how much some of
these regions differ
thinking back to how our global summary
of people thinking about privacy in the
next 10 years
this first the top bar here is the same
data i showed earlier
where again about half of our
respondents globally think there will be
more privacy in 10 years
when we separate this out by country
though you can see that the us
ireland and france have far fewer people
responding that they think they will
have more privacy in the next 10 years
you can also see a country like thailand
which matches the global totals
almost exactly and countries like
nigeria and china
where a greater percentage of people
expect to have more privacy in the next
10 years
here we just see a lot more optimism for
privacy
and as we continue through this tour of
insights we will continue to see this
particular divergence
with a lot of optimism for privacy and
for technology
in countries that are still what we
think of as the developing world
in the fixed effect size analysis we
conducted we found
country level differences matter more
than any demographics
including age gender urbanicity and more
so again the country level and regional
differences really do have an impact on
the results that we're looking at today
however there are questions where this
isn't true as well
and so again we cannot just oversimplify
this
to where certain countries will always
behave in tandem or in unison
we also have questions like the
importance of privacy
where we see some differences here
between what percentage of
our participants and respondents
reported privacy being
very important or extremely important
but there really aren't sharp divides
here
and importantly there's no country in
our data set where we see
20 percent or even 10 percent of our
respondents saying
privacy isn't important those gray bars
never get outside of our margin of error
but this brings us back into our second
methodological break
although i just showed a couple of
graphs where i was just putting
bar charts with countries and you could
make easy visual comparisons
i want us to be really careful about
making direct between country
comparisons
apart from the general concerns of
comparing different communities
cultures and societies there are two
specific limitations that make country
comparisons a challenge
first we wrote all of the items in
english originally
and while we worked with local teams and
experts to maintain
very high levels of translation accuracy
concepts and languages
won't always directly map our
respondents
are answering different questions
secondly the panels are also different
that is
the ways we get participants to take the
survey and what we expect those
participants to be representative of
for example in nigeria which we looked
at earlier as being one of the most
optimistic places about privacy
our sample is most representative of the
online population
almost entirely consolidated in urban
areas often younger than our global
averages
we're looking at a different population
there similarly in
india and china our sample is
specifically recruited to cover a mix
based on a preset list of tier 1 and
tier 2 cities
these are both quite different ways of
recruiting participants
than for example a country like the us
where we have
almost true national representation or
in europe where we have really broad
representation in our panels
and that broad representation allows us
to do additional waiting
for example we can wait on some of the
demographic categories that we know very
well at a national level
and from our survey respondents
we take this work very seriously but
myself and the core researchers on this
project are coming from a western
viewpoint
we are all currently based in the united
states and while we worked with
colleagues in other countries
survey experts translators and local
teams we cannot fully separate out that
gaze from this work
okay now while i'd be happy to talk
about our methodological choices here
all day
and the trade-offs behind them follow up
with me after because i want to get back
to the last two insights from our data
so for the fifth feature i want to tell
a story about how our participants have
strong opinions about data use
here we asked our participants a series
of three questions
all three of these questions are about
when governments and law enforcement
should have
access to people's data the first
was if they should have access to
examine specific
data related to a specific investigation
we might think of this as a warrant or a
very focused data request
and globally we saw a split with about 6
in 10 respondents saying yes
and 4 and 10 saying no that this type of
access shouldn't be allowed
we also asked about monitoring specific
individuals suspected of wrongdoing
and again we see a very similar split
with about 6 and 10 saying
yes this type of data access can be
acceptable
even it's a little higher here and so
you might start to think
okay well about 60 percent of people
think governments and law enforcement
should have access to data
and the other 40 of participants think
that they should have none of it
but this actually isn't what we see we
asked one more
item here if monitoring all individuals
including those not suspected of
wrongdoing was acceptable
and here we see that acceptability
dropped sharply
down to about one in six globally
now i don't bring this up to focus on
the questions of government data use
but rather to show that participants and
and the people who are responding to our
surveys
are savvy enough to understand some uses
of data are okay
and there are others they aren't
comfortable with even if it's
the same types of data this again
flies directly in the face of the common
argument there's no hope for privacy
privacy is dead because all the data is
out there
what we see here is many people
reporting they want some limits and
constraints
on how data should be able to be
collected and used
the final insight i want to share today
is an exploration into how our
participants considered
the possibility of being private in
today's world
unlike the result we showed very early
on where nearly everyone thought privacy
was important
here we don't see that same broad
agreement
we see a substantial number of people
saying
privacy is possible and another group
privacy isn't possible at all we see a
plurality of respondents more than one
in three
right in the middle this means the same
people who
told us earlier that privacy was very or
extremely important to them
think it's also not necessarily simple
to achieve
and maybe some of them think it's
impossible
i don't bring this up to end with the
difficulty of achieving
privacy on this pessimistic point but
rather as a challenge we
must face as we look back over
everything we've seen today
we see that people aren't sure if
privacy is possible online
but it's important even as many see
privacy is challenging to achieve
as having limits in some cases and
having gaps where attacks and harms can
occur
we see across the world there are people
concerned about the future of privacy
and many who remain optimistic
as we reflect back on this and all of
the data that we have
i hope we've shown that people do not
want or believe that privacy is dead
but i don't think the audience here at
enigma needed me to tell you that
when we think about privacy we need to
think about both the individual moments
these privacy decisions
data accesses and challenging events
that actually impact people's lives
but also their overall attitudes and
sentiments
and we've seen that these will be
interpreted differently by people and
groups around the world
and also that people are able to
consider and opine and are willing to
engage with the subtleties of privacy
to close i believe it's our role not
only to study privacy views but to
protect people's privacy
and to do this i believe we need to
invest in three areas
one as a researcher i'm convinced we
need more deep
foundational research into both specific
privacy moments the decisions people
make and how they navigate these moments
but also research that respects and
seeks to understand the cultural
and social ways privacy manifests for
different communities
particularly those that differ from our
own often western
white or silicon valley focused
conceptions of privacy and data
we hope this talk and this data helps to
motivate
more research in this vein
second we need to invest in protections
and solutions whether technological
regulatory or simply by making our
existing systems
more usable and accessible to give
people control in some cases
but even more importantly to help them
feel there are some systems in this
world
that are designed to make the privacy
they desire feel possible
and finally we need to shift the
narrative
privacy may be struggling but we must
maintain some hope
some who claim privacy will die are
saying this to make a claim of
inevitability
because they want to own a future where
privacy is gone and they can use data
however they see fit
this isn't the only way and we must
provide alternate
more optimistic visions of how privacy
protective futures can be built
thank you all so much and i'm happy to
take questions