hi
i'm maddie stone and this is the state
of zero day in the wild exploitation
what do you think of when i say zero day
exploits it likely evokes images of
only the few most elite hackers around
the globe
targeting only the most wanted targets
you might think that these zero days
cost
so much are so hard takes so much time
to develop
that only a couple of entities have the
knowledge and resources to develop them
for the last 18 months i've studied zero
days exploited in the wild
not the theoretical or the hypothetical
but the ones actually being used against
users
as 2020 came to a close i began looking
back over all of the zero days we saw in
and started putting together my second
year in review analysis
this is not analyzing each individual
exploit
but instead taking all of those
individual analyses together
to figure out what are the trends what
are the gaps what lessons can we learn
from the preceding year to then inform
what work we do in 2021 to make zero day
harder
it became pretty clear while doing this
analysis that we
as a tech and security industry aren't
requiring the most elite skills
um for attackers to be able to exploit
zero days
but thankfully the analysis also showed
that there is low hanging fruit
that can be implemented to directly and
immediately make it harder to exploit
zero days
so let's get to it first let's make sure
we're all working from the same
definition what is a zero day exploit it
is an exploit targeting a vulnerability
that defenders don't yet know about
so it is there's no patch available
there's not mitigations to say
block this specific exploit there's not
detection signatures for your antivirus
to alert you about it
defenders don't yet know only the
attackers know
and so my work has been with google
project zero
to learn from zero days exploit in the
wild specifically to make it harder to
exploit series so grounding our work and
understanding
what are attackers actually doing rather
than what do we think they're doing
and so that's where all of this work in
this presentation comes from
and that's why i write a year in review
so
this presentation is a very quick
deep dive into what i think is the most
notable thing we can take away from zero
days exploited in 2020
and what do we do about it so i'll show
you a few different case studies showing
you
how that sort of thesis is backed up by
data
um yeah so let's get into it
from the most basic first start you know
there were 24
zero days exploited um
24 zero day x voice detected in the wild
in 2020
so that's our base level that these are
the 24 exploits that are informing this
analysis
and as i was working through each of
them um looking at them all together as
a group
the number that stuck out the most to me
was that six
out of the 24 zero days exploited in
2020 are variants of previously
disclosed vulnerabilities
they are variants of vulnerabilities
that have been reported before published
about before
seen before in previous exploits etc
so said in another way 25
of zero days from 2020 are variants of
previously disclosed vulnerabilities
they are similar you know only a few
lines change in some places
to vulnerabilities and exploits that the
industry public
knowledge knows about on top of that
three out of the 24 vulnerabilities were
incompletely patched
meaning that with just a few tweaks
you could have an exploit that still
works even after the
patch was applied so through all of this
it became pretty clear to me that what i
can take away from 2020 in the zero days
that we saw is that a cos across the
industry
incomplete patches are making it easier
for ex
attackers to exploit users with cr days
we are not requiring
attackers to come up with you know all
new bug classes develop brand new
exploitation
look at code that has never been
researched before
we're allowing the reuse of lots of
different
vulnerabilities that we previously knew
about
so let's get into my three case studies
this first one is internet explorer
jscript
so jscript is the legacy javascript
engine included in internet explorer
while it's legacy it is still a great
attack vector
because it is enabled by default on
current windows machines
so through a quick timeline of you know
this saga this case study
um this bug class that we're going to be
talking about
was publicly discovered by a researcher
in january 2018
and through that you know numerous
vulnerabilities reported to microsoft
in december 2018 the first
detected case of what a bug in one of
these bug classes being exploited in the
wild was discovered
in september 2019 another vulnerability
in this book class was exploited in the
wild in november 2019 another
patch had been had to be issued because
the patch in september didn't
actually fix the vulnerability the
exploit and the proof concept
still worked even after that patch had
been applied
the november 2019 patch also
fixed a trivial variant that hadn't been
patched previously
in january 2020 another trivial variant
of the vulnerability exploited in
september cbe 2019-1367
was exploited and then in april of 2020
another variant within this pub class
was patched again
and i think one of the things that also
sort of hits home the importance of
these um correct and comprehensive
patches and how we need to be patching
you know the variants and not just the
single bug
is that the same attacker exploited all
four of these vulnerabilities
according to google's threat analysis
group who published about this
back in 2020 so that attacker had
four different chances to use these zero
days to exploit
users and now i'm going to show you just
how close each of these vulnerabilities
were to trigger them
usually only one or two lines of code
had to be changed
so we're going to start with the trigger
the proof of concept
for 2019-1367 the vulnerability that was
exploited in the wild in september 2019.
so this vulnerability specifically and
this bug class as a whole
oh so first the bug class the bug class
is that a jscript object
is not tracked by the garbage collector
which leads to a use after free
and so in this specific case the
arguments array
is not tracked by the garbage collector
in the array.sort callback
so in this sample right here um this is
where we're calling array.sort
we're using function f as our callback
so when that's called
we're going to execute function f in
function f first we have to create a
whole bunch of these jscript objects
then we're going to assign one of them
we're going to
give arguments array one of the
references to it
and so the arguments array again is the
thing that's not tracked by the garbage
collector
then we're going to delete all those
objects and call garbage collection
so now that object that the arguments
array
has a reference to has been deleted and
so that's what leads to our
use after free
so then two months later as i said
microsoft had to issue another patch the
first part of that was they actually
fixed
cve 2019 1367 this time but the other is
they also had to go in and fix another
trivial variant
so this variant to trigger that
vulnerability
you only need to delete one line of code
from the previous poc
and add two poc meaning proof of concept
um and so in this case it's not the
array.sort callback that
um is not being correct the arguments
array is not tracked correctly and
it's this time in the to json callback
so we
simply replace the sort call to
to json and then we can trigger the
vulnerability again
then that wasn't the end as i said
because in january 2020
another trivial variant was exploited in
the wild
and this time it's not the arguments
array
it's a named argument and so what that
looks like is again we have our 1367
trigger right here and the keys
differences were
that in this case we define the function
with no arguments and then we use the
arguments array
to store the reference to the object
that will be deleted for 2020674
the vulnerability that was exploited in
the wild in january we instead
put two named arguments in the functions
definition so
r1 and arc 2 in this case and we just
replace
any um place that we have argument zero
the arguments array with arg1 so those
were the only changes needed and you had
another zero day
yeah so we're showing it's not hard
you know once you understand a single
one of those bugs you could then
you know just change a few lines and
continue to have working zero days
find the other ones that hadn't been
patched or missed
this case study in chrome is going to be
a little bit different
instead of talking about the variance
i'm going to show you an example
of incomplete patching meaning the root
vulnerability
wasn't fixed the first time around
and this is a kind of an interesting use
case because
when this vulnerability was patched it
wasn't actually known that it was
exploded in the wild
that came two months later that it was
found that it had been likely exploited
as a zero day
um and so it shows the importance of
patching completely
all vulnerabilities because we know we
have a detection gap we know we're not
detecting every zero day that's
exploited
if you want more about that check out my
year in review from 2019 which is linked
in the references
but yeah i think it's a pretty
understandable thing we don't detect
them all and so we need to be fixing
everything as if they are
so in this case it is a type confusion
in chrome's v8 javascript engine
so here's the general timeline in
november 2019
set of security researchers reported the
vulnerability
this was a bug collision likely with the
attackers who are using it as a zero day
and we say that because the proof of
concepts the way the report was written
by the researchers
was very different than how the exploit
was written and so
in february 2020 sergey from project
zero our team
discovered um exploits using this
vulnerability and that it was likely a
zero day and that
you know so it had likely been in use
prior to november
because of this importance he decided to
do a patch analysis
from where the vulnerability was
reported by researchers and what he
found
was that it was not a correct and
complete patch it had
patched one way that this vulnerability
could be triggered but it didn't patch
um the other ways and so
what so chrome
went and very quickly released another
patch this time as cve 2026
8383 but it introduced a new
issue a new vulnerability um that
patched it
which um sergey again recognized and a
new patch was then
released for it so we're going to talk
about the first
incomplete patch here so this is
the trigger for the original
vulnerability so the vulnerability is in
as i said
chrome's v8 javascript engine and it
comes
about as a type confusion so in this
case within for loops
there is a area where it is going to try
and
do some induction the key is that
the v8 type of integer kind of has a
special type because it's not only
including
numbers but it also includes negative
infinity and positive infinity
but the other aspect of this integer
type is there is no guarantee
that when you add two integers together
it's going to give you an integer
instead negative infinity plus positive
infinity for example will
result in n a n not a number
which is not a member of the integer
type class so that's this vulnerability
is that in this for loop we are able to
um
cause a sum to be not a number
a k not an integer and that case
wasn't being handled correctly in the v8
engine
so what it looks like we have our for
loop here the
original index is going to be negative
infinity
and then our increment which was
assigned in the line above is positive
infinity
so when these are added together it
equals not a
number which was not handled and led to
this vulnerability
so they patched that they covered that
if you know your original index
is negative infinity and the increment
is you know positive or vice versa
then we're not going to go down that
code path and handle it differently
um thus preventing the vulnerability in
place
however they did not cover the case
where
you can actually change the increment
within the for loop body
thus triggering the vulnerability again
so for
cve 20 26 3 8 3 the second patch
this was the trigger is again we have
our for loop
but the original index this time is zero
while the increment is negative infinity
that's just fine because zero plus
negative infinity equals negative
infinity which is still an integer
however
what we see in this talk is that
once we go through it once and you know
i is now negative infinity
we change the increment to positive
infinity
so when we do that now we're going to
have the next time through the loop
negative infinity plus positive infinity
which then
is the same triggering um triggers the
vulnerability
again just in a different way this time
because it equals not a number
and so that's where we really need to
make sure that all patches are not just
patching to whatever proof of concept or
whatever exploit you see
that we're really getting down to what
is the root cause vulnerability
and how do we patch that correctly and
completely to make sure there aren't
other avenues to still trigger
the same thing
our last example and case study to sort
of show you
about you know this trend is an
arbitrary pointer do you reference
in the spl wow 64 dll in windows
so the sbl wow 64 dll is used for
whenever 32-bit
process and wants to print um the kicker
is that spl wow 64 runs as
medium integrity and internet explorer
which is a common 32-bit process
runs as low um integrity so this
arbitrary pointer dereference
was a privilege escalation so the
timeline on this one
july 2019 it's detected that
a vulnerability um or an exploit is
exploiting this vulnerability in the
wild in june 2020
um a trivial variant was discovered
exploiting the wild
and then when doing patch and variant
analysis i found that that patch wasn't
complete and it was still
exploitable and so then that was patched
in january 2021.
um the reason there's two cves there is
that
they had originally been planning to
patch in 2020
they missed the deadline and it had to
go over to 2021 and so a different cve
was then issued
so what's the problem internet explorer
is able to communicate with spl wow
by sending lpc messages one of those lpc
messages can trigger
this code path in gdi printer func which
will then
process that message so the
vulnerability in july 2019
it was the message type hex 75
and then the attacker can control in
those message it would use
different pieces to control all three
arguments to amend copy so the
destination source and copy size
but in the spl wows media integrity
process
so you have this privilege escalation
where low integrity internet explorer
can read and write in the media medium
aka higher integrity spl wow this code
snippet
and a great write-up is by byteraptor so
i included the url here
yeah so i jumped ahead so message send
is all of the user controlled
information from internet explorer and
we control destination source and the
size
so in july 2029 um
this time the difference was that it
just wasn't the message type 75
it was instead hex 6d and you have the
same capabilities
the offsets of where each of the source
destination and size for the mem copy
were slightly different
but still same vulnerability and control
all three arguments in a mem copy from
the
medium integrity process
finally their fix for that was to
simply change the raw pointers to
offsets which still didn't break it just
now as the attacker instead of sending
the raw pointer for the addresses
you want it to happen you send offsets
and calculate
that to have control over their pointers
so that was not a fix and then so that
was what was patched in january of this
year 2021. so hopefully i've shown to
you that
we have a problem we're not making zero
day a harder
it's um are hard to begin with because
you don't require all these elite skills
you don't have to be able to find new
vulnerabilities
to be able to exploit these zero days so
what do we do about it
thankfully we have options first we need
correcting comprehensive patches
for all vulnerabilities from our vendors
we can't be leaving things open once
they're
known about we need to use the
information to do variant
analysis to patch all of this instances
of that vulnerability in the code base
not just that single one
so thankfully each of us depending on
our role all have
opportunities though to help achieve
this goal as researchers we analyze bugs
for the patches
or we analyze patches for the bugs that
we report and others report to make sure
they're complete incorrect we do perform
variant analysis
we brainstorm mitigation strategies we
offer to work with vendors and
on patches before they're released to
make sure we don't
see holes already in their plan and
through disclosure policies or any other
tools at our disposal can we we can work
to try
and incentivize vendors for complete and
comprehensive patches
as a vendor it's a lot of the things i'm
saying that hopefully
you know researchers can contribute to
by
doing all these things and reporting to
vendors but vendors we really need you
all doing this
internal to your teams too of making
sure
those patches are not just breaking a
proof of concept
and that's what we're seeing a lot of is
because there's a lot of
ways oftentimes to
reach a vulnerability so making sure
that root vulnerability is fixed
rather than just one path to it also
reach out to us researchers we want to
help and make sure the patch is
correct and is actually fixing the issue
we we do this work you know to help make
things
stronger and more defensive so please
use us we
we want it you know just the same as you
is for these patches to be correct
and lastly as users there are still
things we can do too
we can hold our vendors accountable call
up customer service lines when
it's out that they haven't issued a
patch yet for something that's being
exploited or there's
the news headlines or we learned that a
patch wasn't
um correct that we hold them accountable
that hey
if i'm gonna use your software and your
product i need you to take security
seriously
and make sure these patches are let are
working off of all of the different
security holes that reports tell us
about
and so that all comes back to i'll use
the phrase one more time
we need correct and comprehensive
patches for
all vulnerabilities to make it harder
for users to be exploited with zero days
and that's important and i specifically
say all vulnerabilities because we do
know that not
every zero day is detected so if we
adopt this behavior for every single
vulnerability
that is found or reported to us then we
can definitely make it harder
for attackers to use
zero-day exploits and lastly
hopefully in this quick 20 minutes i've
made you more interested in all this
type of zero day in the wild work
um couldn't include everything i wanted
to clearly so
here's a whole bunch of great references
or i say great i wrote them so that's
kind of weird
i hope good references um and with that
thank you for joining me
i really appreciate it i'm maddie stone
in twitter or you can reach us
at google and project zero doing this
work at zero day in the wild at
google.com
thank you so much
you