tony can you hear me
i can
great great thank you tony for staying
with us uh in the in our first
conference
in hybrid
format
thank you so much for your support
and welcome to 8.8 center
thank you so much
thank you i'm happy to be here happy to
join you wish it could be in person
if you if you want you can uh
start uh your camera
okay yeah it's going
i'm up in the uh um
yeah the camera's going if you're good
would you like me to start
yeah please
okay
well hello everyone thank you for
joining us today uh i wish i could be
with you at this event in person
unfortunately not not possible right now
for me but uh thank you for your time uh
i hope you enjoy this session it should
be you know
informational it's only 30 minutes but i
mean it gives you a good taste if you've
never heard of mitre's engage framework
i think one of the most important things
to think about today is
all of the breaches that are taking
place and we're going to talk about that
in a minute because
they continue to happen regardless of
the spend that we put in place on
preventative tools so in mitre's engaged
framework is another way to look at
active defense so we'll talk about that
there we go
so the agenda who is miter and why
should you care
a more defensive posture through active
defense
minor attack and engage
some use case examples
just some ideas for stopping attacks and
how we need to understand attackers and
then of course a quick wrap-up of what
we covered
so miter
any of you
may have not may not have heard of mitre
miter is what's called an
ffrdc in the united states and that is a
federally funded research and
development corporation so they're a
not-for-profit organization however they
exist at the behest of the the u.s
government to solve uh very tough
problems and obviously i think everybody
in the room there and everybody online
knows that cyber security is a tough
problem to solve so they've spent a
couple of decades working on this
challenge and what we're going to touch
on today is some of their recent efforts
so first before we jump into mitre let's
talk a little bit about active defense
what is it what isn't it and i think
that's important
active defense is really about slowing
an attacker down uh out maneuvering them
you know and making that attack more
difficult to uh for them to accomplish
their goals you know if you can slow
them down and derail them and at the
same time get alerts on them throughout
that entire process then it really can
help you tremendously in being
successful in countering you know or
mitigating the impact of an attack
i think it's an important note you see
some stories from reporters and they
talk about you shouldn't do active
defense because they always incorporate
hacking back into active defense and
that's absolutely not true we're not
talking about doing anything outside of
your own uh enterprise where you're
doing defensive measures and active
defense is a defensive measure inside
your environment
of course i had to drop loki on my slide
simply because loki is the uh the god of
mischief if you're an avengers fan and
now probably aware that you know he does
a lot of uh
offensive actions you know uh when he's
fighting and other things where he can
be in multiple places at once or appear
that way so it's it's a good tie into
active defense in my in my opinion but
the whole concept of active defense is
really around you know uh causing the
attacker to incur more costs by
providing them information they can't
trust and that's something that many
defenders haven't done in the past you
know taking home field advantage
understanding
your enterprise and making the
adversary's job much more difficult when
they do get in and they do get in we
need that assumption of breach mentality
to think about the fact that sooner or
later our defenses will fail and how are
we going to ensure the the attacker
doesn't accomplish their goals inside
your enterprise
uh just really quick on this uh you know
nist has a guide uh if you're not
familiar with nist it is the national
institute of standards and technologies
here in the united states most people
around the globe know them because
they're the ones that built the the
first real cyber security framework and
uh the you know hundreds of controls in
this special publication 853.
the interesting point on this uh this
one that i was trying to make is it so
they talk a lot about using deception to
counter advanced persistent threats
nation state actors and we probably all
know that there's been a lot of blending
between nation state actors and criminal
you know groups as well over the last uh
four or five years so a lot more ttps
that the criminals are using that mirror
what uh
nation-state attackers are doing so it's
important to note that the
nist in mitre worked hand-in-hand and
nist is very focused on active defense
and deception
so
i'm probably preaching to the choir here
but i'd like to drop this slide anyway
why is active defense needed i think
it's important to look at just some of
the major cases just since december of
2020 there's been some huge attacks that
have had significant impact around the
globe i pulled these down from the
website on the bottom and by the way
for the organizers there gabrielle and
others i can afford these slides if
anybody would like them but the link at
the bottom is from the us
center for strategic and international
studies and they have been studying and
capturing data on cyber attacks for some
time and these are some major ones on
their website right now there's a lot
more i just pulled down just a few
why is this important
because
we're still spending this year alone
according to gartner
150.4
billion us dollars this year
so regardless of the spend you know
we're still seeing massive attacks take
place successfully so it's something we
need to think about and consider are we
doing all the right things or would we
fit into one of these stories right here
on the screen you know with the way
we've structured and instrumented our
defensive posture in our enterprise so
it's an important point to think about
are you doing something different so if
those same actors tried to go get into
your system would they be successful in
accomplishing their goals
so
minor attack and engage
if you're not familiar with minor attack
it's probably most of you are but in
case there's a few in the room that are
not minor attack is a very interesting
program you can see the link at the
bottom it's free for anybody around the
world to utilize
and it stands for adversarial tactics
and techniques and common knowledge so
what they're doing is mitre is
collecting data from
attackers so from observables across
enterprises around the globe where
people feed information in to mitre as
well as miter does their own capture too
to show you you know how to pick a path
for the attacker that's going after you
what do they usually do you know do they
do a you know a spear phishing
attachment in my example here
exploitation for client execution
hooking so the point is you can track
them and go across your environment
based on this this monitor framework
this database and understand typically
from that who that attacker is are they
a nation state or are they a criminal
group and if they if you identify them
from mitre attack at that point in time
you can potentially identify who the
attacker is based on the common ttps
that that attacker may utilize so you
would know if it's apt-29
comfy bear cozy bear panda bear whatever
attacker a vendor may call it when
you're reading a report miter
standardizes all those names and can
help show you who's after you that can
actually help you really understand
who's trying to break into your system
what are their goals so should i spend
more of my time and effort and resources
on to protecting some specific
high-value assets simply because you
know these are the type of attackers
that go after you and that would be
their goal so it's a really important
thing mitre attack is really cool it's
been uh implemented by many many
companies
around the globe and many governments as
well
so if you're not familiar with it i
would highly recommend you take a look
it's very very helpful there's a ton of
videos and mitre has you know uh
webinars pretty consistently so where
you can jump in and learn more about
attack in different areas
so
as i stated attack puts threats in
context you know you can see on the left
hand side from initial access execution
all the way down to exfiltration and
impact it it helps you understand what
the adversary is doing inside your
environment so very very beneficial uh
to dive in if you're not looking at
miter attack and potentially see if it
fits in well with whatever framework
you're using as well as
the structure for your strategic program
what are your goals in that program when
an adversary gets in are you trying to
just kick them out as quickly as
possible learn from it and block the
hole or do you want to study those
adversaries and understand what they're
trying to accomplish in your system a
lot of different things you can do here
but again attack very very helpful in
understanding the adversary and their
ttps
so
what is it we just talked about mitre
attack what about mitre engage what is
engage
engage is
the yang to the yen of miter attack so
it's really helping understand
what you should do if you're studying
mitre attack and looking at those
patterns the attackers are doing inside
your environment engage gives you the
capability to build an active defense to
counter those attacks
so one side is focused on the adversary
the other side is focused on helping you
build a defensive structure against
those adversaries inside the environment
and we'll get into that a little bit
deeper if you're not familiar with the
term in the middle of the symbol in the
middle uh it's a chinese symbol yin and
yang and it just shows how two pieces
are complementary and fit together well
so an attack and engage definitely uh
fit those fit those roles well so engage
is really that knowledge base of how to
defend using engagement of the adversary
inside your enterprise inside your home
field
so the mitre engaged structure you know
really breaks things down into strategic
actions and engagement actions with the
strategic side you know you're looking
at you know goals approaches and
activities that are going to support
your operational strategy so what are
you trying to accomplish what do you
want out of you know an active defense
so it's really on the strategic side the
engagement actions are really the steps
you're going to take in the uh
instrumentation you're going to build so
to help engage the adversary inside your
enterprise so it's a really cool
structure and one that no one had mapped
out previously
from this path a little bit like the
security framework that nist has and
some others but i think this is a much
more complementary before we go any
further on this i want to point out
engage is brand new so uh it's a version
0.9 not even 1.0 yet
miter is looking for more and more teams
to you know pun intended engage with
them and uh and help them make this a a
much better program i think it's come a
long way and this came out of what used
to be mitre shield instead they changed
it to mitre engage and revamp the
program uh based on feedback from
industry around the globe
so when you're looking at those
strategic goals again the first piece
you want to do is prepare you know and
really help you think about what do you
want to accomplish if you're going to do
active defense inside your environment
using the engaged structure
and then the other piece of course is
you want to understand gather that data
capture the data from your engagement
side and make sure it's being utilized
to help your blue teams and your
security operations center or defend
your environment because that's the goal
if we're looking at adversary ttps and
building instrumentation to counter them
we want to make sure that at every pass
and every effort that we have when we
engage an adversary we get better at
defensive side you know it can
potentially keep them out
so if you look a little deeper onto the
engagement goals so you've done the
strategic piece you've now thought about
uh here's what i want to get out of this
here's my goals on it then of course you
start to build the engagement piece out
you want to expose the adversary
operations you want to affect those
operations of course and you want to
elicit information pull information out
about those ttps from the adversary so
you can see right from these these three
you know uh
categories here you're really looking at
you know how this ties into attack so
you can see in an attack what an
adversary does now you're looking inside
your own environment to see if the
attacker is still mirroring what mitre
attack told you they were going to do or
have they changed have they evolved and
if so
that's great data to feed back into
mitre attack as well as miter engage
so if you look under the hood deeper at
engage
it's really interesting to me the
engagement piece
the exposed piece you know you've got
collection and detection decoy artifacts
and systems detonating malware you know
the effect side there's a ton of pieces
that you can do in there you know where
you're you know you're baselining your
system you know detonating malware again
you know manipulating email it's a lot
of fun you can have in in this space you
know doing this the illicit side of
course is you know looking at and
capturing all of that that data you know
on an adversary uh if you even look in
the far right hand column where it says
personas under motivation you know
there's there's so much you can do there
you know uh to to
really engage that adversary
and collect data so that you understand
who they are when you're building this
structure out for for an act defense you
may potentially even build you know as
part of your your program
build strategic personas that aren't
real inside your environment maybe
you've got a research and development
division and you want to build up you
know a campaign around that to ensure
that the attacker goes into that you
know
research and development you know fake
data so and that's what they're trying
to steal and you start to understand
their ttp's better it's a tremendous
amount
of functionality that you can get out of
this and this is a system where you can
click down click down click down and
really look at the direct ttps and how
it relates back to attack as well and
you're going to see a lot more come out
version one
they think is is going to come out
sometime in the fourth quarter of this
year so sometime in the next three
months since we're almost in october
hopefully it won't slip i know there's a
great team led by dr stan barr that
mitre and mclean virginia focused on
this now
if we put together the engage and the
strategic goals this is a direct cut
right out of the mitre program itself so
if you look on the left hand side you
know your prepare and your planning and
what you're trying to get out of this
and then after you've gone through the
expose effect illicit pieces you know
and you built out an engagement of that
adversary when they get in then at the
end you've got another strategic goal
and that's understanding you know what
were they doing you know hot wash is
like an after-action report so you know
you and your your team can sit down and
walk through all right how did we engage
this adversary where did our
instrumentation fall down what should we
do better next time uh what should we
add and potentially you know what should
we pull out what what did we not need
inside there because you don't want to
make this a heavy burden and it it
doesn't need to be
and you can do this specifically around
specific high value assets like active
directory uh maybe some critical
databases that you have lots of
different ways to do this and lead the
adversary away from those high value
assets into you know a decoy system or
some other structure or just feed
incorrect information to them you know
from active directory in in other
systems easy to do today
so it can be a tremendous amount of fun
so here's a quick quick example of this
you know looking at you know an active
directory ransomware attack sequence if
you look on the left hand side at number
one
still the most common means today is a
spear phishing email that comes in
somebody may spoof an email address from
the ceo and send somebody that they know
is gonna you know click on right away or
maybe they send it to a few people to
see if somebody clicks on it right away
but let's just say that
that user does click on it and
compromises that initial system maybe
the email had a weaponized attachment in
it or maybe it was a malicious url they
clicked on in the email anyway the point
is that that that user is compromised
at that point in time and the attacker
is now on that system at number one and
has an initial credentials stolen so
they've got a set of credentials
one of the first things you see is quite
often with cloud presence
we see a lot of organizations uh over
appropriate you know entitlements to
users so and even if that user didn't
use all of those and most of them don't
the first thing attacker is going to do
is look to see what entitlements they
have for that user so kind of kind of
scary
the next piece that attacker does of
course is discover targets you know they
look for targets and one of the most
common means is looking at active
directory hence why i picked this
selection
if you
know the fireeye mandiant team they're
very large and well respected team
they stated earlier this year that the
of the
incident response investigations they do
you know for their customers globally
all focus on you know where the attacker
was utilizing active directory so that's
that's a pretty shocking statistic in an
area that's that's ignored too much
hence why i picked this one so number
three
once the adversary has stolen those
credentials looked at the targets then
they compromised those targets what's
interesting is we see we don't see the
ransomware 1-0 uh very much and i guess
i could remove that and just stay with
ransomware too or
some companies called it multifaceted
extortion but they find that domain
admin pc they move laterally they steal
credentials they create persistence and
unfortunately they also encrypt high
value targets
and they steal and exfiltrate data so if
somebody decides they're not paying the
ransom the attacker could say oh we'll
look at this very sensitive intellectual
property that i've stolen from your
environment and now i'm going to uh you
know
share that on the web to embarrass you
or you know financially hurt the company
since it could be their intellectual
property so that's what we're seeing
most time is ransomware2o but the point
is that you know uh these attacks are
common and you can take components of
what i have have up here for an example
and relate them back to many of the
attacks uh in the past year that have
been uh you know huge impact around the
globe to multinational companies so what
do we do so we look at this we tied into
you know miter attack we
try to look at the ttps how do we
counter this well hopefully you have an
assumption of breach mentality
and with that assumption breach
mentality then you know you can
turn around and realize you're going to
get breached so you've been looking at
attack you've built an instrumentation
for engage
so we would add in you know components
for derailing that attack across the
board adding decoy assets that you know
the adversary does a scan uh they query
active directory they try to get real
information and instead you know you've
got
an engage structure built and you
provide deceptive information back to
them they don't even see who the real
administrators are and maybe you even
lead them off to a decoy domain
controller lots of things you can do
there
you can deflect exploits so you know
someone scans a system and you know you
can potentially take all the
ports that shouldn't be open on that
system and you can deflect those scans
off to a decoy environment
uh you can hide and deny access and that
one's a lot of fun and we're seeing this
more and more frequently where you hide
all the real credentials and you know
the only thing an attacker utilizing
their tools are going to find our decoy
credentials that alert you and again
lead them off into a decoy area
and the other piece that i really like
to harp on a lot is active directory
assessments i uh i did a
fireside chat yesterday in the united
states with the retail health uh ice ac
information sharing analysis center with
uh the chipotle you know uh uh cso so
who's well known used to be the the cso
for starbucks as well we talked
primarily about how active directory is
being ignored by many organizations out
there today on the security side so
doing an assessment to ensure that uh
active directory does not have
credentials that shouldn't be there
attack paths it shouldn't be there
cleaning it up and changing the
configuration to performance while
minimizing attack paths can be very very
beneficial so you can build all this
structure and much much more into
derailing those attacks
and i know i'm almost out of time here
so i'm going to move a little bit more
quickly because we we wanted to take
some questions so stopping attacks
really means understanding the attackers
i still have cesos i meet with sometimes
that say attribution doesn't matter it
does matter you you want to understand
who's attacking you and then you're
going to have a better chance to build
your instrumentation to defend those
high value assets inside your
environment so to do that you really
need visibility you know understanding
and reducing lateral movement paths a
lot of people aren't looking for that
they have
endpoints and cloud and they don't look
at those lateral movement paths across
the cloud or from the endpoint to the
cloud so it's important really to start
thinking about that whether you have an
on-premise environment with your own
active directory or some other identity
service but understand that structure
and instrument to look at lateral
movement paths
the big solar winds breach that took
place
so it took uh nine months to find that
you know and they are a security company
good one
and when you think about that there were
you know more than 100 companies
compromised and none of them found it
and again because people weren't looking
for lateral movement paths they weren't
cleaning it up and they weren't reducing
excessive entitlement identification
reduction you want to clean up that
attack surface that's critically
important before you're breached so
because that's going to help you you
know to uh strand that attacker when
they do get in and again assumption of
breach mentality is critical so clean up
those paths before the adversary gets in
reduce that attack surface and the last
one is attack prevention and detection
you know uh don't let them go into do
worries active directory update it give
a misdirection you know cloak your data
and encrypt it you know and implement
credential obfuscation and bait and
again same thing monitor for east west
lateral movement because people today
are not so we're seeing adversaries move
constantly inside an environment and
people don't have the instrumentation in
place to catch them they think i have
edr and i'm good
well we all know based on the headlines
we're not good with just edr there's a
lot more to it than that and i think
this audience knows that
so
in wrap up
writer's new engage and active defense
model really gives you opportunities to
engage the attackers inside your
enterprise
um so it's it's not letting them just go
through and trying to you know do
forensics on a system you know and find
out how they got in and where they got
in instead it's direct engagement with
the adversary inside your system and
putting up enough of enough obstacles
and hurdles where they're going to set
off alarms going to know very very
quickly what's going on so you can
mitigate that impact and they may never
get to the point where they could steal
data or even encrypt any systems
miter and nist are both recommending a
more active response to attacks so nist
is updated special publication 853 which
is the controls that feed the cyber
security framework and then mitre has
helped them with that as well as the
public talking about active defense and
engage is the next step up past that
be creative you can have a lot of fun
with us you know you can change the
outcome of attacks by preparing the
battlefield ahead of time and this this
is a battle we all know that so we get
hit on every day you know with attackers
trying to get inside our network
changing the structure of how that
network looks to the attacker without
impacting your operations is critically
important so you can have a tremendous
amount of fun by thinking about uh your
organization
what its goals are what it accomplishes
and then how you can you know uh
structure that that
framework so it doesn't impact
operations but it does impact the
adversary through you know an active
defense
use attack to understand gaps we all
have gaps in our defenses so that can
help you understand if this attacker
comes in and these are the ttps oh no i
have nothing here you know in this area
on this system to look for you know the
ttps for that actor you know that we
know they typically do that and i don't
have any instrumentation there so that
can help you fix that and of course the
engage for the act of defense as well
but understanding them is critical if
you if you wish to win this daily battle
engage was created for any type and size
of organization i've had a lot of people
ask me you know and i don't work for
mitre but ask me you know well you know
uh
my organization's only for security
people doesn't matter doesn't matter
there's lots you can do ahead of time
especially cleaning up active directory
and hiding credentials it's simple to do
and can have significant impact
so well uh
lucho gracias for your time and uh and i
will take uh take questions if we have
time for it
i i have a question for you tony
we can
we find we find very cool to work with
nasa how was your experience working
with them
it was fantastic you know
i really enjoyed my time with nasa and i
will tell you that the big problem for
if you consider yourself a geek like i
do was staying focused on thinking about
risk management you know instead of just
becoming completely overwhelmed trying
to understand all the scientists
technology that they're putting in place
the uh the astronauts you know you can
get very excited about you know
having conversations with them and the
experiences they've had
but it was tremendously fun for me i
absolutely had a blast working with nasa
so we'd go back in an instant you know
if they uh put the structure back in
place for that advisory council really
enjoyed it great great thank you
francisco te queria caracella
we have some questions here
just a minute
okay hi my name is francisco and i like
to know what what do you think about
public disclosure programs or book
bounty programs
well i like bounty programs a lot i
think they're important and really do
help our community so uh you know
when we have just an internal team
that's looking at our enterprise we
quite often miss things and having you
know responsible researchers out there
you know that are looking at your
technology can save us you know from
having a major compromise somewhere you
know so i i think that's critically
important especially for technology
companies you know to uh to engage with
the community talk to the community uh
build the program out so there's
well-defined parameters so we get
[Music]
an equitable process for the patch when
something is found so the researcher
gets credit for it but at the same time
and we get to patch out well ahead of
time i think it's critically important
as well i i don't like the researchers
you know that uh you know or cowboy like
in their approach where they will uh
just toss something out there you know
without working with the company which
potentially could you know end up in
compromise for a lot of people but i
think that that is really really
important you know to put bug bounty
programs in place for governments uh
large corporations and especially tech
companies large tech companies
great thank you tony
no no more question thank you so much
tony for your support we can hope that
you can come to chile maybe in the near
future
oh that would be fantastic so would
really enjoy that
thank you so much
all right thank you and thank you every
everybody for for listening and
attending you have a great rest of the
conference
[Music]
foreign
so
[Music]
my
you