no starch press CBTs cyber-ark Booz
Allen Hamilton
Darkrai no security and the game RSA
and US Bank join the conversation
tweet us at b-side cincy the
presentation will begin shortly
besides Cincinnati 2018 is sponsored by
GE Aviation no starch press CBTs
cyber-ark
Booz Allen Hamilton Darkrai no security
and again RSA
and US Bank join the conversation
tweet us at b-side cincy the
presentation will begin shortly
besides Cincinnati 2018 is sponsored by
GE Aviation no starch press CBTs
cyber-ark
Booz Allen Hamilton Darkrai no security
and the game RSA
and US Bank join the conversation
tweet us at b-side cincy the
presentation will begin shortly
besides Cincinnati 2018 is sponsored by
GE Aviation no starch press CBTs
cyber-ark
Booz Allen Hamilton Darkrai no security
and the game RSA
and US Bank join the conversation tweet
us at b-side cincy the presentation will
begin shortly
besides Cincinnati 2018 is sponsored by
GE Aviation no starch press CBTs
cyber-ark
Booz Allen Hamilton dark rhino security
and the game RSA
and US Bank join the conversation
tweet us at b-side cincy the
presentation will begin shortly
besides Cincinnati 2018 is sponsored by
GE Aviation no starch press CBTs
cyber-ark
Booz Allen Hamilton Darkrai no security
and the game RSA
and US Bank join the conversation
tweet us at b-side cincy the
presentation will begin shortly
besides Cincinnati 2018 is sponsored by
GE Aviation no starch press CBTs
cyber-ark
Booz Allen Hamilton dark rhino security
and the game RSA
and US Bank join the conversation
tweet us at b-side cincy the
presentation will begin shortly
besides Cincinnati 2018 is sponsored by
GE Aviation no starch press CBTs
cyber-ark
Booz Allen Hamilton Darkrai no security
and the game RSA
and US Bank join the conversation
tweet us at b-side cincy the
presentation will begin shortly
besides Cincinnati 2018 is sponsored by
GE Aviation no starch press CBTs
cyber-ark
crying everybody we run a little late
here so we'll get started here present
Coleman came to you guys he'll be
talking about meltdown inspector and the
view of speculoos execution yeah alright
everyone find your seats so before I get
started on my talk I wanted to just kind
of remind everyone that we have this
really neat CTF going so if you're not
familiar a real popular thing at DEFCON
and Derby Khan and some of the other
Star cons is capture the flag challenge
a lot of times they're like super super
technical and we definitely have some of
that here but I wanted to kind of give
people an idea of what else we've got so
this right here is basically like you
can log into it if you go on our Twitter
account you can get all the access info
and everything as far as I can tell I
can actually get the Wi-Fi down here so
if you wanted to play in the audience
downstairs it seems like it works but
basically present a phone map of the
world and then you hover over any one of
these things and it basically has
challenges and stuff like that and
apologies for the crummy resolution my
laptop screen is actually a lot bigger
one of the things I did want to point
out is that a lot of these challenges
are actually kind of trivia quizzes type
things with a kind of subject matter
leaning towards like InfoSec stuff so
the point of this is that anyone can
play and anyone can win you don't have
to be a like Network forensics or file
system you know Carver or anything like
that in order to have fun with this and
that's kind of what we wanted it to be
so anyhow with that I just wanted to let
you know that that's a thing I'll go
ahead and close this now and get my
presentation working
oh geez that's huge
but
presentation there we go and then dude
awesome so now just hope my laptop
doesn't fall asleep on me in the middle
of the presentation which I think as
long as I do this is good alright
everyone so today I'm going to talk to
you
non super technical terms but we will
dive a little bit down into the weeds
meltdown inspector which I'm sure that
many of you saw in the news as the new
sky is falling problem back in January
and then recently saw that it came back
in the news again toward the end of
April early May as it's alleged that
there's a large number of more flaws so
these are CPU hardware flaws you know so
basically architectural design issues
that are inherent a lot of the CPUs so
it was revealed and I kind of expected
this that there's going to be more flaws
of these types they'll probably come up
with much fancier sillier names so we'll
wait and see I was actually hoping a lot
of the details would be released by now
but from what I understand publications
been I know withheld or embargoed or
whatever you want to call it until late
May so while they get some fixes out so
I'll talk to you about these and why
what they're gonna release this month is
the next step and why it's probably not
the end but just the beginning so let's
get started so a little bit about me
I've been a security analyst for just
about eight years so really uh I think
when I first started got out of
undergrad they didn't really have
information security as a career itself
I did a large amount of embedded system
design and stuff like that mostly
focused around Linux platforms I've been
programming since before guerrillas bass
if any of you are familiar with that so
that was probably one of my earliest
you know Tony around with programming
exercises I was a computer engineering
grad at the University of Cincinnati
so differs from computer science in that
it includes a large amount of like
architecture like CPU and operating
system architecture work as well and
then I'm a PhD candidate abd all but
dissertation just finish my coursework
this month at the University of
Cincinnati where I also have put
together some of their curriculum for
their cyber classes so one of the things
I will say is that one way as Danny had
mentioned earlier in his talk is you
know find mentorship opportunities try
and get the knowledge that you've
learned out I've only been in security
for 8 years I've got a lot of knowledge
to share and everything like that and I
try and get it out one way that I do
that is through University of Cincinnati
so I have taught some classes there one
of the great things about this school is
that they don't necessarily presume to
know everything so they actually
recruited myself and a number of other
folks from the industry who didn't
necessarily have a huge teaching
background to help them put together
some of the material they need you know
to actually have a cybersecurity program
that had that's informed by a lot of the
people who do the work every day so I'm
also contributor to a number of
open-source projects this is just a
handful of them but you know through
projects that some of you may or may not
be familiar with creates as an Intel
database Yara is the you know fancy er
thing you know pattern matcher malware
analysis engine whatever you want to
call it extra extra grep and then the
FreeBSD project open source system that
was actually one of my first open source
contribution efforts and I'll say that
another piece in addition to mentoring
everyone is get involved in these
communities just a little tiny bit of
contribution from you can go a long way
to helping a lot of people's lives so I
list myself as a contributor to these
things but my contributions to them is
probably 1% of what they do and
that's the same with a lot of the other
contributors as well and it helps out
those projects immensely and those are
projects that rather than me building my
own version of everything projects that
can help a lot of people and a lot of
different companies so that's one of the
things I always like to stress get
involved in that because that's one
that's another way that we can all solve
the problem together so now to the
actual subject matter that we're here to
talk about meltdown specter so wTF is
that so I just grabbed the information
from meltdown attack they actually have
this nice paragraph that's really really
long I will hit on three things that
have highlighted in red for you so
vulnerabilities in modern processors so
we're not talking about old stuff or
anything we're actually talking about
stuff that's you still go on a best buy
today and buy a laptop you're buying
very likely you're buying vulnerable
processors vulnerable operating system
allows programs to steal data which is
currently processed on the computers a
data in flight it's not necessarily
going to be cracking the contents your
hard drive or anything like that but
it's going to be identifying anything
that other people happen to be working
on this is where I think the point that
Danny was making in the last talk about
we all need to get familiar with doing
threat hunting and doing you know
basically security work in the cloud how
the clouds architected how much you use
and everything like that we've become
accustomed to having a lot of these
dedicated systems where myself plus a
handful of authorized users are what are
responsible or what are running any code
on this system nowadays chances are that
any single website that you're using
today is running code simultaneity you
likely unidentifiable to the owner of
the hardware as well so random code is
running on numerous systems in the cloud
today and you may be entirely unaware of
it as well I think you know we had a
conversation upstairs about the CTF
stuff the CTF website that we got
running
and it actually references something
that's hosted at Google api's org as one
of the UI visual elements or whatever
random thing completely unexpected but
is a part of that platform that type of
leakage into the cloud or leakage from
the cloud is a pervasive these days and
it is incumbent on all of us to
understand how it works so basically
they get a hold of secrets stored this
is kind of you know repeats my point
secrets stored in the memory of other
running programs so we get started with
what our modern processors because as
you know gonna be a lot of subjectivity
about that so the two things that I
think are both applicable to these
vulnerabilities and also the key
features that most people are looking
for and what they would consider to be a
modern processor or a processor worth
buying in a computer I want to buy today
are these features and I'm not gonna
dive into too much detail on all of them
but the big thing is superscalar
architecture so I give some details over
here what that means but in a nutshell
it means that you can if you're familiar
with processor labeling stuff like that
you might see it sold is like you know
one gigahertz 3.2 gigahertz that type of
thing so any of you familiar with like
basic physics that means you know that's
frequency so that's how many times per
second it does a thing you know so in
this case superscalar architecture is
how do I get the processor to run
instructions at a rate that's more
frequent than the gigahertz rating
that's given so there's a lot of
circuitry for that the other goal is how
do I do it without 100% duplicating that
processor so making two of them
basically can I get the same outcome
which is faster than the frequency
faster than the clock rate
instruction speed without fully
duplicating the processor why would I do
that because it's cheaper it mate allows
me to sell a faster processor at a lower
price the other piece that a lot of you
are probably getting familiar with is
multi processing virtual memory
architecture and everything like that so
that allows us to run
Microsoft Excel while I'm washing a
video on YouTube while my facebook chats
updating all of that stuff happening in
real time the critical things here I I
always feel is what we call a time
sharing support so the ability for your
programs to Tranter be silly run in
parallel behind the scenes without
themselves having to be written to say
hand off the processor to the next
program manually so the programs don't
have to be pre-written for multitasking
or multiprocessing
the other thing virtual memory the big
thing here is that you can separate your
memory out into basically privileged
levels you can have memory that's
supposed to be where private stuff
happens and you give memory where you
know Facebook happens or something like
that right you don't want the two of
them to be able to be to read one
another or necessarily or at least you
don't want the Facebook process the
Facebook memory to be able to execute
code that reads the private memory your
you know private key or something like
that so you know the objectives of these
features are pretty you know pretty
clear but your I should say are
desirable but the critical one is this
right here back in the day we may have
had especially working a scientific
environment you may have had computers
dedicated for each one of the jobs that
you needed to do that's expensive
naturally that's a lot of power a lot of
hardware etc the goal with this always
going forward is can we figure out a way
to gradually more and more over the
years consolidate work that's done
across multiple computers multiple
systems into single systems can we you
know basically reduce the hardware costs
while not losing any of the performance
that's the goal that most processor
companies today are going after
in fact most computing companies today
are going after it that's why the cloud
exists
so the other piece support concurrent
computer users that's where a lot of the
memory protection I was talking about
comes into play that's where being able
to divide up access control and memory
and everything work that's why that's
important that facilitates the idea of
this public cloud where you can have
Facebook's living side by side with
Twitter if you want it or you know your
storefront sitting side by side with
somebody's minecraft server that type of
thing you want to minimize real-world
execution times by eliminating
bottlenecks increasing concurrency so
this means you know reduce the cost of
hardware over time while always seeing
it going faster reason for that is we're
always adding new features to software
we're always wanting something to do one
more thing every time you tack on an
extra bit of work it takes that much
more effort in order to get it done so
you know this is the ideal and I kind of
set this here is like this is the
engineering mindset that's behind most
of the consumer you know hardware
development today well this is the
mindset that goes into a lot of it most
of the time and you may run into this in
a lot of your place of business as well
at a management level and whatever is
that security is still reactive in this
environment so in the words of the
Prophet harder better faster stronger
that's what they're going for every
single year they want you to keep buying
more processors more laptops etc keep
upgrading and that's the way they get
you to do it so if you've ever looked at
the you know at the white papers or the
you know what have you called the spec
sheets for a laptop or for a CPU if you
build your own that type of thing you
might have seen all these fancy
buzzwords here so every single one of
these are actual built on so they're not
necessarily core to a processor doing
its work these are all built on or
bolted on features that allow CPUs to do
their work fast
better you know harder stronger etc I'm
gonna cover a handful of these because
to be totally honest this is the type of
stuff they cram into an entire semester
of computer organization but I'm going
to touch on pipelining branch prediction
shared cache and speculative execution
and then probably touch on out of order
execution as well so here we go so way
back in 2005 and I bring this one up I
loved it because this was probably the
first first indication that something
was just not right
we're running ahead of ourselves and
we're building hardware without thinking
the ramifications of some of the
features were implementing it also
illustrates that so this is 13 years ago
so essentially this mindset this
research is actually pretty old suddenly
we had the meltdown specter stuff pop up
this years if it came out of the blue
but if you go all the way back to 2005
even before that you'll see a lot of
academic papers have been published on a
lot of these research topics so in 2005
Colin Percival published a what's called
a cache timing attack against the shared
cache future implementations in I think
at the time it was the hyper-threading
feature that was in the Pentium that was
initially released in the Pentium 4 at
the time so I don't know if any you
remember there was a Pentium 4 his very
short-lived not super successful
actually it was very unsuccessful but
they introduced this idea of can we make
it look like the computer has 2 CPUs
even if it only has one so can we do a
lot of work in parallel by duplicating
more components within the CPU without
actually bolting another CPU on the
motherboard and they did this by
duplicating some hardware but not
duplicating other hardware such as
things like cache and everything which
I'll get into in a little bit not
duplicating Hardware such as memory
access and stuff like that so the
outcome of this
results have been accidentally exposing
a mechanism to identify whether values
are cached in memory or not with a
timing analysis attack it existed before
this but this feature art should say the
concept existed prior to this however
this feature made it very very very easy
to exploit so we'll jump into cache
operation with a quick diagram don't
need to understand all this I'm not even
sure how many people program and see
these days
but basically take this piece of code in
as an example so the idea here is that
you have to source arrays you're trying
to do a matrix addition operation here
so you have two arrays and you want to
add all the values in each array and
then store those in a third array so the
way that most computers organize this is
that these three arrays here are located
in sequential memory segments right here
and then if you walk across it so this
basically goes from one although you
know basically from this one down here
this one down here adds each cell
together and then stores them in a Cell
right here historically what would
happen is your processor would want look
apologies historically what happen is
your processor would want to go and
basically take one from here take one
from here add them together store it
here then take one take the next one
from here take the next one from here at
it store it in here the problem is that
as processors got to be a lot faster
like pretend this guy is 3.2 gigahertz
memory is still a lot slower than that
maybe 1 gigahertz maybe less maybe 800
megahertz something like that I kind of
gave a rough thing maybe 10 times slower
than the CPU if I do that I can only run
as fast as my fastest memory so to try
and get around that what they ended up
doing was they came up with this idea of
caching the data locally every time CPU
talks to this much much much smaller but
much much faster piece of memory that's
actually attached to the CPU and then
what they'll do is the first time that
the CPU wants something from a
all of a is actually loaded into the
CPUs memory and then from there it
basically walks through a by going back
and forth right here without ever
touching this again so what happens is
if you end up having this CPU that's
doing the work and then you end up
duplicating it over here with another
CPU that's doing the work and they're
sharing this cache memory right here if
this guy retrieves memory from a and
then the other CPU tries to also
retrieve memory from a the first time it
pulls the first element from a it takes
a long time it takes memory time it
takes 10 times the speed to get it the
second time it wants something from a if
it's only going here then it's immediate
it's fast whoops this thing's a little
touchy apologies so if you have a second
CPU running over here that just happens
to basically be waiting on a it can
learn that stuff is being read from a
whoops by looking and comparing the
amount of time it takes to read
something from a so that seems innocuous
at first and we'll get into why that
significant but anyway I kind of wanted
to give a real quick refresher on or
brief explanation as to how this works
the basic idea here is like think of
this as if I went to the grocery store
for every single ingredient I wanted for
a recipe whenever I needed it at that
moment
think of how slow that would be that's
why I go to the grocery store like once
a week
buy all the things I need and then keep
them at home this cashier is my home
that's the fridge of the pantry or
whatever and this is the grocery store
so there we go so this kind of runs down
a lot of what I was talking through in
the diagram I won't dwell on this slide
too much but the important thing here is
that I can learn if something was read
from memory or not or if a particular
address in memory was actually accessed
by another processor just by trying to
figure out how quick or slow it took me
to try and read something from that cell
in memory
so the common like attack techniques
that are used for this one of them is
covert channels so that's a way of
communicating data between two cysteine
basically two processes that may be Bo
that may be aware of one another without
that necessarily showing up physically
in RAM and the other one is private data
theft also known as snooping
so trying to steal information so leave
this up here for a moment you know this
right here is the quick is the
description of the math that works here
and again this and it's this in itself
is not the exploit this is one piece of
the exploit just to jump back here for a
moment there's a lot of features here
one of these features is invulnerable
the combination of these features
creates a vulnerable complex system so
this is one thing that can leak a little
bit of information that on its own right
seems innocuous so some attack
mitigations if you actually did feel
this information was you know important
to try and prevent someone from seeing
these are some ways to work around it
unfortunately as you can see every
single one of them comes with some sort
of penalty that takes away some of that
ideal goal that I was talking about
earlier it makes it more expensive it
decreases performance so it reduces the
superscalar Ness of the processor and
that's why you see a lot of people who
may be resistant you see a lot of
architectures that may be resistant to
trying to implement things like this
because every single one of them makes
the processor a little bit slower and as
we all know that's a very competitive
market right now
so I'm getting to the next feature which
is pipelining instruction level
parallelism so this is how you move from
having a very slow processor that can
execute maybe one instruction every few
cycles through having something that can
execute maybe multiple instructions in
one clock cycle you know more than 3.2
gigahertz worth of work in a second so
many operations that you deal with or or
I should say many algorithms are complex
operations that perform like multiple
steps so for instance multiplication or
division in the processor that doesn't
happen in one clock cycle a lot of times
that takes multiple clock cycles to work
because of this the CPU actually breaks
a lot of those operations up into
discrete steps so you can think of it as
like a recipe book or whatever right so
in order to do a multiplication of two
numbers step one get the first number
and put it on the table step two get the
second number put it on the table
step three do the sequence of steps
where you put them on top of each other
and do the multiplication work and
everything right step four you have a
result step five put that somewhere so
remember the computer's not really all
that intelligent it just does what it's
told to do exactly very very very very
well and very fast so the a lot of these
units are designed to execute in
parallel on staggered fragments of the
original instructions so this is a real
common table that's built up and some of
you who may have taken CS or Computer
Engineering or something like that might
recognize it but the idea here is that
each one of these things is a component
so it's a circuitry physical circuitry
within the processor I colored these
things here to show you each of the
instructions moving through the stages
and then this is time so this is the
first clock cycle this or you can
pretend this is set
zero right second one second two second
three second four so this is a timing
diagram basically and then I have some
details as to what these mean but the
idea here is that at the first you know
first second or first clock I'm fetching
the instruction from memory so I don't
know what it says I don't know what's
telling me to do until I actually read
it the second one I actually need to
decode it into what work that I need to
do the third third second I actually
need to go to memory and put the stuff
on the table that I was talking about
etc the interesting thing about this is
that if I was not to start loading in
the next instructions while I've moved
this one forward I would end up with
basically processor performance that's
like 20% of my clock cycle because I
would have to do every five of these
things before I could even start doing
the first one you know the first stage
on the next instruction the other thing
that this reveals and I think I have
this on the next slide is that by the
time I get here so for transitions in by
the time I get here I am in I am
partially executing five different
instructions at once so I managed to
approach my you know approach my
maximize work load which is you know
being able to run five things at once in
the processor but the other thing is
that if we step here to like time three
this instruction hasn't finished
executing yet before I'm already
starting to do work on the three
instructions ahead of it how do I even
know that this one's worth executing
because as we all know you can have if
statements or while statements you can
basically have like jumps and stuff like
that in your code I don't know
necessarily if I'm able to run this I'm
actually speculating here I'm more I
should say the processor is actually
speculating here the processor just
assumes that all the following
instructions ahead of the curve
one I'm working on are probably going to
be run so and I kind of lay that out
right here so the other thing too is
that so for instance this one right here
will jump to this one right here right
so while this one's storing its result
back into memory instruction three is
already loading the data that it relies
on from memory and then the second
instruction already did that so I've
basically loaded data from three places
while I've only completed one operation
so speculative execution so we're gonna
speculate on speculation so consider the
following instruction sequence and I
didn't do assembly language what I did
is I turn to some of the language and a
math for this but every single one of
these things reduces into on assembly
language like you know instruction in
pretty much every single architecture
and the point of this is that the
vulnerabilities I'm talking about today
actually apply across the board so
they're not limited to just your Intel
processor now these are you know
features that I'm talking about here
that exist in every single CPU since
like the Pentium Pro and the AMD 29k so
consider the following algorithm this
one seems pretty straightforward right
so you know a is one B's for multiply
the two of them together and overwrite B
with whatever that result is then add
them together so add a and B together
and then store the result in a so then
by here the original values of a and B
are trashed and B and a have new kind of
combined values not only that but a
contains what you'd expect to be the
result of the operation
likewise then store five in c8 and D do
the same thing here multiplied two
together over right C and then finally
take the initial one that was computed
up here and then add this value here to
get a final value for say the whole
function so getting back to how you can
execute multiple instructions at once
that requires the processor to figure
out what the dependencies are between
all these for instance I can't do this
instruction right here without first
doing these two and this one so I can't
do it so the processor needs to figure
out those things highlighted in yellow
are the ones that don't have what we
call execution dependencies I can load
all this data into these four variables
into these four locations without
waiting on anything else in this program
in this very simple program highlighted
Nakhla are the ones that have minimal
dependencies and by minimal dependencies
I mean they don't depend on any prior
math they only depend on again let me
get back to that cashing diagram right
this one they only depend on this part
of the CPU the part that brings stuff
out of memory and into the cache
because of that a modern CPU might
actually choose to rework a lot of this
stuff so that it can execute more of the
work concurrently for instance because I
can load large rows of memory into the
processor at once in a single memory
read operation rather than doing all
four of these as four separate memory
read operations how about if I just read
all of them at once in one big operation
here so how about if I join them
together additionally what I've done is
this operation down here actually moved
up just above this one right here so
this little whatever you call this
little margin right here between the two
lines that's where this computation to
get the end value of C happens so I
think I'd sure that there the important
thing is that this computation doesn't
actually rely upon this at all to work
so you can perhaps in this case the
processor has broken up the mathematical
you know work into maybe three different
pieces of circuitry or two different
pieces of circuitry so it can do these
two at the same time the interesting
thing about that is
when I wrote the program my expectation
was that I would do this work first a
equals eight equals a plus B I would do
that first before the processor does any
of these three great that was how I
wrote the program to work the problem is
that that's not how the processor made
the program work the processor actually
made the program run this before this
happens or these two happen which means
that when a plus B gets executed
I have the processor has already done
the same memory loading work for these
right here and this so what happens if
this right here runs into an air
condition for instance these two are not
values that can be added together or
something like that the way I wrote the
program I might have had it I might have
had the Assumption bead that I can do
all this work after this condition has
been satisfied it's you know if that
operation is not invalid so if that
operation doesn't fail right it doesn't
cause an error then all this work
happens the processor reordered it so
that that work happens no matter what
and then if this causes an error
the architects concept the architects
philosophy is that oh well in that case
I just wasted my time I did a bunch of
extra work that I'll just throw away
that was the kind of architect mentality
and the benefit was that I can still
have a faster processor the consequence
is that there is work that went into
these woods based upon say another
feature in the processor the caching
piece that also leaks some information
so another piece that's here is um
complex array indexing so this is the
work that processors were originally
invented for so electronic computers
originally invented to handle large
matrix operations basically to do your
spreadsheets on the computer instead of
by hand right so if you go all the way
back to like the work that like IBM and
NASA did and everything like that as
tabulation work large table calculations
things like that so one of the
interesting things this gets a little
bit into kind of memory nomenclature and
everything but one of the interesting
things is that they came up with all
these very complex ways to refer to data
in the table that's in a nutshell what
all this is so you can either say oh you
know if I have a list of numbers the
seventh number right I can even tell it
to give me different data sizes for each
one of those things I can maybe have not
just one column but I can have columns
and rows so I can have maybe B tells me
what the column is and C tells me what
the row is or something like that
ditto for this we have a few simplistic
things here it actually gets quite more
complex when you dive into the assembly
language and I didn't necessarily want
to give an entire presentation on that
but in a nutshell I have a bunch of
circuitry built into the processor that
allows me to do math on the indexes into
my array in all sorts of complex ways
and some of these are native so some of
these are built-in others are operations
that I can create by stringing multiple
different steps together multiple
different instructions together such as
this one and that's a left shift for
instance a complex operation leveraging
you know the mathematical or arithmetic
unit plus you know some other work so
this is kind of remember we invented
these things originally to do you know
tabular calculations and things like
that not to play Minecraft or anything
or overwatch or anything like that these
things were originally created to do
this stuff
basically do matrix math do this stuff
very very very efficiency or efficiently
and at very high dimensions so this one
is the one I'm gonna hone in on for the
next uh for the next feature right and
the next feature combines all of the
things that we just saw in a very simple
program to basically create that
meltdown vulnerability so this is the
one that many of the patches were pushed
out for you know the ones that you saw
the emergency patches from a number of
cloud providers and things like that
were pushed out to close this particular
vulnerability the was at the middle of
the night like undisclosed Linux patches
that went in that then were explained
after they went in that was these all
the the super say the out of out of band
non Super Tuesday patches the one in the
Windows this vulnerability this is also
the one that primarily affected Intel
CPUs so again I converted it and I
simplified it a bit so it takes a little
bit more work than what I show up here
but at its core it's three basic steps
so remember I talked about how you have
the concept of privileged and
unprivileged memory you have the memory
that is your private key great where
that works done versus the memory that
is your Facebook posts so both of them
are running code both of them are
running programs will say that B happens
to be something that is a memory where
your private key is located something
like that and then will say that C
happens to be memory where a random
facebook program is running or something
like that so what happens is first you
may try and bring some data out of that
privileged memory and store it in this
variable X obviously that's going to
result in an error of some sort
sometimes that error might just be to
give you a you know give you a junk
value give you an error code for this
other times that might be to throw to
cause what's called an exception or
interrupt your program while it's
running well the interesting thing about
this is that if you get back to the
pipelining thing that I was talking
about back here this remember that by
the time we get to executing that that
first inch or yeah by the time I get to
executing that first instruction we've
already started doing work on the next
three right and this is a simplified
thing the architecture for your Intel
chips goes much deeper than this so
we're actually executing maybe 15 or 20
instructions ahead of time for that so
let's get back over here so basically
what I mean is by the time you realize
that you aren't allowed to read this
data here I should say by the time the
CPU realizes that you've already started
to do this work and you've already
started to do this work and the
processor identifies that right here
this work is also trying to reference
other memory that's in your program
space that's in facebook facebook's
memory space or something like that so
right here you're doing a very simple
calculation based on this data inside
the processor they allow the speculative
execution to pull this stuff out by
passing a lot of the memory protections
the checks that determine whether this
memory is supposed to be read by
such-and-such process because again
their assumption is that they'll figure
out whether or not the thing they've
computed the thing that they've
retrieved is something you're allowed to
see
after they finish executing this and
they'll just discard the wasted effort
the wasted work the interesting thing
about this one is that I'm taking a
value out of here right I'm taking data
that's stored in private memory and then
I'm using it to basically compute an
index into another array that I know of
so it's not just an array that I can
read get out of gets an array that I
pre-populated with data that maybe might
be a unique value in every single cell
or something like that and then I'm
storing that in Y so this right here is
something I'm allowed to see right I'm
allowed to view this I am basing the
index into this or what's called the
offset so I'm doing math here on the
memory to basically pull out something
that might be four steps or four slots
in front of the beginning of this array
based on whoops based on what was
private here so in a normal world what
happens is the processor throws a lot of
this away after it decides that I'm not
allowed to see the thing in reality what
ends up happening is right here sorry in
reality of what ends up happening is
that I've pre cached the data right here
and I can basically go back through
after I recover from this error after
I'm told that this didn't work I can go
back through and I can try and find out
oh sorry the button is working I can go
find out which of the slots in this
really big array come back very quickly
to me so which ones are a very quick
read versus which ones are very slow
read
and by doing that I can find out what
value X was right here that I multiplied
it by this number and then I can find
out what was computed here based on that
and that's kind of your timing attack in
a nutshell is I basically will go
through and try and read all the data in
this memory region right here and try
and figure out which data comes back
very quickly for me versus which data
comes back very slowly so and then this
is basically the this is the very
detailed explanation of all that so I
figured it'd be a lot easier for the
audience to basically show you using the
using the program there but on modern
processes you know again this is kind of
the core thing here bottom modern
processes architected with the
assumption that these internal details
are transparent to the running program
but there's no way to actually know that
basically note they assume that I can't
do what I just did and that's because
the whole concept of like memory timing
and everything like that falls into the
realm of something that's unpredictable
but not so unpredictable that it's
impossible to say judge within a certain
you know probability that you got the
right answer so that's kind of melt down
in a nutshell and as you can see I mean
the code to do this this comes out of
the paper right I simplified it a little
bit but it's really just the are it's
like I think they have seven lines of
code and five of them are like execution
and two of the lines of code actually
just make it a little bit more reliable
they overcome some other design issue
that might end up causing it to be on a
little bit more unpredictable than
normal so anyway that one was a pretty
big glaring error and it requires
combining all of those different
features together so all those things
that I just talked about that go into
processor design if any one of those had
not been implemented then this wouldn't
work
and that's kind of the you know the idea
here is a culmination of many many many
years of effort and people's little
discreet good ideas kind of collecting
together into a complex system that now
presents a really really really glaring
privacy flaw so we get in a branch
prediction inspector because that's
Spectre is very similar uses a lot of
the same logic that we talked about
there but then also uses what's called
branch prediction and those are you
familiar with the exit twelve meme this
is basically how your CPU works how your
CPU speculatively execute anything that
fits a model like this so if there's a
decision to be made so as all programs
can be broken up into a decision tree in
this case the decision to be made is
when I get to this test right here do I
execute this line at number two or do I
start executing at what's in number six
that isn't shown up here right do I
start executing past the end of this
block so again we're gonna consider a is
a really large array B is a really large
array a contains some data that maybe
you don't I should say contains an array
of data that you want to expose to the
program but there's more memory around
there as well that may be the users
query or something like that or the
program scoring that you want to keep
private so
the branch predictor will keep track of
the frequency with with with which a
branch is taken so if this was inside of
a loop it basically scores how
frequently do we go from this line to
this line versus this line down here so
if you're doing this loop and let's
pretend that a is a really large array
we'll say that a is like a million
elements or something right a million
minus one times it goes from this line
down here and then only one time it
jumps all the way down here out of that
so that's what it means it's literally
basically a frequency test
and the reason why it's doing that is so
that getting back to the pipelining
stuff they can figure out whether it
needs to start loading in these three
operations or if it needs to go from
here and then start pre loading the
operations down here that I you know
they didn't show because they're
irrelevant for the for the case here so
if branch prediction is misidentified so
say on the last run here when you get to
the end of the array it may already
start doing this stuff with the
character with the data that's just past
the array the data that was not supposed
to be read by the program and again
it'll throw away the data because it'll
realize oh the the user really wanted to
go down here so it's a the program
really goes down here but this work is
still done and so we can take some of
the stuff that was discussed right here
you know we can take a very similar
timing attack time and computation to
basically try and figure out what's past
the end of the array if we write this in
a proper way so this example that they
gave a really good use case for this
might be if you end up having a program
that's using like public key
authentication or something like that so
the user's keyring right and that thing
typically keeps some data private in
memory so this is a possible way to leak
that memory out this one's a lot less
successful this is also the one that's
not patched so if you remember when
meltdown specter was published there was
one patched vulnerability or one major
one that was patched which was the
meltdown vulnerability specter remains
unpatched today because if you mess with
this then all of today's processors
basically if you rent if you turn this
feature off this branch prediction
feature off all of today's processors
lose so much of their optimizations that
they become so much slower even with the
meltdown patch the impact was
particularly noticeable for a lot of
for instance cloud compute workloads so
my thoughts and we're getting toward the
end of it I think we have about 6
minutes left so things that I ponder
this has nothing to do with the
presentation but it is a interesting
factoid so the scary so this is where it
kind of gets to you you know you all in
many of the different roles that you're
in want to be the solution to this
problem and this goes beyond just CPUs
right this is kind of engineering and
design mentality so many of these
superscalar enabling features so the
things I talked about they date back to
the design of these two architectures
from the big two CPU companies they also
exist like was it PowerPC implements a
lot of the same features as well Andy's
29k which was predecessor to the k5 also
had that had a lot of the same problems
as well but the important thing here is
that many of you may not have seen these
two chips since the 90s that's when a
lot of this was introduced it was nearly
a generation ago so we're now living in
a world where we've gone through I think
like five or six generations since then
and the assumptions have been reinforced
during all those development cycles that
this is how you design a processor it's
no longer a like oh should I add this
piece should I add that piece it's now
like I'm not building a processor if I
don't include all those features I
showed you earlier and we're constantly
adding even new features as well so all
of those things are basically taken for
granted as building blocks for a modern
processor they're likely more skeletons
in the closet because you know this is
coming up just now it's just starting to
show up on the radar as a lot of you saw
recently there was a warning that I
think this past week there should have
been a large release of even more
glaring flaws that were found by the
same project team those got pushed off I
think they're supposed to be released
later on this month
but in my opinion I think that this is
just the tip of the iceberg for a lot of
this stuff so the problem is remember
there's no free lunch a lot of these
things came up because they're like how
do I get multiple instructions executing
at the same time without duplicating my
processors which itself is the most
expensive way to do it how can I do it
cheaper how can I do it faster how can I
do it easier that's the design mentality
that's coming up with a lot of this
stuff software flaws are easy to fix
you know easier than Hardware flaws
Hardware flaws are more difficult but
now what I'm talking about is kind of
the cultural common knowledge
assumptions floats so this is not
necessarily flaws that are in design
flaws that are in thinking so take
nothing for granted
assume nothing is ultimate you know
don't presume that oh because this
happened 30 years ago it's been proven
it's been tested I should never question
it that's not the full mindset that you
want to take
so this is kind of like what I call
vulnerability model for complex systems
every new feature introduces or adds to
the probability of a new security or
just design flaw in general the renew
optimization similarly brings this risk
in times spent analyzing system
integrity fixing vulnerabilities that
actually carries a risk reduction
typically you're invent engineering
firms are investing in these top two
primarily we need to start figuring out
how to measure this probability increase
this risk increase which is not
something necessarily done today that's
not a science that's more of like an art
or one of us pitching up here we need to
figure out how to measure these
properties effectively using data using
recorded history that type of thing so
that then we can build number-3 into the
engineering process not just the
hardware engineering process because
also software design flaws are
introducing the same thing over time but
think about that every time a new
feature and we all know that with my
phones or Facebook or Twitter or
anything like that
you know with what is it Facebook now
with my it's a whole bunch of features
for to try and duplicate what snapchat
does right like basically try and steal
that marketer away they're all chasing
new features and everything like that
but with every single one of those new
features they're introducing new code
that may introduce new design flaws it's
not guaranteed and is very unlikely that
it is ever going to be perfectly secure
we want to figure out how to build
number-3 system integrity vulnerability
fixing vulnerability hunting into the
engineering process because otherwise
it's going to become more expensive or
even impossible to do in a reactive mode
as we've seen with this guy right here
this is a reason why it's it's not
unfixable it's not practically fixable
right now because we've already
installed all these things around the
world and chances are if we were to fix
this right now we would break the world
and that's not something we like to do
so with that very gun to us or I'll
probably get kicked off because I took
too long
you