shortly besides Cincinnati 2018 is
sponsored by GE Aviation no starch press
CBTs cyber-ark
Booz Allen Hamilton Darkrai no security
and the game RSA
and US Bank join the conversation
tweet us at b-side cincy the
presentation will begin shortly
besides Cincinnati as much here as funny
is going to talk to you about active
defense alright well thank you everyone
it's a pleasure to be here and again my
name is Matt Cheer the slides are
already posted online so if you're gonna
take a phone picture of anything you can
grab that first one and even follow
along on laptops and mobile devices
whatever you like I'm on twitter at c3
rkh if anyway we care to follow me
that's strictly a new fo sec handle so i
only use it to basically promote events
i'm speaking at events happening here in
Cincinnati so it's a great resource just
to keep aware of what's happening the
great thing of starting early is that
there's no rush to get through this
hopefully I got time to go through a
couple demo things I wasn't sure if I
would have time to get through them so I
just kind of saving them if there was
going to be time to do that and without
further ado I'll go ahead and get
started again the topic is active
defense helping threat actors hack
themselves so just a little bit about me
already
introduce myself for a day job I'm a
system security engineer with First
Financial Bank also here in the keynote
you heard a lot about attending local
meetup groups I happen to run one in the
chair for the sympa security sig we meet
the third Thursday of each month in
Springdale these meetings are free to
attend all I ask is if you're interested
in coming please RSVP we're on
meetup.com in the tech life Cincinnati
group and I see a lot of familiar faces
so clearly the word's gotten out but
to also see some folks here that I've
not familiar with so if your local bio
means stop on out and our meeting for
this month is actually this Thursday I'd
love to see some new faces myself I've
spoken at a number of conferences this
is actually my third 'besides
since I live and work in Cincinnati this
one's kind of special to sort of be on
home turf and giving a talk and I've got
a few IT certifications with that just a
quick note about my day job so the
opinions expressed are solely my own and
do not express the views or opinions of
my employer and long winded disclaimer
here basically the idea is that the use
of these tools and techniques is really
at your own risk and what I try to do
I'll talk about some of the conventions
I try to point out the areas that could
potentially get you reported for hosting
malicious content so with that just want
to talk about what active defense is and
so there's a nice description here on
Wikipedia they've got an article that it
can refer to defensive strategy in the
military or cyber security arena the
partum of Defense defines active
defenses the employment of limited
offensive action and counter-attacks to
deny a contested position to the enemy
in the cyber security arena active
defense may mean asymmetric defenses
namely defenses that increased cost to
cyber adversaries are adversaries by
reducing costs to cyber defenders and
certainly as we go through this talk
you're going to see a lot of these
techniques will do just that so why are
we here to talk about active defense
what makes this an interesting topic so
regardless of which end of the debate
you happen to fall on for hacking back
the point is right now today it's
illegal to do so and so active defense
is really kind of just next-level beyond
your conventional historic honey pots
honey files and honey nets
and so our objectives today are to
shield and protect legitimate users at
all times we want to be diligent about
protecting innocent site visitors also
we want to frustrate malicious threat
actors attempting to steal next filtrate
data through unauthorized access
preferably by unwittingly hacking
themselves and finally number three see
objective number one again want to be
very careful about protecting innocent
site visitors so that really it's only
threat actors that are stumbling into
our active defense content so the
present are the focus of this
presentation really is for the active
defense of a public facing website and
we're gonna do that by baiting and
setting traps for script kiddies and
other cyber criminals and so there's a
number of inspirations for each one of
these active defense techniques to be
honest with you some of these things go
back so long that I just kind of
remember looking at and I can't even
really source them today but some of the
things in my life many many years ago I
used to study Aikido a little bit which
is a martial art for using an opponent's
energy or force against them my father
I'm not sure how many original ideas he
had in his life but he had one great one
for junk mail and it was this he would
get junk mail on the mail he would
essentially take out the contents of the
envelope and they would always have a
return envelope and he would essentially
take out the parts that would sort of
attribute it back to him that is the
stuff that had his name on it and he
would really mail them back the rest of
their flyer so that they would have to
simply pay the postage both ways and his
contention was if we do this if enough
people did this we'd stop getting so
much junk mail because there would be
such a cost associated that they would
simply find another way to try to
advertise to you and then certainly from
the title slide you saw a number of
animals animal defenses there's a reason
that we don't go around messing with
skunks on a daily basis so you know
certainly nature provides some good
inspiration here and then finally
nostalgia I talked about how some of
these things are so old I can't quite
even source them
I remember one of the things I sort of
took was what somebody used to have in
their old autoexec.bat file for those of
you who remember windows 3-1 and prior
to those days where you would have that
basically startup script that would you
know set up the system and kick off what
you wanted to and then finally security
minded yet a prankster at heart I've
definitely been guilty of having some
fun at some co-workers expenses in the
past that's just I don't know it's in my
nature
we have laughs about its fun stuff we
get together sometimes to still talk
about these things and then finally a
vigilante nature so there's just
something in me that really loved seeing
the bad guys kind of get what's coming
to them
and so that certainly plays into this
that you know sort of make it difficult
for them to continue just going on and
popping websites all over the place so
some conventions use that kind of just
glossed over the disclaimer early in the
beginning so I kind of use this referred
to as a hot water index so you see you
have an incrementing thermometers do
sort of gauge the likelihood that you
might get reported for potentially
hosting malicious content to me it's one
of these things where we spend a lot of
time upfront protecting innocent users
for good reason is it possible that
somebody could current come across our
active defense content and report it
yeah it's possible but to me it's sort
of like the you know the criminal that
tries to buy drugs illegal street drugs
and then they get nailed by the pool you
know they get nailed at gunpoint and
robbed with our money and they don't get
anything in return and they actually
call the police to report it so let's
things do they can and do happen but
generally speaking not too likely so
again I just try to give you some good
guidelines on on staying out of hot
water
and so again the most important focus of
this is protecting legitimate users and
we're going to go through how you do
that on a website and I apologize that
some of this is basic for some of you I
don't assume people here have a
background in web development at a
security conference so I'm sure some of
you a portion of you do so a robots.txt
file what we're going to talk about that
creating a sitemap XML file the
important thing here is that we don't
ever want to link to active defense
content and you probably want to use a
link checker hyper link checker just to
verify you know skinned your spider your
own site make sure that you don't have
things that are linking to your active
defense content it's very important to
make sure that people don't stumble
across this accidentally it's really
only the sort of motivated thread actors
that decide hey I'm going to go ahead
and attack the site and I'm gonna look
for the content that they don't want me
to find and then also we're going to
talk about disabling directory indexing
on legitimate content and then finally
protecting potentially protecting
yourself by making use of authorized
user only messages so robots.txt file
there's a reference out at the top it's
just ww robots.txt org that'll actually
give you the format that you want to use
and in this particular one is an example
of a robots.txt file I'm using for an
active defense site just really for the
purposes of this demo and so the very
first line is basically telling the
Internet crawlers and search engines and
things that query the robots.txt file
it's basically saying here's where the
sitemap is which is going to tell you
where all the good content is and beyond
that what it's usually used for you can
specify for different browsers different
user agents to keep crawlers if you care
to query those the star just simply
means regardless of the web browser or
the user agent that's trying to connect
to our web server go ahead and don't
index any of this
you can see I've got a number of
directories in there and I've also added
comments just to sort of sell the active
defense content and everything here
that's being disallowed is active
defense content again this is to keep
search engines like Google from actually
querying the site and then putting a
link online to any of our active defense
content it's really the whole point of
this file and also it'll keep other
things like archive.org has their way
back engine that will store it
historical snapshots of websites it'll
keep those things from happening as well
so the sitemap XML files and again the
I've got a reference there to the
sitemaps org slash protocol dot HTML
this is an example of one and there's a
lot of lot of stuff kind of in the body
there but really the important thing is
right here on the location and on a
normal website you'd normally have many
more locations than this but this is
what really tells the Internet
hey here's where the content is here's
where the real content is that you
should go ahead and get and so the other
thing I want to talk about is directory
indexing so as a matter of good web
security you should pretty much always
disable directory indexing a legitimate
web content that keeps somebody from
going into a folder that maybe doesn't
have an index file and listing out the
contents to where people can query it
for the purpose of active offense since
very commonly even today people don't
turn off directory indexing it really
just makes it very easy for threat
actors to really find the content of
your site that wouldn't normally be
exposed and so we actually want to leave
this on just for the active defense
content folder so all those things were
disallowed in a robots.txt file that's
really the the purpose of turning on
directory indexing for those so they go
ahead and find the
and this one you know it's kind of a
puncher's chance it may or may not stand
up but in the act of defense folders
maybe just consider putting in a readme
text file or a readme HTML file in there
just with a disclaimer not saying hey
welcome but you know if you're not
authorized you shouldn't be in here
would this stand up and protect you if
somebody reported you for religious
content maybe maybe not you've got
nothing to lose so maybe just good and
throw it out there just you never know
it could save you no guarantees but
worth a shot
so know that we're gonna go ahead and
actually talk about the active defenses
this first one is you see very low risk
I refer to this as the round trip or
yeah the round trip round kick the idea
is that we create a bunch of unused DNS
subdomain host records putting back to
the loopback address and so what happens
with this is that the harder the threat
actors think they're hitting you the
harder they're actually just hitting
themselves and give some examples here
of some subdomains that would be good
candidates for this so you know API app
blog on and on mail mail server new
servers autodiscover or somebody's
trying to you know break into your
exchange environment WordPress so some
of these so basically if they start
trying to attack these subdomains off of
your your primary domain they're
actually just attacking their own system
since it's pointing back to the loopback
address so that's the one defense
the second one isn't really very
technical but it's more of a
psychological ploy and I simply refer to
this one is stomach Viper or gross out
in my case I'm using some images that
somebody could maybe claim copyright
very unlikely but anyway the idea behind
this is that we're gonna stage a none
reference folder when I say on
references or things that are in the
disallow list that aren't referred to in
the sitemap and we're gonna use a fake
door badge ID template now if you work
somewhere if you're doing this for your
company it should look legitimate but it
should not look identical to the one
that you use real-life because you don't
want to give somebody a template that
they can easily use to social engineer
their way into your door so a very
important note there and the idea here
is that we're gonna place gross out
pictures of choice disguises staff photo
headshots just because I have a strong
stomach and I can look at about anything
yeah there may be threat actors out
there or maybe a little more of a weak
stomach and so what I did for a lot of
the content because I first gave this
presentation in front of my boss I
didn't want to end up in the HR office
so it was essentially people vomiting
for the most part now I have friends
that have a really funny sense of humor
and the other
there's nothing off-limits for those
guys so they'll do goatse and neat spin
and tub girl and all those horrible
pictures that you can imagine in this
case I'm gonna spare you that but here's
the idea we have a basically a fake
badge template measured out dimensions
just enough to sell it make it look real
in this case I guess I'm not the first
one to rickroll everybody here today but
anyway just a picture and again just
sort of a fake name associated with it
and there's a whole lot of images in the
folder basically the same way if we can
make the other person a little squeamish
and
maybe make them run away grabbing their
their mouth and throat and heading to
nearest trash can or towable or whatever
that's a win for us another act of
defense I simply refer to as reflector
madness and so the idea behind this is
that we're gonna create an easy to crack
password protected folder but what's
waiting inside is not really something
that the threat actors will expect and
so I give an example of that
here's a login page to a protected
folder on the website you can see it's
just you know basically calling out the
password and it's prompting for a
username and password to get into the
folder I'll give you guys a you know
just a hint that this is incredibly easy
to crack it's probably one of the worst
username password combos you could have
on say a router maybe want to throw out
a guess as to what the username and
password is for this admin and password
absolutely correct good job
and what does that get you so it does
unlock the folder they're probably going
to see this which is really just a
connection refused message but what they
might see is this and what this is is
this is basically if they're running a
web server on their attack system
they're going to be looking at their own
web server at this point and the reason
for that is because inside the source
code for this page is an iframe that
points back to the loopback address so
if an attacker or any web server locally
in their system then they may
potentially attack themselves and so
especially if they have forms and that
sort of thing I sort of take great Glee
and thinking that you know they may not
recognize what they're looking at they
may even be freaked out by it
psychologically because they understand
why am I looking at my own system here
but best of all would be if they it's
something maybe old they forgot they
even had the web server running and all
of a sudden they're firing up burp suite
and they're trying to do cross site
scripting exploits against their own
stuff then at that point they're
literally hacking their own system and
then just sort of a disclaimer in the
source code that you know this is again
just as a seamless iframe and again as I
stated I am NOT a web developer I don't
even play one on IRC so I'm gonna admit
to this so you don't assume that it was
coded by apes at the Cincinnati Zoo just
moments before I got here
so this other active defense I like to
call going nowhere fast
so it's no big secret that WordPress is
by far and away the most deployed
content management system in the entire
world and it just powers countless
websites
I couldn't even estimate how many there
are but because it's so widely deployed
it's also one of the most attacked
particularly with brute force attacks by
malicious threat actors and so a quick
little sort of side note about WordPress
it gets a lot of bad particularly in
security circles and generally people
that know better the core product itself
I find isn't as bad as the reputation
it's not to say historically that that
was true but the real problem with
WordPress is that as was alluded to
earlier in Coleman's talk the more
features that get bolted onto something
the bigger the footprint is the greater
chance for vulnerabilities and there are
a lot of really awful plug-ins for
WordPress and so a lot of what happens
when websites get popped with WordPress
is because they're not keeping these
things up-to-date maybe they have a
vulnerability in the first place I'm
just gonna throw out an arbitrary number
let's say you have 20% of your plugins
out there with a vulnerability either
known or not if you have 10 plugins then
that means there's 2 of them that could
be exploited to compromised the website
if you have 20 guess what now you have 4
if you have 30 plugins and there are a
lot of quote-unquote web developers who
are really just plug-in jockeys and
they'll throw it just an endless array
of plugins to make the site look cool
and do cool stuff without really
thinking about the security implications
so I'm gonna come off that soapbox a
little bit and show you this active
defense for another login page and here
is a very legitimate WordPress login
page WP - login dot PHP this is similar
to what you guys saw a moment ago
anybody want to guess the credentials
for this one
admin admin close but not really
unfortunately there really is a username
and password it's really just a page
that is meant to draw the attention of
people trying to brute force the page
and I've seen enough of logs it's
actually it's kind of a cheap thrill but
you know sometimes I like look in and
you know see the Russian Federation
repeatedly over and over trying to crack
the WordPress login page and it's like
just keep at it guys
maybe you almost had at that time so and
again so it's just a completely
fabricated WordPress login page there's
absolutely no user real username or
password that would work with it so we
just want the threat actors spin their
wheels waste their time energy and
resources trying to crack something that
can't be tracked and it's further sold
by planning the appropriate folder
structure and default files that give
away a site as a WordPress site things
like the license txt file that lives in
the folder root in the readme dot HTML
file that also lives in the folder root
and then the three main folders of you
know WPA and wpa2 VIN there to sell it
so this other active defense that I came
up with I refer to it as pie to the face
and so the inspiration for this one
really was something I started toying
with I think probably back in December
because I got in the ambered with
reading on crypto jacking and it was
sort of funny because there was an
initial little buzz and it really died
down quick and then all of a sudden in
the last three months you've seen a lot
of websites getting popped and they end
up with crypto mining code on them that
will essentially mine cryptocurrency for
thread actors and particularly the more
popular the site the better because now
you have more people with more browsers
more systems hitting the site and I
thought well that's kind of interesting
I you know the concept the amazing thing
is what it would do to CPU cycles and so
really the idea is that we want to use
sort of disinformation and I'll get to
that in a moment
to help them waste their time and also
you'll see where I'm linking to the
other idea is to hopefully get them
banned by larger service providers and
also waste their CPU cycles drain
batteries on mobile devices and then
really this is just kind of using the
threat actors own technique against them
from that standpoint and so a quick note
about the service provider angle if I
ban somebody's IP address from attacking
me no big deal you know I've got one
domain of just countless number of
domains they'll just simply move on to
the next one there's really no pain
there even then if they have a big
enough botnet they can attack from
another IP address but what will happen
if say Google or Yahoo will not me so
yeah which Yahoo Facebook Twitter if
some of these big providers start
banning you then you've got bigger
problems and I don't know what their
thresholds are and and what they'll you
know what it takes to get them banned
but that's you know worth a puncher's
chance I think and so the set up for
this is
we have a webmaster folder and it
contains a fictitious bookmarks dot HTML
file because if you have a domain that's
got a webmaster and they've got a
bookmarks HTML file that's a treasure
trove of information that a threat actor
would want because now they can you know
get a grip on you know sort of what
things are being implemented in the site
the sites that the person uses Neah
those things could even be used in
watering hole attacks there's just
endless amount of information there and
my idea to help them kind of waste their
time on that is staged non-existent
login account links to popular sites and
services that they would want to waste
their time attempting the brute force
and then you know as I mentioned before
hopefully they trip whatever thresholds
that service providers have in place and
then by the way behind the scenes were
computationally calculating PI hundreds
of thousands of times and then we're
just washing rinsing or repeating with
that and so this is what the bookmarks
HTML file looks like and I specifically
chose Facebook Google LinkedIn Microsoft
Live ID Twitter Yahoo anybody want to
fathom I guess why would use those sites
what why those would be enticing targets
to a bad guy it sort of got hinted on
when we were listening to sort of how to
recover passwords maybe from somebody's
past on these things are used for single
sign-on all over the place to a
malicious thread actor if you get
credentials for one of these me and Eve
about get keys to the kingdom because
now you can log into all kinds of sites
and services that use single sign-on and
so baiting the trap is you see email
addresses webmaster at the domain I
registered cyber nanny comm for all of
these these are accounts that don't even
exist on these services and as I was
sort of playing around with this some
interesting notes got Facebook to work
exactly the way I wanted where
pre-populates the username actually
couldn't I didn't spend a lot of time on
it maybe less than 10 minutes
I couldn't reverse-engineer Google's
enough to get it to pre-populate the
username but the idea here is that they
can read it and
in text and they'll spend cycles trying
to crack webmaster on Google's website
and again potentially get them banned if
nothing else just waste their time on it
and resources LinkedIn another one I
think that one populated that that one
had an interesting effect so will
populate the username into the field if
you're already logged in it represents
the login page even though you're
already logged in if you're logged off
it didn't fill that in a sort of
interesting thing I actually changed the
Microsoft Live ID the actual variable
here I have it as email and if you click
on that it'll let you try to register
that email account
I believe they actual correct what is
username and the reason I changed it is
Microsoft has been around a long time
they go back to the 1970s unfortunately
their live ID login page also seems to
have security methodologies to go back
to the 70s
it'll outright tell you if your username
is incorrect not your username or
password your username so somebody could
very easily script out a way to
basically numerate valid usernames for
Microsoft Live and it'll tell you it's
username if you get the username right
then you know you know that you just
need to work on the password to crack it
so just to try to keep that out there I
went ahead and changed it again it does
pass that into passed that along like I
said it will then let you register that
email address it's already cached in
there
Twitter works exactly like I expected
and I believe Yahoo did as well and so
the source code for this the bookmarks
HTML file why it's pie to the face a
couple of reasons one is I had the page
set to refresh every 3.14 seconds and so
what I found what I found is I've gotten
calling to JavaScript files there are
really identical files just two of them
at the end of the the file just to kind
of further sell it what this is doing is
this is computing PI over
/ and it's computing it over three
hundred fourteen thousand times each of
those so we're over six hundred twenty
thousand computations for PI I'm not
interested in mining cryptocurrency I'm
interested in just really tying up their
CPU cycles and it really uses the same
technique it's just used for a different
purpose and what I found is I can
increment this number and it'll take
even longer the delay is even longer but
what I discovered is this it'll actually
pop up in the browser and warn the user
hey this is taking incredibly long time
to load you want to kill the page I
didn't want that one I don't want to tip
off the bad guys I don't want them to
know hey there's something funny going
on with this page you should look at it
and then - I don't want them the even
worse if they stop the page or kill it
then this instantly stops this as only
as long as the person's there it's not a
persistent attack so that's sort of the
other reason for having a book where
it's HTML file is it'll hopefully keep
their interests where they keep that tab
open and continue working on some other
things so that's the the root part of
the face is just computing PI a lot of
times refreshing every 3.14 seconds and
I found that I sort of when I put in a
decimal point I took on less meaning
like I've had a whole number in there I
might watch I'm I realize it's reloading
the page but you throw a decimal point
in there it just sort of bleeds in with
all the other metadata that you see when
you look at what page source code and so
the CPU impacts to attackers is on a low
powered system like a dual course this
machine or VM that can spike it all the
way up to 100% CPU on a moderately
powered system like the workstation I
have here that gave up to 50% and if
they're running something that's Java
based and really heavy like you know
burp sweet even washes app all these
Java applications just really really eat
up a lot of CPU so if they're already
running about a 50% load this will push
them all the way to the top this is also
gonna grind them
to a halt while they've got that page
open and then just another note hey if
they're on a mobile device and the CPU
instead of running at seven three to
seven percent which would be like normal
idle I think for most systems you know
they're gonna be running peg that's
gonna really drain that battery down
quick and force them to a power
receptacle somewhere so and then this
one now we start getting you things that
yeah these things might get reported for
malicious content potentially again this
is why it's so important to you take
those early steps and protect users from
the stuff that are legitimately using a
site the idea here is I call it the
wrong answer because I'm taking the old
42 zip and I'm basically giving it a
name like employee salary history ex
lesap and so some of you know what this
is some of you don't know what is 42 zip
well it's simply a 42 kilobyte
compressed zip file but when you
decompress it all out it'll expand over
4.2 petabytes worth of data and the
important thing is here that most people
most cyber or data thieving cyber
criminals they're gonna have a hard
drive that large and so just show of
hands here like who here has had to
recover a physical machine because I ran
out of disk space anyway there's a few
hands in there I have and it's a real
pain in fact I've even in the old days
would have to take the drive out of the
system essentially cable it off as a
secondary drive on another system and
then delete the data off of it as a
secondary disk just to free up enough
space to even get the thing to boot
again
this one's incredibly relevant because I
was actually checking out my active
defense website that I had what running
live and Thursday night I was actually
talking to a group in Deaton and we were
talking about app sack I was talking
about accidental exposure which is a
three now on the wasp
top ten list
and what I found is that my demo didn't
work with my site when I got home later
I checked it out and sure enough the
server will respond the ping requests
but the web server itself isn't running
because it's run out of disk space after
I logged into the cPanel I got that
pop-up so it really grinds things down
to a halt I'm kind of spoofing things on
my local system just because the live
site actually is still down
they have I've yet to see an update to
my support ticket so who knows how long
that's gonna be but yeah if your hard
drive fills up with data if you try to
expand the file that you think is the
keys to the kingdom
that's gonna be a bad day for you as a
threat actor and then this one I is
directly inspired by this xkcd exploits
of a mom comic strip and I'm sure a lot
of you have seen this already probably
more than once but again exploits of a
mom so the mom gets a call from the
school hi this is your son's school
we're having some computer trouble oh
dear did he break something well in a
way did you really name your son Robert
drop table students oh yes little Bobby
tables we call him well we've lost this
year's student records I hope you're
happy and mom says well I hope you've
learned to sanitize your database inputs
and so the setup for this is that we're
gonna stage a fake employee database
dump file inside of a none reference
folder and again I'm gonna go look at
your human resources folder here we're
going to give it an enticing name such
as you know we're just going to date it
human resource information system
employee my sequel database backup that
zip or you could have it not compressed
and just put the native sequel out there
what's interesting is I actually got
this from somebody actually had kind of
a course or a little program and they
put it on the my sequel yet repository
they had it basically split out a bunch
of smaller sequel dump files mini dumps
that would essentially all ingest as one
big file I went ahead and imported the
whole thing and exported it as one big
sequel dump file and I think it's you
know over one hundred and sixty Meg's
decompressed that's about thirty Meg's
or so compressed just to save bandwidth
so hopefully the bad guys will take this
because it's enticing enough and they're
gonna try to import it but there's
something in there
aside from fictitious variant believable
employee records that they probably
aren't expecting there's some extra code
in here and it's putting near the bottom
not at the very bottom you actually have
to scroll up just past the comment code
at the bottom of the file to see this
stuff I couldn't find a way and my
sequel dumpty all of the databases so
the best I could come up with was drunk
basically dumping the internal database
files my sequel assists the performance
schema and the information schema and I
put information schema at the end
because it's the one schema that has
read-only information in there and what
I found is it will only drop it so far
before it hits the point where it has
the read-only data and then it just
stops doing it but by that point the
damage was done and for those of you
have recovered a system from a full up
disk trying to recover a database once
you've lost your internal database files
oh that's a really bad day that's even
worse than
the if you don't have good backups
you're pretty much you know cooked in
that situation it's kind of funny
because a lot of times the threat actors
will get on their high horse and well
you know you should have backups and a
lot of people in security well you know
you need to have backups and so forth
well let's find out how well they eat
their own dog food right so if they
import that and try to run it and the
great thing is it takes a while so this
thing is running for a few minutes
before then you know the database is
wrecked and you try to restart my sequel
and it just doesn't happen and so there
are some other avenues for alternative
active defense options I'm not the only
one that's doing crazy stuff like this
but I think probably the one I most want
to plug is Black Hills information
security they have ADHD which is the
active defense Harvinder distribution
and it's a great project it's basically
a distribution they go about a little
bit differently so they focus a lot more
on attribution they'll use things like
canary tokens to basically phone home
and the ideas that hey we can use this
to understand where the threats coming
from I'm a little less interested
reporting people and more air sit and
maybe just teaching them a life lesson
and and hopefully making them reconsider
some of their life choices and then
finally sans SEK 550 they have a class
that's based on this distribution so if
this is something that as a project you
really like to get running with probably
a very good course do you consider
taking so that's another option that's
out there
so with this stuff criticisms
yeah I've gotten some and is I've given
this talk and discussed it with other
people one of them is sitting in the
audience today who thought you should
really make that reflector man this
Login harder to crack
now that was before I improved the
payload because my philosophy was I
think there's merit to having an easy to
crack thing that really makes the bad
guys think yes I've won
and then in this case it actually points
them back to their own server that they
could potentially try to hack so but
you're in control ultimately you could
make that thing as easy or as hard to
crack as you want I went with admin and
password just because I really wanted
them to sort of look at their own system
something to try to attack so some
people that are on the penetration
testing side you know say hey well this
stuff's gonna make my my job more
difficult to try to help you secure your
environment so the idea here is that you
really want to have good documentation
prepared in advance for a white bat box
and gray box and great engagements and
so some of the things you can explain
what the content really is in your
robots.txt law in your sitemap file to
give them some guidance so they know
that hey these things are sort of
trapped and I don't want to mess too
much with this content I might want to
look at some things just to make sure
that there aren't other vulnerabilities
but you know it's just it's one of those
things where hopefully if it's not a
total black box box engagement you can
sort of share that knowledge and since
you have those files they make a great
reference point to say hey beware of
this stuff and then just some other
things had somebody say well I'm not
gonna let this it's gonna really tick
off some skilled attackers and they're
gonna become vindictive and really come
after me then so the whole point of this
is that malicious threat actors are
really undeterred today the reason they
keep doing what they do is because they
don't fear retribution particularly if
they're out of country chances are
nothing will ever happen to them in most
situations unless there's a big
financial component to it or a big PII
breach and also the other part of that
is that they don't fear retaliation
because hacking backs the illegal and
they're usually using other people's
systems to do this stuff anyway
consequently that's why they're going to
keep it up there
keep compromising vulnerable systems and
then finally as another point if you
want to if you're a little fearful of
what may happen to you as a result of
implementing this stuff here's some
inspiration Brian Krebs who runs Krebs
land security comm fantastic
investigative journalist writes on
information security topics he's
authored a book called spam nation this
guy's had death threats he's had people
try to swat him he's had people try to
you know frame him for drug trafficking
all sorts of things the fact that this
man is still alive today tells me that
you know maybe he shouldn't be too
fearful if he's still alive I'm sure
he's a much bigger target than I ever
would be and ultimately the other thing
that you read is he writes some post
mortems when people go to jail it's
amazing because then they want to become
friends with him because they actually
respect the fact that he took time to
fight back and if you're still not
convinced in this stuff you know if it's
not up you know if you're not do it
there's nothing that says you have to do
it look I'm just here to give an
edutainment talk on some information
security topics and you know take it for
what it's worth that's something you
want to do then do it if you're still
weary there's nothing that says you have
to do this stuff so I've got a little
bit of time here I'll just do a couple
real quick demos on some of this stuff
so one of the things that you might be
thinking is like hey I you know you
talked about all this stuff and making
sure that the bad guys will find it but
how do I really know that they're
actually gonna find it
let me see here that's not looking very
good didn't you see if I can
if I'm getting some screen artifacting
from plugging a dongle we just go ahead
and relaunch his app here bear with me a
minute
so the question is well how do I know
that the bad guys were really going to
find this how do I know that the
malicious threat actors are actually
going to find the content that I put out
there one of the reasons I know that
they will is because I'm familiar with
some of the W get command line options
that enabled them to do this
the other is because there are plenty of
great tools out there for testing this
stuff like a wasp zap and quick note it
does require Java just like burp does
but it's a very good sort of you know
lightweight tool for testing application
security and you'll see here in a moment
let me go ahead and
and hopefully what this will show
everybody is just you know sort of how
easy the starting point this stuff is
I'm literally just going to
well let's see or didn't like
you try something here bear with me
there's a mentioned before the demos
will fail
it's off intentionally I'm actually
spoofing it in my local box here we go
what's that a typo in there so very
quickly this is just kind of running
through and crawling the stuff and
apologize if it's a little bit of a pie
chart on some of this stuff but I just
want to point out a couple quick things
so you can see it's using the initial
folder as a seed to understand where
else that should start crawling not only
is it not going to ignore our robots.txt
file definitions - for the content it
shouldn't skin it's actually going to
try to use that file against us as a
seed to know hey the juicy stuff must be
in these things they want to keep me out
of here's where I should actually look
so it's breaking all the rules and the
same thing at the sitemap file it's
using that location as another seed to
know what content it should go after
it's really as it starts trunk crawl
this stuff means you start looking
through this stuff here's the protected
folder the webmaster folder it's
actually very easy to just hit export
and
put this out to CSV file and then you
can simply open it up in calc or Excel
or really anything capable reading CSV
files any text editor will do it
certainly we go ahead and pull it up
which rights one put all the stuff here
pop it up here and okay and naturally it
opens up in the other window and drag it
over here guys
and so at this point it's basically a
really easy to get I can just you know
really even copy the URL straight out of
here use W get curl really just copy and
paste this stuff put it directly in a
browser this isn't really too hard as we
start looking through here you see the
wordpress login page all the folders
that sort of give that away here's where
like oh this is juicy this is an
employee salary history spreadsheet file
again that's really our rename 42 zip
let me see you know a lot of the other
content here
and if we go on and on we would see the
here's the database file that'll
basically dump out all the my sequel
internal database files that sort of
thing so that's how I know the bad guys
are gonna find this stuff I have no data
about that and just show one more aspect
of this and then I'll wrap it up so
putting demo pie to the face here a
little bit so this is H top and you see
the first four are the CPU cores on this
laptop you notice it's not really
running resource intensive at all
that's pretty lightweight so let me go
ahead and
open up a browser window here
here's the bookmarks file again we
talked about that we have an H stuff but
I close that out
we look at our CPU
quite a quite a difference from just
barely a couple bars on each of those
cores right we're paying you know
hitting all the way up to sixty some
percent this was a lower powered machine
the impact would be far worse you see it
drop down so that's that three point one
four second refresh because again I
don't want tip off the bad guys as to
what's going on with that so really
that's sort of the crux of what I have
so any questions
right well yes
so yes you can absolutely and I do use
the inputs in the logs to assemble some
nice password lists for the fake
WordPress login page
definitely renders itself well to that
purpose so all right there any other
questions I'll be around if you want to
hit me up and talk to me later on again
thank you everybody for attending
[Applause]
you