yeah all right anyway Jarek Stanley
Microsoft Security Research Center
leader the bounty program here today to
tell you how to earn even more with
Microsoft bounty program with some
simple concrete steps but also things I
think you can apply to other bounty
programs across the industry so I'm
going to give you a little introduction
the program but by understanding the
program not just thank you not just a
pitch for Microsoft bounty but things to
understand and leverage to use to
exploit to earn even more bounty for
Microsoft some quality make up some
examples of high quality reports
something that's kind of new for our
program tell you how we measure how we
define this and how you can use those
same variables help your reports or even
more about it as well as some new
updates from the program I've made some
recent changes in the last few months a
few these I'll talk about with you guys
do today the first time we've talked
about this publicly to make it even
easier for you to succeed so intro
Microsoft bounty program encourages and
rewards security researchers or
researching Microsoft products finding
security vulnerabilities recording the
Microsoft and working with us through
coordinated owner Billy disclosure to
fix and publicize the bug so our buddy
program has opened it anybody whether
you're a full-time security researcher a
hobbyist part time we're just keeping
your skills sharp on the side so it's
from open to all we believe that the
partnerships with you guys here in India
and across the globe
are one of the best ways we can work
together to secure our customers and the
overall ecosystem so you can submit any
time on any product but I will give you
a couple ideas about what's at in scope
where we really focus and we reward
initial research and how you can learn
about that and focus your research in
the same areas even in addition to
bounty we welcome and we'll review every
case you submit to us on a case by case
basis if it's not in scope for a bounty
program we still offer recognition
awards for anyone it helps us fix and
secure and improve on products it's a
really great way to build a professional
reputation we recognize people through
CDs as well as through online
submissions on our websites
so bounty program let's see let's make
sure this is the right thing yeah so the
power bounty program covers a rough
launch of different Microsoft products
to include office and windows as well as
clouds cloud services also those online
services at your DevOps office 365's
large breadth of Microsoft products with
rewards from $500,000 to 15k for from
office insider up to 50k for windows of
owner abilities head up to two thousand
two hundred fifty thousand dollars for
Hyper virtualization or some other
really complex really tough and really
high priority for Microsoft issue areas
but overall across all our bounty
programs just this last year we paid
over two million dollars
and Indian researchers make a really big
contribution there there's a lot of
talent creativity engagement here in
this room and around the country here so
just when the last year we paid over
ninety thousand dollars and bounties to
Indian researchers that's twice the
amount that we were able to award last
year and four of or Indian based
researchers have made our top 100 both
for Bali submissions as well as simply
for contributions to helping us fix our
products so how do you how do you earn
those bounties how do you get on that
list from a high level I'm gonna move a
little faster just to make sure that you
get to the content I'd love to leave
some time for you guys these questions
two key takeaways and these are very
high-level we'll get it to more detail
so you can actually use but the first is
submitting high-impact
reports on high-priority products earns
higher rewards and the second is by
improving the quality and completeness
of your reports can also improve the
amount of bounty will earn per record
show us how to reproduce your findings
and I'll show you a bigger problem so
first off for that first point the high
impact high priority high-value number
one is read the bounty briefs we do as
much as possible from an economics
perspective this is called limiting
information disparity I want you guys to
know as much as possible what we value
and what we reward
what's in and out
over the program I'm investing the last
few months and the next coming months to
make that easier needs to adjust more
and more information for you to start
with so you know where the target energy
where to target your creativity and
where we are offering them bounty awards
and what bounty works with Possible's so
end of the day I loved to award bounty
to free research for anyone across the
globe it's in scope absolutely out of
scope reports to learn no bounty and we
offer as much information and up front
to help you know what to expect a second
point that at Microsoft we use what's
known as a stride model to think about
the impact of pretty long abilities
stride stands for security tampering
repudiation information disclosure
denial service and elevator the
privilege and the bounty program have
also added remote code execution type of
elevation of privilege but it's
something that's really important to
spear of our products it's all offering
a higher award tier for those types of
vulnerabilities so there's a link down
on the slide I've got some resources in
the back those presentations learn about
this but what's what's in it for you the
takeaway is that we speaking at the same
language about a vulnerability we can
move a lot quicker through understanding
what we're looking at it and make sure
that we're getting right and buy right I
mean retired highest possible level
award for it vulnerabilities found I've
baked these directly into how we set the
awards for abdominals so for remote code
execution critical capability go ahead
little bit up on the volume you said
awesome hey thanks for the heads up I
appreciate that is sometimes hard to
hear in the back so for high critical
remote code execution we offer up to in
the cloud bounty specifically $20,000
which is quite a significant uh bounty
award elevation of privileged critical
severity eight thousand dollars even
spoofing were a lot of cross-site
scripting
falls three thousand dollars for an
important severity high quality award
but you notice here you have a lot of
phrasing it's up to up to how do we
decide up to what well there's another
vulnerability to play or another
variable apply I should say called
quality um in the day the takeaway is
the higher quality you're at
the more value awards we offer for that
report that's not too bad but I'm going
to tell you a bit more about how we
measure that and give you an example
building on the same report about adding
more and more information specific
information that gets you from a low
quality to a medium quality of a high
quality a low bounty to a medium value
to a highest value possible but
productive or provide clear concise
information about the vulnerability
including a version configuration data
or possible really improves our ability
to begin to reproduce researches
vulnerability respond to you fast within
your out of scope and with a boundary
reward well written instructions
well-thought-out repro steps in the
cloud bounty and more than double the
award for the same vulnerability give us
more information give us make more
effort and will reward you for that and
then even addition if you can talk about
attack vectors some root cause analysis
potential fixes I'll take it even
further it's more valuable for our
customers it helps us understand how
best to secure them and we really want
to reward you for that effort so let's
take a look at some real-world examples
of low medium and high quality reports
so the first one it's kind of goes
without saying but I've got to say it
anyway we've got to be able to reproduce
the report this is one of my favorites
it's all your stuff is broken
description and fix your stuff bro now I
appreciate the extra bro it's a little
personal note there by any of the teams
we can't reproduce the teens just enough
information you start investigation
we've got some incredible minds Matt
Miller and others Gaurav who is here in
the audience today will do everything
they can to figure out what's going on
but in the day if we can't repro it what
can't award you a bounty or recognize
you for helping us protect our customers
and the broader ecosystem no low-quality
examples now I guess I think I'd like to
rephrase quality into completeness
because this is still this is a very
useful report it gives us some general
domains some description of what the
vulnerable are seeing and this earns a
bounty reward absolutely it gives us
enough to start our investigation figure
out what's going on and think about a
face so this
we'd love reports like this but the
result is potential a little slower
response to your submission they'll take
us longer to read through this do some
investigations see we can find a lower
bound reward of course this is sort of
the minimum formation to qualify bounty
as well as if we don't understand it the
same way you do we may not give you the
right again right read hired as high as
possible bounty award so this same
report if you added a little bit more
information can move to a medium quality
and even the higher board self same
report here's the next step clear
concise easy to read easy you steps to
reproduce these vulnerabilities again
real or exemplar so we received work
through and rewarded this exact report
so sharing some of your thinking how our
teams can reproduce so huge help this
gets us a faster response we can
understand right away what was going on
reproduced on our own systems and start
working towards the fix and start
awarding bounty also it helps us
understand the same way you did so we
make sure we award you at the right
level of bounty and then uh yeah this is
this is pretty darn good most
researchers will stop here but I want to
give it an extra idea of some steps you
can take even even high quality a higher
quality and even higher award from the
Microsoft bounty program some of this
stuff you'll see echoed in Adams
presentation in Jason's this morning but
certainly applies to Microsoft on a
program high quality analysis or
additional analysis some additional
thinking Adam said one of the things
that they're looking for for folks to
hire through buying programs which
Microsoft does as well it's your ability
to articulate to think kind of share
your story so analysis about root cause
I'm even code snippets potentially where
the patterns are where you see this in
other products this is incredibly
valuable to the team can't get us
thinking beyond this specific
vulnerability to other vulnerabilities
help us get the best fix for our
customers in the ecosystem and we reward
you for the additional effort this is
just one example but I hope by showing
am low medium high quality gives you
some concrete stuff I'll put these
online right after this present
that you can use in your vulnerability
submissions but let's see how this pays
out so stride understand the impact
quality severity equals exactly bounty
this is the same information it's on our
public website if this was an elevation
of privileged bounty you can see the low
quality report would have earned $1,000
she's still pretty significant we really
want you to report to find and report
vulnerabilities and will thank you for
the effort no matter what that level
effort is but adding those reproter in
person steps yeah this is pretty small
you might not be able to see that in the
back of the room but it doubles the
bounty and will go from $1000 thousand
US dollar bounty to a two thousand
dollar bounty
add those additional thinking that steps
about attack vectors talking us through
how you found the ability how you're
thinking of the patterns multiply the
value award by five under five thousand
dollar bounty for adding that additional
information we know this is hard it's
sometimes difficult it's hard to find
them all and really start it late to
understand them we really want to reward
you for that for that extra effort we're
doing this in the cloud bounty this is
actually the payout structure and table
from the cloud bounty the windows
donated a DevOps bounty but rolling this
out slug to all of Microsoft's bounty
programs let's see how we doing with
time let's queue bad talking to the team
about any other tips I could share today
with this community and the folks that
maybe read this presentation afterwards
to others laying out your assumptions is
a really big help if you've made
particular choices in your your repo
your system your set up making that
explicitly reports of big helps the
research engineers on our side will you
just have a brand new test system to
repro and if they've missed something
that you've done on your end it can
often take a longer time for us to
respond understand and also and this is
Adam mission the same thing share us
share with us your thinking from the
attackers perspective what can you do
with this vulnerability how did you find
this vulnerability really helped us kind
of get into your your head there's part
of you there's often a lot of work and
energy that goes into these but that's
not all can make it onto paper so put it
on paper in a structured format I'm all
try and reward you as possible as high
as possible for it
and finally Hartley finally we're
working to make it easier if you succeed
in the value program every day the joke
here is the number one way we make it
easier is by releasing new code and new
products it's always easier to find
suitable for the protis and new stuff
but in reality we're also changing how
we run this program how we engage with
community to make it easier for you to
succeed so three ways we've done that is
the last couple months one eye crease
rewards across the board in Windows
cloud and Azure DevOps from 15,000 to
20,000 for our top award and cloud and
up to 50,000 US Dollars our top award
and it does it salt reward you more with
higher bounties for the same products
one of the major ways we're hoping to
improve the experience of that bounty
program is awarding your vulnerabilities
on our ability to reproduce it in the
past we've waited for a fix to be
confirmed which means a few weeks to a
few months before you even got any
feedback of whether it's a good
vulnerability and what kind of bounty in
like you might earn so in the new system
with cloud and Windows as soon as we're
able to reproduce your availability
we'll give you the assessment and we'll
offer a value award whether we fix it or
not we really want to thank you for the
effort if we recognizes the value on
durability we will make that award we've
also changed our duplicate policies
Microsoft employees over 3,500
securities festivals professionals or
researching and continuously securing
our products every day we find a live
our own vulnerabilities but it can take
us some time to determine the fix and
release that if you're the first
external researcher who's found this
vulnerability and report with us we'll
still give you full bounded weather we
knew about it beforehand and not why
because it still creates a lot of value
for us and our customers to know that
you guys can find it without code source
code access without some of the training
and context and abilities you can find
it outside it lets us know the priority
for fixing it and can even help us
determine what the best way to fix it is
so we've made these three changes
awarding quite a bit more for bounty
orden quite a bit faster
for bounty and awarding everything
that's coming in the door that's new to
us to make it even easier for anybody
who's researching on Microsoft products
to succeed yeah and we'll keep adding
things to make sure that your experience
with the Adamic program is successful as
possible so here's a slide some
additional resources learning more about
the program about the stride model our
thoughts on coordinated vulnerability
SCO's disclosure and some recent
presentations
my team and I Grogg Matt Miller and
others ten years putting out blogs over
the coming year to help researchers get
started one of our first with some hyper
hyper virtualization a hyper-v which
offers bounty Awards up to two hundred
and fifty thousand dollars it's huge for
us it's really hard it's really
complicated but it's very very important
so why we offer such high bounty levels
and it's also why we're starting to try
and provide some more contents and
training to help you guys get started ok
it's still very difficult there's a
reason why we have to we're offering
such a large bounty but we're trying to
give you as much as many tools as
possible as much idea and context to get
you started so from online services to
Windows to office some of our more
esoteric more complex cloud services
particularly be putting out more and
more and more to help the security
research community engage and welcome
your feedback at the bottom there again
you guys probably can't see in the back
of the room us but there's some email
address give us your thoughts your
feedback what you'd like to see your
experience we're always listening to
what we're hearing and trying to make
the best diamond program possible so
wrapping up this leave us a little bit
more time for questions first one is
focus on high impact in scope high
priority targets best way to do that is
read the bounty brief we're gonna keep
playing out more information keep
expanding our scope as our products and
services change the second is improve
your core quality by adding additional
information some of those concrete steps
that give you example about free Pro
steps attack vectors on suggested fixes
all of those will earn higher and higher
bound Awards and then finally we're
going to continue to grow expand this
bounty program both in ways that easier
succeed
and that make it easier and more
productive for us to engage the better
the scope Microsoft is Microsoft is
growing quite rapidly especially cloud
and so those services as those products
grow as a complexity girl I'm going to
build the bounty program to match that
to better secure our customers there's
always going to be new opportunities set
up in the program so check back as I add
more online services more domains and
keep moving forward
so end of the day I hope you guys are
able to walk away well some of the
presentation with some ideas about if
you're already pissing the program how
to earn either hire bounty Awards and
looking like with other programs by
sharing some of our thinking combined
this what Jason was talking about was to
Adam talking about think you've got a
better idea across any both bounty
program how to succeed how to grow even
higher about your boards and yeah I
think that uh that about wraps it up
thank you guys so much for having me
it's really a really great chance to
talk to you thanks for your patience
would be neither at the presentation
with us lower rough start but I
hopefully you walked away with some
interesting information and I didn't
love to talk to anybody
half the presentation we've got a few
minutes here so if any wants to ask some
questions for the crew happy to uh to
call on you if not I'll be here for the
rest of the confidence to look to meet
you any questions guys sure the question
is how to get a license to use some of
these products like hypervisor to
conduct research on our bounty page we
provide a number of areas where you can
register for free accounts especially
like cloud and online services and yeah
if you're interested you can always
contact bounty of Microsoft comm you can
find a way to give you the resources you
can to get your research started that's
a really good question you're right it's
not all this stuff is is necessary free
sometimes it requires some registry
there's some extra steps to start your
research alright guys well then I'll
wrap it up thanks so much for your time
[Applause]