yes so I do you want to do this yourself
to the audience
hi my name is Betty Suarez
I'm a French independent security
researcher I guess for the people who
know me from Twitter I'm used to tweet
about security issues and values helps
website on offense under the username F
Society so last year I started to work
on official other application other
applications so I found several issues
in it so I started to have a lot of
photos in India and started to discuss
with a lot of info signals from India
after that I you lolly position other
leaks on some vulnerabilities in India
in Indian websites I also found some
interesting stuff in the demo
application is the application of the
Prime Minister so it's a pleasure for me
to to connect with the Indian InfoSec
community and to be able to discuss with
you even if I'm not physically here in
India and I can discuss with you so this
is cool
why do you think you're not in India
what's stopping you from coming so sorry
what's stopping you from coming to the
country can you look it yeah yes I guess
as if your government doesn't really
doesn't really look what I'm doing and
sometimes people don't like when you
will show some issue in their in their
systems website or application and
iPhones
one issue in either under all phones
Prime Minister applications or I will
not take the risk to come in India fauna
yes
the other thing I can fight yeah maybe
maybe one day you guys yeah okay so I'm
gonna ask you few questions and then I
keep the suggestion open for the
audience questions asked why Indian
websites Indian applications you know by
the you know or even political person
why India yes this is a question and
this is the most frequent question and
receiving on Twitter why's the hell a
French alike means pinging so much time
on India haps on the website so the
answer is quite simple if India is an
amazing country we've has many
challenges to face with a population of
this size having the future of
cyberspace is an almost impossible task
so this is why I'm so interested by
India because there is a lot of history
improve and as a security researcher of
this is super interested to study this
kind of system when you are so much
people impacted by the same system the
security aspect of this systems are
super interesting and to be honest my
initial encounter with India is a pure
is clearly random at the beginning of to
2018 a lot of my followers
asked me to check the ADA application
the official Android application like I
was young guys I asked me so I decided
to give it to Luke and I found like five
of fifty hundred mobility big
venerability
so after that I started to receive a lot
of exposure events like the Indian media
and my Twitter icons started to become a
famous among the Indian and forsake
community and I started to have a lot of
Indian followers and with all these
followers I discuss a lot on the disk I
started to tell me I found something in
the Indian application can you ask me to
contact the concern company as a concert
- I tons of my phone call
can you do something for me and this is
what I'm trying to do I'm trying to help
people to to contact the concern company
when they function when they find
something and I'm not paid by a pretty
girl Katia whatever
yes and I'm working at war as we develop
her it's like a as you want for a
startup based in London
my main focus today is Richard I'm
working on Richard on whatsapp so I'm
studying or to get messages and trying
to find some reliability inside this
messaging application so this is my date
but I'm afraid and so on quite happy in
what I want to do and in what I can do
so which is why we have so much time - I
have time to spend on Twitter's okay so
tell us
network from what we do
time's up appearing in public yes
appeared I think last week on an Indian
news channel as well oh we have problems
with the Internet
of Audion things
the folks while we fix this if you have
questions to ask him please be prepared
we will float the mics in the hall okay
and you would be able to ask him
so just fixing the Internet okay so
rejoining again
okay yes will you let us know any of
your experiences in reporting issues
with the Indian government or any
politicians yes of course so first
making responsible disclosure is and
this is very common especially in a
country like India where you have a lot
of yaki level and where I can be super
complicated to contains a person in
charge but contrary to what people tend
to think when you manage to reach to the
correct person people are pretty nice
and when you have some technical guy
talking with you in general these people
want to fix the issue when I disk use
for example with application team of the
900 II application this guy were pretty
nice with me and I just wanted to
understand what was the problem on all
to fix the problem so I know making
responsible disclosure is complicated
but you have to try you have to try to
contact concept companion you have to
keep in mind that the most important
things is to protect the personal data
of people so when you are communicating
about an issue you take care if you are
some personal data of user at risk they
came to me one minute after publishing
my tooth is a contact and say some me a
private message and on Twitter
one minute after do you have any message
to the Indian government on how they
should ensure the security of the
infrastructure or on the UID system
after all
I'm working on a deal for more than one
year I found several issues I try to
contact you ID several times but this
guy as as only one organization who
never answered to me and I always denied
what I found and accept accept lame
press releases they are doing nothing
and they try to fix silently the issues
so the first step should be in my
opinion the first step should be for the
googleman for you either to be nice with
security researcher please listen to
them give them an email address to some
issues gives them a secure channel to
communicate the issue as they are here
to help you they are here to fix the
problem and to make the system better so
security researcher the InfoSec
community is really a friend on the one
who makes it good you IDI pvp or five
degrees I never take fitness ok another
thing I may have not done my home book
I'm not studying much but most of
issue that I think you have either
reported in public is not the data leak
of the CVR
or UID system it's actually by different
departments or different agencies that
use that system right yeah we found that
we found a leak in front of some
shorties website by using the idea that
if fungus or some issues directly is the
ideal system on the they don't listen on
at least as I don't communicate with
security researcher what it was the
issue they fund but my change so this is
also this is also the responsibility or
you iodide to - Angelo's a GI bleed that
is safely stored values of your parties
because because if third party of patent
company is authorized to collect all the
data of this companionship a secure
storage for feed data because it's not
acceptable for continue to stir and you
indicate you I don't know what it was
the official document in a open
directory and n DS by D so finding some
inner cat directly for google searches
is not okay audience do you want to
reveal anything interesting or about
your name interesting stories
[Music]
yes I'm working on different stories
it's not finished yet hands me as the
analyzes not finished so I will add ISTA
right now better we will have mostly to
come for all for sure yes okay any
questions from the audience yeah so I
understand some background on this that
some agencies that use other data is not
you know clearly maintaining security
aspect or will this be something
question to the NCI ap folks here will
this be something you guys can help
people like Baptist to kind of middleman
that yeah I'm just trying to get a
background for all the other folks you
know who wants to disclose some
vulnerability so I'll just pass on the
mic to you sir is that okay okay the
question was to it yet yeah the question
was to Elliott know it's kind of you
know I'm trying to set the roads on
where we can solve this issue you know
your question is do you think NCI facie
in bridge this gap exactly yeah okay so
we have an agency call as NCI a PC that
would like to be a part and associate
with you you do responsible disclosure
and reduce the gap between you know the
government then the security community
so if you would like to talk to any
organization in the country I think NCI
PC would be Allstate agree for it yeah
he was he is it the question
all right any other question
no no I just wanted to add one more
thing when you get in touch em anyway
talking I know they can hear me but when
we're talking about okay I'll say it and
then you can draw in it so when we talk
about our VDP and we talk about giving
us an importance let's be patient to
communicate the problem he has to
understand the problem somebody has to
fix the problem so all of this takes
time if you give us an input and expect
us to fix it in 24-48 hours it may not
happen that doesn't indicate that
nothing is happening you know if you
tell a major company or major
organization boss you got a problem he
has to accept the problem own it then
only will he fix it so when you report
something be patient the input from the
organization of ncip see is that when
you report something they request you to
be patient it can't be fixed
but in a day or two there are procedures
and policies follow in order to fix an
issue because everything is not in their
control they have stock to meet
different stakeholders so this is the
response or input from the organization
do you have a response to that or yeah
yes yes yes I am I have some some issue
with that because when you have so much
data in at risk when you have me in yeah
at least your personal data of people
occurs on the malicious people you can
explore attendance data easily
a policy that don't help what process
under just done so data on cell the data
to people who want to buy it
so having policy process is okay but you
have to understand that malicious people
don't have a bishop is why I am so
interested and I so I want to fill the
issue as quickly as possible because if
the data at risk managers people just
get it so I have no problem to discuss
with any agency I don't have any problem
I'll collaborate with police the
government and it will be a pleasure for
me but you have to be dynamic and you
have to understand that you cannot take
months to solve an issue and this is
what I managed to do thanks to my
Twitter account some for example for the
latest ADA leaked I published we try to
contact the company for four days I'm
saying never answered but just after the
leak and just after a secure secure a
publication as they fix the issue in
three hours so it's possible to fix the
issue quickly and once again malicious
people don't care about process
different question so how do you choose
your applications to find bugs how do
the how do you use that I didn't have a
clear process to be honest I have a big
big to-do list with a lot of application
names that may need followers and on
Twitter thanks to the pilot Michigan
listening when I'm seeing that a lot of
people who want to analyze and the same
petition and understand nice application
to my to-do list and thanks so much and
I'm sure that the community has
committed to bring you safely to the
country and make sure your return match
NCI PC has agreed to take help from you
and ensure that they would fix it okay
okay so there is a link called our VD P
dot NCI pcs are done in a V DP at the
rate ncip see the dot in is an email
link so an email account which you can
report was abilities to he doesn't want
to listen to you
so yeah there's an email address or
related responsively disclosed
vulnerabilities - and I think you should
do that you have been doing that in the
past but this is an official statement
I was officiating but response from one
of the organizations that they would
want you to report issues and Magne be
teased to them and they would take it up
with different organizations and
stakeholders to fix it happy to today
this kiss well I would be happy to
discuss with them onto the chat whistle
and by email that have a chat a dynamic
chat not just in a exchange all right
which possible I thank you so much thank
you