hi everybody sorry that Ravishankar is
not not here because like he had a minor
accident and then he's not able to join
the conference but I'll be replacing his
talk with something different although
I'm not that familiar with you SST and
it's too old for me for me something
that's interesting is like in C caches
and stingrays so I'll be talking about
that like all the work we have done in
the last six years and then what has
come up something new and LTE but also
maybe something that's interesting in 5g
or what are the attacks that can happen
in 5g and what are the mitigations are
all this stuff so I'm actually studying
I'm doing my PhD in tu Berlin and Ravi
Shankar is in Norway so we work together
most of it most of the time we are doing
like cellular security research but
since we are on to the like moving or
moving quickly to the 5g and LTE so we
are mostly focusing our work on LTE and
also we do a lot of protocol analysis
which is something really essential on
the research point of view then doing
implementation bugs or something like
this this is also interesting but there
are some limitations like regarding
finding implementation bugs which which
is something different when it comes to
IP world we also do like secure network
building like helping different
organizations trying to build secure LTE
networks also what kind of mitigations
they could use for building a strong 5g
network because a new network doesn't
mean that or a new technology doesn't
mean that it's solving all your previous
problems and then maybe there's a nice
technique to hide the previous problems
and then just market it like wow this is
the new technology and then we are in a
safe world so this talk I just give a
recap of what telco attacks look like
what kind of attacks usually usually
your phones or the base stations or the
cellular networks can experience
sorry then I talked about like two main
important aspects of cellular networks
the first is like privacy and the second
is availability so which is nothing but
availability of a service
of LTE users or in terms of LTE networks
so and then some setup or all the stuff
we used to perform so many attacks and
then so what's the basic problem like
people some people keep asking you like
okay we know that MC caches exist in 2g
and we are now going to fight G and this
problem hasn't been solved yet so what's
the reason like why like why is this
still prevailing and then the the there
are so many strong minds in the world
and that that are not able to solve this
kind of problem so what are the reasons
for that and the kind of impact or
status that we have brought into 3gpp so
that many of the privacy and
availability issues could be fixed and
then I give a little bit inside into
fight G and see leave it where like you
can what kind of research directions
that could be open or for more research
sure if you are interested before going
into the thing like some basic knowledge
about mobile networks like it's it's
quite simple you have the phone you have
the base station which are talking over
there the base station is connected to a
core network which is nothing but the
kind of a central server which is
managing authentication and encryption
of all your subscriptions like so
whenever you insert a SIM card it's
talking to the base station and the base
station reports back to the core network
it would send all your details of your
SIM card and the the core network like
this performs the authentication of of
your SIM card if it's a legitimate one
or if it's a fake one based on that then
then comes the point of security where
over there encryption is setup between
the phone and the base station there
could be also a security level between
the core network and the UE u v is
nothing but a phone so sometimes like I
I get used to this terminology like kind
of technical terminology which is
defined in the specification so u V is
nothing but the phone in note B is
nothing but the technical term for base
station so I interchangeably use them so
moving to telco attacks like this is a
simple flow diagram of all the all your
mobile communication so whatever data is
you are sending from here it goes to
base station to the corner
welcome to the Internet so the first
attack the most popular one is MC
catches MC catches also called as
stingrays so these are some of the
popular like powerful devices that are
being used by governments or state state
agencies or even a lot of hackers and
lot of criminals to actually track users
or to intercept communications to create
denial of service attacks or you could
do a lot then you have when you own one
such device so the thing is like with
this the attacker has to be in the local
region like here these are not remote
attacks so the the the the power of this
attack would be like the range that the
base station is actually covering up so
all the phones that are falling under
the range of this base station or this
MC catcher are really affected and it
depends on like what kind of attacks
this MC caches are playing so basically
like in the beginning like that the term
MC catches was like okay NC is nothing
but it's the permanent identity of your
SIM card so every unique or every single
card in this room has a unique number
called NC its international
international mobile subscriber identity
so if I can if I own this identity it
means that I can really identify you
wherever your SIM card is going later
like when they when they try to increase
the power of these devices like they try
to add interception capabilities where
they can secretly listen boys
do lot of denial of service attacks
either beat on the phone or on the
network I'll show you some some denial
of service attacks and some privacy
related attacks like in the next slides
then the second type of attacks like man
in the middle so there is somebody
sitting in between the phone and the
base station and trying to decode at
least some kind of channels let's say
for example broadcast channels are
usually unencrypted so it's it's quite
easy to do to get access to such
information for example like if somebody
is having a kind of passive device that
can actually read the broadcast channels
or the frequencies of a mobile network
operator can actually
some meaningful information about the
operator and try to use it to actually
establish an MC capture device which we
saw before
third one is interception like a passive
attacker so these these attacks are
difficult to detect because like there
is no noise being made by this attacker
on LTE like doing a passive interception
attack of voice is something not really
possible yet but maybe somebody can can
try on GSM it was quite successful
because GSM didn't have any proper of
security so people were actually able to
passively listening to voice calls and
try to play them back so GSM was kind of
something completely broken down in
terms of security the popular one ss7
most of them are crazy about but the
thing is like you need to get an sa-7
access or find the endpoint that's
actually answering all your ss7 queries
these attacks actually originate from
the internet they do not sit at the air
interface so they dig their remote
attacks and can be performed from any
part of the world so somebody having an
access to a Jamaican operator and has a
shady connection to so many parts of the
world can actually request the operator
to send your location location in terms
like Wichita where you are connected to
and exactly like some kind of what are
the GPS coordinates of a particular
phone which is far away or like in a
different continent so these attacks are
really powerful not only this location
tracking attacks also all the SMS or
calls can be divert to a different phone
number so these are really powerful
attacks and hard to do unless you have
necessary access some denial of service
attacks like where you have like since
flag attacks simply very have like so
many malicious phone that are trying to
attack a base station and then so that
you keep the network busy and not trying
to answer the legitimate requests from
so many phones so these are some typical
attacks that actually
happen in mobile networks so last five
six years we try to play with lot of PVC
caches lot of sting their devices and we
try to build some of them and see what
kind of attacks are really possible on
LT because like when LT was introduced
in 2009 there were a lot of requirements
like okay this should be proper security
compared to 2g or 3G and there should be
the the privacy levels or expectations
were really high but we wanted to test
it out like does this really possible on
LT because like it's we know that it's
possible to operate the base station and
then we wanted to test it out so we we
first targeted like what is privacy and
always the phone is it's kind of a
favorite target because like everybody
who owns one and this could be something
that's easily attackable and see what
happens on that but now with 5g even the
cars or small IOT devices are really or
or your home devices can actually be
controlled by mobile network so now not
only phones even small low-power devices
like narrowband IOT are are actually one
that will to to so many attacks that
that happened on 4G and 5g so when I
talk about five C so we are actually
talking about three different things the
first one is trying to compromise
somebody's identity the second is like
trying to get the location the third is
like how do you hijacked DNS on or like
hijack or do a man-in-the-middle DNS
attack on somebody that's using an LTE
data traffic we know that these these
attacks are possible on 2g but we wanted
to try them out on on 4G and see like
are they really possible but since this
is a repro talk so all this work they'd
dates back to 2015 2014 so okay the
first bug we found one was on so many LT
phones like by standard like the phone
should not reveal its IMEI i mia is
something unique to your phone so once
somebody that's leaking leaking IMEI on
the air interface it's possible to
identify a particular
person at a particular time in a
particular location so we we gathered so
many LT phones that time I think it was
around s 6 or s 7 or Galaxy s5 or even
iPhone 5 iPhone 6 we started playing
this devices so we try to send a special
message that's called I'm sorry a
special message called tau reject which
is nothing but a tracking ad update
project that actually deletes certain
kind of security context in the phone so
by doing this the phone is like
completely refreshed now so it's in the
state like you inserted brand new SIM
card which doesn't have any kind of
security context in the phone which
which can actually protect the phone
from sending the IMEI
to rogue devices so for a network it's
fine - actually I made a religious
magnet in network it's completely fine
to know your IMEI because it's it's
required for example in in the states
like where you don't have a SIM card
they do the authentication based on your
IMEI but but here like in Europe and
Asia we usually use SIM cards so we have
other identity called
MC which which we actually use to do the
authentication so you found a bug and it
was affecting most of the vendors like
ok hardly if you count there could be
maybe five or six different baseband
vendors who are actually manufacturing
this mobile chipsets for example like
welcome Intel who of a or media tech so
there are a few manufacturers and then
we try to report this back to them so
that they could fix it I think it took
maybe five or six years to actually fix
this kind of bug so at least ok I'll
tell about like the the bug fixes and
everything may be up sometime so this is
the first one like which which actually
affects the privacy of LT subscribers
moving on like I showed like there are
different identities that are used by
the phone we know that in C is something
related to sim IMEI is related to phone
and there is other entity called him see
okay we can also call it like GOP I it's
nothing but a temporary temporary
identities that could be used in place
of your permanent identities for
something like whenever you try it
whenever your phone is trying to connect
to the network it would obviously send
its temporary identity and this was
actually assigned by the network so this
could be used to to hide your identity
whenever you are sending your data over
the network in case a phone is not
having a temporary identity it could it
could also send its MC but this this
rarely happens and it should not happen
because like it's there's no point of
using your permanent identities it's
like sending your public like like
private key to somebody so it's like
that so we found like so many issues
with operators like we tried different
networks because like I said this
identity is something that's being
assigned by the network operator to the
phone at different points like whenever
you turn on your phone and you turn it
on again it's common that your phone
receives a new identifier any new
temporary identifier we tried like
repeating this experiment on different
networks like like here so I try to
attach my phone register it I get the
first temporary identity after maybe
five minutes I I repeat I turn it off
and then I turn on again it registers
and then it gets a new identity so the
thing here is like I think this is
something from from Germany and this is
something from Finland so we see that
the operators assigned you a temporary
identity actually this should be a
random number but we see some kind of
uniformity in this random number so
we're only the central digit is only
changing but the rest of the digits keep
keep on the same so which is not really
nice in terms of hiding somebody
somebody's identity over-the-air so this
actually allows to track a particular
purse a particular person's location in
a particular place for example like if I
if I am passively looking at the network
or like passively sniffing the network
if I see this identity today and if I
observe the same kind of
tomorrow it means that this person is
still wandering in this location or
somehow present in this location so it's
kind of leaking your course location but
not really precise so we wanted to go
more precise like okay by using this can
we can we get more precise location of
the user and compromise more privacy so
then we went on with something like
measurement reports so these are nothing
but okay let's take a simple simple
simple case where when you are traveling
your phone is switching from one base
station to the other so and this happens
on the fly like you don't really notice
that there's some kind of disturbance in
between unless you have a power
connection so as you're traveling your
phone keeps sending something called
measurement reports to the network so
this campaign actually the information
of of all the signal strengths from the
nearby cells and their identities so
this is like a huge report with so much
of information that's actually telling
precise location of your phone and once
this report is received by the network
it verifies that appear so you are
actually going close to this tower so
maybe I can handle you to that
particular cover and then your call will
be shifted and then that's how it goes
on according to the standard the 3gpp
like the standards body which is
responsible for making the the stand
that's like our FC for example at for
the Internet they have made in the
standards that this kind of reports can
actually be sent by the phone even in
without any authentication or security
so we try to exploit this bug and then
not not a bug but it's a standard block
we try to set up a rogue base station
like like an eensy catcher and then try
to collect and try to ask the phone to
send measurement report so the phone was
quickly sending its measurement reports
without even though like there was no
any kind of authentication or security
so we tried this on different phones
because it's the standard block all the
manufactures are like who are trying to
implement the standard so obviously
they'll implement are actually affected
with this vulnerability then we found
something called
a ratings failure report the the kind of
functionality is similar between radio
link failure reports and measurement
reports like the for example like when
you are going to and when you are inside
and escalate in an elevator like maybe
sometimes like your call is dropped or
you have like poor signal coverage so
this is some new feature that got
introduced into LT so whenever there's a
poor connection underwritten there's a
radio link failure like you lost the
connection but the phone would
automatically create a report and this
report actually contains like all the
information from nearby cell towers and
also like on which particular cell or
base station this this kind of poor
coverage was happening so that once the
operator receives this kind of report we
can actually use it to to troubleshoot
like signal coverage issues or improve
the coverage and I mean ultimately the
purpose is to like make the network much
better in terms of performance according
to the standard we see that it's it's
it's kind of like mandatory to have
security for this kind of reports but
but we found that most of the vendors
are not really implementing security for
like no like we don't know like why they
didn't implement security for this kind
of messages there was no reason for that
and we try to exploit this so we could
actually receive reports from all the
phones and try to use this information
so after this we moved one step ahead we
wanted to see like if it's possible okay
okay this reports can actually carry
your GPS like with respect to Y of your
enabling or disabling in your Android or
your iOS because like the baseband which
is sitting below or the master of your
phone has more access to the the GPS
chip compared to your Android or iOS so
we thought that okay maybe we can send a
GPS request to the phone and then try to
get back a GPS coordinate from the phone
without actually using any kind of
security or authentication so so this is
like I'm on LTE
then I'm an attacker and I don't have
any kind of keys and I can send like an
establish a base station and try to send
a GPS request to the phone over the air
and I can actually receive the GPS
[Music]
LTE so all the IP data messages that are
being sent from your phone are not
integrated protected so which means that
even if a man-in-the-middle actually
modifies this message there is no
mechanism to actually verify by the
network it was not defined in the
standards thinking that okay most of NLT
like people are mostly using apps and I
think it's the responsibility of the
apps to actually considered about data
modification but if but like these guys
thought okay so this is the thing let's
let's let's see if we can crack the DNS
part so whenever your phone is accessing
your web page obviously it would send a
DNS request and usually there's a
certain kind of and these DNS are like
HTTP so even though if it if a packet is
like encrypted and its head GDP and it's
DNS so that if you can observe the kind
of pattern between all these DNS
received packets it's possible to modify
certain bits in that so that you can
actually divert the DNS request to your
fake DNS server like I said there is no
verification of or like there's no
protection against man-in-the-middle
attacks only for the user data but the
control plane data is actually protected
so so all the IP traffic can actually be
hijacked by this kind of attack so these
are some of the issues related to
privacy then moving on to availability
it's nothing but like denial of service
we know that most of the stingrays they
actually operate based on the principle
that they can downgrade from 4G to
coogee like since most of the attacks
are somehow difficult or LTE it's
possible that you bring the audio Jam 4G
network and then you bring so obviously
the user would move to seize your 2g
network making the attacks more simple
so we tried like three three different
attacks and the last one is something
that's actually targeting the network
not not targeting the phone like with a
board trying so many attacks on the
phones and we wanted to shift the focus
so we thought okay network why not
target the net worth instead of phones
because like targeting a targeting a
network is more
challenging but it's if the impact is
even more when you are targeting a group
of phones so the first attack we tried
was like based on a certain message so
there's something called a tracking area
pet reject message in understand that's
defined so if you can actually send this
message to the phone with the particular
with a particular called something like
LTE and non-lp service is not allowed so
when you send this message to the phone
what the phone does is like it and it
immediately enters into emergency mode
so and it doesn't regain normal service
until you restart the phone or in some
cases like until you remove the remove
the SIM card and then reinsert it again
so this is kind of like a denial of like
persistent Dass because like the user
doesn't really know that okay this kind
of message transaction has been happened
between the phone and the network so
it's kind of like silent and it requires
reboot of the phone to to get back
normal service then there's the second
one
like downgrading the user from 4G to 2 G
so there are like some special messages
called hard are series I'm not for it
basically it's clear but something
called our RC release where you can
actually specify a particular frequency
of 2g network and you can actually kick
the phone from a 4G network to a 2g
network and the once the phone is on 2g
I think like we can do lots of stuff
like without we can actually bypass
encryption and don't do authentication
and then you have like plaintext
exchange traffic between the phone and
the network so it's like taking down
everything maybe sometimes user might
notice that ok why I'm not getting the
4G service why I'm on I am like why my
phone is sitting on 2g so maybe feels
like aware of such things but I ok he
cannot detect these things on the phone
[Music]
then the third one is like poisoning the
BTS so like I showed before they were
like the phones are sending something
like measurement reports and radio link
failure reports so these reports are
actually collected from the phones and
are accumulated in the net
so whenever there's a failure and then
the phone tries to send a report and the
the base station or or the whole network
try to accumulate and save the support
and later use it for like
troubleshooting network coverage issues
so let's say on a particular base
station if it's really performing bad
like if it's accumulating maybe thousand
reports per day which is some kind of
somewhat like a severe issue because
like the wood I mean the performance
like the KPIs are something like the
performance indicators are something
like it should be 96 percent or some
some when the documents show that it
should have a performance of like 97
percent which means that you can drop
maybe ten or fifteen calls per day but
that's too much but for some operators
like it could be different depending on
the place where they install that base
station so what we tried is like we try
to create such radio link failure
situation we try to create such scenario
to the phone and make the phone
experience the radio link failure and
make the phones to send thousands of
such reports to the network and the
network actually blindly trust these
reports and try to use it to control the
settings so in some documents like some
base stations we try we played so if the
phone is like if the performance is
dropping below 96 percent they would
actually blacklist that particular base
station which means that they won't
allow any kind of handover to that
particular base station or in worst
cases like they could really turn off
that base station and try to maybe
install a different one or or send a
service service guy or somebody like to
repair that base station this is
something with it again some protocols
called self-organizing networks I don't
know if you are interested you can
actually Google about self-organizing
networks and some attacks on that ok
these are some of the set up we use
mostly we well we like since I'm doing
and I can make research like we have to
be a bit more open so we have to use
something that's available in the open
source area so that like for example
like we use software's like opens open
LT and SRS LT to demonstrate like proof
of concept attack because like the the
problem with operating such such devices
is like it's illegal to operate an MC
catcher unless you have a legalized
permission or or you purchased a
particular frequency to operate in that
in that region this is some of the man
the middle setups and then we try to
keep the cost of the attack low I was
doing training and then people were
asking me like can you can you use like
lime str because device like us RP costs
a lot so the line str is something
that's really cheap like maybe $200 or
something but this one comes around 1200
so there's a huge cost difference but
with the huge cost difference also comes
the capability so with this you can
actually do more compared to this one it
catches like prevailing in LT like why
are they still existing so basically
like I can go get back to two reasons
why because the thing is like the phone
always wants to connect to a strong
tower so whenever is yeah like even
though you if you are not using your
phone your phone is constantly listening
to so many cell phone towers nearby and
just keep keep observing like okay which
one is the strongest one and then maybe
I can connect to it or switch to other
one so if you can operate one such base
station with a strong power you can
actually attract so many phones this is
like trying to attract the phone then
after this like okay you can ask me like
okay there is something called mutual
authentication in 3G and 4G there are
like so many security algorithms or like
they are using AES and they're using so
much but but why again like we still
have the security attacks or like
privacy or or something that affecting
the denial of service the thing is like
in the standards and implementations
there are like certain messages that
could be actually used even though if
there is no no authentication and no
security so in that case an attacker
like who has knowledge of these
protocols and who has knowledge of some
implementation and access to such
devices can really perform such attacks
and really cause a huge impact so
regarding the status so we try to like
before going going public or like before
trying to inform so many authorities or
like vendor we try to play with so many
devices I mean luckily like we don't
have to deal with thousands of companies
like it's good that we deal with some of
them and then you you do good so at
least some of the attacks we tested like
they are applicable to most of the
networks worldwide whenever like we
travel to conference like we try to
collect traces from different networks
for example like let's take maybe every
country has like at least three
operators or sometimes like only two so
along with that like not recently but
like the basement vendors they started
to have something called like like the
vulnerability disclosure programs like
which are already existing in Android or
or I was like like for so many years so
we try to inform them about these parks
and try to discuss like what are the
practical implications of this and when
it comes to a standard implementation or
like when it when it comes to the
standard law it takes a lot of effort to
convince somebody from the standard that
this is a really a problem and we don't
fix it like there are a lot of impacts
which which might arise then we have
some some friendly organization called
GSM a it's nothing but an alliance of so
many operators worldwide so they try to
help us and distribute our work so that
you receive comments or like cross
questions from different operators like
sometimes they are not agreeing what you
are saying
so when you try to convince them and
then try to answer them so you can
really create a huge impact going
through this kind
disclosure program and 3gpp the standard
body recently they started to have some
kind of vulnerability disclosure program
so which could also be interesting to
use if you are doing some kind of
cellular security research ok what's the
status now like what's the thing now
like with the new phones like we have
iPhone X or like some some new phones
like can we can we consider that like
they are secure yes at least iPhones
which we usually test somehow taking the
privacy and the availability issues
seriously so they try to contact us and
then like see what can be done to
actually fix or sometimes like some some
flaws are not really like they cannot be
really fixed unless you do major changes
so maybe they could be a workaround to
actually fix those issues like I said
like the IBI um maybe if you buy a phone
from 2018 it's not possible to receive
the IMEI of a particular phone unless
you have proper authentication and then
security I'm talking about LTE but these
attacks are still possible on 2g but but
anyway it's old and it's already like so
much of research there so we are not
interesting in that then coming to use a
data integrity protection which I was
talking about DNS hijacking this issue
is actually fixed in 5g and it's really
difficult to fix in 4G so you can expect
like all the user plain data is
integrity protected in 5g so this is a
major change in 5g okay regarding the
availability like I said the attacker
like whenever he tries to send a message
to create a Dass on the phone like the
user has to manually restart the phone
but there's a workaround that there's a
timer which actually allows the phone to
reconnect to the network whenever the
phone receives such a message because
this is also important for low-power iot
devices because like sometimes you place
I were 2 devices somewhere far away and
cannot be manually like
elected or like operated so for such
devices it's really important that there
should be some kind of timer to Auto
reconnect to the network then for the
redirection like bringing if a user from
42 to G you actually need some kind of
authentication message or like
authentication procedures to do such
attack actually and this a nice study
like at least finally the 3gpp is
actually considering to actually deal
the problem of fake base stations this
problem has been in 2g 3G and 4G and I
think it will also be in 5g so there is
some nice work which is going on in CCPP
standards like about what are the proper
solutions to actually deal with these
fake base stations I mean nothing is
finalized yet but it's it's a study
going on and they consider different
solutions and which one is best so
according to that they proceed maybe
like you might think like okay if I I'm
a user like I'm a normal phone user and
then I want to protect from this kind of
privacy attacks or like availability
attack there are some applications like
Android apps which could be installed on
the phone and then they try to
continuously monitor like such attacks
but somewhere in 2017 we actually tested
all of the applications I don't know if
you are familiar with this slopes niche
it's actually in a tool from SR labs and
some of the applications like that shirt
or even there are Android in secret so
detector something like this but we try
to test this application by actually
operating MZ caches and the most of the
applications really fail in detecting
simple reason is like they are open
source and the free so there's not much
research put into that we also tested
some commercial applications like for
example there's a company called
gsm k the the build some military apps
and we try to test em she catches on on
their MC catcher detectors but there are
still so many issues that acts that are
actually not solved in in the place of
in c catcher detectors we're actually
coming up with a new tool that can
actually help
normal phone users like to actually
detect attacks on the 4G phones because
there is no detection yet available for
4G phones like I said okay this is some
some reference to to the fake base
station work that's been going on in
3gpp maybe if you are interested you can
just take a look on the door
okay what's boarding 5g like is 5g going
to solve all the problems or what is
just the hype in the market okay
at least your SIM identity is protected
your phone identity is protected and
your user plain data is protected so at
least there is certain level of
protection is being considered from
rogue base stations but still the
problem is not as solved and there
should there's actually a lot to do
from the basement vendors perspective
like you could use a proprietary
solution and put it in your baseline so
that that's actually detecting all the
attacks but but still like I would say
like there is a lot of scope and work
still pending in that section okay
takeaways is like if she catches will
still exist in 5g but maybe they won't
be able to catch the AMC but still
they'll be able to do some other attacks
like some of the new attacks or for new
ways so you still have to wait and see
because like we will not have a real 5g
Network until 2021 or or in practically
like I would say it will take like 2022
to have a fight G network like as
deployed as an LTE network or even more
and apart from that like we talked about
like I would be these taste very very
often the the cool thing is like
nowadays like I would devices are being
integrated into the mobile network so
you can actually control them through
mobile app and when you are integrating
such devices into the mobile network
layer you really have to be careful in
terms of implementing implementing your
applications on the IOT devices so you
cannot completely or
lightly depend on mobile network
security and then just they can neglect
the application level security I can say
like at least the kind of testing we do
I can say like a phone that's really
stood in 2019 his at least is somehow
safe from most of the attacks actually
mentioned in this talk yeah though
that's the end of the top and then if
you have questions or please okay so
let's talk about like you're making a
like yeah yeah yeah you're browsing the
web page like so there's a man in the
middle
who's yeah I mean that's what like you
operate a base station like a man in the
middle is nothing but it's operating a
base station plus a phone so like maybe
if you if you see this one like it's
operating a base station on one side and
it's also operating a four on the other
side so whatever this is a victim phone
so it comes to this one and then through
this it actually passes on to the
network no no they're not going that way
but so most of the attacks we are doing
are actually on the head interface
that's the main interesting point for me
yeah okay I would go with USRP even
though if it's expensive there could be
like two reasons it's stable compared to
blade RF and other devices and the some
like some of the open source software
which which are available for research
on the internet like they mostly are
using USRP so when you buy a blade RF
and then you're looking for the software
and you're actually missing the drivers
so so you have to put additional effort
to integrate the driver into the
software and then use the application so
why do you want to take this extra
effort sir
[Music]
actually the base station which an
attacker is operating he's never
connected to the real network yeah so
this is a wireless medium so everybody
who has an antenna has the right to
transmit so and somebody knowing the
frequency can actually transmit so
there's no way unless you have the
proper detection ways for example
jamming could be detected jamming is
nothing but some kind of noisy signal
that could be detected but your offer
if you are operating in a proper LTE
signal which is a legitimate signal so
even though if the network operator is
we are listening to the signal you might
end up thinking that this is a normal
signal and you can just avoid it in
Siegen aha they have access to the
diagnostic logs so all the messages
coming from so to install such
applications you need a rooted phone or
some phones like which come with this
diagnosis so they key they continuously
monitor for like monitor reading this
messages so based on this for example
like if they receive something like
paging with MC this is something not
very common in the normal network this
is something malicious network so this
is one way of detecting but still
because like the whole base band is a
huge state machine and you cannot just
detect based only few few parameters or
you have to consider a lot to actually
detect properly detect an instigator or
else like you end up
giving false positives and which will
actually annoy the user so
[Music]
[Applause]