so here we got Army Corp from Detroit
you're reinventing the wheel how are you
doing this but we we're going to go off
our our original project was called
reach detroit and basically what it is a
bunch of nodes that up across the city
it'll be a computer fed information
center so by that i mean people will be
able to upload events and things going
on in different communities and they'll
be up at party stores and libraries and
things like that or something like we
just like the center recycle now yeah we
can have one out front here cause local
people are coming to recycle like
there's block party there is you know
food drive there's these different
things going on so that was our original
concept and we're gonna go with that and
put our unit this time is going to be
more portable and it's going to be
specifically for eastern market so it
would be a portable node for eastern
market okay so I am Hank I'm a member of
omni credit or a based in eastern market
detroit michigan and the omni core
Detroit team participated and redbull
creation and created a demonstration
project for a messaging system that
could be a platform to get community
messages out to all of Detroit's
neighborhoods we started with a
demonstration project that was based
around the idea that it would be placed
in eastern market it's a kiosk and it
brings people together to prepare food
that they've made in the market make a
smoothie maybe grill some veggies that
they've bought but in the meantime they
can look at the feed of community events
that have been submitted through a forum
on reach detroit us and it'll be
submitted on and displayed on to the
screen at the kiosk and at the same time
as they're socializing with fellow
residents they can also find out about
community events oh that was
intentionally to respond to the request
in the Red Bull creation contest that
the creation meet a community need
when we