[Music]
Hello everyone, we continue with Andean 8.8,
there is no doubt that all the presentations have
been of a high level,
clearly we have all enjoyed them, do
not forget to invite your contacts
that we continue, we have a very
intense day and with surprises there will be
prizes for  We are grateful to those
who stay until the end.
Juan Oliva from
Peru joins us Juan Oliva is a
computer security consultant with more than 14 years
of experience, he is very involved in
projects from tim to hacking, analysis and
exploitation of vulnerabilities by e.on
of social engineering physical security
source code review has executed
garden ethics projects for a
variety of companies where he has
developed projects for the
Peruvian state as well as for
national and foreign private entities juan is
instructor resources dedicated to the garden and
fertilization is like  legal professional
linen where he has had the opportunity to
carry out training in p  erú as well
as abroad and as a speaker at
various events in spain, mexico,
colombia and peru
with current certifications of
gh
cpc cpc
ycswy also the lp and c1 certification of
comolli in a correct professional institute
this when you are going to present your
paper that they are of  messer josh and the
vulnerabilities that it deals with the
implementations that companies make
the technical and cultural changes
necessary to adapt the
erbol methodology by introducing
practices such as continuous integration continuous
delivery continuous monitoring of
infrastructure as I have seen then
we passed and stayed from the  go from four
forward
to see how good afternoon
thank you very much for the presentation
an introduction first of all thank
in the organization of 8.8 Andean that
has allowed me to approve my
presentation in agreement and
without more because the time is short we are going
to start and good the talk  It is highlighted
the possibility is that I remember my name  Re
is Juan Oliva, well, I did the
presentation, actually, rather
than reviewing the subject, the certifications
and all that I would like to say, let's say
comment on them, well, I have been a
linux user for many years.
book but if from time to
time I publish let's say some papers I
remember some technical documents
then this
let's say a little let's say I published one
about the pool for services that
have my twitter I manage a blog where I
pointed to the things above all that I
do not want to send me so the  I invite
let's say to visit it and in fact
let's say part in the practical part of the what is
called of the talk and they will
also find it there ok then let's
see first to talk about this this
this issue of that cops and we have to
talk in  first instance about ops
ok because actually it
stood out seems as a consequence of
this let's say
and let's say of the pops in essence ok
then when  we are talking about the box in
reality it is
let's say that the union or the pac or in
some way the interaction between the
operations part and the
development part ok the famous eps and the
famous ops that are let's say both is
the operations part then
This has changed a lot in agreement because it is
not only about implementing,
let's say, new methodologies but also
implementing a new way of thinking
about development.
implement a
circus a let's say a construction cycle
and continuous developments in a very short
time because their intention is obviously to
reduce implementation failures not to
wait until until the last
let's say to realize that there is
a failure in what is called this in the
en  the development of a module that was not
taken into account et cetera et cetera and to be able
to do what is called
rollbacks very quickly  Mind ok is then
let's say that this need what it has
done is that it can be generated
let's say deploy the applications and it is
finished testing today we are going to
find a lot of
rock software terminology so the
blogger term is let's say generate or postpone
production frequently
software products then that
is a bit let's say what what
the ideology of the pops involves in
general.According to then to see and
behind that what we find is a lot
of practical terminology.According to
we find the first issue that is
integration  continues that it is nothing more than
the automation of the
code generation process ok
let's say that it is normally previously
all developers kept their
code and within their own within
their own machine today this has
obviously changed with this new
form of development no  we're all
talking about hosting a let's say
developers are hosted in a
ce repository  ntral their codes and they
generate through various, let's say,
various versions with the objective of
obviously correcting errors and
continuing to advance in development,
we call that continuous integration that
we could represent in this way,
other than the developers have,
let's say, their code repository and
through  They are doing puig no if
we talk about terminology there
towards a central repository and generating
many versions until they manage to have,
let's say, their final product, ok then
that could also be represented,
let's say in this way, many
work teams that in the end use a
central repository  as a lab
and let's say that
others say the product is that in the
long run what they do is the same to know a
central repository ok then
then we talk about
continuous deployment according as one
more step to continuous integration
then the study of continuing
we talk about releasing of
automatically changes made from
repos  Itories to say that we already have in our
code, let's say in the repository and what
it does is that it is continually
grabbing for it or any mechanisms or that there are
and if it stands out because in reality there are
many mechanisms to do this ok and
that is also a strong point to  take
consideration to grab that repository and
then then some software
software mechanism to make or play to
the production environments I run
then these would look like it is
forming then from the
central repository there is some mechanism is
software that grabs in the
central repository and the  leads towards it pushes the
code so that it begins to build,
let's say development at the software level,
one of the best known
software that makes
me almost in kings obviously but
obviously there is another type of software,
let's say that it also does it, why
then we continue in the flow  the
developer putsches into his
jeep repository a nutty
whatever and this and then
something lets say q  eu in the continuous delivery
what tools like jenkins
grab detect in this change and what they
do is start building a directive,
start building and this is the
development itself, let's say at the software level,
which is why a
lot of technologies are handled  As the
artifacts through a repository,
let's say the query of the records
in December, we work with
containers, etc.
It is automation of the
process of creating infrastructure
from code ok we no longer speak in the
traditional way where we did
say next next next
to create a virtual machine or create,
let's say, certain environments according to
we are not talking about it through
the code these are created  environments
say to host or to deploy the
software
then here tradition  At least we can
talk about docker in agreement but
obviously behind that there are
much more complex things such as govern et is an
agreement so it will depend a
little on what it uses at that
level let's say each company ok there
also where they are generated let's say  It
opens the range of things a lot for us, an
agreement then
then through a code is
inserted, let's say in the
development in these forms
of software repositories, whether it is
rocker governing containers or
through ranchers, which I do not want to
focus on software in reality but more
that nothing on the subject of the flow of agreement
to put it into
production through those 98 would be with a small
graph the continuum of levels what it
does is start to generate in sending those
processes where we say in this case
it is built in containers that go  to
host in the town software processes
then he
once I already have let's say
my software in production talks
about the management mouse  On of the configuration ok are
the identification processes controls
auditing within the flow of apps
according to this will depend on a lot
of dedication of each company if it was
implemented they are not in the end
non-mandatory terminologies according to but this but
in some way
let's say some way  mark in the guideline
of what I should have had,
anyway, it should have a process
within my xbox methodology, this is
a process of control and identification
of all those assets that I am,
let's say, deploying because if not how did I
monitor it
then let's say we have  Here in the
part of we can handle, let's say that
architectures like the one that we say already
involve the part of the operations people more
and also depend on how
the teams are organized according to
because some are the famous that are
who are dedicated only to it to
facilitate it.  which are the evolution
of the operations agent that are dedicated to
facilitating the entire environment so that the
developers
can let's say deploy their
applications why
then challenges
challenges behind this what from the
post part really said
developments continuous and
fast implementations that is the goal of data
scalability of power let's say
easily through these technologies
comfortable but with how erneta is  to be able to be
scalable, let's say without further signs and
effort, but if in some way with
measurable environments, ok
and now it is obviously and already entering the
field, it has an
attack surface because because I am using
new technologies that then
we are already talking here about desktops in agreement and
this  It implies the implementation of a new
set of skills that must be
taken into account if I already have it, because it
represented that and so it is that I am going to
involve
processes of this security within the
analysis of let's say security
within those processes within this
methodology then  we already talked about
new types of skills in  So
here the plant would be no if we see the
security of the last stage of
development
and obviously that is going to have
a higher cost according to
because if I wait, let's say only
when I am already
developing through sports it is  I have already
started up and I am just going to go
through a code
verification dependency verification
scans penetration tests
verify if there are
monitoring tools for it
obviously all that is going to be much
more expensive ok so now
we are going to
obviously correct  this in the
early stages saves time and
money ok if i can lets say fix
this in and there are many ways we should
raise this issue if i can for
example introduce for sure
ok automated scans or
ok scan code analysis scans
and  also
security checks in the
infrastructure process as code so
I'm already downgrading  a lot a lot let's say
the risks that we tell myself the
software products have problems and
can only be identified in the
last stages ok
then
what happens if i am improving this
which is a bit the idea the same
methodology of drops that is yes  in
seven parts the continuous deployment
of epsa cox what he tries to implement
is
let's say security reviews also
continuous then if I
implemented that book in
him and in him and on the day that it is infrastructure
as of the infrastructure writes
as  code I can implement let's say
processes an agreement that help me to
verify these problems so I can
this let's say reduce a lot the
security gap in my continuous development in
my products that farc at the end in
which it is required ok then we
talk again do not automate let's say review
of  source code check
target dependencies this
check and I feel like then
that's where we can take  r these issues
but
now essentially based on this without
introducing ourselves to a system of
tools that is that pop is, let's say,
the effort in the fight to remedy the
default security and between quotes,
security by default because
obviously we all think about
security from the beginning  But the issue is
that if we are implementing it well, I
cannot now the idea is to integrate
security through tools and here
I put an asterisk because in reality and
this is a bit the reason for the talk
according to there that we are going to see
Later on,
many tools to put,
let's say, within our flow of
our methodology or within our
ideology of the box, many
security tools but the issue is how
we are handling it because those who
are implementing them, who are
making them, those who review those reports
then  develops a culture of safety
as a code of agreement we no longer expect
us to say in sayamo  s that
the application is deployed so that it is
just to be able to review, let's say the
application, but we go from the
code to be able to correct it, it
promotes cross-ability because
there are various competencies
working together and this is very much the problem
of this, let's say to implement this type of
ideology  I agree that
there are many competencies that we are going to
talk about later then in essence they
allow should should ok facilitate the
management in the rapid development on a large
scale because I already have that through the
cecop my flow is my product that
lends more in quotes  I'm sure I
'm going safe implementations ok that
should allow scaling of
processes much more fluid an agreement is
let's say what is expected and they helped with
a secure environment by default that is to
say if we say make sure
that once the software product is
this  it is as it is called of tested it
is already in production this strap has passed
corr  ectly all the
security tests because then but always
but from that quad or simply a
threat model according to the
continuous integration let's say that I can
verify that errors of
sensitive information such as database users
two passwords is let's say
plain text  ok in the continuous delivery
through the tests I can
detect through the code review to be able to
detect sql injection the pse with
xs address s
vulnerable dependency that is a lot
let's say ignore it is an agreement
and do not perform scans decade after
each  stages we do not win and now but
also I can not neglect the
vulnerabilities in the insecure itself
as code in containers for example
there are a lot of vectors let's say towards
let's say things like two that werner
ok and check if they meet a minimum
configuration standard obviously ok
but  it will be known once everything let's say that
I have gone through all these
reviews its say me  If it would be necessary to
permanently supervise and monitor the applications against
attack, that is to say that it has in some
way is in some way
proactive defense or you monitor
proactive monitoring according to
now the idea would be how to implement it to
that let's say we have a lot
of terminology in agreement
The terminology that I
share is the one that you personally saw
my experience because working on it
I know that there are other terminology
that suddenly out there they will sit and we
will talk in the chat ok but this is the
good essence and the same agrees and  That
is a bit what I would like to
say to share that is to say between comics
determination of version control ok
and before configuring the
repository check vulnerabilities
ok
in the management of the secrets
agree what
if I am correctly managed
the passwords  key the tokens of
atis in agreement and this, let's say, if the
services that are available today  We even generate
towards this towards the repositories or
do deployment ok this is important
is practical application security testing
ok what you want here is that
if we say make tests of
the code review ok let's say from the code
verify if my code is say no
it has some problem at the development level
then we talk about building a little
more with more let's say I don't know if complex
but more laborious software with two
said analyzes to identify
let's say
vulnerabilities in dependencies
according to which is also very important
because sometimes our code is fine, it
's fine  In fact, but the
software dependency that we use this, let's say,
are not well maintained by the
developers who have made them
great dependencies many times and then
forget about their maintenance, and
that is where the problems come, on the
other hand, there are also many
dependencies that apparently are
vulnerable but their areas of
exploitation  They are very complex, so
let's say the probability of being
exploited by a dependency that
apparently because of the tool tells me
that it is exploitable is minimal, then
also those considerations are what
we have why
dynamic application security testing or you
give that it is not more than what  What
we would do is what counts is what we
do let's say in testing it is nothing more than a
review of the front end of
the applications to verify
vulnerabilities already in the part let's say
in the dynamic part of the body now
take into account that you are from here
from  yes, that's it, and we're
talking about that all of these are
automated processes, okay, so my
question would be all those tools
that make these automated processes
do them well,
the other round would be all these
tools that make all those
processes who review them and who
apply  the corrections of that is a
bit let's say that I would have to go
wondering what with coexistence  gums code
what compliance is and this will also
differ a lot from each company if it is
implementing if I am going to comply with
pci dss or if I am going to comply, let's say the
pm standards or then
let's say that it will depend a lot on what
is aligned for example
banks that need their
developments to be aligned at prices ok
and finally
let's say to be their mind with the
skills that is to say analysis of
known vulnerabilities ok that in
theory all this should have been reduced
let's say until we got here because
and last and not least
contains the scanner that verifies the
vulnerabilities in the containers
then after all this
terminology the idea would be like an
implement and in what part then for
that this is mandatory this
let's just say that as I say is part let's say
of one's experience is that this for
example  we can implement certain
certain statements certain parts in the
continuous integration in the continuous
delivery in infrastructure as code
for example in the continuum there comes
to be say yes or yes evaluation of
the source code ok and evaluation of the
dynamic part of the application and in the
infrastructure as code perform the
vulnerability analysis part ok
and so on
successively we can also see it in this way and
a little more entering and as
regional it is mandatory because it will
depend on how it is that within my
opzz process I included these as
these stages are called
now this would be a graph already at the level
of  tools ok
there are many other alternatives that I have
done is but let's say because they are 12
minutes in agreement and this
to be able to apply in each of these
let's say stages in my flow of the box
include tools that generate this
s security statement ok
as I say let's say  The tools
are not mandatory but let's say the idea is to
have in, let's say, at each stage some
part of reviews, ok
then this you already know  And let's say much
much better in agreement with developers
things like talisman that we have a
delay visit of that in s is to arrive
let's say dependency verification that
we say a software and we go
before good blood for sas for that
vast proxy that is the best of  agreement
for the management part of vulnerable
non-scans regularities architecs that
are two things
and restructuring let's say scanning in
open badass trinity infrastructure and
so we could talk a lot more about
them according to monitoring and managing
secrets
now the challenges of that thing is
let's say is
security automation ok yes and to verify security
in a traditional way for pen
testers is complex and you have to have
a certain skin
and almost all of them are already specializing
they are not specialists in web applications
you are competitors others
find in other governors and then
care and  other things then that implies
let's say a much more complex environment ok
integra  ar security tools in the
flow of water also the people who
implement, let's say the correct one, the
correct plugin of each time one of
those tools and that everyone can
be in the same flow of the pops ok
and most importantly cultural changes
because it may involve  that both
development people and people from let's say
operations and now the people of their
day can work
so we are talking that there
are many challenges out there so
we are going to see specific two points
quickly
three comics ok that is what
wants programmatic to attack this
all that is this access focus on let's say
plain text information ok as
you see keys and other things casey ok
then this helps developers to
let's say avoiding incorrect publication
of this
as we attack it or how or what
we can use  well this is an
alternative time and your job is to
ensure that potential secrets
don't leave the workstation.  developer garlic
then what do we need for
that configure jit repositories installed
in the development machine and then
integrate it into these continuous
intervention ok let's quickly see
this
for this I have here a little wine
ok
then here we have a this a
repository of  agreement and then what we are
going to do is make, for example, a
clone of a well-known project
called / blear that surely many
know because the application hamburger
then we make a little one ok
let's say a
local repository of hits we define the variables ok
to be able  connect us for this you already saw
previously what I did was this include
my key the key that was generated from the
development machine to my
git repository here so let's say
special navigation what then added my
remote repository according to and then
I make yours and  it asks me for my key what
the public key
is and what it does is let's say make the
di bus  Let's go from what I have to
my repository, the genre, we already had it,
this branch more ok then until
there I have it, it removes me now what I am going to
do is install talisman for that it
needs this dependency according to the
dependency
then I download talisman
is  only one is let's say that an h
let's say an installation script I give it
execution permission then install
talisman ok it tells me let's say where
the environment variables will be where it
will position where the
exception files will be because it
also handles exceptions issues  where it
goes is where the jobs are, I am no longer
a little auxiliary but it is also
important but above all where is my
directory, let's say where is my
rest directory or my
repository with which he is going to scan
before launching it to the central repository
then  I define in this case roe from
vw to where I am working
then we are going to create
a file that is for example
called
that s  and call secrets okay
then I put my secrets there which
are keys for example of this
[Music]
flames suddenly I am working with mistresses
because then
and added to my re possible let's say let's say
short lady adds secrets and then tries to make a committee to a
committee
committee then he
detects the secret files of agreement
and what he tells me is that in the secret file he
is adding these things that
are potentially vulnerable because
they do not have to be uploaded because they are
excess center files and that someone else is going to
upload the repository
Obviously, he knows our
fair repository, you can add in
agreement then he performs
that type of scan on me ok before that is
now if I want in any way due
to operation issues or exceptions, what do I know,
there are many variants in this type of
thing then I  I want to make an
exception so the tool
allows me to grab grab the fingerprint
of that create a file that is  call
talisman point of rc
then I can
add it so that he ignores the ok
yet it is not linear obviously but there are
many there are many conjectures behind
that there are things that obviously
cannot be avoided but I have to say
what we say in this case this way
to work because there are other
tools for that is precisely to
protect the developer from making us
puig in the repository this kind
of thing okay so that's a
bit this part
ok
then alternatives we have these
let's say other software as I say the
idea is not  to stay with tools
but to stay with the idea and I still do not know
what we can do
preventively because
now if we talk about
static analysis security casting things
in agreement that is to say analysis of the code
ok then what is the scope
of security tests to speak something
automated tools look for
vulnerabilities in the code ok that is and
try to identify that with injection
xs s insecure libraries etc.
etc. from the code ok which I
would tell you and it is complex because for that
we have to go there I want to highlight this
is tools configured by default
of generic revision configuration ok
manual revision is necessary that is to say
I cannot stay with it  The report is
only that someone obviously has to
review that and verify
the levels of exploitation and lida
accordingly, so for that we can
use an alternative like sónarclub
that allows a static analysis
of the code, ok, then identify all
these sad things that are not being
reached  But before only three
minutes and we are going to see a little
demo of that quickly okay
ok we can bring your excellent food
then let me not lose already seen
gentlemen so here
we have
let's say a file called
docker compost ok haylock docampo ok now
what it is and horns have these
things changed i
what in what i have here  it is my
writing that what builds is
my
container and james that makes an
implementation of yanqing if then I have
my implementation of sonarkids ok and the
password each known as super
secure because it is a security event ok
then
then after that
excellent already  I have seven minutes
so after that what I can
do is to do a lift let's
say from the middle with you lift these
containers ok once they
tell me that it is let's say it is
correctly we have raised
income
but I am in
kings ok here depending  Let's say
that obviously the power and there is
another factor, let's say the power of me
from the machine where I am supporting,
then it will depend how fast
when all of the then here I have
let's say who is my continuous
does what we say the continuous part
be released ok eye that is an example of
agreement then a tool as
I say do not stay with the
rub tool  I know that you stick with what you are doing,
then what I have to
tell someone 15 is where my
sonarclub server is, ok where is it being
configured, then what I have to
tell you is
what
but below
for this in this case there is a  15 are the
most popular because it has a series of
plugins, let's say that allow you, let's say,
very simple integration with many
tools that is my peru 136 in
port 9000 where it moves, it
moves, or is listening, they are nerves,
the container they remember what  Let's create
let's say from the local compost
so now what I'm going to do is
create a new chat ok or a new task
ok then because yankee already know where they
are listening they are nerves so they
grabbed create a new task I tell them that
the task is going to be called
from copsa proyde w
chiquita create a freestyle project
ok and then
let's say configure the source of the
code where is it going to get the code
is this going to get it out of  we are going to
analyze vw as we did
in the other example and this takes us out of
the public repository also
obviously I have a choice if it is an
authenticated repository because you see
press and password that is let's say that
it is also feasible obviously this
is a  puig directory a
public repository then we give it to execute and we
tell it that to execute what it is going to do
is to execute a scanner file
why why because it already has
previously let's say the club and let's say
installed and the address
the ip address I mean  and also the
port that then and here is a bit
of the parameterization part ok here where
I tell it let's say where it is let's say
what the project is going to be and the
project that it versioned handle where
the project is going to host locally
workspace the language la  coding the
user knows
then once I have all that
then save
and he this then I tell him that he
builds now ok it is in that now
I tell him to build a beat,
let's say if they see at the bottom,
okay and he's starting to
do the task, let's say to perform the task, I give him a
console view because, not to mention, stop
being
consul friendly, because not so much web,
ok, so here he tells me that it starts.  to
do the whole
process, it connects, let's say with are
active, and begins to generate, let's say the
entire language analyst
begins to analyze all the code,
according to that it works, and at the end it tells me
that
the report can review the report
here, the execution is over.  to the
consumer so much
memory ok and I can click here to
see the job is not a bug it took a
little time to agree to do enter several times
because let's say you still
need to build the project and there it
is ok then apparently let's say it
has happened  That, but I still have six
vulnerabilities to review, okay,
so let's say from there I
have some vulnerabilities, for
example, and that's  a very specific example
in the first one that happened that it was an http
in glee ok that is a flaw in
the parametrization issue at the
web server level ok now to
consider the vulnerability if by
standard ok but i have to
say check it already how  relevant is
because I also have others so the
work just comes here, it is not to
say I have to start or the
developer has to start
reviewing each one of those
vulnerabilities and begin to determine
the levels of exploitation ok and if it
is not the developer, people  In charge
of reviewing this because if it is not of any
use in reality if I can not correct at
these levels
then and
[Music]
ready then we return to the
presentation
and alternatives for this there are
actually several although they already have let's say a
small table let's say marc and
some appear  free software others no other
make important how many languages
I can say to verify in the case of they
are
obviously yes  Well, let's say it meets
most of the revision of the
languages
so to go to the conclusions ok
the development area does not need to think
beyond continuous development but
it is useless to have many tools
within the pack line of agreement if they cannot
be  interpreting and correcting the
vulnerabilities found
then based on that we need
developers with knowledge of,
say,
vulnerabilities to
directly correct these, a redundancy
then or otherwise
a
specialist remediation team is assigned to the vulnerability review is the great
dilemma those who review the reports
who writes the knowledge to
correct those vulnerabilities ok, nice
from sarkozy, lots of very
interesting tools but they have the network, they
correct the vulnerabilities and make
sure that since this that that
product the software is
completely sanitized well my time
is up that is a  little what  I wanted to share a
lot with you, thank you for your attention,
sorry for the speed, I am not
attentive to the questions and doubts, but
there is
thanks for your participation, Juan, this
is a very interesting talk and
there are definitely no major challenges
for the development teams in
regards to  cybersecurity issues
well now we have to go to the round of
questions we have the first question
that comes from jason james and more questions will
talisman work in nature the box
what happens is that it only depends on him
specifically on talisman ok
that does not depend on him  In other words, from the
repository where you push ok, it
actually depends on the
developer's machine because where the
environments where I study,
the developments work, do not work for me with Linux,
so let's say that
if the platform is
developers they will not have problems
because if  It is windows and if it really
does not hurt me to say it no no I do not know
if it works, say  s about windows it
would not be necessary to check the
correct compatibility with here I have other questions
the intern ask me what advice would
you give to the developers to increase
their knowledge of cybersecurity
good question agreement actually in the
background comes from the pops and from the cecop
although this  for ten or
fifteen years the 20 years from which we are
already talking about security issues
since the internet was invented
practically in agreement then in
reality and it is the same tonic it is not and it
is also rescued a little what what
came  In this one,
those who had been speaking in my
previous ones, let's say colleagues,
I cannot defend but attack the
agreement, that is, I cannot correct
vulnerabilities if I do not know how they work
, you agree, that is, depending on the
development teams and this, let's say.
know how it is that an x css is
exploited according to know common sql injection
a session hijacking is
exploited according to
in the friend with developer know
that then when you see that in a
report of these tools that are
increasingly being sent faster and more
powerful they will be able to know let's say and
realize the levels of exploiting it
ok and be able to correct them
then but if not me  They talk about an x ss
and let's say I don't know the flat and only
doctor let's say I know the code and
suddenly I correct it there but at the time that
it passes through you it comes out again
because I did not correct well then there
where the problems are generated that
then  Yes, but from the
developer errors and so on, but let's say
that I learned I develop my development roles
because now I have to have
security, okay, so yes, but
actually before there was development of
developers and infrastructure
and now there are an agreement for apps then.
this is migrating and it is going to continue
looking in agreement then this one as this one is
called
and it is going to continue migrating and it is and that is the
high competition that  e today
developers and everything we
need to these
application development issues we faced not a long time ago we
did not talk about doca nico
really I am we already talked about turbines and
I have to learn a lot with the agreement
so that is part of natural evolution
Yes, definitely
security and safety issues have
to be transversal to all the
implementations that will be made in what
this system is, they will not reach
the next question and it is from fp fred
asks some developers
use the geo tool and for there
talisman applies
of  Today
yes, but it would be more a second layer of
agreement, that is to say in the end according to what
I have seen of geo and it is with me, that is, they do
not see me, I am not going so much the tool
but to what it does ok then this
could apply could get into the  of the
flow I perceived as a second layer of
agreement, we would have to say it would have
to be seen well in mind that if my
tool let's say it meets the objective
from pre comics so I don't need,
let's say a second layer, let's say a
review of the tool that it
uses, ok, because it was said, we don't
stay in the tool.
from pre comics that is
what talisman covers and so there may
be a lot of other tools what
it does is verify that we say the
keys and the and everything that is
credential keys etc. etc. they do not pass
in plain text to my
central repository if I have  Another tool that
does the same then I am already
complying and alfre comics
then it is going to happen there
that is when I have the next
question that Rodham
asks us what tools for
vulnerability testing or paragliding team do you
recommend
because there are many to roll up, so
there are  many, for example, and today
those with flat integration are taking advantage of,
for example,
compared  I would not like products
but let's say that compared for example
open vázquez that nobody liked at the beginning
I remember today it is not
the best tool but it does have
many edges that are integrated for
example with james kingston with another
tool of de  continue
placement ok then just for that
fact
let's say it gives an added plus
ok i dont know if it is the best ok
later i could talk about it say
qualys nexus and other things ok but
i repeat that it can't be
done when it was done  A bridge is
that beyond the issue from
rolling up a single
tool was used several are used ok because you
need to see the different
perspectives of let's say the objective is
that you are evaluating because one can
remove one thing and another can remove another
vulnerability x which one do you stay  you
stay with only one you do not have to see
that report and the
concise universe analysis reports agree they
are all concise nobody  It tells you ok ready this
vulnerable xs existence how to
exploit it no
and true we do not owe each other as they say
marry a certain tool
number is no longer correct it will not be
limited and many times it will be very it
will be given our results and what
I do  I can obtain from the reports that
you are providing us with not many
free code tools also
this one precisely by its nature this
does not publish the source code and I think that
programming skills
are definitely very necessary to
make these small adjustments many times
not to limit ourselves precisely  To the
capabilities at that time have the
tool yes and if that is very
important and there is a key point let's say
no what we review to security and what they
handle from that reprogramming that they
see or that we come what we have learned
let's say there is a lot of advantage with respect to  to
that put the other the other visibility and
not so much of the closed box let's say to
make them a seer that evaluates  úan or if not
we can also have the ability to
review code to be able to do it today for as
it was said today that has changed a
lot and not only ok I have a plan
let's say a lot of tools that
make security religion
to the perfect but you know how to say  from
reviewing that are those vulnerabilities or
that it is already telling me that
the life of that already has time but of the 10
all are correct are the
portability levels are say they are correct or it
is vulnerable or they are simply false
positives or suddenly it does not exist
Suddenly the scenario exploded as I tell you
many times today they require a
too specific scenario to be exploited
so the risk levels are very
low then but nevertheless many
times ok they do not pass in
vulnerability analysis like this one as
vulnerabilities let's say very high
when  actually the
personal evaluation and the evaluation of the
specialist have to go beyond
definitely and  the very important human factor
of the analysis in the
end
well we have the following question which
is from rafael woman he asks us the
teaching of basic programming in
institutes and universities are factors
responsible for the conare skills
in web applications how can it improve
how can it be improved  This well,
in reality I did not say the fault of
agreement that is, it would not be very
irresponsible but no no no no I could not
abide by that let's say actually even
the development framework has
vulnerabilities that is, they are not donuts
as programs to send obviously not
a  Obviously, not a factor but in
reality it is this and even the
development brakes, that is, I will not be
able to talk about names but in reality
to go to the improvement obviously it is what
we started is what we started to
talk from the beginning that is already  The
migrated competencies are already more
complex, it is not enough for me to just
develop to know how to develop in the will
see in calling and ter  oo in spring
okay I don't also have to know is
that I knew more than vulnerabilities
let's say I could find in my development
because then and apply best
development practices so as not to fall into
those vulnerabilities so easily
now the resources do a
quite commendable job today for example for  the
revolution of that before let's say that
like
78 years ago suddenly it was very easy to
find problems in the boeing of the
fingers applications in the
user fumet password agreed they were super
easy and we are going to find problems
there because nobody put the focus there  or it
was not known that they stopped it
when they were so developed that we
would pay to develop functions
that allow let's say that is safe
today jac
almost let's say it would be quite
irresponsible to find a problem
in the access report of an
application is almost this almost already  It is not
found of that
because obviously they have already known each other more than  and
more documentation of that, there are
frameworks that help a lot so it is
an evolution of them today more
things are found inside the
application than outside the application
is not what is always recommended let's say
analysis let's say this analysis of
web applications with credentials and  There,
how does the eps jacobs issue intervene?
It is important as I said
in the conclusions to decide ok
trained my development team or destination a
team of specialists to see that ok
and the month and entered it within my
work team either directly or
commercialized it is already the model let's say
defined the  let's say a model of
integration but today developers need to
work
operations people and people and let's say  and the
security people all three have to
work according to a set it is
difficult if in fact there are two people
to agree on it is complicated
imagine let's say the whole team because
then it is difficult and it is a change in the
way of thinking then but today  For
today, if we are adopting these types, which
is the reason behind the talk, this
type of, let's say, ideology, ok
methodology, if you want to call it,
then I already have to know that we have
to erase those aspects
definitely.
each one with a
certain level of specialization in your
experience, Juan could you tell us
what are the main problems that
you have encountered
when these teams work together
because they are not real technicians, they are not
technical
because let's say that each one knows our
user specialist, let's say and
obviously they are more problems  Let's say
training of each, let's say of each
person ok and there I could c  To address the issue
of
universities institutes of agreements, that
is, if this commercial is always appreciated, this one
and how it is affecting even
the pandemic as a result of this agreement.
fostered
in teamwork according
to her in environments with more
professional thoughts where stress stress
and jump because I need to get
the application right now and well the
security agent tells me she is
not vulnerable she cannot go into production OK
then there  There is more a topic, let's say
at a level, let's say the training of each
person and people, let's say the biggest
problem is one, let's say that I have
to say my part of the backroom
that we say to ourselves below, or that is this
and know that it is not because the  of security
I put on the watch is a t
-shirt of the security area and this is that it is
stopping the work it is not because in
reality it is not complying with  If she
presents then I have to say to
have levels of communication and that is
another thing soft skills in agreement
to be able to dialogue in some way and to
sit next to the security is
what I already ready but I have to
improve to this line of code
promptly already ready  because because this
variable our winding does not have a
validation function to the list
then I can do it for me as it is
called administration
I will have a security function
such simple things but sometimes or it is personal egos
that is the biggest problem
and that is  a cultural issue more than anything
, according to raw no and when in reality
it is not a personal issue it is an issue of the
benefit of the company it is also a
new program for me but rather a program
for the company
and it delves deeper with this type of
change not  From methodology to agreement
because they require much more coordination
than before.
Right done. Thank you Juan for your
answers. The interaction has been interesting
.  tion is also rather this
ventilation that production is flock
we give this arrived the correct time
on behalf of 8.8 Andean the tt I thank you
for your participation and we hope to have
you in future editions
this you have some spaces to be able to
say goodbye to the audience has said no
not many  Thanks to the organization to an
agreement, thank you very much for accepting
me. Thank you very much for the
space and for and for such an excellent
collection organization, it is impeccable
in agreement and I am not happy to
have reported and I hope to be in
another new opportunity  also enter
juan well take out all the people
who are seeing each other it was time to
pause our followers we ask them
to continue participating with their questions
and that this is the end there will be raffles we will be
back after the first thanks
[Music]
and