okay so uh
thanks uh adam first of all welcome to
the b-side edmonton
uh i know you won the challenge
you you impersonated me i owe you a
lunch
i'm definitely gonna send you something
uh
but um yeah so
um adam uh i would like to make an
introduction for you
uh for before you let me start your
presentation for the b-side edmonton so
um adam is a multi-decade information
technology and risk management
professional
who pays large sum of annual maintenance
i.t and security organizations an
observer of human nature
efficiently of elections i hope i
pronounce it correct
and take taker apart of things i know
you are a hacker
adam believes that all information
security and technology professional can
be amazing
communication communicators and
respected for their knowledge and
expertise
so i can tell a lot of things about adam
um but you know
[Laughter]
he's his good friend of mine uh
and by professionally he's the general
manager of
calgary airport uh his title for the
talk will be
crisis communication in times of plague
over to you adam harvinder
thank you so much for uh giving me the
opportunity to hang out with you guys i
do have my
my cali box signed in as well so i will
do my best to watch the stage chat
if anybody has anything they want to you
know kind of dive into a little bit
deeper
uh i highly recommend that as well in
the chat too oh thanks tim that's really
sweet
uh tim kembong's a good guy um
there are a number of people i think
that are actually really working hard to
try and break into this industry
and this is our community this is kind
of our seat
and it's a fantastic opportunity to uh
to really connect
to have the the opportunity to network
and and do things so
if you're willing to dox yourself chuck
your stuff into the chat and have some
conversations reach out to people have
some
some conversations uh always um
well a wash always i i i apologize i'm
probably butching your name and and that
makes me feel like a donkey thank you
very much for stepping in early
uh your auth and session management was
absolutely amazing stuff and for you to
step up uh
kind of unexpected took guts you did a
great job thank you
tanya phenomenal view modern security
communication should look like jason
uh just for you the audience
this is what when someone is an expert
and he can he can break down incredibly
complex
concepts into really simple things that
was amazing
rachel hanny martin tim incredibly
valuable uh
uh session you guys did again for the
audience i i think
that that maybe we we often kind of see
government as
as a as a burden i will offer that what
you just saw
was four amazing security leaders
and we are quite blessed to have this as
taxpayers plus to have this level of
talent working for us
absolutely phenomenal fireeye fortinet
proof point thomas
sentinel one concordia university f5
mimecast and ama
uh thank you for sponsoring this because
you are willing to sponsor this
on our terms uh as the b-sides mandate
goes
thank you for for doing that because it
does take some some cheddar to try and
pull this off
um i did ask carpenter if i could have
my own product placements
are you a dad have you ever eaten dad's
cookies
our vendor's just telling me that i
don't get my own product placements
okay crisis communications in the time
of plague
let me dive into that let's talk about
that a little bit here
uh the obligatory who is adam's slide
i'm old
i've done things chances are if you're
watching this and there are what 205
people connected right now that's great
thank you for coming along for this ride
um i imagine a bunch of us have actually
been in the trenches together that's
freaking sweet
uh because well since the 1990s i've
been fiddling around with risk and
technology
and making things break and trying to
fix them when they aren't um
or maybe you just forgot to log off
after the cso panel and you'll figure
out quickly if i've got anything to say
that'll bring you value i'm here for you
you took the time out of your day to
hear me yak and i promise to do my best
be respectful of your time and attention
uh big disclaimer even though i'm on the
clock this conversation with adam is
totally of my own manufacturer
i don't represent anyone but me heck i
barely represent myself
um so big thank you to harvinder uh
teo nakeesha the b-side's empty planning
committee it takes a crazy amount of
effort to pull these kind of things off
and the easier answer would have been to
just cancel it but instead they chose to
do the hard work and adapt to our
ever-changing world
um and
who am i not i'm not a lawyer i'm not a
psychologist or a physician
i'm not a natural leader i'm not a
natural communicative presenter writer
or magician i'm a nerd from the
born in the 1970s like to think of
myself as a pretty solid technology
delivery professional and decent of
hacker but
as my career grew i came across some
real skill and hackers dudes like
tavis almandie marcus hutchins tj
o'leary
he's in the chat i decided
you know i wasn't a good enough nerd to
like really get paid
i realized it didn't matter if i was the
smartest dude in the room or the dumbest
i sucked at getting my point across
so it didn't matter either way i took
this realization as an opportunity to
learn as much as i could about people
and there's no better industry than
infosec this community to learn about
people social engineering right i love
hacking but i figured any improvements
in my career would require
human hacking and mostly hacking myself
it was a challenge i really wanted for
myself
and resulted in many many cringe-worthy
events
but i'll keep persisting because i think
it's important for me and i see venues
like this
and i've you know learned an incredible
amount along the way
and if i can offer you something from my
learnings for your toolkit
great i'll encourage you too there's no
more supportive environment than b-sides
this is your place to show
us the things that you've learned along
the way to help with your journeys too
oh yes everybody wants cookies uh i wish
we were all together i would share my
cookies i would literally bring all the
cookies
um so anyways in my decades on this
planet i've never encountered anything
like this worldwide crisis response to
covet 19 pandemic but it really did show
me that
most incident response phases and
processes tend to be very similar over
time um apt comparison
would be something like well 9 11. i
remember
you know everybody who was alive at the
time kind of remembers where they were
at the time
a couple of jerks or a handful of jerks
slammed a couple of planes into the
ground and into a couple of buildings
um looking at the bad stuff versus time
graph that i made in ms paint as we
climbed the dark red
the world was starting to react to the
report of an attack
at the top of the red we kind of know as
much as there is to know all the planes
are down the towers are down there's a
hole in the pentagon an incredible
amount of innocent people have died
tracking the red down to the right and
approaching the orange air traffic has
ceased worldwide billions of people are
turning into the news
in the orange we're trying to make sense
of the attacks
uh air spaces are secured around the
planet we've got people on the ground
looking for survivors
as we move into the yellow we're
clearing rubble and we're
building or adapting to new security
regulations
for our pandemic it was the third week
of march things started to get funny
right
uh we sent everybody home intersecting
which is the kind of the top of the red
everybody tried to get used to working
from schooling and working from home
as we kind of started going down the
slope and into the orange again
and then as we hit the orange school and
work obligations shifted from everybody
go home and don't die
to uh oh yeah we still have some lives
to live
and you know businesses to run uh and
eight months later
as we circle down the the yellow we're
still trying to figure out who we are in
this new apoc
uh through each of these different
phases we feel different levels of
stress and different kinds of
communication different urgency
different needs for for the messages
that we need to get across
so let me get on with a little bit of
that here
um
oh look i can see my other screen that's
fantastic that's really cool
um let's take a minute to recognize the
complexities of interpersonal
communication right there's lots of
books on it um
i'm kind of picking and choosing some of
my favorite parts i i think it's
important to kind of do an analysis of
this first just to
just kind of put things in perspective
of of some of the
challenges that we actually face why
communication can be hard especially
when we're stressed the hell out um
in in this case here i'm the sender
and i click there okay there we go uh
and
i'm jumping over a cubicle to chastise
dave
and we'll call him dave because that's
his name beautiful human being actually
knows a lot of taekwondo and bjj and
could legit
destroy me if i actually did climb over
the cube in a nasty way
i'm the sender and i'm falling into a
trap here though i'm always right and
everybody should know the things that i
know and value the things that i do
right dangers of projecting as a sender
well tell more about that in i think two
slides if you've heard about me talk
about the buckets though part of my
coping mechanism during crisis to
consider the things tend to fall into
one of two buckets things i can control
or in one things i can't control on the
other
if i focus on the things i can control
the likelihood of reaching successful
communication goals is much higher in
this case as the sender so much rides on
me
uh in my picture i can't control the
receiver but i can have hope that dave
is using active listening skills
listening with the attempt to understand
the messages i the sender intend to
deliver it dave doesn't have to agree
he doesn't have to agree with me a good
listener suspends judgment though and
biases
until there's any reason to actually
have it as a listener
we want to do our best to understand
what the sender's trying to tell us
what am i trying to get across the
message there's a message obviously that
i'm trying to get across
the information i'm flinging at dave and
it has a pile of
different parts in it encoding even just
speaking the sentence i'm encoding a
message in canadian english
we can encode things in python then for
some reason because an employer told us
to
re encode it to javascript so consider
that kind of thing
with empathy when speaking to someone
with a heavy accent they're parallel
encoding decoding in their head while
you're yammering
right now we're also using tcp ospf tls
and so many
opportunities for everything to turn to
crap and we haven't even started talking
about
the the verbals and the verbals are
pretty simple it's just the words we
choose right
um social engineering's famous for
studying non-verbals and you'll see all
sorts of percentages that people toss
around out there to say oh 86 percent of
a message
i don't know how they're quantifying any
of that crap the reality is though that
non-verbals
are are very very key
um it's a lot of the message and they're
key
more so because of the consistency
required between verbals non-verbals and
encoding uh if you can see my face
if you're if you're watching the stream
let me try this
i'm not mad
or
i'm not mad it's
inconsistencies are are they stick out
with a blinking light to most people
they're often
read as lies which they may or may not
be but they do indicate that something
is abnormal that something is not not
the way it should be
uh and i tried to keep my voice flat in
that that that little example there too
because paraverbals is how we say our
words my favorite example from my cousin
finney
uh at arrest the protagonist says i shot
the clerk
i shot the clerk whoa but in court the
police chief says
and the defendant said i shot the clerk
i asked him again and he said i shot the
clerk
so consider carefully how our emotional
state especially in stress
our mood our exhaustion our excitement
our defensiveness
all can have an effect on how we say
things
uh there's also a media medium person so
person to person telephone spider phone
sms
chat radio teams meet zoom
unidirectional simplex on the
directional half duplex
your communication will be more abrupt
and at higher velocity in a burning
building than in the comfort of a beach
chair after beer number two
context is always important too right
she slapped
hard is a very different statement when
discussing a bass player
than a domestic disturbance
interference all the barriers
between a sender and a receiver with
their message their medium
things like fans and loudspeakers and
douchebags with open headers on mustangs
calgary southeast calgary seems to be
you know the uh i'm all one for for loud
exhaust
i'm a car guy i like cars but southeast
calgary where i live
is the uh the hotbed of douchebags with
open headers
who like to roll around at you know 9
p.m at night through
playground zones um
also the the building you're in right
you can have noise cancellers you can
have you know
happy uh echo canceling
tiles etc um from a ham radio days i
always
talked about trying to optimize in our
personal lives the signal-to-noise ratio
too we seem to have an awful lot of
noise all the time
and so little signal so little actual
important information
dang it's hard sometimes uh what we
also have you know technology we're all
talking over technology now if anybody
tries to call me on the phone i don't
answer it because chances are somebody
claiming to be from canada revenue
agency sending a share of tourists
but packet loss could also be
interference
and what have we all done recently more
so than anybody
else ever at any time
we're sticking masks on ourselves now
and then
having to yell at the poor lady from tim
hortons going i would like a double
double
so yeah okay it's hard we really hope
that at some point we have some feedback
in the loop too
that uh uh and and as a sender you can
ask for some of that feedback as a a
good active listener you can
uh deliver some of that feedback using
reflexive
listening tools paraphrasing summarizing
questioning
my favorite of covie's habits so seek
first to understand
then to be understood again no port does
this mean we have to agree
but as long as we understand each other
we have that mutual respect
so my point communication it's just as
complex as bgp
and just as prone to screwing off if you
found interpersonal communication hard
as a
computer technology professional as a
security professional well heck you're
not alone
especially like when the world is legit
on fire all around you
and i have no idea how my little
animated gif is coming through i stole
this idea from robert falzone of
checkpoint because he always has the
most brilliant slide decks
um i stole so i've the next three slides
are are my advice for
ways that you can form your
communications i stole this particular
one from the emergency response world
the situation report the sit rep etched
in stone as the can report
conditions actions need conditions
what's the current status of my piece of
the incident response
actions what are me and my team
currently doing what do we have in
motion
needs what do i need from you the
audience when you're good
and it takes some time we'll talk about
that too you should be able to relay
what you know
what you're doing and what you need from
any audience in a very short period
brief and organized uh the folks in the
last session talked about that
brief be good be brief be gone
uh but what you need is last working on
the theory of primacy serial position
effect from thorndike's laws google it
if you're looking for some really
interesting
ideas on you know occupational
psychology
uh great wikipedia article thorndike uh
t-h-o-r-n-d-i-k-e
especially in terms of high stress
everyone already is barely hanging on
and your audience is personal fifo
buffers the first and first note buffers
are already overloaded
people can't absorb a whole lot more so
just say what you're up to with the
intention of filling
other people's needs and get a
commitment for what you need
this can be part of a formal roundtable
or just making a request of another
person
or team and you need to listen to the
info you might need when you're asking
for need somebody else might already
have delivered that in their report so
get off your your phone
during the round table and and and pay
attention
um so okay heat is on here's some
examples i cooked up uh
from the firefighting world i'm actually
going to read this one
command there's a search team one inside
the structure light smoke is visible
with no heat we're completing the
primary search of the main floor and
requesting the results the exterior
suite before entering the basement
pretty simple hey what's up it's me i'm
search team one i'm inside the building
there's a little bit of smoke but
no you know real heat or anything um
we're just finishing up our primary
search for the main floor we want to go
in the the
the basement which is known as the
firefighter killer so maybe let me know
if you see any puffing smoke from the
outside
conditions actions needs all right from
physical security
uh control bravo zero an unexpected
person
has just been located in the data center
bravo two's taken up station at the exit
and
we'd really like a supervisor to come
down here and
review the individual's credentials and
maybe call the cops if necessary
conditions actions needs got a whole lot
through there
pretty quickly uh okay adam yadanki
let's apply this to information
technology then
ransomware was discovered on our data
share two it staff members are currently
focused on isolating any infected system
one staff member is attempting to
identify the point of entry so we can
limit the spread
we really need somebody with email
system expertise to assist with the
point of entry work
a team to prepare file restorations and
system imaging and
if you've got it somebody can translate
russian to see how truly screwed we are
if we can't get this under control
not bad i like that i don't know
i wrote it so i guess i'm biased
conditions we have ransomware
actions we have three people working on
it needs we
need a recovery team to say hi to cozy
bear
yeah good times
when you get good at it feels really
organized
crafting your message so conditions
actions needs i stole from the emergency
response
emergency services kind of community uh
this one care
uh where are we or precision clearance
objectivity i heard this on a podcast
once and i pulled over
my car on the side of the anthony henday
um
i i can't remember who i stole this from
and i feel really bad i've googled it
and i've never been able to come up with
it again so if anybody knows where i
stole this from i'd
love to give them credit um but thinking
back to our time versus bad stuff graph
once you kind of get out of the need for
those those really quick sit reps right
and you can start you know actually
crafting your messages a little better
the can report still works
but you can focus on crafting your
message a little more carefully uh
another triumph
of cleverness that i like precision
clarity and objectivity
and this goes back on you the sender
encoding your message precision
i don't care about your filler words use
um ah like all you want
what no one wants when more storage is
undergoing ransomware attack every
second is a 20-minute diatribe and crap
that it's going to make a difference
we don't need a dump of everything
you've been working on we're assuming
you got it handled
unless you need something to help me
along this path i've also been playing
with adapting the
i love emergency services stuff the five
rights of of
of of administering medication in first
aid
if you've ever taken a first aid course
uh through st john ambulance or canadian
red cross highly recommend that stuff by
the way
the right drug the right dose the right
route the right patient at the right
time
yeah i got that right um so i've been
trying to re-adapt that into solving
some of my precision communication needs
get the right information
the right volume of it through the right
medium with the right context
at the right time it's a little big i
know it's a work in progress
just no matter what you're delivering
just do your best to make it precise
clarity is about your audience um the
reality is
uh tanya said it this morning too you're
b-sides i expect that you know about
security and you know about technology
that
you're on top of this that you're good
um
so just be super careful not to fall
into the trap of jargon acronyms insider
knowledge that
your audience might not actually know
about one of my pet peeves is the word
obviously and sometimes i use the word
obviously myself and i chastise myself
for it maybe it's obvious to you
but maybe it's not obvious to everyone
in the conversation and even if it's
kind of an attempt to self-depreciate
it comes across as arrogance of
belittling and the last thing that you
want is
is resistance in the listener um
so besides i'm making this assumption
that you're technical you know how to
use google and jargon assumptions that
i'm tossing out here are things that
either you can google
or you already know um but that's the
danger for us as technology
professionals is that somebody might not
know what ospf is or
code injection or root hints or any of
those other lovely things we talk about
maybe 99 of our audience does in a
crisis situation though with that one
percent
that doesn't understand us has the
potential to be our one roadblock or
maybe it proves our spending request
then it's time to move on to no name
brands
uh an old adage and i talk about it with
jason maynard did such a great job of it
if you can't if you call yourself an
expert and you can't explain the concept
in terms that
that the sender can or sorry that the
receiver can understand
then i as a sender probably don't know
my message well enough to be trying to
explain it as an expert
uh objectivity out-of-body experience uh
i love my homer
there um try to understand your
listeners motivations
to drill down to what's really important
for everyone in a crisis
folks don't want to hear you flexing
they want to hear how you've made an
impact on their priorities or lessened
their noise and given them more signal
uh
if you need some leverage try thinking
of this is empathy for your listeners
bernay brown
has lots of great talks on empathy i
found them really helpful in describing
how no matter what the situation you may
agree with me or not but in this
pandemic in particular we're all in this
together
across the planet uh if we're going to
get through it together we have to let
go of some of our own views and try to
understand the bigger pictures even if
it's a crappy picture like how we're all
supposed to achieve new normal on the
time of plague is a business
or you know a five-year-old's finger
painting of a fire truck with
dinosaur arms
oh water is great um and as crises
stabilize and we're really starting to
focus on things like business continuity
can
you remember we went up and then we kind
of did it down then we did another up
and we're kind of going down again
we could start focusing on business
continuity communications continue to
have less
urgency and more formality we can
aid people in understanding our message
by focusing on storytelling
instead of fact rattling grinding our
way through white papers reports
policies corporate public document
broadcasts
it usually sucks
storytelling and again brevity is is
nice for sure but sometimes you need to
hit people the the simon cynic stuff the
start with why why how what really comes
into play here too
and you can do it i stole this one this
one is is
stolen with license from michael
santarcangelo um
if you google security catalyst he runs
leadership and uh
and vendor education and consulting uh
his straight talk
program has been incredibly influential
to me
i encourage everyone to seek out as
training if you want to be a real leader
or if you want to have a really healthy
sales pipeline in security
great stuff um so yeah storytelling
makes for communications that people
actually want to read and that they'll
take with them and
for sean you were asking about some of
this too how about security awareness
and cyber security education for our
users
characters conflict resolution the three
parts to every good story
um the characters are the people
responsible for and affected by this
incident
hey besides calgary thanks for coming
along for the ride
with me characters pretty simple it
doesn't have to be
easy or in case of my funny pictures
there
ten thousand we could almost buy our own
ship for that but who's gonna fly it
could you
yeah conflict the common goal or
objective that we're addressing
right doesn't actually have to be a
fight i was kind of hoping for a city of
edmonton versus
city of calgary ciso grudge match um
i'm pretty sure hannie can hit harder
but tim
is a good runner so i'm not really sure
how that would have worked out that
would have
been a hoot um with martin in the middle
or or maybe rachel
no rachel would be the judge martin
would be the referee
i think that would have been awesome
sorry
squirrel uh conflict the common goal or
objective that we're trying to address
with in this particular story darth
vader i've been waiting for you obi-wan
we meet again at last i made you some
toast it's a little on the dark side
don't you think
um and resolution here's how we're
working together to achieve
our common goals can not just your goals
not just my goals our common goals
or how we're measuring success and how
we can all achieve it it might feel
silly but it works and if we look at all
media it's kind of
the standard formula everything follows
hobbits like many meals we have to
destroy the one ring
mount doom i'm the doom guy oh
those imps or and floating eyeball
things need to get splattered with the
bfg9000
i reached the end roll credits uh real
world my buddy we'll we'll call him
norman
because that's his name um he told me
that his dropbox app disappeared from
his work computer one day
and so he went to the help desk and said
hey why'd my dropbox disappear
all he ended up was getting the cyber
security group said it's been removed
because of policy
do you think that satisfied them no it
just made them think of cyber security
teams a bunch of aminos
could have been much different um so if
we try it with the storytelling
mentality
again it's not i am a rambler but
characters conflict resolution so i'm
going to read this one off here
well here's the thing our security team
flag dropbox is a risk and our company
is cash strapped and our help desk is
already overwhelmed but we recognize
you have a business need for a cloud
storage tool we can't use dropbox in the
manner you've been doing it
the potential for you to put
intellectual property in a personally
managed tool
and lose access to it could be super
impactful to us
but we have onedrive for business
activated with our office 365 accounts
please grind through that with the
online learning portal and see if it'll
do the same stuff
because uh then the files stay under the
company's protections
and and and our custody and we all come
out looking pretty suave
okay sure it's simplified but i believe
it works so much better than because
policy
um if you want in the words of
tim mcright get people to do what you
what you want to do get people to do
what you want to do because they want to
do it too
and that's what this is about
so we've done the conditions actions
needs precision clarity and objectivity
characters conflict resolution that's
how you can actually start building your
messages
and and and find ways to actually bring
people along for the ride
how do you actually get that work and
and and
you know the reality is this is real
leadership stuff um you might
just think you're not a leader you're
not a boss you know you know i'm just a
pen tester but the reality is
you are leading people along a path to
you know sean's earlier question
the the the reality is we're asking
people to get better at cyber security
sure cyber security can be all about
technology if we want but the humans the
people who use the computers
are the piece of the puzzle that we
still are really really struggling with
isn't it
so you have the opportunity in every
interaction with humans to to help be a
leader
uh introspect like spider-man check
yourself before you wreck yourself
lots of us have talked about uh
dunning-kruger effect or illusory
superior
or superiority over the years the idea
that you know people get a little bit of
info and they think they're experts on a
subject
um and then we point at them and laugh
at them and say ah you're not actually
an expert in anything
uh the reality is is that we are all
kind of subject to it all of us
so recognizing our own weaknesses take a
peek inside recognize our own weaknesses
and use those as motivation to keep
educating and improving ourselves
if you can and do this carefully
so as you don't break any wiretapping
laws i think it's
like part six of the criminal code i
can't remember um
but consider recording yourself during
your own sit reps or participating in a
meeting or
record your side of a phone call be
careful not to break any wiretapping
laws please
uh it's it's amazing what we can learn
about ourselves
with that little bit of separation too
is that if i've recorded myself and then
i go back and and listen to it later i
can
see where i communicated best when i was
when i was doing the firefighting thing
um and anytime that i was in a command
situation
all of our radio communications were
actually recorded
uh after all the adrenaline was gone and
all the stuff was cleaned up i would go
back and i would listen to my recordings
and i would actually say well how did i
sound on the radio and
sometimes i sounded good sometimes i
didn't but i take the times that i
didn't to learn from that
um prioritizing really uncover with
objectivity what's a priority again a
really important leadership thing here
um everybody cringes at the sound of the
person for whom
everything is an emergency um if
if the blood isn't going round and round
and the air isn't going out you know
life safety stuff
that's a real problem your seat got
moved
take a chill pill avoid being that
catastrophizer
put things in a real bucket of what's
really a priority and in the incident
command system we prioritize through the
big three life safety instant
stabilization protection of assets
property environment star dot star
so one two three life safety take care
of the incident and
uh protection of all the things
afterwards
something that's super helpful are
predefined incident severity levels with
built-in accountabilities
um i don't know maybe we could talk
about that besides 2021 or something and
own things care
make a conscious choice to be that
leader
um so i've learned an incredible amount
i learned so much from my own kids my
middle kid 13 years old she's been the
captain of a couple of sports teams
already
um and not because she's always been the
fastest skater
or the takes the hardest shot or scores
the most gold
she's always chosen by her peers and her
coaches
because she wants to help she in her own
words she wants to help bring out the
best in
in everybody else she wants to bring
bring out the best
get people to bring out the best in
themselves those kind of attributes no
matter where you are
if you have them and if you espouse them
if you hold them dear to your heart you
become known as the people to be relied
upon when stuff
goes south um the people who get talked
about like dang
that colton dude he's always so good in
the crisis um
actively choose to improve yourself and
actively choose to bring out the best in
everyone around you
again besides this is a fantastic
opportunity for anybody
that if you're looking for a place
to help this is it this is a great
opportunity
uh and then the last question that i
have this is my last slide before my
my kind of exit which i think i'm trying
to get us back on track which would be
lovely
and i'm gonna go back to the chat and
see if there's any uh
any cool things if anybody's got any
cool uh
cool questions or anything pop them in
the stage there and i'll try to sneak
back to them afterwards
how do we get there how do we become
great security communicators when plague
hits the planet or the north koreans are
all up in our
stuff well do you get precise and
accurate slap shot by reading about it
no um can you beat leader arlo and
pokemon go
when you're only level 15 no
you get good from being in the trenches
so engage
engage practice plan engage
stuff goes off the rails every day find
ways to participate
even if it's not your stuff especially
if it's not your stuff oh my goodness
i'd far rather be part of someone else's
emergency than my own
say yes uh catch when something's going
crazy float the can
float the question i can report hey alan
i heard that storage is completely
offline and everyone is
dead in the water across the entire
company tell you what the comms
department is right around the corner
from me can
i be your liaison for company-wide
broadcasts and take that off your plate
right conditions actions needs i heard
everything's broken um
i'm physically located near the comms
department and we need to you know
just in case you forgot we kind of need
to tell everybody that everything's
broken
and i can handle that for you
can i take that off your plate ask him
permission you know
one of the ones that's always a
challenge and we do this all the time
because we're lazy and we're really
hoping the answer is no
that question of is there anything i can
do no of course not
find something you can do and engage get
in there find a way to get in there
um practice bust out the 20-sided die
and take on the demigorgon
um on my website at missioncritical.ca
and this isn't a plug for my consulting
business because it doesn't exist
uh i've got a but i'm just using that's
my email addresses and where all my
family hangs out oh god please don't box
me it's also
wordpress please don't hack me um head
over to
if you go to mr critical.ca and you pop
into the cyber security tabletop
scenarios it's just some really simple
like a few dozen like really simple
really basic scenarios that you can have
some fun with take it to your
team my biggest takeaway from running
many many tabletops for a very very long
time
make the scenario simple and play along
with your environments
variables don't try to control the
outcomes
let them evolve naturally but just pull
out some floaters chuck them on the
table and say okay uh
jeff you're up here's your situation
you're kind of farting around with
something you're following something
funny and you found out that
the lady who everybody loves has been
with the company for 25 years
uh in accounting you know sings the
loudest on cake day also
happens to you know be doing books on
the corporate computers for the hell's
angels
how are we going to deal with that jeff
go ah right
and plan planning uh me and my seven ps
that i stole graciously from
i think the us army uh proper prior
planning prevents poor performance
using scenarios uh and tabletops
uh anything that you've currently are
previously engaged in
connect with your marketing
communications teams find somebody in
your organization who likes to write
build your own high probability and high
impact risk scenarios
and just build yourself some templates
because oh boy if you've got pci
compliance you want to start dealing
with that animal on the fly a
um essential stuff that i believe is
important to have in your back pocket
ready to go
in 2020 privacy or health information
breach notifications
um which comes in a couple of different
ways one
you might have to talk to rachel uh
at the oipc and your
everybody's got pii don't kid yourself
you've got pii
in your environment um even if it's just
your own hr
information you got pii maybe p personal
health information too
so you may have to do a notification to
them or your customers or your vendors
right so so have some of that kind of
pre-built
and and don't build it under stress
because that sucks well i guess
if you have to you don't have a choice
um
media holding or formal statements if
you can get somebody maybe on
even on a contract to help you with some
media holding informal statements
because honestly maybe your ransomware
attack will get you in the news
if you've got customers and your
customers complain enough you could end
up on global
i don't know but the idea of having that
in your back pocket also
something to revisit on a regular basis
helps you understand where your
customers are and what their
is important to them um insurance and
lawyer activation messages you
don't necessarily want to be walking
down the hallway going
to the ceo saying um do we have a lawyer
on retainer
uh while things are going ugly and same
with your insurance maybe find out what
your insurance is and figure out what
their expectations are
um financial partner compromise
notifications because business email
compromise is still a thing because
people still click things and read
things so
just some ideas of things that you could
use
in your own world ahead of time so
engage
you know say yes get involved in things
it doesn't even necessarily have to be
security but just things that
that are ugly and messy get involved dig
in um and maybe that's just my personal
bias because i like the dirty stuff
uh practice like actually practice but
don't get overwhelmed with huge tabletop
scenarios just
easy quick floaters have some fun and
plan the more
proper prior planning the less poor your
performance will be
so that's what we talked about in my my
five of threes
uh precision clarity objectivity
conditions actions needs
characters conflict resolution
introspect prioritize
own engage practice and plan all in
in hacker friendly green text on black
screen
uh and now we get to eat cake or at
least i do or at least my dad's cookies
uh and we're 244 i think i was supposed
to be off deck at 250 so i'm gonna just
take a quick peek
through oh thanks matt wordpress comes
pre-hacked no worry i know but i was
just trying to get my stuff done
pci compliance on the fly yeah marlon i
been there it sucks it's awful
um for if if anybody at some point
decides they want to get a hold of me
too you can try me on linkedin it's
pretty much the only social media i i
pay attention to the uh
um the reality is is that i i kind of
have
i have message burnout like a lot of
people so if you do reach out to me by
all means
call me a donkey or something it's
totally cool but i might be uh
it might take me a while to get back to
you i do try to respond
uh if cyber oh percent if cyber
insurance is involved reach coaches
yes yes if your organization is large
enough to support a breach coach
get that that's one of those proper
prior planning things get involved in
that
uh and dedicated cost centers to track
expenses related to instant
investigation
depending on your uh your organization
you may or may not get some some
uh some traction with that i've found
that a number of
of of accountants especially now
and in depressed economic conditions are
feeling really pinched by saying oh yeah
here's
here's a here's a variable bucket that
you can use for not sucking what i have
done in the past and has given me some
really really good advantages
is having an instant response retainer
with uh
um any number of vendors and i'm not
going to name any because
i've already done my my product
placements but there's any number of
vendors out there who can give you ir
retainers so and and they can include
things as well
like breach costs and if you don't
actually use their services for incident
response
you can use them for the tabletops so
you can help outsource some of your
design of your your exercises as well
what else do we have in here
oh tj you're so sweet
uh tony tony yeah
the the why how what if anybody's not
familiar with
the simon i guess it was it was the tedx
talk that launched simon's career
it's on youtube it's it's lovely it's uh
it's it's a fantastic thing that talks
about how to
start hitting people at their heart and
i would i would offer
that that's something that we tend to do
when we're when we talk about decision
making and
back to another one of adam's three
things we tend to make decisions
emotionally logically or financially
well there's a three uh you know
emotionally
we tend to make a lot of our decisions
emotionally financially you
what when's when's the best time to go
to the restaurant when we're hungry
uh what do we do when we're broke we
look in the fridge um
or or the logically thing we always
think that we're making
logical decisions about security and
things like that but the reality is
chances are we're pissed off at someone
and we're
we're more interested in having a fight
um
again talking about education and
awareness is that we want to get people
thinking critically
pause think verify anybody who worked
with me while i was at the city of
calgary would have heard that over and
over again is probably sick of it by now
but asking people to pause when they're
they receive a call to action over
email or over uh over a web page or over
a text message or a phone call or
anything
slow down think think critically use
your critical thinking skills in your
brain
to do the work and verify if it doesn't
pass the initial sniff
test just go ask somebody feel free to
use that i didn't copyright it and i
hope nobody ever does copyright it
because it makes really good sense
to be able to you know get people
people who are using computers to really
understand kind of our priorities too
slow down think about it but the reality
is is to get to the frontal cortex where
we do all of our thinking at the front
of our brain again i'm not a doctor or a
psychologist
but everything comes up the nervous
system through the back of our head at
the hippocampus where all of our
emotions
are generated ah so we have to consider
the emotional
aspect of asking people to make
decisions
uh what else do we have in the personas
masks to reduce human talk of nature and
made us
more listening i would one of the more
interesting things for me
is that um because i have resting
resting jerk face
uh when walking through a uh
when walking down a hallway or something
i usually like
i make eye contact with somebody and i
love the idea of
you know giving somebody a silly grin or
something and that's what
and it's amazing people smile back and
they get goofy and that's what the mask
has eliminated for me so i have to be
very mindful now of of where my eyes are
in my head
anyways um there's somebody back now and
some say that he invented the magnetic
resonant
immature and he once lost a kayak on
bomaris lake
all we know is he's called harvinder my
friend how are you
oh i'm good um
thank you it's uh like you know an
awesome talk uh
you know kind of made me think in
multiple ways
especially like you know from for the
communication like in a precision
clarity and objectivity
component um a very very high energy
talk a lot of people actually asking
what is your like you know how many
coffee you consume
for your day full of ir
activities i had three of these but in
the morning all i've had is water since
uh since lunch um i'm passionate about
this i love this i love the opportunity
not only to talk to people but to talk
to people about security and to talk to
people about
um uh communication because
i don't know it's fun oh yeah i know i
know i remember when the day i was
visiting calgary and you showed me the
city of calgary and
i see the like you know how much energy
and how much like
i would say enthusiasm has like you know
inside your head like you know you
showed me
i like almost 70 80 percent of the
facilities
i had you breathing hard that day that
was a lot of fun now my
my my current employer only has one
building so the next time you pop down
pop down highway too um not bring your
shoes anyways we'll go on a run
yeah so thank you very much um
thank you and besides participants thank
you so much for coming along
really appreciate everybody here