okay
we are live uh hello everyone
uh the next i would like to
next presenter uh jason maynard
um first of all i want to say he is like
speaking
like you know consecutive third year in
the row and
uh that's like you know kind of an
achievement
like you know in itself uh so thank you
jason uh for like you know speaking so i
would
uh like you know kind of go through the
jason's uh introduction
so jason maynard has been architecting
designing and deploying security
technologies that secure the most
complex computing environments
for almost two decades his understanding
of technologies
people and process enable him to deliver
effective
comprehensive security solutions that
align to an organization's security
goals and strategic
imperative json is adapt at
addressing a range of risk profile
across
industry vertical skills he cultivated
as an end user security practitioner
partner integrator and now manufacturer
as senior technical solution architect
cyber security for cisco system
json is also active in direct community
speaking at bc aware
privacy and security conference and
as i mentioned before he delivered
sessions uh
all like you know all all the be like
you know most of the b
side i think in canada uh jason also
hold like over 75 plus
designations that's a lot man across a
variety of product and technology
including cci designations
so uh just gonna talk about uh as you
can
as you can see on the screen security
no viruses but the pandemic introduces
new challenges to the security team
so over to you jason
awesome thanks harv and thanks everyone
um that's uh
that's organized b-sides you guys do an
amazing job and uh
kudos to the entire team um yeah so
this session should be interesting if
you saw my session uh
last year um you would have seen about
taking a step back and looking at it
from
a different perspective when it comes to
securing your organization
we're going to do a little bit of that
again we're going to build on that
initial session uh but we're gonna talk
about some of the
things that we've seen during the
pandemic um
i know i don't have video i'm actually
in the rockies i got a thousand
millisecond
latency link so video's probably only
gonna uh
hurt me uh at this time but if you want
to have a visual think of me
dressed up in a suit um you know uh all
cleaned up
i'm not shaving the beard has only
gotten longer um
but in reality i'm still in my pajamas
right
but that's the way it is with uh covet
19 and
and 2020 right
all right so let's talk about the
initial focus so
you know during the pandemic you know
every one of us
that uh drives any type of security
component within any organization
it was all hands on deck right and and
so we were focused on
increasing vpn capacity right and and
that was
probably the the core of most uh
if you're a networking engineer security
practitioner
didn't really matter it was really
trying to keep businesses alive right
people had to work from home and we
needed to start
leveraging and adopting you know some of
the traditional methods that we use
today
and uh vpn was a big part of that
and a lot of it was centered around vpn
licensing and increased capacity so we
work on that head end
and we'd ensure that we've had enough
capacity required
to satisfy the need problem was
is that after we did that other
supporting infrastructure
started to fail right and um and that
could
connections per second on on switch
infrastructure
uh firewalls etc but
we've never built uh the vpn
to to be able to run the entire business
on right it wasn't
at the forefront it was always there
just in case for a pandemic
but it was really meant to augment
certain users that
that needed the capacity to work away
from the office
not to run the entire business on and so
we struggled and that over subscription
could have been internet circuits
could have been like i said switching
infrastructure
and then and then what we did was we in
order to satisfy this and again this
sets the framework
of why we want to take a step back is
that we started saying well wait a
minute maybe we need to offload some
capacity
and and so this is where we start
introducing things like split tunneling
right we start saying you know what
things like sas based services if we
have office 365 in the cloud should we
back
all that through a vpn connection just
to go back out to the internet
um what about things like netflix can we
control
users accessing those resources and
again the burden
that it would put on our infrastructure
if we were to pass it through
that vpn tunnel and so we started
shifting some of those
applications um to go direct
or not even come through that internet
or that vpn connectivity
obviously there's challenges when we
start doing that
and then what we did was we started
adding web services
right so we said well wait a minute some
users don't even need
vpn connectivity what they need is
access to this
specific application and so we may have
introduced that to
the internet and use native tls
as a security wrapper to give access to
certain individuals to these services
and then we extend that beyond that
right we we start looking at
um sas right uh we may have already had
some things in in
in the cloud already um the other thing
is this may have
forced you to move things faster so you
might have had a hybrid
exchange environment right with uh
office 365
in the cloud and and so it may have
pushed you to move
faster to adopt that full cloud-based
capability
or sas based capability and then what
we've done is we've increased
you know the amount of users that aren't
really used to working from home
right i mean i've been working from home
i think over a decade now
um but um you know there's a lot of
people that don't outside of i.t
right i.t may have had more of that
flexibility
but the the average user used to go into
a brick and mortar
type facility and and do their
day-to-day
uh job um and now we've said here's a
laptop
go home and don't come back right and
and connect
and and so we've exposed them to an
environment that they weren't they were
not used to
right and and they're always used to you
know
when they connect in inside the
organization there's some security
controls that are in place
and so they probably don't realize it
but there
there's things to make sure that they're
safe that may not be in play when you
work from home
and so security right what about
security in all of this right
is there an issue is is there a concern
we've done a good job of
giving people access quite honestly it's
the biggest
proof of concept i believe in it
ever right ever we've
forced the entire world almost to say
get out of the office and work from home
and use
technologies uh that
you know some users haven't used before
at a capacity that we've never seen so
it's
been a a tremendous trial and i think it
has
tremendous impact on how we move forward
right
and you've got to think about this what
about covet 2 like phase 2 what happens
in the fall
right do we users have to be sent home
again
right do we have the capacity and and
that right if
if it has to increase but not only that
many organizations i believe
are going to realize that this work from
home model actually works
and if it works then do i need to to
have brick and mortar right or as much
of it right
and i think the commercial space could
be in trouble
um uh you know moving forward right
because of this so don't believe me
um security is is a real problem
especially from work from home so what
i've done
is i've went to you know cyber security
infrastructure security agency
like cisa and and i i just looked for
you know elements around covid and work
from home
um and i found there's no shortage of
threats out there
actually we we're seeing an increase in
in threads
and so again here's one that talks about
covet 19
loan relief web page and phishing emails
right so the threat actor is
is using covid19 to get people to bite
right you've got you know hopefully this
doesn't happen
today um but uh you've got uh you know
all this video conferencing type
technology
um and and you've got to consider you
know if somebody jumps into a meeting
that shouldn't be in a meeting is it
secure and encrypted
these are all things that we may not
have thought about originally when we
started onboarding some of our
capabilities right we were so much in a
rush
to get the capability in play that we
haven't actually taken a step back
and really looked at the threat
landscape right and what it means from
work from home
malicious activity targeting covid19
research
vaccine development so there's a big
push to be first
right and so you've got to think any of
these organizations that are doing
research around vaccine development
development
are certainly at higher risk at this
point in time right whether it be state
sponsored
or other doesn't really matter
the threat is real right people want to
be first or countries want to be first
with vaccine development so either
they're going to steal
intellectual data or what they're going
to do is
compromise the data that you have so the
outcomes
may not be the outcomes that that you
would have seen because there was some
compromise somewhere
ddos attacks are have increased by
500 percent uh again because of covet
one of the elements we've got to think
about is is that i don't now have to
worry about just disrupting your
internet as an adversary
disrupting your internet would cause
issues right normally it would
anything going to the internet would be
at risk right but
usually when you're in a brick and
mortar type facility
all of your resources are usually
accessible still right it's usually not
going over that same internet circuit
it's either back hauled internally or
through a dedicated circuit of some
some sort and so internally i have full
operations my teams continue to
function yes there might be some
disruption but it's not
massive now i have to target all i have
to do is target
vpn head ends as an example or some
web-based service that
that you're having your users leverage
to continue operations
i just have to target that so it could
be a volumetric attack
right which means i could you know shift
traffic
to the internet and scrub it or it could
be more service impacting
focusing on you know a certain service
that you're offering and try to impact
that
service and not worry about trying to
saturate your your uplinks but it
becomes a tremendous problem with vpn
and here's another alert around
enterprise vpn security
and again it just talks a little bit
about um
you know some of the elements here right
as organizations use vpn
right more vulnerabilities exist the
adversary has adjusted its tactics
it's um it gets a little bit more
difficult around
patching right because vpn becomes you
know 100
reliable or and so
you know when do you keep the patch
updates now for your vpn
you've got phishing emails that are
targeting teleworkers again stealing
usernames and passwords if i can get
your vpn username and password there's
likelihood that i i'll have full access
into the organization
right and so you might say well not my
organization
you'd still be restricted based on that
that user identity
um but many organizations may not right
again it depends on how fast you move to
get these users
uh onboarded uh so they can work from
home
and then we've got things like you know
multi-factor authentication if we're not
using it we're more susceptible to
phishing attacks right
and um obviously i mentioned this one
already around
you know the vpn head end becomes a very
critical service to keep operations up
business operations up that is
and then another one here again it just
kind of walks through
a little bit and using covid now as the
theme as the lure right
so now you've got fishing that's got
coven 19
elements wrapped around it you've got
malware distribution points
uh domains obviously have coronavirus or
kova 19
names in them now um and again
um they they continue to target and
here's a couple of
examples right where malicious android
app
um provides real-time coronavirus
outbreak tracker right that sounds
usable
usable right that's something that i
might want but instead it downloads
uh you know it and gives the uh
administrative access to install covet
lock on on this particular device so
it's ransomware for the device
but as a normal user you know i'm
thinking that this application is going
to help me right
especially during the pandemic and and
and to be quite honest many users
including myself
this is where we're going to get our
information we're going out to the
internet and trying to understand what
covid19 and coronavirus what it looks
like in our neighborhoods what we can do
to minimize
you know our risk and this one here
it was it definitely hits home right
this is in canada
where um you know we've seen a shift
where
the adversary is so clever right is that
wait a minute what about if i tell the
user that their account has been
breached and i'm here to help them
right so now they're using the
the aftermath of a breach as a way to
entice you
to maybe click on something or provide
some information
and this one here actually hits home for
me
specifically because i i know somebody
very close to me that actually had this
happen
and this is where you know august 15th
the canadian government announced that
uh cra accounts were compromised and
they used the
credential stuffing attack so basically
what they did was
they went and logged or they breached
and got credentials
through other breaches and used those
those credentials to log into
cra they logged into cra they changed
the
direct deposit information of the
accounts and
then they applied for covet 19 whatever
relief
uh you know things that are available to
canadians
and had that money deposited into that
account
uh and then got out of there right so so
it's real right um
work from home and the pandemic has
definitely
increased our overall uh risk profile
so we're gonna take a step back as i
mentioned right we're going to look at
this
based on a a use case and we're going to
look at it
from what security wrappers do we think
are required this isn't
vendor technology this is capabilities
right
so we'll look at the internet use case
don't look as when you see the flows
don't look
the the cloud is just meaning that this
is the flow that we're looking at
but uh the internet use case will
include users going directly to internet
or split tunneling
um oh went the wrong way here sorry
the next one will be sas use case right
include users going directly to sas
based services using native tls
typically and then you've got vpn use
cases right and now this is where you're
terminating to a vpn headed as an
example and so we want to think about
things like phishing
and malware but also you know
prevention's awesome
the reality is no matter what
technologies you have
how well you cobble them together
the adversary is going to win at times
and so you've got to think about the
other side of the equation right
do i have the data do i have the
information
i need to be able to determine what
actually took place
and ultimately build in mechanisms to
defeat the adversary moving forward
system hygiene right ddos direct
internet
social engineering dns outage right
split tunneling now dns
outage is interesting right because you
don't think of how critical dns becomes
when you start using sas based services
right if i can't resolve can i still
get to office 365
so who you use or what you use for dns
now becomes
something that you want to consider
obviously inside you would do that you
most likely have your own infrastructure
that supports this
but now they're working from home it may
not even be vpned in directly into the
organization
credential theft and we can go on right
we've talked about many of them
and so this is where i build this out
right so now we look at an endpoint and
we
we we we have a user and they're going
to connect and and we're going to build
out these flows together
well it's really going to be me you're
going to be listening hopefully
um but um we'll look at it from two
lenses
right i thought about this at first and
i thought you know what i would break
these up because you've got a prevention
capability
and then you have a detect and respond
capability and and so what i've done is
you know if you can prevent something
that's great right detection well you've
already prevented it so you had to
attack
and response well you blocked it right
so there is already
somewhat of an inherent response there
because you prevented the attack
um but i break them up and we'll walk
through this together
we've got uh patching right system
hygiene
it's still a big thing right if we can
patch 100
of everything we'd be in really good
shape
but you got to think about that work
from home user right how are you
patching those systems
right how are you keeping them updated
right are you using some management
platform internally
using some type of tls mechanism to
secure it are you doing it through a vpn
connection when they connect but what
happens if they don't connect
what if it's 10 days that they don't
connect because they used a sas based
service and there wasn't a need to
connect to the vpn right so these are
things that we want to think about
exploit prevention right so now we get
into
defending your endpoints for from things
like memory injection
right and these attacks are commonly
seen with malware and zero day and they
attack unpatched software
and then you get into system protection
process right so we want to make sure
that those system
processes are not being attacked by
other processes on the system
and again this is focused on capability
right i'm not saying this is a
technology that you need
it's just the capability that you've got
to consider
advanced malware and av right that's
obviously commonplace nowadays
but you want to make sure that you're
using something with multi-engine
platform or multi-intelligence platform
right that has
different insights into the threat
landscape and hopefully different ways
of detecting whether or not something
malicious is happening
malicious activity protection so what
happens if
as an example something does pass your
defensive capabilities
right we know that that's a reality it's
going to happen
and what if it starts encrypting the
drive just starts to do it right
do you have a mechanism maybe to stop
that particular process that's invoking
something that
you deem as malicious right
so these are again things to consider
application blocking so again you might
want to make sure that certain
applications aren't uh
able to operate on on a mobile endpoint
right no matter where they are
um but but the other use case and i've
worked with someone recently on this one
is what happens if you have to let
somebody go
um right and um and they're not coming
back to the office
necessarily right and so they've got to
ship the laptop but from
the point of when they ship the laptop
to when you receive it
you're worried about whether or not
there's some localized data on the asset
now
nobody wants localized data but do you
have controls in place to
mitigate against that that that would be
a question so you can use something like
app blocking to do something clever
right right so say there was a
termination that took place
um obviously you shut down all the
access internally vpns active directory
all that magical stuff
um but i can also maybe build a policy
that says
block explorer.exe from launching
right and so if the user uses the laptop
and flips it up
it gets the update um they try to log in
uh there's no shell
right the the asset becomes unusable
at that point in time so again being
clever with the technologies that you
have
network blocking so the ability to
you know block you know l3 l4 type
controls right and again this doesn't
always necessarily have to be on the end
point this could be anywhere else
but the thing the way i you know some
people argue defense in depth
whether it's dead or alive i do believe
that if you have multiple controls in
multiple different layers
your success of either
defending or making it so
um uh so um difficult for the adversary
to be successful that they move on
right and so you know you want to look
at this as a multi-prong approach for
sure
usb blocking so this becomes another
issue
right maybe not an issue that we thought
was a big deal when they're on premise
but now off
premise you know we've got students from
from home
right and so people are scrambling to
get their
children asked access to laptops and
devices and
and so maybe you know they're using
their work laptop even if policy
suggests otherwise
you know people tend to you know
again want to help their family members
and and
they don't suspect anything risky is
going to happen because they don't know
computers
and so a student comes in or the family
member that's a student comes in and
plugs in the usb device opens up a pdf
the pdf has malware on it right
and so you might want to have some
controls there to force
the data to be in a file repository in
the cloud
maybe or on premise as opposed to coming
in through external devices
intrusion prevention i think that's
commonplace firewalling
right so you got network blocking based
on l4
l3 l4 based on um maybe
you get some security intelligence to
suggest something's bad and so you just
don't want to
communicate outbound and then you've got
you know standard-based firewalling
that might be built into the system
itself or through a you know
an application that you've purchased you
get fileless
uh malware right so this is where we get
into um
you know again taking advantage of
uh memory and injection and running code
and memory and evading and so
exploit prevention and system protection
process those are some elements that are
going to
help you here but we've got to consider
file lists as well
and then you get into you know some more
of the buzz buzz terms right
uh ai and uh machine learning so
machine learning is a subset of ai uh
but machine learning you've got to have
a lot of good data and a lot of bad data
in order for those
algorithms to really mature but it's
something you want to consider
right on the end point and so that kind
of rounds out prevention and somebody
might have their hand up saying well
wait what about what
yes there could be more there could be
less right um
but you get the idea really taking that
step back
i haven't even talked about what i'm
connecting to yet i'm just talking
at the end point at this point these are
some of the things that i would consider
these are things that i've been talking
to people about
over the last you know probably five
months uh
ever since covid really started and then
now we move into detect and respond
right so now you
you know buzz terms like endpoint
detection and response right
the ability to understand that a word uh
document was opened by windward and it
executed a macro the macro then
reached into powershell and reached out
to a ip address pulled down a dropper
file
yada yada right the story of what
happened
um tremendously valuable especially now
that you don't have access to these
resources
as much as you did before when they were
on premise
forensic snapshot right i need to be
able to take a snapshot of that endpoint
at any point if there's an incident
can i do that what if they're not
connected to a vpn
what if they have direct connection to
an internet can i
can i get the data i need again this
could be a very big
breach right and i need some additional
insight and maybe it all started here
um and so i need some insight from that
endpoint
host isolation right the ability to be
able to minimize
the overall risk of that endpoint if it
was compromised
right so once you determine it has been
compromised what do you do
right okay so maybe you have edr maybe
you can take a forensic snapshot
but can i isolate the house and still um
you know do my investigation let it have
limited access
right so these are things that we want
to consider because vpn isn't going to
always be there
cloud-based ioc so again enhancing the
technol
or the intelligent stack that you have
and again based on certain activities
and patterns you might have to flag
indications of compromise now this
doesn't necessarily have to be cloud
but i see the trend moving towards more
of that big
data you know uh data
uh intelligence you know that that
typically comes from the cloud
uh because it's too big to build on
premise
command line capture again if if power
shell's going to be
invoked i i don't only want to know that
power shell was invoked
i want to know that it was power cat
minus c
[Music]
4.4.4.4 minus
you know p444 right i want to know the
exact command line
that was or you're using powershell to
download a file and start the process
i need to know what that command line um
that was passed within that
that application that was used or
processed that was used
you've got sandboxing and file analysis
now i didn't put this as a prevention
capability because i feel that
sandboxing takes a bit of time to do
and in order to do that um you can't
stop
an http connection mid-stream and say
give me seven to
you know five minutes or five to seven
minutes to execute this payload in the
sandbox environment come out with a
disposition and update you late
right before you can you just can't do
that it's impossible
um and so um i see this more of an after
uh thought so it may have been sandboxed
right
then you've got to think about okay now
you know the disposition is bad how does
it tell the end point about the
disposition
and what does it do with it but also i
need this to be able to do my own
analysis right
if i need to submit a file or review a
file that was submitted
i want to know what registry entries
network connections i want
you know p caps i want um you know
what behavioral indicators were
triggered i need to know all of that
right to help
understand the full context of the
threat that i'm dealing with
and then we move into vulnerable
software right you can't be successful
at patching unless you identify the
vulnerable
uh software sure you can do it regular
every tuesday right patch tuesday
but there's other software that might be
on the system that needs to be patched
as well and
and i want to be able to tie vulnerable
software to any breach that might have
happened
that's key to me right because if if i
can mitigate the vulnerability i
essentially break the the adversary's
ability to be successful
but if i can't tie the threat to the
vulnerability
um or the breach to the vulnerability
then it's just going to continue to to
happen
ipfix or or network flow data right from
from an endpoint where it ties in the
process
to the network connectivity that it's
making and so
some of you might be sitting on the edge
of your chair say well wait a minute
isn't that what endpoint detection
response does
kinda right it does but it's usually
limited to the number of flows per
application that it that it actually
tracks what i'm talking about here
is every single application or process
that makes a network connection
regardless
of any threat is actually being
monitored and tracked
all right now we've got the end point
right some people might be saying well
the endpoint would never run if it had
all this stuff on it right but
you certainly can do that in today's
world right
agents are becoming uh thinner and and
streamlined
um there's some things here you can use
uh you know a couple of products with
some are inherently built into the
operating system
just have to expose it and then others
might be you know based on
vendors that you that you might deal
with right but you want to look at that
both from a prevention and detection
and response perspective so
cool but before we even connect any
services there's some other things that
we want to consider
like dns security right again i told you
earlier that now your vpn head end or
your sas based services
all of these dns records that you
leverage
have to resolve and if they don't
resolve then that service will be down
disrupting your users so dns security
becomes not
only the an ability to make sure that
you can resolve
services but also a mechanism to prevent
threats right dns is a first-line
capability when it comes to breaches
right dns has to happen before i make a
connection and so it gives me an
opportunity
to cut it off sooner in the attack chain
web proxy right you might want to have
proxy why
well now you want to run additional
inspections
against that payload if you're waiting
for the end point
to catch it because you might be saying
well wait a minute you know
you could say dlp tls decryption and
advanced malware
wait a minute i have that here right
like so why do i
need it here right it's going to see it
here
i'm a big believer that if you wait for
the end point to solve the problem
right just to solve the breach it's
always too late
in my mind that's not where you want to
defend right
now you have to defend there that's a
reality
because you can't trust the other
controls that you have elsewhere are
going to be a hundred percent every
single time
and so you need something at the end
point but if i had it in my mind where i
wanted to defend i want to defend as far
away from the asset i'm protecting as
possible
and so web proxy allows us now to do dlp
we can start thinking about tls
decryption it's more specifically around
um you know tls 1.3 and some of the
implications that are caused
there around decryption and then i could
do advanced malware inspection
and then i transitioned from the
prevention side to
okay what are the other things that i
would would require
so thinking about this is dns forensics
right that this becomes tremendously
valuable
again determining not only about what
took place
but also maybe understanding the attack
infrastructure right
that that that is being leveraged so dns
forensics becomes
highly critical full uri capture so if
you are doing proxy or the need for
proxy exists
again having that full uri is certainly
helpful
sandbox and file analysis it's a proxy
connection
and so if you've got a sandbox it's http
you can't keep that connection open
forever
and so uh you know you've got to do the
sandbox and file analysis very much the
same as what we talked about on the
endpoint
and now we move into the internet
connectivity right and so this internet
connectivity
might be a little bit more open here
right because they're not coming to
a vpn head end or a sas based service
now in this case
i'm showing email like it would be a sas
based service
and and i'm not really focused on that
side of it
um today but you also have to look at
that if this is web conferencing as an
example
you've got to think about is it is it
secure is it encrypted where does the
data reside like these are all things
you got to think about on the services
side
especially if you're exposing it like
you've never done before
and i used email as an example here and
i'll continue that theme
moving forward so we only have to walk
through this once
but you've got reputation filtering
right spam business email compromise
advanced malware protection again right
like
you might be saying well wait a minute
it's already here right
well yes but if i can block the
attachment from
ever the user clicking on it i want to
do that right and so
here's an opportunity for me to extend
that capability
here and prevent much sooner in the
attack chain
gray mail phishing right anybody that's
done anything around email security
um you know knows these are fairly
common capabilities that that would
exist today in
any mature email security offering and
so
url protection is another one and so
some people and i've heard this
this comment uh you know talking with
many people across the west
is why do i need url protection here at
the email level because when i click it
isn't that dns going to do a dns lookup
and then i got this web proxy capability
you're right
it does right but if i can actually
defang it
in an email so nobody clicks on it i
don't have to worry about whether their
dns security had intelligence to know it
was bad
right i was already able to to mitigate
that risk
or maybe i redirect that that maybe for
proxy as an example
you've got sandboxing now you notice i
didn't say sandboxing and file analysis
i've left file analysis both for detect
and respond
sandboxing i included here is a
prevention capability
because the email is never
you know instant you have an opportunity
here to hold email for a little bit
longer
and therefore you could run it through a
sandbox get the disposition back
before um before
you ever send it to the user itself
dlp right and then you get into some of
the forensic pieces right the detect and
respond
right message tracking i want to know
everything about the message file
analysis right i want to know behavioral
indicators again it's more of the same
so that's email right on the services
side so we won't do that again
although the theme will carry for vpn
and sas right but you get the idea of
the process that you want to go through
uh when you're building out your overall
security posture
and you have the opportunity to do this
right um
now this isn't too late you might say
well we've already got things employed
great figure out what you need figure
out where the gaps are
and address them right there is an
opportunity still
to make the organization more secure
so now we get into vpn right again this
is not a termination point
right so don't say well shouldn't this
be here right
no it doesn't matter this is the flow
right you've got all kinds of different
controls wherever
so ddos right again now we know it might
not be volumetric type attacks
although they still exist and you can
use scrubbing stations etc to be able to
you know offload that volumetric
attack into the cloud as an example but
now you've got
service focused impacting um
ddos capabilities and now they're trying
to take down your vpn service
why because they know that now you're
going to be running you know maybe
you're running at 80
um from work from home i could drop that
down where it's very difficult for you
to operate
tls decryption again if i'm doing a
network based inspection here right
again i need to do tls decryption right
or else malware and ips all of that
stuff becomes
i i'm blind to it right and again i know
some might be sitting there saying well
tls here it's open here
tls here tls here lots of t yes there is
again i want to prevent you know as far
away from the
the the individual i'm protecting and so
if i have an opportunity to block
advanced malware here even if this was
going to catch it
i want it blocked here again
if this fails i need this capability
to hopefully catch it and again the the
green stuff right
all this stuff here is key in case you
do get breached
all right so you got multi-factor
authentication you got endpoint posture
right geo control you might not think
that that's much of a control
but it certainly is something that
layers on the complexity that the
adversary
has to overcome right they've gotten out
proxy and take other methods
you've got l7 firewalls right now we're
getting into application control and
again that might be shifted to an
endpoint right or in the cloud
um but it could be a network-based
device as well that's more traditional
you have ips you have advanced malware
inspection
behavioral based policy like the ability
to be able to understand
that this is a critical asset it's
talking to a critical resource
i have this software version on it and
there's an indication of compromise
right so i may be on all those factors
want this to be a certain impact level
so i can
actually address it then you get into
web application firewalling
you got device insight denied
authentications
right host profiling impact analysis
sandbox and file analysis right so
impacts analysis and host profiling
are key and the reason why they're key
is is that if you don't understand the
asset you're protecting
how do you understand the impact of the
threat that's coming in and so those two
work together right but these are things
that you want to consider
whether you use it in the platform
that's being offered or you try to
figure out a mechanism to do it
externally
vulnerability insight again if i know
the vulnerabilities that are being
targeted i can get them patched
in the meantime maybe use ips signatures
to minimize my risk here you got flow
analytics
event packet capture
um and then um and then you've got
event workflow right so this is the
ability to pivot
and understand what the threat looks
holistically
right from end to end ultimately and
then you get into the application
right and again so sas space there's a
couple here
i'm going to move because i'm already
getting the 10 minute warning
so multi-factor authentication right for
sas based service right we'd also want
multi-factor as i mentioned for vpn
right or any other service that we're
offering
the more critical the service obviously
the the more critical multi-factor
becomes
endpoint posture i want to understand
the end point right before it's
connecting to that sas base
geocontrol we've already covered that
you've got
restrict non-sanction applications right
so applications that
exist for example if you have one drive
and that's your file repository what
about dropbox box and all the other file
repositories the user can still get to
remember they're not plugged into the
network and they're not going through
maybe a next-gen firewall that's doing
application control
right they might be driving this because
they're they're directly
connected to the internet and using that
sas based service
so we want to make sure that those data
that data is not being moved over
you've got sas based dlp as well
and then you get into device insight
denied
authentications right i want to know if
multi-factor fails
then there's a good indication that a
credential was stolen right because they
got to the second
factor and it failed shadow i.t and
community trust rating so the ability to
understand the applications my users are
using in the cloud and
figure out whether or not these are
should be moved to sanctioned
applications
user identity behavior analytics if i
log in in edmonton to salesforce and
then
an hour later i log into um
uh uh office 365
from maybe the continent of africa or
whatever right
if i've logged in there i can't be in
those two places uh very quickly and so
i need something to tie that together to
let me know that that actually took
place
and there's risk and then you have the
service at the end right so whatever it
is email
web uh some web type
platform doesn't really matter
salesforce etc right you've got to think
about the security wrappers for that
application as well
not only within the app right as
tanya was mentioning right the
applications need to be secure but also
anything that's supporting around that
application right as well
and so this is now what you end up with
right so this looks a little bit more
interesting now i have a better picture
of what i need
and now i need to figure out what are
the controls or what are the
technologies that are going to help
satisfy these
these needs but it doesn't stop there
right i think that's understanding the
controls
and the the the the ability to detect
and respond in case of failure
of those controls but then we've got to
think about what happens in instant
response
and threat hunting that that user might
be mobile right it's
they're not connected they're they're
directly connected to the internet and
maybe not vpned in
so how do i hunt right for threats
and so you know lots of people are
building data lakes data lakes are very
expensive to do
and i'm not saying you shouldn't do it
but if you're not down that path
um what you want to be able to do is
hopefully leverage some api based
platform
that can actually query the technologies
you own and provide you insight
and hopefully visuals of what that
threat looks end to end
right so i should be able to say i know
that this is bad
this is a an indicator it's a shaw an ip
whatever
ask the platform questions and it tells
me i've saw it in an email
attachment with this subject i've seen a
dns request go to this domain
and i've saw something on the endpoint
and i'd like that all tied together and
show the relationships between them
and then you've got orchestration and
automation so the ability to be able to
um orchestrate and automate um some of
this right so building out playbooks
becomes
key right and and and even if you
haven't done this and i've got an
example here that you guys can see
in the um the pdf version that i'll
share
with b-sides later but it walks through
going through in the incident response
um consortium and you know you grab
fishing and you walk through fishing you
build out the playbooks that's
meaningful for your organization
but you got to think how can i automate
some of this stuff like if i see a
fishing link come in
wouldn't it be cool if i can say okay
abstract those observations
query the rest of my technologies tell
me the results of all of that
based on my environment right
and also then take a forensic snapshot
move the asset into isolation
uh create a conference room with the
right incident responders so they can
collaborate
and potentially take action right
additional action
on that threat and so maybe that's for
some a longer term strategy
but that when you're building out these
you have to be thinking of these as well
and then you've got threat intelligence
that's going to support all of this
right whether that be third party
in-house
outsourced doesn't really matter the
intelligence comes in and so can i use
these platforms to be able to
feed that new information into to
provide prevention capabilities
and then also be able to query that data
as needed for instant response
and so i'm coming up to the end here
i've included this
just to be complete here so i'm not
going to walk through it
in full but if you're not aware of irc
not irc chat right but irc is
the incident uh response consortium um
check it out right they've got tons and
tons of community-based uh playbooks
that have been developed
and you can grab them download them and
modify them right there's no
no restrictions that i've seen and i've
worked with a lot of organizations that
universities as an example
that certainly leverage uh this this
this site to help build out some of
their playbooks and so
you got to prepare right you got to get
the right teams together
you've got to review a maintain a
timeline and you might have some
interviews and you're going to have some
you know an internal path and your
document that an external path
then you're going to get into detect
right so what is it that we're
actually looking for what are the threat
indicators right we need to understand
those
and then kind of develop them right like
emails that are non-re
uh returnable or non-deliverable right
or
emails that have been linked to an
external or unknown url
right and so these are my indicators and
i need to categorize those
requests maybe packet capture conduct
content scans
now think about these elements too when
you're doing the playbook
are these manual can you automate this
right
these are things that i would want to do
right i don't want my team focused on
trying to capture and pull all the data
right they're too smart for that i want
my team focused on analyzing the
having the human element right let the
technology do all the weeding out of all
the noise
but i need my humans to be able to look
at it understand the context of the
threat based on the business
and be able to come to the determination
to understand the risk to my
organization
analyze it right we need to then define
the risk factors
right log collection evidence collection
data capture etc
then we move into contain we want to
contain it right so how we gonna do that
right servers desktops our credentials
stolen
right uh what other services are
impacted again here's a nice
list of elements that you want to
consider almost done
harv uh eradicate um
triage uh and confirm incident uh
a report right um and ultimately
eradicate the malware that's the goal
um and then recover recover those
systems incident remediation
and this one here post incident handling
although the others are very important
this one i think is critical
right it's at the end everything's been
done
now you need to go back and revisit
right and learn from that
um make sure that you're applying those
lessons and and you're adapting your
your processes to accommodate the things
that you've learned during that incident
and so again you've got to think about
the use case
what you're trying to secure um and
build that out with a longer term
strategy in mind right you might not be
able to get there day one
but you want to build towards something
and building it out based on flow
is going to help you identify what you
require in order to be successful
and that's it and yes
it's anonymous but i i like it oh yeah
awesome presentation again you nailed it
um thank you for that um so uh i have
one question
from the audience um the question is
this
for work from home during covid 19 times
what is the best strategy tips for
security awareness training
for end users who are already under
stress
so so sorry say that again harv i
i kind so so users are under stress
they're already working from home yeah
what's the best strategy for uh security
awareness training
like you know who's uh already under
stress working from home user
so that's the question
so restraining yeah i'm sorry i'm i'm
i'm missing the security awareness
strategy security oh sorry i got it
gotcha it could be that latency on my
side hurt um yeah so i i i think
security awareness training is key right
that's more than ever
um because uh again many of these users
aren't used to it so
there's lots of different platforms out
there that'll actually go through
uh and grade them and test them and it's
not
they don't feel like they're being um
you know uh
graded in the sense like in school right
it's almost more
like playful type uh training exercises
that you can go through
right um and it's not something like
you're bad
it's like you're fantastic and we're
only getting better
but there is a lot of platforms out
there that you could leverage for
security awareness training
okay uh um
thank you very much jason uh like you
know once again
uh you are the one and only person who
are like you know here for
uh three years in the row you know
consecutively so
i think we have to plan this to bring
you every year
so um
yeah so we will be taking break and we
will be back
at 1pm so i will encourage everyone
to please uh visit the uh
sponsor booths in expo section there are
like new
prizes and some draws are like you know
kind of
brought by the sponsor so please visit
them
thank you