[Music]
check
all right so i hope everybody can hear
me
and uh you can see my screen as well
right
okay so let's
start um
so what this talk is about is it's a
uh it's basically uh about
the most common vulnerabilities uh that
are
usually identified in today's
penetration testing
while uh testing.net applications and
and why why certain bugs uh occur and
why do and how how do
we fix them so
fair disclosure to before before we get
into the talk
i was not a full-time programmer i have
not done programming before
uh actually i got into this thing after
conducting a lot of penetration tests on
on the web applications and then
and just to try to make sense
uh why developer do certain things and
and why uh xyz issue occurred
during during as uh in a specific
application
well just to figure out
what's uh what's the developer was
thinking while developing the
application and
uh what might he have done wrong
to cause such issues
so a little bit about me um
i'm a penetration testing consultant
i've uh i'm working
uh as a private uh contractor
right now and and i've been working
for financial organizations uh
government organizations
oil and gas sectors and
whatnot so that's pretty much
it about me and i've been into pen
testing
for like past five years or so
and recently i got into this thing uh
like to understand
to get a better understanding of why
bugs
occur in the application so i decided to
write a
few set of vulnerable codes myself to in
order to
understand uh why these things happen
so this talk uh is going to cover
a lot of issues that that i personally
experience you do
during uh pen test and
how how we can fix them we will be
looking
uh into a code a lot of times and then
we'll be spending a lot of time in and
looking into codes and then
seeing what one line change can
can do so
let's get into it
all right so the most common uh issues
that
uh are identified usually uh when
testing
a dotnet application is like um it's
2020 but
still i i've seen a lot of applications
that are not using secure channel they
they are
still deployed uh uh
over http and then and they are
still communicating over http so pretty
basic
stuff but yes it's 20 20 and we are
still
seeing clear tax issues
in production applications as well all
right the next one is
authentication and session management uh
the other issues is the identify a lot
as
access control issues or or broken
access control or you can
secure object references things like
these so
this is one of the most common issue
found in dotnet application a lot of uh
input validation issues uh
uh for example x sql xml injections
crosstalk scripting these serializations
uh
sometimes command injections as well
template injections
uh another most common category of
issues that are identified while
testing.net application
is is the file upload csrf
is like is not
not that common nowadays but it's still
it's
quite prevalent open redirect yeah it is
still there in
a lot of dotnet applications
misconfigurations and information
disclosures okay
all right so this is uh basically
related to like
informative headers uh enabled and then
how easy
yeah we will get into it and
and see how easy it is to fix those
minor issues
as well all right so
i will just quickly uh go through the
insecure communication channel
and uh basically what it does is your
application is deployed on a server but
the server is not configured uh to use
uh
secure transportation medium for example
a tls certificate is not deployed and
your application is running over http
protocol instead of suvps
so this is one of the issue that's most
common
that's still identified on a lot of
production applications
so uh here is the sample screenshot i
just took it
uh from the internet uh
what can go wrong here if anybody is
sniffing over the network he can
that that attacker can see your
credentials
what is being transmitted uh from the
client side
to the server and then he can even
manipulate
the communication between between the
client and server as well
next up all right this is this is uh
this is where the good stuff will start
and
the furnace stuff will start and this is
where we actually look into the code
code level implementation well what can
uh go wrong at the core level
implementations authentication and
session management all right the most uh
most common issues uh while we identify
uh we identified you during the
pentester is uh
related to this
session id management or or
logout management things for example
when you try to log into
an application what happens in the
background is
you provide your credential and a server
process it
and it checks if the user credentials
are valid and then it sends you back
to some other page and and set sets a
cookie
in your browser so the next time you try
to access any
any of the page of that application
uh you provide the browser provides that
cookie as well
so uh server can identify that
the user is already authenticated and
does not need
to provide uh the credentials again
so as we can see here the first step was
uh
the user logging into the application
the server
redirects the the user and sets a cookie
and then a user visits another page
where he can see his
profile information and server sends
back this is this is the usual behavior
and here is the attacking scenario when
the user logs out
server fails to invalidate uh
the cookie but redirects the user to
login page
so the user tries to access the page
again
and and he can access the information
or view the information again because a
server
or or the programmer forgot to
invalidate those cookies
excuse me sorry so the
programmer basically forgot to
invalidate those cookies that were set
at the time of login and since those
cookies were valid server would gladly
process all the requests from the users
even
when the user clicked on the logout
button
or logout function and will gladly
provide all the information
to user uh regardless if the user is
authenticated or not because of this
issue so
we will quickly look into dummy code
what it looks like and how how we can
fix it
so here we have a
code code base or or a dummy code
basically what it is doing is if we can
see
this is a function or
action you can see uh it's it's uh
basically checking uh it's basically
used for
viewing your profile information all
right and
it checks for
for different parameters where it's it's
a processing
email id as from the user
as input and sending the response back
to
the users but the problem here is at the
log out button we only use session.clear
uh which will not
invalidate and log on the user sessions
even after log out properly
so in order to fix it we have to
remove the cookies and and set a blank
cookie
and then destroy the cookies
and make sure that cookies are destroyed
before
before login in when the user is
trying to log in uh make sure that user
does not have
any previously stored cookies or we have
to clear it manually
and and at the log out
instant we also have to make sure the
same
so this is the actual
page sorry i have to like go back and
forth
in order to explain this example this is
this is the controller view
and this is uh this is the this is
actual user view so this page is not
checking the if the session is valid or
not
and because of that a user
is able to access this page which he was
not supposed to access
before before logging in so
a simple check if a simple check that if
the session is valid or not
we can uh based on that we we can
decide if the session is valid we can
redirect the user
or if they say or if the session is
invalid we can redirect the user to
provide its credentials again so he can
access this page
so just by skipping a check here
uh we introduce our vulnerability that
that can
lead to information disclosure
notice here we are not checking the
session as highlighted in the red box
this could be this could have been
mitigated if we
if the developers uh check the user
session is valid or not
so let's say the user uh
the request got processed and it hits
this control this function
in the controller so here we have
another
issue which we will discuss later on but
combining those two issues uh this
provides a very safer
vulnerability you can access and
retrieve
information of users
without providing any login without
knowing any
valid login credentials if
at the end of the talk if we get if we
have enough time we will get get into
the demos as well so
how do we fix this uh the fix is uh
quite simple
and what we have to do
is to make sure that the pages are well
protected
and and the pages uh should
check if the user session is valid or
not uh
in this case how i mitigated this issue
i was i implemented a simple check uh or
based on the email ids because uh if
i was restoring email id in in the
session variable
and and if i i checked if the session
variable contains
email id or not if the session email
if the session does not contain email id
that means the session is invalid or the
session is blank
so it will redirect the user to login at
the
at the time of login i was saving email
id in the
session variable so this way it can be
mitigated
similarly
if we can see on line number 120
a simple check on session variable since
we are
saving the session variable at the at
the time of login
a simple check if the session
contains email id or not could
have mitigated this issue
all right uh broken access control all
right so this is
uh more uh this is
this uh class of issues often called
insecure object reference sometimes it
is referred to as broken access control
sometimes
we call it elevation of privileges
because
there are multiple names for this class
of bug
depending uh upon
the the situation if if the use
if if the user one let's say
it could it could be called elevation of
privilege if not uh
user can access or modify uh information
of a privileged user in the web
application
in that case it is usually called
elevation of privilege
uh uh i mean horizontal uh elevation of
privilege uh
sorry it's vertical um uh elevation of
privilege
if uh a user can change or view or
modify
information of
of the same role i mean let's say there
are two users
who have like same rights but
a user one can modify or view
information of user 2
this is usually considered as a
horizontal elevation of privilege
this can be mitigated
by implementing uh but just by
implementing
a proper access control
the code example or the dummy code we
are going to look into
is quite similar to the previous one
so just before we go into into the code
here is an example
an illustration so let's say a user
tries
to access following your example.com
index.esp
question mark id is equal to one and and
the server responds right with a welcome
exercise
user xyz and then any when the same user
or
that hacker tries to manipulate the
id value uh the server responds back
with a different value
and then and shows that the information
about different user
so this is this is a very trivial
example
or simple example for for a broken
access control
um i hope uh everything uh is fine
because uh the
screen is flickering at my end so i i
just thought
i should check if there is an issue
with the viewers as well or not
let me check quickly
right right so
again back uh back into the code this is
this code is
very similar in fact it's a copy of the
previous code and we are looking at the
same example
here this function is basically checking
email id and based on that it will
return profile information and then a
user could
view his profile information if he
provides his email id
what's the problem here the problem is
there was no check implemented by the
developer
and that makes sure that the user
is providing his own email id or or
if he is providing someone else email id
that there was no check at all
so what will happen is let's let's say
that there is
it is a user user uh user one at three
example.com
if he wants to view uh his information
he would type
in user one at the example.com and
this would uh flow through
this function or action
and it will written the results for user
one
but if the user one tries to pass
user two at three example.com
the function would gladly return all the
information about user two as well
why because there is no check
implemented there were uh
to make sure that user one is actually
requesting
his information or user one is trying to
view someone else's information
so in this case we can simply
check we can simply implement a small
check
by again by
tagging email id for example let's say i
marked email id as a primary key and i
saved it
uh in the session variable so i can use
that
same email id to check if
that use if the user is trying to view
his
own data or someone else's data so when
the user submits the request he will
also submit his cookie
which will be uh matched against the
session
session id so uh the server will check
what value is there in in that specific
session id and
what value or what email id
user has provided to check so
this way you can the developer can check
if the user is trying to view his own id
uh
his own details or if he's trying to uh
view the details of some other user
all right okay i missed a few
things about broken access control what
what could be the implication in this
case
all right uh depending upon the
implementation and
uh and and
depending upon the implementation uh the
impact could
could vary and let's say if if
if the uh if this this is a view only it
is
it still can leak a lot of information
uh
about the users let's say uh
the user could just manipulate or temper
the
parameter ids to view details of all
users
stored in the applications database
it could get even worse if if if
if such kind of access control is
missing while updating user information
this
this way an unauthorized user
can update data
of an another user of the same
application which is
sadly quite common
[Music]
in in applications today
all right good old
sql injection uh i think i really don't
need to like
dive into uh what is sql injection
and what could go wrong here uh
what can be done with sql injections or
but
i would still reiterate a few things
about sql injection so why
does it happen in the first place
uh it's usually because uh of
uh the lack of input
sanitization input validation and
an untrusted
user input becomes part of developers
sql
query which can which
an attacker can exploit to modify
the data or
retrieve the application data or
sometimes if the database is
misconfigured
or is running under a
higher privileged user this can also
result in
a complete compromise of the application
server
as well how it can be avoided it can be
avoided in multiple ways and like
we can use input validation
we can use parameterized queries
and we can use the source procedures but
uh
again those all have their own
constraints while implementing so i'm
just going to
demonstrate a very trivial example where
an inline theory was used and how it can
be mitigated by
using a parameterized query
okay so here's uh
here's an example code uh basically
it's it's
processing a user input
and as you can see on line number 56
there is no uh input validity
performed on the id uh
parameter value and this way tracker can
terminate the developer
theory and append his own query to
extract data or modify the data whatever
he wants to
do so in order to mitigate this issue
we can use prepared statements
here's a simple example i'm sorry
just hold on for a minute
i'm really sorry guys that's that's my
knees
all right so we were on sql injection
so this way if
if the developer used a parameter
security he could have prevented
again if we
at the end of the talk if we get enough
time we will get into the demonstration
as well
template injection all right this is
this is an interesting topic
and what happens is
uh nowadays we are used a lot of web
applications are using templates
template engines for for for a lot of
uh data processing
ah let me just
give me
hello
all right sorry uh that was my knees
again
she just got up
so you know the kids
so we were discussing
template injection all right so this
this happens because uh an interested
user input
gets passed to the template engine
and depending on the template engine
there is there are a lot of
possibilities
and it can result in server side code
execution
and in some in some cases client-side
code executions as well
so how it can be avoided again it can be
avoided by
implementing some sort of white listing
or
input validation or you can implement
rejects
to avoid such issues and
here is an illustration for example uh
user input is passed to
web application server and it it gets
processed by
the template engine it will
send you back the results for in order
to detect it
an attacker would try to send some
something like
uh add the rate
curly brackets and then some some
mathematical operation and then
it would it would check uh what's the
response of the application
if it gets evaluated if this
seven static seven gets evaluated and
that means that
a template engine is in use and
probably the input is not being
validated properly
so uh i borrowed this code
from from internet and and i've
clearly given incredits who actually
wrote uh
blog about this one uh i'm really sorry
i
i couldn't remember the name of the guy
who who
wrote this blog but i have mentioned
his blog and and his github uh
as well so basically the
this code is
an implementation of his code
but here we what we are doing is as as
basically it's it's uh taking input
from the user and the
template engine is processing the user
input without
any any sort of uh
input validation at all so here we can
see the string
name gets assigned from collections
which is passed from the client end
to this
code and then
if we if we basically
filter out the vectors that we could
have avoided
and the server side template injections
all right another
class of work is command injection it is
again caused by
the lack of input validation in this
case uh
what's happening in the back end is the
user inputs
becomes part of
operating system commands as an argument
in most cases sometimes it is used to
launch a specific command or
run a specific command so what happened
is uh for example this
uh let's look at this one so
there is a page where you can go and
type an ip address
or type a domain name and and the server
will
go and try to ping that domain or ip
address
but if the user input is not validated
properly what
an attacker would do is he would append
special characters or windows operating
or
operating system meta corrector that are
used to
terminate or or indicate that there is a
new command
for example in this case an attacker
could simply implement
ampersand sign and then uh type
another command to execute a calculator
or maybe a powershell reversal
so how would it look like
in terms of code so here is a very
simple example this
function is basically processing user
input
as we can see the variable ip
gets assigned the value from uh which is
submitted from
from from the user end and since there
was no
validation it could uh easily result in
code execution at line number 48
so how can we fix this
uh we could have like fix it easily by
implementing a regex and
and a white list which basically says
allow all character from a to c and 0 to
9 dot and dash
because you
have numbers and
uh domain names
usually contains dots and names and
dashes i'm not talking about ipv6
here otherwise we could have added
columns as well
all right xml injections
uh this one is uh interesting
uh class of work uh there are
a lot of libraries that provide
xml data processing we will look at one
specific implementation
and we will see how easy it is to fix
that xml issue first of all why
why does it happen it happens because
the user
uh the parser uh
the parser are not configured properly
or they are allowed to load external
entities
which which results in in information
leaks
and denial of service attacks or
resource uh
resource draining attacks and cpu
cpu hogging issues things like these
how we can avoid these kind of issues we
can
disable dtd loadings and
use safer implementation methods
uh it's time to like
quickly dive into the code as well and
and we will quickly look
at how what a vulnerable code looks like
and how we can
fix it but again
just before we uh pop
into the code let's look at
a basic illustration i i don't know but
i i just
love creating these user and web app
web server interactions so basically
here's an example user is providing
some data and servers processors
processing it and sending back the
results but
if the user tries to introduce his own
entities and and
send send to the server and if
the parser is not configured properly it
would it would uh
process all those entities external
entities or
and and send back those as as
as part of the result
uh in this case we we are trying to
access
xc host files and then
it can lead to information disclosure uh
if
if that was a real-world attack attacker
would
probably try to read your web.xml
i mean sorry web.config files
or maybe some backup files
there are a lot of things that can go
wrong
in case of information disclosure
so again this code was uh
taken from utah and
modified it and modified but
i would like to mention where i where i
actually stumbled upon the code and then
uh
modified it according to my needs
so uh let's look into
what uh just wanted to give a quick
update i know that you're winding down
um we did have one question from the
feminine from an attendee i was
wondering if you had time to take that
before you wrapped up about
the presentation yeah so the question
was what
tools are you using to test uh when you
when you start to try to break net
applications
all right so uh from from
the testing perspective uh i
basically use verb suit and and and a
few extinctions and that's more than
enough to test web applications yeah
and if you are looking
into the code site and
visual studio along with
some code scanning tools but again
that i won't go into the static scanning
and solutions because the law falls
positive and
well that's that's another debate but
typically i use burp suit
for for the assessment
and if if you are trying to recover the
code then
then dot peak and telricks
have great tools to recover the source
code and
you can do the manual code auditing
there as well
all right so we were at xml attacks
right and
right after example attacks uh we were
looking
into this dummy code so this
code is vulnerable to xml attack and
just one line of change
one one minor change could have uh
mitigated this issue if if
we set the dot xml resolver to null it
could have prevented
xml in external entity injections
attacks
in this case
this is this is one of the
most prevalent issue again it happens
because of uh
lack of the input validation and
this this is not as safer as
the server-side code execution but it is
still severe and has been
used in a lot of high profile attacks
as well we will quickly look how
uh it looks like and so an attacker
basically sends a malicious script to
the application application processes
it and it stores it and when the
attacker visits that same page and it
the scripts get executed in the user's
browser context and the data script can
send users cookies to attacker or
perform
attacks or perform different kind of
attacks for example internal port
system scanning or maybe
perform actions in the applications hi
sorry how we can mitigate it yeah sorry
to interrupt
m is like you know you're over time so
all right yeah just give me two more
minutes so i will just wrap this up
okay uh i'm just i just want to talk
about the
uh communication of crosstalk scripting
so
i hope you don't mind yeah thank okay
so how how we can mitigate it uh the
medication is quite
uh simple in this case
we can use
uh we can use uh
do not use html dot raw methods while
echoing out the user input and and and
use
input input validation again
html provides uh great mitigations
against crossfire scripting attack but
if the user input is landing somewhere
in in html
attribute it won't save you from from
those attacks
so always be careful
while using html dot raw
all right that's that's all i have to
share
any questions so