gracias jean-jacques and what else one
of this good morning I'm Paul I'm the
chair of the NRO Executive Council I'm
also the head of a panic the IP address
registry for the asia-pacific and you
might know that the NRO coordinates the
activities of the 5ra arts one of those
activities being to serve as the ASO in
ICANN 20 years ago just three of today's
rars were around just three have been
around for more than 20 years our system
was established through the IETF back in
the early 1990s so it predates I can by
good seven or eight years it doesn't
seem so long these days we have a
handful of people as I can did to thank
for the invention of the our our system
including some people we know Elise
gerich the recently retired president of
the PTI was the one who wrote our C 1366
in October 92 and that established the
regional approach to IP address
management also the first heads of the
three early RA ours include Daniel Karen
Berg four ripe ncc Kim Hubbard for Aaron
and David Conrad for AP Nick who is
still with us here in the ICANN
community today but I guess most
importantly right here and now today is
is to acknowledge Jon Postel who fully
supported the establishment of the arias
from the start right up to his untimely
shocking death in 98 he worked closely
with those early Rai founders and I had
the pleasure to meet him just once once
in 98 during an IETF and show in Chicago
of course as we heard I can was just
being conceived at that time and a set
of bylaws and initial board members
which John himself I think led in in
creating and selecting so it was a huge
shock to many people to lose him so
suddenly but we have to recognize him as
a pioneer whose legacy persists right
here
all around us what he created was a key
part of what we now accept as the
governance framework of the internet
that became the multi-stakeholder model
which was later discovered not invented
by the wisss the WSIS as the key to the
internet success and it's the icon model
that graduated from an experiment when
the stewardship of the IANA functions
was cut loose finally by the US
government just a couple of years ago so
I cans
evolution continues and as part of that
evolution so does that of the ASO so you
might know that the an ASO review was
conducted and released just a year ago
the internet number communities are
still processing the results but we're
converging on a set of improvements and
recently the RIR ceo's provided some
input to that process with some common
points of agreement so just briefly
firstly the RA our communities do share
a view that our relationship with in
with ICANN is important and should
continue that's fun fundamental but also
that it can be simplified with a sharper
focus on matters of mutual interest
second that the ASO has turned out to be
quite different than other SOS in the
ICANN framework and that we don't need
to take all of the engagements and work
items that are available to us as an
Esso third there's a confusion long term
confusion in the engagement with ICANN
under the dual banners of the NRO and
the ASO you may share that with me that
confusion but that needs to be addressed
by consolidating functions under one of
those identities and lastly we do
continue to support ICANN as the means
to carry out a set of critical functions
the best means to do that while we also
support ongoing evolution personally
having heard the recent work by ICANN on
strategic trends I think we are we have
no choice but to
collaborate work together with I can
very much as as Sheree Shireen said
within our own clean clear arre mitts so
the process of consultations on the ASO
is not over and but we felt these points
sort of can capsulate the progress that
has been made so far and probably worth
reiterating here in this forum finally I
wanted to mention another recent piece
of work that we've also heard about
today and that's a great success of the
ICANN community which is that is the DNS
SEC KSK rollover so a lot has been said
and congratulations due to all involved
but I wanted to recap on some of the
activities of the rars as I think a
great example of the way we can work
together with ICANN and have done very
successfully to support a process in
this case that's really at the heart of
the Internet's health and well-being and
that's the DNS SEC the RAS collectively
serve a community of some hundred
thousand in round figures the network
and infrastructure operators around the
world these are the people who use IP
address blocks registered directly with
the RAS and who actually collectively
build and run the entire Internet
infrastructure so reaching out to all
those operators was very important it
was a big task and one which the RA
hours were happy to contribute to so we
were involved with making presentations
to operator meetings around the world we
were publishing many different blog
posts media items news web social media
updates sharing email updates across our
air mailing lists and directly with our
communities doing all this in some cases
in languages other than English and also
contributing measurements and data
collection to I can zone processes so
that that rollover was completed within
icons stated tolerance limits with no
major issues reported and that was done
very significantly through global
cooperation between ICANN and many
others in the community and I think it
just serves to illustrate the
effectiveness of the global technical
coordination which has been at the heart
of Internet governance for a very long
time now
so at this 20 year mark as we gather
here in what I think Shireen referred to
basically as John's house I'd like to
say that the Internet is is not a thing
of the past the legacy of the pioneers
is critical and certain fundamentals
must be preserved but we all have to
work together to take it forward and
there's plenty of room space and time
for us to do that so I think we could
all be proud of what we've achieved as
we move ahead into the next 20 years
thank you very much for your time and
attention Thanks
[Applause]
[Music]