hello i'm here today with alan greenberg
a lack chair and maureen hillier at the
incoming a lack chair and we're here
today to discuss the evolution of at
large so Alan what was the at large
community like when you assumed the role
of a lock chair
I started in I cannon at large knee Lac
twelve years ago and at that point there
was the 15-member a lack but it was
appointed by largely by the board and by
the NomCom because there were no rail
OHS there was no regional organization
surrounding it by the time I became
chair four years ago we had the five
very robust and mature rail OHS we had a
significant number of at-large
structures the local structures in the
field and unfortunately from my point of
view we still only had one rail oh that
had unaffiliated individual members what
have been some of the greatest
accomplishments during your time as a
Lac chair of the at-large community and
perhaps a challenge
well when I look back the I think one of
the accomplishments is the the
counterpart to what I said it was like
when we started when I started we now
have five rail oaths that have
unaffiliated individual members which
means we're not restricting
participation to someone who has an
at-large structure who's someone a part
of a group but a single person who wants
to contribute has that ability and
that's I think is a very important part
of the maturity of the a lack and at
large in terms of accomplishments we
spent a significant part of the last
four years working on the IANA
stewardship transition the move away
from the US government to ICANN being
you know not subservient to the to a
government and being independent and to
the accountability efforts that went
along with it
the a lack and at large were very active
participants in that we ended up I think
having a very significant impact on the
outcomes because of what we did and we
worked cooperatively with a large number
of people within at large to achieve
those so I think we demonstrated a level
of maturity and ability to participate
in the I can echo system that that
proves we we are we are here and we're
no longer viewed by some people as sort
of an add-on and in terms of going
forward I think the largest challenge
now is to continue what we have done
over the last well 12 years certainly
and to in continue to increase the
participation of everyone within at
large you know so we we truly are
involving the whole group which has been
hard to date thank you and that's a good
point about the engagement of the
individuals as well policy is also a
very important part of the at large
community and a lacks work in ICANN and
Mari and perhaps you would like to say a
few words about outreach and engagement
and the a large community well the work
of the internet is you know that come in
it's becoming increasingly demanding and
I Ken's expectations of its community is
also becoming quite demanding I think
that you know so that you know with that
large being involved as it is in the in
providing advice in relation to policy
makes it important outreach and
engagement it becomes more important as
well because we need to shoulder tap
people who can actually help us and
contribute to the work that we have to
do in relation to supporting other
constituencies within I came to develop
the policies that are important to I
came
and in terms of engagement and
policymaking there have been now going
on the third at-large summit there have
been two prior at-large summits the
first atlas was in 2009 and the second
was in London in 2014 the next one will
be in Montreal at ICANN 66 would you
like to say anything about this upcoming
summit and plans well I mean the
previous summits were so like and
engaged and and sort of involved large
groups of our at-large community and
introduce them to the huge network of
course that as I can but also involved
in policy this time we're actually
having to be you know to change our
approach sort of like circumstances have
meant that we are going to again focus a
lot on the on policy but probably also
on developing leadership and encouraging
you know so like encouraging skills
building capacity to to ensure that
we've actually got appropriate people
who are coming in who are active willing
to engage and making contributing in an
appropriate way to the development of
the policies that you know we that at
large is engaged in yeah and another
large project that you have under your
belt as incoming chair is the at-large
review implementation so maybe you'd
like to comment on that and how it will
benefit and users well the review of
courses as a means of reflect
encouraging us to reflect on you know
how we are doing things within within I
can and I think that the the
implementation plan that we are working
on at the moment is actually something
that's going to help us with continuous
improvement with an at-large and again
making sure that we're actually working
more effectively and yes
especially making it more efficient in
respect to costs so that we actually
still able to select work as an
effective contributor to the work of
ICANN a lack and reloj leadership has
also been added well it's been one of
the important things that for me is that
we are the messages that come from Alec
are actually filtering down to Z to our
grassroots membership members and I
think that if we can by engaging the
rollo chairs into a leadership
discussion it means that we're actually
start connecting making that connection
with our membership and encouraging
again that greater involvement are there
any other thoughts either one of you
would like to impart about your time and
at large and devolution of the community
I'll just say it's been a fun 12 years
and I look forward to seeing what
happens next
I'm looking forward to it I know that
I've got big shoes yeah josepho and
Allan's
yeah he's left us legacy within within
at large which I'm going to take
advantage of thank you both so much
thank you
[Music]