all right so I'm Sarah Mitchell and I'm
here today to present what was my
master's thesis research and it was
applying system dynamics to CNO modeling
but before I want to be before me I want
to give a quick thank you to to a few
people who I could have done it without
the first is Jared any girl who was my
piece of the thesis advisor Andy Moore
at cert CC in Pittsburgh he does a lot
of stuff with SD and insider threat
research and was really happy to help me
apply it to larger CNO modeling and
Deana Chuck who's here today couldn't
done it without her feedback and without
her input and everybody here today it's
actually great that people showed up so
just to give you guys kind of a rundown
on how I approached my research the idea
was really Jared's he kind of threw it
out in class one day of what if we could
do this and so I went up to his hey can
I do this after my thesis and he was
like yeah sure that's awesome and so we
kind of broke it down into fourths over
the course of the semester I did a lot
of SD specific research I did a lot of
research specifically on the adversary I
chose which happened to be a PT one and
then I did a lot of model development
and then I wrote my paper which I am
willing to share with anybody who would
like a PDF copy so basically what the
research looked like was a ton of text
books SD is a very formalized modeling
system there are a ton of text books
they're very awful and very dry but
necessary to read to spend yourself up
on a topic and then I split that with
China and operation Aurora research
researching everything from white papers
published by the likes of north of remin
to online articles from threat
intelligence organizations like Mandy
admirer I I ate it through over ten
model drafts I think I'm on like 20 now
I think there's a version number and
really one of the big things I learned
is feedback as a gift if you're not
getting different perspectives on your
research you're really not learning and
growing and even if it's you know hey I
don't like this or hey don't agree with
what you did it's a good thing to have
that perspective and get the involvement
of others so why did I pick modeling why
CNO modeling conceptualization and
information security is something that
is often overlooked or poorly done in my
opinion there's a lot of complex models
out there
just about the only one that I can think
of it's not complex is the cyber kill
chain but even then it only really takes
into consideration the bite the more
technical side of things and only one
perspective it doesn't offer the entire
CNO from start to finish model and I
really wanted to make something that was
simple and easily consumable by somebody
like my mom like I wanted my mom to be
able understand I want you guys as moms
to be able to understand what's going on
it shouldn't be so complex and technical
that it's unapproachable and
additionally I really wanted to focus on
why why do actors act in certain ways
how do they act in certain ways what is
how is the reflection of their overall
strategy intelligence policy management
and decision making process and this
really comes out and st and what is
known as feedback loops it's the idea of
everybody's iterating through some
process and trying to iterate through as
fast as possible so that leads us into
why system dynamics really everything is
a system everything can be modeled as a
system at some level whether it's an
ecosystem whether it's a computer
network operation it really doesn't
matter and SD really focuses in on that
rates and optimization through the idea
of feedback loops and these rates an
optimization or how you can start to
begin to extrapolate out the why if you
see what people are allocating and how
much of it they're allocating and what
the time frame is you can kind of use
that to infer and extrapolate out their
larger strategy which is there why
because at the end of the day we're not
fighting computers on a bits and bytes
levels we're fighting humans there are
human motivating factors and that's
really why I wanted to focus on the
policies and management and the decision
making processes available to different
adversaries and targets and
organizations and this insight comes
from events so an event in terms of SD
you can be a CNO it can be a larger CNO
campaign it can be one part of a CNO
campaign you can model it at different
levels and at different scales and
rapidly expand and contract so case
study operation Aurora I know this is an
old topic but I wanted to pick something
that was very well documented I didn't
want to have to struggle with all right
well how do I get information I wanted
to pick something that was everyone
pretty much agreed upon everyone
understood what was going on so just to
give you guys a recap
it's been a while uh Google Adobe and 30
other companies were compromised by what
is attributed with high confidence as a
PT one and as a result we will left
China for a time especially their R&D
side because as a result of this you
know Chinese dissidents are targeted via
via Gmail and Google services and also
source code management was targeted
there's a common software management
source code management software utilized
by all of the companies that were
compromised and the theory is or at
least my theory is that they were trying
to get access to current copies of
source code that's kind of a cheat sheet
for vulnerability analysis or be able to
insert their own backdoors into future
versions of source code that even having
to get the get access to it they could
just put their own and it said I'm
waiting for developers to make mistakes
so this basically happened over six
steps so the first one is phishing email
it's always a phishing email they then
it was a malicious JavaScript payload
which had downloaded from ie and
contained a zero-day and then from there
the binary executed a backdoors
established and basically sprayed
throughout the network and exfiltrated
data and this picture is from McAfee so
now I want to get into how all of this
applies at the with the model that I
developed but before I begin I want to
state some assumptions this is a very
young model even though there are 20
different versions it doesn't account
for the balancing of profit and cost
centers it's really designed to be
consumed at this stage with security at
its forefront and I don't know how many
of you are familiar with the software
vensim it's a modeling tool for system
dynamics it's not very pretty so I
didn't use it for my slides but it did
allow for some great things like unit
validation and things like that to make
sure that I had everything was made
sense from a baseline units perspective
in terms of mathematics and like I said
feedback is a gift I think besides has
it's usually peerless to get feedback
definitely reach out to be there and my
twitter handle I'll have at the end I
would love to hear your comments and get
your feedback so this is the key so we
have this idea
of a sinker source and that's basically
where it and where the information
enters the purview of the model so this
is where it starts or where it leaves
the purview of the model that I'm trying
information I'm trying to model then you
have these level equations so in terms
of this model that's kind of like your
TTP there your bag of tricks or things
that you can do and use generic rates
are conversions of auxilary rates in
different things so an axillary rate you
can think of as a subcategory of a
generic rate so if you're you'll see the
larger generic rate it's resources in
the subcategories of that for example
would be people time and money and then
this rate down here this symbol is when
you are converting one things state to
another it's the same thing but you're
just converting it States so you'll see
that's what happens between clean and
compromised machines so we want to look
at a PT one or really any adversary they
have some sort of policy and management
structure they allocate resources here
indicated by the positive these
resources that are allocated into
training hiring people money and
infrastructure hiring people can also be
less formal recruiting people to your
cause if you're you know not quite of a
formal organization these resources are
then converted into capabilities and we
have these are kind of similar to this
you can see a little different you have
information gathering or recon you have
social engineering attacks zero day
attacks non zero day attacks so what and
what I mean by non zero day attacks
really is these are attacks that are
known they've been seen before they're
defensible if you configure your posture
correctly and then we have what is
Middle infrastructure which is coined by
Dina Schick and it's really this idea of
a Hotpoint I compromise host a use host
a to pivot to point B so then we can see
the apt one action so they use all of
these staves to go to convert clean
machines to compromise machines and
information it's hard to tell with all
of the lines flows before back and forth
between information gathering and the
middle infrastructure is also a positive
everything else is a negative and the
reason it's a negative
because you're giving away your TTP by
acting and doing these things you're
establishing a pattern or procedure for
what you're doing and you see down here
that we have this other sink a kinetic
or geopolitical action so think in apt
one's case of Operation Ora
this is them spying on people trying to
discipline vehicle this is outside the
purview of cyber you're doing you're
using computers as a means to an end for
something geopolitical we're very much
kinetic so the large feedback loop here
is a PC one it's allocating resources
they're developing capabilities they're
using their capabilities they're getting
Middle infrastructure and information
back they're reallocating their
resources they're redeveloping and
reallocating capabilities and doing it
all again so it's this larger circle
here that we see which would be
considered their feedback loop that's
what they're trying to optimize they're
trying to do that as fast as possible so
switching gears a little bit we're gonna
look at the other half of the model
which is their target and you'll see it
looks very similar target has the same
things they have a policy and management
body they have resources they have the
same resources that they can use to
allocate however in the case of the
target they're going to develop
hardening capabilities rather than
offensive capabilities and these
offensive capabilities are going to have
an impact on clean machines and
compromised machines and from the
compromised machines the attacks
hopefully you're getting detection
information which can then inform
hardening so we have a little smaller
sub feedback loop of this is your short
short term information impacting your
hardening so think we're seeing data
exfil over whatever port that we should
be seeing so we're going to write a
firewall rule to block that right now
this is a short term it's not strategy
it's more at the tactical level and then
you see this other feedback loop in here
which involves threat intelligence so
this is only for mature organizations I
understand that not every organization
in every state is going to be able to
consume some sort of threat intelligence
but if they are mature enough to do that
they can use this to inform their
detection capabilities and their
hardening capabilities and then the
detection and threat intelligence in the
long run as a strategy will re impact
the policy and management so that's kind
of the idea that if somebody comes to
you like I sac and says
hey you're a bank and actor X is a
attacking thanks how do you reach us
your strategy policy at the highest
levels to help combat that and
reallocate your resources accordingly so
that's really this detection loops here
that we really can focus on we see that
all of these things are going in here
and so if you get you know if you're
seeing scans you know you can use that
to readjust your hardening or inform
your threat intelligence you can use
that and reallocate that information and
sort of iterate through that process at
as high of a level or local level or as
you want and so the final model looks
like this I know it's hard to fit all in
one slide but basically that red box is
the feedback loop of the adversary and
the blue box is the feedback loop of the
target or the defenders and you can see
that they interact right here this
middle point of the thing that they're
all trying to impact is clean machines
and compromised machines obviously the
target wants to keep their Queen
machines clean and the adversary wants
to compromise the Queen machines so just
to summarize the purpose of this model
is really the focus on resources an
allocation to inform what strategy and
policy are and by focusing on the
optimization and using that we can infer
extrapolate out the why why are humans
acting different ways why are they using
this capability versus another
capability you know different things
like that and that all comes from
understanding the policy the procedures
in the strategy not necessarily the
bites and bits technical those are
really just a means to an end
you're not it doesn't matter what tool
you use to scan why are you scanning
well because I'm going to attack that
why are you going to attack that you
kind of get that idea of the larger
system that's being used and I really
think that that allows us to see this
nexus of intelligence strategy and
policy really coming together at the
highest levels to then inform the lowest
levels of technology and just some notes
on my future work right now this is a
retrospective look I'm not a
mathematician I'm very bad at math I
would love to find a data scientist to
work with to apply a mathematic
simulation and be able to model and
predict
attacks so for example you can put in
all of the information regarding the
resources and allocation and information
about policy and management structures
and then the model operation Aurora and
watch it go through using something like
Benson and then I would like to also
test against other information sources
given that I only had a semester for the
research I would love to take another
CNO and see if the information still
holds and analyze it at the level at
which I analyzed operation Aurora and
part of that is all to make this
consumable right now this model I
understand it's very academic and it's
more of a thought exercise but I would
love for an organization to be able to
take this and say okay I now understand
that you know I'm here in the model and
this is where I am in my feedback loop
and this is where I need to get and this
is the amount of time it's taking me to
hit all of these steps so how do I move
through that faster and one of my
thoughts with this at the bigger picture
almost like nation state level is you
can determine minimum operating levels
so if you know that you know you need
this many hired and trained people to
attack your adversary needs this many
people at this skill set to attack you
for lack of a better example you can do
something like what the United States
government did with the Iranians and
blocking them from being able to go into
nuclear physicist programs you can do
something similar pick an adversary at
the nation state level and deny them
access to what they need starving them
such that they can't perform their
actions at least you know the highest
level so instead of having qualified
people who can actually develop and find
zero-days and exploits for them maybe
they can leaves Metasploit now because
that's all they that's all the
capability they have in terms of
training and resources so they're still
going to attack you and they still want
to attack you but maybe you can defend
yourself better because you now know
what to expect or you can expect
something that's hopefully a lot more
defensible for your organization so
that's all I have
that's my Twitter handle please reach
out to me there I'll be checking peer
lists as well and I welcome any feedback
right out
[Applause]
yeah to underscore somebody took 100
snot published anywhere I do have it out
on the people drive and if you reach out
to me via Twitter I'd be happy to share
that link with you so sir I think it was
really interesting don't ask you to
speculate for a little bit okay on based
on the components of your model and how
you might adapt it what are some of the
insights that we might be able to glean
that come from going through a
simulation that you think aren't
immediately evident from the assumptions
you made going into the simulation I
think that one of the most obvious
things is by seeing what capabilities
are thrown at you you can make and
speculate and sort of derive
intelligence as to the level of your
adversary or we talked in script kitties
are we talking you know cyber criminals
or are we talking nation-states
acting for cyber espionage reasons
trying to impact critical infrastructure
for very geopolitical reasons and from
that I think that by seeing what's being
thrown at you you can sort of determine
the maturity and the sophistication of
your adversary and make your decisions
based on that as well that's fascinating
there's some researchers that I should
connect you that are trying to look at
the code itself to make such
implications I think that Matt will be
else micro be really helpful thank you
what opportunities do you think there
are two for the model to work with
subject matter experts and subject
matter experts to compliment the model
to produce a improved combined say view
of the situation that's a great question
I think there's a lot of room for that
I'm not a subject matter expert and
anything I'm just starting my career so
the idea of being able to actually work
with and connect with other people and
make this
much bigger much more well-informed
research project that would be awesome I
think that would be a great place I
think it would definitely add the
credibility required to make this more
consumable okay Thank You Sara and
please remember to follow on on peer
list thank you very much
[Applause]