please welcome hey guys thanks for
coming out
my name is Mathew Park I am a user
experience lead over at endgame
real quick and game they just it's a ETR
EPP platform the context of this is
we're building an attack timeline
visualization which I'll be talking
about during this talk today so this is
come something we're currently part of
typing within the product and what our
company does is they build endpoint
protection across enterprise-wide kind
of stuff well my team does in general is
what we do and what we care about or
kind of building thoughtful and
practical work flows like visualizations
and general experiences for cyber
security analysts so we really care what
the users dough do 100% of the time that
image to the left is it's not supposed
to make sense it's it's a joke defining
what UI and UX is but I got a lot to go
through so let's just start it out
all right I have to do that I would be
totally miss if I didn't actually put a
video of actual war games in there for
you guys that aren't familiar with what
war games are it's a film back in like
1983 basically they the Americans
created this thing called the whopper
that like kind of go through these
wartime simulations during the latter
portion of the Cold War and it's
supposed to like have us have a leg up
and the nihilo arms race at this point
of the movie the whopper can no longer
tell between reality and kind of fiction
or and it's trying to route force its
way into NORAD and getting the codes so
Matthew Broderick is kind of like
yelling at it trying to understand it to
understand the futility of war by kind
of like this tic-tac-toe simulations so
it's it's very surreal I highly
recommend watching it but it's kind of
ridiculous but I'm gonna segue into that
by saying it's ridiculous for something
totally unrelated to it for those of you
who've seen the movie sock analysts and
the actual like generals make the
majority of their main decisions and
driving components primarily based on
all the Whopper visualization I can
honestly count like maybe between two
fingers the amount of times a sock
analyst has like a UNIX shell open
versus when they're like mouths agates
in front of like all these types of
visualizations out there and you can
actually see like in a typical sock
obviously you have kind of
visualizations up on the board but in
their individual monitors over there
they actually have just the same things
just kind of strewn about or on the
stock floor and I kind of came to this
conclusion after watching this movie for
the fifth time leading up to this talk
that the only way that this kind of
makes sense to me is I guess that these
the this visualization was pretty
practical for the 1983 version of NORAD
out there the designs are like pretty
minimal simplistic relatively easy to
understand I guess it had the stock
analyst mindset of a Norris
and NORAD analysts which is kind of
contradictory to what this talk is about
or what it was framed as still home of
the whopper not exactly because
visualizations that we as we know today
don't really have the main like driving
decision force at the whopper had in
this movie
analysts generally don't like dictate
their workflows based on what they're
gonna be seeing in like some sort of pew
pew map so it was really never home with
a whopper whatsoever it's been plot
twists as we know analysts today kind of
are more comfortable sifting through
like a stream of events through like
typical heavy list views and they're
more comfortable doing that and they
form these patterns around how they're
taking the metadata from those
individual list views and what they
generally view visualizations as of what
I found it's kind of bogging them down
and being a little bit more
time-consuming and generally useless so
I took this quote from this guy named
Raphael Marty he wrote a book called
applied security visualizations which is
pretty good and he talked about the
general problems plaguing security
visualizations today he says they're
either the work of designers with no
background in security whatsoever or the
work of security professionals who don't
really understand data visualizations
one is generally pretty beautiful but
not practical and getting work done and
the other is relatively effective but
it's kind of non-intuitive
it requires the average analyst to do a
lot more work in actually piecing
together the story and generally as an
industry we kind of lean towards the
latter of these visualizations because a
they're easy to build you can just take
them straight out of like a d3 library
and it's kind of a disappointment
because we tend to lean on something
that's kind of familiar to what we've
done previously rather than make a
focused effort towards usability in
general which leads me into attack
timelines this is the outline of the
talk right
a whopper right there so this is a talk
around attack timelines in general it's
actually disguised as usability talk
around tech timelines surprise so at the
end of this talk I'll be kind of
discussing and showing a couple concepts
around some prototypes that we're
currently currently putting together
through endgame but these kind of
designs aren't really the key takeaway I
want like this group to leave with it's
it's more around my hope is as I
discussed the approach of how we came to
this conclusion of what we should be
doing for our attack timelines you guys
can take these C principles back and
broaden your own perspectives about how
you should be approaching your own set
of visualizations whether or not it's
attack timelines or anything else in
particular I firmly believe in order to
introduce any sort of visualization in
general that's functional and can be
usable to like whoever the people that
build it first need to understand like
do the proper research into design
structures and understand their user
base to make their corrupt decisions so
going into it surprised I am easier
experienced designer so we went through
a very user centric approach to discover
what exactly is needed for attack
timelines and we kind of split this into
three individual stages the first being
discovery coming from endgame we had
certain biases coming into what the
attack timeline should be because people
within our organization have worked
previously with them so we wanted to
confirm whether or not those are actual
things that were currently out in the
wild we had a opportunity to test a
large amount of participants through
actual stock organizations as well as
our own internal so we ran a couple user
of research testing and to capture kind
of the organs a organizational workflows
from them as well as creating a new
persona paradigm around specifically
around alert triage and attack timelines
the next phase is concept in so through
all the data that we collected we
eventually
came up with a couple design
requirements that gave us the guidelines
to formed what the version of the attack
timeline was and we revisited some
tried-and-true all basic foundations of
what design patterns should be around
and then the last phase which is part is
typing user testing this is something
we're currently in I'm not gonna be
demoing like an actual working thing
rather explaining and showing some
designs that we've been going and
actually are currently building with our
dev teams now the hope again is to take
that back out into the wild and test it
among the users that we previously
research with or whoever wants to get
their hands on it so getting it straight
into the discovery phase I'm going to
walk through each one of these things as
an organization we wanted to define
exactly what in the TAC timeline is to
have like a basic understanding or a
consensus of what everyone thought what
we're trying to accomplish and I'll just
read this straight off as we wrote this
down so the goal of an attack timeline
or an alert triage visualization however
you want to put it is to allow an
analyst to quickly assess the relative
severity of an alert so they can dismiss
remediate or escalate or escalate to
another analyst it really serves as a
means to communicate a story of an
attack because it's generally just a
story like lot of visualizations and
should be used as a platform for data
manipulation and general exploration
like I said before coming from an
organization that had prior experience
this kind of stuff we also had a couple
other biases going into it so we found
that you know large groups of users
generally like tier 1 users generally
lack domain experience in the security
field as well as well as platform
experience on a lot of other security
platform products which made a lot of
the visualizations that are currently up
just in the ecosphere of security
products kind of difficult to navigate
because some of them are kind of overly
complicated they return a lot of
information back to the user and they
really provide no context of where they
should be going or how they should be
mediating it up or down the chain
so that's one the one is the lack of
time and this is just a general problem
among Sox in general repeated at toys
they have like 5 to 10 minutes to make a
decision on an alert so typically
they're looking at streams of like
hundreds or thousands of different types
of data so without context without
knowing what they should be looking for
they have to make a split decision
whether or not gonna they're gonna be
sending it up the chain or they're gonna
be archiving this is something that's
nothing they nothing they really need to
be looking at the last one was kind of
our own thing ports endgame we wanted to
build something it was kind of a bit of
more of a differentiator we wanted to
build something that kind of enhanced
the analyst workflow something that
they've actually used and not be useless
eye candy so the list of different
things that we added to that were
showing response actions being able to
gather on large amounts of data and make
like different types of investigations
off of it building some context to
alerts already taken or so actions
already taken on particular alerts and
IP changed if you killed a process if if
you suspended a process and general
collaboration and commenting kind of
something that we found and I'll get
into this a little bit more is as people
are communicating up and down the chain
within a sock it's it's very difficult
for them to kind of show what they're
actually working on as well as
communicate whether or not alerts are
actually bad so knowing these biases we
came into the study where we got like
three uh participant groups and we
wanted to be able to capture different
types of team dynamics among the workers
of roles within the cirrie organizations
we wanted to form our own unique
personas off of all of them as well as
kind of see how they work through alert
triage in general we've done this
multiple times on multiple features but
this one was kind of segmented directly
off of
alert triage and attack timelines I'll
walk through this really quickly but the
first one was a traditional flock team
so we got 20 people to participate asked
him a set of general broad questions
over our attack Alert triage and attack
timelines to give us kind of a bucket of
responses so we can see where they
should be going where we should be going
with the feature the next one was a
version of our own a bee testing so we
had an actual livestock team that was
participating in a red vs. blue exercise
so we mimicked the exact same thing or
tried to mimic the exact same thing
internally and that included like
general dis side by side monitoring with
other researchers at endgame data
Sciences product people we had some user
interviews that kind of hit on the same
questions that we asked user group a and
we had a larger retrospective at the end
were like a two-hour session were these
people about to air their grievances on
where they felt attacked online should
be going how they were dealing with
alert triage what they wish was there
like within the product at that point in
time so that was how we collected all
this data back and it was a lot and this
is a wallet text but this is of the
basic four types of personas that we
came out of this group and I'll go for
this through this really quickly as well
it's so a Tier one analysts again has
generally no experience within the
domain or a security platform in general
they're more comfortable working through
the UI they are the first line of
defense within osakan organization they
either they look at the alerts coming in
and they have to make a split decision
whether or not to send this up to a Tier
three or a forensic hunter or to just
like throw it down into a queue that
doesn't really matter the tier threes
take this and they actually have the
authority or the power to make
actionable responses on top of this
these guys are both of these guys don't
really use the UI too much they're more
comfortable working in the command line
they just want to rip the api's out and
like work directly off of that so they
generally regard visualizations as kind
of tiresome and like a little bit
overbearing
and the last one is a sock manager so
with sock manager cause that's the the
tempo schedules they really care more
about collaboration and reporting
purposes they want high to low level of
visibility what's going on day-to-day
within individual alerts or trends at a
hole so this was kind of the spectrum of
different users we were trying to cater
towards when we were building the attack
timeline we came with we boiled down to
a couple perspectives of what we found
throughout the entire group so in
general the first two were more
variables and a representation of time
when we were opening the attack time
visualization they there was a general
consensus that a lots there was a lot of
data streaming through and whatever we
were going to build and whatever people
currently had previous that had previous
experience working in attack timelines
they generally thought that we couldn't
stream the amount of data that a an
individual centric sensor could provide
back to the platform so that was a worry
that was a worry among a lot of
different types of analysts there is a
trepidation representation of time a
quote I got from one of these guys is
time is kind of relatively abstract
concepts so it's not inherently visible
in general and we force this not
inherently visible perspective in a very
linear plane so when visualizations come
out there a either force in a linear
perspective or it's just removed
completely
it's just based off connection patterns
so analysts like to know obviously when
an event first started to when it
triggered but they would like to know
they would generally like to know kind
of the connection patterns of time
between those two events which is
currently lacking in a couple of attack
time visualizations out there the next
two was lack of expertise and lack of
time these are our two biases coming
into it and we kind of got these
confirmed this is more on the tier one
perspective they wanted more context of
why they should be remediating alert
through a type of visualization they
wanted to they wanted the platform to
point them in one way or another and
they felt force
to make like these uninformed decisions
under a stressful amount of time so
they're hoping that whatever we built
would help them through both of these
scenarios the next one were kind of new
ones that we serviced out these were
from a Tier three perspective so the
first one is increased working memory so
they wanted to build a a better way to
enhance detection and recognition with
lower end users a large portion of their
days since there's no real great
onboarding process or a way to teach the
lower end guys like what they should be
looking for they're mentoring these guys
and they're spending a substantial
portion of their day showing them what
they should be looking for and one
that's done over and over again they're
not necessarily telling these guys how
they should be looking two alerts
they're just kind of saying what key
metadata points they should be looking
at like md5 hashes or whatever file path
so it's not really teaching them in any
one way or another so they were hoping
that whatever platform we did we put
together or whatever feature we put
together in the platform would allow
them to kind of break that apart and the
last one is facilitate Scarberry in
search so if this was being built in
this scenario a lot of the tier ones
would be flooding up a whole slew of
alerts back up to the tier 3 so they
wanted a way to help them without moving
to different types of products or the
command line or anywhere else that could
focus in on key areas that they thought
were suspicious or anomalous within
their environment so based on kind of
these six things that we boiled down
from all of our user interviews we both
us down into two different design
requirements which we are trying to
accomplish during the entirety of our
prototyping phase right now so the first
is the visualization the attack timeline
should be really used as a tool to
enhance the typical typical analyst
workflow by providing obviously a high
to low level visibility and context on
granular data just in general so if
created correctly and purposefully it
would be able to shine when large when
mapping large quantities of data at
scale over time the next one is
something I didn't get into in the last
slide but this was more for the stock
managers and kind of for the tier ones a
little bit the visualization should be
used as a tool for collaboration
reporting clear visual visualization
representations in general don't require
really anyone to be like a high-level
security domain expert really anyone can
understand trends our content
distribution in general what we found or
what we were starting into where humans
are generally just very naturally
visible people and they tend to process
data at a faster at-a-glance rate which
if again done correctly opens the
accessibility of an attack time line
visualization to a larger array of users
which are talk managers in tier once you
don't have that typical domain
experience to it the next phase which is
the concept phase so we had a whole slew
of different design principles that we
were kind of looking into one was around
perception that I toast the the one that
I like the most in it's a around this
guy named ben shneiderman it's his
information information seeking mantra
and I'll go through this quickly
basically he found that the most
powerful visualizations kind of share
the same similar traits and this might
be just a kind of thing for the rest of
you but it's worth noting and thinking
about as you're building a certain type
of visualization so the first one is you
want to build an overview first so it's
it's kind of the first thing the user
will see and it'll guide them through
other parts of the product for further
exploration the overview when carefully
planned to highlight important parts of
the story it gives it should be giving
lesser weight to like not so critical
parts as well this is also the one
that's going to be the most visual so
you should be opening whatever overview
- bored whatever - the most critical
amount of user testing the next one is
zoom and filter so once you have all
your data presented on an overview
section you want to give that user
obviously the ability to focus on on
particular areas of interest this
involves like zooming and filtering down
on data which is like zooming scrolling
panning drill down legends range
lectures what-have-you
this is particularly very important for
complex visualizations because the zoom
and filtering functionality will be
should be designed in a way where users
can't get lost throughout the
visualizations attack timelines in
general are pretty expansive node beasts
so if you leave it up to like a Google
map kind of like find and select and
zoom generally if you open too many
notes it'll be hard to navigate back to
where you came from
and the last one is design on detail
being able to give the minutiae of
detail back to the user so this is for
the tier 3 case getting as close to the
raw data as possible this third level
would be less visible but it's more text
having kind of focused on accurate
information rather than trends and I'm
running again for the clock so I'm gonna
go through our actual prototype in
phases a little bit quickly so this was
our first iterations of what we wanted
the attack timeline to be these were two
examples of many many ones we put
together it was kind of the wrong way of
going about it when we mapped it on like
a 2d linear perspective it kind of
confined the amount of data that we were
putting up on the screen it also again
map time to singular axis we had the
correct amount of overview section kind
of at a glance stuff there but it was
difficult doubt it was difficult to zoom
and filter down on corresponding areas
of that node map so we were researching
other types of other structures that
could house all the information that we
were gathering from the the user
feedback as well as all the the rest of
the design principles that we wanted to
do
so we kind of went to something called
spatial temporal structures and these
are really meant to map they're
traditionally used for a kind of mapping
3d geography in general a particular use
case around it is mapping hurricane
patterns of like where a path came from
to where I'm I'm running long in I I'm
over speakers okay sorry
we apologize this was a short talk and
we can take about one or two minutes at
most for questions
so that we can get ready for the next
talk all right sorry yeah interviews and
the split testing amongst the different
groups yes sort of um how do you bring
like I guess a hard numerical side or
like empirical to to the testing itself
like you can interview a person and they
say this is way better than the last
thing but you guys are probably trying
to squeeze the most improvement out so
how do you really we try to not be as
biased as possible by like leading them
into a certain path of like hey this is
like it obviously it's going to be
better every time the iteration that we
come out with is so we try to show them
a couple other designs to kind of move
the needle back into the middle to see
if if this is actually something that
they are actually like an improvement on
the last iteration not currently yet we
are doing some implementation within the
product to do that kind of third-party
testing yeah I think we're gonna have to
cut it now and see if you'd like to
continue the conversation go ahead and
follow Matthew on purist okay thank you
very much I