all right she said that's our lengthy
title so we'll pass it through that
thick as the anyone who's read anything
in the news knows there's a lot going on
the destructive matwork realm there's a
lot going on as far as geopolitical
conflict what happens rarely that was
actually seeing these two together and
seeing how the interplay between them
and so that's a lot what we'll be
talking about today and also looking at
over the course of really the last
decade or so it's not necessarily a new
phenomena there's been a ton even over
the last month's thing and there's this
new wiper malware there's never been
before but anything like this we're
going to show that's not necessarily as
news everyone's saying but these pieces
in the puzzle I'm not necessarily been
put together and such an arrant
strategic way and so that's what we'll
be doing and basically show that's how
we've gone to 2017 or there's a lot of
interesting things going on to say the
least I'll cruise through this really
quickly just who we are just show that
we both work at endgame
both have experience in the government
but from the IC and the DoD perspectives
but we take it different perspectives
miami quantity of international
relations background sephora modeling
and conflict and mark as a InfoSec
background and so bringing those two
together on bring those two perspectives
together in a way actually Allison
talked about a little bit during her to
you know as far as blending that the
Social Sciences with the information
security I'll pass it on to mark all
right cool so I'm gonna talk a little
bit about just a background on what what
destructive attacks have we seen over
the last seven or eight years and what
are the differences between these things
what are some of the commonalities what
are some of the emerging themes so I've
been these things into two main
categories and like what's a destructive
attack the first type of attack it
really involves just destruction of like
data destruction of hard drives logical
destruction these are the sorts of
things overriding a files destruction of
a Master Boot Record a lot of you in
this room probably would say sorry I'm
not doing it right apparently sorry
about that
so destruction of data is it's kind of
the first step and you might think
that's not that big a deal what would be
the impact of an attack like that which
might be successful well it's easy to
restore the data on one computer if you
have a backup and repartition a hard
drive you're back in business but when
you're talking about coordinated attacks
across sometimes tens of thousands of
machines that can actually lead to some
very very severe real-world impacts as
secondary effects
so we're gonna talk about some attacks
of that nature the other type of
destructive attack is really more about
using you know cyber access and cyber
means to directly manipulate things in
the physical world usually by taking
advantage of industrial control systems
components and modifying the the way
certain systems are operating the
electric grid other components and that
kind of starts us off with Stuxnet which
I bet everyone in this room has heard
about remains one of the if not the most
advanced and complex attack that created
a physical real-world effect in this
case just quick background if you
haven't heard of this the Iranian
nuclear program has been an a something
of great concern for a very long time
you know they there's a lot of thought
thinking hey they're pursuing a bomb to
build a bomb you need lots of fissile
material enriched uranium or something
else and so they have a lot of
centrifuges which are you know spinning
around trying to separate atoms and
create fissile material so those actual
centrifuges were the subject of a
cyberattack called Stuxnet very advanced
campaign access through USB drives
supposedly got onto systems up to four
zero days built into this software in
order to do propagation and look for
programmable logic controllers PLC's
which were what the attackers were
intending to get on to and then create
some real-world manipulative effects
with great knowledge of the actual
system employing lots of reconnaissance
before the attack which is a theme
you'll see throughout some of these the
things were manipulated and allegedly up
to 20% of the centrifuges in the program
were destroyed basically modified
through cyber means to make themselves
effectively like explode self-destruct
causing a real-world impact so that was
sort of the first time we saw that sort
of effect you know somebody reaching
through the internet and causing this to
happen so jump forward two years Iran
was the target again using of some
malware called flame this particular
malware was one of the biggest packages
we've ever seen about 20 Meg's in size
had a lot of really advanced espionage
components in that malware do things
like you know screen grabs audio capture
you know like recording conversations
things like that also had a wiper
component in the malware so again a lot
of propagation techniques and there as
well to burrow through networks in an
automated way and take some kind of a
broadly this wiper component took out
Iranian oil targets the Iranians had to
allegedly take a bunch of actual
production facilities off line unclear
if that was cause of the attacker if it
was a precautionary measure I'm not
aware of how you know how that exactly
went down but things came offline so
again this was an attack where a
manipulation of hard drives data
destruction and NBR over rights led to
some kind of real-world effect on the
oil production similar attack happened
later something called Shamoon this
targeted at a Saudi oil production
facility like just quick question who
here has been part of a like cyber
incident that happened on a weekend or
on a Friday night and kind of wrecked
your day like yeah I have that sucks
happens all the time you see that also
with these destructive attacks and this
was a time when this was a real theme
they launched this attack supposedly the
Iranians against the Saudis on like the
the eve before a major religious holiday
in Saudi Arabia so that wrecked a lot of
people's you know holiday long week in
this case the all data was overwritten
with a nice little picture of a burning
American flag Master Boot Record
destroyed this matter was hard-coded
with admin credentials which produced to
create like remote admin shares malware
copied across and then a scheduled task
to destroy data at 11:08 a.m. on the
before this religious holiday so like
coordinated wide-scale effect 30
thousand computers supposedly taken
offline I don't know of any evidence
that actual oil production was affected
but it sure as heck impacted their
business operations for quite some time
it was a major of restoration activity
so kind of going forward we see a very
similar attack now out of the Middle
East but in the Korean Peninsula this
dark soul attack which is very likely
the North Koreans going after the South
Koreans and Andrea will talk a little
bit more about that continuing back and
forth here in a minute but again they
timed this attack to have Matt like
create maximum chaos maximum you know
simultaneous events targeting finance
and media again destroy files with
overwrites they actually and then go
ahead and actually destroy the master
boot records reboot computers things are
inoperable huge pain in the butt to
restore from that this not ATMs offline
in South Korea knocked some media
outlets off the air for a short period
of time so
again like secondary bro world effects
based on this destructive malware that
looks a lot like other wiping type of
attacks so jumping forward to 2014 what
did we see kind of some hilarity with
back and forth like you know cyber
destructive attack as a response to a
something somebody doesn't like the
first example targeted The Sands Casino
and this is very likely another Iranian
attack with with malware in this case
Sheldon Adelson a billionaire head of
the Sands Casino conglomerate he's a bit
of a in Iran Hawk he doesn't he thinks
we should push back a little harder in
the nuclear program it made some
statements to the effect of you know we
got a puff our chest out show them who's
boss maybe we should go take a new cough
to the desert to Nevada
blow it up to show the Iranians what
will happen if they don't stop so you
can imagine that maybe the Iranians
didn't really appreciate that and they
actually in response to that went right
back at him and it disrupted operations
of the Sands Casino in very substantial
ways taking out 75% of their systems
with again wiper style malware but also
stealing data releasing some employee
data online defacing web sites in this
case with some nice messages like don't
let your tongue cut your own throat and
you know any threaten you no use of
weapons of mass destruction for any
reason as a crime things of that nature
so kind of getting some messaging in
with that and then another great one
with a lot of people I bet have heard of
is this the guardians of peace later
very tightly connected through the
Lazarus group or North Korean hackers
responding to Sony because they didn't
like a movie created by the guys behind
South Park that talked about it was all
about like assassinating Kim jong-un
ridiculous comedy I guess
Kim Jong hoon didn't appreciate that
either and decided that the right
proportional response was going at Sony
hard with a cyberattack stealing a lot
of data releasing you know unreleased
films all of their email servers which
you can imagine the chaos that creates
if all your email goes online your doxed
like broadly and again destructive
attack wiper and destruction of empty
yards in that case using the same some
of the same components that the Shamoon
attacks had involved same raw disk
access driver et cetera so you're
starting to see you know cyber of
destruction as a response to some
something else even something I didn't
like that I'm gonna go pop you in the
face with a cyber attack
so kind of getting away from that but
something I think a little more serious
in terms of real real-world impact an
attack on a German steel mill in 2014
this one hasn't gotten a tremendous
amount of press but in this case it
looks you know there's been some
connections to Russian hacking groups
doing this you know state-sponsored
hacking getting access via spearfishing
to a German steel mill moving laterally
finding industrial control system you
know components kind of harkening back
to the Stuxnet model where hey I can
reach into a cyber system and do
something to cause a real world effect
in this case they modified you know
multiple components sort of regulating
this giant blast furnace used by the
steel production process they knocked
some of these things off it created some
cascading failures and the thing
basically blew up so I'm not I don't
think anybody died but if anybody had
been standing next to this thing that
would have been a real bad day some
pretty serious real-world consequences
so in this case hackers reaching in
manipulating control components in
causing this real-world impact we saw
more of that in 2015 the apt 28 again
Russian hacking group attacks the
Ukraine power grid you're starting to
see this Russia Ukraine thing really
heating up and cyber activities going
along with that they went in this was a
this was actually a pretty amazingly
well coordinated attack against their
grid about almost a quarter million
people had no power for about like 1 to
6 hours depending on things before they
could manually restore but these guys
you know they went in they clearly did
reconnaissance for a while the Spearfish
their way in they got creds to a VPN
login to the VPN which gave them access
the status components and and did a lot
of things they first actually did a
denial of service on the call center for
these different electrical companies so
nobody could call and figure out what
was going on a report anything so kind
of you know creating some chaos out at
the outset they went in they they
basically broke some communications
components UPS is connected to this
stuff they opened a bunch of breakers
and did some other things that caused
the electrical grid to fail and as they
got out they actually over wrote
firmware and some of the control
components that were supposed to talk to
these systems so basically they couldn't
do restoration via cyber means at all
because you could no longer communicate
with any of the devices
it's pretty well coordinated ninety
minutes after the attacks started they
actually did a like a wiper attack
destroying systems throughout the
network to make it even more difficult
to do any kind of restoration because
all the sudden the like business side of
the network starts going offline so you
know a denial of service multiple real
world effects through ICS components and
a wiper component all coordinated at the
same time pretty impressive attack and
maybe a harbinger of things to come in
terms of like level of sophistication we
also saw another interesting trend here
something called the cyber caliphs it
had a French TV network called TV 5mon
taking 12 tell 12 TV stations off air
for almost a day oh good well yeah that
ICS components attached to the fire
alarm system have been modified alright
these rivalries are basically between
country pairs that's what dyad are
dyadic means so between two groups of
countries these dietetics is exist out
there are disproportionally responsible
for the number of the number and amount
of conflict in the world system and so
you can see any other theories up there
that you know that these disputes are
not you insular events but they're
actually interconnected they're starting
to either research is starting to stray
a little bit for me just a dyadic to the
network aspect and system level and I'll
talk about that a little bit as far as
you see these diets are starting to
become more you having regional
consequences and so these findings
you're going back to you know several
hundred years coding all the different
data in the world based on whether this
conflict between these two groups of
countries does show that it is they are
disproportionately responsible for
conflict and as it turns out these are
the same with these diet the ones that
are some the most conflict prone also
are the ones using ypur malware right
now so while walk through some of the
more common rivalries as they pertain to
hyper malware so Russia Ukraine is no
surprise the interesting thing about
this one and I'll go through some
different power symmetries between each
of the three use cases will do Russia
Ukraine or on Saudi Arabia and the
Koreas with this one you've got a major
power on a minor power and so we start
seeing in 2014 it's basically for Russia
it's an extension he goes back to 2007
with the stone yet he's not even sooner
for all other activities but
see within Ukraine ECU switched from a
pro-russian leader over to a more of a
pro-eu integration leader and following
that you start seeing that that leader
was ålesund by Parliament you have
elections occurring in 2014 and this is
really a case where Russia almost did
stop the elections during this time they
actually did get into the ballot system
they had to delete everything and reboot
just in time for the elections to
actually occur so your Russian
interference and elections is not
anything new by any stretch at the same
time you start seeing there also where
information campaigns going on basically
after the elections saying to the
Russian you know pro-russian candidate
won any of the annexation of Crimea
during this time that was also coupled
with major DDoS attacks other kinds of
attacks at the same time and so that's
where you start seeing this
Ellucian into hybrid warfare where
there's a digital domain integrated with
more physical kinetic kind of conflict
at that time Russia hogs wasn't done
then and 2015 more local elections right
around that time again major attacks
going on this time targeting more of the
news and media industries going on along
with the government entities and then
you've got the attack on the on the
energy grid during that time right as
the holidays we're picking up and that's
again a mark talked about for some of
these allies as we go along or are aimed
to augment the amount of impact based on
holidays and those kind of events or
downtime you go to 2016 and Ukrainian
present has basically said you know
we're under a digital blitzkrieg during
2016 they've been attacked a ton
throughout the entire year not just
these major ones that you're hearing
about he said something like you know 30
if there is something you're tens of
thousands attacks on about 36 different
organizations over two-month period
alone just during last year and so it's
really picking up if the targets are
expanding yet the shipping industry a
financial industries you have media I'm
obviously in the public sector as well
you get this so you get the tech there
and then 2017 you've got you're not
petty coming on when targeting Ukraine
then going spring globally through
additional sanctions thinking about on
Russian force on this activity and so it
is just it's been one major escalation
between those two countries for Iran and
Saudi Arabia's a little bit of different
stories this is where you got a
peer-to-peer country and more of a
tit-for-tat behavior and mark talked
about a lot of stuff leading up to it so
what I'll point out is the only
twelve or on cert issued a warning over
the wiper malware and she started seeing
the tension starting to rise during that
following those attacks and they get
Shamoon and after that though there's a
relative lull at least in the digital
domain during that time there still is
plenty of proxy words you think about
Syria and Yemen
both 2015 nuclear deal you can think
about that in the rest of the region
felt a little uncomfortable you know to
say the least with some of that aspects
of it and so following that 2016 again
you see the headlines you're calling you
know digital Warfare's going on between
Saudi Arabian Iran I know those are the
kind of headlines that are getting
pushed out there for 2016 on top of that
you see the Iranian pipeline explosions
and so thing to point out here it has
not at least from anything I've seen
there been discussions on whether it's a
cyber attack or not it's not been
confirmed but when it comes to rivalries
it doesn't always matter whether that's
happen or not that's the perception is
there that is what will guide behavior
within the the conflict so they may see
Shamoon and finally 2017 he's still
under old Shamoon at the same time we
see everything going on right now with
some of the proxies of Saudi Arabian
Iran with the UAE and Qatar tensions
that are going on in the planning of the
fake news after the after the intrusion
and so that's what's going on with it
with this one and again a lot of it
timed around some of these major events
but it is much more targeted and that's
part of the difference between here at
least over the years but with the being
targeted you compare that to North Korea
which really has not had any kind of
constraint with a kind of attacks that
they've had and so well may point to
Stuxnet as one of first and then they of
the first major destructive malware
North Korea had some back in 2009 which
doesn't really get talked about a ton
and it was part of a botnet a botnet
worm that propagated it first the US on
July 4th again the theme of kind of the
events and then spread to South Korea
during that time what you happen during
that same year those the end of the
six-nation peace talks so it's something
to keep in mind and that the nuclear
testing began again in 2009 in North
Korea and so you see the tensions going
on there and you see their response on
the on it was linked to the North Korean
side being linked to those kind of
changes in the international system that
are going on increased tension going on
in 2010 11 2011 otherwise linked to
North Korea this time really having an
impact on the South Korea
financial system during that time their
torpedo wash launches and some failed
ones and again more more of this
tit-for-tat going on between those two
countries another nuclear test in 2013
and there's another one in 2016
keep in mind I'm get the sanctions the
joint exercises that occurred during you
know 2013 is around the same time and
some of the attacks that happened and so
you got again all these things going on
as far as the different events you can
start linking those to win some the
wiper malware or destructive malware was
was deployed skip there's someone we
know about Sony 2015 war of the words
basically blasting propaganda across the
DMZ at each other there were some
casualties some minor casualties between
the two countries as far as some
exchange of fire and again wit Swift
that we started basically 81 million
dollar bank heist going on Matt was
working so we started seeing really
following that that malware in 2013 a
much more easing of tensions on the
digital domain as far south North Korea
still heating up a bit on the on the
political front and North Korea starts
looking actually even broader and what
the reasons could be that was in South
Korea there's a whole corruption crisis
that they could very well you know from
the North Korean perspective be taking
care of themselves as far as you know
leading to instability and so forth and
then 2017 when CDO DHS cert just
recently issued a warning for hidden
Cobra they're in their includes
everything from DDoS to wiper malware as
the warning and so there's still very
very active enough so that there was a
warning issued so now mark will yeah
cool so you know what's next it's you
know we don't have a lot of like super
bold predictions here because you know
largely this this isn't broke it's
working these techniques we talked about
both targeting the grid targeting
endpoint computers they're all working
so I think we should expect to see the
attacks you know kind of following very
similar paths I however some of these
these countries involved in these
attacks are probably emboldened by the
lack of any real consequences to their
actions both you know destroying
computers and also probing at things
like television stations power grids
steel mills things like that some of
these attacks you can't even really
figure out why they'd be specifically
targeted and so the thought that pops
into my mind is that there may be just
sort of test
now you know testing out tools making
sure they actually work in the wild and
then putting in the tool box for a rainy
day when conflicts might escalate
further they may have to deploy them
more broadly and as these geopolitical
strains increase kind of feels like the
consequences or you know give a crap
miss about getting caught
maybe that starts to go away maybe we
start to see more of these real world
physical attacks where tools just kind
of used in a proof-of-concept basis I
think we're gonna see you know a lot
deception you know and perhaps like
ransomware being included in ransomware
as a cover for action I mean you know
irreversible
you know encryption yeah it can be
reversible but if you don't have the
encryption key it's like effectively
dated destructions so we may see more
ransomware without reversible you know
reversible encryption or provided keys
start to become the norm for when we're
going after computers themselves as
opposed to those overwriting files we'll
probably see more collateral collateral
damage and you know and things like that
you know which organizations we're gonna
see a lot of the same we've seen we
talked about energy sector finance the
public sector all these institutions
where you know if computers go down
business operations cease there's going
to be you know confidence undermined
ability to have sort of strategic
messaging about why things are happening
defacements to go along with these
attacks all of that's going to continue
in you know strategic targets that's
even and even you might call some of
these things tactical but we saw a lot
of in the minds of probably North Korea
and Iran very successful operations in
response to statements and things they
don't like that are totally outside the
cyber domain with the response coming
you know through the cyber domain we'll
probably see more of that as like hey
this is in my toolbox you know as a
government of faint ways I can respond
even if things totally outside the cyber
realm creating some destructive effects
alright and ok we are which kind of
groups of countries might be next any on
caucus thien also comes in mind the
fastest which is you know increasingly
worrisome given that you think of the
nuclear weapon issue on both sides but
what's going on are you with that we're
already seeing you that they're
following a path that's very similar all
we've seen is from the other countries
this would be more of a peer-to-peer
like we see with Saudi Arabia and Iran
we've already been seeing an uptick of
DDoS attacks and then just in this year
there's been some sightings of
ransomware used against you between the
two countries and so given the in the
historical animosity going on while the
other GOP
is going on they seem like a prime
candidate if we were to be forecasting
which rivals might be next
Israel irani it seems like the natural
dis progression of what's already going
on within the Middle East and then you
know one more interesting question is
you know why not the US and China and I
don't think they would be right that
group would be right now for a large
reason that thinking about all this goes
back to strategic objectives right and
so for China right now to attack the
u.s. in this area given the economic
interdependencies given also some of the
instability already going on right now
within our own system you know China can
basically to step back for a little
while and see what's going on
while continuing other kinds of attacks
this isn't you know saying that you that
there won't be any kind of you know
cyber espionage and those kind of things
it's basically saying that you know the
implementation of destructive malware
it's not necessarily in China's interest
or in the u.s. is interest right now and
so when that changes when that calculus
changes that's when there's a reason for
concern and at the same time you look at
all the different you know three
different case studies we did the u.s.
is getting drawn into each of those as
well so we start seeing some those
system effects for more of the US and I
finally win and this is hopefully a
theme that we don't upon a little bit
had a breeze through a little bit
holidays are a big time elections are a
big time think about agreements and
summits we start seeing arranged just
more cyber texts in general during some
of these I'm thinking like joint
exercises those kind of things and then
the sanctions will end with that because
today the house is voting on potential
increase in sanctions on to Russia Iran
and North Korea across each of those die
as we've talked about and say I'll be
interesting to see one if that passes
and then if so if there is any kind of
response in this area so that's
something to keep an eye on so now well
and a little bit over our time but sir
questions be happy to take them
you mentioned that there's a lack of
consequences for probing networks
especially probing civilian networks
what effect like how much of this do you
think is caused by the NSA is refusal to
allow
espionage and non fully destructive
activities into the Tollan definition of
the use of forces in the digital realm
since that was a NATO combined exercise
I can talk a little about that for the
talent and so there is still discussion
so if you get your the inform on the
formal aspects of whether countries you
have to adhere to that right so there's
all that yeah
that's exactly part of the issue right
so whether you in hearing to that so it
is in there is discussion and they that
the ung GE the norm just fell apart that
discussion as far as whether or not
destruction actually does get
categorized as you know with a physical
effect think it categorizes as a point
of war I also don't think there's
follow-through yet from the government's
to be able to to want to respond given
those kind of things so the interesting
thing that's just been coming out lately
is that so ukrainian some of this has
been impacted the ukrainian hospitals we
ukraine and russia are technically at
war by most accounts and so that makes
it a war crime right there been a couple
articles over the last week talking
about that and so well we were coming
Fitbit well met and that's like that's
why it i mean it's it's fuzzy right now
and that's policy in all these areas is
really lagging behind that I'm a hundred
percent though whole nother talk on that
I mean some of the policy is going out
whether they're not the countries don't
actually have to adhere to it
it's very informal they're trying to
build a norms to try and categorize what
is and it is not acceptable but I think
it I think it is lagging behind it even
even if you put the document out there
like so NATO's got Article five right it
has a cyber attack on one it's a cyber
attack on all ahead hey the definitions
that yeah right and that's what not yeah
I I won't speak to anything that the NSA
does unless we're not associated with
them but um they're competing interest
within the US and within all these other
countries as well that further
complicates the entire ways have to
follow through with all these things so
I think it's a fair point I absolutely
think that there's a lot to be done on
international arena to actually hold
accountability in this area and until we
actually do move forward in that area
it's not going to happen and there are
there there are different groups both
you within Western democracies in within
the authority and regimes that also are
holding up part of these processes
any other questions
all right well thanks everyone