excellent welcome thank you all for
joining us today
this is Maurer Ben I'm sure I said that
incorrectly he can fix it here in a
little bit his presentation today is
Google Apps Script skill chain before we
get going here I want you to all
remember that these videos are all being
recorded and they will be available on
YouTube that means if your cell phone
goes off everybody on the internet will
then know that you are the one whose
cell phone went off in the presentation
so please don't be that person I
definitely want to thank our sponsors
I'm gonna pull up my cheat sheet here so
varis pright pro tippity tenable amazon
and the source of knowledge all are our
major sponsors for this and without them
we could not put this conference on so
thank you all thank you sponsors very
much and thank you all for being here
when and if and when you have questions
for this speaker during the presentation
or after please come signal me I'll be
standing in the back of the room you
want to have this microphone in your
hand the reason for that is again these
are being recorded so someone is going
to want to hear your question other than
that there is a website sched org come
get me later if you want to leave
feedback for this presenter and please
do if you have anything you'd like to
say it helps everybody to have more
feedback from the audience so without
further adieu have at it
hi everyone thank you for coming
Wolff I start with a short in to about
myself as this guy mentioned my name is
mala bean i will proof point as a
research lead I come from the background
of win32 row-level development I also
used to do some reverse engineering for
mobile mobile apps and mobile native
code for the last year I'm working on
like we're doing research on SAS
applications especially in Google
included some vulnerability disclosure
so we're gonna talk about Google Apps
scripts and we're gonna present it as
like I killed change sort of things I
don't have a slide on the on the kill
chain itself because I was like saying
yeah this is besides right everybody
knows killed what kill chain is so oh
that's fine and we'll try to go over the
steps and we'll start with like
introduction to Google Apps which for
those of you who are not familiar with
that and after that we'll try to get a
bit more malicious and see some example
I will be switching like screens all the
time because I have these slides over
here and I will like do some live demos
like all the time so let's start yeah so
as I said the short overview on Google
Apps Script so I don't know how much a
feel like familiar with this service
like if you'd like not much okay okay I
love it I love it you like came to here
what
so how much of you are familiar with the
concept of third-party applications like
okay okay better so Google Apps scripts
are like they're in the same family of
third-party application like if I'm a
cloud service or just a cloud provider
or something like that
and I want some people like to develop
like service to expose services of what
I'm offering
so they expose like an API and I as a
developer can use that API and use their
services so Google app scripts actually
do the same just with some limitation of
the regular API we'll try to cover what
like what the difference and stuff like
that so if we were speaking about Google
Apps which it's basically like a
JavaScript JavaScript language and it
it's been execute like within Google
backend it's not low not running like on
my back-end like I said party
application or stuff like that it just
been executed as part of the Google
cloud service or back-end or whatever
you want to call it so and it lets you
use like some services that are very
neat I think like the Gmail app lets you
develop likes and emails and do stuff
like with within your Gmail it's lets
you like do stuff within your drive up
like Google Drive of I'm sure like
everyone here is using Google Drive and
you can do like other stuff as well like
connecting to you like an API or
acquiring another API like for the
service or stuff like that it lets you
do that as well so you can like automate
automate your all your action if I'm
like if I were like cease admin of
maintaining a Google account so I'll
definitely will be using like
because it's like the best way to
maintain an account to my opinion of
course so we have a type of different
types we have the standalone script
which is like basically a file that just
like you know what in your Google Drive
we have bound bound script which is like
if you think about Microsoft macros okay
so it's basically it's like a pound to a
document about you screw about you
Google about a bounty form or
something like that
and we have another interesting concept
which is the web app so let's see one
example like that we have right alright
so we probably see like the example
services we have the Gmail example which
is like it's very simple code I think
very complicated to just go over go over
your Gmail account okay I like in my
dream you can't just prints the
attachments
that's like within my emails we have
like a simple drive up example okay
which uses drive up I'm like searching
in files okay and looking for this ring
Allah would like which document like
created in this date and contains the
title hello would and we have like query
to the API some weapon a P I that I
found online with CI o--'s API so I
guess now that you see it you probably
thinking yeah this is strong to I can
definitely use that
during this talk I will be like going
malicious and will like try to see some
more example how to try to use like this
is the usage of Google Apps Script but
we will try during this talk like
abusing it okay like trying to scale up
campaigns and trying to like do some
more interesting stuff so let's see like
a quick example like how to run around
this thing
okay so this is the script editor okay
when you create a file I just
I'll be right to show you how to do that
but when you create the file you just
like put your code inside you can create
like other files as well and you just
like run like whatever method you want
to wrap to execute so if you will like
try one that will be asking like
permissions like if I allow if I allow
this you should usage if stopped so
let's review the permissions and we can
see that we can see that asks for
Redeemers doing some stuff in your
onedrive and querying like external
links okay that's cool because that what
it does right so let's allow it
let's allow it and that makes clear like
if I allow it now it's just been
executed you can see like I'm preaching
some vlogs here so you can just like go
to the logs and see like yeah no logs
because I have no but let's try this one
yeah
so just Graham the API and you can see
the response of Yahoo api's okay now the
interesting thing about here is that he
you've seen that
this service this script was asking for
permission so if we go to like my mic my
permission
like in my account like the connected
ups in my in my account we can see the
script what it's name example services
right yes of tea like refresh this page
and you can see it right over here yeah
so this is it this is basically it so
this is as I said as I mentioned this is
like legit usage of Google Apps with
like and if we want to create a spirit
it is also very very simple so let's
write you like give an example for that
as well.you like just go into your
Google Drive account and like create a
new file and you go like Google Apps
right this one is standalone script okay
because it stands by itself okay very
simple so you can just like write write
your code here and do whatever necessary
like Gmail app okay and do stuff like
that yeah so that's the standalone
script you can like change its name or
whatever let's see an example of bounce
trip like if I open a Google sheet okay
so as I mentioned this is like Microsoft
macros okay but it doesn't really affect
the binary because there is no binary
we're talking about cloud like if I will
download this file I won't see like
binary difference I mean believe me I
checked it because I was looking I was
like yeah this would be cool if we can
like do something like put some militia
same with inside the binary yeah but I
couldn't find it so you just connect
just like a virtual link within your
cloud provider so let's see how to do
that like we created a new file a new
sheet and we go to tools and open the
script editor and the script editor will
be open and we'll see it takes us in
same like we can write our code right
here the thing is that the interesting
thing that these bound scripts are you
can access them like regular file like
if the standalone script is like line
within your Google Drive this one I mean
you can't find it just you can just
access it from this sheet nothing
nothing more so yeah the same concept
here of course you write your code the
staff do like register for malicious
stuff whatever you want and the last
type is like web okay and the web app is
like you know you just create an actual
web application like a real web
application that I can add that that
they provide you like a link that you
can access like from anywhere and you
can create your own HTML and like do a
real web application with within it and
the interesting stuff that we'll see
like in this example just this is a
static HTML page okay it's like not
doing anything we'll see like if we
continue like few slides more we'll see
like an example of self executing
JavaScript that I can use for phishing
attacks and stuff like that and we can
see another interesting concept it's
like for this
web app using like my cloud permission
like if I'm accessing this link I would
be able to get some information with
permissions of course of the cloud user
that access this link so in order to get
this link you just have to like deploy a
web app like do you like yeah new and as
you see you can choose like who is gonna
execute this this app so it could be
like me or the user that access in it
okay and that that part is really
interesting we'll see why in a few
moments and you can choose like who can
access it like if it's public if it's
not public okay so you you like getting
this this new address and you can go and
try to access this link and you see like
this status okay which is exactly
exactly the HTML that we just created
okay said yeah let's continue yeah so
I'm sure you all understand that this is
a very very powerful tools to as well
for like IT admins like that maintain
Google accounts and for like attackers
right you can you you can now think
about some usage how to abuse this kind
of like things so as I said I don't have
like a slide of the step of the kill
chain but I'll try to you like go over
with you
so the first step is like infiltration
right like how do we how do we do
infiltration so as I said like
standalone scripts and bounce rates are
just fine right so what can I do I can
just share it share it with everyone
right so yeah that's basically it we
just share it and the web app as you'll
see it's a link right so I can send it
by email by instance messages by any
other thing that you might think okay so
yeah that's basically it and for those
of you who are not familiar like how to
share a file over how to do stuff like
that it's really really easy it's like
coming to you this fall and like press
share and you like choose choose
wherever you want to share it with okay
really easy and we just such an example
of like getting web app links oh I want
one more time on that will just continue
to the next step
yeah so if you if you want to do some
like you use this Google Apps scripts in
order to like get data out of the
organization so we can do like stuff
like auto forward emails and post to
external URL and as well use it as a C&C
server like think about that it's like
very simple you just create some random
Google account you create like a web app
okay and start using it as a C&C server
I mean this is a very powerful tool
right I mean I wanted to show you some
example about it but I think I have like
a more interesting example that I want
to show
so I'll just talk about like really
short about the kara bank campaign that
we've seen in the world which was using
Google Apps with us a C&C server
it was also also they also use Google
Forms
if you familiar with that concept as
their CNC server so yeah you can imagine
it's like very very powerful tool for
attackers and we've seen it in the world
so yeah so that's for the exfiltration
part now I want to like show you some
innovating fishing method that we were
like in my researching we were just like
thinking about so we'll try to do it
real quick because we don't have like
laughs much time so this is my CV okay
and if I open it we'll see like an
encrypted document right because I don't
want like I want to have my CV and
document is being down there decrypted
the documents are being downloaded so
let's check the file what is this file
right so if we like before download and
what was the name yeah I have some I do
a lot of stuff with this file you know
so this is a 25 and if you like go to
real quick to virustotal have it right
here
[Applause]
we'll see yeah Wow
basically it's malicious file as you can
tell so as he already guessed I was
using a Google script in order to create
this fishing method and this is us you
can guess by now
this is a bounce script and we will just
let's examine this script and see what
what it does so we'll go to the script
editor again and yeah this is the not
very interesting portlet just look at
the HTML and we're just seeing that I'm
creating an element and providing like a
download in class and at first I was
thinking like yeah I'm gonna set up a
server and like you know connect him to
never and do stuff like that and then I
just realized why not using Google Drive
right yeah so that's what I'm doing here
I'm just like putting the file like
within Google Drive and no no antivirus
and nothing like they don't run it so
why not use it right so yeah the thing
is about this method is like if if I
want to share it so it won't exactly
work as expected and why is that because
Google will actually block Google script
if I like take a shareable link like if
I do something like that go right here
and try to get shareable link and like
share it and copy this link and send it
to one of my friends it won't work now
because they block so we can like do
this like share files like scale up this
campaign using actually Google Apps
trips will just like create a script and
this is the file id which with Google
and will just share it with mr. Brahn
that's exactly describes okay let's give
it permission to do that okay allow and
we're about to see that
okay I have it right yeah new email like
right here opening dogs and this is our
file and we're seeing that downloaded
file again so that's basically the main
example that I wanted to show we don't
have much time so we'll jump right into
the mitigation in if someone has like
question where we don't time for the
propagation but let's continue to like
do real quick to the mitigation part
because I think that's very important
even though probably won't be very
effective so for the self execution of
JavaScript like we might be want to use
like an endpoint security although as
you all know it has its limitations
right so yeah that's about it try to use
it and if not just try to be aware of
what you like guys I do for the
third-party apps will try to review like
the script permission like really
understand what it does like what its
gonna do to your account what's gonna
use and stuff like that so you wanna
review the script scopes like its
permissions and you want to probably if
you installed it and you probably will
want and if you find out it's malicious
you probably want to revoke it like
using this link and there was also like
Cosby solution that T's that like
prevent or do stuff like that so yeah
that's would be it I think that we don't
have time for questions I feel - you can
have the speaker demo in the conference
and ask him everything you want to know
thank you
very much for your presentation
[Applause]