thank you so much I know mid afternoon
after lunch you probably would much
rather cool up and take a nap but we
wanted to bring in sort of a community
hero sort of a leader yeah that's you to
really talk about you know overall
career strategy and really share his
story we're really thankful that thread
care came on as the sponsor here in
higher ground without further ado Marcus
Carey
[Applause]
hey thanks thanks a lot my wife's here
in the front row so she thinks I'm
awesome now thank you very much you
gonna think I'm kind of a badass I love
it
alright so hey thanks for coming
I'm always surprised when I have more
than one or two people in the room with
me so I'm usually usually I usually do
these talks in the mirror to myself to
make myself feel good all right so I'm
gonna go through like the kind of things
that I kind of been through as far as
like how I got to where I'm at right now
some people think that I've done some
pretty cool stuff so I want to share
with everybody
so hopefully this all works imma donate
with Chromebook all right so when I was
18 years old I joined the US Navy and I
was like really fortunate that I scored
pretty high my ASVAB test the military
entrance exam and on it on that exam I
tested out high so I ended ended up
going to the Crypt fill fill sardian
cryptography I got I went to Pensacola
Florida and trained doing all kind of
cool stuff and uh it was pretty
interesting because I didn't know at the
time uh my my my recruiter was funny
because he didn't have a clearance or
anything he was what they call a boat's
inmate in the Navy we got any sailors in
the house Marines a Marine Marines a
sailor to me all day all right so uh
bosun's mate don't they're they kind of
like drive the ship and all that stuff
they don't they don't do like you know
you know check related work so my sounds
like what's the CT in Miami Cody says I
don't know it's classified I don't know
so and so ended up work
for NSA and central security service for
eight and a half years while I was in
which was pretty dope
so what's funny is a um I tell people
all the time I don't I don't I might I'm
like really I'm ghetto
I'm hood and but I was at NSA with all
these like brilliantly smart people and
and I learned a lot of our technology so
I'm still uh crazy when it comes to a
lot of stuff if you follow me on Twitter
you know I'm crazy so but anyway got the
work at NSA and uh I'm not crazy
yes so we're working for it for those
people what was cool so there I started
doing certifications and uh in out of
military friend telling me hey before
you get out the military you have to
take these things called CLEP tests or
Dante's tests or whatever who's ever
taking any of those tests so I it's a
conspiracy that most people don't take
these tests because the colleges won't
make money unless you because you could
save like tons of money on this also in
the military I started learning how to
take tests so in the Navy what you have
to do every twice a year I believe you
have to take a test for promotion and so
it's a very technical test they give you
a study they tell you what the test is
on the beyond and you have to study
those subjects and you have to take the
test it's usually on your your career
fill or rate if you're unlisted so being
enlisted I got to learn how to take
tests really well so that test taking
things have taken me a long way so a lot
of stuff I'm going to talk about is how
I take certification tests and and I've
taught this to a lot of people and it
works really good so I see a lot of
people online asking how do I get this
cert how do I get that cert so I'm going
to tell you how to how to I'm gonna give
you cheat codes so you can pass any
certification and I've taken lot of them
so on this list a long time ago it's to
take a lot of certifications somebody's
expired even some of these are evergreen
but most of them have expired all the
Cisco stuff so now I'll give you this is
going to be funny I'm going to dispel a
lot of myths everybody that works at NSA
is not really smart
so there's janitors recurrences
and it's nothing wrong with being a
janitor but the truth is like if I said
I worked to NSA and you probably think I
was amazing but I could be a cook or
something right which is awesome but
they don't mean it I'm smart all right
so there I started off in it so how the
NSA works is they have tons of military
people like myself doing a lot of
support roles so I rob the NSA I was the
e5 and they put the military on the
crappiest jobs that they can give you
it's so funny and the contractors and
civilians at NSA do the cool stuff but
what I started finding I'm all I ask
more questions than anybody ever ever
asked I know my wife might ask more
questions than I do that but uh I'm the
most inquisitive first you want to know
I'm not afraid to not know anything
sometimes people accuse me being a jerk
but actually I I love being the dumbest
person in the room so I asked tons of
questions about anything so I when I was
at NSA I used to ask these people that I
thought were or beasts like man this
person is doing Cisco or whatever and I
was like hey how do you do this and and
I would ask them questions and stuff and
they would they would tell me answers
that I thought were right and this is
what you're gonna this is this is the
theme of my life even in cybersecurity
you're gonna ask a bunch of questions to
a lot of people and one of my texts our
mentors told me that there is a lot of
wrong answers so just because people
tell you something don't mean it's true
I mean have to think stuff I could tell
you could be a total lie I don't know
I'm gonna try to keep it real done so
here's the deal and I say these people
were telling me this stuff and I was
like okay cool that's how this work
that's how that work but when I started
reading text and materials like CCNA for
example I started like wow that person
doesn't know what they're doing the more
you know the more you know that you
don't know a lot of stuff but it the
thing is I think most of us are it's
kind of funny because I'm gonna throw
out a term I think we're all actors I
think we're all acting a role and I
think like just like an actor acts in
the script
you have to understand your script in a
role that you're playing and you can
learn it so if you look at my man Denzel
Washington will get more on Denzel a
little bit here
Denzel studies the part so well that he
diverted he develops ticks and all these
people like Brad Pitt I love Leonardo
DiCaprio he all these people study their
character that they're playing so I
think in real life you have to study
what you're trying to do to play the
role I'm really confident we're all
actors so started studying my CCNA and
now this is how it progressed the NSA
and and forgive me if I sound like I'm
bragging on anything I'm just stating
facts start at NSA they had me doing a
crappy job trying to do this audit this
messaging platform for the whole world
so what school you had you get cleared
and you see every piece of Intel ever
right what was crazy is an 18 19 year
old it was hilarious because I was like
totally panic and thinking the world is
always going to go to war the troops are
amassing here about you get to read all
this Intel you like man but then I found
out later that sometimes Intel gets it
wrong right so so that got the got the
work in the NSA was working a crappy job
and like then man I'm doing messaging
it's like seriously kill the alarm kill
the beep that was the job and there were
civilians here working for years and
that was their job it was like they will
push their button oh it's a button
ringing right no this is my button right
here and that's why was some civilians
were NSA so hurt if there's any NSA
people here they know what I'm talking
I'm spitting the real keeping it 100 so
so I did my CCNA it's like wow universe
CCNA in this whole department or
whatever NS 8 right the first CCNA at
the joint and then I buy CC and fee and
I got promoted to a day job which is a
dream job a lot of NSA stuff is 24 24
hours like a sedation of midship and on
and Eve so I got promoted to the IP team
is what they call the NSA so I was
working with the global global
management for NSA I managed Cisco stuff
all over the
I know it's pretty dope because it was
Oh crazy Cisco Network you know it was
dope because I had my CC and P but I
didn't I I was a paper ccnp and how many
uh people he might like paper certs they
just studied and do that but what I
found is if you get the paper then you
get moved into positions I didn't have a
clue what I was doing I remember one
time we had like it was a site located
in the continental US I probably
shouldn't tell what a site said but this
site I had a buddy from an Air Force
just transferred to this site and it was
so funny because my first couple weeks
on the job I showed us I shut a router
down and that's Phil site so this NSA
field site was totally cut off from
Earth and so uh luckily you had a buddy
there to tell him a can you can you
reboot that router for me so my buddy
like blown reboot the router the sites
back online but another thing is if
you're not if you're not failing because
there's a lot of people talk all the
time about how they all they do is win
win win you sort of gut well who did the
win who's that who's win win win is that
that's a DJ coward or something right
so people that's a lot if people aren't
felling they're not trying you know so
so and additionally it's good to have a
paper search to get you in a position so
whatever certain you're gonna get good
at these certs don't make you the
experience I think once you get in is
gonna make you who you are so like I
said I think two of these certs are
still active even but I don't put certs
on my LinkedIn and I'm not hating on
people to do I think I have the CH and
security plus I think they're evergreen
and they don't expire but I had CC RSS
see RSS feed that expired too loudly so
anyway that's that's how and I'm gonna
tell you how how to kill these these are
these things as well so all right so
let's talk about and another thing that
I did really well I took all the search
there was all paper certs again they got
me in a position that I was able to
exceed also I did my I did my bachelor's
degree from Excelsior College and I
don't know if you have heard excelsior
before but you can you can look it up I
don't know where you are in your
education journey some people believe
they have to have a
I don't believe you have to have a
degree personally my son my stairs my
wife or in the front row our son my son
started working for rapid7 when he was
16 years old on an internship and he
started working full-time when he was 17
now he I think he's in line for a
promotion to senior software engineer or
something like that rapid7 so he's been
so I tried these tips on my real life
son we always called him our use our
experiment the first one so it'd have
been a cool experiment because he's off
making good money
coding my son is the best Ruby developer
I know and I know a lot of Ruby
developers so so the stuff I'm telling
you it works I've tried it on my son
I've tried it on peers
I've tried it on people that I know
people that were transitioning out to
the military people are trying to break
into the career this stuff works so I've
got 13 more minutes and this is gonna be
action-packed so let's do this so clip
club tests are like a pee test if you
never heard them before
clip this or like a pee test in high
school you can take an advanced course
in it in you take a test and it's worth
three college credits most people don't
know that there's like an exact number
but I would say there's probably more
than 40 or 50 of these tests and that
might be on the low side if you're in
the u.s. most colleges take these
because they're credited by the American
Council on Education they're the same
people that give credits for any class
you took at a traditional college three
credits and some of the tests are it's
six credits so if you like we're like a
lot of people I mean man I did three and
a half years of college or something
like that I see people like that all the
time or I did a year and a half and I
and I almost had my associates I've met
people like that a lot and I say hey man
you should check out clips you could
probably test out on a couple of classes
and finish your degree so I became so
good at this that I used the combination
of the three tests that you see up here
DSST is another one is there's like
30-something tests
DSST and Excel to your college exams I
tested out of a hundred and fifteen
college credits
so 115 college credits you only need 120
for most degree programs so I I pretty
much I still people I did the Abraham
Lincoln school of college I was kind of
like self-taught because I'm apt out to
curriculum I study to test and I'm gonna
show you exactly how I passed all those
tests because I think it's like you know
I don't know if everybody can do it but
I can guarantee you even if your kids
did it you would save a lot of money on
your kids going to college
alright so that's so that's about the
test by examination so I got my
undergrad from Excelsior College the
reason why I went there
is because that kaulitz anybody know
excelsior in-house anybody an alum from
Excelsior undergrad excels here this was
cool because they had no transfer or
residency requirements a lot of people
take classes here and there especially
in the military and they have no words
that go to confirm their degree because
a lot of colleges say you have to have
15 upper level from here and 45 you can
only transfer this crap in this carrot
so that sucks because you might be
totally out of state the online program
doesn't work well with so sure they
don't have any residency requirements
and it's completely regionally
accredited so I accelerate accredited
like by the same field with Syracuse
Duke whatever North Carolina is
accredited by the same accrediting body
so that's pretty dope so my so I then I
went and did a master's degree in uh
from Capitol it was Capitol College back
in the day they just rebranded it's a
capital technology University so did a
master's degree from there and what's
cool about all this is I pay $0 paid a
total of two thousand dollars and I have
a master's degree and that's pretty dope
because a lot of people I know are like
are still paying off college debt that
college that will write TJ we fun enough
TJ's like I want to hack any mayor who
when it's a Libre Sally buddy so you are
told teacher you can only use your
hacking skills pretty good so the dark
side the dark side has cookies and jail
time
all right so another hack that I do in
my life and and and you can do this as
well is I do audible a lot so over the
last five years and this is totally by
accident a couple of things I didn't
have a plan but over the last five years
because I'm an auditory learner so you
got to figure out your your learning
technique some people are learning
hands-on some people aren't listening
whatever right so whatever that way is
you can you can like totally win so I'm
dead
of 120 some books over the last five
years and like a lot of people don't do
that kind I said that's like a big
library but I just listened to it online
I mean what article and I just learned
learn learn learn all the time sometimes
I get addicted and I'll do like five
books in a week and then I'll lay off
and then if I something else I learn so
now it's an entrepreneur what I really
want to learn it sells so all I do is
listen to sales material I listen to the
best salespeople I can get so I'm always
looking for sales books of any all sales
guys in here let me know so this book is
super relevant this is a book that I'm
recommending everybody because it's
definitely related to that career so if
you go to I just came back from blackhat
everybody's talking about our artificial
intelligence in a machine learning so
this book called on intelligence it's
about Jeff Hawkins Jeff Hawkins and this
is cool for just knowing your stuff
because when people try to bring in AI a
machine learning you can actually speak
the language in vernacular so this book
about Jeff Hawkins Jeff Hawkins is
pretty phenomenal guy he invented the
Palm Pilot he has a degree in
neuroscience and computer science and
what he does is he compares the human
brain it's a machine learning in a it's
an absolutely phenomenal read and if
you're struggling to understand yeah
our recommend this book so this is about
hacking a career how do you know what's
bullcrap and what's not I hate food our
actual motto at our company is something
like you know I we exist to eliminate
fear uncertainty and up so this book is
dope check it out
this is just for your career alright so
here's how to study for any of the
things that we talked about for here's
are all certifications so this is a
sample DSST outline this is the
and some people refer to it as Dante's
right every test that you ever want to
do in life if you did its SAT or a CT it
gives you percentages of what an
examination is going to be on and even
what kind of problems so some people
study these things blindly I don't
understand that
because like there is a way in the
military they kind of told you what was
on exam and you kind of you did exam
so all these tests they tell you
percentages of how this is like from our
criminal justice DSST all right
so if somebody's so many people here
maybe law enforcement a lot of people
transition law enforcement to cyber and
I don't know sometimes they have a
degree or not but these tests are
different from any other tests all the
credit by examinations they judge you
essentially on what would a student if
they were studying the same course what
would their uh how much would they
remember after like eight months or
something it's some kind of scientific
thing because everything you do you only
remember a certain month semana you're
not gonna remember anything from this
talk hopefully take one note about it so
you're only gonna remember 20% of what
what you learned in any given thing so
here you're not judged on 25% of the
class you're judged on 25% essentially
like what what was that person that
studied it no at that point so I would
say if I saw some fifteen percent and
somewhat twenty five percent of the test
I'm studying 25 percent 25 percent 25
percent I'm gonna know that stuff inside
out and I'm gonna know peripheral
information but even nowadays I did all
this without Wikipedia you can go to
Wikipedia and build you a study guide
based on this like definitional Cranham
but a lot put it in a Wikipedia put it
in Google like it's like super easy to
build your own study guides to this
material we read the material and your
and your and your here it's like a you
have to get less than 50% on these tests
to get college credit it's ridiculous
right so anybody in military I know
there's a couple military people in here
you got to take advantage of that the
clips are free from military personnel
is insane so that's why I did it
115 credits for zero dollars so here's
the state materials are used on that so
I
cliff notes funny enough cliff notes has
the official outline for many of these
things it since ASA credit it is these
tests they actually tell you like this
is what's required when they look at
North Carolina or Duke their classes
have to follow this same syllabus in
order to grant college credits so if you
read the cliff notes you're going to be
super close to that I read it's this
other thing called standard deviance
anybody ever use those before they're
really dope because they actually walk
you through it and they teach it in like
kid like I have to I tell people I'm a
dumb country boy so you got to break
stuff down to me real simple and they
they break stuff down real simple and
tell you and I'm telling you if you have
kids you're killing yourself if you
don't your kids in high school can take
these exams and they're like 100 bucks a
pop your kids you can save about thirty
thousand dollars I did the calculations
you can say about thirty thousand
dollars if you got your kids to take
like you know ten exams and some of my
work six credits so the for dummies
series books are amazing you know it's
funny because a lot of times when I talk
to people I talked to me about civil war
and he swear to God did I like a Civil
War historian no I just read civil war
for dummies and like I said nowadays we
got Wikipedia which is a beast this book
right here everybody that complains
about information security uh what is
called burnout I heard a lot they need
to read this book so you know and this
book talks this book is the funniest
book ever so it has more f-bombs in it
than any book I've read in my life
especially in the first chapter but
what's cool about this book is a it
gives people it gives you the ability to
concentrate on what really matters and
personally what I've learned is like you
can probably just concentrate on one
thing at a time
I see so many people coming in
cybersecurity and they want to know
everything I tell people you good if you
know one thing well in cybersecurity and
you could build a whole career on
learning something better than anybody
else
so I think it's cool it's experiment and
listen and learn from the talks but even
if people up here talking
stage they're probably only good in one
thing you know if you ask somebody they
might tell you I'm not good at nothing
so but but focus on what really matters
in execute like like like crazy so if
that's getting the college the green
just focus on that just throw everything
else to decide if it's getting that
certification get that certification and
that's how that's kind of how that works
so down to the interview
so here's about tips for interviewing
only put on your resume when I when I
interview somebody I interviewed them
only on what's on their resume so if you
set yourself up for you set yourself up
for failure if you put stuff that you
don't know on your resume put everything
that you're really good at on your
resume and talk about stuff on your
resume learn how to do redirection and
talk about stuff that you know and every
every place is not a good fit you know I
you know but I only interview people
based on what's on a resume so if they
have I'm a diss programmer I ask him
about that
so people are asking you outside of
outside of that or something like that
you probably don't want to work there
anyway because what what I found is if
people are trying to fit you into some
kind of position or whatever no matter
who they pick they're not going to know
everything required for that job
requirement it takes anybody in this
room about six months to know what
they're doing and by six months you're
probably better than everybody on that
team and that's kind of that's kind of
hot I view these things so Denzel Denzel
if you want to be a pen tester this is
Denzel in training day he says if you
want it if you want to catch a wolf you
got to be a wolf wolves I mean don't be
a sheep and filing what everybody sends
because probably nobody knows what
they're talking about including me
don't be a sheep that's the end of my
talk thank you very much
so we have a few minutes for some
questions anybody got questions from
Marcus no questions okay here we go hold
on pass the mic so in order to take
those tests that you're talking about
can you just go online and sign up do
you have to go through a university did
start the test out of some of those
classes or how do you actually do that
so it gets counted as college credit
yeah yeah so most colleges offer these
tests especially most state colleges
some private colleges don't do it so a
local state college or a or even a
Community College probably offer these
tests you can probably go to their
testing center is where all the college
kids take their tests and you can sound
totally signed up online you can
download those exam outlines yourself by
the books and just go take the test you
don't have to be rested to the college
typically can you assure the slide of
that College where you get your masters
from again okay Capital Technology
University so that College was totally
an online program which is which is a
really good program when I was at NSA
all NSA had a partnership with that
program
and they paid for a lot of NSA people to
go to their program and when I got off
the military I went to their program
because all my heroes kind of you know
people I looked up to 130 college so
it's right down a rope NSA about 15
minutes of NSA so that's why I went to
that college and it one up here want to
prevent sorry just to re-emphasize um to
pass certifications just look at the
breakdown percentages of where
everything's focused on high percentages
go for that study that and they're now
yeah okay cool thank you so yeah look
for look for in also online forums
they'll give you some clues as well but
but just know know the stuff is the
highest percentages like the back of
your hand and you'll pass the test you
don't have to study everything I figure
they're good Thanks that's good thank
you Mark
[Applause]