thank you everyone for being here we are
really glad to be in Vegas including
from France so I'm Tomas and MIDI and
some Shu point before starting first as
we are French please excuse our broken
English that first one the second point
is who you are basically some auditors
in info information security responsive
incident
we have several years being professional
so that's it what what is the agenda
today so briefly we will introduce you
let me ask you something first
who's Reggie Wayne who's familiar with a
doob who's ever heard about a dupe using
MapReduce cool so a lot of people that's
that's great
so we'll be moving on quickly from the
first part to the second in the first
batch we will introduce briefly a dupe
and its security model and to understand
what are the known limitations and then
from the second chapter second section
we will be a reviewing how can we pull
and what are the different steps in
order to assess the security of a do
cluster there's some coupons few tricks
and by the end we will be giving you
some recommendations as we have been
auditing and penetration testing several
other clusters mainly mostly for for
French client but we get some
realization that topic so we can guide
you and give you some I hope good advice
so Hadoop what is a loop is an open
source framework that I was for the
distributed processing of large data
sets and using simple programming model
for the distributed processing so you
know the MapReduce algorithm at at the
beginning it was invented by Google in
order to sort an index web pages large
large amount of web pages here is the
principle I won't be telling it but you
can see that you have different phases
mapping shuffle and reduce the the goal
is to sort some some stuff using a lot
of different nodes
by grouping them on some unlucky that's
the first one then for the open source
point and character characteristic of a
do I do comes is now back from a patch
and from the Apache foundation from
several years now is completely open
source and free and but in real life I
do promote I gathered in distributions
just like Linux the the current three
main distribution that the following so
Claudia often works in mother really in
real life you find eighty percent of of
clusters where is my 80 percent of
clusters are either clodia of often
works Claudia
have fun proprietary stuff autumn rocks
because fully open source restful open
source with only open source products
and the cheaper license fee and mapper
is doing Hadoop without a dupe to be
sure they are fully understood what a
diplomate Asians in terminal performance
are and are trying to bypass this kind
of this kind of limitation we will be
talking about the name node limitation
just after they're fully understood the
case and they are doing Hadoop without
really how do I do this just a connector
for some stuff but in real life we are
mostly doing some cloud era optim-ox
distribution the common point is to is
the use of the a patch a patch core
framework which is doing mostly only to
stuff basically a dupe is what storing a
large data set and processing large data
set that's the only point in real life
what does a real be that element looks
like it's at the beginning you you're
buying a lot of CPU RAM disk on top of
it you're putting the I do
co2 in a lot of support at the life
cycle in the platform for the
acquisition here are some different
modules you will see different modules
that will appear in that in this slide
for acquisition you have like relational
or non-relational databases and most
importantly you have HDFS
GFS which is the distributed file system
in order to store law
large data sets then for the processing
you have a lot of modules really
different modules maybe the most popular
right now Apache spark attached I don't
know Apache drill for SQL SQL requests
and on the deep core you have MapReduce
in yarn MapReduce which is the algorithm
in order to distribute some tasks and
yarn which is a scheduler like a plane
operating system is just and it's pretty
complicated to be fair it's just odd
scheduling and managing some resources
on the crystal then you have some
indication module I guess you ever heard
about elastic Suraj Salah listen at the
end you want to construct your data so
you have different module for end users
mostly web applications in order to be
almost as friendly as possible so you
have Jupiter which was I Pete on a book
I pad on that book you how they are you
tableau SAS which are sassy it is a non
non old window public data a coup its
plankin and so on for the administration
typically for Claudia you have the
cradle manager which is a proprietary
product for Auton works you have a patch
unbury which is doing all supervision
and administration for the cluster and
you have different for each distribution
like a proprietary or a specific
management platform and at the end
because we are here for this today
security so you can see that security
there's really two modules and even in
these modules there are really they're
very one task a note which is a gateway
Ranjha which is the central policy
management and you can apply some your
copyright policies and how to protect
data and to put on some ACN some tree
which is to be you know like one rival
of ronzo but in VN in in real life tell
me after in from one but it is kind of
broken and not really useful and not
really not really user-friendly but
that's a bit
abandonware and you have record service
which is coupled to some tree
the roster but mostly for security
modules you don't have many stuff that's
the first observation that you can can
can make by looking at the equation a
typical system a dupe under you do two
parts as I said storage and processing
processing so you have some data nodes
which are stirring the food data paths
and you have a single active name node
which is typically a mapping list of the
five paths since the name node knows for
your file which is divided into blocks
two different sub file they are stored
among among that in they cannot they
note where no knows where you can
retrieve the path of offshore wanted
file for the processing as I said you
have my produce and young MapReduce
being the job distribution on the
cluster and young which is a scheduler
yun is a pretty as I said pretty
complicated stuff and we haven't been
digging that much into the security of
it I guess there are some real number it
is to be fair right now you can say okay
cool but really you who uses a dupe
anyway in the real life so from the
official I do pages you can find some
different providers or web web Giants
using it and you have an idea of their
number of node a node is a server to be
fair with with a lot of resources CPU
runs and this and you can find you know
the Yahoo has a lot of doop nod and his
and was massive maintainer and massive
contributor to the project hi everyone
so note that who matters we had secret I
will present it security model so first
let's talk about authentication so by
default there is no real authentication
mechanism implemented on i dub or mostly
is the the ototoxic Asian mechanism
called simple which is implemented but
by default so without Kerberos which is
the user authentication mechanism
available on a loop the cluster won't
verify your identity so you pass the
string
for example you are HDFS and the cluster
will trust you
so the two mod authentication mode are
simple which is just identification and
the other is corrals which is more
difficult to implement so simple
authentication is just identification
and you can be whoever you want which
service you want you can perform any
action with any username that you want
you just have to provide this name so to
improve the security you have to
implement the whole proper
authentication mechanism which is
Kerberos and which is more difficult to
implement on the cluster so be careful
when you activate authentication because
on a dupe you can activate partial youth
education with carriers and and for
example you have the parameter to to
implement authentication on the whole
cluster just on the core a dupe so that
the parameter but then you have to also
to enable the authentication on the web
pages because there is a lot of there
are a lot of interface web interface
which are accessible to the user and if
you do not enable this parameter you
don't put Kerberos we will have the
simple authentication activated on the
service and any user could be he wants
but then you can you have to also to to
activate this parameter which which
allow to which use anonymous anonymous
authentication so you have to disable
this parameter and then you have also to
also to enable this parameter to to
activate authentication on the yarn
service so you have to put carriers
instead of simple
this on these different parameters in
order to activate curved arrows on all
the services just not and not just on
the on one of these service so be
careful and that's that's a big deal
because we have see several time
authentication enabled but not on every
interface so that's soon so in the end
it's like simplification is like
deployed and you can access and be
whatever user we want so be careful
that's the first strong point for I have
security remove all simple odds and
that's not just one parameter that's a
bit tricky but that's the first trap not
to fall into we will we will show you
some films attached etc based on the
simple authentication
so next authorization and auditing so we
will show you there is and as Thomas
already showed there are a lot of
service components on a deep cluster and
each of these components implements one
authorization on or one auditing model
for example you have the HDFS which
which is the Hadoop distributed file
system which implements POSIX permission
with extended SL like on Linux so you
can have a user group and an author and
you can set permission for this these
different people and also use sa since
the 2.5 then you have for example hive
which is a SQL DBMS on a dog which
implements authorization on sequel verb
for example you can grant you access
with select to one user and you can
grants directed to another user and
perform authorization model on using
this sequel verb ACL so you with this
two example you see that there are two
authorization model for two components
and that's the point you have lots of
authorization model it's
difficult to manage so in order to
manage you have some third-party
components which are used in order to
manage all this office UK education
model and to to centralize this
management in order to simplify the
administration and these components are
also used to concentrate to the security
and the audit policy and the security
logs for example you have the Apache
Ranger that Tomas already already talked
about which is the only serious
components used for security feature
which allow audits auditing new
centralization log of centralization
administration of the authorization
mother deploying of Kerberos etc and
it's only package with the Hortonworks
which is the most open source package
that you could use and then you have
also a past century or a cloud era
record service which which are coming
with with with cloud era cluster but
which is not as mature as rauner is so
for the moment the only strong third
party module is around here on century
you can perform something but it's more
difficult to administrate and it does
not implement all the capabilities of
render so next data protection as the
the cluster are often used to store
sensitive data is it's an important
feature so you have to - encryption
features we have encryption in transit
it's when the encryption of the flow of
data and encryption at rest which is
encryption on storage so this
to encryption are available by default
on the do but you have to implement
Kerberos in order to activate it then so
encryption teen transits for the
communication with the name node which
is the node which old the indexed of the
of the file etc you have freely
available and protection mechanism views
on purpose RPC shame and is ASL
mechanism so you have the authentication
of me which is no option but just
authentication then you have the
integrity setting which is
authentication and integrity and you
have the privacy which is full of
krypton including authentication and
integrity for the communication with the
web interface you have also by default
the the capability of of activating SSL
and TLS on the on this service but it's
not it's rated by default then for the
communication with the name node data
node sorry its own its prettiest the
same that on the day node you have a
data transfer protocol which involve two
phase key exchanges in three deaths and
rc4 which are not the strongest
algorithm algorithm we know an
encryption which is used by a us
algorithm using a different size of key
before 128 bits then you are you are the
encryption at rest hadoop implements its
own encryption model which is based on
to two key which is the encryption key
used to encrypt the directories on the
cluster and the and the in a key dec
history which is the encryption for the
file okay so you have this gem which
will show you
minimal architecture so you have the
inane node you have the clients sorry
yeah the name not you have the clients
and you have the kms the name not store
the EDA key the kms sword the deck the
deck key and you have the Android the
clients so you you ask the day node for
the index key which asked the kms which
all they are cell if you if you are
allowed to access the key the chemists
will give you the decryption key you can
decrypt and then manipulate the file and
store it after so here you can see that
the security boundary is not the crypto
system or not not related to
cryptography button just on the ACA and
the rubbish nest of the game as you
because the chemists old all all the key
so if you can tune the kms you can
access to all the key and decrypt all
the data so it's not a crypto problem
but he just robustness of a chemist that
the boundary just just one word about
the cryptography you may ask what is the
overhead and what are the drawbacks of
using in transit and at rest to be sure
there's no rematch overhead using in
transit this is pretty much a crip shun
you know known with SSL TLS yeah no
performance impact but to be to be
honest fortress you have some
performance impact in the documentation
they are speaking about at 20% I think
it's it's pretty correct try 20 maybe
even 30 percent of personals wasting
yeah I guess I would say but that's the
that's the price to pay today in order
to have attrition that at rest for
defenders
what be careful again this is not the
first section you put encrypting or
flipping the data reg is not the very
most very first action you have to to
implement in most of the case we we've
seen option encryption at rest is really
mandatory for some regulations I guess
you have some and you have some in the
US but this is to be fair not the first
point and not the first security measure
to put in place no creation at rest in
Indian but in front rosy this is pretty
much mandatory and this is really common
so for the next part we will talk about
the mapping mapping the attached surface
so as we are entering the second section
which is focusing on the attack
techniques to be fair there is no much
we will see some some defensive measure
after but the point of that talk is
really attacking how you can attack a
cluster and and improve improve its
security in the end from our experience
an adduct deployment commonly follows
one of the three following topologies so
I then add an attacker know your
environments know where you are
I know in which case you you are
connecting your assessment so first you
have the simple topology which is
everything is exposed on the corporate
network you are plugging into meeting
room and you can access every you can
the infrastructure is very exposed and
the one on the corporate network I guess
so you have you can find just on the
flats network in flat topology you have
some H nod what is the national energy
on is like a bastion it's like a unique
entry point to a cluster this is
basically what the John is a Linux
server offering you have to connect on
this with SSH and just offering you know
the a dupe Native Client you know doc to
perform some actions that will be see
after like a doop doop lists me list me
some fire at the slash path and so on
this is for I diffusers to you know dot
well there they are working over a month
you know stand down and having the same
bin arisen having the same version and
not not not administering in in reducing
your action from your own PC with
different Russian and so on then you
have the name node you understood that
the name node is a single point of
failure because without name node you
can you can't access anything and
on the cluster and you have some deacon
not storing the data so as you may
understand this is this represented by
that extra face you have a chance I
probably T of pruning some stuff and
will be an existing some data on some
resources then you have the second
topology which is a bit better where you
expose only necessary end-user services
because in the end on nuclear stuff you
don't have many usage mini use case and
you don't it was a fall from a security
point of view it's not good if you have
multiple entry points and multiple way
to access a cluster so in that topology
you only have the edge node and some web
apps for consultation so Claudia are you
Jupiter I fit on that book zip in which
is the open source and open source
version of Jupiter not an open shot not
the sorry not the Pancho's version but
another open source version of for the
same usage you have a notebook you can
input some commands and retrieve some
data from different data sources and
then you have the internal network that
time you know you can see the you know
the name node are not exposed on the
corporate network that's a bit better so
in the topology that xfa is really
reduced to be fair because as an
attacker being plugged on the
cooperating drugs you won't see much
stuff and you must Indian exploit
trivial or default credential on this on
these services or web you know our
inability on the web apps which exist by
you and the last and the most
restrictive topology which is the highly
segregated version from the corporate
network you have a unique or true a
unique access point which we can be see
tricks or bastion and whatever I won't
say I won't quote some some brands but
you understood the idea of having one
dedicated on three point where you can
implement logging logging stuff GLP and
so on then you can see from that bastion
affronted the front end a dupe network
which are again
the edge node and the webs for the end
user and you have the back end and
imagina there is some some fire wars
between each each Network in
implementing some granular access lists
and so you have the back end from that
topology you can see that in order to
access the back end you really have to
first go on to and to access the base
channel which reduce the probability and
then you have to prune some stuff from
the edge node of Web Apps so again it
divides the probability so the attic
surface is really minimal and as I said
from the first patch you have a unique
access point you want our loop
infrastructure and you can implement
some more compulsory conserving measure
like logging and gel B so the first step
when you will try to from pen test on
the processor will be to map the attack
surface so first you will see a lot of
service if there is no network
segregation or network filtering because
as we already told there are a lot of
theories available in cluster for
example the HDFS related services which
are for example this this this service
which which is used by the IPC
connection then you have some web access
interface and web app API for example
see this this HTTP interface which are
used for example to browse the HDFS file
system and then you have also some young
related interface which are for the
first one the IPC IP support and then
you have the HTTP port for for viewing
the log of the young service of the task
yeah young as I say the schedule we just
scheduled some tasks from from these
services you can submit the task and
follow a status and then we just put
some old stuff that we
you might not not see on the pen test on
new cluster so then on the data node you
have also a lot of services this TCP
service is is used for HDFS data
transfer and it is called when you use
for example of the Hadoop FS the -
comment then you have some FS which
which is which are which is for sorry
pretty much the same that this one on
the DNA not a lot of of interface that
are commonly used on the data and may
not and which are very verbose and the
same on the in the neighborhood and the
data and there is no much difference
between them
and then you have some young stuff also
on the data node for example on this
part so I will show you some some
example after and then you have also
some interesting third-party module we
did not put all the the module but some
interesting stuff we have the HTTP FS
interface you have the cloud era manager
which is used to manage to cluster you
have the Apache I'm Barry which is
pretty much the team that's cloud there
our manager is rude also to to Mendel to
cluster you have the aperture in her
interface cloud there are you extra so
let's see the interface like I said
before you have here on the name not the
the interface you can browse the the
HDFS and see the different file and you
can also download all this interface are
related with an API and there are some
call with the API and
we'll talk about after we have the
pretty much the same but maybe a little
bit more ugly on the data nut but it's
the same thing we can roll it that
another browser name okay then you have
the young interface which are used to
preview the the job which are running
[Music]
and the container launch head etc you
have the this this one you can see which
resources are used for the moments on
the cluster exit app so you can view the
story of the of the yarn that then it's
pretty much the same that than the
previous one you have some job story
young young sorry so you can use nmap
the map to in order to figure Fritz
disservice because there are some some
some scripts on stream three which have
been developed in order to in order to
identify this service you have very easy
to track data
the output is like this one so you can
view which which service is listening
and in order to to cartography the
network so after you you you made your
you're mucking net one my thing
what you want to do to access data how
you would like to do through browser
because you are lazy really lazy you
want to use your own browser to access
anything so you have to use and you will
be cutting in the end web each GFS API
which is you may understand how to
access HDFS through a web api it offer a
Resta appear to access data it you can
do pretty much everything with the gfs
and where can you see some ETFs what is
EFS
every season some first on the HDFS that
another web um is that you suggest
before on also the HTTP module which is
just exposing webby GFS and in the end
also on it Apache knocks get well which
is all UNIX only exposing some webby GFS
and some some stuff I picked up ash Knox
is a security component but it is only a
gateway and it is only for network
network purposes and I you how you can
filter and put in place just a single
entry point for your data infrastructure
so now what is the cluster only enforces
you know simple simple application which
is again a notification that you can
access any store database by using the
username parameter that's not a bug
that's a feature and that's an
authentication feature thank demo so
here you can see one the command
interface that you can see a lot of
variables data from the configuration
here if you go to the treaty's brought
the system you can browse and access
whatever you want and then you can you
see the permission the permission denied
message you're saying that by default on
Doctor Who and I can access that that
folder because I'm not you know and not
fight the falcone user so and now if we
can call under the hood under the hood
of this this is just calling the GFS API
that you can see here so here you have
your pass on the HDFS you put on some
some cooperation lista choose open G
late in whatever and so here I want to
access you know the slash user slash
HDFS directory and it says I'm not a lot
because I'm Doctor Who okay if this if
there's really some simplification in
nokia bellows which is the strong strong
security point you can input whatever
you want and you can be HDFS and that
this time you can you can you can see an
access everything so just by inputting
your engine username that's pretty
ridiculous but that's a security model
that's why you have to implement
Kerberos this is a strong requirement
and then you can access access some data
erectus just by saying
firstly we have created a fine name
besides and you can oh sorry this won't
worship because of some networker stuff
but here I can access the file this is
the next step is to open the file and
now I would just being able to to have
the complete you know tree
directory tree on the cross which is
really useful fight occurs another
because you have to access data and yeah
so we've been developing a tiny script
this video there's no magic in this is
just automating some web gfs course and
you can you can browse everything and
now if you want to access data but
through CLI in a dupe native stuff you
can input the same username the use of
the name parameter you can input it as a
element variable and here you can see
first I'm denied because I'm toe to toe
then I'm seeing an HBase which is a non
relational database and then I can
access I guess access everything that's
pretty much as simple as this you can
just maybe bring a slight demo so you
can can access this that's it I guess
this is a you see the first point when
you until a dupe you know that you think
that big data is really quick and fast
no that's a joke because everything is
is in Java everything is pretty much
slow so here I can because I'm rude I
can access everything goes I'm new I'm
rude I'm not the correct user to access
it so I will just say that HDFS just the
same as you run it use all the temporary
table and that time I hope it will work
it worked
you can access there's no magic in here
so that's the first one being able to
access some detail on the cluster but
then we have some more interesting
attacks which means we'll introduce yes
the after you have access the data you
want more you want execute code on the
cluster so remember a dupe in the
framework used to execute some stuff
some comments in order to sort file etc
extra so we simple authentication as we
have see you can do pretty much
everything you want so let's let's try
to execute some code so a dupe is
developed in Java so by default I would
say you have you are forced to develop
in Java but some people have developed
the a dupe streaming jar which is used
in order to execute any kind of script
Python bash etc on a dupe so the the
common line is this one so you have the
Hadoop jar you put the the pass to the
streaming jar you put the input file
which must not be empty you put the
output directory and the mapper for
example bin cats
it is his / password and the reducer
known because we won't use reducer it's
not to be much in order to be faster
this is just a slight optimization just
because you don't need wait for this
test you don't need a really really sir
so then you you try to to check if the
and have been successfully performed and
then you can read the file and for
example you have the access to the stash
this is not password file so then so
like we have seen there a lot of step in
order to access the the file and the
data so we want we want to to optimize
this this process so we will use
Metasploit in order to to have a real
entirety shop so we will use reverse
speed reload the reverse speed road is
generated by the command line miss my
name is a theorem then you you launch
the Adept streaming by adding the file
file parameter which is used in order to
upload the MSF payload which have been
generated before on the cluster and then
execute it and you have to execute it
with the background parameter in order
to not stop the process after the after
time Mart because if you don't put a
background parameter you will your
process will shut down after some time
at so let's have a demo as this is as
you may take some time
will we launch and will go on and
hopefully we will see we will see the
shell arrive on our on our computer so
here is my attacking machine you can
recognize Kari so here all set not who
just to to listen for the for the on
layer and then our just a prod and try
to execute my not much aperture but we
reverse disappea for the reason we
expose the straw so I guess it would it
should be okay this is just sending you
know the payload
this is admitting the job and missing
good job so which in token yeah okay
just to wait in order to have your
connection
back so but like we said the a dupe is
pretty slow and even more on our
computer machine so we have to wait
until here you can on the putea
window this is the access on the server
side
this is just for monitoring purpose for
demo just to see when the payload gets
executed but normally as an article you
don't have access to that protein window
you're just with your Metasploit in your
attack in experiment wait we just have
to wait so we don't know when it would
be exhibited that's the first one to be
that big data you don't know where you
when your job will finish so let's move
and we'll go on just after when we see
the shadow right just some it's a good
cut so you buy a dupe is a distributed
processing model so you can recruit a
decryption code on many nodes and you
don't have the capability to shoes on
which nut you want to execute your cut
so you will launch MapReduce job the
adult core will choose on which not it
is a job and you but you don't you can't
target a specific node so that's the
first the first point you can't target
specific then you have to to configure
your adept variants because we didn't
show you because it's not very
interesting in our demo but you have to
set up your environment in order to be
able to call the other clients
I do Client executable so you have to
retry the configuration in order to get
the configuration you can access on
pretty much pretty almost on all the the
web interface expose the slash conf
slash confer pass and you can retrieve
the configuration on this this interface
then so you can
there is also some vulnerability on
third-party module which allow users
educated user to access the
configuration so in order to yeah I'll
show my right come on so yes so that's a
bit long but our right and youyou we are
able to execute cut on the cluster so we
are here yarn which is normal because
the yarn is the the user used in order
to execute job so yep you can access
there's no magic here as I do just
allows to to execute some stuff but if
your user is really pretty malicious you
would execute another path or something
like this and we will show you the
variety after but once you are on the
cluster you can browse the data node on
which you are and and try to find some
some file and we have found that some
file are not well protected for example
on the you interface by default the
configuration file is readable by anyone
so you can read it and if you read it
you will have access to the data the
database password used by you so you you
could access the hash the username etc
but you also can access once you access
to the database to the session cookie
and by listing the session cookie you
can just take the session cookie of the
administrator and canary use this is one
variety we should just after but you can
see you we just showing you that when
you install you idea for pretty much on
the same server and there's a Verity of
ten minutes let's move
thank you so we have developed a script
in order to retry to automatically
automatically retry a minimal
configuration which is called a dupe
Snooper you can find on github and we
you just have to learn the script
if retry from automatically the
configuration for you so you can say
okay that's good but come on weak to
this service anyway on the internet for
instance with the Shannon request you
can see a nice dog is that what all the
result here are not really a due process
but that's a good input not find some so
yes the point is is there's they already
add some new cluster free accessible on
the internet and some figures from a
study alone so I was mender stood well
the first point is to say to see if
there's simpler kevro's of application
so from this figure
I guess you understand that there is no
much clusters with camera implemented
and also points at the watch out point
when we say remove all simple odds from
that the figures on the right shows you
for the five glamorize cluster how much
how many are implementing you know a
fully implemented cameras end-to-end and
onto HTTP interfaces so you can say you
can see 0 and again that's cool but come
on who's really interested in attacking
at the stuff so in in the media you can
find some stuff there's some run
somewhere and some people are wiping
some I dupe databases on the internet
you can find here with a slight message
no data for you secure your there
are pretty much encrypting or removing
everything and you have to pay your
ransom and you can find some stuff in
the media so that now let's let's see
how you can put on Krista with Antron
sake a dupe component so here we are
exposing your analogy that allows you
know any authenticated user on the on
the matching to to impersonate
and to steal the identity of the etfs
user there was a Bernard well this is
this is patch now but for this version
you can find a lot of actual and current
cluster having that rationale below and
here when you are putting that command
that that's the real novel come on
GFS groups something it tried to retry
to retrieve the groups for user and
this is not escaping correctly stuff so
you can see that you can execute
anything and here you can see that the
command is exhibited as the HDFS even
for credit now for Tokyo to attack a
barrage cluster no simple not not Ricky
oh no simple stuff like this you can
with this reality go from Dwight sorry
so fresh you can go from your identity
to HDFS again
ETFs is the root user on the rooted for
system you can do everything you want on
the on the on the projector system with
that user we are not the variety find
out we just documented the exploit as no
stuff has been published even even if I
do be fully open source some demo time I
just show you to say that we are not
bullshitting you
[Music]
so I'm just trying to put a file you
know into a session P to see that which
is alright executing this and now if I
can just yes I mean ahem HDFS so I moved
from Toto standard user with no
privileges to HDFS with this is the
relative how you can expect it how how
bad is it the prerequisite for Baku city
is that the shape based unique group map
in should be used this is not the
default value and we are not expecting
to find much cluster with it again some
figures from ours to differ on the
internet you can see in purple a mini
cluster now you have some room on cert
party modules even security modules
Apache Ranger you can see a nice
inscription so you can you can use to
stuff dump use our credential but they
are ash that's not pretty much not
interesting and all better don't use up
session cookies and reuse them that's
easy you don't have to crack anything
remember that rendre is the security
module and there is a sequel nutrition
on the login guess we already talked
about before on the cloud there are you
which which is often installed on the
edge node which is accessible by every
user that we showed this game before and
there is a vulnerability which is that
the you dot ini' configuration file is
really evolved for owner 21 so you can
just steal the the credential of the
database and then still the cookie on
the under the debate that we show we
have the session cookie we can just take
it and reuse it in order to access the
the administration interface of you and
the mitigation is to unset the
permission of
not more importantly not to me no you
because this isn't a web application you
don't have to deploy a web application
on the nation not because an attorney is
like a client you know deported client
and you don't have to install what
application on the side of an edge no
that's that's a bad design but we've
been we now have the region it was not
really here for us but now it's clear
do not study anything except I do
clients I do p FS - FS or whatever no
other application and in the end our
maybe last but not least high technical
high skilled attack our most elite
attack is is that for generalize cluster
that come on tries to find any key tab
accessible on repos read further story
and in real life it give you that kind
of results you from we developed a
slight theory where prills
scientist in a grey box attack with only
one profile accessing an edge node or
server with a simple profile no
privileges
just with this command you will collect
and you will be able to access 80% of
the of the data leg because of because
people misuse it as their you know what
what is that don't know that key tabs is
all pretty much the time that a password
so that they just told the file with
read further refer the rights and so as
a defender please put in place some
detection measure not just to see if
there are some key tabs accessible to 21
that's the really a strong measure again
this beside the simple notification just
put put in place some significant bit
acute control because people will do and
will misuse kidnapped no read falls off
it so now if you also want to start
inching forward venerate is with us
get on the boat with us and as steady
and you could be a challenge use a
prepackaged of our not which is really
easy to install eases the standalone new
virtual machine as you the demo we
perform are in standard machine
get on the boat with us try to find some
stuff and make the big thing
upon to falsify double security
everything we we printed today
everything every room every stuff are
published okay two minutes are published
on our github please
we are already eager for some feedback
and some contribution please now taking
a step back that you can see that this
security maturity of the of that
ecosystem a'dope is not a technology
built upon security no encryption by
default no the real application by
default then you have a fragmented
ecosystem Apache Avenger is not is only
accessible and package for often works
best on one stuff there's a lot of image
immaturity in secure development you
have a lot of classical veneer it is
even for security modules and you have a
complex a personal security because
people will misuse Cameras Cameras file
so some simple recommendation so first
and most important carry out your
cluster because like we showed you if
you don't carry out the cluster you will
have no security on your Kerberos
cluster then reduce the service
exposition we have seen that the survey
the services are very very variable
there I suppose sensitive information
and so the two data so you have to
reduce the exposition then don't give a
free shell if data scientist does not
have the rights to to launch your yuen
yuen job do not allow us to do it then
deploy the application do not deploy
application on edge not for example you
that you have see it's affected by
vulnerability then try to prevent and
detect the misuse of Kerberos
key tab it's very important because we
have see a lot of cluster paralyzed but
with lots of key tabs available for for
everyone and then try to harden it's I
think the most difficult recommendation
try to harden component and try to keep
up to date your cluster it will be a
challenge to keep up to date because
it's a
it's a big issue but you have to you
have to do it so thank you that's that's
all for us for thank you for being here
what is it eight to give us your
feedback and continues the description
and started institution on schedule good
car and thank you
[Applause]