so good afternoon good evening thank you
everyone for coming out for our last
hour of content this is going to be an
exciting hour we have had some
phenomenal recruiters who have given up
their time flown in from the east coast
to give resume review and career
mentoring but these are also friends of
mine that I've worked with for 10 15
years other than the guy on the end I've
only known him for two years
but these guys really want to help you
figure out what you need to know about
hacking the hiring process really sort
of breaking it down and saying screw it
I'm frustrated what can I do next so I
would like to introduce my dear friend
Pete Radloff take it away Thanks
how's everybody doing oh that's a very
good like response for 5:30 at night I
appreciate that it's probably way better
than like the 2:30 slot where everybody
is comatose from lunch so we're gonna
walk through a lot of things like
Kathleen said today and some of that's
going to start with some pointed
questions for you guys as well because
we really want to get a better sense of
you know where the pain is from your end
and they're really deal to partly that
it's an insight from from RN so just to
give some quick intros I'm Pete Radloff
I'm the principal technical recruiter
for comScore we're a consumer behavior
analytics firm based out of Reston
Virginia I've been there probably eight
out of the last twelve years or so Steve
I don't work in comScore I'm Steve Levy
I'm an engineer crossed over to the dark
side the dark side being HR and
recruiting you see these are my HR
tattoos in case you weren't they are
been recruiting for damn near 30 years
now and I have my own consulting firm
and one of my clients is actually
Lockheed Martin so there's a shitload
happening in the cyber hiring space
there and by the way this session is
sponsored by Red Bull cuz we're all
freaking tired right yeah this on hi I'm
Kirsten Renner I am the director of
recruiting at Nevada
they are complex analytics firm in
Northern Virginia and gosh I've been
doing this recruiting thing for
20-something years so and she's only 29
and yeah I started when I was 9 years
old
obviously mommy daddy I want to recruit
people yeah and so my favorite part of
summer camp is the car hacking village
that will be happening at DEFCON if
you're going to DEFCON stop by and see
me I'll be the one selling badges and or
I'll be the wine the now we're into it
saying sorry we got sold out of badges
already and for giving away a truck hey
there so I'm Chris rides I've got a
company called tyro security we were an
information security staffing company
and also a professional services company
based out of Los Angeles started it five
years ago and I've been in the business
for 20 years and this third year
speaking here so looking forward to it's
always always interesting with getting
some interesting questions so one of the
things that we wanted to start off with
initially is is to really get your
perspective on something so and free
form show of hands scream it out what
frustrates you about working with
recruiters okay great they don't
understand technology great yep a number
of seem to have a high sleaze factor
snow to Eskimos the Flies okay so
you doing your own recording okay and
these are your in-house recruiters okay
do I think we we see a lot of that
frustration from the candidate side of
things right and I and I think we
realize that there's a lot more that
happens behind the scenes that I think
what you realize the way and somebody
clicks apply right now no way it means
or shape justifying
the resume black hole that a lot of
things seem to go into you put it in
there you never hear back you get an
email other positions close but you've
never heard anything you know one way or
the other around the feedback of your
interview why you didn't get the job
what you could have done better
etc and I think one of the things that
we believe in and please everybody
correct me if I'm wrong here that that
feedback is is important it's important
for us to make sure that we're giving
that feedback now because we live in an
incredibly litigious society that
becomes a little bit hairy sometimes but
it is something that we feel has to
really be part of the process in order
to make it a higher right we want to
make a good hire we're gonna make a
strong hire we want you coming in the
door feeling that you've been able to
make the right decision for your career
when you guys think about this and
particularly looking at the InfoSec
portion of things what's what do you
what is important to you all as
recruiters people who are looking at
these backgrounds is it certifications
is it training is it a very nebulous to
have a passion that you can't put to
paper what are you guys what's important
to all of you when you look at these
backgrounds so the talk that happened a
little bit ago to talks ago one of the
pieces of advice that's very important
was they were saying that the recruiter
needs to make a connection and talk to
the individual about themselves right so
it goes it goes both ways so that the
standout the connection should be there
should be some one piece where where you
connect where you relate I'm going to
tell you I haven't I haven't actually
directly recruited in awhile but one of
the things I was horrible at was looking
at the applications
isn't that awful was the last place I
would look you would think there would
be the first place I would look but
truly so many of the applicants that
applied for the positions weren't
qualified so often so that that would be
the last place I would look isn't that
awful so the same way the recruiters are
reaching out to you and your systems
engineer and they're asking you if you
want to be a Java program and that's
Trading is hell right it happened 10
times today the connection isn't
happening on both sides is part of the
problem so I think that one of the best
things that they said earlier was do the
Kevin Bacon thing right there's this is
a really small community and everyone
that you know there's only a few
connections away from somebody else that
you know start with talking to someone
in your community that had a good
recruiting experience that's going to be
rare and when you reach out to that
recruiter and say I got your name
recruiter Jim from my colleague they're
gonna pay more attention to you they're
gonna remember you because it started
through a genuine relationship does that
make sense so you're not just another
applicant anymore and they're not just
another recruiter anymore and you just
started a valid relationship and I think
it's gonna be it's gonna be a lot more
fruitful for both of you nothing that
will help this lady mentioned recruit is
not knowing what they're talking about
and there are plenty of those and the
sleaze factor comes into that because
they their way through what
they're doing right and very quickly you
get to tell that so if you want to find
a good recruiter you need to go where
you'd expect the real recruiters to be
so you go to your Issa meetings go to
your wife's meetings yeah go to cloud
Security Alliance meetings because first
off a majority of the ones going there
are doing out their own time right
they're not getting paid to do it so
they're passionate about what they're
doing they're willing to spend their own
time understanding and learning about
what we do and it's surprising how much
you can actually gain that's a great
place to actually find the people that
that kind of you know know what they're
talking about
and I will also say when I'm hiring for
and I run an external agency so when I'm
hiring for people I don't tend to look
for people necessarily with technical
experience in fact in my experience it's
not been a great way to recruit people
that's not to say they're on amazing
people you know including up here that
have been been excellent but sometimes
when people have a technical background
they feel like they can question
people that are coming into the level of
somebody that you know you're talking
something that's got eight years
experience and you know you've studied
cybersecurity and you think that you can
have a level conversation in it you end
up going too far down that road so I
think having a knowledge about
recruitment and gaining it from those
sort of places will certainly help them
have those conversations with you but
you know don't expect them to know that
as much as you guys do because they
won't there are some fundamental
problems with recruiting now every
recruiting is not recruiting is not
broken you know just like if the problem
is the we have this barrier to entry
problem there's very little barrier to
entry to become a recruiter you know in
fact that's how you know many folks have
started on the agency side you know
their first jobs were here's a phonebook
or here's a list it's on the on the
computer when I started they were phone
books in three by five cards and you
know well well actually less than 1200
baud dial-up it's another story but the
problem is that you know an empty to
your point in the fact that you're
better than your recruiters at
recruiting people there is a point in my
opinion where all this stuff could
really get a heck of a lot better and it
would sit and and you folks are part of
the solution we hire people to solve
specific problems in your case you know
you might have specific you know cyber
challenges related to product related to
customers you know you have you know you
have you know some sort of architecture
drawing and you know there are X's where
the you know red X is where there are
issues there we solve we hire people to
solve problems we don't hire people to
simply be task Wranglers you know in
most every job description that you see
every job description by companies that
are exhibiting here they're not
recruiting documents they don't give you
any insight into what specific problems
keep the hiring manager awake at night
now you know what you I don't know your
name
and I should clairvoyantly know that but
they don't Jamison a very very good name
for several reasons but Jamison you know
when and and I'm gonna have a little
conversation with him and it may help
when you have an open job you know you
you meet with a recruiter your
recruiters and they say well what's
really special what do they really need
what are the must-haves things of that
nature
do they ever ask you what specific
problems are not getting done by the
existing staff and and what specific
things would a what specific problem if
they were solved by the new person would
allow you to sleep at night what they
don't go to that and what you would
typically they'll say you you may say
well it's in the Job Description or out
so many more resumes all know it when I
see it it doesn't work like that I want
to know specifically this is the current
situation the current state this is the
problem this is the desired outcome and
this is how I think we're going to get
there I think it behooves you as as
folks looking for jobs to press the
recruiter whoever reaches out to you you
know if you see something posted don't
just blindly apply to it knowing that
it's a generic Job Description
again every company here most every
company here if I take their name out of
the jump owes to job description and
they put in one of their competitors
that JD job description will be just as
valid for those companies you're trying
to read minds of companies instead of
directly applying maybe paying the right
back you know find out you know
Jameson's email you know because he's a
popular fellow you can find his email
and if he has a job listed ask him you
know in the first 90 to 180 days what
specific problems will I be specifically
will I be asked to solve what are the
deliverables you know be be more active
in that and don't take from a crappy
recruiter well just SEM your resume
we'll talk about it be you know an
educated consumer and push back on just
not really
I think that's a good look that's
actually if that's a great point and and
and actually managers line managers and
hiring managers are much more likely to
do that when it's a contract position
they're much more like to give you more
information on the projects you're doing
and stuff but then we need something
they turn to permanent that goes out the
window right yeah it's on your spec so
you don't yeah you're spot-on I mean
again it's it's about you know where
your expertise is you know what specific
problems you're really good at there's
nothing wrong with you when you see a
posted job instead of applying you know
try to you know instead of applying we
reply back with these are the kind of
problems I've solved these are kind of
things I'm doing right now is I can't
tell from your job description whether
it's there or not can you tell me if
these are the kind of things that you're
working on it's a good segue to because
I think when you look at that I think
the table turns as well too right so a
lot of times and I focused primarily on
infrastructure development and develop
DevOps so a lot of times what I find in
that interview process and this is
really with me right now I'm not an
engineer I'm not leaving went to the
dark side but I've spent almost 20 years
with engineers and sat there watching
them code asking questions and what does
that mean you know why are you doing
this and why do we do it this way and
that helps me to do my job a little bit
better when we get to the interview
stage and I find this more often with
technical people that non-technical
people they say tell me about your role
tell me about the stack and I want to
know what you do what I'm not looking
for with that is to just regurgitate the
bullet points what I want to know is
what did you work on that really changed
the game where you are today why where
what did you work on and have your
fingerprints on there that if they lost
you they wouldn't know what to do and
what makes you attractive to another
company and going into that detail and
understanding and quantifying right so
it go ahead and I do so when I talk to a
Java developer and he says where she
says yeah I went ahead and I patched up
some scripts so we got everything
running I'm like okay great what did
that mean for you well it meant we went
from three hours of data processing time
to 86 seconds and that's what I want to
know that's what I want to know the
tangible impact
of where that is and I think a lot of
times people get so worried that they
need to spit out all their key words and
all their skill sets in this 20 minute
conversation that they're gonna have
with the recruiter where that'll get
fleshed out the next call I'm okay with
that that'll get fleshed out in the next
call what I want to know is if you could
talk about business problems and you can
tell me how you solve them what the
impact is for your company or for your
client while you're doing that the word
the word apiece referring to its legacy
you know what's your legacy and you know
at your current you know if you were to
leave your current job now or your past
job what do they remember you most from
what did you what did he give to the you
know to the to the group that they
realize in hindsight was pretty damn
good what about those interviews are
there other fo PA's or mistakes that you
see people making interviews that are
that are pretty avoidable so good so by
the way I would like to see the
conversation shift and be less about the
position and more about the candidate
and have it be more about their
experience the more you learn about the
person you manned up because I'm
guessing every company that every one of
you works for and that we all work for
has more than one position available and
more than one type of job that people
are doing there so just because you're
over here doing X Y widgets doesn't mean
that you're not capable of doing a whole
other thing right and in addition to
what did you do and did you take it from
three hours down to 86 seconds what did
you what instead of just always
mentioning to me the things that you did
these tangible good measurable things
that you did what did you what did you
mess up that what did you break what did
you fail at and what did you learn from
it that conversation and by the way I
steal that from an interview I did a
million years ago at RIT with some kid
that was graduating and he was he was
literally only 17 years old genius
person but he said oh I all there was
this robot and he built a robot and it's
a really long story and it's amazing in
this interesting and the robot blew up
he was trying to get it across the
street and then we talked about what did
he learn from that
so I'm guessing that a he always has a
fire extinguisher handy now right and
then none of his robots are blowing up
anymore so he actually invited me into a
whole different part of his
problem-solving skills and and just a
whole level of humility from this this
person that's always had like a
five-point whatever right he because he
failed he blew the robot up so so so
talk to the individuals about their
experiences about their work experiences
about the things that they learned and
how they learned them because you're
gonna end up finding out you know what
that person would work perfectly on bla
bla bla team so so the recruiter
shouldn't make it about the job never
ever they should make it about the
candidate and in some of the best
recruiters and there's there's people in
the room that have done this they're
gonna go you know what candidate I'm
listening to you I hear you
I want to hire you I can hire you but I
also know this guy named Peter who has a
who has an environment that sounds like
it's going to be a lot better for you
and then we just established another
important relationship right and
candidates gonna remember that that
happened and I didn't feel my job I
didn't do my job to that I didn't fill
the position but I just did a good thing
so I I want the conversation to be less
about the job so you as the candidate
switch it around if the recruiter
stopped doing their job and making it
about you there's a round thing for me
Oh even better
I got an upgrade so from the candidate
point of view to switch it around how
can how can we ferret out the good
recruiters from the bad and I actually
recently had a very long and significant
amount of time wasted by recruiter and
an actual end company they were
recruiting for so I think that's kind of
my questions is how can we get through
some of those key points that are
deal-breakers and not offend the
relationship and still hopefully keep it
open for the next job they have and keep
calling you know
calling you back I think there's there's
a couple things there right I'd never
get off the phone with a candidate
without asking them one question what's
most important in your next role what is
it is it growth is it money is this
stability so you're not going from
contract to contract to contract what is
that thing that you need most that you
can absolutely not take this job without
and I get a little pure into their
psyche I get to understand what family
life looks like for them I get to
understand if they're an early bird or
one of those people that's not going to
be scheduling any meetings before 10:00
a.m. get to understand a lot a bunch of
those things that I think are really
important for that the second thing is
test them if they say I'll give you an
update on Tuesday and it's Thursday and
you haven't heard anything not your
answer
I know update I have no update for you
is still an update you know that you're
still top of my mind and you are still
important to me and I'm working on it
but I just need to tell you any other
more time if you're not getting that
level of concentrated commitment then I
think you can kick that recruiter to the
curb sure why not sure what yeah
absolutely and I tell them look
sometimes I get slammed her in the day
and if you don't hear from me by Tuesday
call me and I'll get back to you I'll
double down on that one it's I'll give
people my phone number I said look I
hope to call you with an update by
so-and-so but just like Pete I am
swamped every which way to Sunday and if
you don't hear from me by a certain time
call me or text me if you know what your
deal-breakers are there's nothing wrong
with presenting those right up front to
your recruiter and saying you know that
this this is this is what my situation
is right now it does not necessarily
mean that all of these things will be
deal-breakers for me in the future but
right now this is where we're at and you
know if that's not going to fit their
role
you're not wasting their time you're not
wasting yours you know you said that you
hold a well there's your answer yeah I
mean if it doesn't fit what you're
looking for right now you know if the
other thing you mentioned you said the
the recruiter in the ultimate end client
say were you dealing with an agency yeah
tell me if you guys agree with this but
leverage Glassdoor to your advantage if
you're having a really shitty experience
with a recruiter
let that company know I respond
personally to all of the Glassdoor
reviews for my company and it crushes my
soul some days but hell if I don't have
a dummy email that we set up for the
company that somebody need to get more
specific information from somebody about
a crappy experience they had here's an
email address you can reach me at
directly really quickly if you only
remember one thing I ever said remember
that the recruiter that you're talking
to they want it to work right they want
this to be successful right so they're
already on your side
they are your advocate so so make them
your best advocate because you're the
champion of you because nobody knows
what you want better than you do if
you're not telling me the right story
I'm not selling you the way you need to
be sold so said this some somebody
earlier so you've done this and you've
done this and you've done this and
you've done this so if I take away the
wrong story from either what you told me
because you think I wanted you to hear
and that's what you think that's what I
wanted to hear or don't do that just be
the true you because if you pretend to
be whoever the recruiter wants you to be
and I and I'm sorry I apologize on
behalf of every recruiter that sucks
that you have to get through to get to
whoever else the next person is but if
you sell the wrong thing that then you
are gonna get fit into the right to the
wrong spot right so you're not doing
you're doing yourself an injustice beat
be who you truly are
say the types of environments you enjoy
working in and recruit the recruiter a
little bit right interview them talk to
them ask them to tell you stories actual
stories recruiters like to talk have you
ever noticed we like to talk make them
tell you a story about the environment
about the problems about the tell to
make them tell you good things and bad
things let me go back one more thing cuz
we talked earlier this is how you know
the fakers the pretenders from the real
recruiters the real recruiters know what
you what the job truly entails if they
go back to the JD the job descriptions
are saying this is the real job they
either don't know what the real job is
or they're just making up as they
go on
real good recruiters will know what the
deliverables are for this position
within a reasonable timeframe and if
they don't then they're merely assessing
you for the presence of buzzwords cuz
how about you from the agency side you
see a whole different perspective of
this and much to your point it's
different working with an agency
recruiter that it can be with corporate
sometimes yeah it definitely is because
we we looking at a broad range of
clients a broad range of jobs and but
actually there's a lot you know the
similarities are the same if you're
never honest with them about what you're
looking for the in yet matched up with
things that you're not interested in and
there's nothing more frustrating for you
and getting phone calls about jobs that
you're not interested in right so
absolutely been completely honest and
open and I know you know you'll read a
lot of articles about not telling your
recruiter about this holding it back
until the end we're there to try and get
you the job if you hold anything back to
the end there the surprise is that that
don't get solved right then you get the
job offer you're not looking for or
expecting so I would definitely say that
keeping open and honest and and
answering all of the questions honestly
it's going to get you much nearer to the
job that you're looking for I think from
an agency other than that we're looking
at multiple clients so we're trying to
assess
from the business site what they're
looking for and getting them to sell
each of that companies sort of big
points and actually one of the most
frustrating things for us is not getting
to speak to the person that put the jobs
back together and getting to ask those
questions which are really the questions
that we need to know if we're going to
fill that position and I will say that
often by the time we get the role we can
get positions that have been open for
six months we filled one we filled one
three weeks ago that was open for almost
nine months before they came to us and
we filled it in three weeks and we just
spoke to the line manager and the line
manager had a similar story to Jameson
in that internally they hadn't had the
conversation and the questions that I
asked weren't the same questions that
they're internally what we're asking
and we found candidates a completely
different pool of candidates when they
haven't seen any resumes of about two
months by the way don't be afraid people
are scared of agency right and they say
it's real quick so there's a difference
between insert name of giant agency that
you've all heard of and working with
someone like this that actually is going
to understand what the customer needs
and care about you and they become your
agent so then I am coming to pay some
loose agent well you know that's you
know notice a wait wait yeah show me the
money absolutely there we go yeah in the
interest of keeping us on time for six
o'clock questions for us things we can
go ahead
[Music]
so for my past life I was a hiring
manager at a large corporate and I spent
a lot of my time going around recruiting
whenever I possibly could and I'm just
wondering you know and though how how
could it you know that I could never
find a way to work effectively with
recruiters because what I would do is
you know they've come to me and want a
job description and so what you do is
you throw white you know a little bit of
everything in IT in there because that's
essentially what the position entails
and somehow lost in the translation the
nice-to-haves get turned into hard
requirements and then you end up with a
whole bunch of resumes from people who
are either lying about having every
certificate Under the Sun which I don't
even care about anyway or you end up
with you know no resumes at all
so I usually end up just kind of working
my network and you know the best way to
get to me as a hiring manager was a
direct referral by either another
manager at the company or by somebody
who you know who is in my professional
network but I feel like I was doing it
wrong you know I think that probably I
could have done better at this if you're
a hiring manager how do you not suck at
working with recruiters oh boy you know
it's you know exactly where to go with
this you know first and foremost I sort
of have to ask it this way anyone here
who here is married okay okay so no
specially we'll talk to the hiring
manager there is Mary
Jameson but you know when you were first
dating you sort of you kind of felt you
got to know each other and you found
better ways to know each other get along
with each other then you get married and
then it starts all over again yes the
toilet seat problems and things like
that you will learn how to get along
with recruiters by being calexis
collectively committed to the same goal
so the part of the problem with the
hiring managers don't have these
conversations with recruiters and
recruiters don't have these
conversations with hiring managers
generally speaking
like I would come up to you say how do
you like to be how would you like us to
work with you a simple conversation like
that recruiter should say the same thing
well then III I'm not gonna apologize
the entire profession because he's not
working with the partner RT if you know
asking that question then you know the
ones to work yeah you have that's if
you're not getting what you want you
know how you like to be how you like
people to work with you that's on you
yeah it's completely on you to say this
is what I need how you to help me get
there you know and it's up to them to
ask those questions right rather
regardless of whether or not I filled
one position with this manager or a
hundred and one positions I need 30
minutes of your time so we could talk
about it because whatever you guys were
doing in that group six months ago you
sure as different now so let's go
back and if everything else is the same
but the projects you're working on and
what's coming up in the next 6 to 18
months is different let's talk about
that because that's different things I
can sell those are the different things
that I could pitch is to somebody who
okay great we're gonna be moving in the
cloud awesome
you want to get involved with AWS you
can come into this project here I now
know that that's where we're headed and
we don't need that skill set necessarily
but boy if we had it that would be great
and that's not on a job description and
you need to spend 30 minutes with me
just give me the information I need and
then we can switch things on the fly
later on if we need to we could pivot
because inside in that through in that
30-minute intake session which I mean I
even call it a strategy session because
it implies an ongoing discussion with
the hiring manager this is the stuff
that happens behind the scenes like I'll
share with is I met you were hiring
management if anybody here is a hiring
manager Niro was one I'll share with you
my strategy session form so you can see
the questions that I ask of the hiring
manager so you can see how they're very
focused on performance on future
strategies on deliverables not just
tasks and in the presence or absence of
skills you know being you know I want
someone who's detail-oriented that's not
a deliverable
that's a subjective assessment of
somebody so it's income this the system
isn't broken it's it's it you all need
like marriage counseling so I think
we're almost out of time but it goes
both ways and two things that are really
helpful if you let the recruiter sit in
one of your technical interviews they're
gonna listen to you ask questions
they're gonna listen to the answers and
they're gonna learn and then if you will
give them two or three knockout
questions to include in their pre-screen
when they first talk to say they've
never even they don't even have a spell
job all right that's how technical your
recruiter is but they're gonna get on
the phone call and they're and they're
gonna say they're gonna ask twenty
people today with what it's
encapsulation and what is polymorphism
and Liuba at the end of the day your
recruiter is gonna know how to pass a
java interview because they're gonna
understand because you're gonna include
them a little bit more in the technical
and they're gonna learn so you know I'd
like to see what why this is important
when you go on interviews when you
actually get to get fit on-site face to
face ask people for a white ask the
managers the inner door the recruiters
for a white board and white board your
environment white board you know the you
know and put X's where you were and and
draw out this was the problem this was a
solution stand up don't just use your
words be an active participant in that
right Tim yeah you just remember code is
way more fun than sales quotas
substantially so let's thank my dear
friend Steve Pete Kirsten and Chris for
giving us their advice back incidentally
if you want to find out more how to work
better with recruiters there's nothing
wrong wrong with reading the articles
that recruiters right there are there
are two of them some of them are pretty
good man some of the not all over ship
some of us really illiterate you know we
can spell cat sometimes but they're
there they're there they're there
there's there's a er me er II Mediacom
uh probably tweeted out into the thing
go to EP Mediacom there are blogs that
that recruiters write articles for and
there's another one called recruiting
daily.com
where Pete and I write crap there it's
not crap it's good
stuff but we tell you how stuff really
works we tell you what we like we tell
you what we dislike it's it's it's going
to help you and by the way nothing wrong
with for example on Facebook getting
into groups where recruiters hang out
and just saying hi I'm here help me and
we will promise you we really will so
let's thank Steve and Chris and Pete and
Kirsten