thank you so this is AI club and so can
you I'm Christopher Lamberson as I was
introduced quick talk about Who I am
I work two part-time information
security jobs and I also study at a
Columbus Georgia based university more
importantly for this talk I'm also
president and founder of the
university's collegiate Information
Security Club black box society so what
is this talk about first is about why
you should start an information security
Club lessons learned from my struggles
and successes things I've seen work at
other clubs and I'll provide a brief
information security Club starter guide
I want to emphasize that this talk is
not just for collegiate clubs but I try
to frame the advice and insights in such
a way that they would be applicable to a
more general group or a professional
organization or a collegiate organizing
if you want to go that route real quick
when I refer to an information security
club in the most general sense that is
just a gathering of people who want to
get together to do something information
security related the real goal here is
that people will come here hear this
talk or see it later on YouTube take the
knowledge learned and start their own
information security Club alternatively
if clubs already exists in your home
town or city hopefully this will inspire
you to take a look around and become
involved otherwise you're already
involved in which case keep being
awesome so why start an information
security Club your reasons basically
boiled down to helping others or helping
yourself you can help others and the old
fond of fantasy games the white mage was
the healer you will be supporting your
group like the white mage would support
the party you can be the change you want
to see in the world in that if you want
to see more people well versed in the
OWASP jinn your group can have a webapp
focus and your audience could be
professionals already working in the
field you can also attract newcomers to
the field
and get them started on the right foot
you can also take a stab at shrinking
the phone-sex skill gap that currently
exists alternately you can be helping
yourself one of the best ways to learn
any subject or topic is by teaching it
to others studies have shown this so if
you wanted to learn web app security
spin up a lab read some books but then
go and do a tutorial or workshop or our
talk about web app security to help
cement your knowledge and ensure that
you know the subject matter also you'll
be growing your pool of contacts and
connections which you can call upon in
the future when you're networking or
trying to move into a new position you
can also group up for competitions
expect your group has a competition
focused win some money have a lot of fun
maybe a little background I come from a
smaller city which when I started
creating my information security Club
had no vibrant information security
scene that I could think of or assault
you see at the time and I really think
it's important that if you don't live in
a big city to still be involved and
cultivate a community around you and
improve yourself and the InfoSec
community at large
so I Club experiences I actually founded
two clubs one that kind of morphed into
the other the first one was the computer
security special interest group or cops
X cig blackbox Society or BBS
I've also checked out Def Con group DC
404 in Atlanta and the information
systems security Association Columbus
Georgia chapter I included my what I've
seen those groups do the good things
they do to give this talking more
rounded presentations so again it is not
just aimed at collegiate groups so I
started with a computer security special
winter
we had some good successes we grew the
group from pretty much just me and a
couple of friends to a mailing list of
something like 32 to 36 people we
produced the university's first
competitive capture the flag team to
actually place in the collegiate level
competition that I am aware of but it
wasn't all great and I picked up a lot
of lessons learned from the experience
first of all the organization was
created as a special interest group
under my University's Association for
Computing Machinery or ACM my thought
process was well now I don't have to
deal with paperwork or any bureaucracy I
can just offload it to ACF when in fact
I just added another level bureaucracy
that I would have to deal with when
reserving rooms for meetings or trying
to request or request funding also since
the organization is a flat structure all
of the workload kind of fell on my
shoulders there weren't other people
with other responsibilities that could
help me in a lot of things which was a
struggle which we would solve with the
black box ascites so with the black box
society we went to the university we
formed the organization as an official
organization we had a structure officers
someone to handle reserving a room
someone to handle social media and
websites that we run so I want to handle
all the money so we distributed the
workload everything with a lot smoother
since we were also an official
organization we could take advantage of
the social media platform that the
university provides for all registered
student organizations we can also
schedule rooms and have regular meeting
times and places the organization is
still not as good as I think it can be
one of the key areas where we should
improve I think is more community
involvement more members
and attendees doing presentations and
I've seen other clubs do that we'll talk
about it it's really great and it's
something I want to try to emulate and I
think you should emulate in your
information security club when you go
home and found one so a good thing of
seeing that these other clubs at DC 404
new attendees get attention they have a
brief moment at the beginning of every
meeting where new members are asked who
they are to introduce themself
yeah it helps to me it helps them to
mingle attendees do most of the
presentations that I've seen there's not
an official talk guy and that's
excellent that's something you should
try to get done in your organization
probably the coolest thing they do is
they always have background events like
a network king of a hill CTF competition
or a lock-picking village as for the ISS
a Columbus Georgia chapter they have a
more well respected and prestigious name
attached to them as far as companies go
in the eyes of companies which means
they have better backing they can
usually get better venues for their
meetings and sometimes get their
meetings catered so the overall
takeaways from the real-world experience
I've had and the things I've seen from
other clubs distribute the workload have
a structure to take care of any
budgeting you need to do if you want to
go on trips you may want to consider
membership dues sponsorships bake sales
you know the usual have a consistent
meeting time in place this helps others
to schedule around you and to make sure
that they can be there for your meeting
communicate well have a well known means
of communication whether it be a mailing
list the IRC IRC channel or social media
such as like meetup maybe so information
security clubs starter guide first thing
you need to do is decide whether you
want to bootstrap your own organization
or branch off from an existing
organization there are pros and cons
each this talk will be mostly concerned
with bootstrapping your own organization
the second thing you want to do is have
a look around your local area maybe a
group already exists that does all the
things you want to do and all you'd be
doing is kind of adding to the noise by
starting your own Club that just a proxy
for the other and always always keep
your audience in mind through the entire
process since social essence clubs are a
social thing you probably already have
your audience in mind the second thing
you really need start thinking about is
logistics
you want to consider a location how are
you going to advertise and how are you
going to communicate with your location
I've seen organizations use University
classrooms corporate meeting rooms
restaurants cafes and pubs in the dual
Tetris picture sometimes it won't be so
obvious what you're the best location is
the key things you're going to need are
probably a projector depending on what
kind of meetings you're going to be
having it needs to let you get loud
enough to have a meeting and it needs to
be court and let you get quiet enough to
have one-on-one conversations between
other people some other nice things to
have are power strips lots of power
strips never you can never have enough
power strips and lots of different
adapters for different hookups if you're
using that projector I swear that was in
the talk the whole time so you want to
start thinking about advertising you it
could be as simple as putting up flyers
where smart people hang out using social
media such as meetup or working with
your parent org if you decided to go
that route meaning you start thinking
about communications how are you going
to keep in touch personally I usually
like mailing lists you may prefer social
media or IRC once you have all your
logistics figured out once you have
figured out where you're going to meet
when you're going to meet and how it's
going to go down you start thinking
about your first meeting because you go
back to considering your audience what
you should be doing all the time and for
simplicity's sake I've broken down
audience into students professional
in general secondly you may want to pick
an angle this probably should change at
least every other meaning to keep things
fresh but it can be something like in
these are just examples competition
preparation skill development networking
and career development so let's say you
have a club with a collegiate audience
with a competition focus a meeting you
may want to do is introduction the CTF
talking about the differences between
jeopardy style king of the hill attack
the fan maybe talk about other security
competitions like collegiate cyber
defense competitions stuff like that
alternatively if you have a more general
audience with a career development focus
as your first meeting you may want
talked about local tech companies what
they're looking for who they're hiring
for bonus points you need guest speaker
from one of those companies to come in
and hear it straight from the horse's
mouth we talked about spinning off your
own organization are spinning off of a
existing organization there are way too
many organization organizations that you
can spin off of to go over down this
talk but for example if you want to do a
Def Con group they have an FAQ if you
want to do an ISS a chapter they have a
startup kit if you do want to do a 2600
meeting they have guidelines
so in conclusion critical up just do it
it can be really easy it can be just it
can start off it's just a social get
together with you and your friends for
networking of a heel competition all you
need to do is have that room and time
ready invite people over and have that
first meeting in your mind I'm going to
take questions here shortly
but first I'd like to thank my proven
guy proving grounds mentor Rachel Rachel
Linenger all the black box Society
members and officers my academic mentor
dr. Beaucaire and all the computer
science faculty at CSU and a shout out
to DC for for and the columbus chapter
of the Issa for unknowingly contributing
to my talk
questions alright thank you very much