so I worked with Jay quite a bit he's
become one of my good friends in DC Trey
I'm new to knowing him but he's very
very smart on a lot of these issues
clearly Alex we work together I think
I've met you like five different times
from five different people pointing us
at each other right and Jessica flew all
this way just for a couple of days and
we actually thanks to besides Las Vegas
got besides to pay for her trip out here
as a congressional staffer which was not
easy because there's a lot of paperwork
that I had to do actually a.m. had to do
a lot of the paperwork somebody I work
with the Atlantic Council is here in the
room with this and I think it's in
pretty incredible thing that we were
able to have a crazy experiment like
getting policymakers and hackers in the
same room and hoping that they'd
spontaneously combust
which they didn't in for a couple of
days we've kind of secretly been been
nudging this track towards more broader
societal level public policy level of
conversations ending in this which was
this is almost identical to what you'll
see in an actual congressional hearing
down to the structure and format you
have ten days to submit your formal
response which is excellent this was
really a good mock congressional hearing
and if I could pull on some of the
themes from the last couple of days one
of the things that I was a little bit
concerned about coming into this is are
the beast' sites people are gonna tar
and feather me after this because I'm
directing this so much towards public
policy stuff and I think by virtue of
the fact that people sticking around the
number of you here as well as the
questions you're asking and the genuine
curiosity you're showing I think that
this experiment was a success in a lot
of different ways we also wanted to help
build capacities here and capacity
building as a DC
type term which basically means you make
people smarter who are interested and
you make more people interested and then
make them smarter so it's increasing the
number of people and the quality of the
interactions that you can have and I
think we did that in a number of ways
not just on public safety human life but
also on building bridges and in getting
involved in different with different
stakeholder types including public
policymakers and we wanted you to feel
empowered after having been here to take
some action that was maybe outside of
your technical wheelhouse and maybe
beyond your current comfort level but to
hopefully make it okay and let you
understand that you've got permission to
engage in some of these conversations
it's it's not the rest of society that's
holding us back
it's ourselves and giving ourselves
permission to engage in some of these
conversations is in some time in some
cases the only thing stopping us from
having a bigger broader impact beyond
our immediate spheres of influence and I
Josh I don't know if you have any
thoughts we're gonna kind of do the
wrap-up and then close a little bit
earlier by about ten minutes then we
thought we would so we'll let you guys
get on to the next thing very very
shortly
Josh key thoughts I'll just be short and
sweet and along two days hopefully
fulfilling two days but very back to the
beginning in the main room yesterday
things are getting pretty serious and
it's gonna take a lot more ideas in
innovation and an action than any one of
us could ever do on our own so I really
hope the theme of this year was shifting
from us being solo actors and taking it
on ourselves and seeing each other's
competition and more turning into not
just empowerment generally is a
platitude but look at the kind of ideas
that could come out today from having
the superpowers of someone from Congo
two superpowers of someone from FDA from
NTIA from DOJ it's not that we just want
to like be fanboys for the feds it's
that there are things that only they can
do and maybe the best way to summarize
here is uh you know Eli Sugarman at the
Hewlett Foundation has this great line
he says there's things the public sector
can't do and the private sector won't do
and that's the role of philanthropy and
Alturas and I think if we're gonna be
our best we need to do things like
you've experienced for last two days to
look for whatever contribution each of
you can make and force multiply it with
the contributions that different
teammates can make and I think the
reason this crazy experiment four years
in has been so successful is not because
we had experienced what we had heart we
had empathy we tried new things and we
did it together so if you have one
takeaway it's the safer sooner together
and I hope you take it back to your day
jobs this isn't something you do in
Vegas but it's something that lights a
fire here in Vegas and then we go find
out which Dragons we can kill together
next week so thank you for being here
for two days and give yourself a round
of applause you know some of these guys
are my heroes well now I have a few new
heroes to work with thank you
[Applause]