we're here talking about some work that
we did along with some other people on
measuring brain wallets so who in ah we
can go to the next slide I'm a newly
minted professor of computer science
university of new mexico just finish up
my PhD and a lot of this work was part
of my dissertation I discovered Bitcoin
back in 2011 and it's interested me ever
since I wrote my first Bitcoin papers in
2013 published in 2014
I'm also a con noob this is my first
hacker con
I'm Ryan Cataloochee I don't do Bitcoin
stuff professionally this is just one of
my weird hobbies I think somebody
described this is Orion tries to prevent
people from losing lots of Bitcoin and
generally this pisses them off so a from
a sexual job I do bought detection
research for Y tops and then Bitcoin I
have been messing around with since
early 2011 and I'm not sure how many
hacker cons I've been to at this point
but it's not your first so if we think
about how to securely do key generation
we could look at a scheme like RSA now a
bunch of really smart people have taken
a lot of years to write libraries in
order to generate really really big
random numbers with very special
properties these numbers have to go
through some approach X and then make
some calculations based on derived
values now Bitcoin uses another tick
curve key generation if you went to
Ryan's talk you know that what you have
to do is generate a random number
basically what it has to be is it has to
be 256 bits and it can't be 0 and it
can't be another number so this this key
generation process
can be fairly trivial now there are ways
of securely doing it
however if maybe you don't trust your
computer you don't trust the hardware
you don't trust the random number
algorithm that some person you've never
met wrote you could say hey why don't I
why on create my own system and why
don't we base it around something really
really secure I know how about passwords
and so what these people did is they use
this MIT really easy-to-use tool um you
just insert a password and the Bitcoin
private key is the hash of the password
now people have actually stored quite a
bit of money with these schemes and so
on the flipside so on one hand there's
these users that have lots of and secure
money stored and so naturally there's
this attacker ecosystem that evolved out
of that it's like a money pinata you
just have to guess the right password
all right I'm sure everybody who's seen
this comic before but this is this is
xkcd on passwords and the the passphrase
is that this this suggests using are
more secure than typical passwords but
um they are not secured against offline
attacks so one of the offline attacks
that I ran when trying to look at what
passwords people had used for brain
wallets was based on xkcd password
generation I found a couple xkc password
generator tools used their word lists
and generate a lot of passwords I think
it was a couple trillion so correct
horse battery staple was actually a
default password on brainwallet on org
which resulted in it getting you
mistakenly a lot and it was also
involved in some of the bitcoins spam
attacks that happened one of the ones
that I found that was more obscure was
expect-- pants size clue which actually
looks like it was a randomly generated
one that somebody genuinely thought
might be secure that one held 2.18
Bitcoin in it then there was earth air
fire water which is not random of course
and then deal iron science food that one
actually does seem random - although
it's and we had a few cents in it and
due to the transaction that created it
it looked like it had been made by
somebody who is just trying to put out
bait to see who would take them we also
identified a large group of brain
wallets that were created in August of
2014 all of them were extremely simple
single word passwords there were about
15,000 and something of them all created
within the span of a few hours and all
of them had only tiny fractions of a
penny worth of Bitcoin in them so we're
we've excluded those from analysis
because they're not interesting and as
far as other things try it
as I mentioned xkcd style up to four
words for four words I had to trim down
the word list size just a little bit so
I picked words that were common between
the three tools that I found but for
three words I combined all of the lists
and use all of the words and got some
hits there as well
cryptocurrency IRC chat logs were
sourced from my computer I've been
sitting on a bunch of cryptocurrency
channels on freenode
for a good six years and I just
the mall in his past phrases that got
some weird hits like somebody had used
was it there's a Bitcoin
over-the-counter trading channel and
there's a bot you can authenticate
against and somebody used an
authentication string that was posted in
the channel to authenticate to the bot
as a brainwallet password again this is
that was probably somebody just doing
that to see how long it would take
then there's a data set of reddit
comments that is available online
it's got comments for basically every
every subreddit since the beginning of
redmond except for a few some comments
have been deleted in there but mostly
it's complete
that was that was processed mostly to
strip the markdown punctuation that
reddit allows and do some other minor
cleanup wikiquote I scraped and turns
that into a phrase list Wikipedia the
Wikipedia list I used as far as I can
tell was included with ocl hash cat at
some point that was the list that I
found the how much wood could a
woodchuck chuck if a woodchuck could
chuck wood brain Walla that had 250
bitcoins in it and I tracked the guy
down and he moved he moved the Bitcoin
out of that wallet was very appreciative
brainy quote is another site I scraped
basic normalization Facebook names came
from Skull securities lifts ribbon
dictionary I scraped and then I
purchased a song lyrics database that
was fairly recent and that was where I
got that data I would cited phrases I I
think these lists should be familiar to
a lot of people the rock you list is of
course obligatory crack station has a
good list there's one put up egg a guy
who goes by
éxito I don't know if I'm pronouncing
his handle correctly but it is very
large I think it's about 40 gigabytes
uncompressed and full of kind of garbage
so I clean that up yeah and got it down
to about 4 gigs but originally it had
for example every 5 letter asked there 5
character ASCII string in there using
printable characters and then having
them and no list is not super helpful
uniq passes a commercial list that you
can get fairly cheaply I have a couple
different versions of it because they
update it I think quarterly and school
security as I mentioned I used that all
of their lists and I did a bunch of
brute-forcing
every ASCII printable ASCII up to 6
characters
lowercase letters up to I believe 8
numbers up to 10 or 11 I think it was 11
and this was all done on AWS
so so the AWS setup there's an NFS
server that hosted all of the data files
needed to feed the cracker all the
software was on there and output was
written there two directories named by
job ID so they wouldn't overwrite each
other and so that was non the man
instance and then they used a bunch of
spot instances for the actual compute if
you're not familiar with AWS spot
instances are a way for Amazon to sell
capacity that they otherwise would not
sell by letting people bid on it so if
you want to do a bunch of compute and
nobody's willing to pay full price for
certain type of instance at that
particular time Amazon will let you do
it let you use it for a steep discount
the instance types I use typically you
get an 80
90% discount by tina this way the caveat
is if anybody else wants to spend more
money than you your instances go down
with two minutes of warning so it's good
for certain kinds of workloads where you
can split the work up and keep track of
what you've processed and restart redo
redo interrupted work it would not be a
great way to run a web server for
example so this with a bunch of spot
instances I had to have some way to
distribute jobs so Amazon has something
called simple queue service and what
simple queue service does is you set
this up you set parameters like whether
you want exactly once to delivery
first-in first-out how long whether you
want the messages to be resent to a
worker if a worker doesn't confirm that
it has finished processing by deleting
their mess their job and they have nice
Python libraries for interacting with
that so that's what I did I wrote a
Python script that added jobs to a queue
and then a script that ran jobs from the
queue by executing them directly which
is completely insecure but yeah it's
it's my job queue and then one copy of
the script run for virtual core so
here's here's what accessing the sqs api
looks like credentials removed for
obvious reasons just a couple lines of
code to set it up then to read the job
queue I have it get one message function
calls receive messages maximum one
really straightforward and then to
actually run the jobs there's just a
pretty simple loop and all of this is
started up using the cloud init
functionality that most AWS instances
have and the
this is when you start it up you can say
okay I want 30 machines and they should
all run this shell script when they
start up so the shell script will have
them mount the NFS files or Melfi em in
NFS file system execute the job runner
script and anything else you want to do
like like even you can install updates
or whatever and let's look at some
example cracking jobs so the applicant
utilities are fantastic for all of the
pieces that I don't want to implement
myself as far as password Canada
generation goes so this first one is
using a tool from hepcat called NASA
processor and what that does is it just
generates passwords based on a mask this
is some specific ASCII characters
followed by its like yeah for lowercase
letters so yeah so it will go right
through all of the possible ones and the
reason it's picking out specific
characters is because there will be I
had a couple thousand of these running
with different first characters and they
all wrote two outputs which were then
merged at the end then Combinator 3 is
another tool that I was using to do the
sum of the XK CDs passwords had to split
this up into a bunch of sub lists as a
way to divide up the work but what this
tool does is it you give it three input
files it takes the data from each file
and outputs every combination one
standard out so anything that can read
from standard in on standard i/o can use
this as input for cracking so this is I
don't know how many of those jobs total
there where this looks like it was job
um other shell shenanigans this is going
through the skull security word lists
that I had picking out the dot txt files
removing the redundant versions removing
RockYou because they did other things
with rocky and then passing it through
through can to combine them all together
and stripping out da style new liens
because da style new lines are no fun
this used a feature in brain flare where
it will start in this example start at
the fifth password given and then only
process every sixteenth final example is
just the hash tag by taking in a
combination of rock you myspace and
Linkedin and running in this example the
leet-speak
role set on it and passing it in for
drain blair and the shell script is is a
really simple thing it just has common
parameters pre-loaded so that i didn't
have to put any of your job one of the
interesting things I learned the my
first attempts of distribute data files
was to put them in an EDF snapshot which
is I think stands for elastic block
store lots of three-letter acronyms on
AWS
so that was incredibly slow it turns out
that the first time you access a block
in one of those it has to fetch it from
s3 and it goes somewhere so this was
just unbearably slow so I went with NFS
instead which still takes a long time
because it has to copy bring player
usually was loading up about 20 gigs of
files to do its run and there's a copy
there's all over the network which takes
some time the other thing is this spot
instance price can vary a lot between
regions and if you want to do large jobs
you have to call Amazon and say hey I
know what I'm doing
I will not get myself into millions of
dollars in debt by running away too many
instances please let me run more so you
have to get you have to get a limit
increase approved and like if you don't
have a limit increase in the right
region that can be problematic this is
if you if you've got an AWS account and
you're planning to do something like
that you got to do it a couple weeks
ahead of time just to make sure there
won't be problems okay so Ryan dealt
with getting all of the passwords
processing them seeing which ones were
actually in the Bitcoin blockchain then
the next thing is to find all the
transactions the passwords that are
actually in there as a first pass we had
an entrepreneurial undergraduate who
wrote a program to download the block
pane gather transaction data for each of
these brain wallets however we don't get
that granular of data when we're doing
it on on transactions that happen years
and years ago the attacker is also drain
way too quickly for us to pick up
information because you get about a 10
minute granularity when attackers are
working within seconds so what we did is
we use the blockchain dot info API they
can give us when the transaction that
put money into wallet occurred and then
the next transaction a couple seconds
later when the attacker drained the
money out of the wallet
this isn't as defensible is downloading
the blockchain so we also sanity checked
it using the first method and it's same
information different granularity of
time so Ryan took three point nine
trillion candidate passwords and from a
bunch of different lists now this is a
edited version because there's all of
those lists that he talked about but
these are the most interesting ones we
can see one that really sticks out is
the reddit one that was reddit comments
reddit user names we see that
on this forehand column it's the money
in US dollars so it's it's the most it
also has a lot of the really unique ones
and the data set there's some other
interesting ones so Lamas off to gave us
some data that's used just for you guys
today
it was two hundred and seventy five
wallets they're all unique in the data
set and it's actually quite a bit of
money it's about fifty thousand dollars
we were surprised that brute-forcing
didn't get more there's only 84 unique
and only about twenty four thousand
dollars and then from miscellaneous that
was some old data that was some
combinations of data those were all
unique because we tossed out anything
that wasn't unique so there is about
2000 total distinct brain wallets just
over that there's just under that
distinct number of passwords that's
because some passwords were turned into
two brain wallets one compressed one
uncompressed we also found about 3,000
Bitcoin now that sounds like a lot of
money but a lot of this was lost back in
the day when Bitcoin wasn't worth that
much so what we did is we converted it
to the amount of US dollars that it was
worth when it was put in and that's
about three hundred thousand dollars so
it's it's a good chunk of change we know
that we're necessarily missing things
right so we only have information on
brain wallets where we actually knew the
plaintext but it's still a good amount
of money we have some notable past
phrases so the first brain wallet that
we found was this string contains 0.25
Bitcoin hiding in plain sight some guide
posted this in the Bitcoin forums back
in 2011 it was the first real time that
people started using these brain wallets
and around the time of his post people
in the forums also created other similar
wallets
it was the first kind of community
around brain wallets however
unfortunately now the the second one is
the empty string this is the most common
brain wallet and I don't think anybody
actually ever intended to put money
there but a lot of people did and a lot
of people lost a lot of money this is
because of softwares it was also one of
the default passwords on brain wallet
org which people used so if you didn't
understand what a brain wallet was and
he went to the website it would
automatically prompt you with you know a
private key and a public key that
associated with it and the private key
was just the hash of the MD string we
found the most amount of Bitcoin tied to
this phrase Bitcoin is awesome now this
person put the money in and then he
drained it himself
we found 500 Bitcoin now the drain that
walk Ryan did the woodchuck drain while
that one had fewer bitcoins so bitcoin
is awesome is 500 Ryan's wood chuck was
250 Ryan's with worth a whole lot more
because the price of Bitcoin at the time
of the drain was not insignificant if
anybody hasn't seen my previous talks I
like I put the money back because I
emptied it on accident and then I found
the guy and got him to call me and I
explained why this was bad and he was
happy so we noticed that we normalized
the price of Bitcoin to US Dollars and
that's just because the price has
fluctuated a lot over the course of the
time and Bitcoin brain wallets were
actually somewhat popular in 2011 so the
first post in the forum that started off
Bitcoin was in July of 2011 and we cut
off our data collection in January of
2017 the bars is the number of new brain
wallets used every month and then that
is this axis so in 2017 there's a couple
created we can see that there is a bunch
more creative in 2013 the gray is the
uncompressed brain wallets and the black
is the compressed now what's really
weird about this is the most popular
type of Bitcoin wallets more recently
are compressed wallets you save money
because you pay a transaction fee based
on the size of your transaction and
compressed keys are smaller than
uncompressed so you actually save a
little money by using pressed we know
that the default standard for most of
the brainwallet websites is uncompressed
which is why we see this trend though we
do note that during this time period
here compressed keys weren't available
to get into bitcoin it is certainly days
now in the blue line what we see is the
new wallet value in u.s. dollars and
then that axis is over here and we see
at the beginning while there's a bunch
of there's some brain wallets that were
created they weren't actually worth very
much because the price of Bitcoin wasn't
actually very high and we can see it it
approximately tracks the popularity
though there's a couple big fish that
put in quite a bit of money so on one
hand here we're looking at the user
behavior we can also take a look at the
attacker behavior so we can look at the
time that it takes for an attacker to
drain a brain wallet so in black that
shows the overall amount of time to
drain so our time to drain metric is the
time from when the user put some money
in the wallet to the time that the
attacker drains the wallet out of drains
the money out of the wall and he puts it
in a zone we used a cumulative
distribution function so we can read
this chart as on the bottom is time and
hours and on here is our cumulative
distributions so in like you know
it's about half of all of the ever
drained brain wallets were drained and
then we can see about 80% took about
half a day and almost all of them 99
percent of them were drained within 24
hours now there's some speculation that
attackers were colluding together and
they were trying to not drain wallets
that only had a small amount because
some users were using this to test the
security of a brain wallet so they so
some people thought that maybe if you
get them to wait a little time it's not
drain then they'll put a bunch more
money in we can't really see that effect
so in the rabbit and the blue is so the
red is wallets I had less than a penny
in them blue is less than a tenth of a
penny well it's actually significantly
different than in our overall trend a
lot of that is because transaction fees
right so you're not gonna if you're
trying to drain a penny during some
amounts of time you would actually have
to spend a penny to get that transaction
on the network so it's not actually
worth it and so what these attackers
would do is some of them would wait for
more things and then some of them would
wait for a mining pool that would just
take a transaction with a lower fee now
we can look at how the attackers changed
their behaviour over time so in the
early days of Bitcoin in 2011-2012
attackers took a longer time to drain
those brain wallets there's fewer
attackers so we looked at the number of
unique addresses that these brain
wallets were drain to so a lot of times
the attacker wanted everyone to know
that they had the money so they would
have one unique address it might be a
vanity address and we can see that it
goes down to zero
so here in 2014 the median time to drain
is seconds it picks up again so in 2015
there was a lot more time with just all
transactions that spent and so it took
longer for any transaction to get on the
network and brainwallet transactions
were no different now we also want to
know two questions about the under all
underlying passwords that were used so
when one hand we want to know if user
behavior change so did users put more
money into rain vaults that were better
that were more complex harder to guess
on the other hand we wanted to know if
attackers because there's just so many
of these brain wallets that we're with
really insecure passwords
we're attackers actually going after
more complex passwords or are they just
sticking to the easy to get ones and so
what we did is we measured the
complexity of each of the passwords that
we found we used zxc vbn which is a
which is a password metric it's
developed by wheeler at Dropbox it's one
of the canonical measures we actually
tried out a couple other ones but they
gave us about the same results and we
tried to see if more complex passwords
affected anything so we looked at every
single thing we could possibly try to
throw at this we used a Spearman rank
correlation coefficient and we couldn't
find that it was significantly
correlated with anything so we don't
actually see any effective password
strength on anything this is actually in
line with literature so if you do a
bunch of user studies and people have
looked at passwords that users use for
Bank websites compare
to throw away websites users don't pick
stronger passwords when securing more
money or when securing money at all
compared to anything else that's that's
the same that we found we also noticed
that attackers don't prefer more complex
passwords they just like more money two
quick notes about zxc BBN one if you
don't understand the name look at the
bottom row of a keyboard - it is very
much designed for passwords not pass
phrases so here's why we have the next
slide so the next slide we tried to look
at the length of the password and we
could see that the 0 to 5 character
passwords or drain much quicker those
are in green than overall which is in
black however we tried to look at longer
passwords which are in blue aqua and red
and they're not actually significantly
different than the overall trend so we
can see that small number of character
words which are likely to be passwords
and not pass phrases are drained quicker
we don't actually notice any difference
between pass phrases in the overall
effect right so people taking money from
weak Bitcoin addresses is not limited to
brain wallets there's a lot of other bad
key generation stuff that has happened
one of the most notable was some Android
Wallet software was not using proper
random nonces and if you create two
transactions with the same signature
nonce in Bitcoin that is sufficient to
derive the private key which is a
problem
the popular brain wallet org tool had a
random button on it which would just
generate a random key for you but it
works by calling the
thought random function from JavaScript
and that was not very random in Firefox
in particular this the random number
generator is seated essentially just by
the time of day that the page was loaded
so that's rather easy for an attacker to
replicate and that was the random
function on brainwallet org so a lot of
users were actually using these things
and thinking it was secure yeah I
actually talked to somebody who lost
money because of that other other tools
allow users to they have they generally
are used with random seeds but the user
can select their own if they try there's
a bunch of example published example
addresses that have published keys with
them and I've seen seen those cleaned
out whenever somebody sends to them for
whatever reason also random arbitrary
constants are sometimes used as private
keys for reasons that I cannot begin to
speculate about I've also seen random
data from the blockchain used as private
keys hashes of files then if theorem
there was this site called ether camp
and it did it did a cachet cache of the
password and it didn't tell you that's
what it was doing you'd go to the sites
and hit generate new address and say oh
here's a password and it it didn't say
how it worked and I suspect some people
got burned by that and then after I
[Music]
called the guy out on this he was like
it's not a problem it's not a problem
and then a bunch of other people yes it
is he replaced it with something that
still was not secure I think it does 213
rounds of of KISS check because nobody
has rainbow tables of that or something
then there's the etherion parity
which is has been in the news lately
because they had a bug in one of their
multi-sig contracts that caused that
resulted in a 31 million dollars worth
of aetherium not a private key problem
just the etherium has smart contracts if
they have bugs they can be real big bugs
and then weird payday script - stuff so
here's some private keys they're all
empty but feel free to check and there's
a bunch of weird stuff so the first one
is the sha-256 of one of the default
pictures that comes with Windows 7
chrysanthemum dot jpg how I found that I
fed the contents of my hard drive as raw
private keys in what that house was
doing on my hard drive I cannot tell you
the next one was a Bitcoin transaction
ID the next one was another it was on my
hard drive I don't know why it was just
a bunch of it which is part of Pi
represented in hex as the fractional
part of Pi represented in in hex
although it was it was robbed i'ts on
the disk another was a padded zero
padded hash 160 of that address found
one that was one two three four in ASCII
prepended with the bunch of nulls which
is of course the frame wallet an idiot
uses on his luggage the next one was n
which is the order of the curve - 105
and about week or two ago somebody sent
ten Bitcoin to that and it disappeared
right away and this person was kind of
sad but he said it was his fault
I messaged the guy on the coin talk
trying to find out
what happened there another chunks of
raw data from Bitcoin transactions block
hashes other random strings of bytes
that were on my hard drive for who knows
what reason
the sha-256 of the Bitcoin paper was
used as a private key and then the last
one was just one and I I don't know what
to say about that we also found some
other interesting things so there's a
couple ways of making Bitcoin
transactions we looked at hated script
hash also and we found 139 Bitcoin brain
wallets
I'm their first seen in March 2012 and
actually quite a number of them are
still under aimed there's most of that
money is actually all in one of the
wallets
there's ethical reasons for us draining
it there's Exel reasons for you not to
drain it to the ones that were draining
though again we're drained in 24 hours
the median drain time is 9 hours so
they're about like the other ones they
actually have a similar group of
attackers so about out of the hundred
ones that were drained there's about 25
different people who drained it and 13
of those also drained brain wallets and
at least eight of them were spam
attackers originating from the same
group and one of them was a mining pool
and we'll talk about both of those later
yeah about those ones the pea script
cache ones that aren't drained I believe
all of those were two addresses for for
which there is no way to satisfy the
scripts to make it spendable so yeah so
the large Bitcoin Collider is is a
interesting project that somebody
started up on on the Bitcoin forums and
this is if you remember steady at home
if this is that for Bitcoin just
sequentially searching all of the key
until the end of time or whenever
somebody decides that they're done
burning electricity on this so they're
doing an incremental key search and
they're only searching for keys with a
balance which really disappoints me
because it is interesting to see keys
even if they don't have a balance the
admin claims the sweeping funds as
Austin found is legal in his country
which is somewhere in Europe and I I
have no comments on that claim they have
a gpu-accelerated client that is able to
do sequential search only it is launched
by a scary piece of Perl code that will
execute arbitrary code from the server
that was that was also there was a
debacle about that some people tried
messing with the script and it started
deleting itself after the server set
back a kill command people weren't happy
they actually did hit some keys with
small balances these were likely
original keys not not collisions none of
them had very much in them and I assume
they were tests there's also this puzzle
transaction I I wrote a blog post about
it but basically somebody made a Bitcoin
transaction with 256 outputs each of
which had one more random bit in it than
the last so it would be a bunch of zero
bits followed by a one bit followed by
random bits and so they're chewing
through that and they've gotten up to 2
to the 52 and think they're not going to
they're not going to find anything from
anyone who used a proper random number
generator so most of the transactions
that we've looked at have been Abba sort
users money gets drained to an attacker
in the early days that's what they look
like they might leave a small
transaction thief the mining pools later
when the when the time to drain went
down two seconds one way to have your
transaction be the one on the blockchain
is to get a larger transaction fees the
miners so that I get to put on the
canonical chain so we're used to seeing
that sort of thing however we notice
that there was a number of brain wallets
that were just drained completely -
transaction fees and that's what I have
this slide in the next one talk about so
we saw there was only eight different
mining pools that did it they drained
quite quite a lot of brain wallets
though the amount of money was quite low
so they only in all of these drains it
was like less than five hundred bucks so
clearly they're not doing it for the
money well not I mean not clearly but
they're not doing it for the money but
why so in Bitcoin what was happening is
people we're putting like the lowest
number of Bitcoin that you can into
brain wallets and they were just
flooding what are known as the
unconfirmed transaction at puts so
people who want to run Bitcoin owns each
mining pool has to run at least one
Bitcoin node it eats the disk space so
it's all of the transaction outputs from
previous transactions that still have
not been spent now one group of people
that decided to abuse this was in the
the Bitcoin block the the network stress
test were a bunch of people advocating
for bigger block size cause mass
disruption because that's that's what
people do in Bitcoin and they were set
out to create a 30-day backlog of
transactions they achieved it
they put
bunch of money into fifteen brain
wallets and some other types of easy to
guess keys
and they put a bunch of Bitcoin in it
and the mining pools then drained it so
that it really reduced amount of
consumption on the network though if we
do look at the dates mining pools did
that before the stress tests and after
so before we end our talk and ask for
questions we'd like to thank people that
also worked with us on brain wallets so
this is largely based off their a topper
for my dissertation which was largely
based off of a paper that Ryan and I
wrote along with Joe Pino who's at the
uff and Stanford
he's a password X expert Cameron Keith
who's our entrepreneurial undergrad and
Tyler Moore who is my PhD advisor we'd
also like to thank Filippo at CloudFlare
who did an earlier talk with Ryan at
hope I believe yeah on brain wallets
we'd also like to thank llama soft who
gave us data that we used on this
version of the talk and as a conclusion
this is a this is a screenshot of a
website run by ether camp about why
brain wallets are the best and we're
just like no this new one thing I would
like to say about that in this blog post
a challenge aetherium wallet was posted
which i believe that current value is
worth $70,000 and my estimate on the
compute cost using AWS fought instances
to crack it is about fifty thousand
dollars so if anybody really thinks this
guy wasn't lying you could do that
because he said it was available for
anybody who could find the password to
take and questions yes
okay okay so the question is okay so the
question was how do we distinguish
whether is a brain wallet a normal
wallet what we did is we did that by
guessing the password there's no way of
just looking at a wallet and saying what
it was but we only looked at things
where we knew the password I am not
familiar oh that oh so the question was
about the random sanity org project by
Gavin Ryan do you want to comment I have
no comment on that service yeah I don't
either sure sure okay next question okay
so the question was have we spoken with
the drainers Ryan yeah one of them
reached out to me after the paper that
Murray and I wrote for FC last year was
published and was was kind of bragging
about his exploits a bit and mostly just
wanted to get paid for data and we did
not pay him for data yeah he wanted a
lot of money for like the place yeah he
wanted to empty strange like like if he
wanted a tiny bit of money maybe I would
have paid it out of pocket
I've actually serious I planned to set
up a website eventually to offer
bounties for brainwallet planes but I
have far too little free time yeah we
also had some money that was just being
able to that we were only able to spend
on Bitcoin related research projects so
if it was actually good data and a small
amount of money we could have paid it
yeah but he wanted way too much money
yeah so that's also like there are a lot
of people who think that it is totally
ethically and legally fine to drain
brain
it's um I think those people are
assholes but uh like on public forums
people have bragged about this trivially
attached to their real name like if
anybody's familiar with hacker news
somebody was recently bragging about
feigning brain wallets out on Hacker
News oh and there's also I've met people
in person who have talked about it and
talked about their crack legal theories
of why it's okay yeah yeah there was
also a guy who was on reddit for a while
who would take them and then if somebody
posted on reddit hey where did my brain
while ago he would give it back went by
PTC Robin Hood I talked to him a bit yet
another instance of people doing
ethically questionable things out of the
goodness of their hearts yeah next
question yes so yes if we track the
funds after they left the brain wallet
the next steps we tried because we
thought that maybe there is going to be
a bunch of people that you know owned a
bunch of identities that were draining
brain wallets what we actually saw is
that mostly they had they drain to one
single wallet and we could see some
amount of people mixing their Bitcoin
after it left either using a mixing
service or by gambling using Satoshi
dice at all but we didn't act so we we
tried to do it but there wasn't actually
that much there there are there
additional questions I guess not okay
great thanks for coming
[Applause]