hi everybody i'm rachel indra and i'm
here to talk to you about risk and here
is sort of the obligatory bit about why
you should listen to me i'm a risk
enthusiast i get really happy about
talking about risk roman can tell you he
didn't even he came from or i don't
understand
i'm not a risk expert I've been working
in information security for 14 years and
nine of them have been in risk I've got
the usual alphabet soup of
certifications I'm currently working as
a security strategist at Leviathan
security group which is pretty great
because it means I get to talk about
risk all day so here's what we'll be
doing and here's sort of like how long
stuff will take hopefully so cools here
really likes risk I know right and who
really hates it or thinks it's stupid or
whatever come on
sometimes ok good this talk is really
for that because I think that most of
the reason people really hate risk is
that is so often so dumb it's often done
pretty badly have you ever seen the
thing where say Opstal refuse to patch a
server and then it'll get owned and then
they're like information security why
didn't you fix that they're like we told
them it was a risk but we're left
holding the bag on the risk effectively
we're the ones signing off on all the
risks whether we want to or not how many
of you have seen this yeah yeah isn't
that the best part of Metro suck yeah I
get a lot of nods I think you're all
being sarcastic what do you think you
know this whole talk is about stopping
that after this talk hopefully you'll
know what risk is good for know what a
decent risk management program which
would actually look like be able to set
up a good enough program cheap which is
kind of important when you're really
small be able to do a pretty simple risk
assessment and now what documentation
will get you through and on it the goal
here is to
your auditors drowned them in
documentation in here the lamentations
of your regulators right now everything
is risk-based it's this sort of fairy
dust that we sprinkle over everything
whether or not it has anything to do
with actual risk the auditors wanted the
regulator's run it the frameworks wanted
the customers wanted the fake will don't
want it marketing wants it
employers want it I see so many resumes
that talk about how much risk stuff
they've done it is like I'm looking at
this and like you're a mid-level Tivoli
administrator you have never touched
risk sorry you know I honestly think
this is one of the unsolved problems in
information security we can't do risk at
small-scale we can't figure things we
can't identify problems cleanly and get
them fixed before they get really
entrenched this is like super technical
debt a Minimum Viable Product getting
something working really includes
security or risk and all these invisible
risks just add up part of the problem is
we have a lot of confusion about terms
as three people in security about what
risk is you will get five answers if
you're lucky you might get more here are
the terms I'm gonna use there straight
out of fair which we'll talk about later
it's possible if not likely that I will
mess this up myself in them even though
I've been living and breathing this
stuff for ten years it's actually pretty
hard to keep it straight because the way
the language works is sloppy a risk is a
threat is evolve is a whatever
so what's risk in this talk we're gonna
go with probable frequency and probable
magnitude of future loss an asset
something of value frequency is how
often aloft may occur with any different
within a given time frame and that's a
little bit different from likelihood
because likelihood what does that mean
is that is it likely in the next ten
years with a little likely in the next
millennium qualitative risk is expressed
in words like rare medium and well done
gotcha
quantitative risk is expressed in
numbers dollars per timeframe in our
case a threat is something that may act
to cause a loss a threat event is the
thing the threat does that may cause
that loss a vulnerability is a weakness
that may allow a threat to cause a loss
and in this case our backup generator
has escaped into the wild
you know it's making a break for it we
don't have backup here's a loss event
the specific loss and here is a
secondary loss event which is the
reputation damaged after our specific
laws so why have a risk management
program for most places the answer is
compliance is necessary but it's not
sufficient your program won't work if
nobody cares binders full of auditor
Bane do not excite anyone or at least
not anyone I know they don't really help
the business so what are real reasons
for this your customers vendor security
questionnaires are probably gonna ask
about risk do you have a risk management
program that makes for easier sales if
you can say yes and mean it you know the
whole point is being able to make better
decisions
it helps enable long term planning it
helps you decide which risks to
outsource like say you know your core
business has nothing to do with payment
processing so maybe you want to just
skip the whole PCI thing and send it to
stripe or Square or whoever and finally
you can fix the really dumb thing the
co-founder legs and it's gonna cause
problems later but they really like it
but let's fix it early
the usual risk management advice assumes
that you've got a lot of staff and I'm
telling you we're not cheap you've got
some expertise you may or may not have
some expensive tools and you have lots
and lots and lots of time and then
there's the thing where they don't
actually list this is something you need
but you
trying to do its the organizational
maturity I don't mean just in the
capability maturity model sense of you
know you have a process you're aware of
the process and the process works and
stuff happens there's also the not
having the same freakin conversation
about what is risk over and over and
over again in the same conversation
about whether you can do information
risk and information security with an
intelligent adversary have you all heard
this conversation yeah
I'm friggin tired of it you know give up
please you know and then there's the
problem where those who are responsible
for the risks are also accountable for
them if you don't have all of those your
risk management program is gonna have a
hard time the current all options for
small and immature organizations are
hire consultants we like this option we
think that you should do it there's Chad
over there my boss was at hacker pyramid
you know we would love to help you if
you get other consultants you might get
something that looks a lot like the lots
of time and stuff and expertise and
maybe it's too much for your
organization you may get a control
deficiency audit risk assessment this is
not a risk assessment it's just a list
of all the controls that think you ought
to do that you aren't and maybe there's
a good reason you aren't but you're
still gonna get dinged for it this is
also the other best thing about InfoSec
right yeah and sometimes you get these
like 800-page risk assessment so anyone
never seen an 800-page risk assessment
you know and you had like thousands of
low risks and a few medium ones and one
high one and that was like super
actionable and super helpful right yeah
if you're in HIPAA there's health IT gov
security risk assessment tool and the
only reason I mentioned this is I do
recommend taking a look at it so you can
see what would an auditor have to pass
the bar is low my friends you know and
then there's what most of us do we kind
of give up
we need something better we need
something that passes the island okay
that's necessary but it's not sufficient
we need something that's actually useful
we need something that's inexpensive if
we're in a small scale because we're not
gonna have a ton of money to throw at
this necessarily and it would be nice to
have something that scales all the way
up and all the way down because changing
how you handle risk in an organization
is basically a pretty big deal or in the
organizational transformation project
how good is information security at
spearheading organizational
transformation projects yeah and maybe
not so much so this is all my boss's
idea you might have heard of James
Muriel Arlen he does hacker Perriman
it's really great I'm the minion that
built it out we're using a hodgepodge of
different resources don't worry about
writing it down because there's a
handout soonish and the big players are
factor analysis of information risk
binary a risk assessment the Canadian
harmonized threat and risk assessment
methodology because the Canadians are
the best and Australian risk management
standard the basic plan and we're going
to go through in detail in a minute this
side on scope inventory assets and
donors sort the inventory by granularity
perform a binary risk assessment asset
owners decide on the treatment for low
and medium risks senior leadership
reviews all the risks and decides on the
highest and then you document document
document and now for our actual program
and you guys I totally nailed that
timing I totally did I'm very excited so
our first step is deciding on the scope
are you gonna be on it ed that's your
scope are you subject to some kind of
regulation or have you signed contracts
that's your scope do your customers want
you to protect their stuff that's your
scope do you want to protect your stuff
might be your scope but we do recommend
that you kind of start small and grow it
would be nice to do everything
eventually you'll do everything but
get things running before you try to do
everything if you can if everything's in
scope then you know you're just gonna
have to cope then your inventory the
assets and the owners all I can say is
that yes this is heart this is something
that we have been yelling about for a
really long time you need to know what
you have anyway this is one of those
things where I'm kind of hoping that an
extra reason for doing this you know
more compliancy more whatever will help
get it done but this is something where
I you know leadership skills have them
the next thing you do is you start the
inventory by granularity and this is a
bit that we're stealing from The
Canadian threat and risk assessment
methodology appendix feed by the Royal
Canadian Mounted Police that's what
makes it great and why are we doing this
we're doing this because you don't want
to do that thing where you're
complaining all of your servers to that
one desktop running XP or whatever that
you have to have because you've got you
know in million-year-old MRI that
doesn't work with anything else or I
don't know sometimes you gotta have it a
number of risk management programs are
going to have you classify your assets
by confidentiality integrity
availability sensitivity that gets
really hard to do other ones start
talking about classifying your assets by
business continuity criticality or maybe
sort of a presumed impact and I think
that's a bad idea because impact is also
something you consider in your risk
assessment and then you're sorting your
assets by that and you get really good
recursive and really confused really
fast we're going with scale because it's
pretty it's a lot easier and it also
changes a lot less you know if you're
doing a database you know suddenly your
database can go from having not very
high impact to all of your PCI data that
would kind of suck but the it's still
database sized you know in here some
granularities I literally
just took them from the back of that
appendix it's all written out there you
can adjust it for your organization
we're not saying you have to do it this
way but it's just start with so he
tangible assets on a high level and then
break it down and to you know you've got
your data you've got your hardware
you've got your software you've got your
facilities and then you break it down a
little more and you're looking for that
the personal data or your network
components or you know your buildings
and you break it down more and you've
got data centers or all your Windows 10
operating systems or all your firewalls
and you break it down more and you've
got specific credit card data the
specific iOS tablets that all your
doctors are using or you know whatever
all your execs are using specific
buildings and just if you break stuff
down that helps you so you don't do that
thing where you can pet comparing a data
center to you know some handwritten
notes that someone's likely to take and
then you do something called binary risk
assessment it was made by Ben Sapiro
it's online at binary dot protectio is
Creative Commons Licence it's free you
can use it commercially it's fast it's
transparent it's pretty compatible with
other stuff and it doesn't okay so no
training required will be done by the
end of this talk
so it's minimal training is required so
using binary risk assessment as part of
a program can be a little weird cuz
there's not a lot of talk about this
which was really just discussed as a
point kind of thing to do a point
assessment but if you start at that
subgroup level like Windows 10 or your
tablets and just sort of work out you
pick an asset you think of a probable
scenario not your movie plot threats you
know probable submit scenario around
some winter fishing something like that
you need to do multiple assessments per
assets and because you can do them so
fast seriously they take like five to
ten minutes you can get in a lot of
practice and you can do multiple
assessments per asset and the reason for
this is binary really only
focuses on one narrow scenario at a time
that's also part of the reason when I
first encountered risk stuff my brain
kind of exploded because it's like well
this thing is really vulnerable to
fishing but it's not really vulnerable
to viruses or whatever you know and so
you consider multiple assessments when
threats don't have the same objectives
nation-states are going to have a
different objective from criminals or
from hacktivists or whoever the threats
don't have the same capabilities
nation-states versus kiddies versus
squirrels you know or the threat events
differ ransom wherever sufficient can
yield very different effects and so
here's a little philosophical segue it's
important for doing risk what's the
purpose of doing all this risk
assessment I have opinion on this and so
does a program I'm outlining so if
you've got a different opinion you want
to use this program you need to like
just agree they disagree when you're
doing a lot of risk assessment you
probably are not the person who actually
gets to be the decider
I cannot force people to patch their
servers I can encourage it very strongly
you know if needed I can run it up the
chain and make sure their management
knows they're not patching their servers
and what that problem is but I cannot
make them do it it's also not terribly
helpful to think that the only purpose
for this is convincing other people that
were right people get to disagree you
know if you're really really invested in
being right all the time you probably
are going to get much done so that's my
little philosophical discussion the next
step is the asset owners decide what to
do about the low and medium risks you've
got all your assets with their owners
these are the people responsible from
these are the people who can patch or
not make them sign off that they're
doing it make them sign off that they
understand hey this is a risk if it's
lower immediate risk you have to let
them make the wrong decisions you know
if it's a real problem run it up the
chain but you have to let them make the
wrong decisions you cannot force them to
do stuff
they don't want to you know stand by
those decisions but we don't want to let
them go either and that's why we end up
with this really awful tug-of-war with
them saying no not gonna patch and now
saying well you have to and I'm saying
no not and then everybody else saying
well information security why'd you let
that happen you know we never gave it up
this is another thing that you know you
want leadership skills and it's probably
the hardest part of any risk management
program so there are four basic ways to
treat risk you can avoid it we're not
saving that data in the first place so
we're not saving those pictures of the
internal map of your house anywhere so
there's no chance we're going to sell
them to anyone who wants that map of
your house if you've all heard about the
Roomba yeah yeah don't save it you can
mitigate it you can add controls that
reduce the possibility of something
happened good examples of that are
two-factor authentication
Network segmentation stuff like that you
can transfer it by outsourcing to square
stripe like I talked about before or
buying cyber insurance read your
contract really carefully if you do that
kids you know and then there's accept by
having someone at the right level agree
that the organization is okay covering
any losses that's what it means to
accept a risk so what's the right level
to sign off on a risk it's kind of best
to think of it like purchasing power I
can sign off on $200 you can sign off on
2,000,000 and anyone can sign off on
what $2,000 meetings something like that
you know this is actually really hard to
figure out when you're just starting if
you don't already know what risks you
have or what they look like or what they
feel like I mean honestly most people go
by feel after a while you know you don't
know where to draw that line a lot of
programs want you to do it ahead of time
they call it risk appetite that's the
amount of loss exposure you're willing
to run as a cost of doing business it's
really hard to figure out and it's also
something that if you try to figure it
out in advance you get really kind of
wrapped up in abstractions and you
get really bored with the topic before
you've even gotten to any useful
decisions so what I'm saying is just
draw a line change it later when you
need to because even if you figured out
something beforehand
you'd get annoyed and you'd still have
to change it later the next step is you
get a batch of these low and medium
risks that have been signed off on at
the appropriate level and you get any
high risks that you found and you bring
them all to senior leadership and throw
them out them and say here you deal with
it that's how it works right now the
senior leadership will review the low
and medium risk decisions to know the
context this means that they can talk
with people about the quality of their
risk decisions although it this is also
something to be careful of because you
really still have to work with people
later you know crazy talk you know and
then the senior leaders decide on the
high bar the high risk you still have to
let them make wrong decisions your a
your role here in this particular
program is to identify problems and
persuade another thing to keep in mind
is that more high risks doesn't
necessarily mean riskier assets that's
kind of a factor of how we've broken
down our assets in the granularity step
and how many scenarios we thought up and
risk aggregation is kind of a next level
thing that almost no risk management
program does well and this doesn't do
well until the end when you've got a lot
of trained people who have learned to do
it and are spending money and then the
last step is document all the things so
you can drown your auditors in artifacts
so this is a point where please pass
around the handouts we are going to do a
risk assessment are you excited
you're not sounding very excited
[Laughter]
ya know if we're out please share make
friends talk to people I know it's hard
so at 2:40 sharp we're gonna end because
I have to finish it but I'm pretty sure
I can finish from them because I have
Neil the timing twice now it's a very
exciting all right so the thing about
binary risk assessment it's a series of
ten questions about a given asset and
scenario you don't necessarily need to
be a risk expert or a security expert in
order to answer them it's fast enough
that you can do more than one for each
asset what you need to do since you
usually think of more than one
reasonable scenario what asset do we
want to accept we've actually got enough
time that we can do several I'll take
suggestions or we can assess a windows 7
user desktop okay I'm not seeing any
burning suggestion so let's just go with
it and what kind of scenario do we want
to assess again suggestions or way we
can talk about ransomware sounds good
all right I can do um wait for the
microphone sorry I can't hear you at all
okay so for the windows seven my wife is
a controller at a company so she
accesses the bank information for the
company I think how would that fit into
this um can we work through it first
Thanks would that be part of this risk
assessment it let's work through it okay
so if you look at your little binary
work card it's a very colorful side you
know stop reading Alec's sentence blog
post so Windows 7 ransomware cannae
ransomware attack be completed on
windows 7 with common skills yes no I'm
not hearing any news it's up to you
personally I mean they think the thing
is is these questions will help you
argue with the business okay they're
like what what's a common skill why is
this common or why is it not this gives
you a framework for talking about things
so you get decide for yourself what it
is you know so and that's a perfectly
reasonable thing to say and if you
notice most of the people in security
said yes I think because you can
download it from exploit dB yeah and if
you look Michael Reutemann from Kenna I
Oh has talked about how the likelihood
of and exploit being actually used in
the wild and actual causing problems CBS
s has nothing to do with it whether it's
in Metasploit an exploit DB does so when
you go back to your team you can talk
with them and say hey yeah I know that
your guys can't do this but anyone in
the world who can download this can do
it does that make sense
alright then can the attack be completed
without significant resources yes and he
knows all right then is the asset
undefended it's a Windows 7 desktop but
it's it's on a little company network
and we've got a DMZ
and we've got a firewall and so is it
undefended and that's another one where
you would have this discussion and your
line of business is probably gonna look
at you and say then what am I paying you
for if money laptop is undefended and
there's something to have an answer
about yeah awesome that will go over
really well you know are there known
weaknesses in the current defenses yes
because I like my tunes I've got a Sonos
and Jonas required for Windows requires
SMB one yes it does you have a so no
stone you can the attack
it's a vulnerability in the answer
always present its Windows seven
I'd go with yes anyone know can they
attack we perform without meeting
preconditions do you need something
special to do that do you need to be
there in a particular time do you know
you know I would say that there's not a
lot of those preconditions here you know
the the Windows 7 machine needs to be
turned on people tend to leave them all
all the time I'm not sure that you know
I would say yes some without meeting
preconditions but that's also something
that you can have a discussion about and
you can actually talk about it alright
so like if you followed along
where'd that land hi yeah so we're high
on the likelihood here let's talk about
magnitude and this is where your
question about the bank goes will there
make consequences from internal sources
we've got ransomware inside yes
will there be consequences from external
sources
are you sure maybe yeah
and this is a yes new thing this is
another thing where you can have a
really good discussion with the business
how likely is there to be a problem that
gets out yeah it it would depend like
maybe if your company has ever had a rat
ransomware attack that got into the news
that's gonna be yes because people will
have been burned if you haven't you may
have to argue you may need to discuss it
on the basis of other companies you may
need to sit on you know like your
friends companies what whatever just the
history you know it's this is a
framework for having discussion it's
it's not going to be all the answers you
know does the asset have or create
significant business value it's one it's
it's it's somebody's desktop is one it's
a rental or is this work significant
necessarily you know right yeah so maybe
not you know on the other hand if it's
the one connecting to Bank stuff and
then ransomware travels maybe it depends
on your individual circumstances and
again this is something you and have a
conversation about well the repair and
replacement costs be significant now
depending yeah yeah one laptop now the
other not but huh
only a Syrian baby I have none of them
but so how did that one land and your
handy little work colored and we are
getting a little more about some of them
so it might have been meaning my been
high but you're probably coming out with
a high risk around somewhere on a
Windows 7 7 desktop yeah and then you
can have you know your you know your ops
people are like yeah but we don't want
to upgrade this works this works for us
we don't need to upgrade it costs money
besides the Windows 10 is spying on you
and it totally is you know and and we
don't want to we don't want to make this
change you know isn't microsoft keeping
us updated we're not end-of-life yet but
now you have a framework for talking
about the issues and working your way
through it
so is this perfect no is this good
enough to start a conversation okay
that's good because I did kind of feel
like I was talking to myself a lot I do
that you know but me myself and I had a
great conversation hopefully you enjoyed
it as well we have seven minutes to try
and do another one you want to do
another one yeah okay
as we're doing this next one so item
three and four on here I see there's
like three categories of three sets of
low medium high
how do you get between the low low low
low medium low I if it's talked to me
later because I kind of need to point at
the picture sorry it's just I'm not sure
that'll be I'm not going to pretend just
I understand your question
when we need to point at the picture and
it gets confusing and and stuff so to
the more complex matrix under 3 & 4 like
how do you interpret that
okay there's determine likelihood and so
yep you get all the way to buy them
after six and you determine likelihood
sorry and then there's if I'm
understanding you I'm talking you
talking about the moving from 2 to 3
under determined likelihood okay so 3
okay I get 3 3 & 4 it's more complex how
do we interpret that alright let's talk
more about the original scenario instead
of trying to do a new one can the attack
be completed without common skills yes
can the attack be completed without
significant resources yes if I miss
remembering anybody what we decided just
yell you know so yes and yes as a high
is the asset undefended yes
are there known weaknesses in the
current defenses yes so that's also high
so yeah yes yeah so Yuki so you've done
the high and then you're in that column
with the high and if it's no no you can
go down to medium but if it's yes no
where yes yes you can you stay in high
and then for the next two questions you
know the same thing it's a vulnerability
in the asset Oh is present yes can the
attack be performed without meeting
preconditions yes is that making a lot
more sense to people and then you do the
same thing on the impact side and then
you
your likelihood and impact and put him
and swish them together and create
Voltron you got it alright so I'm not
yeah just to make sure I'm understanding
you correctly so for underdetermined
impact for the external sources would
you say that if you have requirements to
disclose any sort of information
security incident that would fall under
a consequence of external sources
personally I would go for that yeah but
it could be that whatever disclosure
you're doing just isn't gonna go
anywhere you don't care that much so
maybe not
you know it's your personal
determination of what is significant and
you get to argue about what's
significant that makes sense yeah thank
you awesome
so don't know that we're gonna have time
to do another one but if there's time at
the end and there aren't questions
there's gonna be questions never mind
forget that all right so we've done this
and we had a nice conversation but there
were obvious weaknesses here right
it doesn't actually meet the definition
of risk then I talked about probable
frequency and probable magnitude of
future loss not quite there it's kind of
close but it's not quite there the
questions are pretty technology-focused
not people or processes you know you can
do petcock obviously but you know really
talking about administrative processes
is gonna be pretty hard with this it's
kind of hard to answer for the non
malicious threats it's gonna be really
ambiguous regarding those secondary
losses like reporting requirements if
there's a breach whether or not let's
say you've got a lost laptop that's not
supposed to have personal data on it but
maybe it does so the second there those
secondary losses only happen some of the
time but when they do happen they
can greatly outstrip the cost of any
primary losses from losing something you
know and it's kind of weirdly ambiguous
between low frequency high magnitude
risks and we picked a high frequency
high magnitude risk so it wasn't quite
as obvious but if you pick something
that's low frequency and high magnitude
like say you know your rogue DBA you
know that almost never happens because
we've done other processes supposedly to
take care of it and also to be honest
most people are reasonably honest and
stuff so that's a low frequency risk but
high magnitude very nothing you're going
to do if your DBA is decides to you know
decides to flip so it's kind of
ambiguous but I did say that this was
going to scale and what you do is you
add factor analysis of information risk
it's made by Jack Jones the open group
standard for risk management it's free
to read all about it or you know you can
like buy the book for 40 bucks or
whatever it is that's essentially free
there's a sliding scale for commercial
use and it's not completely unlikely
that an organization would already have
it because open group also does TOGAF
and some other stuff that's pretty
established the training is pretty
inexpensive it's way cheaper than sans
and if you're in ISC squared you get at
50% off so it's even cheaper than that
you can do it qualitative or
quantitative lis it doesn't require
special vendor tools although you can
get them they're kind of cool and it's
not as fast as binary but one assessment
takes about two hours how many of you
have done a work a risk assessment in
your organization that involves
answering like 200 million questions
yeah they did only take two hours no no
that's a question so fair is the best
framework for risk management and the
best methodology for risk assessment I'm
not going to argue about it let's take
it outside so here's how you I'd fair
the amazing thing about fair is that the
way you scope a fair
scenario is the exact same way you would
scope a binary scenario they have to be
pretty narrow you need one asset and one
not just one thread event but one thread
event model you know one type of thread
event what that means is that fair can
be a drop-in replacement for a single
binary assessment you can still binary
all the things and only do fair when you
need more information more rigor more
usefulness that means you're only doing
extra work when you have to that's
pretty cool so how do you start with
fair the analyst training really helps I
have been doing risk for years and years
and years and I needed the actual
training you know I had all the books
and stuff I read it I'm like this is
awesome
I get it I don't get it I needed the
training it helps it's pretty cheap just
do it or send somebody everything is all
in the open fair body of knowledge
qualitative assessments only need pen
and paper if you want to do quantitative
assessments they can be done with Excel
you can do them with R you can do them
with Python or risk lens which is the
commercial end of the fair stuff they do
have a tool it's really cool you can use
it but you don't have to because one of
the things where we're going for is this
would be at least start really
inexpensive the thing here is you keep
doing binary on everything and then you
do fare as well and a few things you
need it and there's a still reason to do
binary first first of all that was
really fast right it's not a hardship to
do it it also helps you make sure that
you've got your scope and what you're
thinking about nailed down you know so
just do binary for everything and then
add fare as you need it so how far can
you go with fare how far do you want to
go in your risk management it will
support pretty much the highest levels
of risk management complexity and
maturity I know insurance companies who
they're using fare you know it can be
fully quantitative you can do all the
numbers all the time and they're
actually like reasonable numbers instead
of like that kind of numbers
and one of the really really difficult
questions in risk management is well how
do I know the risk for the whole
organization how much risks do I have
you can aggregate it and it'll work in
the tool here's the book it's noted on
the handout the reference for it and
finally we have to document the external
documentation that you'll need is the
binary risk assessment from binary
protected I Oh again that's free
harmonized threat and risk assessment
methodology from Royal Canadian Mounted
Police appendix B that's also free fair
standards from the okema group free to
read sliding scale for commercial use
ferret training way way cheaper than
sands or that's the main risk management
training I know of you know it's cheaper
than most stuff you know risk lens
platform I have no idea what that cost
ask them if you want it but it's like
it's way far in the future you've got to
maintain some on in artifacts I know
you're super excited about this yeah
you're going to need a system of work of
record some kind of workflow to or maybe
just a conscientious assistant you know
an office suite you need a policy you
need a process you need some templates
for storing the risk assessment you need
some forms or templates or whatever for
the risk decisions you need a risk
register because everybody wants a risk
register and you need meeting minutes
from those review meetings your risk
management policy you're gonna want to
have what the purpose of the program is
the actual scope so the auditors don't
say hey why didn't you review this and
you're like that's out of scope didn't
tell me what the scope is you know
here's a finding statement that you'll
actually treat the risks to reduce them
to an acceptable level statement on
asset owners are the ones that accept
the risk that decide on the risk
treatments what the documentation czar
requirements are for your organization
how often to perform risk assessments
and how often to
review the risks and their treatment
decisions your risk management process
we just walk through that whole thing
the only change is performed binary risk
assessment and maybe fair if you wants
more cool stuff yeah you'll also want to
document whatever the process is for
making and signing off on risk treatment
decisions both at the asset owner level
and at the more senior level you know
process for reviewing risk decisions
because like every year you got to
review your risk decision that kind of
stuff and it helps to have a racing
matrix you know responsible accountable
consultant inform on who's supposed to
be doing what so your policy does and
processes don't read as if invisible
fairies aren't performing all these
tasks because that's a really common
failure mode for policies and processes
the risk management process owner would
be the person who's accountable for the
risk management process not the risks
unless they happen to own the asset
sometimes they do but now usually you
know and then the process manager or
whatever you want to call them is the
minion that does all the work and the
target acid owner is a person who owns
the asset and the target asset manager
is the system and who does all the work
and then finally you want to name the
executive person senior leader whatever
who's accountable for information risk
in your organization you know who gets
the orange jumpsuit or who is
responsible for the organization not
just completely including due to an
information security problem you need
some kind of consistent way to store a
risk assessment you know it can be Excel
it can be Word it can be in your JIRA
workflow tool whatever you know but some
consistent way to store it so you know
you can keep track as standard ways
standardized way to document an
assessment you also need a standardized
way to document the risk treatment
decision template planted plans and you
know what was the asset what was the
scenario we were talking about what risk
did we find you know here's what the
decision is here's the people who are
going to do stuff here's the project
plan whatever and then you also get some
kind of signature some kind of I'm
accountable for this
no you need a risk register because
every auditors gonna ask for that
probably by name it's just a list of all
your risks and all the decisions made
and then for those exciting fun review
meetings you know you need minutes to
prove that you had the meeting prove
that you did the review and document any
decisions made we made it does this work
yeah no really this is route we've
implemented this a client it helps them
teach themselves about risk it helps
them teach themselves how to talk to
each other about risk and how to make
decisions it's really really cool
it gets accountability and authority
actually aligned instead of we didn't
pass but it's your problem you know
unless decision-makers drive the depth
of analysis and the amount of work based
on what information they need and want
to make decisions instead of trying to
run this huge to two million question
program or whatever and everybody's like
what do you do with this I don't care
and it keeps the investment of time
resources personnel in line with the
value does it work without Leviathan we
hope so if you would like to talk with
us again we'd love to talk with you and
help we are gonna be really seeing white
paper and blog posts all more about how
to do this it was just let's get the
talk and see if people what questions
we're missing and stuff like that but
you all probably know my boss James
Harlan he does hacker pyramid you know
talk to him and that's it
[Applause]
any exciting questions yes
why is risk register important I can't
get a straight answer on this because
the auditors want it and sometimes you
just need to do the auditor babe aren't
you shedding light on like you're
creating exposure to the auditors on
what your issues are I'm not sure I
understand the question is that are you
asking if it's cheating for the auditors
to ask you where all your weaknesses are
exactly it is cheating there are the
doors you kind of stuck with sure that's
kind of how it is one of the things with
auditing is consider what kind of fines
people have gone for the most part
there's slap on the wrist the point of
auditing has been mostly to ensure that
you're doing processes if you get a
finding it's probably not that big a
deal with auditing they want to you to
they would rather know that you are
aware of particular issues and I mean if
it's properly accepted then a lot of
times they'll go over and say you know
you did that it's very rare for auditors
to start talking about your decision
quality unless you've had a big problem
or unless you're PCI and you have a
breach and therefore you were clearly
never PCI compliant even though you were
certified every year for the past ten
years
yes did that answer your question it's
it's it's kind of the way things are you
do need to tell them where your problems
are you just have to it's not fair
that's how it is yeah when we when we do
our risk assessments one of the things
we find is that our business owners once
we've extrapolated the the impact and
the likelihood it kind of gets into that
you know that stoplight that high medium
low kind of area and at the end of the
day we say this whatever is high-risk
say back to them and they go okay now
so one thing we have found that is all
run is disabled there's really
understanding dollars they understand it
you know well how will this affect me
but we not I've not found an easy way to
t extrapolate it back down to what that
really would that real impact isn't a
dollar value but the reputational risk
or whether it's a you know cost per
breach or something do you have any tips
on that that's where that's where the
fair can I talk now okay
so that's where the fair analysis comes
in that will give you dollar values now
will help part of the reason for this is
the the quick and dirty version is to
get people talking about issues and why
you're having this issue why it's a
problem like I said it's not perfect
this is supposed to be a good enough one
of the problems with us risk people and
I've been as guilty as anyone else is
like the perfect is the enemy of the
just getting by and at least with this
you'll have broken down things more to
talk about where the issues are well
part of the this risk is coming from the
fact that the they there are no
weaknesses and the current defenses
let's change that so there aren't any no
one weaknesses and look it's go down so
it goes down too low they're like oh I
can accept that how expensive is that
change whoa you turn on Windows Update
alright then you know thanks to the help
yeah so um to add a little bit to my
wife is the accountant and controller
thing
thanks to her relationship with me she
knows all about phishing emails to get
someone to do a transfer overseas kind
of thing so she's very cognizant aware
of that with the binary risk assessment
example that used it was assuming evil
hackers as opposed to just good social
engineering so I'm struggling a little
bit with how do you apply it for
assessing the risk
that my wife as a human being gets
hacked as opposed to a technical asset
that is part of the weakness of binary
risk assessment is it's not as good with
people although you know with the
phishing example I mean who does fish
ape non evil hackers you know I mean
it's still evil hackers you know it's
just a different vector and you know
that's one of the weaknesses of binary
you can go and say okay can the attack
be completed with common skills it's a
good phishing attempt to call them a
skill yes no I mean this is a hard hard
thing to think through you know can a
good phishing attempt be completed
without significant resources that one
I'd say yeah you know is the asset
undefended well we have security
awareness every year and we have fake
phishing attempts and the rate of clicks
has gone down so the acid is not in
defense undefended are there no
weaknesses well yeah they're people you
know is a vulnerability in the asset
always present you know you can actually
make an argument that that's no because
a lot of the times with phishing
attempts people do catch them and it's
just occasionally they get through
because you know you get the dfl or the
FedEx phishing attempt right when you're
expecting a package that's kind of luck
so maybe for that you say the
vulnerability is not always present you
know can the attack be performed without
meeting preconditions you know and
phishing yeah they're kind of our
precondition so you know you you you can
still think it through it's kind of a
proxy it's kind of approximate it's not
perfect but it's good enough to do a
risk assessment and be able to talk
about stuff does that make sense
awesome oh no okay
[Applause]