hi everyone off you're having a good
besides so alright so just starting to
present to a my Patrick Matthew I'm
co-founder of access it's a conference
in Quebec Canada
I've been doing fantastic and consulting
for around eight years
I'm correctly working at Sookie compass
in Toronto I've been into hiking since
around 97 join this on like before
internet VBS and those kind of things
and found those texts about aking and
never stop so um i i've talked at Derby
come last year did the demo labs about
the tool I did and I'm doing a black at
Arsenal also this week so if you go to
black hat you can join me there my
Twitter and info is there so we're going
to talk about purple team what is my
experience about purple team officially
I've done like I said around eight years
of consulting and it was mostly staff
hugs inside government and huge aid
agencies insurance those kind of
companies and I did around ten years at
the same time of pen testing so I said
about both side the red side and the
blue side a lot of there are those races
was like I said government banks
insurance and at current employer right
now I create the services about the
purple team so I I also lead well I
create the service I lead and create two
major purple team exercise which are
usually one to two months exercise pen
tests and what I saw so by doing all
those experience and all staff hugs
inside government I saw so many things
that were wrong and that's why I came
out and do the talks there was so many
organization that was no sock there were
no
a narc most of the security inside the
organization was like just governance so
people writing rules of what to do but
nobody putting them technically or just
analyze the circuit edge and really or
personal people so not a lot of
technical and aking or even incident
response and even like one of the best
government I saw in Quebec down there
was the logs that were having millions
of those they were not even filtering
them it was like terrible blue team so
that's why we need to talk about purple
team just quick like this I can people
raise your hand if you're inside the
blue team right now awesome anyone in
red team cool too so hope I can help you
guys so white talk again about purple
team it's kind of a subject that come
around in the last few years a lot of
people online even Publix or others are
talking about this but when we see what
people talk about they don't cover it
out or usually it's I don't find it
properly so we need first a lot more
talk a lot more defensive research and
talk inside conference people focusing
on everything defense we're a lot into
offense most of the conference and
research is done inside finding issues
instead of fixing them or finding ways
to fix them we need to have the red team
to help the blue team is not just about
people going against an organization
destroying everything and giving a
report and run it's really to elf and I
mean the red and the blue are supposed
to work together they have the same role
which is making the organization better
and more safe purple team services
shanell organization made sure and
grow faster it's really a game-changer
so when I was doing like from pen tests
to a major or purple team effort most
most organization that we talked about
those kind of service that we're looking
for red team and when we explain what we
can do with the purple team with the
mentoring and everything will change
ideas so it's really a good game changer
also it's two out the blue team against
red and because defense need like I said
a lot of love there's red and blue I
have the same objective not the same
approach one is to attack when should be
to defend and both sides should talk
together they should mentor L grow and
challenge itself so it's not just about
doing a pen test and finding issues and
you will see the more details I will
show afterwards but it's really purple
things should really be an experience
where both side grows and talked
together to enforce security and the
most important when we talk often about
red team organization or kind of scared
of it because it costs a lot of money
like I said like a two months exercise
could cost a lot when we talk about
council think it could reach 100 to 200
K but there's a way to do purple team
for small organization they're really
cheap costs and that can help everyone
so so if we go back at what a red team
should be what it is it's to access the
business so the main thing you need to
know is that a pen test will test
against IT risk you will find technical
issues a red team in a purple team is
going to assess a business risk so it's
based on a trademark it needs to define
goals and objective based on those risks
and the red team will go against the
risk that were found based on the tread
models so if inside an organization the
main risk is the client list we don't
care about testing the exact application
or a specific web server we find we want
to find ways to reach this list and any
ways to achieve this goal so this is
what really the red team should be about
it's a nose codebase so when we do an
intrusion tests we want to do here's a
list of IP of web servers of application
that you need to test a red team a
purple team is a noscope so everything
inside the scope is what you should not
do so technically you can do anything
except the nose code which usually is
like do not destroy anything do not
steal an asset like go inside this
server room and leave with a server it's
really to limit the damage that you
could do red team is based on the tree
domain so social physical and
electronics IT so you want to use any of
those domain to achieve your goal and
objective it helps find ways to breach
an organization based on a risk so like
I said the red team will find a way a
path that was not known by the
organization to achieve their goal the
objective which is to assess the
specific business risk any question ok
all right
purple team definition so what people
already talked about what it's been
discussed in different talks or a blog
online is usually the purple team
approach would be a technical exorcist
that the red team will test a specific
attack against the blue team the blue
team will monitor it we'll try to find
the red team attacking
and then they will talk and try to
improve the process for this exercise
there will be like a post-mortem
discussion those kind of things oh sorry
about that not supposed to happen okay
whatever the sliders just not showing
but the computer works okay so oh there
you go okay
so purple definition so what people talk
about is really that it should be an
exercise with more like a workshop type
so people will do a small exercise and
post-mortem afterwards when a complete
purple team should be is really base
like I said on the business risk so we
want it to not only assess a technical
side but the business risk and
regardless of the risk of the department
or anything related to this so how to
get the business risk is there's
multiple ways so we can do the sweet see
sweet interview so interviewing anyone
related to the sea levels to gather
information about what the risks are for
any departments we can base ourselves on
the existing trip model documentation
that exists inside the organization or
if nothing exists we can create a fit
model exercise and find a business risk
of the organization based on this we
need to know what kind of system data
room assets or even person that are at
risk where are they why they are
important how the asset is protected and
which security misery exists or not and
based on all the other information we
can create a good trade model the
advantage of this is that the earth the
exercise is targeted against valuable
targets so it's not just to test
something but it's to test something
really important
and the approach is in base attack it's
really risk assessment
so whatever the attack used by the red
team it will be what we want well it
will be the path that they will find to
achieve their goal so the organization
at the minimum must be mature and when I
say this they should usually have a
minimum budget of security they should
know that they should invest in security
a lot of organization are not even there
yet so it's important to know it's
interesting at least so they have a
shock or blue team in place mentoring a
team that doesn't exist is not the best
they to determine the level of maturity
of the to do the purple addresses
there's a lot of different exercise that
exists a lot of levels so we can do
smaller to really like a two month
exercise so what it should really be
it's a mentoring and learning exercise
it's actively involve the blue team
inside what the red team is doing each
day each week daily it should the red
team should describe what they have done
how it works why it work and give their
recommendation and what the blue team
should do it's not just about giving a
report it's really to sit with them and
explain how it work and why and even
make them try if they if they want so
it's really like a consulting service to
everyone grow like this so the different
kind of service or steps that exist the
first one like I said is at red model so
if the trade model doesn't exist
you wanna at least do it by a real chat
model exercise or the c-level suite
interviews then you do the workshop so
you can have an organization without a
lot of money doing just predefined
exercise that will test some specific
attacks
so specific scenario or specific
objective without having to go for two
months and then you have the full purple
team where you will sit with the team
you will assess all domains the blue
team is involved inside the
communication they know everything
and then you have the full red team
where the blue team doesn't know
anything and afterwards you see how they
react and if it was good so you can go
this way and each year six months or
whatever you can review your security
and see if you improve which is to leave
what every organization should do a good
purple team is based on communication so
when the blue team is involved each day
it will be daily weekly or monthly
meeting it would be to discuss what the
red team is what they've done like I
said and now to remain the eight and you
can even do like a retest so everything
is inside the process of the
communication and you got the concept of
the mentoring process so by when you do
workshop it could be daily weekly when
you do a more bigger purple exercise you
want to usually not do it daily but
after each scenario after each goal that
have been achieved so if the red team is
going after a client list for a week
well after the week you sit down and
verify what everything has been done
what succeed what fell on both sides so
even the red team can learn from what
they missed or everything regarding this
so meeting will cover that the subject
covered by the meeting of the red team
is what has been done how it was done
why it fell and white succeed so the FEL
are also important because if the red
team fells it means that the blue teams
have done something good
so they need to explain which attacks
fell so the blue team will know what
good security is there and which part
are missing what recommendation on short
or medium and long term and is there a
retest that should be done or anything
to confirm the fix on the blue team side
on the other side on the blue team they
need to verify what was the tech what is
what kind of detection
what process was involved who was
involved other communication inside the
team was and what is the outcome of it
same thing for recommendation same thing
for Rita's but they will also have a few
more step regarding lugs should the lab
be analyzed what are the next step
inside the recommendation so planning on
on fixing things then when you have
everything in place which like I know is
could be something big because it's a
cell about the management that needs to
be involving this you can have the
concept of gamification everything is in
place for a purple team so your
organization is also made sure you've
done a few exercise and maybe a real
purple team
so the concept of gamification is really
cool you do a game with the red and the
blue and you see which one got the more
points after each exercise each goal or
something like this
when they gain access the gain points if
they complete those scenario a same
thing for the blue team but you have to
keep in mind that it's something for the
organization to grow so we don't want to
like having a bad game here you don't
want people to be mad at each other it's
really just a learning curve so how to
sell this to our management it's really
from
it's really to push the concept dye
management so they know the concept that
the purple team will bring business
risks into account and not just the idea
so it can assess any part of security of
the organization the mentoring is really
good so they need to understand this
part and the approach that this all
those steps will make the organization
grow regarding security so the level of
purple team will be like I said the
threat model workshop purple and red so
they need to understand each step and
then the upper management needs worry
about the business risk and I not just
the IT issue so we need to have someone
inside the organization that gets speak
to a management level and not just
report the technical issue up so it
really needs to have like a seesaw level
of person and then everything will make
sense so mentoring to identify the gaps
in security and for employees and system
and yeah so we're running a bit out of
time just a minute all right so last
part was the use case so just to go
quick about what we've done on our side
it was 21.5 two months or purple team
it's a organization of five hundred
thousand employees financial
second-place it's aware that they need
to invest in security they know about it
we've done a first round of workshops
then with the year after we did the blue
team with rebbe reb recon external
lacking social and physical and it
definitely helped on the workshop
because we were able to test specific
attacks inside the organization what the
real attacker will do and we help we sit
with the the blue team and tell them
what
to do what recommendation and then they
fix it the year after when we access all
domain within that fie the risk we test
all the domains and then we confirm even
the known existing security issues that
they know but they wasn't aware that
people could do it maybe so that covers
it thanks everyone
here we don't have time for questions at
this point but please track this speaker
down and outside and ask him any
questions you might have
[Applause]