all right so was an evening right yeah
it's evening time six o'clock no seven
o'clock now so what's going on my name
is Tommy topics on boning Software
Defined Networking I did actually like
to find word ponying to a marketing
person today it was actually really
complicated anyways don't care let's
disco let's get started clicker it's
very useful so usually in the talk I
talk about myself
something about Sdn I can walk right yes
are you good so component breakdowns of
st in itself and you know VR and the
whole angles of like we're not trying to
do what i found and what maybe you could
find in the future who knows right so
about myself so much curvature at grim
has anyone heard of grim henry's no one
I really said no okay okay boom was it
no okay anyways alright so first time
presenting up besides Las Vegas holy cow
also of these sites in general so a lot
of check marks and achievements right
being in Las Vegas as well I mean since
like day two I think and I just got to
the strip I think order this is called
no idea but you know I'm learning new
things here in Vegas and being on the
west coast right now kind of west coast
if you're West coaster this is my view
of the west coast so I'm sorry but you
know give me suggestions on what you
think you know I should do I love
suggestions right background backgrounds
always kinda useful I guess you know I
started networking long time ago in
phone networks so I I had a job long
time ago wiring t1 lines there's going
what t1 line is has he won a wire it's a
t1 line
has anyone liked doing that hell no
right I think I was crap but yes I spent
some time there six months don't like
that as much so switch to load switch
gears went to a different place and
they're like oh you'd be uh you know net
net admin yes
cool awesome what kind network all we
can't tell you yet get there like oh hi
it's a Novell shop
but 2010 by the lace I'm you know I'm
like what is this you don't even learn
this in school anymore
or or less and if you do it there's
something wrong there but they haven't
you know IPX SPX said oh you know I
don't understand this at that time I was
kinda like all right whatever let's go
with this research focus so my
background is of course in networking
because networking presentation always
useful I also do a little bit of machine
learning signal processing target
tracking but we don't care about that
kind of stuff
networking so fast-forward like I like
questions you know if you have a
question just you know raise your hand
be adults right asked I don't care and
there are things you know I like to talk
over drinks right double was always good
that's my to go you can't really mess
that up unless it's like a really bad
dive bar concept right and if you don't
drink you know I like steak so that's
always delicious so motivation here Sdn
so when I first heard that Sdn angle you
know I I hated wiring you know I I had a
lot of jobs for like you know I wired
something up and then an ignorant on
tractor with like accidentally cut like
five lines down the ceiling and other
rewire like hundreds of lines because
they made a mistake right so I got a lot
of stories too and wiring and networking
in general but that's related things
anyway so now it's computers getting
super beefy you know huge not physically
huge well maybe physically huge fight
but resources wise you're getting like
the whole like you know five 12 gigs
memory one terabyte gigs memory the huge
like con 20 cores plus depending on
where you go right and the biggest thing
is you know you make these computers
into like some sort of hypervisor
solution plop some vm's in you know
support your infrastructure and drop
some buzzwords like SAS and pass and
whatever you want to call it right check
marks on the assist things right well
the biggest thing here is you know as
you your infrastructure grows and you
have VMs here you want to be healthy you
want to have the ability to you know
customize and tailor your network to you
know whatever you need right you know
quality servers fault tolerance you name
it there's some circuit abilities and
you know for those who don't know about
25 pair of wire is this is like one
giant fat wires fanned out in a punch
block I hated this and it
worse than like you're colorblind let's
see if you can't match colors that well
alright no offensive you are great
so stn suffer Defined Networking so I
had a thing a long time ago work I try
to put a paper to a conference right and
it was rejected because I didn't add the
hyphen in Sdn and that was the only
reason and I'm like are you kidding me
right
so like either a fantasy or a reason I'm
sorry but so here's my primers right
lots of primers so you know vm's it's
like everywhere you know VMware virtual
box parallels you name it we got
something right and the big things like
I said before is you know a VM has some
limitations right you can't really you
know apply quality service to some VMs
maybe you can nowadays depending on
hypervisor but there's still a lot of
different like limitations in your
hypervisor solution
you know pad selection like finding like
the best optimal path for routing or you
need sort of like flow control and you
know customisation like if you want to
drop your own networking protocol
because you know you're super fancy like
that then you can't really do that right
and like off-the-shelf product right but
the biggest thing is like Sdn you know
there are two major marketing terms is
of course global view and
programmability as you know a lot of
customization so you know there are many
vendors out there that do the whole Sdn
inkle nowadays here's some lists like
Cisco HP you name it and there's of
course software like floodlight almost
and etc right you know a lot of like you
google something and boom helps on top
like five ten lists right so in the
whole Sdn angle there are things called
planes right so I I had someone look
over the slides earlier and they thought
an airplane and I'm like no no this is
like a networking thing right so there
are three planes and networking an
application control and infrastructure
and we kind of kind of think of it as
like three separate networks here kind
of think about that but each plane by
itself has a purpose of Business
Administration and your actual
communication control for your clock
tell or your servers or whatever you
call it what three planes through
purposes remember that not an airplane
so here's a you know lovely diagram I
drew right always nice blocks of course
it's always good so what happens is in
Sdn there are two major components that
controllers and switches you guys others
as well but what is called switches for
now right and each device is serviced in
a plane so controllers will be on
controller and control plane your
switches computers and point servers you
name it it's all in your infrastructure
data plane and what happens is you know
your business people love and of littlez
like next fancy graphs the spinny dials
and like trend marks you get the idea
right so they need some sort of an API
function to like query that kind of
visualization right and you can begin
for like a threat map or you know
projector screen for all your you know
fancy people so in the SDNS switches
very side switches before and so what up
my view for the whole switching angle
you know there's a lot of difference
which is out there you're off the shelf
or you know online and get help so open
V switch does anyone use open V switch
before and raised on to Canada hand
raised two and a half points to seven
five ish I don't know depending
there's a lot of switching technologies
out there and I think open V switch is
my my V array so I can't be right so
this is you take it at you like learn
right but I think open pieces just like
the most popular one because aids you
know open source you know I love free
things because who doesn't
versus like going to Cisco like hi Cisco
wait does even work at Cisco my good
very good
not the bashing landing but you know I
don't want to go to some some vendor
product company and be like I want this
switch all it cost like $5,000 or the
service contract support fee and no and
you can't do all the stuff right so I
don't like I I hate all the rigidity
nonsense but no open source is always a
good thing
you know big community I like making new
friends right you can be all my friends
later if you want to doesn't matter
remember drinks and steak that's my
thing but yeah so the biggest thing is
you know open thesis is software and if
it's plopped into a VM that runs some
sort of like Knicks environment of your
choice right and the biggest thing is it
you know traffic it's how your traffic
in your network moves from A to B so in
the switch itself
they have flow tables and that's how
basically when traffic goes into the
switch it looks at this kind of a table
scheme and it's like oh this traffic
profile matches this line entry and the
route in a flow table has like oh I'll
go from port a to port B and it goes to
my destination so here's an example of a
flow table structure so every time you
have a you know network sequence or a
flow or some sort of communication
channel whatever you call it on a
network a flow is inserted into this
table right so every like everything
that moves has a rule somewhere if it
does have a rule it can't move so
remember that so this is an example rule
where I had two boxes on a thought 10
Network and all I did was pink right so
on one of the rules the traffic goes
into the switch the switch looks over
the table and it's like okay that got it
from you know box 11 right and oh it's a
you know ping some sort so let's just
shoot it out to 12 because you know 12
was the destination marker and it says
port port 5 4 4 5 you get the idea it
moves it virtually in virtual space
software right so with pee-hole Sdn
angle there are controllers so
controllers by itself you know there's a
lot of controllers out there you know a
lot of software everyone makes software
nowadays on github
you got floodlight floodlight stuff you
know the big thing that I wouldn't talk
about but you know major competitor is
you know ryu does anyone else use a fan
controller scheme know any cisco people
or is it contrail no idea if I I will
try remember that or I just talk to me
later and will I look it up so there's a
lot of things all right so I talked
about floodlight because you know I was
introduced to a much older software
called pox NOx but I've moved along and
the world and went to more fancier
looking things right so floodlights
there and it follows a similar scheme of
the whole application control and
infrastructure yeah you know a lot of
times when you buy a product from like a
vendor
they'll start relabeling certain
extremes and they're like oh this is
business marketing families fantasy so
we leave this stack or rename something
like this and they get our terms and you
know put some copyright trademark
nonsense on that right but so like
flatly it's good because you know
learning wise you know they do follow
the scheme you know they match the
protocol to some standard right and
these when you do the analysis or
investigate and you're like oh okay so
this is application control on
infrastructure so they do follow things
so this is important here so
capabilities you know the controller is
the brain of the operation you know like
you have switches and routers in the
global infrastructure right and they
individually can you know act by
themselves but the biggest thing is like
you know if this controller is like dead
you got no rule network I mean you have
switches that can kind of move but over
time you know over a certain period of
time it doesn't know how to move traffic
anymore because it doesn't have the
decisive control of the controller the
controllers point of view or the
controller's function here is basically
just to say okay I got some traffic I
have to figure out how to get from A to
B I do some you know some math nonsense
in the background and then this is how
it routes and it goes but when the crow
chiller is down your packet goes in
switched which is like help me I don't
know what to do let's just blast it
everywhere and hope it gets there
broadcast right so the biggest thing is
to you know like what happened to the
whole like eggs in a basket right we try
to avoid you know security some angles
risk risk analysis I don't know so like
if your infrastructure is so dependent
on a box or two and one of them goes
down all right no bueno so closer than
Java you know I get a lot like a view
points that people don't like Java here
and there right it's not really that bad
maybe I don't know does anyone like Java
boom like this guy I don't know what's
your name Mike that's his pseudo name it
could be really James don't know
but so in Java it's not that bad right
so it has the whole rest API function
for you know your business people but
then also within the REST API you can
manipulate and control your controller
as like you know administrative nonsense
the big thing is hey I got the service
it's a REST API interface it's listening
on every interface I have on this
controller and all by the way there's no
one encryption encryption or
authentication to it so you know as long
as you find a controller in the network
if you're doing some scans and it looks
like one that has an API function to it
you can just send commands to it and it
magically accepts and listens to you
whoops right so with that so there's a
Alain in traffic called southbound
traffic so what happens is when the
controller gives you instruction set to
the switch wouldn't you know inserts
flows and rules to it it's called
southbound traffic it's kind of like a
visual diagram right so what happens is
that traffic by default is in plain text
and you can you know do some magic you
know wizardry replaying whatever you
wanna call it and your switches and the
other side will kind of like say okay
sounds good I'll take that any questions
so far by the way I love questions you
know your questions just raise your hand
right so the OpenFlow protocol and
fuzzing so you know I um I would say my
network person by trade I guess depends
on that angle but Sdn I've been doing a
student feel like I don't know probably
five years ago I think I have no idea a
long time right but it's kind like
relatively new nowadays in the market so
we'll just go with it so in the you know
your first packet in networking right
you know your client sends the traffic
to network it does this whole art thing
right as this resolution protocol what
does a network seal make for a noise
Network seal think think protocol
Formica what does this protocol this guy
all right this guy right ARP ARP ARP you
know it's really corny but the funny
thing is like I think like six years ago
seven years ago I actually got someone's
phone number with that corny joke
so that didn't end well the end of
course but you know it's still a good
achievement for me I think to say this
kind of quirky like nerd joke that
actually worked anyways don't care so an
all Engel Sdn is a little bit different
in the sense that you know when you
communicate on your network from you
know Peter a to computer B it takes a
very first packet in your network flow
your stream of traffic right and what
happens is that initial packet is sent
to the controller and the controller is
like okay I'll look at this packet and I
let me try to find a profile to pack and
determine what those computer I need to
go to how does it need to route what's
the purpose of it that's the idea based
on the first packet and so what happens
is that initial packets it's
encapsulated into an open flow message
right this guy seems kind of confused
what's up boom so we'll get to that
okay so yeah the guy was thinking about
port scanning we'll get to that kind of
interesting thing later a good good
visual eye contact thing anyways so
first packet goes to the controller
control looks at it and I was like okay
I know where this goes and goes boom so
the flow gets inserted into a switch
switches like oh cool I can then afford
all the other like 900 bajillion packets
do the rest of the network and you know
we basically have a happy network at the
end and it says that you know both
clients at the endpoints are
communicating but what happens is so the
other thing of with Sdn is is everything
is virtualized you know we don't have a
actual visual map of a network as
everything's software driven so one
thing with Sdn by itself is it uses two
techniques to identify links in a
network right because we don't have
cables anymore everything is just you
know bits flying so uses to discovery
protocols to identify links and all
those is layer two broadcasts everywhere
spams all your switches all your ports
and you know it gets really noisy so you
know anything like cisco serve protocols
or juniper discovery protocols people
same idea just you know different
marketing term and people stamp you get
the idea
but the biggest goal is with their
dysentry protocol is it finds paths
finds the shape of your like network
graph anyone colleague graphs right math
people graph and it determines the best
path based on latency so what happens is
when did this here protocols are
broadcasting in a network that time it
takes to measure between switches is
your measurement of latency and then the
controller's like okay they get from a
switch a to switch B it took me like
five milliseconds that is my latency for
the link so that when it does
calculations that determine the best
path it starts adding numbers to get in
is like Oh to get from I am from one
point position network to the other it
does some crazy math and it's like this
is the best path can't like you know
when you're driving the car and use
Google Maps and Google Maps kind of
screams that use like oh they'll take a
right turn down this like sketchy
alleyway and hope you don't get shot
right but what happens is Google Maps in
the background does some calculations
determine you know how do you meet your
you know goal of getting to a
destination fastest right and what about
in having traffic or congestion so
there's some like weird things in Sdn so
what happens is in the southbound
communication right so like I said first
packet goes the controller rule comes
down right what happens is the rule the
flow rule so when the controller sis
rule into the controller so to speak
right there are timers there as well to
maintain say okay after certain amount
of time will keep this rule into a
switch so that all the remaining traffic
goes through but then once the you know
an expiration timer comes up or I'll
time comes out that flow rule or like
disappear so somewhere midstream in your
traffic one random Packer will shoot
back up to the controller to get
reanalyzed to say okay this is the path
again but what happens is sometimes
depending on how your NOAA's configured
your traffic mate mid should be rerouted
in a different path depending on how
it's constructed because everything
software driven right you can't really I
mean you could do that in like real
networking but there's a lot more like
issues like telecom issues right
so rather than thinks I've found
interesting so you know this is about
vulnera so Rendon Pisa file interesting
using escapees so this guy what's your
name again Richard so that's a pseudo
name Richard could be like Bob or
something I don't know anyways I'm
saying and what's your name because I
have no idea right but so port scanning
you know port scanning you can send scan
all day of course and you can even
change like so match even like you know
syn flooding DNA you know now service
you just changed like your source
address field or a destination address
field right so the interesting thing
about syn flooding and other things is
like each packet fills a role in the
table so your tape so basically if you
just change an address field or it just
changed a little bit something like that
each packet will fill the table so your
tail becomes huge and a switch so like
when the switch starts reading this
table it gets slower and slower and
slower and slower because now my like
ten rules and this table becomes like a
million and switch is not happy and you
know all your customers so speaker and
happy so I mean it's kind of a it's not
lame but you know it some mention the
bullet thing because thing I thought it
was kind of like a interesting setup see
the thing too is I found it's kind of
interesting was that so with the whole
like you know first packet going to the
controller as like the way the profile
networks stream right if you send a
super large packet like a huge like next
cell all that feels possible packet
concept it actually like starts sinking
your CPU on the controller down there
like 10% um I guess I use this kind of
you know like machine so like you can
you know do some racial calculations in
term of the rest but I mean I think that
it looks pretty beefy but like all the
cores when tons like 10% lower just
because I sent one large packet so
that's kind of like a that's a little
different right but the other thing was
like you know because for rules they do
expire over time like I said and default
is like five seconds so like if you're
straight like a really slow loop you
know like I'll true sleep five
send packets sleep five you repeat this
cycle but speak you can kind of like
start
slowing down the control of their and
you know if you have like five clients
or you have one client and change the
source or hydrous feel our source or
destination address field you can kind
of like start really rolling down the
controller just because you you know
follow the de facto standard it's just
you use it in a much interesting way so
northbound REST API so that almost the
other like angle and the whole
controller angle so it's no web web
stuff right so you can use curl all day
so I try to funds the API on your face
and Java was really upset with me as it
was kind of like trying to process my
request and what happened was it
literally just locked up in general so
you know a lot of times is it's like why
like why is this happening and you know
people say it's Java right but I don't
know I this guy likes Java right
mike-mike boom Mike likes Java but I
don't care it's just like public you
know public static void main string args
blah right but anyways so it would
periodically locked up then network
didn't do so well because you know
controller wasn't really functioning
well and switches can't get instructions
so it's like what to do right so it got
even worse because I had to throttle
down the fuzz the point where like it
was like 200 Gatchaman 200 200 I could
request a second the most it was like
that was a fasiq again but it's so
unthinkable a debt so like you just you
know Senate command and it accepts all
right so you know someone needs to put
our password there that's kind of useful
right the Sierra Protocol what happens
is yes
boom a good question so what happens is
when you are a client in Sdn you're in
that infrastructure data plane right
what happens is the rest api resides in
the northbound the application plane so
you have to reside in that particular
network interface but what happens is in
the virtual scheme now your VM still has
a you know an interface that listens to
some sort of internet access network or
another internal network right but in
the SDA angle use your virtualized
entire network within the VM or within
some set vm's you need to reside in a
you know a similar level of like
networking but going from like your
infrastructure data plan it's not that
really easy but so I have two minutes
print that guys so I'm going to speed
this up a bit so past elections a
certain protocol if you spam that thing
you can basically force a network to
redraw the pathing by itself so it's
like you don't need to men really man
the million I think you can just force
the network to say hey move everything
there because if you what happens is
because it uses Dussehra protocols to
measure latency and greet you know
inform the controller controls are
seeing these you know packets but they
have like weird timestamps right it's
gonna measure them like oh this link
took me an hour to go through so let's
just go everything in our direction so
it's like a like a really weird way to
like move things in the whole networking
scheme without doing any sellout rules
anyway so hiccups that happened so when
you try to move actually mihrab traffic
from one box to another i have switching
between but Wi-Fi mirroring it you know
layer two dropped everything on the
switch because it isn't matching the
fields so my solution here was this
really janky way that kind of worked TCP
dump pipe to it net chat tunnel dive
piped into a replay thing this guy was
like what the hell you doing but it
works it's just not really practical I
mean it was practical I guess with this
angle so it kind of worked
summary a CPI stop now boom summary I am
done
hushed questions hit me up on Twitter
there's my Twitter here's a QR code you
can scan me wants you it's legit
don't worry about that follow up room
always good right that's why work thank
you
[Applause]