thanks to all the the speakers we're
gonna roll right into our panel QA we've
got a microphone up here we can ask
questions if you do need to change over
to a different room that's fine but
remember the questions are in the spirit
of pressure testing the ideas in order
to make them better even if you think
the idea sucks let's let's have a little
bit of kind of a innovative and
improvisational spirit and say yes and
so how can you make this idea a little
bit better than it was before these
folks came into the room and improve it
iteratively this is where we put on our
friendly pen testing red teaming hats
like Bob said and maybe use the nerf
bats rather than the the fungo bats if
you're a baseball fan so yes first
question this one's received so my boss
always asks me what are the assets were
protecting when I want to bring new
technology or new processing so I'm
curious does anybody analyze what this
major cybersecurity attack on the
country would would do what the impact
would be life loss financial impact have
you seen that anywhere ever have you
looked into it the closest thing I could
say that would address that is from
different presidential directives
including DVD 41 which is out and easily
read damage to property loss of life now
what is will that one loss of life trip
the wire that I'm talking about or is it
a catastrophic shutdown of all the
electrical grid in one area and now you
have lots and lots of loss of life I
don't know what the delineator is I
could imagine in a political sense that
one loss of life could in certain
circumstances be okay that's not that
some of the things so the government
every year or two they run some
exercises one of them is called cyber
storm there's like three or four that
seem to be competing for weird cyber
names
and a lot of those from what I
understand have not focused on the loss
of life issues they've been the power
grid goes down yeah some of the stuff
you guys are doing in the energy sector
looking at I forget what you guys call
yours which is not a government-led it's
industry led right
it's the it's the North American
Electric Reliability corporation so
Newark Newark runs so events yeah so
Newark operates the grid X event every
two years and coming near to you
November of this year is number four
yeah so there have been some of those
simulations that have been done in
talking with some of the Congress people
congressional staffers agencies how I
quit Steve said you know a single loss
of life might not be the things that
trips that breaker especially when at a
national level you have loss of life
every single day right there's some
number of people who just die from
things every day that's true it's it's
it's less funny than true but uh like if
you look on the highways about eighty
people every day died from car accidents
some percentage of those are preventable
so that's why the department
Transportation is pushing so hard for
autonomous vehicles because the stats
say that about sixty of those 80 every
day could probably be saved so that's
the type of thinking that they look at
the scale at which they have to think in
order to have a societal level of
cohesion and kind of stability I think I
saw a question over here somewhere oh
there it goes okay so my question is for
Steve also I enjoyed your talk but from
a military perspective we talk about a
nation state level attack that would you
know affect a large part of our nation's
defense capability or power grid or what
have you I think part of our capability
from a military standpoint to either
deter that or
our attack comes from the a word right
attribution and that's something a lot
of people kind of like to assume away
and it seems like we've got a real
problem with that
every time that we try to attribute any
kind of major attack to a nation-state
we largely get laughed at right it's
like well if you if you want to
attribute an attack to China just hire
mandiant no problem they'll find China
right so I think that's a problem and
how do you see us solving that in the
future from a military cyber standpoint
because I think honestly if you don't
like to as the gentleman talking about
the electricity of the electricity
exercises was talking about you know we
don't like to air our dirty laundry but
if we have some that's it you know from
from a national military standpoint
we're not good at it we're not good at
attributing those large attacks to a
nation-state and so what is their cause
to to not attack us because at this
point we can't really generally find a
smoking gun we haven't yet really unless
I missed something so so I agree with
you on that absolutely and I don't have
an answer that is a there's another
wicked problem that has being order to
you all the time the only thing I would
say is where I'm focusing is I don't
want to have to go back after it so
attribution is when you want to go back
I would rather us move into we're good
at we're doing things look we've got
nuclear weapons sitting there right we
know that that keeps other people from
using those we've got military
capabilities in the military example
we've got those capabilities forward
deployed here's what we do we've shown
willingness in theory that tamps down
anybody else's desire to do things so
then I don't have to have the
attribution part because it is so
difficult so I'm probably wishing that
one away more than I should
that's a very different difficult
problem no doubt I mean I agree with you
there I would rather get away from just
the reactive mindset that's my concern
we'd rather sit around and argue that
problem as opposed to what if we just
show we're able to get our act together
and it's not just military it's not just
government our collective national act
is so squared away that there's go yeah
I'm not going to do that it's not worth
it that's where I think we have a
warrant this is yeah as Steve said
there's not enough booze in the bar to
really have the end of the deterrence
conversation which is where attribution
is really effective and only in some
models of deterrence do you need
attribution yeah it's it's the
retribution piece it's the increased
cost after the fact for attackers and I
think a lot of that conversation comes
from the thought of you know we can't do
any better to defend our nation against
a nuclear attack other than deter the
other guy from doing it because it seems
like there's a lot of that conversation
that comes in from the nuclear and
military side and think about deterrence
but like Steve said you know I'd rather
build our walls higher to begin with I'd
rather keep people out rather than worry
about how to punch them in the face
after they do something and I think that
there's a certain segment of the InfoSec
population who says well we're gonna
give up on this idea of prevent we're
just gonna detect quickly and respond
quickly but how do you respond when you
have you know maybe a thousand people
die right how you bring people back to
life that's hard so the response and
recovery piece of that is fundamentally
different when you deal with so these
bigger societal wide cyber issues and
instead if we invested more of our
political will an institutional will in
the defense piece and the preventative
piece then we could do two things one is
raise the bar higher than the
low-hanging fruit adversaries can jump
so if we clear that battle space we
don't have to worry about you know was
this some dopey kid on a laptop in
Southeast Asia we don't have to worry
about was this Isis then we can only
worry about the higher caliber actors
which makes it easier to do attribution
and with a higher cyber tideline or
cyber hygiene line you also get more
into
Gators that can point you in the right
direction so right now like somebody
gets hit there's probably not a lot of
log files depending on who gets hit but
if there's log files everywhere it's
like having trip wires everywhere then
it's easy to to tell it's easier to
build a story to tell who was doing what
so it makes attribution easier and it
prevents attacks from succeeding to
begin with so that's the way that I tend
to look at it and you had a question
like oh there any question for David so
I'm part of a National Guard unit we've
worked with local public utility
districts to help look at their security
just completely voluntarily right plays
one of the questions they've been really
willing to hear our security advice
because they don't have a lot of
resident experience in Incident Response
or really digging in and finding
security problems so if we've got a
hundred and what did you say 121
utilities part of this coalition do you
feel like the security expertise is
resident within that group to be able to
actually respond or are we gonna end up
with a an issue where we have 120
electricians plumbing so that's a great
question so within within the the
current membership of cyber mutual
assistance we've got majors like big
major utilities with multiple millions
of customers and we've got utilities
that maybe are serving twenty thousand
customers in you know in the middle of
you know far away so there's a
combination there's a recognition though
that frankly the incentive for the
majors to play is it's in everybody's
interest to help the little operator out
because if you're an attacker are you
gonna you can go after the major and
really beat on them hard you I guess you
could how better wouldn't it be like
easier to go after that the smaller
operator so the objective is to have
sharing sharing of expertise in and
building a community across all the
utilities that are a part of this so
we've met
we had an in-person meeting in February
we're gonna have another one in August
but but to really build a community into
within several mutual assistance one of
the things that we strongly recommend is
that the utilities take a look at their
footprint and they look at their
neighbors to the north south east east
and west and if their neighbor and
utility is not a part of several mutual
assistance for them to poke them and say
hey there's a thing you should be a part
of and if their neighboring utility is a
part of a cyber mutual assistance you
poke them you say hey we need to talk
about what is really going on within our
systems and we need to share we need to
we can talk about indicators of
compromise and we need to have a cup of
coffee while the sky is blue and you
know we can patiently talk with one
another but before the storm starts this
is another question for David
specifically with mutual assistance one
of the things you have with the hardware
the the power lines etc is they are all
standardized and easily replaceable
now with the Cypress cyber mutual
assistance is there also a regulatory
look towards standardization and
interoperability from a you know
software systems perspective or
industrial control systems perspective
with these utilities so we recognize
there's like super important differences
between setting poles and hanging
conductor because you know a journeyman
electrician is a journeyman electrician
and they're they're pretty fungible you
can move them all over the United States
it's no problem
with with cyber and with utilities and
industrial control systems they are
extremely customized to the specific
application we we get that there is I
think that as a general matter there's
not high interest in the notion of oh we
should all just do standardized
implementation because I talk about
common mode failure I mean to a degree
common mode failure is is already a kind
of a pretty high risk when we look at
the number of major systems integrators
industrial control system vendors that
essentially all utilities use there's
there's not there's not tons of them how
the specifics of their implementation
will vary widely in terms of
configuration files in the cetera but
the hardware itself is pretty common
throughout the industry so one of the
issues that came up was when when the
program was first being built people
said how do you wish to do this should
we have a database we'll have a database
of skills oh that would be awesome and
then other people said that's a terrible
idea
a database of skills and personnel and
all that it doesn't make sense it
changes a hundred times faster than you
can actually ever write it or share it
don't do that so what the what the
counterpoint is is don't inventory you
know all potential stuff but if there's
a utility who has a problem and they
call for help we expect that utility to
be able to say what it is that they need
because if you call for help really you
should be able to say what I need I need
five forensic examiners I need 50 break
fix technicians to be able to say yes
yes yes I agree and enter a 20 digit
license code you know based off a gold
image or I need I need
reverse-engineering animalist sir what
is it that I need so the the utility
who's got the problem has to be able to
define effectively what it is that they
need and then we believe that the
community will be there to provide the
answer to responsive to the need it to
make sense yeah one thing that's
interesting about that is I could see to
one of the previous questions that you
know if you have an organization that is
very immature in a certain capability
that might come into response like you
know let's I got in my consulting past
I've worked with big enterprises who are
you know they have great let's say pen
testing capabilities but they're
incident respond they've got like you
know two people who kind of do Incident
Response and everything is outsourced
for example like just because an
organization isn't or is big or is you
know fulfilling some the industry need
doesn't necessarily mean that they're
mature on all fronts and so like an
inventory of maturity like capability
maturity it could be an interesting like
proactive way to align the right
resources and groups to do a particular
response scenario I would think it would
also help to for the organizations who
are calling for help as well as the
others and have some cross-pollination
of ideas and skills and build up the
maturity and make it more standardized
systematized across the industry um my
question is for both David and Bo and I
hope this state doesn't deviate too much
from the focus but about a year and a
half ago I had a an occasion to attend
an FBI in forgot me ting where I met a
gentleman that was talking about
electronic or electromagnetic pulse EMP
threats and to be quite honest it was a
little bit of a stretch for me so we
investigated some more we went to the
National space weather workgroup meeting
that was held in Colorado a year ago and
one thing led to another and and and
what we came
is that that the electromagnetic
magnetic pulse is a huge threat to the
electrical grid and also that that in
traditional engineering methods we have
not addressed that possibility in so I'm
wondering from Bo's perspective as you
work with medical device manufacturers
if if that's being addressed or if that
has come up in the discussions I haven't
thought too much about EMP I know a lot
of people to find that it's a class of
electronic warfare where they also
classed cyber is a different part of
that I don't tend to just because
they're wholly different threats I mean
one is you know you're talking about
decimating a physical layer the other
one is pretty much everything else
medical device makers unless they're
dealing with radioactivity to begin with
they're not really thinking about
shielding other than what's required by
the FCC and and other governmental
agencies that regulate shielding
electromagnetic interference my my
personal feeling is if you're dealing
with an adversary who can muster the the
logistical and technical capability to
pull off an EMP you're probably talking
about a nation state or something very
near to a nation state anyways at which
point that's a higher bar then we'll be
able to get to with a lot of the things
it would be commercial grade stuff off
the shelf I don't know if you if you
wanted to tackle that or that's another
one where we could have a whole long
discussion over beers the Russians have
done certain things and other people
have done certain things so I'll take
that as an invitation to keep my
comments short because we will probably
talk about some other things as well one
of the things that that the electric
industry is doing is there's an
organization called the a pre the
electricity power Research Institute
they have launched a three-year program
to look at different aspects of EMP ie
IMI HMMP the whole deal in issue reports
throughout one of the challenges with
EMP is you don't have to start talking
very long before you start run into
classified space and one of the one of
the challenges is that utility operators
owners say ok if there is a if there is
a particular design basis threat give us
the specs and will totally buy equipment
that matches those specs and then we we
talked to our partners in DoD in DoD
says you know I would just love to tell
you but you know we we go above this
line and now I can't talk about anymore
because it's classified so it's a really
challenging topic in and I know that
there are certainly advocates who just
they love to get out their aluminum bats
actually and beat on the heads of the
electric sector and you know call us
really bad names I would say we're happy
to do what we know what to do in in
terms of things like design basis and
you know really the the technical issues
related to defending against those types
of events but frankly we also have a
dependency on our on our DoD to dissuade
or prevent that type of activity we're
not good at stopping misses so I see
we've got a handful of hands in the air
we've got about four minutes left before
we're gonna break for lunch we are going
to continue down into the pub 365 again
today so we can pick up some of these
conversations there but maybe we can do
like a lightning round of questions one
two three and then we'll do a lightning
round of answers up until our time okay
so my question is for Bhavana is it
Carolyn or Carolyn
Carolyne so as far as electronic medical
records go you talked about ways to
convince management to spend money on
security teams and you talked about you
know compliance with industry standards
compliance with regulations and then
risk as far as the industry standards
and regulations go what's the current
state of them are they convincing to
upper management is it helpful to have
more or is it counterproductive to have
more you know for for EMR companies okay
so a question one is regulations do they
help our herd get get budget for
management are we supposed to answer we
saw let's get three questions and then
we'll go with the answers that way we'll
have more time cool we're running low on
time so just a comment rather than a
question Steve I'm from the ISP I'm here
to help the good news is that things are
probably a little bit better than you
think there's definitely a lot of room
for improvement though so find me
afterwards I have some very specific
suggestions for you this is questions
also for Caroline um you mentioned
before doing the I ego shaming of your
ears your CFO saying all the people
around us our peers are doing better
than we are and so forth so you should
put more money into that one of the
things that Tom the Verizon but not
quite here yet is insurance and at some
point the CFO can very legitimately say
it's gonna cost me how much to fix this
myself and there's no guarantee we've
actually fixed it versus I can pay that
amount or potentially less and even if
it happens we're covered and do you see
that trend toward insuring it go against
give me more money all the time
yeah so is it cool I can just respond to
these really quickly in the interest of
time so with regards to the insurance
thing cyber insurance has actually been
around for a long time an organization I
worked for 10 years ago
it and I think it's a really important
option to put on the table especially
with you know the gentleman back here
one of the themes that you've referenced
is actually a skill set problem so we
have a major talent shortage in
cybersecurity and if you can't find
people to do the job even if you have
the money to pay for them then maybe
insurance is a better option for you
know it really depends on the
organization I don't know that in a lot
of cases only insurance is gonna be your
best option
I think when it comes to cyber insurance
just like when it comes to life
insurance health insurance you gotta
look at the fine print so when does it
apply and when does it not apply and
when it does not apply what sort of
mitigating controls do you have so I
think it's a valid option to put on the
table and then you know the conversation
really becomes about about under what
circumstances would we not be able to
make a claim and how do we account for
those and with response you know my
response to kind of the question about
industry standards best practice
frameworks it's it's another like kind
of lame response like it depends on who
you're talking to but but that's the
truth right so when I was at Zynga we
were starting the security team from
scratch they got a lot of money because
they had a major incident and they said
okay build a team and we built the team
and then we hired a CIO and the CIO said
to my boss who was a CIS oh hey it seems
like you have a lot of really smart
people and they're really busy but how
do I know that they're working on the
right things and you know we responded
and she said well it would be a lot
easier for me if you guys would just do
an ISO assessment and then I would have
an industry level accepted you know lens
through which to view your program the
other common scenario that I see is so I
work for a vendor and our clients have
their preference for whatever you know
lens they see the world through and a
lot of times there's a framework or best
practice and so we'll kind of ask like
well what do you what do you need and to
what extent can the documentation that
we've prepared accommodate that but I'll
let Bob speak to the medical specific
component of that yes
so one interesting thing that I've found
about both regulatory standards and you
know the best practice like ISO and you
know NIST or whatever other standards is
that for us it has been convincing in
the sense that it's been in hindrance
for business development purposes or
other things that the company is trying
to do so like you know HIPAA if you're
dealing at health healthcare is like the
very very low bar that you have to get
across but you know doing something like
CMS is a RS or suck to or you know all
of those other I trust all of those
other regulatory or industry standards
when you're when you're working with
other enterprises or you're trying to
sell into new markets those things are
enablers for the business they're not I
mean they are a pain in the ass but if
you frame them as enablers and things
that are gonna actually help you help
the business owners open up new doors I
found that to be really really effective
so like for instance going through sock
to sock to type to audit for us for a
couple of our products allows us to just
get into a lot more enterprises for
example and then one other quick comment
on the insurance so we we have cyber
liability insurance and one thing that
is worth keeping in mind that if you
don't have some semblance of a security
program in place they can refuse to give
you coverage or they can refuse to pay
like they reserve the right to pay out
claims
so you know anyone who like a CFO who is
thinking that they're just going to
throw you know 50 grand and insurance
annually and get everything taken care
of like a couple million dollar policy
they're probably hearing some pretty bad
advice and it's so it's worth getting in
front of that all right well thank you
to the panelists again
[Applause]