so morning everyone I'm actually
surprised people are here after well
yesterday normally people are not up
this morning
yeah this is scamming the scammers let's
go ahead and get started I have a lot of
knowledge to go through in a short
amount of time so the table of contents
for this we're going to go to
introduction I have to do legal of
course we're going to an intro to the
talk some exploits concept other inputs
skip over number four there we're going
to go to a demo but first we have to
pray to the demo gods we all know if we
do not say that short prayer it will not
work then you know the actual demo if
you actually want to contact me go right
ahead I'll give you my information I'll
even give you my phone number don't call
it so Who am I
my name is Nathan you can find me on
twitter at log killer IT guy
specifically a IT manager I'm also a
physical penetration tester I do some
development work like Java get to see
Python I can't say who I work for only
thing I can say is they're at this con
free time I'm working a home lab just to
get a dumb a power bill is insanely high
I do do safety and security for Circle
City con besause Las Vegas so I'm the
guy that makes sure you don't get drunk
and fall over and hurt yourself I'm also
a staff member for skylock con as well
and I'm Austin organizer of be size
Lexington and let some teen Kentucky
even though I do not live there so let's
go ahead and go through legal first off
if you're sensitive profanity
this talk will might have some profanity
in it also I am NOT going to read this
out you can totally read it the email
address is valid please if you want to
spam it make sure you lose some good and
while your Joe STIs that does go to my
actual lawyer dumb
mmm so cool we're done with the legal
stuff we can actually get on to the meat
and potatoes of this talk so let's go
ahead and go through the introduction I
always like to start out presentations
with a survey
I wonder who never heard this topic all
I know almost everyone here has well you
know what it's probably not gonna play
but yeah it's not gonna play fantastic
but most of you guys have heard of a
Microsoft Tech Support Scheme call
hopefully mostly you have hopefully most
of you guys have fucked with them
amazing so reason I'm doing this talk I
have had so many of my co-workers and
even our call centers have been getting
these calls so much so I've had to
actually load up rededicated laptops of
deep-freeze so these guys can screw with
it and you know I've also given them
ransomware okay but this is happening
too much in these days and it's that
you're getting bad Americans lost for
seven point we're billion dollars of
this in 2015 I can't even imagine how
much money that would actually be be
course I don't make that much I wish it
did but this is gonna be little bit
small but the survey was actually done
by true caller true caller is a spam
blocking service you install on your
phone Android iPhone if you have a
Windows Phone I feel sorry for you but
actually is a service that actually
blocks each type of calls from a
database so they've done a survey of all
the user that done it all the ones that
were willing to participate and you know
these are ways that they actually you
know block or how they stop or once they
have been scammed what do they do well
you know some of them down on a caller
ID yet they check their phone bill they
call the carrier they call it the
authorities they send up for credit
monitoring awesome they send that for
the Do Not Call Registry which for the
this would do absolutely nothing because
these guys are already breaking law whoo
what makes you think you're gonna follow
federal law he'll change your phone
number but the one I'm really concerned
about is the one second from the top did
nothing people did enough and bees are
ashamed they would do nothing because
they just gave you their credit card
number to someone over the internet and
just gave them money people don't want
to admit that and it's getting so bad
that over a hundred people a day are
getting scanned an average price is 200
to 500 dollars you think about that
before come before Commission cuts
there's a lot of money it's absolutely
disgusting how these guys are doing this
but you know if we got Gordon Ramsay in
there they'll be amazing
so here's just a typical list of what
we're going through these days so of
course you have your vacation ones which
those are really nice you know warrant
for your arrest tech support you know
you have to get personal scams you do in
person looking on self like eBay and
Amazon eBay just a scam itself it's all
PayPal but how are people actually
protecting us that's the real question I
like to add here so I am going to
display who my carrier is I don't care I
use t-mobile if you have used t-mobile
or if you currently have them you'd know
of this wonderful feature that goes on
your phone call scam block it will
actually do a network over right for the
caller ID display it is a scam phone
number and if you even subscribe
subscribe to their name ID service it'll
actually to con the call in general so
you don't even get the phone call
they've done this because of course
people are losing money they want to
make sure their customers are actually
basically being secure they want to make
sure their customers are not following
to this and they least release this
really cheesy promo video of how it
actually works on a why go slow-motion
that's it very cheesy but you also see
how easy it is to a roll on an iPhone
and then you're enrolled simple as that
that's all you have to do to
Network basically this network caller ID
feature it's fantastic it works great
and this is even well it looks like this
was taken on an LG g4 board up the phone
number
I caught truck hauling it was it was
spoofed but this is what looks like and
of course you know you'll see on the
actual dialer this is also what it looks
like so it helps people you'll actually
stop getting this done to them so that's
one great way people are actually
helping us stop this and of course not
having money stolen so what are some
exploits in some concepts we can do for
this but first I have some questions how
can we get these out of offline that's
my main thing this is going to be part
of the exploit part we have three ways
we can do this one we can do scan
baiting em you guys actually know what
that is wow if you get a phone call from
and you start fucking with them that's
called scam baiting you start doing us
to some exploits which will go over a
quarter see gauzy your typical social
engineering and have phone that way so
let's start with exploitation how come
you actually exploit some of these phone
systems well the what I have found the
most common phone system used by these
scammers is 3c x36 is a free PBX that
you can actually download on their
website get a license key you have a
a.com you get a free license key who
knew but is a windows-based PBX it can
run all on net you can write your own
net app so even integrate into it so
it's actually a pretty powerful software
but it has this you know it has those
nice vulnerabilities so I went on Fiverr
and I posted this ad I'm still inside up
for you
$50 yeah just give me $50 I'll set it up
for you you might have a backdoor in it
but who knows so I set this up and I
she got tons of messages about this hey
will you set my phone says hey we sent
my phone system
they got one message in particular hey
we are based in Pakistan we need a phone
system to do technical support for
Americans and Canadians with their
Microsoft Windows operating system about
viruses great phantoms that's actually
what I wanted I wanted that message to
come in and you know what they didn't
even buy the basic they bought the
premium delivery it is almost just like
Amazon Prime but you know cool I install
their system for them I set up all those
engines I give them support but then of
course you know I have to change the
root password I keep the private keys
for the Linux distro that this runs on
they're not going to SSH access and you
know here's my packages so you will see
the premium unlimited entrance I started
three days
oops but set this up for him and
actually got into the system now we'll
let you be displaying a demo system not
their system Diaz they've already taken
down reported to authorities they gave
me their real address fuck's sake they
gave you through legit address in a
legit business name really but this is
just one simple way we can do it of
course I got legit entries and Nagi did
help some doctors offices and everything
on that yeah but a couple of things
about this don't fuck it up if you're
actually gonna do this make sure you do
it right and make sure you're at not
showing I'm gonna screw you over by this
yeah who cares also don't be an idiot
see above all so let's go ahead and go
on to some social engineering so the
weird thing about these offices we all
know there's these mom-and-pop shops or
you know smaller doctor's offices about
ten users they only have 80 these guys
have four users and they have a DFS this
is actually a system that I found
what using shown in and you know I just
went in there yeah I changed it non
InfoSec and change the password from
administrator to password one I don't
think they still guessed it but this is
one thing that they do and they leave
all these ports open they basically have
their firewall to allow every single
port but you know you're doing that
customer service for or customer service
for them you don't want your network to
be bought just to love everything in
screw it within the you know they also
do know the syn password never expires
ok cool gotta password amazing the weird
thing about this one the IG done to get
these screenshots I went in change your
whole entire domain system change
everything to my information so now they
they can't even log in properly because
they probably don't even know what the
domain actually is yeah who cares but
the weird thing was that also ran
BitLocker networking lock these guys
were actually securing systems with
deep-freeze BitLocker and some other
suite of tools to actually stop some of
the stuff we're actually going over do
you guys were actually gettin smart
which is the sad part these are actually
hiring real engineers well we're done
this is not row engineer um but they're
actually hiring real IT guys to actually
start doing this stuff this is a stupid
why are they doing this well of course
money but also they do have a couple of
you know they actually started also
doing training the one I want to say
about training I've actually had one
basically was a blower reach out the
company actually bought training from
social engineer that is that was needs
dollars where for training to stop
social engineering attacks you tell how
much money these guys are making so I
didn't go over a little bit of scam
baiting but basically we've already
explained what it is well so basically
how can get it off offline scam baiting
is fun yet stupid
you can be on the phone call for four
plus hours screw of them yeah you know
you stop someone else from getting
scammed but your whole day's been wasted
if you're at work getting paid for it
sure system exploitation it's fun yeah
illegal Astrix I don't know your little
applause in your area if you're not
random country in the world I don't know
if your laws are only they knows in
Canada it's illegal
so engineering well it's fun it's really
fun and especially get their information
and get access to everything they own
cool you're basing it on the company so
it's like of these how can we get
people's money back you give your credit
card to them they take about three
hundred dollars okay well I've also
found out that most of these guys are
also using stripe for the payment
processing stripe it's an easy
alternative you can actually integrate
it in almost anything and you can
actually immigrate into 3cx phone system
as well so you can do payments right
over to foam but stripe is also getting
this really well what they were actually
doing this amazingly well because if
you're having fraud
they just ban your account instantly
almost then they report your information
to other credit card processors so you
could never sign up again for another
credit card processor they're actually
doing it right some are now using PayPal
for the processing and PayPal does
doesn't care you suffer as me PayPal
account sees you want if you get limited
make a new one with someone else's
information you have credit card
processing so IG did reach out to stripe
to see if we can get some more
information but they actually told me
they have actually stopped over 500
accounts for this 500 accounts
shut down overnight just because of
fraud for the sub situation so you know
we kind of have a party about actually
getting people's money back because to
be honest I feel getting that little old
lady's money back is some of the best
things ever you know you get you get
their database you call the little ways
saying hey this was a scam you're in
I just refunding all your money back to
your card
that is probably the best thing where I
have had doing this but again we still
have we can fight back well we can do
systemization
such engineering or just be a dick
reason I say be a dick is course
maneuver
the most use phone system is 3cx it
looks nice is very pretty is designed
for someone that doesn't want to use COI
yeah we're doing phone system CL is kind
of a pain in the ass but there was one
great exploit in version 15 oh that lets
you download the whole backup it without
credentials I didn't reach out they did
fix the vulnerability actually insanely
amount of time they report about to me
two days later saying it was resolved
and pushed out in the next update but
simply you can go to backup get their
backup file and the cool thing is these
aren't encrypted
you cannot encrypt these so but also
presentable yeah this will be URL I'm
not gonna lie
remove after remove everything after
list and then you get a list like this
so the cool thing is again you don't
need you don't need credentials at all
to download these so you see where it
says download ID basically you get the
ID so if we want to get do this backup
right here
I cannot draw if you want get this back
up right here tapping the ID it'll start
downloading great
then you'd open up the XML file it's
super easy just open up a XML file that
has random letters and numbers of sound
secure but again it's legitimately not
encrypted here's username and password
for Aven
that's it you now own the whole phone
system and if they even have the proper
and by sensing for this phone system you
can even set up a backup phone system or
a failover phone system and just have
all calls out to your new phone system
they won't even notice the difference
you know I'm sitting acceptance all
their traffic on your network
hey you're cool you're good then so with
this information we just do this sit
back relax and let the fun go on but the
years just some simple ways we actually
can do some of this material
these are simple ways we can actually
get these guys offline get people's
money back in more information the
easiest way I will say to start getting
all this information these guys just
don't care they want money so you can
easily probably get get them to install
TeamViewer on their computer and just
give them the get the idea password
start doing the selling file transfer a
lot of people that they've actually
scammed or some of them have even
started using SQL services like on AWS
cool thing is AWS actually it's a great
policy if you're doing illegal activity
on their soft on their services yeah
they'll shut you down reporter yeah who
knew so I like to do a little bit of a
live demo here just in just some ways if
we actually do get access to some of
their internal systems how we can
actually screw them over so I am going
to that I don't care about Inc shut up
so I see I can have a soft phone running
over here the weird thing about 3cx is
you you really don't configure it
yourself
you basically get a configuration file
so if I open up sublime here's the
configuration file shows everything it
has everything in here you can have as
long as you get this configuration file
you've now on that ascension it is an
admin essentially you can even log in to
the software so I have to
dear my soft phone and I have t-mobile
digits this is not my phone number this
is not a valid forum I ain't cancelling
this line as soon as I get out this talk
so if you want to call it or text it
fantastic I don't care it's gonna be
gone he's now my phone numbers to play
that phone numbers displayed to the
whole entire world fantastic
so one simple way I found that you can
actually go ahead and do this whenever I
was actually doing Fiverr for this I use
lightsail I just closed it when I say
was a simple way to get VPS is running
on Amazon so had this demo here cost $5
they don't need to know that but
basically you can just go ahead and make
a new instance on Debian go back over
here and let's look at some of the
essentials you'll see this one is
registered and if we go in here the
weird thing that makes me go crazy is
this that is one of these simple ways I
have found to actually help so if I
change this from nine one one two oh one
one eight nine nine seven two five three
so so that's the easiest way to remember
it you seeing it and it's like oh it's
your head forever but you know it's not
the emergency service is your emergency
services so now we have that new caller
ID if I simply just want to go to a five
nine nine seven nine sixteen eighty six
if you're like me I am NOT going to
answer a phone call from that number is
that I don't think we're getting roaming
charges are like international calling
fees like what the hell is that
or sometimes you can actually even get
it to do caller ID so sometimes if you
do this FBI Los Vegas
you actually pulling this phone number
here and actually you look like you're
called from the FBI who's my mr. FBI
phone call no one so that's one way you
can actually stop this if you get access
to your phone system make a failover
change your caller Ids is fantastic you
can even make your own ascension and
start even getting into the reception
cool have a Las Vegas area code or here
but you can actually give me a nurse
that trunks cancer accept rent service
you have full access to SEP trunk cool
you can even add yourself into the call
queue so you start getting their phone
calls you actually start getting phone
calls at your reception and if you still
use fax make a fax machine I don't know
who uses fax it's absolutely stupid but
then again you can also get done with
the logs see all whoo let's see you who
you've called or see who they've called
and if I go here if I really want to
screw them over if I really want to fuck
with them
I want to dial this number again and I
can actually look here I can actually
see a see status so you see what their
status is can make them do not disturb
and if I access to the supervisor portal
I could actually even go ahead and
disconnect their phone call over and
over and over again or join the call
barge them off and be done with it well
those are some simple ways we can screw
these guys over I will give you my
contact information up crap I'm not
having a good morning you know script
here this is my contact information if
you need me reach out to me email
complaints do not call that phone number
that is for the FBI unless you really
want to get arrested but tweet at me if
you have any questions and now be more
than happy to help you guys out
thank you you can
and up here with your mom pls one of our
sponsors
and I guess that said I need questions
right now we have a minute one question
all right thank you all we'll start here
in about five minutes
[Applause]