hey thanks for the big noise in the
small crowd um yeah so a sympathy for
the developer my name is Sara Gibson and
I work at Perico
I know that ro has so we we scan a lot
of applications we've used up for a
security testing do static and dynamic
analysis and we do a lot of it but
really large amount of it and I've been
working with scanned results at very
code for a little over five years and
I'm working with the results one kind of
another servo static and dynamic in a
bunch of different ways and right now
what I would I'm back talking with
customers so I'm dealing with results
that are down in the weeds dealing with
developers talking about what we find
helping them fix it instead of working
through their skin results and what it
is it's actually been found and I got
into this role about a year ago also
about a year ago certain audience member
so I need a research topic for Minkow
security course at Tufts University I
had a really great idea I thought and I
was gonna fix webgoat everythin like get
down I was gonna become like that
developer has been doing auto
etnographic study of what it's like to
fix web code and I submitted this
proposal and and Bing said it was a bad
idea he was like so you always research
on what's out there as far as these
flaws why don't you look at that is
there anything that's been been
published in the last a couple years
such as in the state of software
security report that's interesting over
time is there some trends is there some
data that's out there that's more
interesting than just fixing webco it
turns out yes yes there is so as I was
saying before very code has a lot of
data so we do a lot of scans and for a
lot of different organizations and we
have data and it gets published in this
form about once a year
and mostly annually and it's talking
about trends across applications across
across different industries a flaw that
we find for how they're fixed what's
happening some of those findings I was
like really surprised cuz they're really
similar over time and what I was
focusing on my sequel objection
it's the flaw type I wanted to fix and
webgoat it's fairly prevalent we find it
fairly often barracuda finds in static
scans fairly well pretty good at that
and we can detect fixes which was really
important because I really wanted to
know if people were fixing things that's
what I was interested in because I was
helping people fix things and I wanted
to know if I was effective so it I had
to be able to figure out or
programmatically that things were fixed
and I had made some assumptions I looked
at flaw prevalence data over previous
sauce reports and the numbers were
really flat and I didn't really
understand why I didn't really
understand what the metric was I had
assumed that was a metric that was
across the entire application base so
the prevalence was similar because
people were either not fixing very fast
but reducing what they were introducing
or as they were introducing flaws or
fixing them so this is an equilibrium I
had assumed this was flat because of
some poor of equilibrium and I want to
know why but it turns out that's not
what measurement is umm the measurement
is on first scam so of an application on
first scan a first static scam does it
have a sequel injection flaw if so then
it sort of shows up as in this
prevalence metric if not it doesn't and
it was a standard measurement across a
report one of the reasons why is because
it gets rid of some the variance a lot
of these applications are really
different really smalls and they're
really big so they might have lots of
different sequel injection flaws and
might have only one and this sort of
just take some of that away so you can
get down to just okay across this
application base of all applications
scanned with us how prevalent is it to
have an application that has sequel
injection and everyone poops
so the flaws happen I'm looking through
there seeing it really flat across all
those years I think that this just comes
down to flaws happen we know that
regular code quality issues happen we
know that you know we make the same
spelling mistakes over and over again we
know that we have as humans you know I I
know how not to have bruises what I move
in my house so I know how to do that I'm
still covered in bruises um I know how
to do these things but we make mistakes
we're human
so why will you pretend that security
flaws are different why are we thinking
that if we just teach the developers
enough it so he just gives them enough
information that their flaws are going
to go down because they're not so this
is the data this is so this is from 2013
through to mid 2017 and this is the
total sample size for this presentation
is about 150,000 scans this isn't but
the total sample size is about that big
of this so the mean is 31.9 that doesn't
mean that's how much exploitable sequel
injection that's how much we finding of
static analysis it's a pattern through
the application of tainted data from an
entry point through to a sequel
statement we do see a fairly steady rate
of exploitable sequel injection as well
through through dynamic but I'm not
really going into that here and then the
standard deviation this is ridiculous
it's it's it's tiny I just like I'm
really not gonna do any more of that
it's just flat but I did take a look as
I was curious okay fine it's really flat
against all of our data just they're
just like one organization that's just
dominating this is there if we slice to
the data by organization are we going to
see the same sort of pattern over time
yep we do I mean there's variance right
there not every organization is exactly
the same so this for me my husband
thinks they stopped using sequel
hi I didn't check this was randomly
selected in blind I don't know what
accounts they're they are fairly large
accounts or larger there are over a
hundred applications with us since 2013
and and 30% is is right around here so
you can see that it's pretty cluster
it's it's also flat and within these
organizations it's also fairly flat over
time so across these different
organizations of different industries
and different sizes because you above
100 but there's variants there and how
many scans there are we're still seeing
that same pattern which is I thought was
um kind of cool actually okay so we find
sequel injection we find it about the
same rate organizations don't seem to
get better over time some get worse at
introducing it right on first scan so
it's not that they never get better cuz
they do they get better once they have
that data in hand so fixed rate by
applications so this is similar
measurement to before so this is looking
at but at but a smaller sample size one
of the things that we we do is we'll
scan applications at different will say
this is a bucket of an application you
can scan whatever you want in the hope
is you're stating the same application
over and over again so I'm sort of
controlling for applications size to try
and control for that but we're seeing
that after three scans of the similar
application size all fixed twenty three
percent that's pretty great some fixed
twenty one no change
okay thirty that's guns that's not good
an increase in twenty six percent so
they kept going they were like let's go
I just assume that everyone's actually
as they're developing introducing more
flaws I suspect that what's happening is
that the that might be on me that's game
that might be something with it just not
fixing them and this is looking at
individual flaws so this is the
individual flaw fix phrase about forty
eight percent so of a flaw introduced on
that first scam what a forty eight
percent of them were fixed
but on the second scan more flaws are
introduced and they also have a fixed
rate and and so on so it does go down
it's not going up we are seeing a
decrease over time and flaws in in
applications but it's not that full
forty percent an individual flaw that
that much but in full applications
because as developers go there's more
flaws being introduced it's a slower
slower slope so good news but maybe not
perfect something else that seems kind
of cool and I'm ripping through this so
I apologize but we have a feature that
came out actually you can see when it
came out I'm so this is this is the same
data we saw before but a little
different so this orange line is all of
the scans again and I apologize if
that's a little blurry but the blue line
is not all the scans the blue line is
policy only so we introduced a feature
called sandbox which allows developers
to play it allows for consequence-free
scanning that doesn't go the development
team development team or so to the
security team the security team can look
if they want to you but doesn't get
pushed up to their level of alertness
right away so the security team is
doesn't you know if you have flaws
there's no consequences we've seen an
increase so we introduced it in 2014 hit
more across from 2015 in 2016 it became
generally available and in 2017 we're
seeing because it's not it's a minute in
one relationship we're seeing 90% of
first scans and sandboxes so you've many
look you've got several developers
working on a project they can all have
their own sandbox all scanning all
checking for their own code checking for
their own flaws fixing as they go so the
time it comes policy that's the only 26%
instead of 32 so I thought that was kind
of neat and also this idea that you know
developers are fixing flaws so it's not
just yeah we see the flaws we see that
flap we see that interdiction duction
rate sometimes if you're seeing that
over and over again
there's this idea of all developers
don't care they obviously just keep
introducing clauses or not learning why
is this happening well they they are and
you have to but they're not learning on
the introduction side right so it's not
that flaws are being introduced at a
different rate but we can see that if
you're giving them the ability to fix
them if we're giving them the tools to
be able to play and learn little fix+
we'll go through it and do it around the
time I was preparing this there's also
was a study that came out on general
code quality which I thought was kind of
cool this was a survey by O'Reilly and
and the software improvement group the
survey questions act about these are
general code quality tools so it wasn't
necessarily specific to security it was
general code quality sir but I think
it's important to see how we relate how
we fit into that landscape and it asked
a book if people use them and then of
those people who use code quality tools
and ask questions about native fix and
in that but 32 percent of respondents
reported finding before fixing 80% or
more of issues found using code quality
tools well we saw the 23 percent all fix
it turns out of that but sample 34
percent had 80% or more so it lines up
pretty nicely with with general code
quality with what people are self
reporting so that's kind of cool
what that was neat the bottom half does
not line up at all in the O'Reilly study
we had only 11% that that reported
fixing less than 20% of the issues we
obviously saw more than that we saw
people introducing more issues and we
have actually it's like 50 percent of
the sample had less than 20 percent fix
no change or more flaws so the bottom
end doesn't match up that might be one
of those things that self reporting you
say that you're better than
[Music]
or or it's possible that security has a
higher buried entry and that this is
actually where we start to see that you
know we do have some room to tip for
education and for help
I'm from being able to get in there and
make a difference and it's gonna be on
that low end that doesn't quite match up
again I suspect it's the mixture effect
it's probably a little bit of our low
self reporting as well as a as well as
just the fact that these plots can be
tricky like when you get these sequel
injection they're not always
straightforward sometimes it's just okay
make a prepared statement stick that
parameter into a prepared statement in
the way you go sometimes it's more
complicated than that sometimes the data
is coming from the sources and you
really just care about where it's coming
from you want to make sure because it's
a white list or what have you
and depending on how its set up and what
the design is so that I'm not sure at
that point where the the difference is
there but it might be a combination and
and so everything does anything affect
fix rates so this isn't directly from
the data I was looking at here this is
from the state of software security and
we did see that there were two things
that we track one is what I do the
remediation coaching so that's big
having a helpful ham somebody in the
security team sterve understands what's
going on who's familiar with code and
can get in there and help people
understand what the flaw is why it's
being reported why you should care about
it and then what you can do about it
it's that full range it's not just
here's how to fix it it's also hey why
do you care about this where does that
data really come from and then the other
part was elearning subscription so an
account that head e-learning also had a
faster Ryota fix so that was just having
some information
we were using that as a proxy for some
information with security and having
some developer knowledge of what
security flaws or in how to fix them and
it's like we're helping so what does
look like we're making a difference so
we're seeing that flaws get introduced
sort of no matter what but when we're
giving those that information to
developers they're they're fixing them
again maybe not fast as we want but
they're fixing them and when they have
that access to those consequence-free
scans to that sandbox we're seeing that
they're getting to them before security
even really steps in so they're able to
sort of do a lot of self help and then
be able to then bring the really hard
parts to security where we can work in
conjunction with them to allow everybody
to be successful so we can have that
collaborative relationship we can not be
necessarily just gatekeepers but also
people there to help push things forward
and I have rush like this I apologize
but um but so but me they learn for
questions but so which is why I have
some sympathy flaws happen you know
these are not just flaws because Avella
/ doesn't care whether you're not
showing up because your developers are
special this is normal and really where
the the difference is is going to be in
the fixing and non the finding you're
going to find flaws this isn't something
that you've punished over it's something
that you've worked collaboratively
together to try and get better and cuz
devs will work to fix findings and it'll
do even better when you help out and
then just if you look for flaws I think
that's the the big one the other part
from the O'Reilly study that actually
came out not in that paper but in
another article was that only 25% of
organizations for reporting running
static analysis at all which means that
a lot of people are not looking
sufficiently and people were self
reporting
that they didn't feel that they were
doing enough to even look we know the
flaws are there we know that if they're
found and you have the information and
tools to fix them that they get fixed so
be really cool people look for them yeah
and I Paulie oh that was really fast but
I love questions
yeah oh and there's gonna be a
microphone does that other can we just
be like really bad with the lovely
you're really official here cheating so
I feel like full disclosure I'm a
developer yeah and I've I spent a lot of
time helping developers solve this kind
of problem
SQL injection specifically I'm honestly
a little astounded at how low thirty
percent is it's higher
I think that's astoundingly well I think
it's way higher yeah you're probably
right
this is across all of our application
base not just applications that you use
sequel yeah at double mic action so yeah
so I probably probably has higher that's
sort of one of those I'd like to know
that too there was a really cool and
different project that looked at PHP
fine it just looked at PHP samples from
Stack Overflow over the last six years
and it looked and it starts up really
slow like there's not very many of them
and it goes really high but if you look
at it as a percentage of questions asked
on sequel it was fifty five percent and
it was fifty five percent the entire
time I think there was a little wiggle
because it went for a really small
sample size to a big one
yeah I suspect it's higher I mean you
get it I'm just gonna do my own evilly I
can tell you looking I'll be brutally
honest and tack on to that I'm looking
watching your presentation I went from
wanting to rage quit to being completely
mind blown that you know subscriptions
read learning subscriptions really help
yeah I mean how is that possible I mean
that's that I mean there's been stuff
about this stuff we have me above sequel
injection out there for years and
they've made that big of a difference
I'm like it's not it's not on the
introduction rating to probably has more
information on this because he's
[Laughter]
conveniently in the room but I'm
probably screwing up the TV thing and
not a question but our response one of
the things that we learned as we started
to do the studies that serious citing
here is that there's a lot of different
things that organizations that are
actually serious about educating
developers and fixing vulnerabilities
can do to to make you know things better
and eLearning you know actually offering
developers like formal training Eva to
see if it's CBT is one of them but that
also may be a proxy for other things
that they're doing like putting it in
developers goals or you know or you know
or something else like that so I one of
the cautions that we always have about
the data in studies like this is we're
measuring what we can measure we can't
actually measure that you know Bank XYZ
has their developers gold on application
security because we don't see that that
that data right I think in there yeah
I'm so Mike there was an extra man
[Music]
did you uh did you ever break this down
by language because I'm thinking like
for instance dotnet like the MVC they've
kind of mitigated some of that some of
the problems you can have a sequel
injection so again I kind of live in
this data right I'm about a large number
of the white man tattoo is done MVC and
and using sometimes it's using old parts
the framework and like so using legacy
systems and sometimes it's just getting
around the things that are there to try
and protect you so maybe um the language
data we have and was that I had access
to I didn't completely trust because
this is you know coming from our
database so it's being pulled out of our
customers skin information and sometimes
something some of those flags aren't the
way that they're recorded is a little
because you can scan multiple languages
in one in one scan and some in that flag
when I float it only has one language so
I know it's not perfect and so I didn't
want to do that I'm divided just in case
it wasn't but yeah I know that there is
variance by language I don't exactly
know which direction but I don't thought
and I him I don't think was um beautiful
and perfect okay so it's a little bit of
background I've gone back to my old
University and had polite conversations
about the curriculums and I I would say
that wouldn't think that you should do
if you continue with this is break it
down by wind the new hires from
universities come in and see if you see
like spikes that last because quite
honestly um people
say in this room Oh sequel injection has
been around for years yes but the people
coming on board this is the first thing
they've been heard of the concept of
sequel injection often times this job is
the first job they even heard of
databases so the other my other my other
rage well in that rage point it's just
one of those things I've come to the
point of my life of polite resignation
because it's a whole lot better in the
heart is that so often times you see yet
a new framework come out that talks
about how easy it is to create
applications and in the security part of
that framework is non-existent or shows
up later as an optional package so and
and I think they'll be interesting if
you could slice your data like on does
this application have those libraries
that represent security on and enabled
and see what happens to those numbers
that that would also be awesome but it
turns out that's really hard to see does
that but so if you wouldn't mind if I
ask you're doing development right now
so it's a very simple question how did
you learn like things like equal
injection and cross-site scripting and
all the application security stuff if
you wouldn't mind if you wouldn't mind
if I am and not at all for for me it was
just personal interest I'm kind of
overly pedantic and so sequel injection
is one of those places where it pays off
to be overly pedantic and so it was
something that I was always interested
in and wanted to talk anyone's ear off
the college so I'm not a good case study
for that
I had a hard time getting anyone
interested in actually solving the
problem and the ones that did get
interested I think I think probably hit
that 30 percent mark more often that the
30% mark I would say would was further
people that were interested okay thank
you very much
[Applause]