um so hey I'm Josh sacks so my my day
job isms a to scientists at Sophos and
I'm the talk I'm giving today is
entitled the new cat-and-mouse game
attacking and offending machine learning
based software so I'll start by just
introducing where I come from my team so
that's me on the upper left these are
all the people who I work with
so our groups a mix of machine learning
scientists and also engineers who helped
builds build prototypes and our role
within sofas as we build machine
learning models that go into our
firewall products into our sandbox
product and Torrie endpoint security
products that kind of thing we are we
are hiring so if you're interested let
me know
[Laughter]
okay I'll start with an outline of the
talk so I'm gonna start by discussing
why I think machine learning security
matters a lot I'm going to talk about
the increasing role of machine learning
in in the technology landscape let me go
on to sort of set up this is my
discussion of missioning layering
security by just giving it a brief
overview of what how I see what machine
learning is just in case they're machine
learning sort of neophytes in the room
to make sure everybody's on the same
page then I'm gonna talk about machine
learning attack and defense go into a
little bit of bacca demmick literature
on attacking and defending machine
learning models and finally I'm gonna
give a case study where I show how I can
attack a machine learning model that
we're actually we actually built and are
using it at Sophos and talk a little bit
about defense also okay so let's get
into it so so that this quote is a play
on the comments or tech aphorism
software is eating the world which maybe
some of you guys have heard too so this
idea that since like the 80s and 90s
right you're seeing software pop up in
place in unexpected places and it's sort
of ubiquitous throughout our society
whether it's in the fast food industry
or in hospital illustrate places where
software wasn't a key factor net now it
is right into what we care a lot about
soft software
wherever it pops up and software
security as security experts right so I
think I think we're gonna be seeing
machine learning popping up everywhere
in a similar way over the next couple
decades so it's a one way of framing
this right is that we've had a series of
industrial revolutions over the last
couple centuries each each of which was
driven by a new technology right it's a
steam power in the 18th century like
mass production driven by electricity
and in the late 29
in the early 20th centuries then the IT
revolution that our generation is sort
of lived through and and a lot of people
a lot of economists and technologists
are saying and I tend to agree with them
right that we're gonna be seeing over
the next few decades a big shift and the
way that we we live our lives and run
the economy based on based on machine
learning artificial intelligence whether
it's the transportation industry right
with trucking and self-driving trucks
and cars whether it's education right
and new education platforms that rely on
on machine learning etc so machine
learning machine learning is gonna be
more important than this machine
learning security is gonna be more
important so our community tends to see
cyber security risks everywhere and
everywhere software exists right and I
think we're gonna be seeing I think
increasing we need we're gonna need to
sort of learn more about machine
learning and think about the site of the
cyber security risks that pertain to
machine the machine learning as well
okay so I'm gonna bet so before talking
about machine learning security is when
I back up and give some machine learning
basics how many of you guys would say
you're pretty fluent and the way say
like neural networks or support vector
machines work ok that's what that's what
I was hoping you said so a lot of people
aren't says that hopefully this will be
helpful to you guys okay so I'm gonna
today to try to illustrate some of the
basic ideas behind gnashing there I'm
gonna walk through a toy example since
this is a security audience and we're
all security people in them to walk
through a use case where we build a
machine learning system that detects
malware so to get into this example so
he says imagine I want to build a
malware detector that just uses three
attributes of software binaries to
detect whether or not the min the
malware is a binary as malicious or not
so so let's say to see these three
attributes or how how compress the file
is how big the file is and the number of
printable strings in the file so so if I
sort of if it let's say have a data set
of files and I extract these attributes
from the files I can plot them in this
three dimensional space right and
suppose my malware and is all sort of in
this area of the three dimensional space
and my benign where is all on this area
the three dimensional space right so the
red dots here are malware and the blue
dots here are benign where then I can
pose the machine learning problem is it
sort of as a mathematical problem right
of identifying a plane right that
separates that the blue dots from the
that's right so we can pose as a
mathematical problem then the problem is
to solve it so in the image I just
showed you there's there's a plane that
separates the examples in the real world
usually we need to find a much more
complete and complicated function right
so like these lines in this image
separate the the green dots the code
let's call those benign where and the
red dots let's call those malware right
and the mathematical problem is is to
find a function that sort of that
defines all of these lines here let's
call those lines decision boundary is
right because we're making a decision if
you're on this side of the boundary
right your benign where if you're on
that side of the boundary your your
malware so everybody with me so far
okay so there's this sort of geometric
intuition to have how much in learning
works obviously so this is a
two-dimensional case with two features
this is the three-dimensional case and
in real-world machine learning systems
you've got like thousands of dimensions
right so you can't visualize them but
it's the same geometric ideas that they
drive in so how do we create a decision
boundary I'm gonna I'm gonna show if
technology cooperates here and maybe I
won't show a video let's see if this
works there we go okay so so here's a
video in which we watch a neural network
which which is shown on the right
learn as as part of a training process
write a good decision boundary for
different data sets right so what you're
seeing is sort of any of these
animations the neural network starts out
by not having a good decision boundary
separating the the green from the blue
dots and then as the training process
goes on right it's sort of learned how
to separate their greens from the red
how does this learning process work and
I think a good intuitive way of
understanding it is through this knob
metaphor so imagine these knobs on the
Left if you if you sort of tweak them
they they change this decision boundary
in the image right sort of like an
etch-a-sketch but with like a million
knobs straight so you're sort of moving
the knobs and the decision boundary
changes position so but so the problem
is to turn the knobs into just the right
position so that the green dots are you
know that benign wire is separated from
the malware so how do we know how to
turn the knob so in modern so in neural
networks which are currently a an
important sub area of machine
the way that we learned that the way
that we do it is is through some simple
calculus basically and in this iterative
process called stochastic gradient
descent so the basic idea is that we can
use some calculus to determine for all
of the knobs what direction we should
turn them in and in to what degree but
the calculus isn't perfect right so we
can't just solve the problem by doing
that we have to take sort of a little
step and then we look to see how good
the decision boundary is and then we
take another little step bite by running
the calculus again this process is
called so figuring out what direction to
turn the knobs in into what the group
degree is called back property we'd use
it algorithm called back propagation to
do that and then actually in the
iterative process by which we'd sort of
turned and check and turn in check is
called stochastic gradient descent and
there's a lot more depth than what I'm
giving here but this is just an
intuitive description of how it works
so these are so the two simple idea is
that you just I just described it right
the idea of a decision boundary in this
geometrical space and the process by
which we learn the decision boundary
through this sort of knob tweaking and
learning process are really the
foundations under which that the complex
and modern neural networks that are used
it like the Facebook's and googles of
the world work right so you get these
really complex neural network
architectures like the one shown on this
image this is a famous neural net called
Alex Ned that's a computer vision neural
network so it involves like dozens of
layers of neurons thousands of neurons
right but but but the whole system
really is like what it would announce to
is it identifies a decision boundary
between two different types of images
and it's in its tuned to this sort of
knob tuning process okay so um I'm gonna
move on from so that that's sort of my
brief spiel about how machine learning
works I'm gonna move on to talking about
machine learning security now and
specifically subverting machine learning
classifiers so subversion to me machine
learning systems is currently the
current in the current state of the art
is it's it's quite possible this over
Michigan learning systems and it's it's
relatively easy so it's sort of
dramatized that I want to walk through
an example of the way an attacker can
separate it's considered a computer
vision system so look at these images
here and and so and we're gonna talk
about a computer vision system and the
way in which we can trick it into into
thinking this school bus it's a
different kind of artifice
right so if so imagine I'm an attacker
and my goal is to get a computer vision
system to confuse the school bus for an
ostrich right so a burden and so the way
the way I do that at a high level and
rate is I compute a delta to all these
pixels so so so for each pixel a small
sort of change that I'm gonna change to
its magnitude so the Delta is pictured
here right so these are this is what I'm
gonna add to add to all the pixel values
in this image in order to get a new
image that's gonna confuse the computer
vision system and what I have here on
the right is the new image that the
results from taking this image adding
this specially crafted Delta right and
then and then getting this new image and
it turns out that so there's really no
visual difference for to the human eye
in between these two images but the one
on the left is classified with high
confidence by the computer vision system
as a school bus and the one on the right
is classified with high confidence is an
ostrich right so this is this is
interesting I mean so this is a toy
example in a real world you know case
you could you could you could smuggle
porn onto Facebook or wherever you're
violating somebody's torn Terms of
Service by using a Delta like this and
computer vision systems would miss it
right you can get you can make your way
through spam filters that look at images
right by subverting them in this way so
that there are real-world consequences
to be able to being able to subvert
computer vision systems in this way so
let's go back to the decision boundary
idea and sort of think about how this
attack works in a more mathematical
sense so suppose suppose this is my
suppose we have this decision boundary
and it separates sort of the world of
images between sort of the the school
bus territory and the ostrich territory
right so if you thing about it this way
so all of these red dots straight are
images of school buses that are machine
learning system has correctly sort of
placed in the red zone right so it gets
those images right and all of these all
of these green dots are examples of
Oster states right and the machine
learning system is sort of learned to
discriminate between the tube based on
this decision boundary so that this is a
goal of the attack right is to take an
image of the school bus and sort of
shove it somehow over into this Green
Zone without changing the way it's
received by the human eye right every
every following and so it's so how do we
do that so it turns out we can use the
same kind of mathematical ideas that we
use in the training process for the
machine learning system in order to
craft
at Delta like what I should in order to
shove the example over the decision
boundary to do that the basic attack
shown at the school best example you
need access to the to the model code and
all of the model parameters basically
you need access to the model and so in
the real world you can always do that
right so if I'm attacking like Facebook
or like if I'm attacking like GG mail
spam filter and great I'm not I don't
actually enlist impact into Google's
servers but I don't have access to the
model so that's an issue for an attacker
in the real world there's a way around
so the the problem of having to have
access to the model though which is
what's called what's what we can call a
proxy attack so basically if I have
access to let's let's say I don't have
access to Google spam filter but I can
send millions of emails through the spam
filter and see what gets classified as
spam and what doesn't then I can
actually build a model that attempts to
replicate the results of Google's spam
filter and my own machine linear model
and then I can do I can do this attack I
can do the school bus attack against my
own model and it turns out that the
attacking my own model which has been
trained to mimic the Google own model
actually will reliably get through at
least in experiments it's been shown
that it can reliably get through the
Google models is a sort of called a
proxy an attack so I've been talking
about images and the way we can subvert
computer vision systems and I haven't
been talking a lot about programs right
like malware versus benign where
programs and this is because it's harder
to subvert systems that classify malware
versus benign where and the issue is
that so with images you can image this
gracefully degrade straight I can change
every pixel value and an image and and
shove it over the decision boundary
it'll look visually similar to the
original image but the program I can't
go and change every byte value right it
just won't run and malware and so a
malware author who wants to subvert a
machine learning based malware detector
it has has two problems right they need
to get through the machine learning
system they also have to have their
program work and it's it's much harder
to accomplish that it's hard to
accomplish that task right so it makes
it makes it trickier to get it is still
very possible but it makes it trickier
to get get programs through machine
learning based detectors I'm not gonna
talk too much about the academic
literature on attacking and defending
machine learning models by just want to
give you guys a sense of the the back
and forth and the back and forth that's
going on in academic literature about
how to attack and defend machine
learning systems so for example it so
that so that
school bus attack is sort of based on
ideas that come from Ian's good fella
who's sort of a superstar and the
machine learning security space he came
with a method that uses model gradients
so it requires access to the model to
support machine learning classifiers
somebody else came up with a defense
called distillation that people were
excited about and appeared to work and
then somebody else came out with a paper
defensive distillation is not robust
ever so you know said that actually
shows that that doesn't work you know
you can you can you can tweak the
gradient based method in a small way you
can get past it right so we're seeing a
lot of there's a lot of interest in this
area right now amongst computer
scientists and using a lot of
back-and-forth and it's basically
defending against these kinds of attacks
as an unsolved problem basically and
like many things in the security field
right I think attackers have the
advantage right now okay so the last
thing I'm going to go through is a case
study where so to the background a case
study where where I attack and defend a
security machine learning model that we
have in our group and so foes the
background to this is we've started a
project within our data science group
where we're going through an attacking
our and our machine learning models so
the models we actually have out in
deployment and models that we plan to
deploy just as a kind of Red Team
exercise and then we're working on
figuring out defenses because we want to
be prepared for potential attacks that
happen in the wild so so the target is a
model that pretended before conferences
so it's exposed neural network this is a
neural network that we use to detect
malicious file paths registry keys in
URLs so as part of a larger defensive
system that we have a net Sophos here's
some examples of kind of URLs that the
system detects right so so so if you
look through these URLs right the first
one is a URL that points to a trojan and
svchost.exe the second one is a phishing
URL that this attempts to steal people's
Apple login credentials and the third is
a PayPal phishing link right so if you
guys like so these look suspicious yeah
if you guys like okay so they obviously
look suspicious so they look suspicious
to the human eye so our idea was that
you know and machine learning systems
should also be able to detect that
they're suspicious right and it turns
out I'm not gonna show accuracy results
but it works well enough that word you
know it's a model that we use internally
and so first so I want to demonstrate
how if I'm an attacker I can get past
this this model
so I mean first to show some that you've
attacks against it so Matt my goal isn't
as hacker in this case is to craft a
fishing URL that will trick like my mom
or you know my grandpa right like into
into clicking on it but which also gets
past the classifier so I can't just
randomize too much about the URL right I
needs to look like you're given some
fishing URL but it also needs to get
past my internal network so I'm this so
I start I'm going to start this
demonstration by just making up a
fishing URL so this actually isn't a
real fishing URL I just made it up
Wells Fargo customer support that web
hosting de piel it looks suspicious to
the neural network right it gives it a
97% probability of being malicious
so here's it here's a naive attack
against this neural network that
actually doesn't work great so I tie I
take my URL and I append some random
suffixes right and I and the hope is
that it'll it'll it'll make the score
lower but it doesn't write actually the
score stays about the same or even gets
a little bit higher so it so a random a
random suffix doesn't work now let's try
some instead of random suffixes some
sort of benign words like Disneyland
while we're sand Jacaranda every toy at
the same URL
I just tack tack these words onto the
end again it doesn't work that you know
fortunately for me as as the researcher
who created the neural network created
the neural networks resilient to this
kind of attack as well now let's try it
so that so then so the more
sophisticated approach that I tried was
I created a genetic algorithm that
systematically attacks systematically
search serve searches the space of
possible suffixes and sort of iterates
over thousands of examples and in try
and sort of evolves suffixes that do
well at lessening the score and after
after about 50 generations of evolution
so after having tried 50,000 examples
right I can get the score down to 43%
and 57% with these suffixes
right they don't look that different
from the random suffixes but they were
evolved through this genetic process and
if I take the evolution even further in
so I double the number so I get up to a
hundred thousand exactly of sort of
examples that I've tried I can I can get
the score down to eight percent right so
basically at this point the neural
network thinks the URL is benign
even though it looks like a phishing URL
right I mean it still looks suspicious
right so
that I would say that the tech was
successful just to give some insight
into the genetic algorithm obviously I
can't cover this in the 25-minute talk
but the basic idea with genetic
algorithms is that I'm modeling my
suffixes as individuals in the
population and and I go through a series
of generations so I so I start out by
creating a thousand random suffixes I
look at the ones that minimize the score
as much as possible
and I made them so I combine sort of
their character sequences and I do
another generation where I where I try
them again and to this evolutionary
process I get good suffixes and in the
animation you're seeing individuals in
the population and just to sort of carry
the example for their in thighs that
every generation the ones that survive
are the ones that get higher up on this
hill and let's think of the hill as is
my ability to minimize this the score
that my url classifier has fits out so I
also explored some defenses to my attack
the best defense I've come up with as
far as is it's pretty pretty
unsophisticated basically if I read
retrain my model on a different subset
of my training data and the attack no
longer works so we have a lot of URL
training data that so first so we
trained currently we trained our Europe
URL model on about 100 million URL
examples about half of those are
malicious and half of those are benign
so it's not so hard for me to like I sub
subset 50 million of those and you know
I can have multiple well I can have
multiple if I wanted to just you train
on 10 million right each I could have
ten different models right and and
there's somewhat resilient to this
genetic algorithm attack so so basically
my score goes all the way back up if I
train on a different subset of the data
the problem with this approach right is
that I'm not training all my models on
all of the data so the model performance
is going to suffer as a result so I
don't think my solution is it's perfect
but it's the solution I've come up with
this far so I'm just want to end with
some I have two minutes left so I want
to end with some common-sense wisdom on
defending you can't have a serial attack
so I'd say I think it's important to
attack your own models and see where
that where their weak spots are and fix
them don't give at a careers access to
your model if possible that makes it
easier for them don't even give it at
attackers the ability to query your
model with thousands of examples like so
don't give them black box box access
that also makes it easy
with the proxy attack that I showed
earlier and the genetic algorithm to
talk coda showed you Slayer defense is
approach you know defense in depth you
know helps read no system is perfect and
if for those who are Michigan learning
researchers and computer scientists out
there I would say this is a really
interesting area to work in right now
it's a hot area and it's a high-impact
area and I would say so do do research
in this area so that's it thanks a lot
and I don't know if it's time for
questions and comments
okay yeah yeah so I'm assuming the
attacker like like I'm assuming the
attacker has doesn't have the model
codes or like the like the model
software but but can query the model so
like like say for example we released
them all as a web service within Sophos
maybe like a paid web service for our
customers and the attacker could get
access to that they could upload you
know 100,000 URLs and get this course
but they would need to they would need
to be able to really brute force the
system and get scores back for all of
their URLs before that he'd get through
it yeah you'd have to have act you have
to be able to query the model a lot so
that's one that's one limitation the
attacker has in this case is there a
difference between being able to query
the model for legitimate reasons like I
buy a license and I can create the model
versus I buy a license than I query the
model maliciously sorry can you like if
I bought the software I gotta find it to
defend my network or I could be defying
it because I want access to the model so
that I can attack the mall itself yeah
is there a way to to provide the model
or how do you provide the model without
for positive use versa without allowing
the negative use that's a good question
I'm that I'd have to think about it
that's a good question yeah and you said
that training on different sets of your
data
you helped defend it did you look at
bagging using you know bagging type
approach using multiple models and did
that work yeah so in this case we're not
doing bagging and so the hand-wavy
wisdom about that in the neural network
context is you can sort of get the same
effects this bagging using it the
technique called dropout which adds
noise to your neural network so it's
just not something we've I mean so we
baseline all of our models with with
like a bag like a bag in your purse
called random forests rated and this
outperforms random forests so yeah yeah
go ahead yeah so uh for your genetic
algorithm um for each iteration are the
URLs fairly similar like just a few
characters different or are they
drastically different overall so you
mean when they mate yeah are they very
different yeah you know I I don't know
it was a real kind of a quick it was I
probably spent two days on it I never
actually inspected like what the like I
never lever introspected into the
algorithm to see how similar they look I
will say that the successful if you
watch like the leaderboards as that as
the solutions evolved like you'd get a
lot of regularity and like it would wind
up finding like these characters sub
sequences that just like stuck around
generation after generation so it's a
probably probably there was a lot of
similarity between the parents and the
children so that might be a good way to
go for the defending that gate was
asking yeah if you get a lot of queries
that
very similar yeah maybe just like yeah
mm-hmm yeah so you're saying if there's
some like global minima that the
optimizer is finding that we could just
like waitlist like you know basically
just like waitlist away or something or
like train on like that would help
defend against this attack right like
yeah yeah that makes sense yeah that's a
really good idea yeah so you you seem a
web reputation service or are you using
this as a replacement for it so so they
would be I mean I don't so yeah I don't
want to speak to like sophist is product
plans I will say that there right now I
mean so it was you know it has it has a
reputation service this is the the role
of this neural network is is there's a
separation of concerns right so the
reputation services for stuff we already
know about the this URL malice recept
that we don't know about yet right it
stuff that is not on a black list
because it's not detecting based on
Hatchery just detecting based on the
semantics of the URL so make sense like
so I think it's complementary to a
reputation service you definitely want
to block stuff that you know is bad you
also want to block stuff they don't know
about yet and that's what they know that
works for the latter problem yeah yeah
yeah when you showed the slides where
some of the euros got caught and the
others did not get caught yeah what was
happening in the back end in the newer
network that cost that difference it
seemed that was there would have been
the same yeah that's the million dollar
question yeah yeah so you know I mean
these you know neural networks are like
kind of famously black boxes it's hard
to know what's why they do what they do
we try our best to we said we've got
some work like like rich here is like
doing some work on explaining why they
do why they make decisions when they do
but uh right now I I would say I don't
know it's a mystery yeah yeah thanks
yeah so in this case the neural network
you could say derives the features we
feed in basically just like the kind of
like the integer you know ASCII kind of
a I mean they're using Unicode but
basically like you know we just feed in
the characters and
and it discovers what useful so it's
it's a convolutional neural network we
could talk about more but we also have a
paper about it I give you the link but
we talk more about it afterwards yeah
thank you mm-hmm all right where we are
out of time
if there are any more questions please
follow on peer peer list folks and thank
you thank you
[Music]
[Applause]