everyone yeah I know of questions
probably because it's been recorded
maybe save them till the end normally
I'd say just interrupt me so you don't
lose your train of thought but if you
save them to the end so the recording to
go here I guess so yeah I'm Joe Cohen
this is talk about some of the
shortcomings that I've perceived from
two-factor authentication both push and
time-based one-time pad HMI based
one-time pad and a proposal for some
designs that I think could mitigate some
of those issues feel like I know you ok
so anyway if you don't take anything
else away I guess the problem with 2fa
that I've found is that it's got abused
from its original design so when the RFC
was first buyout in 2005 for HMI trace
one-time pad the design was supposed to
be for mitigating you know consumption
of breach data but since then it's being
proposed to be something that will
protect you from phishing and something
that will protect you from confirming
something out band so each of those the
second one is in reference to push bass
to FA the first one applies to
push-based and also totp to fret to so
just to bring everyone to the same level
I know really most of you already know
how the OTP scheme works most likely
better than I do but if we go for the
first one which both of these are
counter based one-time pads
totp and hatred CP both use this H Mac
design and the reason they use that one
is for integrity of the code but also
because H Mac is collision resistant
under truncation they can truncate
something very long so if six character
to string and still have the integrity
guarantees of the H map so most of them
what they do is they change this hate
map counter and here this is the thing
that varies amongst all the different
schemes but the majority of the schemes
are just hecho TP or totp which is this
other one and the way this one works it
just takes the time from epoch and so
now subtract that from when the token
was created divides up by a period which
might be like 30 seconds minute whatever
and then it just flaws that to give you
an integer value and then essentially
that just becomes
same as the normal account base one time
bad and that's that's all it's doing
when it's sharing the QR code you know
with you when you take the QR code and
that goes into your Google Authenticator
all that's doing is transferring the
secret and the time seed so yeah what's
the problem with this so if I was to
talk through something Jamica with the
type attack here we have live calm so
this would be like the Microsoft domain
and if we look at another domain that I
could purchase that would be AI ve calm
and if I capitalize the high it looks
indistinguishable from live calm I can
also get a TLS certificate free from
let's encrypt and then simply just
forward across these details and I'll
show a demo of how we could go about
that in a second
did we encounter this type of issue
before and the answer is yes we did in
around 2005 when they released H map
based one-time pad there was also a
scheme called cram md5 that some of you
may be painfully like aware of that we
don't use anymore right anyway so they
found this to be an issue they cited it
and they cited this attack at the same
time that the RFC came out for hm at
base one-time pad but interestingly
enough these two parties never discussed
those things together so I'll just move
to a demo and also check that this is
all right for everyone everyone see that
okay from the back and so so this what
we've got here is is anyone familiar
with Heroku anyone's used Heroku so I
took a domain called Heroku comm just
with spot with an eye instead of an e
and essentially if I just drag the video
back it's really easy to create these
types of things like all you do is just
save that page and then you just do a
bit of like GIMP if you're cheap like me
or you use like Photoshop if you're like
a rich man and then you just like change
the characters to make it look
indistinguishable from an actual Heroku
thing I didn't actually purchase this
domain because I thought that would be
somewhat kind of criminal so I just
instead just put an se hosts
entry for this so excuse me if this is
not a legit SSL certificate but this
domain was available so I could have
bought it I just didn't want to kind of
blend blur the lines between white hat
and black
for this one and then the other thing
we've got is just an Android emulator
here which just comes with Android
studio is just a qmu emulator and in the
top thing this thing you can see here
this is essentially just watching the
folder directory for the screen captures
are about to get yeah so this site I'm
just gonna put in my primary factor here
you can email that domain if you on all
that email it's not I don't really
monitor it spam away so we've done the
primary factor and then on the back end
I've got phantom j/s running that's just
running somewhat headless Chrome with
some actual rendering features and it's
just adding the first factor and then
it's taking the output of that first
page and then just waiting on that and
then we put in the second factor here so
I've go to my free OTP put in the second
code and what I did here is I put a
really long time out to kind of emulate
some sort of server-side error that
might happen and then I redirected to
the actual site here so this is the real
Heroku now so what's mostly likely
happening for the user now is they've
had this fish email they went to log in
to Heroku my fake one and then after
that failed I just redirect sends the
real Heroku then they'll probably
complain to support that there was some
sort of issue with the logins and as we
can see now if we look at the
filesystemwatcher dashboard should show
up eventually once my thing finally
screencaps it and I'd saved you an app
for all you guys called b-sides Las
Vegas 2017 on my dashboard in Heroku
just to show you like that we did get
the real Heroku here obviously you could
go to greater lengths with this you
could for example do full video store
you could actually get like session
cookies and then just browse to that as
an attacker but essentially you have
that session once you've completed this
and so that's one of the shortcomings of
TOTP or HTTP doesn't defend us from
attacks that target a specific platform
it would defend against you know
compromises of passwords but not from a
targeted attack like this
so when I was thinking of the issues
here I thought of the desired features
of the solution that we'd want so
firstly obviously we wanted to protect
their to protect from an attacker
stealing the users credentials so the
primary factors and that would be vie
dns hijacker tax so whether that's some
sort of DNS change of malware some of
the router hacks etc we'd also want a
hammer glyph hostname protection which
is not something contrary to popular
belief that TLS would give us TLS you
can have a secure channel to a bad place
right it doesn't help with that and then
we also want to protect static inputs
with variable inputs and what I mean by
that is if you think about the primary
factor you don't frequently change your
password with totp that code is changing
every 30 seconds so we'd rather put
anything that's changing first because
compromising that is not those Cass
traffic is compromising the static
factor and then also it'd be nice if it
was technology agnostic so you know
someone could write a design that maybe
some UML some sort of like RFC and then
it can be able mented any language you
know your favorite language I'd rather
it wasn't a proprietary piece of
hardware and that was the comparison I'm
making that the other thing is it may be
in my perception if the people that I
know it seems that we've reached a point
where two-factor is just a thing that
people use and users have kind of said
okay we're okay with this level of
friction so I prefer not to add to that
but if we could make it seem like it's
just about the same level of friction
base add in some more enhancements that
would be ideal
less friction would be desirable but if
we can't do that the same level of
friction could be okay
so a proposed solution weirdly enough if
we look at the original RFC from 2005
they even said interestingly enough you
can actually use this in a
bi-directional type way and I only found
this after thinking of a design to
protect it but essentially the way that
this works is the user would enter their
token the server would send back is
token and they both verify each other's
page mac-based one-time pads and so
there's there's two secrets in this
exchange this wasn't widely implemented
by vendors at least I haven't seen any
vendors implement this I don't
necessarily think it's much more
friction than what we already have the
only thing about Hecky OTP is it's not
great for multiple clients sports
because you have to keep counters in
sync so imagine you have like a counter
one that's incremented here and this
other client doesn't know about it this
one's going to be out of sync with this
- it's hecho TP generation the good
thing about time-based is that's a
universal counter and providing there's
no attacks on network time protocol or
something like that that keeps all the
clients in sync and so the one that I
chose to use was TOTP not hate your TP
I'll get to that so what I'm proposing
is say we take this this example of this
live comm this Microsoft site and then
I've got this spoofed I've calm so when
they use the first visitors is that it
sends a header and the reason it's
sending the header is just so that the
browser extension that I've created I
can just listen for other headers that
coming through ideally this would be
baked to the browser but you can't do
that until you've proved that it's
actually valuable so then they would
submit they username I feel like giving
away a piece of username is not a
totally sensitive credential so it's
okay to release that the server would
then send back something called the next
fearless response and the only variant
that I've made here is I've concatenated
to the flawed counter that we have this
thing I've concatenated an IP block so
this could be for example an IP range it
could be a static IP that used for
logging in it could be an ASN number
just something that is harder to attack
than DNS and so the the attacker now
would have to go after the Box directly
and compromise that box and in that
scenario you need different protections
and so what this does it stops a site in
the middle from then utilizing this totp
code and passing it down the chain
because the browser itself is going to
do a dns resolution against I've calm so
the browser itself will do a DNS
resolution against I've calm it would
calculate the expected OTP ker and that
would be wrong because the actual code
came from this one down here and here
I've got a demo of that so what we have
here is in the top window this is a
cycle violence Pro these are real sites
now I'm not
like I was allowed to buy these because
no one cares about these so this is
violas Pro this is a real site this is
the one that we're gonna try and
legitimately log into this is a Hamid
glyph attack this is various Pro slash
login and then up there we just got the
browser extension that I created and
that window the bottom is just a debug
window for any extra information you
might want so what we're gonna do here
is we're going to log in with this user
one password fubar so first of all we
have to register with this site and
what's interesting about all of these
schemes as the registration is the most
dangerous part of all of this process so
it's the place where we need the most
hardening the most detection everything
but that is indifferent across all these
schemes so once we register it's going
to give us a server secret and that the
time were secret was created out and we
can just populate that and the browser
extension obviously if this was a
production piece of code it'd be more
slick than this it wouldn't just this is
more to illustrate what is actually
going on to you guys to kind of show as
a proof of concept so now the extension
is going to be listening for that
particular type of OTP code to come
across so if we go to login on the
legitimate site what we're gonna see
here is that I've put in user 1 I'm
gonna then receive a if you see in the
top corner we've now got the the TOTP
code that came up as a notification this
is the client code so the extension
itself has already verified the surfers
the server's TOTP code and check that
the dns resolution for that was legit so
there's no site in the middle in this
case and then if we was play if we
continue I'll show you how we do that
against the site here that's a Hama
glyph attack against this and how it
resists that in this case this is using
a beta feature of Chrome called
declarative web extensions which I'll
talk about in a sec and we see here that
it was actually blocked we've got a
notification say various top Pro is
blocked this is not actually the
legitimate site and that's what we
prefer we prefer that there was some
sort of smarts in our browser to protect
us from losing our credentials in that
way
this extension just will not give up the
client code unless the server code has
been verified that's it for that demo so
yeah what just happened here so it was a
fan of UML I'm expecting no hands like
I'm yes you guys are the best like I
really like plant UML I think it's
awesome and you can also generate in
ASCII who doesn't love ascii diagrams of
like networks like this amazing right so
anyway this is this is the flow of what
happened so can you see my mouse pointer
you can write so anyway the user
requests the site then they get this x
fields in it and what this does is it
registers with these Google Chrome's
declarative web extensions that it wants
to listen for some sort of dynamic input
from a header and this is great because
your chrome extension could have like a
secret cache and you can generate
dynamic headers that it wants to listen
for I don't know Firefox has this it
might have this I just haven't tried it
yet
then you input your username now they
need you a post request and it will
receive the TTP code from the server and
what the extension then does is it uses
the dns resolution api to say okay where
did that server tcp come from and it
came from this IP then what it does is
it checks are these valid so it computes
wherever it was
great-great-great-great-great where is
it it computes this thing so this is
what the client is going to compute
based on the dns resolution that I got
and it's going to compare that to what I
received from the server and then after
that it's just a normal flow I mean this
this kind of things arbitary after this
you don't really need to use client TOTP
don't use a password you can use
whatever you want you could use whatever
scheme after that it's more this step
that's the most important that the is is
this valid comparison here and so the
benefits of this scheme is credential
phishing somewhat goes away because
you're protecting the user from
submitting this ephemeral code
accidentally to a site that's using DNS
hijacking so the the only way that the
attacker could really go about attacking
this one is attacking the client
directly via malware breaking into the
chrome sandbox or something like that or
alternatively breaking into that
actual legitimate server anything in the
middle is somewhat protected by this
scheme the other thing that I want to
kind of labor about is the corrects the
user trust model
I thought about drawing a graph for you
guys but I think it would be too
confusing because I did not find it
helpful
looking at the graph so essentially if
you think about when you sign it for
LinkedIn or whatever site you want when
you first sign up that asset has no
value there's no actual user details in
there it's just an empty portfolio right
so that things of low value but as it
goes on over 10 years it increases in
value so compromising a 10 year old
LinkedIn account is more valuable than
compromising one at time 0 the way we
currently have designed these schemes is
users have to be the same level of
vigilance all the way across so from
registration attendings down the line
they still have to be scrutinizing the
site and we know that their tolerance to
changes becomes heightened as it goes on
so like if something changed they don't
care they just like login yeah login I
don't care like I just have been to the
site before so what we want to do is we
want to align our authentication schemes
with that model and what we've seen from
the previous thing that I described is
that it starts off yes a registration
that's the most risky point but after
that this scheme is defending against
that and it means that as the value of
the asset increases the actual user
scrutiny can decrease they don't they
don't need to be worried about changes
to the site yeah challenges are that the
client needs access to a DNS resolution
API when I say client I'm talking about
browser extensions mobile device etc
these things are coming from a user
developer standpoint but they're not
available everywhere and they're not
available in the mainline you've got to
be in like a canary release to ever
leaves beta etc we have compromises
between usability and secure isolation
so in this point I put it inside the
browser extension but ideally as I'll
show you in a sec I'd like to move this
out to a mobile app and the browser
extension would just be more of a dumb
client that's just referring on the dns
resolution that it got and the token it
would see from the server unless the
mobile device do the verification of
that so it just kind of got a few layers
to it user adoption obviously this is
not going to work in systems where users
have not accepted you didn't see a
teepee
or push-based 2fa so I don't know how to
solve those problems because those
people don't want to use these things
yet so yeah future directions there's an
app called free OTP that Red Hat does if
anyone's from Red Hat after that I've
submitted some pull requests for like
backfilling of tests is that you I know
is you anyway so I've submitted some
pull requests for tests backfilling for
that because I really like the app and I
like it that Google Authenticator is not
a public free open-source app anymore
they private sourced it after a certain
point so you know it's nice to be able
to verify what this code is doing
because it's very this scheme is very
simple and like we should be able to
verify this is the public so I really
like this one go check it out the actual
app called for your TP which is
maintained by Red Hat community
so I started extending this and what I'm
looking to do here is we have this
normal flow this you know browser
extension thing where it sends the TOTP
header and then this dotted line here
this is using something called firebase
Cloud messaging or firebase something it
used to be called Google Cloud messaging
and it allows you to set up a Google
token bound access channel called the
device group where your devices can
speak between each other and kind of an
authenticated manner in terms of they
they have a channel to speak to each
other essentially and so in previous
projects I've done some work around that
so it seemed like an ideal fit to
combine these two together and all this
would do is it would send it to an
Android app and then the Android app
would do the verification just as it is
in free OTP it would just look to the
user as if they go into free OTP they've
logged in to the site then free OTP
suddenly allows them to click on the
thing and then they can copy paste it
back into the browser browser and go
with the normal flow so as far as the
user is concerned even though this looks
convoluted to us as developers or
security people they don't see any of
this because this is all happening on
the the back channel via the cloud base
firebase cloud messaging and we can also
do this similar thing with push based
and what I'm calling this is a reverse
push so normally so normally with with
push based we do this login and then the
server would send the push request and
then we have this approve or decline
option but instead what I've done here
is
normal flow that we discussed earlier we
send it over firebase cloud messaging
and then all we do is we pop up and
approve decline and then if the user
approves it we do a reverse push and
this could be integrity checked with
something like an app ID or some sort of
signature the other server knows about
and then in this case we've protected
from an out-of-band
approve or decline issue with push-based
because obviously if you try to
compromise this in a normal push base
scenario some user could just get sent
and approve or decline and they might
just hit approve you might get lucky
right
in this scheme there's no way for them
to prove because approve decline will
become available until it's received
this deadline here and that's it
any questions can help myself
this guy this guy right here alright so
there's this looks great there's a lot
that's very reminiscent here of the TGT
acquisition in Kerberos which has been
around for 30 years
RFC 1510 defines the a s wreck and a
scrap process which is very similar to
the flow here might be worth looking at
the lessons learned in the 4200 series
around DNS resolution around the use of
preauth to prevent replay attacks and
see if that applies here just to
strengthen this this protocol is here to
finding it here us excellent nothing in
that same vein there it could even be
valuable to consider using the existing
spawn a go mechanisms and the browsers
and extending the HTTP negotiating
header instead of creating something
custom so just something to think about
I could see where this could very well
fit in no I can't exchange details with
you afterwards yeah okay so it's curious
how much you've looked into applying
this to like some of the newer like to
FA scheme to stuff like that II use
certificate based OTP as opposed like
TOTP I haven't looked in
certificate-based have mostly just
focused on counter base TPS and push
base because those are the things that I
encountered in the user space law I
wasn't focus on enterprise great
solutions because my angle of interest
is consumers might user user level and I
would assume I don't know enough about
this but I would assume that the
certificate based ones were more
enterprise related and through that
thing I'd consider that securities to be
proprietary right yeah no I should look
into that that's great thank you
all right I think that's everybody thank
you so much see you in a bit
[Applause]