going to talk about kind of how we got
to where we are with vrm today a little
bit of the origins and what has kind of
pushed change in the last decade or so
we're going to talk about what VR might
look in your organization currently
because there's almost definitely some
form whether it's called vrm or not that
that that's going to be highly dependent
but there's there's something going on
what just kind of want to point out what
may be going on
in your company right now
then we're going to kind of take a peek
at like who cares right vendorous
management isn't something that most
people care about I know I didn't think
about it until I started working for
wistic now I I see from of course from
an Insider's perspective but I see a lot
of value in it in terms of how it plays
into overall information security
we're going to talk about the key core
two fundamental pieces of vendor risk
management which is the difference
between here and residual risk and how
that impacts your organization how you
can use that to I guess Drive change
Drive decision making and then we're
going to go over a high level this is if
I had no tools if I had no way to
approach if I had very limited knowledge
of what needed to happen this is kind of
how I would recommend on an unofficial
basis how to get started with the vrm
program
so a few things to keep in mind this is
me talking I'm not here inherently as
your representative of wistic I'm not
here to preach the gospel of this is how
vrm should be done or must be done this
is simply some of my experiences some of
the discussions that I've had with other
people throughout the industry and uh
please take as take everything I say
with a grain of salt
um I'm generally not a speaker in front
of people I don't know so
please take that as you will
I'm also hoping to be more descriptive
in terms of hey this is what
has generally worked but you might find
a good variation that works better for
your organization as opposed to hey this
is right this is not the gospel of this
is not the way of how vrm is supposed to
be done
and as always if there's anything that
you're unsure of please don't claim me
as giving you advice because I'm
definitely not a lawyer I'm not about
that life
um
like our last keynote said it's great to
have lawyers I'm not one so if you have
questions about how to go about this or
if something's kosher or not for your
organization please ask them not me
um you can ask me just don't take that
as proper advice
so when we're thinking about vrm right
there's been some form of this and
in in business for a long long time I
mean longer than longer than it's been
in its current form for sure
uh you might also know it by third party
risk management
procurement I mean there's there's all
sorts of different ways that you could
look at it and vendorous management kind
of falls into multiple different areas
right we're essentially wanting to know
what is in our company's ecosystem
what's in our environment what are they
doing how are they doing it how much
asking those kinds of questions and
seeing how that's going to impact then
how you operate
uh in in the last decade right I mean
this part a big part of why we're all
here is because we want to keep our
organization safe and the trend over
recent decades especially since The
Internet's been a bigger thing is that
there's a lot more easy access to data
and things that we don't generally want
people to just have unfettered access to
so when you think of issues of why vrm
is important you think vendor related
breaches right this is the favorite the
favorite I I can't even say buzzword but
this is the
sorry my ears are weird it's just not
wanting to stay
um when we're thinking about how our
supply chain right this could be our our
actual physical supply chain our digital
supply chain and how this impacts our
business
um we're thinking about how
in multiple steps of this process a
vendor not nearly our organization can
impact how we deliver the quality of
what we deliver and then the trust that
our customers have in us right
so when you're thinking about the bad
guys the hackers the the folks behind
with the hoodies and the masks on behind
the computer
some of the bigger names that have
happened in recent history are I'm not
sure if I could use logos so I kind of
pick your generic ones like your
favorite hardware store this has been a
big deal I I I'm a recently new
homeowner so I don't love knowing that
people can get access to my card
information just because I made a
payment at like I said my uh your
favorite hardware store my wife's
favorite store it looks a little bit
like that logo on the right right
there's that that was a big issue
several years ago
uh pretty much every social media outlet
has had some sort of incident many a few
of them have had many uh unfortunately
and then also right because data is
money and sometimes money is money also
uh there's also been lots of incidents
breaches data leaks with financial
institutions fintech right I mean
everything ends up coming down to money
especially when you're on on the other
side of the keyboard and you're just
looking to
make a make a living whether you're just
looking to burn something down right
that's everything ends up relating to
money in some capacity
if it's into your organization well
chances are your organization exists to
make money
um I I know that there's a lot of
government organizations and schools
which I guess technically is a
government organization right you're
still delivering a service right there's
still some exchange of good of value of
time and effort in exchange for money at
some point right and looking at the
inside of Any Given organization
there's
thank you for your patience
um at any given point there's going to
be tools Services contractors people
that are giving services to your
organization so you can in turn you can
in turn turn around and give something
to your customers to your bra to your
buyers
and in my perspective that makes vrm an
issue for everybody in some capacity
right
um and and a big part of this is an
awareness deal kind of like we heard in
one of the Keynotes today right you
can't protect something that you don't
know about you can't protect something
if you don't know how to protect it so
having a base level awareness of why
theorem as important is essential I
would argue for everyone in your
organization in your company
uh like I mentioned before businesses
exist for the purpose of making money
right there's there's other
goals that can be with her right driving
positive change
um improving livelihood improving
quality of life but in essence right no
no one's going to really spend all their
all their time effort and and coordinate
the time and effort of other people
solely for that right there's got to be
some exchange of value so when you think
about it when you get down to vendors
are just organizations they sell Goods
services expertise for money
so if you're thinking Costco I'd blow
way way way too much money there on a
unfortunately more than a weekly basis
right you're going to shop for your
groceries that's that that's a vendor
everything is a vendor is is the blanket
term I like to stay away from um blanket
always Nevers but hey this that's it
just kind of fits in this case uh if you
sell software with stick a software many
of your companies also I know our
software
um you're a vendor you're a software
vendor if you fix toilets you pull um
you pull piping or cables for uh for
electrical work you're also a vendor
right you're selling your service and
sometimes the goods if you're an
underwater basket weaving teacher I
thought this was a really cool thing
except I'm not good at staying
underwater and I'm a terrible Weaver you
are still a vendor because you're
selling expertise same thing if you're a
consultant right it could be something
from anything from corporate strategy to
Checker strategy this is a fun one I was
playing with I was playing checkers with
my daughter and she said oh I want to
learn to be better like well let's try
and work that into the presentation I
know it didn't really land that well but
hey we'll get over it
um so everyone is a vendor right and
everyone is a vendor because they want
to make money and how that ties in is
pretty much directly related to how your
organization operates and how we manage
that and how that impacts your
organization is really what comes down
to who is responsible and who's
accountable which are generally
different things for managing vendor
risk in your organization
so everything comes down to risk in this
case right we we cannot operate without
having some level of risk there's
there's a risk to getting out of bed in
in the morning I got out of bed this
morning and I tripped that was
embarrassing but I mean it kind of
illustrates the point right just just by
being alive there's risk same thing with
driving same thing with going to your
favorite restaurant there's risks
Associated and depending on how you
think about it if you're really paranoid
like me you're thinking about risk all
the time even if it's not in a
professional capacity so what we think
about as Information Security
Professionals for event from a vendor
risk perspective is how is this
particular service provider this
particular vendor going to impact
my organization my my ability to deliver
whatever I'm selling uh and then and
being able to properly
control that maintain that without
causing disruption to that service right
there's there's that kind of vibe in our
industry where security where the
security team or the people that you go
to when you want to hear no
um I make that joke even though I say
yes a lot to stuff but I mean it's it
seems to be pretty common if you say no
and there's no explanation why then
there's a lot of distrust centers coming
from there and and I would argue that
our goal is kind of the opposite our
goal as Information Security
Professionals is to properly manage the
risk associated with delivering our
value as professionals so that our
overall company can do what they do make
money so we can all get paid and put
food on the table
when we're thinking about risk right
this is this this is high level
there's
there's a tolerance there's an appetite
in terms of how much risk that an
organization or an individual if you
want to think about it that way first is
willing to take on
um if you like skydiving right there's a
lot of risks that go with that if that's
not something within your appetite
you're not comfortable with those
particular risks being actualized you
probably shouldn't do that and it's kind
of similar with information security in
our organizations right generally the
board of directors sometimes the c-suite
they'll say hey this is what we want you
to do this is what we are comfortable
with we are not comfortable with losing
more than
five hundred thousand dollars or five
million dollars I don't know how big
your company is how big your
organization is right but there's going
to be some level of appetite worth where
we're fine saying hey it's okay if this
happens because we have resources
reputation we have guardrails in place
that if this happens where we can
tolerate it we can handle this
all right and that's going to be unique
to each individual organization so
that's something that if if you as the
information security team don't set it
probably isn't that's something you want
to get in touch with your Senior
Management about or your board of
directors because ultimately they're the
ones accountable right we talked about
the difference between accountability
and responsibility they're accountable
for it so they should be the ones giving
the high level Direction you make that
plan happen
risk is more than money I mean we I I've
mentioned the money a lot in this up up
to this point and and there's I mean
it's for good reason right if we don't
do our job we don't get paid and I'd
like being employed and having money
um but you have to also kind of consider
the different factors that go into maybe
that overall Financial aspect right so
there can be negative impact to your
brand to your reputation there's legal
action that just slows you down adds
extra bureaucracy and worth that you
just really don't want to generally deal
with so you have to consider this when
you're looking at your overall vendor
risk level
and and as a heads up I mean we'll we'll
dive into different ways to mitigate
risk or to rather manage risk to to talk
about risk
um not all risk is going to be worth
uh reducing right there's you you can
pull some levers to say hey this is how
much the risk will currently pose to us
sometimes the amount of effort time
person hours dollars that you have to
throw at a problem sometimes just isn't
worth it uh in terms of if if you were
to take that course of action so I mean
just just keep that in the back your
mind just because a risk is there
doesn't mean you have to deal with it
you can step away from it one completely
right I mean you can't step away from
all risk because then you might as well
just close your computers take them off
the internet shut down business because
that's just the way it we can't deliver
without having some sort of risk in the
game
and if we're thinking about high level
right qualitatively I mean I know you
can quantify this using real numbers but
in general when we're looking at risk
it's How likely is something to happen
multiplied against how bad is this going
to hurt right if my five-year-old
daughter throws her favorite toy I mean
what she does on a regular basis it's
gonna hurt but she misses a lot she's
five and she gets my jeans she's a very
bad thrower so
um as she gets bigger and older and
hopefully more athletic than I ever was
she's going to be capable of throwing
bigger things more accurately
meaning that it's a higher chance that
she's actually going to hit me with her
toy and it's going to hurt more so
that's kind of the visual that I that I
think about
um of course out of the professional
context there's four different ways
generally speaking that we that we treat
risk that we manage risk right we can
accept risk right using the analogy of
my kid likes throwing toys at me I can
just accept that's going to happen and I
frequently do
um it's it's just her favorite thing and
I'm working on that so I can I can
accept that it's going to happen I'll
let it happen
I could transfer the risk which in this
case is not very viable because that
means I have to carry a door or
something like that or I have to use my
wife as a human shield which she's got
better reflexes than me so maybe that's
a viable solution
um
yeah I mean the toys aren't that hard
but I don't like things being thrown at
me I'm a really bad catch
um
you can avoid the risk right by stepping
back right like I mentioned if it's just
too expensive to fix this risk then you
just step away say hey it's not worth
integrating this vendor this this
happens from time to time we had it we
our marketing team wanted to
excuse me our marketing team wanted to
use uh engage with a new partner but we
don't have certain mechanisms certain
mechanisms in place to help us with the
gdpr requirements because we are
expanding our operations outside of the
states and I was like look guys this is
just going to cost us way too much to do
and if we do it with all the proper
guide rails in place then we're going to
have gdpr issues that's definitely not
something that we want to do
or the what the factor that we look at
most generally as as Security
Professionals is the reduction or the
mitigation of risk right this is where
we do something or have our vendors do
something to reduce the chance or the
impact or both preferably of something
bad happening
so when we're looking at identifying and
tracking risk you want to know what you
have what different data types you have
names special categories right we're
thinking voting history
um sexual identity criminal history
right these these are things that some
organizations track and you have to know
what you have or else you can't properly
Safeguard it protect it keep it where
it's supposed to be you have to classify
that data right not not all data is made
equal so if you have a name by itself
that is not the same as having a name a
date of birth a social security number a
password number because that bundle of
data right there is much more
destructive potentially if it become if
it falls in the wrong hands if it's used
for inappropriate purposes right so you
have to know right is is this your
company's crown jewels is I I don't
particularly love that term but I know
it's used somewhat frequently is this
critical is this low risk data is this
informational only right you can come up
with a schema that makes sense to your
to your organization but you got to know
hey is a game sensitive is a date of
birth sensitive right and a lot of
that's just going to kind of depend on
how on how you run things
and you're also going to need an
inventory of vendors not just hey their
names but you you want as much
information on them as possible because
things are going to happen right
relationships are going to change
processing purpose is going to change
there's going to be a fluctuation in
volume and you want to be aware that
these things know exactly where to look
so you can keep your team updated you
can keep the teams that you support
updated and your customers as well
so for example right I won't go over
that I I I I timed this and I went over
a little bit so I'm not going to do that
one uh and looking back at the core
tenets of essentially what vendoris
comes down to right we're looking at the
difference between inherent risk and
residual risk
and essentially how we look at that is
inherent risk is hey vendor a what do
you have
if you have high-risk data you are just
plain straight from an inherent
perspective you are inherently a
high-risk vendor if you only have low
risk data you are inherently a low risk
vendor right something can happen right
if if if if you have two vendors one has
low risk one has high risk data both are
breached both are compromised in some
way the one of the high risk data
regardless is going to have a higher
probability of impacting negatively
impacting your organization because
they're in your supply chain then we
think about the residual risk which is
kind of what is sometimes a little
harder to quantify or even qualify it
just kind of depends on on on what's
important to you but this is where you
take in all the different factors right
you take your analysis you take your
assessments and you figure out hey what
is in place to make that risk lower do
they have things in place to lessen the
impact if they were to be breached or
do they have things to make it less
likely that this is going to happen in
the first place even if it were to still
happen it'll still be painful
so keeping that in mind this is how I if
if I were thrown into a new organization
I didn't have any tools I didn't have
any budgets like hey just get something
stood up this is the high level of how
I'd approach it
so you want to start with a good
relationship right and this is with not
only your team although you just
definitely want to have that because
like I mentioned everyone in your
organization is going to use tools has
some interaction with vendors you need
to have that good relationship or else
people are going to start going around
you they're going to engage in what
sometimes I don't think it's used as
often they're going to engage in what's
called Shadow I.T where hey this
application isn't approved but it makes
my life easier so I'm going to do it you
also want to have a good relationship
with your vendors right they're the ones
that from from a partner's perspective
right someone can be giving you a
service but if you're pursuing a true
partnership to make that relationship
effective you want to have a good
person-to-person relationship with that
you all want a catalog right this is
just kind of part of the information
security Basics right you want to have a
good asset inventory a good catalog or a
way to track who has what and how much
what's it used for
ETC you you you just have to know these
things because if one of my vendors if
one of my core vendors is breached and
10 of my other vendors use that vendor I
don't know what's and I don't know
what's there that becomes an issue
because now I got a bunch of customer
data that's floating around floating out
there being potentially abused and I
don't know what to tell my customers
that's not a situation that we want to
be in so having catalog having an
inventory of who has what and for what
purpose is going to be critical
you want to go through an assessment an
analysis I mean the words you want to
use is is its own thing right but you
pretty much want to check and confirm
that your vendors have something in
place right that could be through
questionnaires I could be through other
independent studies or or assessments
but we'll we'll kind of touch on that
but you need to have something you need
to have something more than hey my gut
says that they're cool I've seen that
happen before it doesn't generally end
up end up well
you're also going to want to check in
regularly with your vendors right
reassess them from time to time doesn't
have to be every year that's generally
the recommendation but you don't have to
do that just make sure that you're
checking in sometimes
oh
all right check in make sure that you
have good relationships with people I
think that security is a people I think
information security is a people
industry right and and it kind of rubs
me the wrong way when I hear that people
are our weakest are the weakest link I
get what they say but it still rubs me
the wrong way right people are the
reason that we do stuff right we provide
value via our company via our
organization because we want money to
take care of our our people our friends
our family and everyone else in the
world is out there just to do the same
right so if we kind of just are good
folks
we don't have to be best friends or
anything but if if we are courteous and
we're respectful and we are looking out
for each other looking to help that
makes all the difference I mean some of
the best vendor relationships we have is
where hey we treat each other like
people not as a contract not as a dollar
figure because I've seen it go both ways
and it never feels good to be on that
end of you're just a dollar figure
and and I mean golden rule states right
you want you want to be good to you you
want to treat others the way that you
want to
create that inventory have that catalog
have the have the asset management
inventory right know what each vendor is
going to do right Microsoft does more
than just office so you want to know are
we using Azure for our infrastructure
are we using um Power bi for our
analytics right you want to you want to
know exactly what each of these vendors
that you're using is going to do for you
so you know what data they have which I
guess is down one more bullet than I
thought it was going to be and leaning
on the on leaning heavier on the person
part right you also want to know who to
talk to right if you have billing
questions if you if you need to update
your licenses which we had to do for one
of our vendors and I didn't know where
to go so that's
it was a hassle knowing who to talk to
for specific questions is really is is
really critical and and it saves you a
ton of time a ton of frustration and
nowhere to turn right and and again you
want to know what data they have what
they're doing for you and how much
you also want to know in this day and
age of Integrations being everything I
know it's super convenient but you got
to track that right are they pullings
from Salesforce which has freaking
everything right Salesforce has
everything that is the lifeblood of a
lot of organizations so knowing what
data they have what their organ what
they're ingrained into and what they're
able to do with that is something you
want to be really cognizant about
because if if you don't say hey we don't
want you to do this they very well might
be doing that and that's something you
want to keep a close tab on keep the
pulse on that and probably the biggest
piece of this is you want proof like I
said you don't want to just say hey I
did a review I feel comfortable with
them okay prove it now you're being
audited by someone by any of your
customers it could be it could be an ISO
it could be sock too it could be any of
these different areas you want to be
able to demonstrate yes I did something
not just my gut felt good about it
uh so I I don't know if I promise but
this isn't a sales pitch for wistic this
is just how I happen to use our own tool
to help us with vent with vrm
um I I'm tracking our data right this
this is these are some of the key areas
of which I'm managing data for each of
our vendors so I know exactly where to
turn to if I have an issue with x y and
z
all right so down here I know exactly
what data types are they that this
particular vendor has I know who in our
company is responsible for this who so
if I have issues internally with this
who do I talk to who do I direct people
to
so you want to have the grant as
granular information as possible right
so they're inherent risk they have
medium data they have medium risk data
so inherently they are a medium risk
vendor but we have other place we have
other mechanisms in place that I've
confirmed that other people have
confirmed and demonstrated so and and
our feeling they are now a low risk
vendor because I know if this were to
happen then this particular control on
their side would reduce the chance of
this happening or reduce the impact it
wouldn't hurt us nearly as much
all right and I have a history so if
someone says hey tell me did you really
assess vendor XYZ like yes I did it on
these days these are my comments this is
what I found these are the artifacts and
I can demonstrate we know exactly what's
going on so if and on on the flip side
if you've entered a light about
something right this is not something
that you run into very often but you
always want to cover your back end if
your vendor was untruthful or less than
truthful about something you can say oh
this this is what we knew so we made
choices and decisions based on the
information that we had so that kind of
helps you well on the liability side
again not lawyer not telling you that
this is this will keep you safe but this
is something that has kind of helped
support us over the years
you want to assess each vendor's
security posture there's lots of
different acronyms that I'm just going
to kind of throw up many of you are
familiar with pretty much all of these
there's been a good shift I think one
thing I will say is that there's been a
good shift away from each company having
their own spreadsheet Custom Design
questionnaire that takes 10 days to fill
out and then you have three months of
back and forth right there's been a
shift away from that it's not totally
gone because I still deal with it I'll
tell you it still exists but there's
resources out there if you know you have
a lot of SAS customers look at the cake
send them that because everyone is going
to have the same set of questions that
answers a lot of the critical questions
that you're looking at like
where is your data hosted is it
encrypted how is it encrypted and that
way you don't have to go through a bunch
of different stuff you can fill it out
once so when your customers ask you that
you as a vendor can just say here's my
cake or here's my sock too here's my
information security policy my
acceptable use sock to ISO right if you
have these things ready then use a
vendor save a lot of time but these are
also some assets some options that you
might not have known as available to you
to get a good pulse on how your vendors
are taking care of your data
and maintain the relationship right just
just be good folks I mean I I feel like
in the industry most folks are are
really really good but I I think that
there's also definitely very much room
and where we can look to support uplift
help
the industry and the community as a
whole right if if you lift the water
level then all the boats are going to go
up and that's what we want
metaphorically I guess right we want
everyone to we want everyone to have a
better experience to have a better
security posture to have
um to make their lives easier and by
supporting other supporting other
information security teams one maybe
they don't know what's going on or
they're not as familiar with the terms
that you're using hold their hand walk
them through that that educational
payback many times and that'll help
strengthen your relationship I feel at
least I know it has for me so
um
follow up on commitments conduct
reassessments sometimes right doesn't
have to be annual I put that in here
that's a best practice don't really love
that term
but in in this case right just just make
sure you're checking in every once in a
while see if there's been any material
changes is how a lot of lawyers say it
right if there's material change just
check and see hey what's changed
um don't be a jerk about it I mean I I
get questionnaires not as much as I used
to thank goodness but if someone's
throwing a bunch of thousand plus
question questionnaires that yeah
um you want the time and the flexibility
to handle that you can give that same
Grace to your vendors
and if if if if you can ask what do you
need from us how can we help you how can
we support your security program how can
we help improve things just just offer
yourself as a resource I mean frequently
you won't be taken up on that but
sometimes you'll make good friends and
be able to participate in fun projects
on that side so
um that's that's it that's that uh yeah
any questions
yes I love when there's no questions
that means it was great right everyone
thank you very much
[Applause]