all right
anybody else not excited to get back to
reality on Monday does this kind of feel
like not reality yeah me too I'm lucky
enough that I get to
basically ignore my work life for a few
days so not everybody is so
thankfully I have a amazing boss that
lets me do that so all right so
um
let's get started uh I I I've noticed uh
in my technical days that a lot of
people
um
don't have really the don't have any
background in sales like I did and I've
done I did an alarm sales for a couple
years for ADT and I learned a lot of
things about humans and interacting with
them and getting them to trust you
um if they trust you they'll buy stuff
from you it's kind of sad and good at
the same time if you have honest
intentions
but I think that's helped me a lot in my
I.T career dealing with
uh Executives and bosses and owners of
companies whether I've done some I.T
Consulting in the past I noticed a lot
of my I.T Consulting co-workers had
issues getting people to
secure their networks and because they
didn't know how to talk to people about
it so
um that's mostly what this Talk's gonna
be about as well as a little bit of my
experience implementing specific things
that are kind of some basic CIS controls
kind of thing if you haven't looked at
that document
uh you probably should so here's a
little bit about me
um my wife and I moved to Utah in 2008
so I guess a little over 10 years now
um
I have way too many hobbies and most of
them are expensive so can I kind of pick
one unfortunately and I don't that's
tough to do sometimes
um
I love photography I just got to go to
Yellowstone a couple weeks ago if you
haven't been it's amazing it's worth it
it's expensive
but it's worth it
um I've been in tech for over 20 years
off and on different roles
uh troubleshooting internet tech support
everything you can think of
um
I've been a sysadmin technically I guess
that's I guess that's kind of the role
that most people would notice it as it's
kind of all the Jack of all trades if
you work at a smaller company you know
what I mean you get to be you know
security engineer and you get to be
network engineer you get to be you know
Microsoft Office 365 engineer AWS
everything so it's you get to learn a
lot but it's it's exhausting sometimes
um
uh I'm a big uh proponent of privacy and
the eff as I'm assuming most people in
this room would be I would I would
expect that's been my experience anyways
so I I love supporting them I love
supporting uh privacy organizations and
companies like protonmail and and other
and others so
um another big love of mine and my
wife's more probably more my wipes than
mine but is fostering animals and if
anybody likes cute kittens I guess
you're in luck here oh sorry I forgot to
put this first so another love of mine
is helping people
um I found Operation Safe escape a few
years ago
um there's a great group group of people
that love helping people and victims in
need a lot of people get
entangle their devices when they're in a
relationship whether that's you know
actually married or not and they've been
living together as many of you know if
you have somebody's Apple ID or access
to their phone you can pretty much track
them anywhere they go as well as see
their text messages and everything
um if you're in an abusive relationship
that becomes a problem really fast
and a lot of people don't know where to
go
um
I've helped quite a few victims just
basic stuff you don't need to be some
Elite hacker and know Kali Linux and
stuff to help these people you just need
to know where the settings are at in say
an Apple ID to set up two-factor
authentication and basically kick all
the devices off there I mean it's simple
stuff like that that these people need
help with so if you do have some extra
time and you're looking for to volunteer
they're a great organization and I
absolutely love working with them
they're also for those interested
they're also working on it I don't have
a ton of details on it yet it's kind of
new they're working with a couple
different organizations including some
federal law enforcement on child sexual
abuse material and hunting those people
down there they've got some people that
have had experience with that before and
um like I said they're they've got some
great relationships with some law
enforcement uh people I don't know if
it's FBI who exactly it was I think it
might be I can't remember like I said
it's been a while since they they talked
about it and they're still kind of
spinning it up but that's kind of an
active threat hunting kind of thing if
you're interested just in that I think
they're you know they're two different
kind of things even if you're not
interested in helping people secure
their accounts I think that I think a
lot of people here probably be
interested in that so I wanted to put it
out there which I'll reach out to I'm on
Twitter that's where I I end up finding
them so
um there's a great group of people there
that all all love helping people and
making the world a better place so
all right on to the kittens
this is Osborne
um sad story he was found with all his
siblings who were dead
so we got him
now he has new siblings we got a new two
new friends
and now they're one big happy family so
we're raising them Best Friends Animal
Society is a great organization if you
want to help animals so
my wife my wife does most of the work
but I help out so but she loves raising
these little guys we've we've had like I
don't know I lost count now 70 80
animals over the last couple years
it takes it's tough to give them up so
if you if you get attached it might
fostering might not be a job for you
because you'll end up with a house of
like 15 animals so all right
this is kind of what I'm going to go
over
getting leadership buy-in
soft skills like I spoke about sales
skills technically and you're you're
selling your company on why they need to
do this whether you're whether you're a
consultant or you're an employee of the
company
it's your job to make them understand
why they need it and I know
I would I would guess that just about
everybody in this room
struggles with getting people to spend
the proper amount of money on security I
mean that's every security conference I
go to that seems like it's underlying
you know theme is that we don't have
enough money
um I listen to the to the the ciso talk
the other day and that was that's the
reason cecils are leaving they get in
there and they want them to do this this
and this and this but this cost a
million dollars and you have 50 Grand
figure it out and they figure out it's
not very much fun and then you get
scapegoated when there's a breach
so
um along with that sales communication
uh finding a core test group of
employees of co-workers of friends even
they're your friends I've got I've got a
couple friends that that of users at my
company that if I need to test something
they're they're the guinea pigs because
they I know they're not going to get
really that mad at me if it goes wrong
um and then back to a couple basic uh
CIS tenants
um and securities inventory and Patch
management including system upgrades and
stuff too so
[Music]
all right as most of you know
if you don't have leadership buy-in
you're probably not going to get funding
and you're probably going to have a
rough time
I've experienced this you can do it
without it and you're not as successful
and it's a lot more frustrating but
sometimes that's what it takes sometimes
you have to do that especially at a
smaller company if you're a one-man shop
or two-man shop or whatever
um if you only got a couple people in
there it's going to be tough to to
justify 100 grand for cyber security
but
the reason you need this is you have to
have
policies in place and there has to be
consequences for breaking those policies
for your fellow co-workers or they're
not going to listen to you I've I've
dealt with this and I'm thankfully in a
place now where I'm getting more
leadership buy-in and it's it's a whole
lot easier it's almost I I would almost
bet you to say it's impossible to do it
do it well without it because if you
tell somebody they need to update their
computer
and they don't have to listen to you
what are you going to do I mean
granted you you can you can install
things that you can force them to update
and push it to update
but when that happens and you brick
their machine
and they run to the boss and say you
know and there and then that boss is not
on board with you doing that
you're going to have a you're gonna have
a bad time I thankfully have not had
that happen yet but I can imagine
and so and and I think I think a lot of
uh snow and Jason talked about too is
that you need to have policies in place
so those users know what you ex they're
expected to do if if they don't know who
to call or when there's a problem when
they get it when they click on a
phishing email or what they're supposed
to do that's on you like you need to
tell them what they need to do they need
these needs to be in writing it needs to
be communicated it needs to be easily
found and and not just in an email we
all know how often people read emails I
I don't know about if anybody else has
more success but I I don't seem to have
very much success getting people to read
and respond to emails very often
especially when you send them out to the
whole company so
um having that stuff in writing having a
place to refer back to obviously
training training and going over is
important but having a reference so they
can find it and you know if if you do
training and somebody clicks on a link
or gets a phone call in 18 months from
now are they gonna remember that stuff
probably not
if they have a place so that they can
refer back if they can pull up a web
page a Wiki anything like that and go
hey I remember that there's a the place
I can find this stuff that's what I'm
supposed to do and there's a number that
I'm going to call or there's an email
that I need to send it to whether you
need to set up a distribution group for
you and you know to send spam emails to
or a breach email if I think I
downloaded a virus whatever it is have a
place for these people to communicate to
and let them know you know re reiterate
it what they're supposed to do because
they're not gonna they're not gonna
remember especially when they're
stressed out when if they think they
clicked on the link they've infected
their computer or the network they're
stressed out
um so and the reason like I said the
reason I want to go over sales is
because you need to sell leadership on
this most of the time if they don't have
this if they haven't budgeted this and
they have and they don't have a budgeted
now
um and they haven't had a breach
they don't think they need it and so you
need to you need to convince them that
they do need it and that they need it
before they get a breach and not after
uh it's kind of like the old adage you
can't you know the horses are already
out of the barn if you already had a
breach now that's not the time to spend
money on cyber security
as we all know like I said I'm I'm
preaching the choir a little bit but
like I think I think more people need to
realize that
um
their bosses need to need to be
explained why they need to care about
this stuff you need to show them what
happens those numbers that that snow put
up you know of the average
cost and spend of a single breach of a
data breach is in the Millions
and suddenly your 20 grand or 50 Grand
or 100 grand
doesn't seem like very much
all right soft skills
I know it's fun
to talk about
hard skills and technical skills and we
all love geeking out
but if you're in a smaller company
and you're not in a leadership position
and like I said if you're a one-person
shop two-person shop
you need to know how to talk to people
you need to know how to convince people
that what you're saying is truthful and
that they need to trust you and there's
some skills that come in about that and
and like I said it comes into sales
basically you're selling them on why
they should believe you
this is a big one that I've had to work
on over the last 10 years or so
um
I worked at Apple for a couple years at
The Genius Bar and it's um
it's a tough job especially for what you
get paid for it but I did learn a lot
Apple does a great job on their training
and and their their their training their
leadership on how to train their
employees and how to talk to people
the one thing that I learned there is
that perception is reality if somebody
thinks you're not approachable you are
not approachable and there's a reason
for that uh one of the examples is that
when I would when I would get a
customer's device and we had 10 minute
call a 10-minute appointment times for
uh iOS devices and 15-minute deployment
times for MacBooks or Macs in general
and that's not a lot of time
so my perception going in there was I'm
going to get right to work on this
person's device I'm going to start
pulling the serial number and start
typing their paperwork as they're
talking as they're giving me the
information
the problem with that is is that that
customer oftentimes perceives that as
you don't care you don't care about
their problem you don't care that their
phone's broke you don't care that
they've lost data on their pictures even
though you do so it doesn't matter if
you actually care if they perceive you
not to care then that's all that matters
so I learned uh at that job and it's
it's crazy how well it works it seems
really simple now when somebody comes
into my office and needs help
um even though they haven't put in a
ticket
um I will stop what I'm doing I will it
depending on if where they sit or stand
I will close my computer I will give
them eye contact I will give them my
attention I'm not looking at my phone
I'm not looking at my watch I'm giving
my intention because they've come into
my office for help I'm getting paid to
help them and that's what I tell people
a lot of times because a lot of times
people think that they're bugging the
I.T person or the security person that
you've got better things to do than deal
with their issue and that what that
leads to is them not reporting stuff
they're not they're not going to bother
you oh well I clicked on a link but I
don't think it did anything so I'm not
going to buy I'm not going to bother him
you know so and that's what it leads to
and and I've had
and I like I said I've had to
consciously work on this it's not for
most of us it does not come second
nature most I would guess that most
people in here uh minus some sales
Engineers that are actually in that role
to do to do selling are not used to you
know selling people and and really
talking to people and really comfortable
with it
I'm what's called an introvert extrovert
Troy actually told me this last year and
so I can fake it really well but for the
most part I'm an introvert you know so
and like I said multitasking even though
you think you're being helpful you're
working on things and you're still
listening to them they don't see it that
way they think they think you're too
busy for them and you don't care about
their issue no matter how small it is
and the and you caring about their
smaller issues especially if it doesn't
seem that big maybe maybe you don't
understand why it's a big deal to them
maybe they didn't explain that they have
a project due in an hour and they just
need to fix this problem with PowerPoint
a lot of times they don't but if you
just take every problem seriously as
they come in there then when there is a
serious problem they're going to come to
you and I and I like I said I I I've
noticed that firsthand I I have people
come to me right after they click on a
link and say hey
you know I think I think this email is a
scam email and I clicked on it and I
typed this password in and so and then I
was able to fix it right away I was able
to take the machine and wipe it and and
mitigate it and then take it off the
network immediately not
a week from then when they like hey my
machine's acting weird and I clicked in
this link a week a week ago
and so
that trust that you're not going to get
up that's another thing too you can't
get upset with him you can't roll your
eyes you can't
you know all these little things that
people pick up on the the this body
language and this non-verbal
communication you have to you have to be
conscious of that and and sometimes it
even it even takes working out of the
mirror that you you see people
rehearsing their speeches in a mirror
for a reason because your face portrays
your emotions for most people's anyways
unless you're a sociopath I guess but
most people's faces portray their
emotions so if you're annoyed if you're
frustrated even though some of us get
that way you have to at least try to
hide it you know and because that's how
people trust you they they trust that
that you're not going to get mad at them
you're not going to get upset with them
if somebody keeps clicking on links and
clips opening up emails
um depending on our organization I would
guess that most of the time that's not
your job to get upset with them that's
their managers that's their bosses
that's the owner of the company whatever
it is you shouldn't get to be the bad
guy you shouldn't have to be the bad guy
you should be the the person that
everybody can come to when they have an
issue
um like I said if they keep doing it
then that's a problem but you don't I I
personally don't want to be the be the
bad guy I think it's easier to do your
job when people don't hate you so hence
the reason this talk so
um when there's tons of good books on
this on this on these topics uh the one
that always stands out to me that and
that it sounds really cliche the one
that really changed my life and changed
how I deal with people is very popular a
lot of people have read it a lot of
people haven't How to Win Friends and
Influence People
um there's a ton of good information in
there I didn't even finish the whole
thing I had a I had an old boss that
that said especially with books like
that they're like self-help books and
such
um if you read it if you usually when
you read a book like that you get one
two three pieces of key information that
really ring true to you that really go
like wow I really need to do that that's
a great idea if you read halfway through
that book and you get those already move
on
like you know sometimes there's more
information in there if you still want
to read it that's fine but I don't know
I don't even remember what happened in
my life at the time I got about how like
I said about halfway through that book I
got several good pieces of her
information so I didn't want to force
myself to go back to that book even
there was so there's I'm a big book nerd
so I love reading books but
um like I said even even if you just
read some of the highlights of that book
there's some great stories in there
there's some great advice on how to deal
with people and and it it seems simple
but it is that simple humans are for the
most part are pretty simple creatures
and and communication and talking and
and and it seems intuitive at first
until you read it and you're like wow
okay that's really that not really that
simple so
uh I think I've got over this a little
bit
um sales uh back to How to Win Friends
and Influence People that's when I read
that book is when I was doing sales
um people like to talk about themselves
get to know people what their hobbies
are into don't discount that don't spend
a half an hour speaking talking to
somebody about cars or about photography
you're probably your boss is probably
not going to appreciate that on both
your ends but don't discount spend five
or ten minutes talking to somebody about
just about not about work it has value
you know those relationships have value
especially now that a lot of us are
working from home or not working in the
office
that's you have to work at it more to
get to know people and when people know
you they trust you like I said like I
know I've got a few friends at my office
that I even if even if something was
going wrong that nobody else wanted to
tell me I know they would come to me and
let me know and that that that has value
so don't don't discount that same same
thing with your bosses if if they trust
you and you you know and they trust what
you're saying is true and they like you
they're more aptly they're more apt to
to take your suggestions and Implement
things and give you money to spend on
things
so and this is all what sales is that if
you've ever done any sales at all
like I said they the the customer has to
like you if they don't like you they're
not going to trust you when you tell
them hey you need to spend you know
extra on this or you need to buy this
this is a great product you need to buy
it if they don't like you they're not
going to trust you and they're not going
to they're not going to take your your
word for anything so
um one of the great things that Apple
does with their sales people
is their training process and how to
talk to customers how to sell customers
on their devices if you ever get a
chance it go even if you don't want to
buy an Apple device I know that's a
polarizing Topic in this in this group
um
either go and observe how they talk to
customers or even just go and act like
you're a non-technical customer they're
not going to tell you that this device
has 32 gigs of RAM
they're going to explain why that why
what what benefits you get from having a
device that has 32 gigs of RAM they're
not going to tell you any technical
details from unless you ask I'm sure if
they ask they probably will you know if
you're a technical person and you don't
want 16 you want 32 or whatever it is
they'll tell you they know that stuff
obviously it's selling those devices but
most people don't care your boss doesn't
care for the most part unless they're a
technical person for the most part they
don't care you know you know what the
you know what features of your endpoint
security keep you safe or what features
Office 365 has when you buy an E1
license versus the you know versus a
regular business standard license you
know all the security features you have
they don't care about that stuff they
don't care about the technical details
they care about what it does for them in
the company and what it does for users
and the features the the benefits not
the features basically so that's that's
how you need to explain stuff to them
they don't care that you know this
endpoint is great against ransomware
protection and the exact details and how
it does it you're going to watch them
glaze over faster than anything and
they're you're going to lose them and so
that's why you need to explain you know
hey we need if we get a breach it's
going to cost us this much money and
that's exactly how I had a I had a
client that didn't want to spend money
on an antivirus at the time I was
working for an I.T consultancy and the
main product that we used was sofos
um
and I think at the time with their
ransomware protection it was like seven
or eight dollars an endpoint and they
were a smaller business they wouldn't
have the 10 15 endpoint something like
that and they didn't want to spend that
money it would have been a few a couple
hundred dollars hundred bucks a month or
something like that and I explained it
to him and I said hey if you if you get
a ransomware breach or any other data
breach
um
for me to clean that up and be sure that
it's gone be sure that they're not in
systems you're at least 10 to 15 hours
of my time at over 100 an hour that's
assuming you have no data loss you have
to recreate no work which is almost
impossible that's assuming you have no
downtime you have downtime you're paying
your employees now and they have no
connection they can't work like I said
just My Time is like I said 100 an hour
at 10 to 15 hours if not more like
that's just a conservative estimate and
there and that sold them he was like yep
you're right let's let's pay for it so
that's that's the way you have to break
this stuff down you have to let them
know uh it's it's tough for bosses to
know
to visualize that stuff because a lot of
people and and this is the this is this
this is a risk management thing they
think this is never going to happen to
me until it does that's the problem
that's the problem with with a lot of
this stuff is that they don't see this
happening oh we're not a Target we're
not a defense contractor we're not the
FBI we don't have you know we don't have
any super any two super top secret
but you have competitors and you have
actors out there that just want money
they don't care who you are especially
now that we're in the ransomware age you
know 20 or 30 years ago when the
ransomware was not a big thing there was
no you know a smaller business probably
didn't have any risk of getting targeted
it was probably really really low and
that's understandable and but you have
actors now that don't care who you are
they don't care that you're just a
mom-and-pop with you know a couple
hundred grand in Revenue they're still
going to get money out of you then when
you lock your files up so that's what
that's what people need to realize they
need you know and then maybe you need to
put it like that maybe you need to talk
to them about exactly obviously being an
I.T person you're going to know which
files are valuable
hey what happens if I shut that the
server was offline you know you couldn't
access your QuickBooks what would happen
how much of a problem would that be and
then they get to thinking well I use
QuickBooks like six times a day you know
and that's just me I'm not even the
accountant we didn't have all that
numbers and stuff we had to recreate all
that data that would take weeks and then
not to mention the time you would you
lost work at that time too that's where
you get those wheels turning about what
actually happened what the actual cost
of reach is going to be
communication
I know that a lot of speakers have spoke
about it I noticed a lot in the like I
said a couple of the Keynotes
give people
actionable facts when when you're
sending emails out what you want them to
do don't make it vague explain to them
hey this needs to be done by this date
or whatever it is you need to have
actual
actual facts in there what you need them
to do we need you to update your
computer we need you to do this you need
to do that don't make it vague it needs
to be very laid out and and if you have
to if you're if you're not used to
speaking to non-technical people
have a good friend that's not technical
review it say hey do you understand this
send it to them first
have them review it do you understand
this does this make sense do you have
any questions because I think a lot of
us realize is that we have a lot of this
knowledge and we just assume things a
lot of times and you can't do that
um
this one thing my boss taught me here
she was worked in the defense department
uh for I think of Defense contractors
and they had a limit on how many emails
they could send out
um basically from their bosses because
the more emails you send out
you know hey this new update came out
this thing came out the more people are
going to ignore them
you have to pick and choose what's
important to to email about to send to
to communicate about the more you send
out
the more people are going to start like
I said yeah just another email from it
just another update
so you have to be careful about that
um I I've been guilty of that especially
we have a lot of Max of the shop anybody
that's that has Max and and has and
operates them and and controls them
knows the amount of breaches that have
happened over the last couple they're
not breaches uh security issues that
they've had over the last couple years
the some of the remote execution more
remote code execution bugs that I've had
out that have been being actively
exploited
um I mean the amount that have happened
for iOS and for Mac OS over the last
couple years has been much much higher
than in the past from what I've seen
anyways so
um you have to be careful about you know
being Chicken Little when the sky's not
really falling kind of thing so you have
to balance that
talked about this earlier
um
not just your friends a couple of people
that are you know are
less technical users
have a group of people that you can roll
things out to First and test it
um
you can have a really bad time
if you click the wrong box and you send
something out incorrectly
um I I experienced this with our MDM I
was trying to push a password policy out
to our computers and I did not test this
as real world as I was going to use it
when I when I actually pushed it out for
real and it thankfully only pushed it
out to a few years a few users
but it did cause some problems I found
out after I pushed the password policy
out that my plan was to create the
policy
and push it out to five or ten users and
then add five or ten users to that and
then in another week or so after they
change their passwords add a few more
few more users and roll it out slowly
over time
the problem was the documentation for
our MDM did not make it clear that every
time you made a change to that password
policy it pushed the whole thing out to
all the devices again so if there's a
force reset in there and you add devices
two or three times and hit save two or
three times all those devices get to
reset their password multiple times and
that cues them up so you change your
password
you lock your machine go log back in
again you get to change your password
again so needless to say
the few users that I got sent to were
not very happy with me if I had to
pushed it out to the whole company
including the the uh the owners of the
company I probably would have been a
whole lot worse uh I as it was I only
end up having to wipe one machine
because I didn't have encryption Keys
saved for that MacBook uh
in sofos so that I could when they
basically they use this user type their
change their password for the second or
third time and they typed it in
Incorrect and must have bumped the wrong
key and locked themselves out so wiping
one machine and wiping 20 and 30
machines and trying to recover data from
them is a whole lot better so
um learned learn from my mistakes learn
from others mistakes you know and and
and test things as real world as
possible the exactly how you're going to
use them as as much as possible if you
can have a test bench that's even better
something that you can easily blow away
and you can you can you know wipe if you
had to if you screw it up
um and like I said test it on users that
aren't going to get too mad at you if
they you really screw their computer up
ones that you know that they have their
data backed up or it's on Dropbox or box
or OneDrive or whatever so that you do
have you do screw their computer up it's
not going to be that big of a deal
um this is kind of getting into the
little the CIS stuff
Troy did a talk of this a couple years
ago this is where I first found this
like I said I'm a little new to him for
a second General
um it seems really basic
inventory you know password policies
hardening
um but a lot of teams I've seen people
uh I've seen people that I've known that
have been more experienced that don't
that aren't doing this stuff and I know
a lot it seems like I said the Keynotes
I know Jason preached on this if you
don't know what devices are on your
network
you have a problem you need to do that
it's a basic thing that a lot of people
are not doing we're not doing that and
I'm working on it right now
um it's it's tougher than you think
um especially if you don't have
leadership buy-in if people are buying
machines that aren't going through it
and they have you know there's how many
people in your how many people in your
organization have credit cards and they
need something they just go and buy it
that's a problem
unless you have controls set up where
they can't put that device in the
network until it goes through you that's
another thing we're working on too if
anybody can just put any device on the
network if they know the password
you're gonna you're in for a bad time
um I I had to find out the hard way that
just allowing people to plug in devices
into the network and the hardware or uh
Wireless
um somebody's going to bring a router in
and turn on a DHCP server and start
handing on IP addresses
so that was the day that I turned on
Port security so
you don't think you need it until you
need it did I lose this you ready to
hear me
oh
maybe it was just a little louder before
okay
all right so uh same with software
inventory
um when this is something we didn't have
any put in place when log 4J came out I
had no clue if we had anything running
that none
I had to go and start asking our
developers I was like hey do we have
anything that runs this they didn't know
that's a problem when a when you can you
can be on top of this stuff as much as
you want and right when that stuff comes
out and know exactly how to fix it but
if you don't know if you're running that
or where all those machines are at
you're going to have a problem uh that's
that's what happened with Equifax I
don't know if anybody is aware of
exactly what happened they missed the
machine they they I think I believe it
was it was an Apache bug I can't
remember exactly the details but I know
they the company that or that size
didn't have controls in place to make
sure that they had everything patched
they missed the machine and the hacker
is gonna excuse me I don't want to use
that word a bad actor is going to make
you pay for that all they need is one
time all you all you need is all you
need to do is Miss one you don't need 50
machines that are available you just
need one and that's all they need and
they found it and so you have to have an
inventory of this stuff and know exactly
what's been patched and what you have
what you're running what software you're
running so in order to keep your network
secure
um I guess I could kind of jumped ahead
of myself a little bit here so
um yeah like this was a bit this is
something we're getting under control
that like I said I've been in the the
company now three years now and all of a
sudden people would just show up with a
new device and I was like
where'd you get that oh my boss bought
it for me okay can I have it I need to
put you know endpoint Security on it I
need to put patch management I need to
record an inventory and a lot of times
that I wouldn't even see it a lot of
times devices would just show up on the
network and I was like okay who's who's
got a new Macbook so you have everything
has to run through somebody some point
of contact in it so you so you know
what's on your network or you have to
have security controls or better you
have to have security controls that
doesn't even allow them to have access
to anything unless they go through you
has to be added and that's tough to do
sometimes that's that's it's a whole lot
easier to just spin up a wireless
network and put a password on it and
give it out to anybody everybody so a
lot of businesses do unfortunately
that's what ours did for the longest
time R said the same password on the
Wi-Fi for 10 plus years over a building
move
and I'm sure that there was in that that
10 plus years there was nobody that was
fired or let go and it was disgruntled
at all they would still have that Wi-Fi
password
um
yeah along I think a lot of people at
times think of inventory as just
Hardware inventory but like I said it's
it's software too along with this
um this is another way you can push this
too there's another way you can get
money for just spending on patch
management and asset inventory is that
we had a problem with with people
needing an Office 365 license and they
didn't know where to get it so they just
whip out their company credit card and
sign up and then three or four years
later when we've got the company they've
got a company license they're still
getting charged for that
so how many how many other how much does
this happen on your company where people
are just buying licenses we found out
that we had we had more Dropbox licenses
at our company than we had employees
like by like 30 or 40 percent
and that gets expensive really fast I I
found a uh
I don't remember what the name of the it
was like a online file server type
program kind of like Dropbox and
OneDrive
um
it was about six or seven hundred
dollars a year that we had nobody had
touched for like two or three years
and I've been finding stuff like that
all the time so when you have that stuff
recorded and somebody's checking on that
stuff
they know that hey we stopped using that
we need to cancel that this year when
you have to be able to document the
ability to document that stuff and
record it in a central place where
somebody's watching it you can save your
company money and like I said if
nobody's watching it it's a free-for-all
I guarantee there's waste
um my boss calculated over 100 Grand
that we they were wasting licenses that
we're paying for that nobody's using or
that we've got duplicates of
so
um
the company I work for is not huge 100
Grand is a lot of freaking money
depending on the size of your company it
could be or could not be but that's all
that's 100 Grand that could be going
towards I.T and security
that was just wasted they literally lit
on fire
figuratively sorry not literally
figuratively lit on fire
um
so yeah it's it's all about finding the
angle to get you to get to get money to
spend on on security and and if you can
save them money and it's not just an
overhead expense
your CFO will love you for that
um patch management kind of comes back
to software inventory a little bit they
kind of go hand in hand I think it's
been in my experience anyways
um if you don't know what you have or
what software version is running
um
then it's kind of tough to know if
everything's up to date
users I have users I don't know if I'm
guessing everybody has this raise your
hand if you have users that leave
browsers open for weeks at a time and
and hundreds of tabs
and then and then when a problem happens
they lose their mind that you want them
to completely close their browser
so that's the only way that browser
updates you leave it open it's not going
to update they the browser is Chrome and
Firefox and brave all are great about
pushing automatic updates but if they
ignore that little update button in the
top
doesn't matter if you don't close your
browser restart your computer it's not
going to update so if you don't if you
don't have any way to track what version
of software that is on it and you have
more than a few machines you have to
there's no way you can do that manually
and I and I found out I find that out
too now that I have a I have patch
Management in place and I can see in a
central location they the the company
that I use it's I think it's manage
engine
even Flags severity of patches too so
that's that's less work for me I don't
have to go and track down which patches
I need to do which ones I don't need to
do which ones I need to prioritize they
give me a little colored box and the red
ones I do first
it's you know it seems simple once you
have it in place
um along with this especially the way
new laptops are people need to have
backups and I and I know like probably
half my employees do not uh
if a patch pushes out wrong it could
screw a computer up and you have to wipe
it and reinstall if you've got a backup
probably not a big deal it's a minor
inconvenience an hour or two if you
don't have a backup
depending on the on the user that's
probably kind of a big deal
um with like most modern laptops
nowadays you can't just pull a hard
drive out of them you know and pull the
files off of them that's not a thing
especially if you've got a Macbook I
think a lot of other manufacturers are
going to that now too where uh that that
drive and the SSD and stuff are soldered
onto the board that's becoming more and
more of a thing so
that's that's a much much bigger idea to
to back up if you're if you're going to
push updates and make people restart
their computers
um you need to be cying and at least
letting them know that I can't recover
your data if your computer crashes if it
doesn't power on your data is gone I
don't think the company is going to
spend 10 or 15 grand to set out to a
data recovery Place uh most depending on
the on the data they're probably not
they're just going to be kind of out of
luck
uh I guess I got ahead of myself again
uh backups
and uh
same thing with ransomware a lot of
people know that the only real strategy
against ransomware foolproof is a backup
and an offline backup
I've got a hard drive that I plug into
the server
um there's there's several backup
programs now that will disconnect the
hard drive after it's been backing up
that's that's that's the best way as far
as I'm concerned to make a backup so you
don't have to actually manually unplug
it all the time
uh
if you're not testing your backups at
least pulling a file out of the
receiving if it can open
if you can test the full backup a full
restore of a server that's great
sometimes that's not plausible sometimes
you don't have a whole test bench and
you don't have another 10 grand to spend
on replacement on duplicate servers to
spin that backup back up but just even
even opening that back up and pulling
some files out of there and see if they
open up Word files PowerPoint files
whatever it is you can catch a crop
backup like that a lot of times I've had
it happen where I open a file up and it
just it just will not read or it opens
up and it's just garbled basically and
you can do another full backup and check
it again if you're not testing them just
like just like all the just like a lot
of these these policies and stuff like
that if you're not testing them you're
not running through real world scenarios
with your employees when they happen
what they need to do
you're not you're not you're not going
to have the results you need when
there's an actual emergency when you
actually need that backup you need to
have a policy in place a schedule in
place where we're testing this stuff
regularly
okay I guess I'm a little early here
um
I'm guessing obviously preaching the
choir a little bit in here
this is just the beginning this is not
this talk was not supposed to be some
comprehensive on how to secure a network
there's lots more stuff to do there's
lots more interesting that CIS the just
that CES is kind of a kind of a basic
start basically they even though it's
kind of a comprehensive
um
risk management is what we do all the
time our building has clients that come
in there all the time I I'm not even
there half the time when they're there
at night time in different Towers we run
events out of there stuff like that you
have to control for users you have to
protect users from themselves you have
to assume that they're going to plug
they're going to plug machines into your
network and you have to plan for that
you have to assume that somebody's going
to bring a router in from outside and
because they didn't have enough good
enough Wi-Fi in their office and just
plug it in
and and your network has to be hardened
against that you you can't just allow
that it's is it a pain in the butt to
have to to
you know turn Port Security on and off
when somebody changes machines
yeah but it's more of a pain to try to
hunt down a rogue DHCP server or or find
out later that you had a rogue access
point and and there there was somebody
from outside that they left open and got
in your network
it's it's you get a you get to pay one
way or the other one one weighs a whole
lot less painful
um like I said the the CIS controls it's
it's it's crazy how how well done they
are and going exactly over step by step
by step exactly what you need to do
um
but
you need to prioritize what's what's
right for your company like I said the
port security was not a priority in our
company until it wasn't like I said
until until somebody plugged in a router
and I had users getting random random IP
addresses so uh that got moved to the
front of the list so you need to assess
your risk if you don't have anybody
coming into your office
um
and uh you know random clients plugging
in random machines that's probably not
as much of a priority you know asset you
know asset manager is probably more of a
priority you have to worry about what
where your employees machines and your
users machines are at rather than people
coming in from the outside but if you've
got all if you've got the general public
coming into your offices and you've got
ports out where the general public can
access and and like I said to our office
we have we have clients that are needing
internet access and stuff like that so
what I have to have a plan in place to
give them internet access that doesn't
have access to our Network so
everybody's company is going to be
different you have to you know
prioritize yours depending on your risk
so
and that's it
okay anybody have any questions
I haven't specifically but um
that's that's I think a world that
software inventory can comes in you have
to automate that software inventory I
haven't I haven't got to that point but
I'm guessing there's got to be products
that can alert you when a new piece of
software has been installed depending on
your situation
I'm still working on getting local admin
removed from a lot of our computers so
you know it's it's priorities at this at
that point so like the people at my
company was the Wild West for so long
that it's just going to be baby steps
getting that little you know you know
taking a little bit of time and making
people realize that
now you probably don't need to just
install whatever program you want
whenever you want to like you I get it's
easier you know when you you don't need
to come find me when you need to install
a program but you probably don't really
need that you know for the most part we
can plan ahead with a little bit of
planning we can plan ahead for that
um so I I think there's there's a
mixture of solutions to that problem
obviously the software inventory is one
of them flagging stuff that that you
guys don't normally use that are like I
said products like TeamViewer the people
that are free for home use and then and
then they want to make you pay
um they're thankfully not as aggressive
about sending letters and and and
wanting money back because you're using
it they just excuse me they just lock
you out of it basically they find that
they if they detect commercial use they
just kind of lock your account kind of
thing so I think that's a mixture of
things I think I I to me I think the
solution is not letting users install
whatever they want whenever they want it
and making requests but um if you're
just a one-person shop two-person shop
sometimes it's not that's not always
feasible we have we've we have account
Executives going out to events at all
hours of the the day and night and I I
don't know about you but I don't want to
get phone calls at 11 PM on a Sunday
night you know needing a program
installed right now that doesn't sound
like very much fun to me so
um it's it's all a case-by-case basis on
what works for you
so cool anybody else
I can't see
okay I think I don't I think that's it
perfect thanks guys