by way of introduction my name is Josh
Broadbent I am the RVP for Solutions
engineering at Beyond trust software
specifically our public sector group
I have been doing I.T in some form or
fashion for 25 years now I started in
MSP when I was 12. I did National
competitions and National certifications
when I was like 14 which was a record of
some kind at the time I guess and I
transitioned that career into doing
architecture and design for networks in
public sector
K-12 and Department of Defense so that's
a little bit about me on a technical
level I don't have the picture slides on
a personal level
I am married I have four kids or as I
like to tell anybody when I travel I
have one kid in three spares so if you
are here and you would like to take an
extra child I am more than happy to give
them away no I'm just kidding
um
no seriously I love my kids they are I
have four of them the oldest is 12 the
youngest is four and the youngest is the
only girl in the group
um so she has definitely figured out
that she's the boss of the house
um so that that works out really well
uh in our spare time we wakeboard uh my
middle two kids play or my my yeah we
wakeboard the youngest one doesn't play
sports yet the middle two kids do soccer
and baseball and my oldest son is a
spelling bee athlete I don't know
whatever you would call that but he
competes he he's competed since he was
in third grade he's ninth grade now
spelling bees never lost a regional
Place third last year in state and this
is his last year to try to make it to
National so hopefully he'll he'll do his
thing he didn't get spelling for me I'm
glad they invented word check
so all right tell you guys a little bit
about Beyond Trust
a couple of things real quick
um this is a really fascinating
conference for us to be at and one of
the reasons it's fascinating is because
it brings together so many different
sections of cyber security and Security
in general seeing lock picking and safe
tracking and all of the other things
Hardware cracking downstairs uh is
really fascinating to me
because security does encompass so much
more than just software
um at Beyond trust we are a software
company we specifically Focus uh mostly
around the
um privileged identity space we want to
take care of privileged accounts we do
have 1250 employees and uh 18 different
countries one of the things that I like
to call out about these slides that's
important to me is that we have 75
different patents in the Pam space which
is really unique especially when you
realize that they go all the way back to
like the mid 90s so we inherited some IP
in one of our Acquisitions that's around
the way that you manage
uh privilege access in Linux so it's a
it's a policy form for for pseudo and
stuff like that so
um before other companies even had a
thought about privilege access
management and what that looked like we
had patents in the area so that's one of
the things that I always find
interesting about that
so
I like the slide to set the stage for
just a second about
where we are from a current events
perspective
and the funny thing about doing these
kinds of slides to me is
you put together this slide
or in my case my marketing team puts
together this slide for me
and I get to deliver it in two weeks and
it's usually outdated by the time I
could deliver it like we could add 15
more up here by the time that I deliver
the conversation and it's one of those
things that
exploits or hacks or breaches or
ransomware attacks whatever you want to
call them
they happen exponentially more every day
and it's almost to the point where they
make the news but
were desensitized to it in some way
we had breaches over the past 18 months
that compromised water facilities and
hospitals and gas pipelines
and
those things barely made a blip on our
radar
did you get anybody in here watch Tiger
King
like right at the beginning of covid I
got one guy all right
nobody else was that bored during the
first part of lockdown like it was a
train wreck that I couldn't look away
from
um it really was it was the weirdest
show I have ever watched
in my life and will probably stay that
way hopefully because I don't ever want
to watch anything that insane again
but I remember a couple of months after
it came out and I'd watched it
I saw a meme that was like this show was
so strange that this happened in the
show and you never saw it and it was a
picture of one of the main characters
um driving a spider which is like a type
of motorcycle with two wheels on the
front and one wheel in the back and he
had a skeleton in the passenger seat
and it's like this clip happened in the
show and you never noticed that this
dude was driving around with the
skeleton in his motorcycle the entire
time
and they were right
like I went back and watched the episode
just to be like that skeleton was never
there
sure enough in this show this dude
driving around with a skeleton as his
passenger
okay it was funnier in my head
um but anyways the reason that I bring
it up is because breaches are a lot like
that like they are so wild and out of
hand today that
the dude driving around with the
skeleton doesn't even make the news it's
like living in Florida the strange
things happen and they just don't make
the news
but what It ultimately results in is
that we have to have a different model
for how we handle cyber security
especially from an Enterprise
perspective
from an Enterprise perspective
we have for 30 plus years as long as
I've been doing this looked at our
Enterprise security as a traditional
moat and Castle type infrastructure
right so we've looked at it as as long
as we build a wall around everything
that we have and we make sure that that
wall is robust enough and there are
enough things on the wall maybe we put a
moat around the wall
anything inside the wall is
automatically okay like we're all right
we trust our users which is a terrible
plan but we trust our users
um
everything that happens here
we're going to be okay with from a
security perspective it's an acceptable
level of risk
over time we've realized a few things
number one once somebody breaches that
wall we have no long no idea how long
they're in there
which is what happened with the
solarwinds breach
they were in there for six plus months
and we're still cleaning up
but beyond that
nobody anticipated the massive ships
shift to work from home
so now every admin assistant's kids Xbox
is on our corporate networks their Wii
is on our corporate Network so
we can't build a wall big enough for all
of these devices to fit inside our
corporate Network
there's no way
everybody that's here I'm sure has has
seen or been familiar with
um security conferences like this one
and others where they sh you know have
the Wall of Shame up and they show you
text messages that are going in and out
from people's phones
from a corporate perspective you consume
or have that many devices on your
corporate VPN at some point you you
can't do anything else it's it's there
and you have to give them free reign but
you don't and that's why we've looked at
zero trust as a model that's why it's
made a lot of headlines that's why it's
it's been a conversation
and the funny thing is 10 years ago zero
trust was a term that was mostly made up
by another Pam vendor so that they could
Splash it all over their marketing
um and then it slowly garnered
like a meaning of some kind and then
eventually somebody picked it up and
decided hey this should actually have a
standard to it
so nist came out with nist 800 207
and they put a standard behind it and
they said in this standard what we want
is a continuous verification of users
every time a user goes to access a
resource or authenticate we want them to
authenticate we want to know that they
have authorization to access the
material that they're accessing and we
want to audit all of that
and whatever tool that they're using to
do that we're going to put together
um we're gonna we're gonna collect that
data together so that we actually have
one single source of security data and
authentication data for our entire
network
and that's what's important when we talk
about zero trust is the collective use
and organization of tools a lot of tools
used to define zero trust or to to build
it in the architecture already exist in
corporate networks today the problem is
that they're siled right the problem is
that they all exist as individual tools
and not as part of a broader security
model that is integrated and
Incorporated together as a security
strategy
so the principles of the zero trust
model go like this so require and secure
requires secure and authenticated access
to all assets
adopt and enforce the least privileged
model
and inspect and log all activities using
security Analytics
as you're taking a look at implementing
a zero trust model across your
environment
there are several things that you have
to look at you have to understand what
your data looks like this is probably
one of the hardest things about xero
trust as it exists
data governance identity governance has
always been a challenge because we've
had so much unstructured data for so
long that we don't know how to tag it
and sometimes we don't even know what
the data is to know how to tag it
in addition to that
this requires cooperation from the end
user and from the business users and use
cases
understanding where sensitive data
exists getting them to stop storing
sensitive data in places that it
shouldn't go all of these things are
important in implementing a zero trust
model so that you can ensure proper
security is there
but it requires cooperation from
the end user or Enterprise to make sure
that you have that stuff tagged
correctly and it's one of the most
difficult things in the process
and then once we have that done we talk
about access to that data how are we
going to control access to that data
how are we going to understand roles or
needs or operations or attribute-based
access so that we can make sure that the
people who have access to that data are
the people that are supposed to have
access to it and that their access is
revoked when they are no longer supposed
to have access to it
we also have to monitor threats as we're
doing this we have to understand the
behavior that's happening on our network
is someone that's accessing this data
are they accessing are they accessing
the data outside of their normal
behavior analytics so they're used to
accessing this data you know at noon or
12 30 on a Thursday from their desk and
now level all of a sudden they're
accessing it at 2 A.M from a seat in
Nigeria over VPN
it's probably a problem
and we have to understand that
so we have to understand what those
threats look like and we have to
understand what a normal Baseline of
behavior is so we can understand what
abnormal behavior is and then we have to
be able to apply analytics to all of
that so that we can ensure that
so that we can ensure that we understand
the moments that we have a Potential
Threat we understand the moments that
something is abnormal and we can
investigate what those are
a successful zero trust implementation
requires privileged access management
for a few reasons number one you have to
secure
the privileged access and assets you
have on your network whether that is
your network admins that have access to
network devices whether that's active
directory admins whether that's your
file storage admins all of those use
cases have to be audited and logged in
order to make this strategy work
in addition to that we also need to
understand what our end users are doing
and we need to allow our end users to be
able to do their jobs and do it well
um
so
what we have to do is take the privilege
off of the end users and actually add it
through policy to the applications that
they're launching so that way they don't
have they don't have access if those
accounts get compromised and there's
lateral movement because the policy is
in place
so as we talk about
zero trust and what that looks like nist
800-207 outlines a successful
implementation for zero trust uh as an
architecture again it's not a product
that somebody buys you can't go buy zero
trust off of a shelf if somebody tries
to sell you zero trust off of a shelf I
would highly recommend you walk away
um but beyond trust can uh address
several of the 207 tenants through
various uses of our our tool and we've
listed some of those on these slides
we want to make sure that we are here as
we implement this to make sure that
everything is monitored everything is
measured that you can audit all of the
things that your end users are doing uh
from a privileged access perspective
that you can audit all of the privileged
access that they have on their servers
and network devices that we can monitor
and audit contractors that are coming in
remote users that are coming in to
understand that they're accessing the
assets that they're supposed to access
we want to make sure that just in time
privilege and least privilege is
enforced across a network
and these things are all important
because as we adjust to this kind of
passwordless concept we need to make
sure that
the assets that we're protecting that no
longer require passwords but require
some sort of other authentication
mechanism if they are ever compromised
uh if those authentication mechanisms
are ever compromised you're going to
struggle with lateral movement in those
because
once they have that authentication
method and they have that token say
they're going to be able to move
wherever they want to move so if that
account itself doesn't have privilege
but rather the applications have
privilege even if they move laterally
there's nothing for them to have access
to other than the standard user
permissions that anybody would have
so this is the zero trust diagram that
80207 put out where they kind of
outlined what a successful strategy from
an application standpoint would look
like we put our logos in there because
we think the Orange is pretty
um no I'm just kidding
no we put our logos in there in a couple
of spots
because we believe that these spots are
important and they're important from the
modules that we offer first of all we do
offer the policy Administration piece so
from a privileged access perspective you
can use Beyond trust to do
to manage the privilege the policy for
your privileged administrators for your
users all of that policy can be managed
in a central console so that you
understand what they're doing and what
they're supposed to be able to do and
then we have several places inside our
products that allow us to have
enforcement points whether that's on the
workstations that we're not trusting we
can continue to add privilege Management
on those like I talked about with the
just in time privilege and also as an
enforcement point on your administrators
and privileged accounts
this is our four pillar slide these are
the the pillars of products that we
offer that sit across the 800-207
deployment we look at traditional
privileged password management from a
um from a perspective of
password vaulting session management
being able to rotate those credentials
making sure that no one has access to
those credentials except when they need
it making sure that they get checked
back in rotating service account
credentials all of those things
the second pillar on the left over there
is the the secure remote access which
has come in as a strong conversation
Point as we talk about work from home
being able to have a way that you can do
remote access that doesn't require a VPN
that allows a connection
secured over an encrypted tunnel that
doesn't give broader sprawl access
across your network but allows
somebody's specific asset access to a
specific asset
um and then the just in time endpoint
privilege management that we talked
about whether it's Mac Linux Windows
Windows servers uh we have something for
for those os's and then there is our
Cloud Security Management pillar where
we talk about Cloud entitlements and how
you're going to handle those
we are giving away a raffle so my shoes
are not near as bright as some of my
colleagues that have been walking around
um but we are giving away a 200 Noble
because it's no bull gift card to uh to
their to their store so that you can
order shoes if you want them to be as
bright orange as some of my colleagues
you're welcome to they're up on their
website though most of you would
probably choose a more muted color so
you can scan that QR code and register
for that the QR codes also at our table
downstairs
um and then we're at booth number 20
which is on the very end by the food
table which is where I like to be by the
food table
um and you can also check out our
trusted protector cartoon series uh and
then our Alice and Bob podcast is is a
great podcast with industry experts
talks about the human side of cyber
security and I promise it is not the the
podcast is not a uh a product pitch
constantly through I actually listen to
the podcast on my runs it's otherwise if
it was sales and marketing stuff I I
wouldn't so it's it's a great podcast
for The Human Side of cyber security we
interviewed some some really interesting
people uh I encourage you to check that
out thank you guys and if you have any
questions I'd take those