I'm Josh Linton as I've been up here
staring at these lights I thought I do
not
stand in front of spotlights that often
and I thought why don't I do that and
then I remembered it's the reflection of
the head that really is not it's not
flattering so I apologize for anybody
who has to deal with that in your eyes
but I'm glad to be here Josh Linton with
Valcom and I really want to talk about
some
strategies for cyber security but I
wanted to start out with with a story
about five years ago I got a call from a
CEO
and uh he's in a panic
he had just seen a check try to clear in
his bank account for fifty thousand
dollars
and normally you don't want to check to
bounce this one did he only had about
forty thousand dollars in his bank he
had recently within kind of a week of
that had just withdrawn
um
it's about thirty thousand dollars to
get them below the fifty and he says the
problem is I didn't write this check
and I don't know how anybody got into my
bank account to
um to do this so we started to
uh do a little bit of research and uh so
I'm asking him and said you what other
computers do you use do you log into
your bank account from your phone and uh
he says no it I have my laptop and
that's it right all I do is
um
I log in for my laptop I don't even log
in for my phone I don't share with
anybody and uh
so we're I'm trying to figure out if he
if somebody's got a key logger how are
they accessing this information right
and then I ask if he keeps his passwords
anywhere
now this is an older gentleman
so I was thinking that he might keep him
on post a note under his keyboard
for good or bad he didn't it would have
been better in this case but he was
keeping them on a note on his phone
right and his phone was pretty private
but this note was sinking to his Office
365 account
right and as we uh I did not figure it
out this fast for the record it took me
a little longer than that but uh as we
kind of did some research turned out
about three weeks prior to this uh he
had received an email with a shared
document and uh he had clicked on it put
his uh
his credentials in and immediately
recognized that it was fraudulent so he
called the help desk and got his
password changed so he was compromised
for maybe 10 minutes right in those 10
minutes the the Bad actors were able to
download as enough data that they
quickly identified his notes with his
passwords and had logged into his bank
account created a new uh bill pay
recipient and had written themselves a
check and if he had
luckily withdrawn some of that that
money from that account uh he would have
uh lost that
this was four years ago
and
interesting part is different CEO I got
a very similar call just a month two
months ago
somebody had
sent an email to their customer
from their email domain asking them to
change where they sent their uh
multiple hundred thousand dollar payment
right at that point you're in in many of
these cases you're hoping your business
can survive some of these things right
I'm probably not sharing anything you
don't know but everyone this it's it's
serious business everyone's a Target
um whether it's a business personal and
uh as we talk today about the cyber
security strategies it really is your
data your business that is the key uh to
your to your success as a as business uh
as businesses so one thing that I wanted
to kind of get by raise of hands who
here is in uh leadership positions raise
bands okay
uh sis admins kind of admin positions
and then I know that lots of students
how many we have some students in this
in this session nope one that's good
kind of students that's fair right my
wife's a student she's going back to
school
she will not be here though she's a
nurse different program uh what we want
to talk about are eight strategies for
uh preparing your company for cyber
security attack and we'll talk about
these in priority but really the the the
trick with cyber security is in many
cases it's not about if you're there's
going to be a breach or some sort of
security incident it's about when right
and so
having a strategy for protecting
your business is probably it's the best
you can do a determined criminal is
probably going to get in anyway right we
just don't want to make it easy for them
right so as we talk about this we'll use
This Acronym safe Pace we'll go through
each of these security availability
flexibility and extensibility and then
policy audit compliance and education
we'll talk a little bit about each of
these and how they might apply to your
business
um
so let's start first with security this
one may be
the most basic and at a security
conference may not need to be said or
we're going to say it anyway right and
that is you have to take a secure
approach securing your devices securing
your network access physical security
all of these things are so important and
making sure that you are setting
yourself up for for success in this area
all right one of the big uh
challenges and maybe you don't want to
raise your hands here but how many of
you have dealt with a ransomware attack
from someone else right no yeah don't
raise your hands we deal with them all
the time we've we have our we will
typically have
um I'll bet we get a call a month from a
different customer earlier in the year I
feel like we were getting them almost
every week with somebody having a
ransomware incident they're trying to
recover their data or trying to
determine whether or not they want to
um
pay their Anthem try to recover the FBI
says don't pay
because every time we pay them
we just kind of the cycle continues they
make money they do it again and they do
a better job next time right
and this security and preparing is
really the the very beginning of a
journey to secure your environment uh
and so you'll want
this is sorry it was one slide behind
there uh veeam pulled a thousand it
companies all of them who had had a
cyber security incident
73 percent of them
in 2021 had two or more incidents of
ransomware
right 68 of those
their backups were also compromised
that's a major problem anybody who's
experienced ransomware the really good
uh Bad actors
they're going to wait until they have
access to your backup data because then
they know you have to pay
right without a good way to recover from
ransomware paying that Ransom may be the
only way that you can keep your business
in business right and so uh and then 32
percent of those that paid the ransom
were not able to get all their data back
so it's uh
and ransomware is just one one example
maybe one of the most prolific right now
but it's a major issue and so you need
to be prepared for ransomware and this
is one of the things
but I want you to take away if there's
one thing you take away from this are
these questions right
to ask yourself and then to ask your
team and uh a marketing team did a great
job they actually uh created some PDFs
two PDFs one for you as a leader and one
for your team
at the end I'll put a link you can just
you can download those and take them
back
and
um
ask your team these questions and
compare them and that's really the key
right how confident am I that my system
is secure that current threats are
prevented how confident am I that if
there is a security breach that we can
rapidly recover and mitigate any damage
how confident am I that my team knows
what they need to do in order to provide
ongoing security for our critical
systems right and then as you ask your
team these same things right uh
that I think is where you will see a lot
of areas for improvement
where there's a discrepancy between what
you believe
is happening and what your team believes
is happening right and you rank that on
a scale of one to ten and now you have
an opportunity to go and start making
some improvements in your security
policy and procedures
uh
now if you have questions throughout
this I will not take the full 45 minutes
so if you have a question raise your
hand I can address it now or we can do
it at the end whatever feels most
relevant for for the question uh so
next let's talk about availability
um
prior to covid
at our office we might have had uh 25 of
our employees that had kind of VPN and
and remote access
to to the data
prior to covet a hundred percent of our
employees can work part-time uh at least
part of the time from home right this
availability requirement and uh is is
key it has been for some people for a
long time for us covet forced it on us
and now that data needs to be available
24 7 to all of our employees right and
uh
one of the things to consider in
availability is what it costs you in
downtime right and one of the things I'm
always wary of in presentations is what
I like to call marketing math
that is if you buy my product you're
going to save a million dollars that
whole thing at some level it's probably
true right but for each of you as you
take these these numbers and this is why
we kind of did it this way is that
um you just take your annual revenue and
you divide it by the number of hours if
you're a 24x7 operation that's 87.60 and
if you're an eight by five operation
it's 2080 that gives you your Revenue
per hour
that would be a potential loss in
revenue for downtime so 100 for example
100 million dollar company
uh that is eight by five
if they 10 hours of downtime cost them
480 000 in Revenue
right and so as you
calculate this that doesn't count that
doesn't take into account lost
productivity or redirected
um resources as you're trying to resolve
these types of of situations right so
the availability isn't just something to
to help the company grow but it costs
money right and uh unplanned downtime
really becomes something that's that's
not an acceptable
situation for most companies and for us
one thing that we learned quickly this
is prior to covid uh we got a call in
fact it wasn't a call the fire
department came into our building and
they said you need to get everybody out
of here
and we said is there a fire they said oh
no but there could be there's a gas leak
right outside your building and everyone
has to leave until the gas company can
come fix it
and then we can clear the building
you would think that would be fast
it was not
uh and for me well for any of you I
imagine when some when there's an issue
you jump on these things right away it
took about I think it was 24 or 48 hours
before we could bring everybody back
into our building well during that time
we only had 25 percent of our employees
that were able to continue to work right
the amount of lost productivity that
that cost us as well as the challenges
when everybody came back trying to get
caught up right
uh is kind of a recipe for additional
errors rushing through some of these
things right so availability becomes an
important uh part of your overall plan
um
and and that's really uh from if you
don't have one additional thing that
you'll want to
think about is a business continuity
plan
how many of you know what a tabletop
exercise is yeah
uh if you're not doing those regularly
you need to be that that's an area in
which as you build your business
continuity plan and you can kind of run
through that exercise and say okay what
are we going to do when there's a gas
leak or what do we do if there's a fire
or an earthquake and you can run through
those scenarios to make sure that you're
addressing the issues uh that
that might be part of your organization
but that you're prepared for those
issues as well right and that your
environment is prepared
uh and we're back to these these
questions right how confident uh are you
that your I.T system will remain up and
available regardless of what might
happen right
uh how confident am I that my system
goes down from a technical failure and
disaster or breach that my team can get
it operational before it impacts the
business
and then for your team these same
questions right
be interesting to see if these are
different for your organization
flexibility
how many of you
well you don't have to answer this
question if you've been in this in in it
for maybe longer than 10 or 15 years
I remember the time when
uh we did not have to be flexible
IT director said here's how it's going
to be and you're going to do it my way
and
that's pretty much how it goes that's
how we maintain security around here
right
uh no you can't have an iPad it's not
secure
no you can have one computer only
that is not the case anymore right
most users have two three plus devices
we can't control that right we have to
be flexible and we have to be prepared
uh to
adapt to the needs of our
uh
our users right I call them our
customers our internal customers right
that's who we're supporting one of the
challenges with this is also Shadow I.T
how many of you are dealing with Shadow
I.T
yeah
um
our marketing director might be in this
room
and so I'm going to take a little risk
here and share a story
um
we were as a number of years ago I'm
talking to our CEO and I said we've got
a problem with kind of Shadow I.T people
going on buying tools and software that
we can't maintain
and he says well why why does that
matter so because they bring it in and
now there's a whole other Vector attack
from a security perspective there's
other issues too but from a security
perspective here's an attack Vector that
I don't even know about right so how am
I going to be able to takes me longer to
remedy whatever situation might occur
and he says well give me an example he
said well the marketing department just
got a new project management software he
says I'll talk to them about it
so he's talking to the marketing
director and uh
and she says oh we don't do that what do
you what do you mean we don't do Shadow
I.T he says well did you get a new
project management software she said oh
yeah we did
oh yeah I guess that is
Shadow I.T the thing that clicked for me
is
she didn't even realize what she was
doing
it was so easy
for her and her team to say hey we need
project management
we need and I can go get it for five
dollars a month
I'm just gonna do that and put it on my
card and I'm off and running right as an
I.T organization those things
they needed that we were not prepared to
offer it
right
and so we either have to from a
flexibility perspective we need to be
prepared to offer the tools that they
need
or we need to have in place methods for
them to get those tools and to let us
know so that we can then secure them and
put them into the
the fold if you will of the tools and
the security posture that we're
preparing for
um
so similar questions uh how confident am
I that my it team can rapidly respond to
the changing needs of my team
how confident am I that my system is
flexible enough to accommodate new tools
new systems and new data sources
and then ask your team the same thing
right
how confident are you that we can
accommodate Next Generation Business
Systems and tools that our teams need to
remain competitive
that's what they're doing as upset as I
want to be with the marketing team
they're doing what they need to do
to be the best at what they do
and that's what's changed between now
and 10 or 15 years ago when the IT
department and the IT leaders could say
you've got to do it my way or we can't
get it done
that has changed and we're saying we are
going to provide what you need so you
can get your job the best way possible
so we can grow our business
so that we can be the best that we can
be
and then at the end extensibility
this is one of those big words that we
put in here because everyone's using it
it really and because it works into our
acronym
this is about scalability right this is
about being able to grow quickly
uh to me one of the best examples of
this is if you are part of a company
whose growth strategy is around mergers
and acquisitions
right
you could overnight double the size of
your business
if you go merge a company about the same
size as yours
so why is that important especially from
a security perspective that you're
prepared for this
right
rapid growth requires new technologies
new tools tools you've never even heard
of because you acquired somebody that
was who knows what they were doing right
on their I.T in their I.T Department
the reality is is over time if we don't
have a plan for scalability and
extensibility we end up with a patchwork
of tools they don't work together it
becomes really difficult to manage the
security right if you've got 10 tools or
a hundred obviously 100 is going to be
harder to manage
and so having a plan around
scalability is important as you whether
it's from mergers whether it's just
you're a startup and and your growth is
exponential right
if you're not prepared for that type of
growth you end up having lots of holes
right you're just plugging these things
in uh and you'd hate to have to fix all
of that because of a breach right having
that security plan and saying you know
what we're going to put in place
internal tools processes so that we can
be prepared for that growth and that's
what extensibility uh
is about
same questions or similar right
is my system extensible enough to
accommodate new tools
uh how confident are we that we can keep
up with the growth in our company
right
there are not too many companies that
don't want to grow
right
if you're a public company it's the only
thing that matters
um but that growth is coming and we need
to be prepared for it
so safe
uh
and now we're going to move on to Pace
policy audit compliance and education
how many of you have
documented security policy
most half maybe
that's where we're going to start I was
having our VP of cyber security review
this I wanted to make sure I wasn't
telling you stories that aren't true
and one of his notes as he was reading
through this on this section was well
you can't have a policy without auditing
lucky for me audits the second one right
um and and that really is know that you
can't you can do these in order priority
but you cannot stop
if you stop at just having a policy it
will
ultimately fail
right
and so let's talk about
uh policy
um
we had a customer
and this is a story maybe a little about
policy
well we had a customer and they had a
patching policy
and their patching policy was we will
patch
every 270 days
I think that's plenty right
one of the things with policy that you
want to make sure you do you need to
have it reviewed both internally
and externally get some separate set of
eyes on it
because
270 days is not enough right and sure
enough they ended up having a breach
because of uh
of vulnerability in one of their systems
that was that had gone unpatched right
so
it's an example of having a policy and
then not having it
up to speed not reviewing it often
enough and not making sure that it meets
the requirements uh whether those are
many of you may be regulated regulated
in some uh form or fashion whether it's
government or Finance uh
PCI right lots of areas that have
certain policy requirements right those
of you who may not be regulated it's
really hard to get
to a point of good security
without having
some level of of policy
right
um
these are some of the questions that are
most important who's responsible for
keeping the policy updated
and I love this next one are are they
the right person for this role
right and if you go to the other one
this is one that I imagine would happen
at our organization not at ours some
other organization I'm sure
I think that it's supposed to be one
person and then when I ask that person
they think it should be someone else
right
this is clearly not going to be ideal
for keeping our policy updated if we're
not clear on where we need to be you
know when was the last time we reviewed
the policy
does the policy include how often it
should be reviewed
all right when was the last time we had
our policy reviewed by a third party
right and this clarification with
expertise and security policy
our marketing director is awesome
probably not the right person to review
your security policy
I should not pick on her I'm going to be
in trouble
um
and then ask your team the same thing
right
audit
um
audits can be expensive and they're
typically not fun whether that's an IRS
audit or a security audit right
uh
the goal of an audit is to show us where
we are
lacking
where we're missing the boat on our
policy
right how are you auditing these tools
and you really want to do it in a way
that is
um
that is automated right
how do you know when somebody uh logs in
to
um
from the wireless or from wired
you know are they logging in from when
and where they're supposed to do they
have new devices right
uh I think
this probably doesn't happen a lot of
times but
your Executives go to a uh an event and
every they all get new iPads right they
bring them in they connect to the Wi-Fi
how are you making sure that those in
your auditing to make sure those new
devices are following the policies that
you've put in place for those devices
right
do you know that they have new devices
on the network
these are all come into into play in
terms of making sure that that policy
that you've put in place
is being audited that you know what's
happening on your in your environment
and on your devices and your users right
we haven't talked about users a lot
because I think it's
I mean they are the problem
let's be honest
right I mean we love them we support
them at the end of the day and we're
going to get to education here in a
second that's when we'll talk about our
users at the end of the day a lot of
this is in place because as human beings
we make mistakes
right and uh in fact I was down in in St
George this week meeting with um
a customer and they have a policy this
was
they do a uh kind of a phishing test
how many of you do uh kind of an email
phishing test on a regular basis right
does anybody do it more than once a
month
a couple of you yeah this company does
it twice a month
and if somebody uh kind of clicks the
link two times in a six month period
they get written up and have to meet
with I.T director and their boss and if
they do it a third time they have to
meet with the CEO
and basically they're saying if you
can't learn or you can't pay enough
attention you are becoming a risk to our
business one that we may not be prepared
to keep on board
hey good luck
question
I you know I think it could
um this if you met this gentleman I
don't think you would think that he's
about the kindest man I've ever met
um
I think that as as they talked about it
in the way that that uh I heard it is
kind of like wow that is really strict
the way he presented it was much more
hey we sit down with them we talk to
them we want to understand like were
they just not paying attention uh and so
I do think I do I did feel like uh the
way that they they had presented it was
a much Kinder than what I kind of and
for those of you didn't hear that he
said doesn't that create a Culture of
Fear right and the first one was what if
it is your CEO doesn't see if you
couldn't if you couldn't hear back there
but so I think it's it's a really good
point and I think for them it was about
their approach of that correction to
kind of balance out like
uh he didn't say you do it three times
and you're fired but I think it was very
clear like this is serious business you
know so a good point how you do that can
be critical
yeah he mentioned just about snow having
a presentation on Tuesday about creating
a culture of security and as you create
that culture it kind of shifts probably
from Fear I'm paraphrasing but kind of
shifts from Fear to kind of this this is
important rather than don't do this or
you're fired and and I certainly felt
that from him
um but it was the first time I'd heard
of kind of this pretty you know it's
serious you're going to meet with the
CEO if if you don't understand what's
what's going on here so great comments
thank you uh so
this is uh for for audit those are some
of the things so here's some of the
questions uh to ask yourself
um who's responsible for part policy and
implementation audits uh how do we audit
the implementation of our security
policy and what is our exposure if we
don't do this I think this refers a lot
to governmental regulations right most
of them uh require you to have a policy
and they will also require certain level
of auditing so where do you fit into
that right
and then asking your team really these
same questions uh with one additional
that says how much of it is audited
right it would be impossible to manually
audit everything that's going on right
so automating that and getting the
alerts that you need in order to know
hey we've got a new device on here we've
got a device that's just joined the
network that doesn't have the security
controls in place that we require how
are we going to address that
um and then compliance right this is
about making sure that um
our people are are complying one example
that we you know we have a policy that
you can't access our
um
our tools and our environment unless
you're in the United States we're a
local company you really don't nobody
from Europe is going to be logging in to
our systems right
causes some problems with some of our
people when they travel on and they're
on vacation and they now want to notify
us
and that they're on vacation and they
want to work
we usually let them but they have to
figure out a way to tell us I mean they
can't teams us because they can't log in
they can't email us because they can't
they can't log in
luckily we like them and for the most
part they have our cell phone numbers
but uh this is one of those areas where
forcing that compliance becomes
important right in one way or another
creating those parameters that say we're
going to make sure that our human beings
our users are complying and when they
don't we want to know about it
and that's a part of uh
creating that
kind of that full circle right policy
audit compliance and then some questions
around compliance here
um I think the same question who's
responsible for it
right if nobody's responsible nobody's
doing it
well you probably are
whether you want to be or not uh you are
probably the one in charge and whether
that makes the most sense or not I think
is is a really good conversation to be
having
uh what is the potential for
non-compliance how do we Monitor and
mediate that compliance right
um
as we talk about this one of the things
I haven't mentioned and around this is
is really around bad publicity right if
we're not prepared and we have a breach
and and we were compliant or we're doing
everything we're supposed to and you can
really mitigate the
the bad publicity and the and the
negative impact that that it might
happen in the public
space right in the public Arena where if
you're non-compliant I mean it it can be
career ending or business ending right
and so making sure that you understand
what is that what does that look like
you know what is what will happen if
we're not compliant uh with what we've
agreed to do
right
back to this policy of 270 days of
patching
at least they were compliant with their
policy even if their policy was bad
there is some strength in complying with
your policy even if it's not that good
right so make sure you have that as part
of what you're doing and then education
I'm sure that those of you you talked a
little bit about doing fishing uh
tests right doing annual or more often
uh
security training uh
I don't know how many of you know what
we do at Balcom we're a we're a cyber
security kind of uh
reseller so one of the things that that
we are getting all the time is people
are always trying to buy stuff from us
that are from
uh
that are princes in in Africa for
example right
uh and they have gotten I mean that was
20 years ago they have gotten very very
sophisticated and I'll bet that we have
um
at least a handful of emails every
single week that we send out and say
this is a fraudulent email do not
respond to this they do not want to buy
a hundred laptops we promise right and
the the reality is that for our sales
team
they're doing training every quarter
because we do not want them to get
complacent around looking for these
types of things
for many of the other people in our
organization we do it annually and
that's typically sufficient right and so
for your organizations I think this is
one of those areas where for a lot of
compliance requirements governmental Etc
you're required to do training once a
year for example right
that may not be enough
and and really asking yourself these
same questions of you know uh
how security conscious is your team
you know
are you checking on the security posture
of your vendors and your partners this
is something that's new for for us in
the last maybe two or three years the
number of uh Partners both customers and
vendor Partners who are sending us and
saying tell us about your security
policy
share it with us
can you show us that you are auditing
and complying with your own policy
because in order for us to do business
with you on an ongoing basis we need to
know that you're doing the things this
is not just the government right
it's our partners that are asking us the
same thing that's something to consider
are you doing that uh
what is your education in place and when
was it last updated that's an important
question too you don't want to you want
to make sure you're not
training things that are old
make sure you're updating it
we all here know how quickly things
change in in technology and cyber
security is probably fastest of all we
need to be updating our our training uh
curriculum if you want to call it uh so
that everybody's getting that updated
training
um and then what routines do we have in
place we touched on that a little bit
and then ask your team on a scale of one
to ten how security conscious is your
team right ask them how security
conscious do they think the employees
are or your customers your end users
how can you increase that number
you know just by one
just take it one step at a time one
person how can we be one percent more
security conscious
and if you can take that a little bit
better at a time you'll continually
improve uh what you're doing the thing
that I would add to this for those of
you in leadership positions as well make
sure that your team your your
administrators are also getting the
education they need obviously you're
here right I imagine a lot of your teams
are here this is so important for them
to see and understand what's out there
right and to be prepared for those types
of things so just a quick review
um
safe Pace secure accessible flexible and
extensible
policy audit compliance and education
again number one takeaway get this
assessment
right take a picture of this I think
we're sending I think these are all
available
um anyway but this is available right
now and you can download it as I was
talking to our marketing director I said
well let's just create a
um
let's create a form they can fill out I
promise we won't gather their data and
then I right thank you
and none of them will believe us even if
we're being honest about it and you
shouldn't I mean we think we're honest
but
I mean I'm talking to a group of
Security Experts right
so this is a PDF you can download it
there's no we don't have you don't have
to give us your email address or
anything to get this it's just free
um and uh if you want to share with us
any feedback on it we'd love to hear we
do have our contact information on that
we do have a team of of really good
cyber security Engineers that would be
more than happy to
um
talk to you about it if you have
questions but but feel free to use it
and if it's valuable please let us know
and thank you all for joining us today
it's been it's been a pleasure and for
being here we've got a question right
back here
yes
with our customers business Executives
or with our own internal executives
yeah
um
it has been
um somewhat difficult it's easiest after
they've had a breach that's when it's
really easy unfortunately
um right uh and one of the reasons that
we that we did this presentation
is for them
right we want
the executives to know that this is it's
not a
please be prepared don't wait for it to
happen and
um in my opinion it's a lot about
education and uh I'm gonna call out
Philip Philip you raise your hand right
here this is our VP of cyber security
he'll probably have some better input if
you want to sync up with him about that
the conversations that he's had he's
having those direct conversations with
the executives of our customers and I
know that he has them
before they have a breach and I think he
can talk very specifically about
um how we're getting that that message
across uh he's way better at it than I
am
um
I don't know why I'm I'm doing the
presentation
he probably should have done it but
actually par part of that is that
um I can kind of sell Valcom and I can
talk about some of these things Philip
is really good about just understanding
what our customers are are needing and
how we can
how we can help them what they need to
do next in their security journey and so
I think that's where his his strengths
really are so thank you great question
any other any other questions and you
don't have to stay for the questions but
you're welcome to stay or check with me
after either way or ask Philip
so
okay thank you so much appreciate
[Applause]