so our first keynote speaker uh most of
you know him he's been in the industry
over 22 years been robbing people and
corporations for over a decade he's a
close friend great road trip partner
gives the most awkwardest of hugs so
everybody please give me help me welcome
and give a round warm of Applause to
Jason Street
thank you my brother oh my God yes I am
good to go
yes
yes all right thank you for the
introduction as I said I'm jcd Street
we're also known as the reason why
everybody's running late uh today so my
sorry not sorrys right off the bat
I did actually prepare a little bit so
it's not as awkward well I can't help
but be awkward but we'll try here
it's right there this goes there always
here
hi there we go I need to get
something on my purse real quick
there we go
we got this here
and yes I am presenting on this
because it's awesome
and people don't expect you to rob
people with this so it's even more
awesome
it's like I'm telling you go into a
server room that doesn't allow computers
and like oh I'm just playing Soul
Calibur on my child's switch no big deal
I got a three hour update
and then you leave the place and going
like I won we're good
there you go
yay so I'm incredibly nervous this is
going to be epic like and I'm like when
I mean epic I mean epically fail or I
don't know which It's like because I've
never done this one here and that's like
uh we're gonna fit and do it live so
bear with me uh but this is my legal
disclaimer uh I'm not a lawyer but I
played one on the internet before
successfully
um and so when I talk about the bad
things you see me doing something bad or
you see me doing bad stuff you're going
to be like
he's horrible what a terrible person
remember the kittens I'm adorable okay
I'm not going to try to rob from you
still from you or kill you unless you
pay me first there's always a contract
okay it's like I lie professionally I
don't do it for free so I don't filter
uh it's like and and be prepared for
that too
because trust me people always think
that I'm I'm joking about that and then
they figure out like oh you you found
out you shouldn't have effed around
there we go
so the name of this talk
hacker striptease peeling away the
layers of physical compromise
start right there oh favorite part shoes
off okay so
um what we're going to do is we're going
to just talk about like all the
different kinds of personas that I use
when I'm robbing people and some of the
ways that I do physical compromise
because I'm not uh you know a big red
team ninja dude so I'm just this weirdo
um I I don't like talking about myself
so just go to jcstreet.com you find out
more about me hackeradventures that
world you know uh shows you uh where
I've been and at Jason Street on Twitter
is my live journal or diary and dream
journal all rolled into one
unfortunately sorry not sorry because
yeah some of that stuff you don't want
to see I don't care
um but just I like riding motorcycles
educating reporters it appears screaming
at people which you'll you'll see that
later uh going and doing weird things in
weird places uh Rob de bank at National
Geographic we'll see that a little bit
later love playing no man's sky like
Spike way to go it's like you know my
other no man's Sky you know fellow
Interlopers yeah okay awesome
um that that's the most exciting part of
the whole effing bio to be honest with
you it's like it's like Minecraft in
space for old nerds uh I love building
bases there
um okay that fun part's over let me tell
you about how much this industry sucks
um so
I am so tired of hearing stupid user
clicked on a link stupid user went to a
website stupid information security
didn't properly train their users and
trying to ship the blame all onto them
humans are not the weakest link they're
the least invested in
it's like if you were running it's like
in investing in your technology and your
defenses and you as you invested in
people
you'd have a Cisco picks from 97 put
into your thing with an ACL that's allow
all but no logging
and think you're secure with the snort
IDs with the default signatures on
that's exactly what you would have
the problem is we need to invest in
actually teaching our users that they
are responsible for a piece of equipment
when you give a delivery driver a van
you don't tell them the keys good luck
you know what to do
no that sixty thousand dollars piece of
equipment you make sure they're trained
on you make sure they understand the
rules they understand the defense tech
oh my God I don't want to see everybody
because then they'll see them judging me
it's like uh it's like I mean some of
you are quite handsome and pretty but
it's like you know but still no they're
okay uh so you don't you don't want to
get you know you don't see that whole
distraction it's like and this is why
we're running late thank you oh not that
dark it's like then I'm like a shadowy
shroud it's like too close to Halloween
for that my gosh okay
um but yeah you give them this equipment
and you tell them it's like hey you know
here's your your blinkers your defenses
okay we'll deal with that because I
don't want to keep it light changing
it's like and you know you don't want
them to like you'd let them know what
they're expected of them we give a
person a laptop
I'm like oh yeah you know the rules does
the policies have fun
if a person wrecks a van you're out
sixty thousand dollars
that person is probably getting fired
how many people click on links that have
cost companies over 350 million dollars
Target but yeah
it's like and we don't even bat an eye
they're jeopardizing and could
potentially cost accompany millions of
dollars
and we're just like yeah it happens
we need to get better at showing our
people what the real threats are
because we're getting all the ccos and
cios care about the apts oh my gosh
we need spooky music you know advanced
persistent
threats
right gives me chills
well I don't know how to do you know
what you know what apt really stands for
because let's face it the only thing we
use apt for is your CEO to tell the
public and the shareholders that you got
piped by an email right it's like
because apt actually stands for adequate
fishing technique
that is apt
and he's like but I want you to know I
don't do apt it's like I'm a high school
dropout usually behind a dumpster ain't
that fancy
you know don't don't look this for you
it's like no
I do bad
basic adorable destruction
I don't care about your compliance I
don't care about sarbanes-oxley Granby
Smiley or any other Old English white
dudes I don't care about any of those
guys hippo hippo hobos I don't care
I'm just there to F you up in the worst
possible way at the worst possible time
it's like at the worst possible I'm
great at parties it's like trust me it's
like that's all I'm there I just want to
go be a bad guy
so it's like that's how I do it and I
show them exactly what a real threat lot
is like and I love showing people what
real threats are like so they get
understanding it's not that advanced
it's not that all this leak coding skill
and all these tools it's like no it's
like it's this is how easy it is I use
one of the this first of all mostly
every attack that I do involves the most
dangerous hacking tool ever invented by
man it's like still in use today is
don't please don't say Cali it's like
it's still the best most leadest hacking
tool
I'll start with Google
um something you don't really know about
me it's like I'm a nice guy I try to be
a nice guy or at least play one on the
internet sometimes I'm very Petty
Ian why you know back in the day because
I didn't have a high school diploma and
I passed all their other they wouldn't
hire me
I'm not saying I hold a grudge but let's
go hacking why and see if we can break
into their building okay why not
anybody for me and white don't raise
your hand because also I don't care I'm
still going uh so we're going to go
after Ian why
it's like I want to physically because
this is about physical compromise so how
are we going to rob them well let's find
out where they're they're stationed at I
had to go to the New York office so uh
once for eny for a class that I ended up
finding a vulnerability in their MySQL
server that was facing the internet that
got mad at me about still Petty so you
know
um it's like so yeah so this is where
they're located it's like five Times
Square
now and they've got their name on the
building
have you ever seen any Ernst Young
Building in Times Square it's like all
lit up on the side Ernst young you know
Tony Stark wannabes it's like you know
but I got a question for you
they own that building but do they
manage that building you think Tony
Stark is out there you know collecting
the rent off the Starbucks making sure
he's hiring the janitorial staff and the
security for that building no because
he's passed him a moment of silence for
him
#too soon it's like miss you Tony it's
like so yeah no he doesn't do that
you get a building management company
Ernst young is all about security
Ernst young is all about the auditing
and the numbers and not hiring very you
know Wonderful adorable Scrappy young
you know newbies it's like sorry
um I digress but yeah that's what Ernst
young is about what did the building
management company do
like the originally named you know very
original five Times Square Property
Management Company
they're selling space
to them it's all about getting that room
you know getting getting those offices
filled up because they got to pay for
the maintenance they got to pay for the
other thing and the electricity for that
big flashy sign that they've got outside
the building
so what are they going to do
well they're going to get potential
clients a lot of information
hey you want to know where the Ernst
young employees are probably going to be
eating
because they're not going down to
Chinatown for that noodles even if it's
on the subway
it's like no they're going to be like
within five minutes of the building
because they're good employees they're
go-getters you know it's like so it's
like they're going to be like you know
right nearby say at those restaurants
right there where you can put up a prox
card reader you can like you know
actually do some pictures figure out
what their badges look like you know
what the traffic looks like you know
send some coupons for some discounts
because everybody likes to you know a
little bit of money off on something in
a PDF you you do that it's like oh
hotels oh you're visiting out of town
employees your Executives oh that's
where they're going to be staying good
to know
can't do anything with that kind of
information
not at all it's like and then your
neighboring officers I don't care about
them it's like I've used a a neighbor's
uh uh that was nearby in the same
building to set an appointment with them
so I could then just take the elevator
down and not get it squirted down of
course because they don't they just
leave you at the elevator and just go
one floor down and then Rob the place
that was fun
um
the blueprints
seriously
I mean if you if anybody's ever here has
worked at a bank they're getting PTSD
flashbacks It's like because that is
terrifying to actually have the
blueprints
and I mean and they give it to you
I mean I love this this is all the
public areas you know the main lobby and
The Concourse uh below the building I
love how they highlight it because like
please pay attention to this area and
I'm like no
you got like security looking all mean
and intimidating and like you know
they're asking really mean questions
like you know what are you doing here
why do you have that computer I don't
want to answer those Quantic questions
so I'm looking for the gray area that's
the good stuff right that's the stuff
like nothing to see here nothing behind
the curtain right because actually where
the loading dock is
that's where the freight elevator is
if you're using the I mean come on okay
I understand the freight elevator it
does smell every once in a while okay
and there could be a guy named Ernie and
stuff there and there which still gives
me flashbacks but that's fine
It's like because that is the least
protected area to get into the upper
floors
but I don't know where the upper floors
go I don't know what their layouts are
and when you're trying to rob someone
you want to have the familiarity you
want to be walking someone questioning
like what are you doing here what's
going on oh I'm going to the electrical
closet right down there to the right
next to the main conference room oh that
sounds legit never been there before but
I don't have to be because I got all the
floor blueprints as well telling me
where the electrical box is right next
to the main conference room
so that helps
and once again
that dark shaded area
do not look here
this is not the access level you're
looking for
you know this is not the doorways that
you need it's like well my Jedi Mind
Tricks don't work on me
takes intelligence I'm do but also it
takes a wonderful building management
company that included in their brochures
the ungraded out areas
so they exactly tell you exactly where
everything's at
it made you work for a little bit and
one of the things I love is this whole
first of all you have basements in Utah
I'm so evangelia that
you know I love all these idiots trying
to like shame people like from hacker in
their basement but I would kill for a
basement
I would love to have a lab in a basement
I would totally be there
and I would call it my Lair Without
Shame
okay
[Applause]
I didn't use some super computer with a
whole bunch of screens with like you
know two people typing on the keyboard
to make myself lead
no I had pizza and Diet Pepsi the Panera
Bread when I was hacking these wools
company wonderful people eating why
great great great auditing work uh
they're gonna audit me I'm I can tell
now it's like but yes that's what I did
and the reason why I did it there is
because I'm also doing it in your
company's Lobby
at your company's Starbucks or little
cafe
so I can do that
on that small little handheld device
that doesn't look like a computer
and that's only got 16 gigs of RAM
running Windows 11 and stuff you know
with an i7 processor it's like with a
one terabyte hard drive it's like I
barely got anything done that's why I
love this thing because it's actually
got 32 gigs of RAM two terabytes of hard
drive space running an AMD ryzen
processor with a 6800 GPU
much nicer it's like um and and also it
oh my gosh the graphics when you're
playing no man's sky and soul color but
don't tell my CEO because he's the one
that bought it because I'd use it for
contesting only
it's like uh
we'll go with that
say nothing Alex okay good
um I forgot the co-worker was here oops
my bad it's like uh so yeah so I use
that
and I'm watching the traffic patterns
I'm watching to see what your security
looks like what they're what everybody's
dressed like what the badges look like
maybe doing some Wi-Fi stuff you know
because I like to act like I'm lead it's
like oh all that stuff but I'm also
using other memes I don't just Google
I'm not one trick pony
I'm also on Instagram
you want to know why people drink
#new badge search on Instagram that's
why we drink okay maybe not here but
it's like a lot of people drink because
of that and it's like and I love this
Ernst young was so nice to actually
include a location tag for the insta you
know because you gotta do it for the
gram right I can I don't have to be
inside the building
because I'm literally seeing pictures of
inside buildings that I'm about to Rob
and seeing where their stuff is set up
seeing where they're they're uh where
the go to their architect's website
because they're very proud of the the
work they did inside the interior of
these Office Buildings and you can
literally see
where the conference room is how the
reception is where the break rooms are
because you always want to go to the
break room first
seriously it's like you got to hit the
break room first uh and so and then you
also see other pictures like who needs
to do fingerprinting it's like like an
OS or what operating system are they
using what technology they have oh I've
got insta for that they're using Windows
Dell machines it's like a Lenovo think
pads they've got iPhones for their
mobile devices for their their email
carriers and stuff you know probably
like some kind of iPhone app or iOS mail
carrier it's like yeah I've got all that
down
no worries
it's like and trust me if that doesn't
work don't worry that's what linkedin's
jobs postings are for
you do a search for the job posting what
the company's hired they're telling you
what they're looking for what
architecture that you need to have what
coding you need to know what technology
that you need to use and if that doesn't
work you just go to the people that are
currently working there and you see what
their skill sets are
because you're not going to get a person
who is well versed in checkpoint and
Fortinet and stuff you know in those two
technologies and you know and McAfee and
think like oh I wonder if they're
wondering Kaspersky with Cisco picks no
if like you're you're basically telling
you what what they're running
but I mentioned the badges right love
the badges
that that that that one in the upper
corner upper right hand corner is even
better you know why
because it shows the key
who here has 3D printed TSA Keys Lord
knows I do
thank you TSA Homeland Security
we treat your physical security of your
luggage like we want to treat the
encryption of your emails but you know
don't think about that too much it's
like so yeah it's like um you got to you
could make a whole 3D print I don't know
how to do lock picking you got deviant
for people that actually know people
that actually do that kind of stuff I
literally cannot lock pick to save my
life I use cardboard or a crowbar but
most times I just ask someone to let me
in and they usually do it and that's
works for me
but I love badges
I love badges
and you know what it's like I love other
people's badges because they show me
what to print
because I've got the badgie 100.
the only way this could be cooler
is if it was named the badge 3000
seriously from getting a picture off of
Instagram in Boston from getting it
printed
it's like I'm a friend's uh you know
badge printer
15 minutes and yes I use that exact
badge
and they're like yeah but Jason doesn't
have RFID it doesn't have you know it's
like you didn't uh prox bar clone or
anything like that and it's like yeah
I love it when I don't do that
because then I go up to the badge reader
I got a meeting in five minutes
can we make something happen
you know
hello soup important white person look
at me plug in
hey if you don't have white the only the
only reason why you should be using
white privilege is to be telling people
how bad and horrible it is right
seriously so I'm like yeah it's like you
know use that
so another thing and I get this a lot
from people
it's like especially my detractors you
know there's plenty it's like you're not
that technical Jason
you're not that you you've not done any
like skills you're like you didn't even
really red teaming stuff you like to act
like I'm like yeah
exactly I'm not that technical I don't
know how to code I've never heard out of
code it's like literally I would say
that if you look into the dictionary and
if you look at imposter syndrome in the
dictionary you'd see my picture but I
don't think I'm good enough to actually
be in the dictionary under that okay
it's like
so yeah so no I'm not talking about but
let's ask a question it's like
do you think your company's as secure as
a bank who's trying to guard money
especially from some loser like me
that's just going to walk in off the
street
well let's do this little friendly thing
let's actually look at a video
of me robbing a bank and Beirut Lebanon
unedited exactly the way it's going to
work and it's like this is none of the
video it's eight minutes and we're gonna
see how long it takes for me from
walking into the front door
to compromising my first machine
here we go
walk in and I love right off the bat
look at that lady
she she did such everything so bright so
wonderful she knew I was sketchy AF as
soon as she saw me
she knew I was up to no good
oh look wait hold on oh 15 seconds
between walking the front door and
compromising the first machine if that
was what your answer was you won
uh that's 19 seconds 20 seconds it's
actually executing the code
running the payload in around 22 seconds
saving it finishing in 25 I have
completely compromised one machine in
another 30 seconds
that took a lot of technical know-how to
do
and I love the fact that she stops me
wait hold on I forgot hold on there's a
I'm not professional by Nature it's like
uh
there we go
can you hear the sound
there you go I'm here to do the USB
she's doing wonderful she's asking me
questions she's challenging me but I'm
in an assertive role I'm doing a USB
audit I don't know what a USB audit is
but I do a lot of them
[Music]
and they're very successful no problem
but she challenged me I was literally
taking the offensive you need to call
headquarters didn't headquarters are you
I wasn't cowering or acting like I was
caught or The Jig was up but look what
she does she takes me to the manager
with exactly what she could do but then
she made the one mistake
I let her go I said I'll stand by
because she thought I was
honestly okay so then I switched to a
passive row as a Helper and I
compromised the bank uh Bank manager's
machine
because I went from assertive and now
I'm in the Pastoral and I'm trying to
make make the network faster
you can be on a T3 line through fiber to
your desktop you ask someone the network
running slow yeah I think so well I'm
here to make it faster mother what do
you need and do you have a network
server here too as well I was like hey
let's go for the Gusto right let's break
into the data center
I mean I'm here anyway right
that's my trusted agent because I'm
doing a security awareness engagement
I'm not doing red team so and I'm
telling him to step back because he's
way too close because he can't believe
what's going on either I'm like you and
me both bud it's like you and me both
so and this is unedited because I want
you to think that I try to cut and paste
it and make it look cooler so sorry for
the buck cam
this is a hidden uh camera and a button
uh from the National Geographic show
that wasn't used at Darren kitchen
acquired somehow I ain't asking
questions and so I'm showing you
and here he goes he does the you know he
does the the code which is super secret
that I could never have shoulder surfed
and told you what it was I think it was
his kid's birthday and he opens up the
now I thought here let will you let me
stay here unattended okay thank you
hold on listen
that was a side defeat I want them to do
good
I'm an advocate not an adversary I'm
trying to root for the guy but but then
I remembered something wait that mother
here's my golden ticket
I don't want to be too far from him that
lady May question him because she was
doing a lot of good stuff so she may
question him it's like I got to catch up
with them it's like no don't leave my
side Bud we still got to go to do the
teller line
I would run over and talk to you guys
over there but it's like I would fall
down and it would be funny but it would
not be constructive so I'm thinking
about you right here it's like so now
I'm behind the teller line
yeah
yep that's not good for somebody
ain't me it's perfect I'm having a great
day right now
it was good
but this part was so rude
and they're usually very hospitable
kind of employee locks their workstation
how am I how am I supposed to Rob them
but that's okay the manager went and got
the employee so he could come over and
and unlock the workstation for me
oh that was close I'm trying to go for
100 here people
I'm sorry I'm literally French so I
always tell people I always try like you
know because uh lebanoni speak you know
French Arabic and English most countries
speak you know two or three languages I
tell people like I'm from America I only
speak one language I'm from Texas I
don't speak it very well I did what I
can than my Chinese so it's like what
are you going to do but now we're going
to go to the Vault it's not that big
shiny metal thing they like to make it
look like in the movies now we're in the
vault with the most powerful person in
the bank let's just plug this in real
quick you know why
yeah that's the one doing the wire
transfers so in the way
that's where the money is that's where
the money's being transferred
oh and she was in the middle of a wire
transfer when I interrupted her
my bad oops
because there it goes executing right
there and I'm like oh nice maybe I
shouldn't have plugged it in right then
but too late now
LOL okay
there we go payload's done okay
and I'm like
well this was unexpected I really
appreciate your help
I'll take it unexpected thank you
and as we're walking out I remembered
one important thing good I think I've
got everybody I'm Petty AF I'm the data
center so oh I didn't get her machine
real quick I forgot to get the one
person who stopped me
on these engagements I'm being paid to
be a horrible person remember the
kittens
so of course I have to compromise her
machine but this time with the manager
behind me okay making sure she does it
the only person I have felt bad in
engagement in a very long time was her
because she was a model employee she did
everything the correct way I'm done
except for she didn't talk to the
manager and explained hey there's weird
you know American dude you know wanting
to talk to you and I'm not I don't know
what he's doing because she thought he
was going to vet me thank you he thought
she vetted me and no one vetted me
and this sums it up pretty well right
here
that just happen I don't
I don't know
I was more surprised than anybody else
but I mean I will have to admit
there was no Python tutorial so luckily
I was able to avoid capture you know and
I didn't have to use Ruby or you know my
metasployal metasploitable shells and
never I didn't have to use any of that
stuff you know thank goodness or I would
have been in trouble uh it wasn't needed
I will show you this one tool that I
found that I used it's like on this next
engagement don't worry this is much
quicker notice I'm coming from the
public area
but I don't walk directly to the teller
line because they're going to be
suspicious because I came straight from
the outside so I hide behind this column
there's a lady on the phone behind me
and I wait there for just a few seconds
and then I walk from the private area
where that lady's desk was like I had to
talk to her and I just walked right
behind the sewer line
I go to the very last machine
make sure they see me go out of my way
to say hello because I'm a polite robber
okay
I've got manners I'm from the south it's
like so there we go I plug into the
first machine that is not plugged in or
turned on
but I'm establishing a pattern
so when I go to the next
machine which is hers
I'm just like pardon I have to plug this
in
there you go do a USB audit another one
of those
Mercy because you know polite and I
speak French not really
and then this lady was not having it she
was a little busy I already read it in
her body language so I just did what any
good bank robber does I spin in the
chair uh until she's available
and she's like I I'm I'm busy I'm doing
work I'm like oh that's okay I'm just
doing one quick thing uh robbing you
don't don't mind me it's like uh it
won't take but a moment
there it goes thank you
so nice
and look I'm leaving it's like you know
we all ended up smiling they're smiling
I'm smiling everybody's smiling it was a
very positive experience for a robbery
and then the lady that was on her phone
I'm now coming from the teller side
which is the private side for her the
non-public side and I was able to take
her machine as well
and the only reason why I was able to
manage that was because of that column
if I would have walked in directly from
the front of the building
people subconsciously
would have not trusted me as much
because they knew in the background see
I clearly I I was not this is not
something that I was taught this is
something I've adapted over my life as
being someone on the Spectrum and having
to deal with like horrible people a lot
in my younger years you have to read
human nature because seriously normal
people frighten the out of me it's like
and so I had to start learning what
human nature was like and what normal
people were supposed to be like and I
was like so I could learn to either
avoid or to mimic and stuff you know so
I could you know mask be like Oh I'm
that guy yeah I'm what you're looking
for it's like you know don't hurt me
we're good right and so and that's what
I've learned on human nature and that's
what I use to attack your companies it's
like I'm using human nature against them
those natural things that you think
about in the back of your head but you
don't really think about them you just
operate with them
so after that the question was you know
you sure hope so but maybe not really
because I'm not attacking your network
technology or zero days to get in
I'm just attacking your people
because we're not empowering them and
educating them enough on what a real
threat's going to look like and just to
basically question someone if they come
and say they want to do something with
their machine
well I don't want to be rude
what it's 2022 seriously
have you been on a plane lately
it's like you don't have to be rude you
don't have to tackle the person I'm
fragile I bruise easily that might be me
don't tackle
but you have to ask questions are you
supposed to be here call security
call information let them know to call
you and say hey there's someone sketchy
AF here I think we need to do something
about it because once again I'm trying
to put them at ease without them
realizing it
this picture was taken one day apart
it's like one the first day I showed him
the goatee ungelled hair your company's
Computer Guy
you know because you know I thought it
was funny and I come with warning labels
it's like in a couple devices sticking
out there the next day I'm in a nice
dress shirt oh this one I don't know
what that means it's like some flashy
cufflinks nice watch gelled hair shaved
because I want them to think that he
looks familiar
can't really place them but I think I've
seen them before
it's put in the back of their head
but also notice the most important
element of those pictures
it's effing snowing outside
I am freezing every you know thing
horribly I am cold
why do I not have a jacket on is it
because I'm an idiot don't answer that
no because once I break into the company
spoiler alert I did it's like once I do
that
if I still had my parka on because
that's what I needed I'm from remember
Texas it's like it's like
wouldn't I be a little suspicious
wouldn't I stand out walking around
inside your hallways with a big winter
jacket on
but if I don't have a jacket on
if I'm wearing short sleeve shirt inside
a company while it's snowing outside
then that means I must have put my
jacket up somewhere
that must have been that I'm here and
I'm like him I put that in the office
and I'm doing a day's work
and that's not something you think about
but now that I said it you go oh
the weirdo's got a point and I'm like
yeah
that's just human nature
so let's go over some of the layers I
use
Layer Two is the assertive role you know
it doesn't mean aggressive I've been
aggressive in certain countries it's
like especially uh in some European
countries being assertive actually helps
it's like what part of surprise
inspected do you not understand
I needed the server room I need it now
and if you don't want to be on the
report that's going to happen don't you
think so
mother been here
it's 3 A.M my time I don't need this
please let you in and I lied I still put
them on the report but it's like so um
but usually the mannerisms are like this
it's like when I used in the bank when I
was being challenged I didn't like go oh
no I don't know what I'm I don't know no
I challenge back didn't you get a
message from uh headquarters I'm
supposed to be here I'm doing the USB
audit I was challenging I was being
assertive I'm doing an audit role it's
like and the hardware I have to use has
to be a little bit more discreet because
the better discrete it is the better
chances you are of getting it and then
it's like
it helps if you're dressing for the role
right
I love this
you know what this is
this is the business suit of Doom
I call it the business through the Doom
because it's hand tailored for my tailor
in Beijing Peter wonderful guy uh can't
go back to China anymore but uh long
story but it's like uh but I I love my
suits
because it makes me look fancy
and also the best part about these suits
is when I was trying to explain to Peter
what I wanted
and when I was telling him he said are
you a magician
and I'm like no Peter I'm not a magician
It's like because a magician you always
hear them they say nothing up my sleeves
and Peter didn't I specifically tell you
to actually put pockets in my sleeve
so I could like carry a bash bunny too
or some other device in the sleep
because was it practical no is it cool
yes
so yeah Peter I'm not I'm not a magician
I'm a bank robber it's like or hacker
you know pin tester so yeah so you gotta
love those you gotta love my pockets
right
and I'm and but also
he makes me fancy
and I love being fancy every once in a
while okay it's like spoiler alert okay
hoodies are cool and comfortable okay
but I like being fancy and but when you
make me wear a time of I'm going to
wreck you
okay and that doesn't even cost extra
you made me wear a tie you're going to
pay for that it's like but that's okay
it's like but hey
I can accessorize still
do you see the three hacking devices
there
well I mean the pin's sort of easy right
here
that's sort of easy
video camera pin I'm a walking talking
Google streetcar on these engagements
yeah that that's fine it's like but what
about oh
I got a couple of these
this one I love this 16 gig USB hard
drive with a high def video camera with
infrared but you unscrew that plug in
the cable download 16 gigs of your data
which probably wouldn't do any harm to
your network right 16 gigs of your
proprietary information and I walk out
with it because you know Screw use noted
in your Rubik's Cube It's like yeah it's
like I do that
that's cool
I like that it's like because it's fancy
but
where's the other hacking tool
I made sure all my shirts are French
cuffs
one
because of fancy
and two because the cufflinks
like this one
here we go
I ain't it's coming off okay
that that is a threat it's like but okay
okay
there we go
hey
anybody need a wireless USB adapter
plugged into your server
no not at all
are you going to get one yes definitely
but you know some of those servers are
not very cooperative
you know or some of those machines
aren't very Cooperative that's why you
have a two gig USB drive that actually
has all the wireless adapters for
Windows Linux and and Mac uh there and
maybe a command and controller too you
know just for fun so I turned your CEO's
desk or your server into my actual
wonderful you know
what's that called
command and control center yeah that's
it
and router
those are fun so yes it's like I like
that you can get them on Amazon I think
still but you know what I love about
this jacket the most
it's got pockets
ladies don't hate me okay
I don't know why Western Society is
women can have pockets and men can't
wear purses because I often love my
purse is amazing it's like the only
problem is if I can't get a bigger purse
because then you got to have the word
tactical in front of it and it's like uh
so it's like and this guy like have all
the packages a lot of slashes and I just
like something like small that just
carries enough you know Hardware to
actually do damage uh and I love all
look at all those devices
are you not intimidated and entertained
how many of those devices do you need
Jason none of them hardly
but it looks cool
you ever seen those movies with those
assassins and Hitmen and that invisible
wall goes away and you've got all these
racks of guns and knives and numb chucks
and crossbows and all these different
daggers and cannons and and let me get
this 38 right here okay we're ready
let's go
so that's that's my assassin wall right
there or couch it's like I guess it's
like yeah but I I do have I do carry
some things you know it's like just to
like to show that I can carry things so
I got a little drop box here uh you know
that acts as like Wi-Fi pineapple it's
like the Wi-Fi pineapple light don't
tear and tell Darren that it's like a
bootleg uh then I've got like oh hold on
do I got something else in here oh
another Dropbox but smaller much
horrible and scary that's good what else
do I have in here
ah
oh hidden camera so you just place that
in the in the library on the shelves and
stuff you know so you can take some uh
CEOs type in on the passwords if you
don't using the keyboard and I have oh
don't I look smarter now
video camera okay
um
and then we got a nice little old school
rubber ducky uh because that looks very
intimidating why would I have it like
that uh another bash bunny
there was a cell
oh another little micro computer
as a little Game Boy Yes this did work
going into a server this is the original
one the original GPD I used to break
into a server once because I was playing
a Nintendo kind of DS knockoff and the
guy let me in because it was a three
hour update uh that didn't take three
hours it was I was able to Rob them in
less oh
um
I'm not good with the whole lock picking
thing remember
so when I want to steal a laptop I just
use these things very poorly takes me
like you know way demon I'm sure you can
just like look at them go like work and
unlock it me it takes a little bit
longer so I got these little things to
take the laptop because they like to
think they're secure
all right waiting there we go
take this off dude I feel something else
where that where where oh the stop
pocket
voice recorder leave that line around
somewhere
and oh oh my gosh I would have felt so
embarrassed if I forgot my Wi-Fi uh
keystroke lager an injector thank you
Darren again it's like so I can inject
keystrokes into a machine or just record
them and wirelessly translate them to my
car out in the parking lot
or the screen crab
I love that
because it's got HDMI you know most of
the the people don't get HDMI monitors
right because that's those are fancy the
CEOs do
you plug this one side into the CEO's
monitor the other side uh uh into the
output and guess what I'm now copying
everything that your CEO is writing on
the screen or looking at on the screen
and either I'm taking screenshots
recording it through video putting it
onto a Micro SD card or I'm just
transmitting it wirelessly uh to my
location so I can look real time and see
what it is better than soap operas
so yeah I got that what the that was
unexpected
okay we're gonna keep this on right now
but I finally to take this off so now
we're going to look at another layer
right
we want to go to the passive layer
what is the passive layer about
well the passive layer is where I'm
going to go and be a help desk person
it's like you know oh I forgot to
I also have like you know phone some
other gadgets iPhone oh I forgot I had
this like pocket I'm not packing heat
I'm packing exploits everybody don't get
nervous It's like got another bass bunny
got a couple OMG cables oh my gosh these
are amazing because each of these are
micro computers with Bluetooth and Wi-Fi
that can do remote code injection uh
from your hotel room which is nice
especially because you get room service
uh shark Jack where I don't even need a
computer I just plug this into your
conference uh Network Jack and this was
just cool that I built I got somewhere
like I don't know if it was a casket or
something it was just cool because it's
got a Micro SD card hidden in there uh
it doesn't do exploits I just thought it
was cool uh and I put it in there ah
there we go I also have Andrew lemon's
business card one of the most best
business cards ever and I'm giving him a
shout out because his business card is
actually The Little Door Sim so I can
just open up the door
because that doesn't I can handle this
this kind of like making
in you know or I'm sorry
hacker voice I'm in
there we go
now
let what does the passive roll look like
well
the passive role you know is going to
look like a worker
right
I'm gonna be a worker showing up in my
jeans
coming out
here to work on the server
here to work
okay okay sorry I digress y'all don't
want to see that either there we go
got my Microsoft badge
it says hacker on it I got another one
that says Gregory D Evans on it it's
like uh
I know still still too old but yeah I'm
old you know what the best part about
this badge is
anybody here work for Microsoft don't
don't answer it'd be embarrassing this
is their old badge
that I was able to acquire and give it
someone actually tweeted out the new
badge
but I've never and I've got a copy of
their new badge printed out
but why bother no one cares I still use
the old badge and I get in everywhere
with it so sorry about that guys but
with this I've got something else
the clipboard of Doom
Dawn
is there anything more fearsome
more terrifying
than a checklist
oh you don't think so huh
good to know
right
I got my clipboard to do
and so I once again but it's got pockets
okay get some other stuff in there
one of the things I love the most though
oh my gosh
look at this
the best physical compromise device in
the industry
there has been nothing better since its
invention
oh I'm not talking about the OMG cables
those are cool mg cables are cool and
everything I love them uh they're fine
envelopes
with a red marker because I'm in your
your secret area I mean your secured
area and there's offices and desks and
cubicles that are unattended but you see
their name
really
so I go over there
and I just write down that person's name
on the envelope
I take one of my little malware USB
devices
and I put that on their desk
and I walk away
which one of your employees are not
going to come back to their desk with a
sealed envelope with their name on it in
red and a USB drive and not plugging it
in
exactly I'm using human nature to do the
work for me
but also
I'm like an ogre I've got layers it's
like so I've got another layer of oops
also got a jacket stuck there we go but
yeah I've got like the Wi-Fi kind of
another screen crab another cameras got
like land turtles proc smart
and a whole bunch of other stuff that I
hardly ever use ever it's like but it
looks cool to have and it intimidates
people and shows like look I could hack
you with these things
scared okay those are good so what else
do I have I love this
every worker should have a nice
flashlight
especially with a high def video
recorder in it
spoiler alert there's no one from
Egyptian security is there in here okay
I literally was on a speaker tour of the
Egyptian Museum in Cairo where they do
expressively forbid you know uh videos
and cameras and stuff and so uh I had
like my my spy watch uh my spy cameras
like these and the battery ran down so
by the time I got to Tutankhamun's
exhibit and oh my gosh it's amazing that
they I mean well first of all it's
amazing they still got all that stuff
that you know the uh colonizers didn't
steal from them but it's like it's like
it's amazing some of the artwork that
you see in there it's like the British
museum would rate it in a heartbeat it's
like but I didn't have any other things
so I had to use the flashlight
and I was literally doing like this and
security was like excuse me you can't
turn that flashlight on no light oh
don't worry I'm not turning the light on
I'm subtle ask anybody who doesn't know
me there you go
and then of course I got another USB uh
pin uh this has got a laser pointer
because it's cool my friend from
telespace gave it to me uh I only use it
to for the USB drive to like you know
put stuff on it and scare people
um this one oh I forgot I'd be put I
don't know why I put that in there this
is a device if when I when we're talking
Petty to the next level uh if someone
steals any of my devices in my bag I
have devices like this and what it does
is it just builds up an electrical
current and destroys anything you plug
it into because you shouldn't steal my
stuff that is bad okay stealing is bad
wait unless you're paid for it unless
there's a contract let me make let me
make that clear okay
but then we get to the OMG layer
oh my gosh
I find myself using the OMG layer way
too much okay and that's just because uh
I have ADHD and I don't adult very well
uh don't judge me uh so yeah when I'm
doing the uh the OMG layer uh one time I
was in Kingston Jamaica and I literally
went in as a TV executive to hack this
one thank you
it's like
I've used once I used a the TV producer
to break into a charity organization in
Kingston it was very embarrassing
because I felt so bad about doing it but
I was being paid to be a horrible person
but my favorite
is when I Rob hotels because I'll run
into a hotel
fully clothed going to the men's
restroom staying there for about two
hours don't judge it's like and then I
take my clothes off
and it's like and then I roll up the
shirt and the jeans and the shoes and
the socks and I stick them under the
sink and now I'm a guest
now I'm a hotel guest just robbing your
hotel
and that favorite picture is that one in
the upper right hand corner that's me
and Jean cop ferrat at a hotel
overlooking the water that was the dump
they put me in because they couldn't
only afford to put me into their actual
hotel for one night
so they put me in that low rent place
right there it's like for the rest of
the nights I was there uh breaking into
them and I literally went in it's like I
said told the guy I was jet lags like
I'm just jet lines I'm gonna go walk
around the grounds I did that found it
uh the underground entrance which is
like that's where all the good stuff is
underground it's like you know basements
it's like and so I go in and I start
doing that and now I need to leave
so now I just go to the the room service
guy you know the late night room service
guide I'm like
[Music]
um
I'm not supposed to be here
touche
L later I
well uh
excuse the moi
foreign
I flustered him so much he put me in the
employee elevator
which let me out onto the first floor
into the management offices
as I was walking out I found a computer
that was unlocked in one of the offices
with the hotel master keys did I mention
it was a five-star hotel they provided
everything it's like and then I just
walked out from behind the desk going
hey hi how's it going I'm I'm good now
and just left that was fun uh that I
have to carry a little bit smaller
devices you know it's like uh usually
like I got the new you know rubber ducky
it's like this one's like the newer one
so it's got like USBC too because that's
the cool stuff Apple
um and it's like it's got the you can
put the payloads on there OS detection
really nice device and let's be honest
this is where I do most of my attacking
with it's like also if things are really
bad
you gotta
got a phone you can call for help
okay it's like uh I'm not gonna tell you
what the name of this phone is it's sort
of implied uh there it goes and then
I've got and I love this because it's
got It's all this is is a disposable
micro SD card USB card reader you know
why because you put a two terabyte hard
drive in it uh microSD card and then you
go
and get
yeah
it's there it is and you get this little
boy right here how you doing
plug that out there
plug that open and then there is your
micro SD card that you can walk out of
the company with
right there on the necklace
that's cool
it's like so
and then you just discard the micro SD
card you don't keep that with you
because you don't want to be found with
that and that because then they're going
to be looking for a Micro SD card and
trust me that could get uncomfortable
so I guess what we're trying to say is
if I do find a way in and I usually do
it's like uh I love the lower right one
because I can't do that anymore that was
me climbing seven stories above the
nicosi Cypress out of a window right
over the sheer drop just because the guy
said I couldn't and I didn't like that
uh and show how I could bring it to a
server room and then I made them take
the camera out of my jacket and take the
picture because Petty
so to make sure your employees don't
have to respond once I'm there
because that's the important part how
long have I been going
oh wow okay
I'm doing I can actually show you some
of the defensive stuff now because
usually it's like this time I've run so
long I'm like okay I would love to tell
you how to defend against this stuff but
I got to go now sorry my bad
it's like y'all I feel like I haven't
done that it's been very awkward so here
you don't just warn your employees you
show them
stop giving them 10 question multiple
choice every quarter and thinking that
you've done your security awareness
engagement
gamify it make them engaged in it make
them try to my friend Ben 10 actually
showed me a game that one company was
doing where they did no uh where's Waldo
every quarter
every quarter an employee would be given
a badge that was exactly like their ID
badge with the same exact privileges
same exact code everything except for
they replaced the person's picture
with Waldo
and the first person that detected it
gotten a reward
do you think people started paying
attention to people wearing their badges
or not
yes do you think people cared about
security more no
but there was something in it for them
now
they knew what to look for
they were engaged
show them these kind of attacks show
them what you can find on social media
about your CEO because who doesn't love
showing the CEO and finding stuff about
it with I mean make sure you remember
like the CI says Pete tells you upper
management buy-in is very important okay
it's like especially when you're doing
that because we call that a career
limiting move uh it's like so yeah but
make sure you're using examples that
they can relate to
also interact with your employees when
things aren't on fire
how many people look at security and
think that they're but the people that
are just looking at them to find out
what they did wrong
if you only interact with your employees
when something bad is going on
what are they why would they come to you
when something bad actually happens
so there's a new iOS iOS iPad update you
know yesterday or today
did you send out an email company-wide
letting them know they can update their
iPad
you don't have to tell them about the
security part tell them there's new
emojis or something I don't know that
usually gets them
but let them know when there's a new
Android update or an iOS update when the
FBI actually did something decent and
actually sent out a thing about the
D-Link routers and stuff let your
employees know that let them think about
security
let them be security conscious let them
know that you're not there just to make
them fail
or catch them when they're doing wrong
but you're there to help secure the
company and make they're sure they are
secure
do lunch and learns involve yourself
with the employees just not when
something bad is going on because when
they accidentally click a link
they'll call you in five minutes instead
of you finding out in five months
It's like because you know your solar
winds it's like that's not good
so and also this whole nonsense of
chasing old days
seriously
there was a a survey like in 2015 or
something like that where they said 89
of vulnerabilities were over a decade
old
people talking about like you know we
got to catch the low-hanging fruit you
know we got to go after the low-hanging
fruit and my mother the fruit's on the
ground
get a wheelbarrow
pick that stuff up first
you ain't ready for the tree
no fruit for you from there
we need to act you're talking about like
zero days and zero trust how many people
know how many machines are on their
Network right now
how many people in this company do
proper Asset Management
this is my judgmental look
and I'm looking at you
well and you too because definitely
um
so this is one of the key things we need
to do
the three E's
I came up with myself because it's like
three's you know all right educate
Empower and enforce you need to start
educating your employees
letting them know what the real life
kind of threats are like
but also educating them on what to do
when they detect something suspicious
why aren't you giving them an email
address to forward a suspicious email
too
why aren't you giving them an extension
number for them to call 24 7 when they
find someone suspicious in the building
I robbed the place in Iman Jordan
agreed with the manager the whole entire
time I was there that I was not supposed
to be there
she was like you're not supposed to be
there and I'm like you're right I
shouldn't be doing this I you should
have heard from management because I
shouldn't be able to do this
to any of these computers I mean if you
don't know
why I'm doing this that I shouldn't five
times
with me agreeing with her
and I asked her when it was over because
I don't do red teaming I do security
awareness engagements it's teachable
moments not testing it's like I don't
give them losses I give them lessons and
so after I finished an engagement I will
come back two minutes later and talk to
every single person I compromised talked
to that manager like you knew I wasn't
supposed to be there why didn't you call
someone
why didn't you have someone stop me
and she was like no one told me what to
do no one gave me a number to call
I had no number for security
how was that her fail
how was that on her
that was on the security team
they caused that breach to happen well I
caused the bridge to happen but it's
like you know they were responsible for
not telling their employees what to do
we need to educate them
we need to empower them to do it and
mother why aren't we enforcing it
how many links does bobbin accounting
sorry Bobs and accounting people does he
get to click on
before we realize maybe he's The Insider
threat where we should be worried about
people looking for maliciousness instead
of incompetence
if a van driver wrecks a van
they may get one warning
they wreck it three times they're not
working there anymore
your computer is equipment that can
cause millions of dollars in damage fire
them if they keep clicking links if they
keep showing that they are a threat to
your internal security
that's what guidelines and policies are
for start enforcing them
y'all think I'm joking I'm doing
[Applause]