nice to see you here I hope I don't put
you into your after lunch food coma
we'll we'll see how it goes uh here's a
little brain teaser to keep you occupied
during the talk so
if you've seen it it probably won't keep
you happy for very long I don't think it
will be on the hackers challenge
leaderboard so it's not going to help
you there
um but think about that the answer will
be at the end if you're still here yeah
okay so our agenda is pretty simple
we're going to set the stage talking
about appsec and why it's important and
why companies need really be thinking
about application security now
especially if they're developing
products it's very important to them
so we'll covers a lot of material so I
apologize for this this is a um uh
PowerPoint slide bomb I've learned
earlier today that I need a lot more
happy kitties or other things like that
but I did try to put in a couple of uh
cartoons in it to keep you entertained
and play along on the journey but we'll
look at what makes an appsec program and
then specifically look at three things
which is security Champions threat
modeling and s-bombs and then there's
some appendix material that we're not
going to look at
but this is the first time that appsec
has featured prominently at St con um
there are last year I submitted this
talk and it wasn't accepted this year
was and there's three other talks that
you can go to if you're interested in
application security
first one is uh Kenton McDaniel who is
talking tomorrow about application
security maturity models hope that
doesn't overlap too much with what I
said
and then coding secure without becoming
a hacker is also on Thursday and then on
Friday there's a plunge putting the SEC
back into devsecops so check them out
and there's an absolute Community
Village down there if you want to try
your chops at appsec
yeah
okay this is the obligatory who am I
slide and this is where I say everything
I say here is my own opinion does not
necessarily reflect the opinions of my
employer or my boss who is in the crowd
so hopefully I don't get fired by the
end of the day so
um I am a long time software developer I
spent a year years a entire career being
a software engineer before I switched
over to Security
I got my first job as a software
engineer before I got my first degree
and then I slightly over compensated and
went and got a PhD so
um
big long interesting Journey everybody
takes a different path to security so
you have a different background and that
diverse background is very important to
have
um I currently work for Arctic Wolf
which has a booth down in the front
lobby if you do do some
I think if you post something on
LinkedIn you can get a special mini
badge from them so go check it out
this is my third time presenting at
saintcon the other two times have been
upstairs doing an introduction to python
class so
and but that's enough about me now
earlier today somebody mentioned that
executive sponsorship is very important
so that's a given so this isn't even
before we started the setting the stage
stuff we're instill the front pattern if
you don't have executive support things
are not going to work out so well for
you it is very important and enough said
on that so that's why it says at the
bottom you can't get it done if you
don't have the buy-in from upper
management
all right so we're going to set the
stage
who has who has developers on staff
doing stuff now and do you have an
abstract program
okay does your abstract program look
something like this security guys tell
developers about specific
vulnerabilities
and then it goes into a black box they
may figure it out they say it's fixed
and it comes back to you
and then invariably security finds other
flaws and the security guys complain
when a breach happens
does that sound like security at your
place
nobody no okay uh it's pretty common
this is actually David rook and
principles of security development from
OS Ireland conference
back in 2009 so things haven't really
changed that much in the 13 years since
he put the slides so I did steal them I
hope that's enough a copyright notice
for it
most places have a different approach to
it and that's everything is fine
right we do a little bit we have
GitHub Advanced security it covers our
bases we're taking care of our
vulnerabilities but that hey it's
skipped a slide that's neat
sweet you guys don't get to see the
everything is fine
the meme of the burning house because
that was there
um
oh there it is everything is fine
that's how it typically works right but
is it in the last couple years we've had
a lot of different things that come
through yet I've had log for J if you're
a developer that probably ruined a
Christmas for you a couple years ago
um spring for Shell more recently
proxy not shells going around now that's
a a current one
different types of repository poisoning
is going on we're different uh actors
where their environment activists or
just people upset with the system or uh
intentionally corrupting GitHub repos
and injecting vulnerabilities into them
and then there were solar winds anybody
heard of solarwinds no it's not not a
new thing for you all right
the interesting thing about solarwinds
is everybody I've talked to about
solarwinds I've asked some very specific
questions about it it's like do you know
what happened and and what was your
company's response for and there are
companies and very response was
invariably we patch solarwinds nobody
ever stopped to think about
if that trusted software that was signed
by the development process
was
compromised how has that happened and
how do we prevent that from happening in
our own organizations
right
does anybody know how
solarwinds got compromised
they haven't really said who but I
believe the password it was a network
compromise of a server with the network
password of password123
I think I heard that somewhere I don't
have a source to quote that on but they
got in got on the network compromised
the build server didn't modify the
source code repository didn't modify
anything except they installed malware
on the build server
and that malware did a specific thing it
looked for a specific file to be written
on the file system and it overwrote it
and then it just got happily built
there's no evidence
Left Behind after the malware was
removed it was only because a security
researcher noticed suspicious Network
traffic after it got released
so
you have wife a wife will protect that
right that that's the common theme that
most security conferences for a long
time is you have a laugh right and the
nervous Chuckles from the groups in the
back going yeah no we don't really have
one yet well they're more common now but
you don't really know how you're going
to
um
how they're used and every time
something comes up you poke another hole
in it pretty soon it's swiss cheese and
it collapse
so oversight is coming you can see this
coming from compliance Frameworks
governments
uh
and the most important one is executive
order of 14 14028 which came out from
Biden's Administration last year but
there's other ones back in February of
21 there's executive order 1417 which
instructed people to start improving
their supply chains zero trust reference
architecture came out from nist
um
and
foreign
thing coming out from this is the
minimum definition of an s-bomb we'll be
talking about that one a little bit
later there's a specific section on that
but it's not just America that has
happened this this slide is all about
American forcing America forcing
improved software security this one is
different countries doing the same thing
so Great Britain Germany
um the European Union as a whole and
then the EUR the trade and Technology
Council has been put in place all of
them are working on different things to
help make sure that application security
is a forerunner and um
and thoughts and contracts for
government organizations and selling
software is what we do selling software
to
governments is always looked after by
your uh sales team so if you can't
support them by having the processes
that will be made you'll be missing that
opportunity and one of your competitors
will have that opportunity
yeah
you typically come into a lot of
different reasons or excuses for why um
software security can't be built in now
and those really come into a lot of
different things it's good enough for
now
these risks are not relevant it's not
the number one priority
it's it's just a pilot project that ends
up invariably being in production we're
changing too fast your controls will
slow us down we depend on third-party
Solutions we don't want rigid we're
agile we can't do it
uh other challenges is there's so many
Frameworks out there there's the new CSF
there's ISO 27001 their CIS
uh controls which is the top 20.
anybody familiar with this well it's 18
now and when they revised it anybody
familiar with the CIS controls there's
one section in there that's about that
long about application security and
you're supposed to cover everything in
it so
um
and the other option is there's lack of
developer team buy-in you have
a team that is responsible for
delivering features and you have another
team that telling them that they need to
slow down that they need to be careful
that they need to think and engineer the
solutions that they have that that's a
different rant I have of whether or not
your organization calls somebody a
developer or program or an engineer
those all have three distinct meanings
to me so
we want to have software engineers and
Engineering is a
process that is rigid and followed
it can be fast but you have to have a
process and it has to has to be
repeatable
and most of the features that the
development teams are already working on
oh they're they're probably behind
schedule because they're optimistic when
they make the big guesses about how long
something will take and when they start
to break it down they realize it's a lot
more complex so you have times
now some days if you're doing abstic
it's going to feel like this
but here's my question for you who did I
who do you think I see as the
application security team
agent Smith
okay because that's what
engineering thinks that they're Neo so
you have to fill the role of agent Smith
so okay keep that in mind
it's a matter of perspective security
team members are going to think yes I'm
doing the right thing but you are seen
as an impediment to Neo accomplishing
his mission
now there I can go at osm about
different reasons why this is needed so
there's headlines all the time that that
you can see
uh most of these repeat the things we've
already talked about but
um mobile Trojans being distributed by
mods
app developers are increasingly targeted
by slackcan devops tools so
that the attackers have learned that
there is a nice
soft underbelly out of the hard shell
that most I.T security systems put in
place and if you get in you can have
practically free range
because if you think about it when your
network security team is prioritizing
what work they are going to do
do they prioritize a server
or a developer's laptop
they prioritize the server right because
that's what makes the money
but if they compromise a developer's
laptop and that laptop has shes SSH Keys
into AWS or whatever other system that
they have
that's a low criticality system that
might not have as much rigid controls on
it as you might need to have
some more my popular one is popular iot
cameras need patching to fend off
catastrophic attacks that's like right
up there with the killer light bulbs
that you you've heard about recently in
the news so
um
so
if we take a look at the top 20
um
actively exploited items that exist in
2021 you can see that about 25 percent
of them
are related to application security
there's the log for J that one's going
to be up there for years
um somebody stated that it would take
decades for that to be truly remediated
but I can't think of another company
that has has not come out and said oh
we're not affected by it we passed it
we're good
there is way too much Java code out
there for that to be true because we
have software that has had defects for
decades that is still not being taken
care of
um then there's the other question if on
day one
somebody says they're not effective for
for log4j it says
yeah great they're not using for log4j
but what about solarwinds oh we're not
affected by it does that mean
they don't have solarwinds or they have
solarwinds and it was running an even
older version of it so they're not even
they don't even have a good patch
management strategy in place so
um so log4j GitHub vulnerabilities
elastic and vulnerabilities a couple of
them were at last in sitecore which is a
marketing website management system and
the Apache httpsover all have had
critical attacks that have known
exploits that are really easy to script
so script kitties can do it too
here
um so I think we've clearly demonstrated
the need for application Security in an
organization
but let's think about how it gets rolled
out there's basically four phrases the
phases that this happens in uh the
reactive a Baseline and expanded
an advanced one the reactive one is what
really happens when you first decide hey
we're going to have an aptech team and
that's you start hearing about
vulnerabilities
and you take them to the security team
we're at a baseline is okay we're
starting to get a little bit of handle
of this maybe we'll roll out some tools
we'll start defining our processes we'll
work on it but everything is building up
to having an advanced area and
Advanced capabilities in it where you're
proactively seeking and searching for
them and that is through whatever means
you have whether it's pen testing uh
unit tests misuse abuse cases internal
testing QA writing requirements up front
and that's your ultimate goal
but what is the appsex team's role in
application security I've already hit on
it it's not what you think
it's not about you it's about them
Your Role is to build trust simply put
just spell trust
with the development teams
and you need to make it so that it looks
like
a unifying effort so here you see a fire
support team where there is person in
the trench with the developer providing
active support form okay
all right
if you look at the devsec on the SEC Ops
model you can see that it's pretty easy
it says Dev QA Ops and in the middle
it's devops
been a trend lately to calling that
devsecops so that that's a good nod
that's security is becoming important
but
the devops aficionalities will say it's
always been there it's always been in
the manifesto there's a little teeny
font that says Security in it so it's a
team sport you're part of the team you
need to integrate into this devsecops
model because that's how software is
done you're not going to be able to
change that you need to work in that
model
so it's like a team sport and a team
sport I did not know much about
was
rugby right I did not know they had so
many positions and I don't know why I
can't see my notes but so we're going to
be winging this because I still don't
know all these positions
um but there are different different
positions that they have they are highly
specified specialized and that's the
main point of the slide is you have
props hookers locks flinkers the number
eight man who is like the center in
soccer you have quarterbacks who is
their star from American football
Wingers centers and fullbacks each of
them have a specific role and that role
is very specific to what they do
and
when the development team says we have a
handle on security
what specialization does that have
right
we can take care of security because
we're already taking care of all the
other abilities we're talking about
reliability sustainability uh resilience
but unless they staff for it and they
have people that are dedicated and have
time for it they can't stay on top of
all the changing that is going on it's
just not possible for them to do that
and if you look at the structure of most
development teams here's a sample of
some that I
pulled off of the internet while I Was
preparing for this
this is your standard application
security or your standard development
team where is Security in this model
here's another one
where is Security in this model
a third
no security
a fourth no security
a fifth
no security
and a sixth
so development teams aren't Staffing for
this so they can't take it on they don't
know how to do it
so
so as we already said development
developers already have a lot to
remember it's impossible for them to
keep track of this would you rather have
a cardiac surgeon operate on your heart
or your GP
okay
um
also internally if you're making
decisions about yourself your opinion is
going to be biased you're going to think
you're doing better this happens even on
security teams security teams might
think that oh our processes are good
enough we're catching it we have a good
enough development
I'm sure solarwinds thought that that
but they had the Pearl Harbor of attack
so the the somebody was thinking out of
the box and figured out a way to get
past them
all right and then if you look at your
Dev Ops models
who has the devops teams that actually
have minimized rights
or do all developers because they're all
devops all have rights
so even though you have a devops model
your your authentication method really
looks like this your authorization roles
is an overlapping developers can do
everything everywhere which means that
it's really critical for them to have it
have
lockdown computers and have plans for
addressing that and they need to know
limited rights type manner so
to get it right
it's it's getting back to the basics
it's getting back to the fundamentals
making sure that you have better
workflow if you have an app set program
and you have employed it right it makes
it so that you have the ability to have
better workflows better remediation
better overall management but
and safer products better reputation
higher qualities
which might mean less cost because
you're not paying out afterwards
seamless collaboration among teams
so that I haven't quite seen I've seen
collaboration among teams still working
on the seamless part it's a love-hate
relationship
um
um going back to the higher quality
results for Less cause
I I can't remember who said it but I
heard somebody say once that the
difference between a pin test and a
breach is only when you negotiate the
cost
right so
all right so this is the part that will
bore you to death we're going to talk
about a lot of different Frameworks that
exist out there and you can see
where you might have to start if you're
building it up from scratch or what
resources you might have that will be
useful for you if
you already have something in place on
coming into thinking about which
controls that you might have to put into
place
the first one the easiest one to start
with is Microsoft has their secure
development lifecycle website there is
lots of material out in there
depending on how close you've looked
maybe you've discovered the Microsoft
STL portion of that but a couple clicks
on this you can see that they have an
operational security architecture and a
secure devops and if you dig really
close they even have some content on how
to do Agile sdl within their within
their organization
the Microsoft security development life
cycle has 12 simple things that you can
do to get started
number one is provide training
in all Microsoft Frameworks number one
is provide training
now that's a little bit of an edgy topic
because I can't think of any place that
has actual good training I see plenty of
things that have awareness but nothing
that actually develop tells the
developer how to code securely and
anything that's done ad hoc in-house
usually is done with the security
engineer in mind where they say hey if
you don't do this you have a
SQL injection or something like that and
they talk about it in terms and
terminology that is familiar to the
security engineer not in terms that the
engine the software engineer will work
on so
um
defining security we're not going to go
through all of them we're just going to
bear with me we're just going to go
through this one pretty quick to find
security requirements that's important
everything that you do after the
developer is done is reactive so by
having security requirements you're
doing things up front you're working to
address the problems when it has a lower
cost when it is easier to fix
and before the developers considered
themselves done okay
all businesses run on metrics and
compliance reporting so you have to have
kpis to go with it performing threat
modeling is one of the tenants you saw
that as one of the three things that I
signal that will talk more about and
that's because threat modeling
allows the developers to start talking
about the designs that they have and
gives a form for the software and the
application security engineers and the
software Engineers to collaborate in a
freeform space and there are ways to do
it that are not formal that are engaging
and make it a lot less painful process
okay
um
design requirements goes kind of hand in
hand with the security requirements
putting them up front
make sure your company has
cryptography standards and using them
number seven is an important one is
managing
the security risk of third-party
components that's all why there's news
or talk about s-bombs or third-party
compromises and then use approved tools
how many places have dedicated Ides that
they use or is it anything that they
want to use or how do you control even
what gets put onto a server how do you
harden your image and then SAS Das
penetration testing and establish an
incident response process
you might not have to establish an
incident response process because most
places already have one
and you just need to figure out how to
interface with it effectively right
so we'll start going through these a
little bit faster on the other side they
have the operational security Assurance
which if you think about it it's with a
Dev Ops or devsecops everything's coming
together and developers are doing more
so you have to think about the coding
aspects you have to think about the
hosting aspects and you have to make
sure that you address all of that in
your application security program so on
the operational side they're looking
about how how the controls are put in
place for authentication how least
privileged and this isn't in the
application you're writing this isn't
the software that you're hosting or
running making sure that you have your
WAFF your rasp your I asked and if you
don't know what any of those tools are I
can tell you tell you what those are
later but protecting against DDOS
attacks and making sure that you have
hardened configurations and again
perform penetration testing because
that's still the number one way to find
out how you're going to get attacked is
to try it again
Microsoft has a framework for trying to
manage your supply chain
number three is the most important thing
and that is inventory does your company
have an asset inventory system
okay I don't see any hand so that's just
scary so okay
okay all right so I can't even ask the
follow-ons to that because I didn't see
any hands but does that asset inventory
go down into the containers that are
running does that do you know what
software is running on that container
which team owns that software and where
to find that software in your source
code Version Control System
yeah
and then more secure devops stuff so and
that's where they start talking about
software composition analysis and
protecting so it all ties together
there is another company out there that
exists it's called uh well I don't want
to say the name of the company but they
have a product called bsim and that
stands for build security and maturity
model I'm sure if you Google that the
company name will pop up really quickly
um
they do a report every year on the
controls that make the most sense and
their controls are broken down into
governance intelligence ssdl touch
points and development and each of those
controls have
three different sections so governance
has strategy and metrics compliance and
policy and training
and then I you can read that I'm not
going to do it for you so
the most important thing from there is
they also say what their top 10
activities are so if you start looking
at the items that they have they're
leaning heavily on things that security
teams do well already so the number 10
thing and
really wish I could see my notes which
gave me the percentages
um
is translate compliance this was done
about 79 of the time
integrate and deliver security features
that's actually good because that's
talking about building features into
your products
um if I recall correctly that was 82
percent of the time integrate and
deliver security fee that's what I just
did use automated tool code reviewed
tools that's when you roll out your SAS
tools and all the SAS tool is is a tool
that automates the process that code
reviews accomplishes it's best done
inside of an IDE while the developers
are working a lot of companies choose to
implement this as a step in their build
process where they will on a pull
request reject something
but that's after the developer may
consider themselves done
or what scares me more is they rely on
the pull request to tell them that
they're not done because that doesn't
sound like engineering to me
it's like oh well let's see if this
works
which
um it's kind of like back when I was in
college which was a really really long
time ago slightly after they got light
bulbs so I would go work and submit a
program on a mini computer
submit it to compile go eat lunch
play a couple video games in the
cafeteria come back and see if the
compile was done and find out that I
forgot a semicolon on line 37.
so it's not an effective use of time
perform Edge boundary testing in QA
if your team if your development team
happens to have a QA Department that's
great
most devcops teams I know have gotten
rid of QA because the developers are
responsible for the security
which means that they are very good at
testing the happy path for their stuff
and not very good at thinking about the
bad path or in particular the evil path
um Security review features get extra
eyes on it that's always a good concept
external penetration testing that's an
important one why external
that's because external brings a fresh
set of eyes as well internal you start
testing the same things
and we like to change the pin tester
that we use because if you use the same
one year over year they're probably not
going to find anything especially if you
get the same guy in the engagement
again interface with
um incident response I think we're in
the uh high 80s now I think 87 for this
one 87 of companies here
um engage in this activity and then I
didn't identity identify privacy
obligations this obviously comes from
Global businesses wanting to support
gdpr or any of the other privacy
Frameworks out there
and then the things that we're really
good at is ensure you have the CIS
controls in place because we've been
doing that for decades
and Implement security checkpoints
and Associated government so we're
pretty good at saying hey we need to
stop stuff because our GRC Department
says a but we aren't good at practicing
ourselves and making sure that we have
checks and that are aren't required okay
um
that one's only 90 of the time
the only one thing that happens in visa
from all 100 uh that happens 100 in time
and the 113 people that participate in
the survey every year is that they have
an application security team instead of
putting it off on engineering
okay
there's another framework this is open
Sam that comes from the uh well it
doesn't come from it but OAS has taken
it up and it's now an OAS Flagship
project it's designed in a similar
manner actually if you look at the
history of it Beeson went this way and
oh Sam went that way so they have
different controls underneath underneath
it but it breaks it down into governance
practices
design practices
implementation practices
and verification practices okay oops and
operations put the and in there in the
wrong place
um more recently there's
SP
800-218. now anybody that's gone out
after fedrap is probably familiar with
SP 800-53
because that's the Big 4 400 page
document with all the wonderful controls
that you have to have but this is what
came out in response to Biden's
executive well it existed before but it
can be used to address the the
um
the control uh if you're pursuing fedrap
again have to understand that you have
to start considering State ramp
or well I think it's going away but
there's Texas ramp too or text ramp so
that's going to fall back down in state
Ram so that's the logos for all of them
you can be uh ready
provisional or
what's that last one authorized under
that one
um
so under nist and that really does not
work good on the screen I apologize for
that
um it's prepared the organization
protect the the software produce well
secured software and respond to
vulnerability so it's it's nice easy
practice these are all easy to Google
but a similar type controls that you've
seen from the other ones so we won't
spend too much time on them
um
and then if you happen to take credit
cards there's PCI
DSS
which has some controls that are very
similar to it like build and maintain a
secure network protect account data
build a maintain a vulnerability program
the interesting thing about PCI DSS is
it says you have to secure the data and
Transit
if it's over a public network so if it's
on a private Network they don't care
I think that's wrong
um PCI also sorry about that also has a
secure software
framework that it makes it easier for
you to start implementing the things
that are covered under the PCI DSS spec
they go hand in hand they map back and
forth between the two
uh number 11 there is secure software
updates so
uh that that's there are more Frameworks
out there those are the top ones that if
you're building an appsec program you
need to think about and make sure that
you write your controls to adjust to it
so if we're thinking about how do we get
started with this
and hopefully I can finish before my
plugged in computer dies because it says
my battery is almost gone all right
um
there's no blueprint for your company I
can't tell you exactly what you need to
do but I can tell you that there's six
things that you should consider doing
involved the development team early
access where your organization is Evac
take a good hard look know exactly where
the bodies are buried
which bodies you need to bury and dig up
first and start working on them have an
asset inventory and that asset inventory
isn't just what computers you have or
what it is watching it has to be
everything whether it's a corporate
system whether it's a AWS Cloud resource
even if it's you know something that
just lives there for a while you need to
understand the process that builds it
and when it will show up and when it
will disappear
uh know what you have in the threat
modeling
automate automate and automate I think
there's no way that you can do this
without automation you won't scale you
have to make sure that every as much as
you can do is automated and then test
evaluate and report and then obviously
rinse and repeat because it's a
continual process it's a program not a
project
places that go in and look at something
as a project for appsec will never
really do a good thing because you'll
get a little bit of time
once a Sprint once a quarter once a year
or something like that instead of
changing the culture that you need to
have you have to have the security
culture like they're saying in the
Keynotes earlier today
and one of the best ways to involve the
development team early is to have a
security champion
this is a concept that comes out of
besum and that's a really long um
bit of verbiage for anybody who gets the
slides later to remember what I was
talking about at this time but the
important thing is the security
Champions are resources on the
engineering team they are the developers
they have stepped up and said I will own
security for my team okay
the the benefits for them is it looks
good on their resume depending on how
you roll it out they can get incentives
or you know
um one of the companies I worked for
before if you were a security champion
and you had enough active involvement in
it they would send that champion to
Black Cat
of course not all Champions are
motivated by that so you have to think
about your target audience and what
motivates them some of them might be
fine with
just money so
um
so the Champions role is specifically to
give the security team somebody on the
engineering team that's directly
responsible for it
a
bi-directional pipe for communication
the champion can come to the engineer
saying hey this is what we're working on
we need to think about how to do it
securely and get advice from them and
then the security Champion can receive
from application security there anything
that's coming down the pipe that might
affect them like hey we heard from
marketing that we're going after fedramp
that type of surprise might put a damper
in the software engineer's day when they
realize that they have to meet all these
controls
make sure that they're able to host in a
different area and review all of the
components that make up their system and
make sure that they are fed ramp
authorized
yeah
um it's the only way to allow
security efforts to scale right
application security Engineers are one
hard to find too expensive
and three
I don't know the best way to put this
they just say that they're they're
overworked just like everybody else in
the organization so
you have to have
a ratio a a small team of application
security Engineers cannot work with 600
developers effectively if you have five
five application security Engineers
trying to talk to 600 developers that's
going to make application and security a
bottleneck form but if you have a
different model and it's you have one
application security engineer for 10
Champions per 100 developers now you
have a very a very good way to scale
right
it it adds a layer of indirection that
can help out
um
it also puts somebody on the development
team that helps spread that culture
within the within the development and
team because if he's taken to him they
respect him they might not respect you
unless you happen to be like me and
poached people from the engineering team
for your application security team
um
and if marketed correctly it can be a
competitive differentiator
okay ISO 27001 is not hard to get you
have to be right 70 of the time to get
that certification
lots of companies have an ISO 27001.
lots of companies that have been
breached have an ISO 27001.
right but if you can demonstrate a
market that you have a secure product
especially if you have something like a
bug boundary program to work on it
so how do you start it
Champion program you need to decide what
you want to accomplish you need to
decide who is going to participate now
earlier I said that it's very important
that this is a volunteer effort right
sometimes this becomes voluntold but you
really want it to be a volunteer effort
because that way you find somebody
that's passionate about it who's
interested in it already
you need to clearly Define what is
expected of them
and again going back to the training how
how will you prepare them for the task
and again upper management support
and how do you keep the Champions
interested and that's the gamification
that I talked about earlier
um
so then threat modeling threat modeling
is usually the second thing I do the
first thing is adding a software
security champion
program so that you have somebody to do
the threat modelings with now
application security Engineers can do a
threat model on their own
but that's not the most effective way to
do it the best way is to get in a room
with your application security engineer
your security champion and hopefully the
entire development team if you can take
a take the time
and really start
getting into what the process and
business function of the software that
you're looking at is for so you start
with identifying what objectives you
want to have
then you look at an application
application overview this is really
great if your development team already
has data flow diagrams and flowcharts
and things that you can work on or that
might be one of the findings that you
have from this is that we need these
before we can do that you break apart
and decompose the application the most
important thing there is to think about
the trust boundaries that any data might
cross and how you protect the data as it
crosses those trust boundaries
start thinking about threats against the
system and how to identify
vulnerabilities the most common method
for that is stride it's an acronym for
spoofing tampering repudiation
information enclosure denial of service
and elevation of privilege
okay so
um another common wave
another common thing to consider at the
same time is privacy a previous company
that I've worked with there there's a
game called elevation of privilege we
added a privacy deck to that and we'll
actually see that here in a little bit
but there's also another common way to
think about threats and that's attack
trees where you want to discover
vulnerabilities
that instead of just thinking of here's
a request and a response on what the
problem is this takes a more uh overall
Approach at it and you can find Multi
multi-step attacks and you start
thinking about what it takes to
compromise each stage of that and it's a
much more detailed and rigorous process
from the adversaries Viewpoint you think
about how much will it cost them to
launch the attack
what's the effort to set up an effort to
execute
what are the required tools and skills
and what is their Roi so and then from
the defender side you got to think about
what is the impact of the attack what's
the cost of the failure what's the
likelihood that your security operations
team is going to be able to detect it
and what is the lowest cost
countermeasure that you can effectively
deploy to at least reduce the the
problem the impact to a reasonable
amount
and here's a common example of what an
attack track tree looks like so in the
middle it's we a web application was
compromised because of a
configuration file modification
with modules in the web directory
and the ink file was could be displayed
in text form so and it's a very visual
it's easy to work through
and I'll admit looking at this kind of
boring developers don't like to do it
there are eights will glaze over so back
to that gamification that we're talking
about Microsoft has the elevation of
privileged card game it goes against the
stride
um there's a OS Cornucopia which has a
different set of controls that you need
to work with
and then the one I found while I was
researching for this and I need to take
a closer look at it is the
um
attack patterns one in the middle
okay now let's go back and take a look
at s-bombs okay
um anybody XKCD fans here you might
recognize that cartoon okay at least a
couple people have seen this I've
doctored the cartoon a little bit it's
really hard to see but one of them one
of the modules now says jQuery another
one says uh log for Jay and and then
another one says spring for Shell in
addition to that one component that
somebody in Nebraska has been supporting
since 2003.
foreign
well unfortunately Vlog for Jay has
hundreds and hundreds of developers but
it's a good example a couple weeks ago
there was
um
a 2007 python
vulnerability end quote we'll call it
put it in quotes because the back in
2007 the developers did not consid deem
it to be a vulnerability so they did not
patch it so in 2022 it became very
popular to exploit
through this this vulnerability again in
quotes because it was published back in
2007 nobody's defended against it and
that was in the part of the Python main
library for handling and unzipping files
so it's
it's possible to have a overwrite files
in your file system by crafting a
malicious tar file and having it
unzipped on the server because it does
it it just the writers of the package
says our job is to unzip tar files so we
don't care what the tar file says if it
says it goes out of this Parent
Directory we write it out of this Parent
Directory right so
are they right yeah probably
their job is to unzip tar files somebody
else has to
actually make sure that that makes
business sense for them to do but if you
think about the tools that exist whether
it's sassed or dashed none of them
detected it
um and
it's an interesting question SAS tools
started to detect it now but if your SCA
tool isn't detecting it you have no idea
if the open source libraries you're
using which may also impress a tar file
um would would have the same
vulnerability because they consider that
a coding problem something that the SAS
tool would catch so it's a good example
of wherein you have to be have
comprehensive knowledge about what's
going on and think about it
um for log4j I know that we had
um many vendors came out with tools to
detect it not all of those tools were
created equal
so I had a vendor give me a tool that
said this will detect log for J on your
network I asked him about it and it was
okay well what it does is it looks in
your system process table
for the strings that the attack has
but the system process table will be
executing whatever malicious payload the
log4j attack had so it's way way down
the stream and those attack indicators
wouldn't be there anymore
um
so
back to the s-bomb
we've already said many many times it's
important to have an understanding what
you have and
what compromises your system this is why
open source is becoming important is
because there's 73 percent
year-over-year growth in the use of Open
Source which means that more and more
open source is used less and less custom
code is written there are 37 million
open source components
2.2 trillion open source package
downloads and 6 million new package
versions introduced last year
um a third of them have known
vulnerabilities
only six and a half percent of them are
uh non-popular
because the big ones with the most
downloads are the ones that get
scrutinized and looked and exploited
um
the 650 percent increase in supply chain
attacks over and that's up from 430 and
220. so it's an exponential curve that
you're having there my favorite one is
the next one developers make sub-optimal
choices 69 of the time regarding
upgrading third-party components
so
that's because of the enormous volume of
Open Source dependencies that are
present
the incredible rate of time that goes on
between them if you're using GitHub
Advanced security it will tell you that
there's a new version available it won't
tell you what's the best one to solve
the vulnerabilities that exist in that
right
it has two different versions but other
tools if you look at them they have the
capability of telling you hey not only
do you are you using this component the
one that's mostly likely least likely to
bork your entire software stack is this
version
or it can also they start tracking
metrics like um how many commits were
done in the last year how many
developers made those commits so that
you can start looking for the ones that
are actively maintained instead of using
the one maintained by that one guy in
Nebraska
um nist came out with the securing the
software supply chain recommended best
practices for developers and really all
that is is a mapping between this
document the executive order and the
ssdf framework
but the majority of it focuses on the
top left corner which again has asset
inventory and uh vulnerability
repository so you need to get the handle
on that when you're thinking
oh now we're having trouble
is there a um
it's plugged in
let's see did that save it
it does not seem to have changed
all right well good news is we're almost
done but I don't know if you'll be able
to see it right
so
um
obviously don't use Alpha Beta we'll try
to get through this before it shuts down
don't upgrade to a more vulnerable
version
um
okay so I had some expected questions
what is the minimum that you need in my
opinion you need security Champions
developer uh secure development training
documented understanding of what you're
trying to include and there it goes so
um
okay so I know the rest so we can we get
from here the other thing is I mentioned
bug Bounty once why
why is that not a important strategic
way to do things it's great for finding
stuff but bug Bounty programs
are the the designs that come from them
are from the perspective the bounty
hunters they look for things that they
know how to find they don't look for
things that you need them to look for so
that's why a pen test by qualified
people is better than a bug Bounty
program especially since pen tests are
recognized by most compliance Frameworks
bug bounties are not
okay and then there was one more
expected question that I'll try to get
back to at some point in time but uh any
unexpected questions yes sir
uh what kind of measures
have useful in an access
findings
typically and I think
that not always helpful and not
in our cases
how do we communicate to Executives with
what like how secure our activities I I
think that's uh it's it's a very good
question but your metrics journey is
going to be a journey you're going to
have to start with the hey this is the
number of findings we have a lot of the
times it's being able to take the number
of findings you have and pivot it and
then something actionable so instead of
saying that I have 5 000
um
issues of this type you can pivot that
and say I have one issue that says I
have SQL injection vulnerabilities in my
system and then design a program to
focus on that and that will help but the
trick is when you said going to upper
management as as you start sending stuff
up
the amount of information you can give
starts to dwindle I give my boss a
couple of PowerPoint slides I think it's
four right now he has to give his boss
two he has to give his boss a third of
the page so you have to make sure that
your absec risk scores map into your
governance risk scores and accurately
reflect on it so but it's a journey you
have to start with the counts then you
have to start looking at how fast are we
closing them versus how fast are they
being created are we making making a
sustainable program what's the average
age that they're open and then start
building up more knowledge after that
any other questions or did that answer
your question
okay any other questions
yes
if you ask most of the time they will
step up I actually switched to security
because I heard the CSO and the CTO
saying hey we never really need to start
thinking about application security at
this company and I'm like you know I
went to school for that I'll be more
than willing to help you with that so
but you what you need to do is design
the program and then design incentives
for for the people that you find so if
you find people that are interested in
security training you can do the let's
let's if you participate enough score
enough points or however you want to do
it we'll send you to Defcon if you find
that there are people that are looking
for supplements to their paycheck go for
cash Rewards or something like that
um but you have to sell it to them it
looks great on your resume it builds
skills that will go with you no matter
where you are
anyone else
all right
cool thank you for your time