okay
so I have to admit I'm kind of excited
about this talk
because like I said in the description
if I could talk to myself 12 years ago
I would have said this is a thing be
ready to feel it
and then I would have grappled with it
for a couple years and uh
not like myself and then I've talked
enough therapists that I'm okay with it
um does anyone in here feel like at some
point in their life they've felt
imposter syndrome
every day
all right
okay so first off
uh of me uh this is me
so you can do a recognition that's black
and white this is color
I'm a husband to one dad to five for Dad
to two they're both dogs
uh I I like cats but I can never eat a
whole one
I am neurodivergent I have ADHD just
like most of you and I am on the autism
spectrum like many of you
you just might not know it
uh I'm adopted
which brings another challenge to the
Imposter syndrome when and this is a
real thing uh before you have words as
an infant
when your mother you've come to know her
heartbeat and her smell and her sound
and then she gives you away and you
can't say anything about it you can't
express it all you have is the the the
the trauma
you feel like an imposter you feel like
no one loves you
it's tough I still feel that today it's
tough
um I support minorities in Tech I think
we have too many pasty white guys and I
am a pasty white guy
I love lgbtq people I think around here
they don't get enough love and
I do love them and all my hugs are free
but you have to ask for them I will not
just hug you you have to ask
um we're going to talk about what is an
imposter what is imposter syndrome who
feels imposter syndrome
give you a hint everyone how do I know
if I'm feeling it how does it manifest
what should I do about imposter syndrome
who didn't feel imposter syndrome but
should have
and this is important and then stop
comparing congratulate yourself
and here's a disclaimer I am not a
therapist I am not a psychologist or a
psychiatrist I have spoken with many of
these types of people but I am not I
don't play one on TV
um I'm not a doctor I'm not a lawyer I'm
nothing I'm just an infosec guy
okay what is an imposter this is a
definition of what an imposter is it's
someone who's going to be sneaking in
they pretend to be someone or not social
engineer or someone
um
Jason Street going through the bank he's
doing the USB audits
he's impo he's he's an imposter he's not
I.T guy
that's an imposter he doesn't belong
there
but imposter syndrome is a real thing it
is a psychological effect where someone
doubts their skills their talents or
accomplishments and they have a
persistent internalized fear of being
exposed as a fraud
now a lot of people think they this is
in their career you had it in school
you might still have it today do you
remember the dreams you have where
you're speaking and your teeth are
falling out
no one cares but you like you can't
catch them they're all over the place
you can't get your teeth
your subconscious does not trust the
words you are speaking
your dreams where you go to school or
work naked
it's not a sex dream
because no one there cares
you're going because you don't belong
you're naked because your subconscious
says you don't belong there your
subconscious believes you are an
imposter
it sucks
because those dreams are the worst you
wake up and you just you're frazzled you
don't know what to do
it really it's very unsettling
it's imposter syndrome you felt it in
school you feel it at work you'll feel
it in relationships it's brutal
so who feels imposter serum I asked
earlier
I have asked my doctors they feel
imposter syndrome
I've asked my lawyers they feel imposter
syndrome I have asked past professors
they feel imposter syndrome I've asked
my father he feels imposter syndrome
about being a parent
I have asked ecclesiastical leaders they
feel imposter syndrome I used to run a
con I felt imposter syndrome I should
not be running a con
I know Jupiter feels imposter syndrome I
know the entire staff of this Con feels
imposter syndrome I know all of you feel
imposter syndrome did anyone did anyone
think maybe I should submit a talk to
Saint Khan this year but you didn't
has anyone ever considered submitting a
talk to any con
but hasn't
that's imposter syndrome because the
ideas you had the ideas you had to share
are valid and good and we want to hear
it
you have experience that you can help
others by sharing what you know
and you are good enough to submit a talk
all right
studies say that 7 out of 10 adults will
feel imposter syndrome sometime in their
life and I know in those studies the
other three people were relying because
they wanted it to seem stronger than
they are
so here's a graph for you
47 of humans that get imposter syndrome
in blue
the green is the other 39 and the
remaining 14 they also get imposter
syndrome
foreign
if you need to see the details
so how do I know if I feel it
if you if something goes well in your
life do you think you were lucky
do you think it was the work of someone
else
do you feel that someone else did more
work than you did it's possible
but do you discredit your own work
and your own contributions
are you afraid that someone's going to
pop into the office and say who hired
this person
why are they here they don't know what
they're doing
are you afraid that someone from your
past life is going to going to see you
at lunch and say hey what are you doing
and you say oh I'm I'm working at this
company like you do what
you
if you're afraid that's going to happen
you might have imposter syndrome
do you feel like you have to overwork to
meet expectations
this is one that I am so guilty of I
will pour myself into work trying to
make sure they have no reason to fire me
I work and work and work and I work and
I'm chasing down every fire and I'm
trying to do every new initiative and
I'm trying to get more and more out
there so people can see me and it's
because I don't want to be fired
because if they find out who I am
they're going to fire me
feel Unworthy of attention or affection
this one hits a little close to the
heart
but there may be some of us here
who in their relationship or they can't
find a relationship because they think
they are not worthy of love
it's not true everyone
is worthy of love and a healthy
relationship
and you need someone to interact with
you are more healthy if you have someone
to interact with you need love
do you downplay accomplishments if
someone says you did a great job do you
say ah
thanks I didn't do much it wasn't much
if someone says hey let's let's thank so
and so because they did such a great job
at this initiative and they saved us so
much time or so much money or they made
us so much more secure and you say
it wasn't that much it wasn't
that's imposter syndrome
do you hold back from reaching
attainable goals do you set a goal for
yourself
and then you might get 80 percent there
and you just and you tell yourself I
just can't do the last 20 percent
I'm not good enough
does any of this sound true does
anything ring true to anyone
yeah it's
it's brutal
so how can this show up at work
you might say that wasn't me I didn't do
that much it was him he's better she's
better I'm just me
you won't ask for a promotion
you might get passed over because you
play quiet all the time
you might be stuck in your position and
you'll get very frustrated
and you'll think I could do more but I
don't deserve it
at home parents every good parent
will feel inadequate they'll feel like
they're making mistakes
sometimes they'll feel like they should
not be apparent
if you've ever heard of a story where
maybe one parent was absent because they
thought they were a bad parent
some cases if the person is
irresponsible in some cases they think
they're a bad parent
we all know bad parents maybe you had
some
if they're doing their best they're good
parents even if they make mistakes right
for you if you are doing your best you
are a good parent even if you make
mistakes
uh if parents feel they're too much of
imposter they may not they may not feel
comfortable helping their child make
decisions
later in life because they feel they're
not making the best decisions for their
children
at school
students might not speak up they might
not ask questions they want to seem as
clueless as they feel
that's to their detriment
they're not clueless they're students
and relationships again if if you think
that you are not worthy of love
you might sabotage your relationship
you might end it before they can end it
and that is so frustrating it does not
need to happen
so how can one overcome imposter
syndrome
recognize the facts
one that I often recognize or I have to
recognize I think
that guy would be better in my position
than me she'd be better in my position I
think they should have my job
that might be true they they might have
more experience
now if they have more experience does
that mean you're not valuable
no it means they have more experience
they might be getting paid more than you
because they have more experience
that's a fact
they may have there may be someone
working with you who has experience in
another niche of infosec security than
you do maybe they have more forensic
work or more threat hunting or
uh they have been a manager
so they have more skills that's a fact
they might have more skills than you
they're not you
I have been a manager and I have hired
people and I have seen their
shortcomings I've seen where they lack
skills that they said they had
and I don't care
I say let's focus your energy on those
skills let's get those going so you
match what you think you are
because you don't need to feel like an
imposter
just fill the gaps
you're hired
I'm not going to fire someone
for not having everything they put on
their resume as their as hard as they
can Flex
I'm going to hire someone because I see
their potential and I see their
initiative
and their ability to figure things out
and learn new things yeah I want that
person totally in my team because
they're going to be stepping up
if they feel like an imposter I need to
fix that
[Music]
right like I've seen people write it
like every mid senior yeah
I would want to see on a resume I have
done this and this and this I have
helped with this and this and this and I
want to do this and this and this
and then when I'm interviewing them I'll
say okay so you did that
tell me about that you helped with that
what does that mean and you want to do
this oh you've you've done a little bit
you want to do more of it great I know
beginner entry
good
make sense
that's what I'd want to see
exactly
and
into what my actual role I'm trying to
try to film and those are the facts
I have when I was younger I put on my
resume everything in the tech stack and
every every initiative that the company
tried to do I was like I was part of
that
I wasn't part of any of that
that was the network guy and the systems
guy I was just the security guy
I responded to alerts
and I felt when I when I came to grips
with the facts I was like oh no I didn't
do those things
and then I was like well
my resume actually I feel very
comfortable with my resume now
because that's exactly what I did and
what I haven't done
so when I go to interview they don't ask
me about those things anymore
nice
separate your feelings from those facts
you are not bad for not having
experience
you are not bad for
recognizing your inexperience you are
bad if you say you have experience and
you don't
if
if you are if you're in a relationship
and you do something that hurts the
other person
that's going to happen you are going to
hurt the people you love
you are going to be hurt by the people
you love
if you love them and you guys can talk
about it forgive them likewise if you
hurt them own it talk about it and they
can forgive you
you love each other
don't defend it and don't hide from it
and don't pretend like it didn't happen
you deserve to be loved and so do they
take note of your accomplishments if you
have a problem with in with with
imposter syndrome get a Post-It note and
write down the things you've really done
recognize what you did recognize how you
contributed recognize how much of a part
of this initiative was yours was it 50
was it 10 was it 75 percent was it 99
percent
write that down and stick it somewhere
on your desk
and then when you're feeling like you
don't belong there look at what you did
no one else did it you did it
you're totally qualified to be there and
be participating with your team because
you did that you contributed that much
recognize it own it
share with with people you trust
say I'm trying to overcome my imposter
syndrome and I did this today
and it was good I did a good job
imagine saying that to someone I worked
on this and this and I did it and it was
good and it it contributed to the the
success of the the project
and someone go wow good
how would that feel
talk to others
everyone in this room feels imposter
syndrome everyone out of this room feels
imposter syndrome talk about it
ask how someone else deals with it what
they're afraid of how they feel it
if you talk to the right person they're
going to give you the feedback you need
you're doing a good job look at you
you're at St con you're learning you're
sharpening your spear
you're you're doing a great job
preparing yourself for tomorrow
talk to a therapist
I think everyone should have a therapist
I can play a therapist I've had therapy
for over a decade
uh I think everyone should have someone
to talk to so when you trust that you
can share your secrets the things that
you're afraid to tell anyone else
because they're not going to judge you
they're going to try to help you find
the problems where you are not
functioning the way you want to
and they'll help you
so who didn't feel imposter syndrome but
should have we're going to get to one
more thing on how to deal with plaster
syndrome and I want to use this guy as
an example
can anyone guess who I'm going to say
you won't but any ideas who who does not
feel imposter syndrome but should
anyone
who
is awesome your boss
I promise you your boss does feel
imposter syndrome
and if you walked in and said you don't
belong here
they'd have to Grapple with that because
they believe it
um
Kanye
maybe I mean Eddie just dropped him
anyway um
did anyone see this movie or read this
book this is the Martian
okay
what did he do
okay but what was his training
he's a botanist
he was on Mars if you didn't spoiler
alert you should have seen it by now
he was on Mars part of a mission and
they had a storm coming and was going to
knock over their uh their return ship so
they had to
abort the mission and run to the ship
and take off so they could go home
and during the storm something impaled
his suit and knocked him out and buried
him in sand and they thought he was dead
so they left
he was not dead uh he came he woke up
made it back into the to the outfit and
started figuring out how to survive
now the chemist could probably atomize
H2O and not cause an explosion
he didn't know how he knew the concept
and he Jerry rigged it together and he
made an explosion
and then he fixed it
if
the whole team was there
and the chemist was off doing something
else and they said hey can you go figure
out how to atomize the H2O so we can
grow potatoes
he'd say why am I doing it why wouldn't
he do it
they said oh yeah you're right you'll
probably make an explosion
chemist can you go do it the right way
the first time
right
now the chemist wasn't there
so he did his best
he caused an explosion he didn't die and
then he figured it out and it didn't
phase him at all
because the chemist wasn't there
this is the key to imposter syndrome
stop comparing yourself to other people
their background and their history is
different than yours they're in a
different position than you are they
have different problems than you do they
have different concerns they than you do
they have different fears they have
different priorities they have different
perspective
they are not you it is not fair to
compare yourself to them for any reason
even twins are different enough they
should not be compared to one another
they might be similar but they shouldn't
be compared and they should not compare
themselves to one another
don't believe anything you see on social
media from anyone
no one
is a hundred percent factual and true
on social media
it's a highlight reel it's the best of
the best
people don't say oh my gosh I suck
I
I did not tweet when I shut down email
for a weekend
I feared for my job because I screwed up
so bad I learned don't do your work in a
bubble have someone else check your work
I shut down email for a weekend and the
sales team enough people have come and
gone they don't remember it but for a
long time they're like are you messing
with our email again no you're just not
getting your leads it's not me
I didn't tweet about that I felt
terrible
I tweeted a whole bunch about Jason and
snow and deviant and I tweeted that I'm
doing this talk today
but don't believe anything on social
media
don't look at your peers
they're where they are for their reasons
and you are where you are for your
reasons you they belong there and you
belong there
you're not better or worse you're just
you and that is perfect
don't look at your superiors they've got
more experience than you do that's why
they're your Superior
if they're a wizard if they're if
they're a freak of nature and they just
breathe if a sec and they're younger
than you and they are your Superior so
what
that doesn't mean you don't belong
you belong just as much as they do your
Superior might be younger than you
okay
don't look at your juniors
if anyone is there younger than you
don't think you're Superior
they're there for a reason and you're
there for a reason on the resume they've
got their I'm good I'm I'm best I'm good
I'm better
maybe you have more best than they have
better that's great
I promise you both belong you are a
valid
contributor holy cow okay we're almost
done
uh don't imagine that anyone is a rock
star no one is a rock star everyone has
struggled everyone has problems
they they belong where they are and you
belong Where You Are
how
someone else's success has nothing to do
with you it doesn't take away from you
it doesn't
mean you're any less they can succeed
and you can succeed they can succeed and
you don't succeed
that's okay
there's nothing wrong with that
now before you kill information uh
information security
I wish I wish before you kill imposter
syndrome
you have to congratulate yourself
because
recognizing that you don't think you
belong
says a lot about you it says that you
want to belong
you're afraid of being fired
you're afraid of being exposed as a as a
fraud
you want to be better
feeling imposter syndrome is a good
thing if you can recognize you're
feeling it
pat yourself on the back and then drop
it
I don't need to feel this
it's a real thing and it's only to hurt
me and I don't need it I can let go of
this because I belong and I am important
and I bring value just as much as anyone
else
and then go and do what only you can go
and do
okay
any questions
any thoughts
anything you want to vent anyone any you
want to share
what's the best way to help others get
past this especially
when you see that they're struggling
ask them what they've accomplished
tell them you can see the Imposter
syndrome
and they don't need to worry about it
you're not going to expose them as a
fraud you're not going to to recommend
they be let go
you see the Imposter syndrome it doesn't
belong they belong they have value and
talk and ask them get them to say what
they've what they've accomplished and
celebrate that
Institute
I think so many people get negative
feedback
his wife will try to compliment someone
every day and we get we have so much
negativity we don't get
the pot we don't get the compliments
this is true and something that bugs me
about information security we're trained
to find the problems our brains are
tuned for the problem and the bad thing
and so we need to make a conscious
effort to find positivity and be a
positive resource for others any other
questions or suggestions
say if you hit all people raise their
hands about the talk I spoke last year
we were speaking this year
I'm unsure talk to the organizers yeah
they will let you know that something
that they think
I'm sure let them know say hey I think
I've got enough knowledge in this and
that they might and I didn't
know that's great we would love to have
that
came up to me afterwards and like ask me
for my opinion and I was like what is
going on
do you want to know what I have to say
like I'm nobody so he's saying if you
have an idea and you you don't trust
yourself talk to the organizers and
people on the committee about what your
idea is and they'll help you uh they'll
say yes that's great or they'll give you
ideas or suggestions or pointers or
things to look out for my time is up
thank you for attending participating
enjoy the con
[Applause]