you know what we wanted to have an
opportunity or I wanted to have an
opportunity to talk a little bit about
the future of Utah Saint and Saint Khan
uh the slides you're about to see are a
great representation of ADD
and so they're going to be all over the
place but if there's some things you
can't glean out of what we're doing and
stuff in here that are helpful to you or
fill a gap somewhere
that's really the intent here I'm hoping
that there's a lot of our committee uh
Board of Trustees and other folks that
join us in here and can answer some of
the questions that you might have about
the organization and what we do and how
we do things and the conference and
everything else so that's really it and
it's not going to take a full hour I
don't I mean if if we take a full hour
that's because you guys have a lot of
questions uh because there's only
probably about 20 or 20 or 30 minutes of
slides here uh which will give you your
last opportunity to go down and trade
any of the many badges that you've got
anybody not get a Yoda mini badge in
here
holy crud
and
I don't think there was a class for the
Yoda mini badge ever like so here's the
thing this morning we found a bag of
Yoda mini badges that was kind of
stuffed underneath of the something that
was never supposed to be undone or
whatever so I literally have in a bag
right here don't come up here yet
probably I would say 20 to 25 of them
and I will hand them out to you on my
way out the door after this presentation
so if you didn't get one there's
probably not enough for everybody who
raised your hand but if you had one
already don't raise your hand or get a
second one because there's so many
people that didn't get one and uh I
guess I just failed in the number of in
or the amount of interest there are in
Yoda mini badges this year because man
I can't walk 10 feet without hey
until you have one of those and it's
been so awesome I'm sorry I'm a little
tangent here before we even get started
but it's been so awesome to meet so many
people I I just had forgotten how
conversational a mini batch can be when
you're sitting there and you're catching
up with people
uh and such and so I've had a chance to
meet so many people uh many for the
first time and many that uh I consider
you know many of us consider St Khan as
a family reunion of sorts you know you
get to see the security folks that
you've worked with or met and you know
done things online with or whatever and
put names to faces and things it's also
a wonderful event so we love putting it
on and that's why we're here so we're
going to talk just a little bit about it
but we're going to talk about the pants
issue first
so
[Applause]
here's the history and I'm still seeking
information as I was mentioning so many
years ago we took these very cool photos
of all of the committee members that
were the planning committee for Saint
Khan and it was one of those kind of
pose things and it was you know waist up
shot and we put it on the website to to
give recognition to the people that put
tons of energy and effort
and of course somebody's going to take
that and find some other image and
Photoshop them together and it became
this ongoing Meme and they did such a
good job that people were like hey do
you did you actually wear those and is
that a photo or not you know so you can
tell the top part's black and white the
bottom part has color it's Photoshop
together but I still to this day don't
know who
created this but it pops up every year
and I figured you know what hey it's
time to just own it
like if if I own the meme then I I have
the power right so hey I'm owning it
so that's the story so if you're
wondering I'm not trying to you know do
anything other than just own own a meme
and maybe
help kill it finally or whatever
but let's get into a couple of a couple
of things for those of you that are new
uh to the to Saint Khan how many of your
first timers so you're kind of in here
just wondering what the heck is this
thing or whatever okay good there's a
lot of you here like it blows our mind
how many new people churn in every
single year for Saint Khan but let me
give you just a little bit of history
about Saint con okay Saint Khan is a
conference that has actually been going
for 21 years
but it's probably something you've never
heard of until the last five to six
years
um and what it was is it was an it was a
conference that we started running out
of the Utah education Network now the
Utah education and Telehealth Network
many many years ago because I I got to a
point in my career where I was somehow
in charge of this new thing called
security 20 some odd years ago
and we would go out and we would visit
the people throughout the state and we
would find out that
we don't even have firewalls in place
like they're we're not doing anything
what's security like yeah we know that
there's hackers and things but they're
not like they're not after us we're just
people in Utah and things and so it
became very apparent very quickly that
we needed to start having conversations
about security and so with the help of
uetn we started the security Summit and
I think the first one of those was in
2001. and that was 25 people from most
of like education and some state
government folks and the things that we
got into a room up on the University of
Utah Campus and we just talked about
security for a couple of days and it
blew everybody's mind it's like oh my
gosh I had no idea that you could do
this and we showed people how to hack
things and and gave them the tools like
hey why don't you just try this and see
and it's amazing and hopefully many of
you had this experience during sync on
this year where
where you've had that aha moment like
who's picked themselves out of handcuffs
for the first time in their lives
this week right was that an aha moment I
hope that was that you're like this is
not that hard and the thing is is when
you start looking at security and other
things you can realize that there's a
lot of vulnerabilities and a lot of
things that we need to protect uh and
and make better and so anyways the
history of the Utah Saints conference
and things
um
it's it grew a little bit year over year
and there was several years where there
was about 150 of us I think was that
critical mass for many years and we held
it down in St George beautiful area down
there it's nice and warm in October you
know and such but we would hold it down
there and it would be about that same
150 people every single year that we
would do this and we had so much fun in
fact they're used to break we used to
break out in Nerf gun fights in the
middle of talks we used to throw things
at the presenters I mean it was a little
it was a lot more
I don't know what's the right word there
mischievous I don't know
Rowdy that's the word a little more
Rowdy and stuff but we had so much fun
and we would have the craziest people
come up and present you know who they
were it was that guy right there it was
this guy right here and we didn't know
everything there was to know about
security at the time but we'd learned
something and it was like we're going to
share this you know like hey did you
know that if you actually started
blocking ports and protocols like you
could do some really cool things and
that was where this kind of started
um and so it graduated year over year
and what we ended up doing back in about
2006 2007 is we created in kind of
conjunction with it an informal group it
was literally just hey you want to be on
a mailing list and we'll talk about this
stuff and we created something called
the Utah Saint group
um and it kind of became just the same
people that come to the conference and
other things and we would let them join
the mailing list and we'd email things
back and forth and like hey this is what
I'm seeing because it created more
timely conversations rather than just
once a year it's like we could talk
about things then we went through a
process of vetting and making sure that
everybody on that list was cleared to
hear the information that we were going
to talk about and stuff we went through
all these kinds of things but once we
created that organization it was started
to be called the Utah Saint conference
from that point forward and it proceeded
until about I want to say 2013 2014
like I said I have a headache it's kind
of I'm fuzzy on dates right now or even
years at this point we'll get it close
to a year anyways then we get to the
point where we're at the slide what we
decided to do because of the complexity
of the conference and everything else is
we formed a 501c6 non-profit membership
Organization for the Utah Saint
organization that's what we called it
and as as things became more complicated
uh and things with the conference and
some of the other Outreach we were doing
we started running the Utah sync
conference out of this 501c6
and created a Board of Trustees and
everything else I'll talk about here in
a minute bottom line is
we're here and we have this organization
and I'll bring you up to the current
history here in a minute but our mission
really hasn't changed the Utah Saint
organization provides community and
education to cyber security and I.T
professionals that's our mission that's
what we do
um it's it's an it's evolved over time
and we include more people in different
communities and other things and we we
it started very much in the roots of
education so if you see a lot of people
if you're in edu in K-12 or higher ed
education raise your hand if you're
willing to okay if you look around the
room and you're not familiar there's a
lot of us here because that growth came
out of that Utah education Network we're
kind of just working on some things and
stuff and so a lot of people here come
from that background uh and but we
opened it up and started taking in
private Industries and other people
because we knew that if we grew our
security Community that's a lot more
voices and a lot more talent and
capabilities coming in and and feeding
into this and so it benefited us in a
big way it also became that spark that
you lights you know that starts burning
and you get to a point where it's going
down and you know that there's a big old
dynamic might block over here that it's
going to hit at some point because all
of a sudden it blows up into oh my gosh
this conference and what we're doing is
actually a thing and it's not just 150
people in a room talking weird things
about security
and anyways there that's the evolution
that we're dealing or we're going
through volunteer non-profit wanted to
help you understand that everybody that
participates in the Utah Saint
organization
is a volunteer there is not a single
paid
employee or or anything else for that
organization and we built it that way
it's in our bylaws that we do that it's
that way so there's no paid person the
the organization so here's the
governance of the organization the
leadership the Utah State organization
is run by a Board of Trustees a board
chairman a secretary and a Treasurer or
the primary officers and then we have a
bunch of other trustees that are part of
a voting committee that helps Orient and
run the art or the organization and
again they are all volunteers they're
giving their time and talents to do this
uh underneath of that is the conference
planning committee and they get a lot of
praise and everything else but they are
technically separate many of the Board
of Trustees members are on the planning
committee as well but the conference
planning committee is organized by the
board chairman of the organization is
responsible for overseeing all planning
for the saint con conference this
process begins each January and the
volunteers are responsible for
everything that happens here
there's also a membership committee uh
formed in the Utah State organization
who's responsible for handling all
membership functions and activities this
is whether you want to join the
organization whether you're like I'm out
I don't think we've ever had that really
happen but
um you know those types of things
there's a membership committee and
that's how we're that's how we're
structured we're pretty simple this
isn't you know when you're working with
volunteers and everything else it's not
like we've got this big conglomerate or
anything else going on it's it's very
simplistic and it takes tons of hours to
do all the tax work and all the other
things that happen with that
organization so it's it's kind of a
thing so what we do uh you know bringing
us into a little bit more modern history
or anything else St Khan is obviously
now the primary event that the Utah
Saint organization puts on and it
continues to grow in size and complexity
every single year
okay a couple of other things that the
Utah State organization does that were
that maybe is a little less known so
you're going to want to get your cameras
out here in just a second I'm going to
show you a slide that you might want to
take a picture of maybe maybe not okay
but one of the other things that we do
is we have semi-weekly security
briefings
if you've not heard of those you're
going to have a slide here with the link
on in just a moment to join those okay
every other week we get together as an
organization as a group and we talk
about all of the current threats risks
vulnerabilities things that you should
be working on or new trends and tactics
that are emerging that you might want to
have some understanding about it lasts
anywhere between 30 to 40 minutes of
your time it's live we do it in WebEx or
Zoom or some other platform like that so
it's interactive if you've got a
question you can ask a question or if
you have something that you see that's
emerging or coming up that you think is
interesting There's an opportunity at
the end of their at the end of The
Briefing to present that and talk about
it and it's actually how many of you in
the room participate at least on some
regular basis in those briefings there
should be quite a few hands okay because
we end up having between 70 and 100
people every session participating in in
that briefing most of the time it's just
me you get more me I don't know why is
just me but you get more me telling you
everything about what's going on based
off of my limited capabilities of
researching and so Community input and
Community Driven content is something I
really appreciate there
but that's one of the other things we do
and then we also do education Outreach
we have as you can see downstairs we
have like 40 soldering irons we've got
all kinds of video equipment and
microphones and PA systems and other
things we purchased over the years to
facilitate events in the conference that
we lend out so if you are in a space
where you're doing education whether
that's a local group whether that's a
religious or church group or whether
that's an education group and you need
30 soldering irons if you're a member of
the Utah Saint organization we'll lend
them to you will also give you our
solder and our components and other
things
based off of what we've got we don't
just like buy them for you or whatever
but uh and we'll lend that to you to
facilitate you taking
um and enriching some sort of Education
activity uh within those types of groups
and so
um it's really great uh for medium sized
groups and teaching security topics and
other things that's our mission that's
what we do so those are the primary
things that the Utah State organization
functions on this is the URL if you want
to
um join our security briefings this
takes you over to a mail chimp that's
the the email system that we use a
MailChimp sign up list and what that's
essentially doing this is subscribing
you to the list where you'll only get
one or you'll get two emails or what
hold on you'll get one email every other
week and it's not just like a hey a
reminder thing you're going to get
whether you attend the briefing or not
the entire agenda of everything that's
going to be discussed in there so that
if you can't attend you can read here
are the things that we're talking about
this week or maybe that's hey let's see
if it's important enough for me to
cancel my other meeting and join or not
you can make that decision but it's good
security information and you're you're
welcome to join us
what generally happens is the first few
right after the saint con all of a
sudden it turns into we're trying to
cram 500 people into a zoom room
and everybody kind of gauges whether
it's effective or not the next briefing
will be this coming Wednesday so
like five seven days or whatever it is I
don't even know what day it is today
hardly
um so anyways if you would like please
join okay so let's talk about Saint Khan
because
it's it's kind of a thing
um
Saint Khan comes from humble beginnings
I think I've shared some of the stories
about where we come from and and how we
got here
um or I got you up to the point where we
were calling it The Utah Saint
conference and we would hold it in
different places all around the state
um and then we finally got to the point
to where we were getting 300 and 400
people coming to this conference and we
had to start like renting out the entire
Union building at the at Weber State
University and things to hold these
these things
and uh it was about that time I think it
was 2015 that we called it Saint Khan
anybody want to correct me on that 2015
is when we changed it over and called it
Saint con uh instead does anybody know
why we call it Saint con or where Utah
Saint and those things come from
anybody curious I mean that's kind of a
whole different story or whatever else
um and things but when we created that
Utah Saint organization it wasn't
you know anything about any sort of
religiosity or anything else it was we
created This Acronym the security
advisory and incident Network team that
spelled out Saint and it was kind of
cool so the proper way to spell it is
Utah with u capitalized ta uncapitalized
but Saint is all capitalized if you want
to follow our style guide you know
um excuse me
but that's what it is
um the it's the security advisory and
incident Network team for Utah
um and so it was really hard to fit Utah
Saint conference on all of our materials
and things in some format so we just we
truncated it and that's why it's called
Saint Khan and that's why whenever you
see it officially it's all capitalized
because it's sankcon anyways there you
go there's your history for the day
um we began opening it up to the world
when we renamed it to syncon meaning
that we no longer just advertised it and
talked to or talked about it to
education the state government and some
of these other areas and from that point
it just started we lit that fuse and it
started exploding and size and
complexity driven growth is now becoming
our biggest problem with Saint con
um and I can kind of talk to you a
little bit about it it has to do with
volunteerism and and everything else
meaning that as I mentioned we're all
volunteers there's nobody that makes
money off of this conference or anything
else and when you have a day job and
you're responsible for all the things in
your day job and everything else
everything becomes nights and weekends
and we burn a lot of nights and weekends
to the point to where there's a lot of
burnout that happens with the planning
committee with staff members that are in
charge of contests or communities or
events and everything else but it's a
labor of love I put it in there and it's
it's managed fairly well up to this
point because of the community that we
have and you probably heard me say it
many times in different talks and it's
kind of cliche a little bit at this
point but Utah does have by far the best
cyber security community of anywhere
I've ever seen
and it's true
I mean it's weird and crazy that here in
this we'll call it Podunk State you know
that we can get 1500 people together to
talk about cyber security and 80 to 90
percent of them are from the state of
Utah I mean it's a big deal we do a lot
of cool things here but with
volunteerism there's only so much you
can put on people and so growth is our
challenge meaning that all of a sudden
we went from 1200 people last year
approximately that attended the
conference to this year it's 1500 people
that attended the conference and if you
can imagine just for a minute in fact I
think I've got a slide for it here
because we talked about nights and
weekends I should mention here that
Saint con now just for all the things
that you get to participate in takes
approximately six months of planning
we start in January
and then we really start in March and
then we start really good in April
and then by May we're spending nights
and weekends a couple of times a week by
June and July that's nights and weekends
every week
and then August September October I
don't think we even sleep like we have
to start doing the overnights and
weekends kind of things but let's talk
about the other issues here and that's
Logistics you probably noticed those of
you that have been long time Saint con
attendees that we've always had
opportunities for like discounts and and
hey just kind of work out your
connections with these folks and other
things to get into the conference and
everything else and we took all those
away this year we didn't do that because
we're in there for the money grab or
anything else like that but I'll tell
you what every time we create some sort
of exception at this point at this
volume the logistics explode
into a million different directions and
it becomes super hard because now that
person that's in charge of registration
if they have to deal with more than just
one ticket type and one registration
process and now we have to have
discounts and then we have to have
discounts on discounts and then we have
to have discount codes and then we have
to have redeemable codes versus
registration codes can you see real
quickly how it just gets out of hand and
so we started doing a way
and we're starting to try and streamline
and simplify all of our processes and so
that's the reason why we've done that in
case that was a question for from
anybody
and so we are trying drastically or
desperately to standardize our processes
to make this be more successful and to
take a lot of this load off a lot of
these volunteers and such and so a
couple of the other challenges I think
are worth mentioning here other than
Logistics in fact we have two people in
our Logistics department now
just to manage all of those little
things like every time you get one of
those attendee bags even though there
wasn't a ton of stuff in there this year
somebody had to go through and procure
all that stuff bring it all in put it
all in bags and there's 1500 of you guys
now that's a lot of work we spent an
entire weekend putting together
registration bags in my house
kind of crazy anyways some are some of
the other challenges uh that we have
storage
we now have so much junk
because if you think about it as we've
evolved the conference we used to do all
of our own AV meaning that we would
bring our projectors we would bring our
cameras we would bring our audio systems
of everything that we needed in order to
make it work because paying for the
venues in-house systems and other things
were not it's not something that we
could do
um at the time and so now we're getting
to the point where we've got all this
extra stuff over the years that we've
collected and it sits in a storage unit
for 11 and a half months out of the year
most of the time uh and so so we
struggle with that staging
um we struggle with a lot of that too
getting ready for the conference and
such we struggle with setup sometimes we
do have a wonderful volunteer effort
that comes in and helps us set up but
it's unorganized like you're not coming
in here with hey you're supposed to do
this it's
in fact it's when I'll I'll say this and
I don't mean this in any sort of
negative way but when somebody comes up
to me on Sunday or Monday it says hey
what can I do to help
the thing is is it's not like it's
almost like I don't know
what you can do to help go find somebody
that's doing something and help them you
know because they all think that I'm
somehow the Oracle of here's everything
that he said yeah if we just do this and
this and this because it's so complex I
don't even know all of the things that
go on anymore everything that happened
at registration this year I I don't know
um everything how those communities got
set up other than hanging the banners
which are pretty cool by the way other
than hanging the banners I don't know
you know so all that stuff happens by
volunteer effort and it takes people a
lot of time attendee bags badges we
talked about mini badge design some of
these things take a lot of time and
energy and
create Logistics problems and everything
else and so if you are interested and
maybe this is the slide where I'm
supposed to land and say hey if you are
interested in contributing to the youth
or the saint con conference in some sort
of meaningful way these are our biggest
needs these aren't all of our needs but
these are our biggest needs we need
Graphics designers
I spend literally I'm just going to
throw this out there I mean it's a guess
of a number but probably
two to three hundred hours
building Graphics designed for this
conference every single year most of the
graphics that you see on signage on your
mini Badges and other things are
something that I've designed either last
year this year or whatever the logo
designs and everything else and that
takes a lot of my time
tons and tons of it I could totally use
some help so if you're a graphics
designer or no one that's really good
and that is volunteer effort or is
willing to volunteer I'm interested in
that one web content developers and
managers we do a really good job with
our website but we struggle with that so
if you're able or willing to volunteer
and help keep our con web content up to
date and things that's one area many
badge designers we've probably seated in
fact we coined the phrase at our
committee we call it poolcon where we go
sit around the pool and just talk about
how the conference is going
um but we talk we we coined the phrase
we have poked the mini badge bear this
year
and we know we have
meaning that even though there are
probably only a hundred mini badges that
were unique to the conference this year
okay and maybe I've heard rumors of up
to 200 or whatever if we think that
that's the threshold how many of you are
are planning on going back and designing
your own mini badge for next year
that you didn't have one this year right
like yeah it's going to be off the hook
next year for many badges
just saying many badge designers hey we
can probably use you and those of you
that have been inspired to maybe go and
learn that new skill we might have a
community badge that you could design
next year because that's a ton of my
time that I spend on that as well
hackers challenged uh puzzle designers
we're always looking for good ideas
um Josh Galvez he's over there talking
about hackers challenge right now but
the interesting thing about this is you
can't run a challenge or a contest like
that for as many years and keep just
coming up with fresh ideas you run out
of ideas at a certain point I know
because I ran out of ideas before it got
handed off to Josh Galvez
um and so he's getting to that point and
he's indicated it and very respectfully
like I don't know if I can think new
things up and so ideas are what he needs
and so if you've got hackers challenge
puzzle ideas that's one way to work on
it so let's talk a little bit about
Saint Khan and the future
okay we're likely I'm going to drop this
right here so that you are all unfair
warning
we are likely not going to continue to
let Saint con grow in size Dave
I'll get to that there's a slide for
that
okay so Saint Khan is likely we're not
going to let it continue to grow in size
we think that with the volunteer effort
that we have and without having to go
hire people for the Utah Saint
organization to manage books and all of
these other things that the 1500 Mark is
about what we think we can hold plus it
fits well in the conference venue you're
you're not bumping into the shoulders
and things but there's a lot of people
around too so anyways I just want to put
you on notice 1500 may be the number the
maximum number for the foreseeable
future doesn't mean that we won't make a
decision later to hey you know what I
think we've got this figured out we can
take on 300 more but for next year don't
anticipate growth in the conference this
will be the first time
ever that we have capped at the same
level as the year before on conference
registrations now this also needs our
Board of Trustees to weigh in on this
this is not an executive decision that's
being made right this moment but I want
you to be on notice that Saint Khan will
sell out quickly
in the future and so when we start
sending out those notices like hey it's
time to register you're probably going
to have a week
maybe because it's sold out in a month
this year which we've never seen that
kind of
um that kind of demand before anyways a
couple of other things costs for Saint
con will remain low in fact we are
considering lowering the cost of Saint
con for next year again the Board of
Trustees need to weigh in on this and
everything else because Saint Khan is
not about making money this conference
is a cost recovery con meaning that the
majority of the money that we bring in
pays for the venue pays for the food
pays for the free sodas pays for all the
mini Badges and all the other things
and so what we plan on at this point is
a break-even point this last year or
this year at about 1100 attendees
meaning that we needed to have 1100
attendees in the room or registered for
us to not have
that come out of my savings account or
somebody else's savings account which
has happened in years before or in years
past by the way but
um that we had to have 1100 but when we
sold from 1100 to 1500
now we have a little bit of extra money
in in that bank and so what we think is
if we're going to hit that 1500 Mark our
break even Mark will probably be
calculated at 1400 attendees ish meaning
that we could probably drop the price
back down because again we're not here
to make money on this conference at all
and we think it's very reasonable for
four days of content and coming out and
hanging out and networking and getting
about 50 000 mini Badges and and
everything else although the CL the cost
will likely follow any inflation curve
because we're all kind of worried and
seeing that kind of craziness and so
just be prepared I don't want to say
yeah well he said 250 in that
presentation so but now he wants 300
well if the dollar's worth less and I've
still got to buy many badges we're going
to want to have mini batches right
anyway so just understand that that's
our mission as well we're not here to
try and make money off of this
conference at all in fact in our we only
bank or put I mean this is full
disclosure like if you want to know
every single year for several years we
would only take in about five to ten
thousand dollars extra buffer each year
and it took us a really long time to
save up about seventy thousand dollars
to put in the bank before 2020 hit and
we did a virtual con for free and we
basically blew through that entire
budget or most of it and so we're just
kind of recouping Our intention just
again for full disclosure for those of
you that are interested in the
governance of the organization is to
keep about a hundred thousand dollar
Reserve meaning that we can
pre-pay for badge costs and other things
that have to happen before registration
opens and some of these other things
that also covers the administrative
costs for the organization okay we have
storage costs uh we have to file we have
to pay attorneys we have to pay CPAs and
and bookkeepers and other things like
this for some of the some of these
services to make this easier and so we
do have some of those administrative
accounts that's what those go to there's
full disclosure if you want more detail
well come ask me we are
which year
okay
I I can generalize it so to run this
this conference it'll end up costing the
Utah Saint organization probably
somewhere around three hundred and
twenty thousand dollars
and we took in approximately 348 000 in
registration and and other Revenue if
that's there there you go I mean that
I'm I'm throwing out generalized numbers
if you want specifics we are very
transparent in our finances as an
organization as well and you're welcome
to come up and say hey I want to see it
so that's fine okay bigger and broader
content we think that because of all the
buzz that surrounded Saint Khan and
other things we're becoming uh we're
we're a security conference that's on
the map now how many of you are from out
of state that are still here right okay
anyway and keep your hands up for just a
second I wanna I wanted to do this an
opening ceremonies and I forgot if
you're from Idaho put your hands down
because we kind of adopt the idahoans
right okay
but but still I I would be interested in
hearing in fact I could probably look in
the registration system there's so
little data that we collect because of
privacy reasons but we do want to know
some of that information so there's very
little data we have I'm going to go look
through I didn't have an opportunity to
see but it's becoming more noticed
saintcon is now talked about at Defcon
and at schmoocon and other these other
things so when we're talking about
registration selling out quickly in the
future there's a lot of external demand
that if they just knew what we were
doing here in Utah they're going to be
the ones competing for these tickets and
so one of the challenges that we'll
we'll talk about later or figure out is
how to make sure that our local
community has the first chance at
tickets Seth right here one of our
membership and the registrations are for
the Utah State organization has a
comment
14 of the people here are from out of
state according to the registration
system anyways
we're growing in reputation and
everything else I think that's a good
thing it's attracting some good content
like all of a sudden the the presenters
that were like what the heck is sync on
it I don't want to come present there
we're getting some really high quality
presenters and and people interested in
participating here so anyways that's one
of the good problems to have and so
we're going to continue to grow in that
in that area as well
this answers your question Dave here's
how to get involved if you are
interested interested in getting
involved in Saint Con in January we have
what we have what we call a call for
committee and this is where we seat a
committee a conference planning
committee uh that is responsible for all
aspects of the conference and its
functions
and so what we do currently is we kind
of do an attrition-based thing meaning
that if a committee member has not burnt
the candle at both ends enough yet
that they can continue to be in the role
and responsibility within in that
committee year over year until we either
kick them out or they're like I'm done
and the I'm done thing happens from time
to time and it's not never a negative
thing it's just some people are like I
need to take a break and a year off so
that happens in January and so what
happens generally is to the Utah Saint
list uh in the Saint con Discord and
other places you're going to hear about
open committee positions uh in in
January and we hope to have those seated
by the end of January because by the
time February and March open up we have
a committee Retreat where we get all
those folks together and we start
planning the conference we plan the
structure we plan the how are we going
to do these things or what are we going
to do in these areas and it kind of goes
through that process and then by the
time that's done as early as April and
May we have a call for contests
communities and events those are three
separate items but this is how you can
get involved in Saint on and probably
the most meaningful way if you don't
have six months of your life to give
away okay so six months of your life up
here
two or three months of your life right
maybe maybe three or four weeks of prep
time and life here and down here you
give a week of your life at the con kind
of thing just helping you understand the
levels here of commitment uh and we'll
sell it on it's like a timeshare we'll
get you we'll get you sold
um but contest community events these
are our staff members uh and they fall
underneath of one of the committee
members's roles and responsibilities and
these are the ones that are putting
together the app set community and the
RFID Community these are all again
volunteers that are coming and spending
three months of hey I gotta go out and
procure all this stuff and hey can you
help me find this and man wouldn't it be
cool if man that question is so
dangerous sometimes wouldn't it be cool
if
right and so call for contest
communities events happen sometime in
the April May time frame depending on
how ready we are for for it as a
committee call for presenters generally
opens in the May time frame and again I
put approximates here because it changes
based off of where we are in our
processes and things our deadline for
all of these things is generally we have
to know by the time registration opens
who's volunteering so that we can give
them the codes that they need to
register because one of the things that
costs us so much money every single year
is somebody will pay for the conference
and
they want to volunteer but they haven't
heard back from us yet whether they're
going to be a volunteer or a speaker or
you know or something else and then they
get awarded that and we have to refund
that our refund costs on our
registration transaction system is 15 a
ticket
so it costs us quite a bit of money when
we do that so our goal is to get all
that stuff done before we open up
registration in July so that helps you
with the time frame here anyways call
for presenters in May call for
volunteers happens in June this is the
if you want to come and just get
involved and just help in some general
area that's probably the easiest best
and and nicest way to get involved is
come volunteer for us and get a feel for
it and then maybe it gets you get it
kind of stirs the bug in you to come
back and be a staff member in one of the
communities or contests or something
else or I mean down here these are a
little bit more just
you know generalized things we have a
just call for great people one of the
one of the things that is is super
interesting about Saint Khan is most of
the people in what we would call a
leadership position at the conference
these aren't people that went through
some strong vetting process or anything
else these are literally the people that
came in and said hey I'll do that for
you and it just kind of morphed into
okay well can you do this too oh yeah
sure and we just suck people's lives
away that way I mean it's a real thing
but we're looking for great people if
you are interested and you want to to be
involved in the conference you don't
have to necessarily follow these
processes exactly in fact these
processes are kind of
arbitrary you know to some degree
volunteers not so much we we want
structure there because there's almost
200 of of you out there we also have a
call for diversity we think that we need
more diverse opinions and ideas inside
of our conference planning okay I think
that that's critical I think that's
critical in our just our industry in
general not just on planning committee
and everything else and we also need to
call for connected people if somebody
knows how to get a hold of Mark Rober
we have been trying to get that guy to
come keynote for us for years
and we just can't get the right contacts
we can't find hey here's how to get get
we think that Mark would come up here
and do an amazing job and probably have
content for all of his YouTube videos
for a month just experiencing what we do
at this conference right
but something like that
if anybody knows Mark let's let's read
do you know or
okay I am not necessary
I'm not necessarily advocating that we
spam him
uh and thinks
but we would love to have somebody with
that kind of Charisma that kind of
influence and other things come and talk
to us about the cool things that he's
doing and maybe use the opportunity to
help him understand there's this whole
other side of things other than building
stuff that that that is right up his
alley right anyways he's one of many
people that we're seeking but if you are
connected to people that are movers
shakers and and and would fit well into
a community our community is either
somebody that's running a community or a
keynote or something we need you we need
your con we need your connections okay
here's the dates for for syncon 2023
it'll be in October
that's kind of a meme is Bash ninja in
the room
he's oh I bet he's his next door for
sure right he keeps asking me like every
other day like do you have the dates yet
do you have the dates yet do you have
the dates yet I says no we don't have
them we're not going to publish them or
anything else anytime soon and so this
was kind of a meme for him it's like I
wanted to let him look like wait you
just told me you weren't going to
publish him and he has his reasons and
everything else but here's the reason
why we don't publish our dates at the
close of one con before the next one is
that until we have a conference planning
committee that we know is going to be
able to pull off the con
I'm not going to sign a 300 000 contract
uh when I only have a hundred thousand
dollars in the bank
for the next year and so when we have
that taken care of we generally sign and
contract in the uh March April time
frame uh with the venue here uh and and
start entering into some of the other
contracts that we have at about that
time so watch for our save the date
announcements sometime early next year
um after we get the next committee
formed okay then just a little side note
this is the add part of me if you are
interested in one of the most incredible
book series that I've ever
trust the awesome this is my favorite
book series and if you're a geek like me
you will love this in fact I highly
highly highly recommend that you listen
to this on Audible by the reader RC Bray
he does all of the voices
and this will Amaze you okay but here's
the caveat you have to promise me that
even though the book is sort of
interesting but not super interesting
for the first half of the first book
you have to promise that you will get to
the part
where you meet Skippy
if you can get to the part where you
meet Skippy you are going on a 13 book
Adventure
and it yes
yeah so here's another testimonial up
here I'm sure this is my favorite book
uh series of all time well not maybe of
all time I still I'm really akin to like
the Ready Player One original not that
too junk or whatever anyways I digress
if you're looking for a good audible
book to read to listen to on the way
home this one's the one okay
all right it's time now for Q a I'll
take any generalized questions I don't
promise to give you all of the detailed
answers how are we on time so we've got
about 10 to 15 minutes before they're
going to start tearing the walls down
and everything else but go ahead right
here
okay great question registration for
Saint con typically opens up sometime
between the 4th of July and the 15th of
July in that window but what we will do
is by the time we get to the point where
we're going to open up registration it
won't be ambiguous we will say it'll
open on X date and it'll be on our
website we don't try and hide it from
you like oh we're just going to pop it
up that's not how it happens
but good question so July first part of
July
I think that maybe it used to kind of
tie to it but the the reason why it
lands where it does uh in a lot of in a
lot of ways is a little bit traditional
and has to do with education meaning
that a lot of the Educators and folks
when you're starting up school
and it's August September man for I.T
folks in education it's a heavy lift to
get all those Chromebooks out and all
those other things and so we always
bumped it a little bit further so that
by the time Saint con would happen that
these guys aren't just completely
inundated with stuff and so that's where
the tradition came from but that's not
necessarily the main driver anymore this
is just it's become the that's the year
away in the part now and to move it to
something like March like there's no
there is no way that we could move it in
fact my wife's got a great story about
how we moved it to March one year
right and and we've heard that before
and so what we try and do is avoid the
fall break week when we can but
sometimes we're limited to hey this is
when the venue has the the options and
things so but a good question but that
is where that comes from and I don't
anticipate Ever Changing we need 12
months we need that break for a little
bit I need to not think about Saint con
for three or four months
and if we were to start planning
something in March or something there's
no way we would all die go ahead
okay so the question is what about venue
and is it going to be here for the
foreseeable future and we think yes
the Utah Valley Convention Center is the
right size for us it is the right
um I don't know it's got all of the
things that we've grown into and need
the only other option for us at this
point would be to move it to something
like the Salt Palace
and
as much as we would love to get it into
the Salt Lake Valley because that makes
it so our Keynotes and all these people
that we're bringing in from out of town
don't have to get off the plane and be
like
I gotta drive for an hour
because that happens
we would love to get to Salt Lake but I
I'm just not a huge fan of the Salt
Palace for I mean if we were had a 30
000 person event yeah let's fill the
place but uh I don't know it feels empty
to me when you have even a group this
large in that gigantic event and so the
only other option that we've had
available to us has been the Mountain
America Expo Center or what used to be
called South Town Expo and such but
we've been in so many events there and
the Acoustics in their Expo floor for
talks and other things is just awful and
so we we just don't think that that's a
viable option so for the foreseeable
future to answer your question directly
we plan on being here at the Utah Valley
Convention Center so where we apologize
profusely if that is inconvenient for
you but it the one of the other things
and if Danny's somehow in the room I
don't know if he is
this place they work with us so well
they they are they are so accommodating
they are so understanding about the
weirdness that we bring
the dumb weird things that we do uh and
everything else and so we couldn't be
more honored to have them as a partner I
mean we consider them a partner here we
do pay them money uh to to be here and
appropriately so like it's not free to
power what your guys are doing down in
home Labs like I don't know what you're
doing down there
but uh you know it's not free but a
great question we will be here uh for
the foreseeable future we know there's
at least one more Saint con to happen
I'm not trying to scare anybody but we
only plan one year in advance and so
don't anticipate that this is a 10-year
thing because there might be a point
where my candle at both ends is burnt
and you know somebody else is gonna have
to take it so if you're ready to take
that
come see me after I'll give you a Yoda
badge
and it's yours you know kind of thing
anyways was there another question or
comment go right here
okay great question so we talked about
the call for volunteers and everything
else how's that disseminated our website
and Twitter feed are our only two
official communication mechanisms and so
if you are subscribed to us on or you're
following us on Twitter you'll get those
alerts or you're going to need to visit
our website periodically and the call
for volunteers will be on the main front
page you won't miss it that's where it
happens
what's that Discord two like there's if
you're in the Saint Khan Discord you're
going to hear about it for sure
so anything else in the back red shirt
okay that's a great question and it's a
trade secret
actually no it's not it's really not
those LED filaments they're cool huh
right
when I saw that for the first time I
thought yeah I immediately thought
lightsaber mini badge there we go we got
it
um and so very honestly I got them off
AliExpress they were super cheap
which is why I was able to make 250 to
300 of them for you guys to all have
um and make sure you get the 3.3 volt
ones because they make other voltages
that we don't facilitate on this badge
so
but yeah they're they're pretty
inexpensive overall so build your I
expect to see one or two
non-troy non-jupiter created uh
lightsaber mini badges next year as a
result now don't steal the idea of the
flux capacitor badge that I'm going to
do with LED filaments next year okay
that one's coming don't steal that idea
I'm just throwing out there don't think
of it on your own and think oh that'd be
cool and I'm coming in and I'm like oh
mine sucks
so anyways anything else any other
questions about the conference
uh or our Direction go ahead
oh
yeah do you have an hour like
we don't so here's the thing and Danny
if you want to start moving walls you
can I like you can do it right in the
middle of this thing and it's not not a
big deal we're just going to start
opening up
um family night one of the things
whether it's cultural to us here in Utah
being very family oriented or anything
else
um or whether it's just I love
personally
seen a kid have that aha moment
to where you know you've just broken
their brain and you've really and
they've realized that I can do some I
can pick a lock I'm five years old and I
can pick a lock now my kids have all had
that aha experience and I've seen how
it's changed their lives and how it's
changed mine because when the the
principal from the school calls and says
hey your son's tried to pick all the
locks
on all the bicycles outside kind of
thing true story
um
true story but I love seeing that aha
moment and so it just makes sense uh the
family night event is actually
administered by the the saint Khan
widows uh which is a women's group uh
and if you're interested and if if you
are uh of that gender
there's a vibrant group of women that
love to share those types of things it's
a stem-based activity if you didn't
participate you missed out
um and such we apologize for those of
you that didn't make it in time to get
pre-reged and that didn't weren't able
to bring your kids because it filled up
like that and such but we we've got some
planning to do we know there's some
growing there's if there's growing pains
in Saint con there are growing pains
with uh the the kids night event and not
in a bad way but that's a hard Logistics
logistical thing to to pull off and so
thanks to those widows for doing that uh
and facilitating that event but it's
going to continue and that's kind of the
impetus I I love getting those kids
brains broken early on earlier on you
don't they don't we don't teach that
very much anymore so anything else last
question
who cut my hair
who cut my hair I I maybe I didn't hear
the last part of that uh but anyways I I
go to Great Clips just like everybody
else so
thank you everybody
and I'll transition to the other stage
and we'll close this thing out