welcome I hope you're having a great
Saint con experience already
um I'm just going to take two seconds
before I start into my presentation and
just say thank you for for coming and
trusting Saint Khan with your training
money or your I get to go to a one
conference a year opportunity and those
kinds of things we're so pleased to
bring a high value great content
conference to Utah and to our local
community and so we're we're super
pleased to be able to do it we're just
blown away by the response and how big
and crazy uh it it's getting so anyways
I am Troy Jessup I go by Jupiter as my
handle
um I've been doing cyber security and
infosec for longer than before it was
sexy and cool
um it's about 25 almost 30 years of some
sort of cyber security or I.T related
types of field which also kind of makes
me old I think so I'll wear glasses
every once in a while up here as well
but we're here to talk today about risk
acceptance and as I was talking to my
mom at the end of the back of the uh
room here just a little bit ago this is
going to be kind of like you're all
pretty culturally aware about Utah but
this is going to be like that general
conference talk that you fall asleep on
you know Sunday afternoon session kind
of thing because this isn't that really
super exciting kind of topic it's not
the thing that you're coming to Saint
Khan to really dig in and learn but it
is an important process that we all
could use some Refreshers uh maybe some
discussion and that there's some gaps
that we can maybe fill with some of the
information that we have here and so
that's my goal here is to see if I can
fill a gap that you might have or make
you think a little bit outside of the
box for risk acceptance but risk is kind
of a big deal so let's talk about risk
uh if unless you've been hiding under a
rock you know or whatever you should
have at least some understanding of what
risk is I I would assume that I'm mostly
talking to it and Security Professionals
in the room and so we do risk
um acceptance all day every day
365 days a year kind of thing and risk
is risk okay it's hard to really put a
solid definition on risk but it are the
things that make us vulnerable to some
sort of outside influence coming in and
making us have a bad day right it's a
the risk of a compromise would be one
example the risk of some sort of data
breach or data exfiltration or data
exposure or those kinds of things we're
all familiar with these types of risks
and our jobs or what we think are our
jobs as it and Security Professionals is
to understand that risk and put things
in place and and everything to try and
mitigate it as much as possible
and so
um risk acceptance up here I'm saying
risk is risk and it exists regardless of
anything we do does that resonate with
everybody whether we do something about
a risk that is either identified or not
identified does it keep it from existing
no it doesn't right that risk is going
to be there no matter what it's what we
do to either
remove the risk or mitigate the risk
that makes the difference and so it's
critical to have these types of
processes in place and there's five
major domains around risk acceptance if
this is super remedial for you just pay
attention or you know kind of drift off
for a minute surf the web what you're
going to do and then we'll come back to
some more important things but for the
refresher it is critical that when you
are in your role as an I.T or security
professional to identify risk that's one
of your primary jobs more so if you're a
security professional then if you're an
I.T professional but one could argue
there's a lot of overlap there right so
identifying it defining risk is a key
component to a risk acceptance process
as well and I'm going to dig into some
of these in a little bit more depth
later
but defining it documenting it how many
of you guys might raise of hands have a
process in place within your
organization where you have at least
some risk
that is inherent to your organization
documented somewhere on a piece of paper
maybe it's just an email that I sent up
to the CEO and said hey this is a bad
idea or whatever right okay and the
things I'm not seeing a lot of hands and
that's pretty typical and part of the
reason why I wanted to so badly to do
this talk this year even though it's a
kind of a boring mundane topic it's
super important because we need to be
doing a lot better job in Risk
definition and risk acceptance processes
so documentation not a lot of us are
doing that how about security controls
and other things that are preventing
risk how many of you guys have some
security control in place to mitigate
risk okay 99 of the hands should go up
because if you have a firewall hey
that's a pretty good security control
right to start with there's so many more
layers we can talk about here in a
little bit and then monitoring risk how
many of you guys have had an opportunity
to identify some risk talk about it
maybe come up with some processes to
mitigate some of the risk and go through
this whole process and then don't ever
revisit it again
you never go back and say Hey you know
we did that one thing to the server
three years ago
and opened up those ports that we
probably shouldn't have but it was
justified at the time is it still
Justified today kind of thing right and
here's the thing I'm already going
through half of the slides that I've got
prepared uh by just mumbling here so
this is going to be an interesting talk
this is also one of those talks that
um
I'll just set the the stage
I have I'm riddled with ADD types of
Tendencies so I'm going to be all over
the place I hope you can follow along
this particular slide right here I want
to talk about a risk acceptance process
in general okay defining and identifying
risk and we document the risk and we
explore compensating controls but this
is where the math comes in see if you
can follow me on the math risk minus
compensating controls everybody
understands what compensating controls
are right we'll cover them a little bit
more in a minute but risk minus
compensating controls equals mitigated
risk okay should be a pretty familiar
math equation for you and unmitigated
risk minus mitigated risk equals risk to
be accepted does that resonate with
everybody seems like a pretty reasonable
conclusion here I don't know I haven't
put a lot of numbers into the math
equation so there might be some errors
and issues in there but in essence that
should resonate
okay and so what what I want to do is
kind of take us through a couple of
these processes and I promise not to be
super long-winded with it but how do we
identify risk okay in fact I'm going to
come back here not let you cheat and I'm
going to pull the audience here
who has an example of how you are
identifying risk within your
organization anybody have a good
suggestion and there might be a Yoda
mini badge or two in it for you
go ahead
okay so Gap analysis against security
Frameworks okay great one over here
okay internal reporting so internal
information and things actually I'll
just have these this is my sweet wife by
the way
who has decided many well not many years
A couple of years ago that instead of
being a widow for six months out of the
Year while I work on Saint Khan she's
part of our volunteers and she does so
many awesome things she'll hand out some
Yoda mini badges
[Applause]
so okay so internal reporting anybody
else throw them out go ahead
vulnerability scanning penetration desk
great one suck
okay sock 2 compliance or Regulatory
Compliance of different types HIPAA
FERPA those kinds of things did anybody
else have any other unique ones back
here
data sensitivity take me through that
one just a little bit how does that
inform your risk
okay so okay in my mind I'm thinking
data sensitivity is a little bit
different in my mind than data
classification but I totally get your
your Jive here back in the back
okay user access and segregation of Duty
reviews what do we sometimes find in
those types of reviews
over privileging right role-based access
controls like hey somebody gave this
person administrative access to the the
active directory domain because they
needed to install a printer right that
never got undone way back in the back
foreign
process of review again or monitor that
risk great ones okay so all those are
all great suggestions these are just a
couple of the high level ones that I put
on the slide many of these have already
been talked about but one of the first
ones that I don't think we captured
really well uh from the audience was new
change or sorry new or change in
projects or initiatives how many of you
have had some CFO CTO CEO CEO
we blame all those three letter per
people right come down and say hey by
the way there's this cool new initiative
that we're going to start doing we are
going to put web servers on every phone
right or we're going to turn on SSH for
every single device because that makes
it secure right
how many of you guys have experienced
something like that does anybody want to
share one really quick there might be
another Yoda mini badge in it for you
that's okay oh go ahead
okay
expressions
right okay and so identifying maybe
vulnerability scam found out how did you
find or was that a summer initiative
from some higher up I mean I guess what
I'm trying to get to is it's inevitable
that you're going to be told hey we're
doing this new thing
and we we've got to we've got to do it
it's business case and and everything
else and you know darn good and well
that this is a bad idea right go ahead
things
okay so in case you didn't hear it in
the back he's talking about hey we've
been having problems with email and so
we're not going to require every single
phone to have a VPN back in the back one
more right behind sorry one more back
really loud
ooh collecting coveted immunization card
images and then storing them somewhere
on a organized hey that's a great story
for the vent
um event later okay in case I'm sorry
Segway if you're going to follow my ADD
for just a second that vent event is
going to be off the chain by the way if
you have these fun stories that happened
into a hypothetical organization at a
hypothetical time and you want to go
share with other people that can feel
your pain that's a great place to do
that but no thank you for sharing so
it's things like that we take in all
these new changes and new initiatives
and and things and it creates risk that
needs to be assessed and it's going to
take us an hour or two to get through
all this if I don't hurry vulnerability
scans we talked about that penetration
tests tabletop exercises I just had an
opportunity just recently to sit in on a
tabletop exercise where we involve the
FBI sisa and a couple of other
organizations uh the local state sciac
and others in a tabletop exercise for a
healthcare organization within the state
of Utah to go through their incident
response processes and things and guess
what there's fine meetings and there's
new information and risk that needs to
be looked at bug bounties we kind of
talked about internal threats and other
things so this is how we find risk we
can look at it all day and we can find
it right now we need to Define it a
little bit
I have this favorite quote that my
mentor one of my mentors my current boss
at the Utah education and Telehealth
Network says he says and this will
probably resonate probably with many of
you as technical people we often see the
problem and the solution at the same
time you guys ever have that now it
sounds like just a little cliche to say
it but I'll give some definition and say
we as technical people really have this
problem it is hard for us to focus on
or on problems and issues without
immediately jumping to we got to solve
this
here's the solution and it's not a well
thought out solution it's just a we are
here to solve problems it's built into
our I.T DNA right we are the problem
solver hey my mouse is broken well if
you try it I'm plugging it and plugging
it back in kind of things right where
that might not be the solution but we
offer those so defining risk as we're
going through these processes and
realizing that risk or we identify it
but defining what is that risk of having
to put vpns on every single phone for to
manage email right what are those risks
now we can talk about oh well there's
this and this and then here's how we
solve it or it's important to have time
between Define or identifying and trying
to solve the problem think it through
understand it really well because we
often so quickly move to trying to just
solve the problem rather than in putting
it into a process and this is where we
lose out on a repeatable process that we
can do for all of this okay and so let's
talk a little bit more about defining
risk before we get into some of this
other stuff
because I want to just give you some key
components that might be helpful and
fill a couple of the gaps that you might
have separate risk from current
compensating controls when you identify
something that creates risk within your
organization separate the compensating
controls from it first think of it as
this is a brand new risk I don't have a
firewall in place I don't have Network
segmentation and I don't have other
compensating controls what risk does
that create in in that mode and then
build those compensating controls that
currently exist back in and then see
where you're at because if you always
just assume that the compensating
controls that you have check all of
these boxes over here without reviewing
them first you're going to lead yourself
into that trap as it were of not having
all of your risk or or sorry not having
all of the compensating controls that
you think you have up against the risk
that you're trying to assess and and
Define okay real versus hypothetic
hypothetical risk definitions I added
this in here just to make sure that if
again if you're going through this
process often sometimes a hypothetical
discussion with you and a couple of your
other I.T or security colleagues is
great like you know what if the CEO did
decide to send out his email credentials
to everybody on the planet like what
would that be
but likelihood of something like that
happening I mean I don't know all your C
CEOs or anything but I mean probably low
maybe right but making sure that you
keep risk definition real don't get too
far into the weeds and that's really
what the next slide's about as well but
take the time to think risk through okay
because oftentimes if we just jump from
Define from identifying to trying to
solve the problem we're not thinking hey
you know what that SSH thing that we're
trying to shut up in fact you probably
this will resonate with many of you as
well we just jumped to a solution we
turn off SSH but then guess what happens
tomorrow
some other department comes and says hey
we can't run payroll today well why
can't we run payroll well somebody shut
off SSH on the such and such a thing
right because we didn't understand the
whole risk to the whole the whole thing
so take time think this through in most
cases risk isn't something you have to
just snap your fingers and deal with
immediately at least not if you're doing
it well and doing it right okay
um let's see
um don't just Define a single major risk
and focus on it alone that's the other
part of this this point that I wanted to
make is that it's important to think
outside the box understand the risk
holistically rather than just oh vpns
are bad
for phones or whatever and just focus
only on that piece because
it might not be so bad if there's other
components with it anyways moving on the
rabbit hole as I mentioned it's
impossible to fully Define and
understand every piece of every risk
that you have in an organization so
don't try
get close and that's where when we come
later on and we repeat and review and we
monitor that process there's nothing
keeping us from
reassessing this further down the road
let's mitigate the important risk now
and so work to just understand it is
probably the key phrase here okay next a
critical portion of X risk acceptance is
documenting this okay we had to raise
some of your hands before not a lot of
you have formal documentation processes
this is a key component for risk
acceptance okay because if you have all
of the risk
thought through and identified and it's
all up here in cerebrum and nothing gets
documented then how are you I mean I
know memory is fallible but how are you
keeping track of all of that
what happens is the most recent risk
becomes the thing on top and the thing
that we've learned about a month ago
kind of Falls by the wayside and we if
we're not documenting it and we're not
running it through a process we're going
to forget about it how many of you feel
like within your organization there's
some risk that we've hashed through
we've identified we've talked about it
we've done some things but it never made
it past that stage does anybody feel
like an organization might be there okay
a couple of hands right and that that
would be a very honest answer for many
of us unless you've got our well-defined
risk acceptance process and so
documenting risk this is crucial and all
and it feeds into a couple things here
in a minute
okay so once to find all risk needs to
be a set or all risk needs to be
assessed and should be done that's
probably me just writing weird things on
a slide uh last minute risk acceptance
forms and processes are a great template
how many of you all have a risk
acceptance
form within your organization that you
go through
to assess risk does anybody have those
okay a few hands okay today if you learn
nothing else from this presentation I
want you to take back and apply into
your culture
I need a risk acceptance form or
template okay and I'm going to show you
a couple uh or one of the ones that we
are hypothetically used uh by an
organization I may or may not work for
go ahead
okay that's a great question he's asking
about risk tolerance
versus risk acceptance and if you have a
tolerance for a certain level of risk
within an organization you know where do
you require a risk acceptance form
another process to track that to happen
can I defer the answer because I think
I'm going to answer it later and if not
re-ask the question and let's let's
cover it
um but yeah coming up with a process
that can be repeated even if it's not
the perfect process to begin with is is
a great place to start okay risk needs
to be well documented and undocumented
risk is accepted with or without
justification if if you've talked about
it and it's been one of those things
that oh man I told you guys that we were
going to get hacked because we left the
SSH Port open on that web server that
was exposed to the world
you know that's a lot of what it Coulda
because it wasn't documented it didn't
go through that full process so let's
keep going let's talk about a risk
acceptance form and give you kind of an
overview this one is very close to one
of the ones that we use at the Utah
education Telehealth Network okay it's
not an exact copy because there's some
more proprietary things
for our specific functions and our
specific processes that I wanted to keep
internal but in essence it's something
just like this we have a form that we
fill out often from the security office
standpoint and when we identify risk so
uh an employee name this is generally
meant for hey I want to do this new
project
I I need to understand what kind of
security ramifications and other things
come from this and we ask the requester
to fill out some information most of the
time unfortunately as the security
officers like I said they're filling
this out but let's talk about a couple
of things general information which we
don't care about which is pretty
self-explanatory but the first paragraph
thing that they can start typing into
this form is describe the risk requiring
acceptance okay risk definition risk
identification this is them or us as
Security Professionals saying Hey listen
Bob from HR wants me to leave SSH open
on the Wayne web server
we keep using that as a great example
because I've had that happen before
because we need to SCP those files back
and forth we need to do it securely and
things so describe that risk and then
describe the business justification for
the accept the risk acceptance request
right it seems pretty straightforward
why it doesn't need to be this way well
HR needs to send payroll off to the
third party to do whatever kind of thing
right and then provide a list of
organization data and services that are
potentially at risk by this request okay
you're allowing them to say well let's
see we're going to be sending our
banking information across this it's
going to be you know personal
information probably some social
security numbers and some other things
and so it allows them to identify and
and and tell you what some of that data
is some of the times it's us you know
hey we're going to be leaving one of our
front door web servers open to another
Vector of attack that probably shouldn't
exist anyways let's move on so this is
like this either
hey you know that is a great question
and so the answer to that is you could
um what I would say is in fact so for
those of you and for the recording the
question was by documenting a risk does
that create more liability that's
probably the better like for you as an
organization because now it's documented
you knew about it kind of thing right
and how does that impact cyber security
insurance and all those other things
this is a wonderful question I've got
what I think is an okay answer did you
have something to add to it
now
right
I didn't even know about it
yeah
and so David do your to your question
specifically I think that there could be
some interpretation of increased
liability if it's something is
documented and not dealt with meaning if
you're just sitting back as a security
or I.T professional and you're just
churning out risk of sex acceptance
documents
and all it is is definition or
identification definition and kind of
understanding what the risk is and then
it just goes into a box somewhere yeah
you you could create some more liability
for yourselves because this this is part
of that important process and maybe I
mean I might be just kind of supposing a
little bit here but maybe that's the
fear or the risk that we're trying to
avoid when I said hey who documents
their risks and not a lot of hands go up
because if I don't document it then I
can claim ignorance later or maybe
anything else but up here to your point
just like a couple of slides ago whether
you identify it or not it exists
and it's better for you to go through
the process but to avoid the problems of
liability and other things you've got to
carry that process to the end of the row
somebody needs to know about it and
we're going to talk about it here in
fact it's probably one of the next
slides here once you have it
in fact let me defer and some of this is
going to be answered in a couple of
slides here but you've got to come up
with compensating controls to start
mitigating that risk right because if we
just document it and throw it in the bin
document and throw on the bin maybe we
send it as an email up to the C the CTO
or to you know some other executive like
hey found another risk found another
risk but there's no compensating
controls being built and developed to
mitigate that risk then yeah there's
some liability that can come as a result
but I want you to understand in the
security industry compensating controls
are the primary way that we reduce risk
the compensating control is the key term
there and this is anything we put in
place to mitigate the risk or to
mitigate the risk that we create that
needs to be accepted a couple of real
quick examples in our web server SSH
Port thing would be that if we have to
have that open a compensating control
could be something as simple as we put
an access list on the system to only
allow SSH to talk between two approved
hosts that would be a compensating
control right might not be the best
control or the most appropriate control
for that environment but that's a
compensating control it could also just
be that we have now a policy that we are
going to review the SSH logs on an
hourly basis on our web server that's a
compensating control now one has a lot
more likelihood of being successful than
the other one right
but all of those are compensating
controls this is how we mitigate risk as
we Cur we understand it and we put a
control in place to mitigate it
sometimes we can mitigate it to zero
oftentimes we leave a little bit of that
risk on the table and remember the
formula up here
unmanaged or unmitigated risk minus
security controls equals accepted risk
at that point and so there is always
going to be a business decision that
needs to be made on how much risk is
tolerated within the organization and
I'm still going to answer the other half
of that question here let's talk about
how we control risk in this risk
acceptance document here okay this is
pretty simplistic this is part of the
document that I pulled some things out
of but you're welcome to take a photo
it'll be in the slides and other things
but what is your proposed strategy for
mitigating risk okay this is just
continuation so they've identified the
risk they've talked about and they've
defined it and what the impact on
organization data and resources well
what is the requester's proposal for
mitigating this and so you're
automatically putting that person in
that mindset okay you as the user
need to start thinking about what are
the mitigating controls what's the limit
of
that you can see that is the right
approach for this so that it helps
inform the security review later okay
provide a summary of the security
controls that will be implemented by the
request or okay so hey I need to install
VPN on every single phone okay
we're we're going to
well it's probably a bad example because
everybody thinks that putting vpns on
phones is a good thing right but hey we
need secure email and so the mitigating
control might be hey we are going to
implement VPN on everybody's phone maybe
that's the better way to
to
articulate that so
anyway it's lost my train of thought now
I'm I've gone too many different places
bottom line here is we we go through a
process of understanding and developing
those security controls and
understanding them go ahead
foreign
not yet
you're jumping ahead again
oh that's great let me in fact I'm going
to go through a little bit quicker here
because there is a review process okay
and so once you have the requesters
information and some of these other
things and again this process might not
work 100 for you you might have to come
up with a different approach this one's
working pretty well for us but once
defined and documented and we understand
the impact and the security controls
that are going to be there you need to
be able to convey risk clearly for
acceptance okay and so that kind of
leads to this next part of the form
section two
where we go through a review process and
so this one
gives us a level of risk where the
security department or some other
authoritative individual that has the
responsibility for this role starts
reading through meeting with making
phone calls exchanging emails and
understanding this whole scope we go
through that whole process again and
then these are the likely outcomes that
we've identified within our organization
which is
the risk that you're talking about is
acceptable for us
and it's acceptable with maybe a reduced
scope or it's you know hey everything's
fine we're we're not going to have to do
much this is this is great or acceptable
for a temporary period while other
controls are improved meaning like hey
we've got to go back and we've got to
upgrade firewalls now and we've got to
do all this stuff but we'll put in this
ACL kind of as a stop Gap measure and
we'll fix these kinds of problems but
there's a an ongoing component to it or
fully acceptable without qualification
meaning that at this point there's it
there's
no there's nothing that needs to be done
or there's a not acceptable meaning that
the residual risk is greater than the
potential business benefit and the risk
acceptance is just flat out denied we're
not going to allow this to happen stamp
right
or something that often happens for us
is that and if I might jump back and say
this is the security director and the
security department within our
organization's approval process this is
me and my role I go through this and I
look at this and there's some things
that I as the security director can say
yeah we're good this is compensated for
we've got good monitoring and management
for this thing that you're trying to do
but there's oftentimes a new initiative
those of you that are are part of the
um education world that understand like
cbrs these are really cool terms anybody
know what cprs is okay only a few of you
it's not going to translate well but new
initiatives that require all kinds of
new Security review and processes I'll
tell you what when it happens I kick
that thing up to the CTO I'm not the one
that's responsible for saying hey this
entire new Initiative for our
organization and for our business
sits on me and so there is a process to
kind of Kick It Up The Chain does that
make sense and then I'll just kind of
moving move down here I want to talk
just briefly about accepting risk and
who right because I kind of alluded it
to it and maybe this is part of a
discussion that we can have with the
audience here but what is ex what are
the acceptable levels of risk to be
accepted at the following levels what
risk should the user be able to accept
on their own without having to go up for
more approval is there any
does anybody have any opinions on that
so at what point does I mean as you
identify a risk
there's some things that the user might
be able to say yeah you know hey it's
okay I'm going to type my password into
that thing fishing or otherwise go ahead
okay so he's saying if they're the
user's the expert in the area or in
charge of their domain right that that
would make sense and so what I see in
this case is a lot of my personal use
not business use and other things I'm
the one that gets to decide what's
acceptable like if I'm going to go put
my personal email credentials into some
weird form because I want to download a
Minecraft Plugin or something that's my
risk to accept right but is that
appropriate for a business related
account on other things right helping to
understand the foundation of what I'm
asking here and if we take this
discussion to the end of the row this is
a lot of splitting of hairs and things
in here but what I want you to kind of
get from this is that there are
appropriate risks that can be accepted
at these different levels
but you have to Define in your
organization and that's kind of to bring
this kind of into a conclusion you've
got to figure out within your
organization where your risk tolerance
is to your point like what is the
accepted tolerance of risk we're a low
tolerance we we have high security we
don't allow people to even change or we
don't even allow people to not change
their password every 90 days and we've
forced two-factor authentication we do
all of the things
with low tolerance right or we have high
tolerance maybe not to throw education
folks under the bus but in in an
education environment when you've got
thousands of students in a school
district and they all need access to
their Chromebooks and everything else
I'll tell you what the username and
password that you're using and sending
out to all those students is not a super
complex one it has to be something that
you can hey student here's your password
again for the fourth time this week
right
kinds of things go ahead
okay and so that's a great question the
question was what example in our
organization do we allow a user to
accept the risk on their own and the
answer is in our organization there
isn't a lot there's almost zero meaning
I I wanted to bring this up in case
somehow it was relevant to some
organization or for your own personal
thing but for our organization it's it's
not acceptable for user to say hey you
know what I'm going to do this funky
thing with my credential
now does it stop them from doing that it
absolutely does not this is we're
fishing and and fishing and some of
these other things occur right this is
the vulnerability at this user making
their decision at their level to accept
some risk okay and sometimes it's not
really clearly defined for them they
don't know that they're doing this type
of thing and so it's important for us as
it and Security Professionals to help
them recognize these things but it's the
same thing with I.T staff how many of
you guys feel like you would Pat I mean
all of you I.T and and security staff in
here how many of you would pass 100
every single time any phishing attack
that comes in and drops into your email
box or onto your phone as a text or
anything else anybody feel confident to
say yeah I'm 100 percent
okay right thank you for not raising
your hands because that's probably an
accurate representation we have our own
vulnerabilities even at our level of
accepting some risks sometimes like oh
you know what I it's just easier for me
to give admin to the Bob over here so we
can install that printer and just get
off my back
and in these domain admin credentials to
do that right and so on and so forth and
so there's different levels the
appropriateness is not definable by me
for you and your organization and that's
the key component here so what I've done
here is I've filled in a couple of gaps
and I said you need a risk acceptance
process and some of that is ubiquitous
meaning that the math in the free in the
first slides doesn't change you know
accepted risk is a result of all these
other components and compensating
controls and the whole thing all melted
together but risk tolerance as to your
point earlier and Other Things become
part of how you have to Define that
within your own organization and so the
examples that I put up here of our risk
acceptance process template might be
valid and appropriate for something like
you're doing but it might not even touch
how you need to be doing those types of
things my recommendations are that you
spend the time
to go through and better your security
situation by developing something if you
don't have a key piece of this within
your organization if you do great in
identifying and defining but not
documenting start with documenting and
then work your way down the list go
ahead one more time
yes
hi
so yeah so for those of you in the back
that might not and let me
ask the question back just to make sure
I got it so that in the in the position
of you you have security folks that are
going out and they're identifying risks
and other things but if they assess it
as low
as low risk can they just accept it and
not have to go through the documentation
process
okay document it within a ticket gotcha
to kick it up or accept it or reject it
right
right so what I would call that kind of
approach is in an environment where you
need to be a little bit more Nimble and
there's good well-established boundaries
on yes and I one of our I.T security
people can say yes or no to this type of
scenario and that those are understood
then that's an appropriate approach
meaning let's document a ticket Bob
asked for domain admin credentials and I
said no
right it doesn't need to go through a
whole hey should we give it to him and
what's the risk and everything else some
of those are going to be obvious right
and so what I would say is that that
would be risk acceptance light having a
streamlined process for the easy to
derive things is going to be more
beneficial it's going to save you a lot
of time but those need to have really
clearly defined boundaries and that's
the key component to that is you need to
understand this is where I can't approve
things versus where I can and really
understanding that well
foreign
anything above like a low level requires
that process to be completed and that's
an appropriate approach and so where
those lows and the mediums and the highs
for you and your organization are going
to be different from you and yours and
so you've got to go figure those things
out but again my plea and my
recommendation is figure out where you
are in the risk acceptance process and
finish developing that and building it
out so you've got better opportunity to
see it understand it communicate it up
to higher ups and get them to accept it
if they need to be the ones to accept it
and what It ultimately helps you do in
the end is keep things inventoried and
understood and get the right people
accepting that risk because some of it
is accepted at your level here or here
depending on where you are but some of
it should be the CEO saying you know
what we're not going to do this or we
are going to do this because I'm making
that decision and then it's not on your
shoulders okay this is that you get to
lift that burden off your shoulders you
can be in that I Told You So mode of Hey
listen I sent you an email about this
last month before we got compromised
what I would hope you would do is not
take that kind of approach as much as
make sure that it's not on you because
you didn't document it and you didn't
know about it or that you didn't follow
it to the end of the road okay so that's
really it I've got some other slides and
other things but
to to go through more probably burn you
out any questions that I haven't
answered that anybody has about risk
acceptance process he's got a million of
them up here before I take his anybody
else first going once twice hey go ahead
then
we have this uh yeah
okay
okay so before you keep going I'm going
to kind of for the back of the room
that's hard to hear so you've got
processes in place and things and you
give department heads some ability to
accept risk and kind of make some of
these decisions and things but you
rarely take things to like an executive
like a CEO or whatever because
because of lack of high confidence in an
appropriate judgment level for them it's
Greek it's SS SWAT or web what kind of
right okay and so is was there a
question that I missed or
okay so the question is are we missing
something there and what I would say is
um maybe maybe not I mean if you've got
a good structure where you've got
department heads that know what their
roles are and data stewards for data
classification that know what their
roles are and and the approvals for
Access rights and all these other things
are well built out then it sounds like
you've probably got a really good
environment for risk acceptance and
monitoring and things and yeah you don't
necessarily have to take everything to
the CEO of an organization in fact it's
very rare in our organization that I'm
talking to our chief executive about
these things almost every single thing
that we do within uetn if I don't feel
comfortable making the call and and
that's kind of a subjective thing I feel
comfortable in making a lot of calls and
I've got the respect within my
organization that when I say no
that they're like okay I get it and
understand but sometimes yeah I'll have
to kick it up to the CTO and that's
about as high as it gets in our
organization and that seems appropriate
you need somebody sometimes to say no
you guys can't do that because they're
not listening to me or you know I'm
trying to have that discussion back and
forth and so use it to your advantage uh
where you need to like hey if I need to
go up to the chief executive up here and
talk about this and maybe that's what
we'll have to do and then at that point
the chief executive might side with the
person that you're having odds with and
then it's a business decision it's like
yes we got to do this I told Bob over
here that we got to have this system up
and it's got to be up tonight and and
you're like well listen we don't have a
firewall to put in front of the thing
you know like there's some risk here and
if it's a business decision then it's a
business decision
right I mean again you got it whether he
says whether the requests come from the
CEO or not and how it all comes it
creates politics which we love there's a
political layer
in the OSI model that's probably
resonates with some of you right we all
know that there's the political layer
and it does exist okay one more question
Michael or actually I'll come back to
YouTube but go ahead
allow yourself to do
it
wasn't that a great keynote this morning
yeah let me let me illustrate this for a
lot of you technical people in the room
local admin
okay how many of you are all just
cringing right now by me saying that
right this is the perfect example of you
allowing a user
to make risk judgments of their own
accord
because you've allowed them local admin
on their machine right and it's the bane
of our existence those of us especially
those of us who work in education where
every single day there's a new teacher
that needs a new thing installed on
their computer to do things and it's
just easier to say here here's local
admin get out of my hair I do not want
to come over there for the fourth time
this week and install your software for
you uh kind of thing but that's that's
an example of kind of what we're talking
about but you also asked a different
question or a different component there
that I want to answer and say user
education training and other things
within your organization we saw that
Jason did an incredible job I was super
thrilled with his keynote this morning
where he's talking about having to
understand and and the the social
components and and getting good training
snow did also a good example of
understanding that 0.5 percent of our
time as I.T and Security Professionals
actually goes to training our employees
what they should be doing and so there
is risk in us not doing what we're
supposed to do did I cover what you were
asking like is that a good response I
might come back to you if you have
another minute already come up
afterwards and I'll because I might have
forgotten part of your question in the
back last question
oh
that is a great question and I wish I
just had an oh yeah you just do it like
this but that adds a whole new dimension
that many of us are probably facing
already meaning that what I've presented
up here is very simplistic compared to
now I've got multiple clouds that I'm
living in and what are they doing to
protect my data and it's a third party
that we've contracted for for our HR
System so PeopleSoft has all of our data
and and all these different things
absolutely that complicates things and
every time that you are putting so the
best answer I have for you right now
quickly and on the spot is anytime that
you are handing off the responsibility
of your I.T and your infrastructure to
somebody else whether that's just to a
cloud and you still admin it or whether
that's to a third party that's just
going to handle it that should always
have a risk acceptance process that
accompanies that decision
should never do something like that
without a risk acceptance process like
there is risk that hey that data could
be compromised from the PeopleSoft side
throwing people soft under the bus not
on purpose but that's one that comes to
mind
right but they get compromised and our
data is gone like we have nothing we can
do about that and there's some risk
there that needs to be understood and
accepted uh in doing some of those types
of things now sometimes it makes it a
whole lot easier and it's a cost
decision and all those things Cloud it
and make it complicated but yes
I'll just sneaky in go ahead
they accept something
right
did you guys all hear that okay or do I
need to repeat it
so what he's saying is Well now I'm
almost forgot forgotten it was so
eloquently put but that
you when you contract with those folks
and part of that risk acceptance process
should be that they're contractually
obligated to be liable for their storage
of that data and everything else but
what he's also saying is it's a very
apropos and appropriate is that even if
you said 100 of the liability is yours
that's never going to be true the
reputation the you know the fact that
your data is compromised and other
things will never be a zero liability to
you and so again there is some risk
there you're hoping that people's often
those folks are doing a really good job
uh doing things let me throw out one
other tidbit I want you to write this
one down if you're in this situation
okay if you're thinking about bringing
on a third party for a service or a
software as a service and those types of
things there is a really cool form that
was developed in higher education that
you can easily translate over into
commercial if that's the space that
you're in I know we still have a lot of
Educators and education in here but
write down the term heck that HEC V8
okay and search that on Google that is
probably one of the best refined
checklist item things that you should be
reviewing for every third party
engagement now not all that's going to
translate perfectly for you in all
situations but it's a great framework to
work off of if you're doing that it's
not necessarily part of risk acceptance
as much as it's risk definition
and kind of understanding what that
really means and what should be taken
care of to make that work so anyways
I'll end it there
um because we're at 4 30 and I never
thought I'd even go this long but it's
my pleasure to have you here and thank
you for coming and joining us we'll see
you either downstairs in a little bit if
you want to come trade a Yoda or a badge
for a Yoda badge or I might have some
other ones in my pockets that I can hand
out for the mini badges you're welcome
to come see me I'll be down at the badge
Life Community Booth probably for the
next half hour 45 minutes at least but
thank you and have an awesome con
[Applause]