thanks for everyone
coming by
today we're going to talk a little bit
about not shooting ourself in our feet
which is something that we in
information security tend to do more
often than we like
first off my name is Tyler Strickland
I'm a manager of one of the managing
managers on the detection engineering
team at Ray Canary I've been there for
just over a year a great company we get
to work with some really cool folks
um fun fact I've now lived in Provo four
times in my life I can't escape the
place where it can't escape me I'm not
quite sure which
um but it's good to be back it's been 15
years now
and before we dive into the content I
have a warning for you all
some of this may trigger flashbacks
of experiences you may have experienced
some of it may also trigger feelings of
guilt
because none of us are perfect in some
of these areas
so just to be warned you know you may
need to have some of your heart
medication nearby
it's a hard subject
so let's talk about a story so
in a past life I managed vulnerability
management
and for any of you that's managed
vulnerability management you know that
that it can be sometimes a knock down
drag out fight to try to protect an
organization
and when I joined that organization
there really wasn't much of a
vulnerability Management program
effectively we were asking the system
administrators to log into our
vulnerability management tool find the
vulnerabilities they needed to fix and
go fix them
and you can imagine that that probably
didn't work out so well and it didn't no
one ever fixed anything and over the
course of the next several years we
spend a lot of time thinking and working
toward trying to build a vulnerability
Management program that actually worked
within the organization that we were
operating and in the end we did we were
fixing 80 90 of vulnerabilities within
our SLA and some of the foundations of
how we built that program and other
aspects of our information security
program or what kind of drove me to look
into
this topic or think a lot about this
topic
So today we're going to talk a bit about
some symptoms of relationship issues
between information security and the
rest of the organization
we're going to talk about a root cause
for that or something that might be
leading to some of these symptoms and
then we'll talk about some treatments
some things that we can do to make
things a little bit better than they are
today
so first off we're going to talk about
symptoms that we see in our partners
next we'll come back and talk about
symptoms we see in ourselves
it really does feel sometimes like other
teams do Scurry away when infoset comes
to call right we're you know because we
bring that pen tester for we bring that
list of vulnerabilities we bring that
big project that uh perhaps is going to
take away from them delivering on one of
their key deliverables uh or we're
asking them to make a big change to that
major Endeavor that is going to make or
break the their quarterly goals
so
let's talk about some symptoms here
number one deprioritization
sometimes it feels like
anything that we ask of other teams just
goes really slowly
right
either some other project is more
important or their resources are
prioritized elsewhere
um we just can't get the support we need
in the time we need it oh you want to
fix that vulnerability in a month give
me three right
sometimes things just don't flow the way
that we hope or expect them to or other
things that we look at as not being
critical to the business or definitely
not security get prioritized but dark
mode have to have dark mode at the same
time we're trying to get them to fix the
SQL injection that could get you hacked
any minute now right
number two avoidance
this is the part where they kind of
maybe run away from us or they forget to
call us right so there's this in major
project that's happening you know the
this thing that's going to drive the
business going forward and we hear about
it six months in after it's already been
designed the requirements are are
decided upon we have a date we've
already made the press release and oh
infosec by the way
should probably know about this
but don't change anything please don't
change anything because that's going to
impact our delivery date
they maybe leave us out of important
discussions about systems to buy or
decisions to make about how to design
certain aspects of the system
I've even seen cases where
other teams within the organization have
had tried to hire their own security
people so they didn't have to work with
us
right so the infrastructure security
liaison or administrator right so then
if you know if you want to talk to them
no you go to that security person they
have to you know somehow sit between you
and The Business
we don't find about problems till they
are a big problem they've exploded
instead of being something we can fix in
five minutes they take five weeks or
five months right
symptom number three
Blissful ignorance
maybe they just don't care they're not
interested in learning about information
security or how it impacts their job or
denial that their this for whatever
they're doing has any security
implications
but I need to put that Dev server on the
internet in order to work with our
partner I have to it's the only way to
do it and it has to be done yesterday
which is why it's already up there and
you're just now finding out about it
even though it has RDP exposed to the
internet and we're getting attacked left
and right
that anyone have that experience
what do you mean I shouldn't click on
every link in every email that's my job
I've heard that right it is my job to
open every attachment and click on every
link
and you know what
and sometimes it may be actually uh
that terrifies Us in information
security
and symptom number four outright
hostility
maybe they're not just slowing down
security initiatives but they're
actively working against them
we tell them what best practice is and
they say they don't care they want
nothing to do with best practice because
in their mind they just have to get that
product delivered
you do your job I'll do mine I even saw
one occasion where a an executive level
person told their team do not talk to
information security
only managers only senior leadership
gets to talk to information security
because they're getting in our way
they're getting on our turf
obviously that does not lead to good
security outcomes uh in fact
it often leads to things like attrition
it leads to companies having major
security issues down the road
if things have devolved to outright
hostility
there are big problems that are
happening
now let's talk about some symptoms that
we see within the information security
team itself
first off then US versus them mentality
and I want to say this before I dive
into these I'm as guilty as most of
these as as probably anyone is we've all
done it we've all experienced some of
these symptoms
we need to be honest about that with
ourselves
sometimes we feel like we're better than
those teams are working with I know
Windows Administration better than the
windows administrators
and you know what there's some what at
tiny little aspects of it where I may
but I definitely can't do their job
yeah
we've we view it as a roadblock
bonus points out there for anyone who's
heard of the bofh
a
I encourage you to do some Googling and
read some really hilarious stories from
the early days of the pre-internet
um the bastard operator from hell is
about the well is that the bastard
operator administrator from hell but we
view I.T as being a whole bunch of
people that are bad at their jobs and
they're getting in the way of security
we start talking about pepcac
and losers
and all of that builds up walls and
barriers between us and those teams
I spent some time in the Navy I was an
Electronics technician
my job was to fix the electronic
equipment that other teams use we
weren't users we didn't use most of the
things that we worked on we had to make
sure it was functional and fix it when
it broke and there was a tendency among
a lot of these Electronics technicians
when the see the uh there's a position
in the Navy called an operations
specialist they're the ones who
operate Radars right we would fix the
radar they would operate it and they
would have a problem with it and they'd
call us and say it's broken we come up
there and like ah you have this switch
wrong they've flipped we'd flip the
switch and treat them like an idiot
and you know what the next time it broke
they didn't call us
or when something was really broken they
definitely didn't call us because we're
just going to blame it on them
that's not how you build relationships
threatening to have them fired for
things it doesn't help either
but it happens happens a lot
how many of you have seen
when you know someone proposing that
someone fails three phishing tests and
they should have some sort of a penalty
like an official on the record penalty
that doesn't help
they're going to be scared they're going
to be skittish with anything that
information is security is involved with
next Bubbles and walls we kind of wall
ourselves off from the organization
sometimes
we are perhaps afraid that they'll get
in the way of what we're doing
um we may not consider the impact of our
actions of our projects our proposals
our requirements on those teams
we throw our requests really demands
over the wall and say hey this is what
you have to do figure it out
you see that I'll often often in
vulnerability Management Programs right
you run the scan you come up with a list
of 70 000 vulnerabilities you've export
it to excel
you hand it to them and say fix them
go you have a month
we'll scan it again in a month you
haven't fixed them well you're in
trouble
it happens far more frequently than most
of us like to admit
another one you can't go live without
this particular control
you know security architecture there you
know there's probably a few security
architects in the room
we want to have you know apt level
protection a lot of these applications
and so we'll sometimes block
applications from going live without
particular controls or things in place
and at the same time across the table
they're they're kind of quaking in their
boots saying but but I have to deliver
tomorrow or next week
no I'm not arguing that they're in the
right but I'm also not arguing that that
we are there there's a there are some
problems underlying the cover under the
covers there
next smoke and mirrors
who here has used fud to drive Security
Programs
I think most of us have to some degree
or another right fear and certainty and
doubt are something that that get used
for and against us all the time
we use it in our trainees
we use it in meetings to get our way
we also sometimes try to obscure what
we're doing
being afraid that they're going to get
in the way of a particular security
program right
oh but but if I install that agent on
there and tell them really what that
agent's going to do because you know
most EDR tools are actually remote
access Trojans right
if we tell them what's on that agent can
actually do they'll actually stop it
they'll get in our way
or my favorite the apts are coming
and I I hope that little QP chart here
doesn't cause trauma in anyone
but sometimes we do act like that as
what's happening
you know we we give them metrics that
say
we stopped 50 000 attacks yesterday
because our firewall blocked 50 000
packets
and then finally
but mommy said so or in in our terms
usually but the CEO said so or the board
said so
we feel like the only way that we can
get anything done is through coercion
we're forcing them right
um
I was at uh a company that had that was
a close partner with another company
that had a breach a big company I won't
say the name uh really really big health
or company and we were we worked very
closely with them and so our mandate was
to get it right
insecurity and you know what
that's the starting point for some
discussions but it can't be the ending
point
so
some of you might argue
that these things what I'm calling
symptoms are actually causes right these
things that we do are causing those
symptoms either listed for our partners
and you know what you're probably right
they are causes
but they're not
the root cause for a lot of this
I want to propose a root cause that
perhaps underlies some of if not much of
the these issues that we experience
because most of these are in the end
self-inflicted wounds
so to talk about that root cause I want
to set some fundamental truths here
first off most of the people we're
working with within it
and within the business
are good people
trying to do their jobs
they're not hacking the company there
are some that are you know most of us
have dealt with Insider threats that
really are trying to hack the company
from the inside
I've had to deal with those they're not
fun they're the least favorite part of
my job but most of them are
fundamentally good people trying to do
their job and some of them are really
good at it and some of them are not as
good at it just like in information
security we're fundamentally generally
good people not all of us there's some
been some ceases that went a little bit
off the wire if you read some of these
news stories over the years
but most of us are good people trying to
do good things to protect our
organization
similarly some of us are really smart
and some of us are not so smart some of
us are really good at our job some of us
are not as good at our job right
we're all normal good people trying to
do good things
unfortunately
our actions don't always reflect that
good intent some of the things we do so
like those symptoms we just walk through
maybe may not reflect the intent of what
we're trying to do right we're trying to
protect an organization
we're starting to talk about pepcac
doesn't necessarily reflect that intent
I would posit that one of the reasons we
behave the we the way we do
is that we are at War and we feel like
it
our organizations really are under siege
from invisible attackers
that can attack from anywhere at any
time from any angle
it can be a USB dropped in the parking
lot an exploit against a website an
email that gets sent in
it can be physical attacks though I'd
argue those probably happen less than
most of the rest of these
um
attacks can really come from anywhere we
are truly Under Siege and what that
means is
we view ourselves in some way shape or
form as soldiers right we're or security
guards or whatever metaphor you want to
use where they're protecting the
organization in sometimes very literal
physical ways right if we're pulling an
all-nighter trying to respond to
particular vulnerability right we are
putting our body right there trying to
get that that vulnerability addressed
and so we align with this Mission and we
most of us are very deeply committed to
that mission it hurts us
when we're not able to protect our
organization it hurts us when someone
clicks on that email
when someone gets on the phone with that
pen tester to very kindly help them
install malware onto their system that
hurts us at our core
because of this we tend to be very
distrustful distrustful by Nature right
of most of the people in the company buy
their job are trained to be trusting and
to work with each other and be really
nice and we're telling them don't trust
anyone
and that's hard to take for someone for
some people
we also have this constant sense of
urgency everything has to be done right
now
or the attackers are going to get us the
apts are coming now
sometimes these things really do need to
be done right now there's no question
about that
but in our work almost everything has
that sense of urgency to it
and we come to this to build this
mindset where those who do not cooperate
with us
who do not have the same commitment to
the mission that we do
are our enemies
if you're not with us you're against us
All is fair and Love and War right we
we kind of use that mission to build up
that US versus them mentality
and so because of that view there are
things that we do that will push away
our partners
so I'm going to take
you know we talked about symptoms
earlier so let's take it to a higher
level
these people that should be our allies
often end up our enemies
and here are some reasons why that
happens
at a fundamental level we tend to do
some basic things we run a rough shot
over our obstacles focus on the mission
more than the people
we don't always follow our own advice
how many of you have said you have to go
through this security assessment process
before your website goes live and then
turned around and sent your own
information security website live
without going through that process
I think a lot of us have
um
sometimes or even kind of jerks about
things right
we we're not that nice sometimes
so what are some of the things that that
fall along these lines number one
poor communication
we don't necessarily share our needs our
plans our goals with with those Partners
in I.T or in the business they don't
understand what we're trying to do or
why we're trying to do it
along the same lines
we don't care or try to understand what
they're trying to do or why they're
trying to do it
going back to the dark mode example
they may be doing it just because it
looks cool
they may be doing it because one of
their biggest customers said if you
don't get dark mode I'm dropping you
I hope not
that's kind of crazy but things along
those lines happen all the time and if
we don't understand
why they're doing what they do
we can ask them to do some things that
simply don't make sense from their
perspective
we've got to talk to each other instead
of at each other
we've got to listen
next
requirements
following similar lines if we're not
talking to them we don't understand why
they're trying to do what they're doing
or what they're trying to do
we may sometimes give them requirements
that don't make sense from their
perspective
if we look at that vulnerability
Management program example I gave
earlier we have hand someone 70 000
vulnerabilities and say fit it in
their their plates already full in their
minds at least right
we're saying do so much more with the
the time that you have now we're always
saying that we're always going to be
saying that
but the way we say it matters a lot
and if we don't work with them to
understand
the implications of our requirements on
what they're trying to do
we can end up with some very grumpy
people
with some enemies instead of allies
sometimes we put requirements down that
don't necessarily align with risk
they may be they may feel arbitrary or
onerous to the people that are receiving
them now they may not be arbitrary or
onerous we may have very good solid
Logic for them but are we communicating
that to them clearly in a way that they
understand from their perspective
I don't think that we do all that often
we struggle with that in information
security
and again going back to requirements
that we don't necessarily keep ourselves
we can be some pretty big Hypocrites in
information security sometimes
and that burns relationships that causes
us to lose trust with our partners
one example of that was a an
architecture team that I that I knew
that
used an opportunity of a database
upgrade
to say we need to revisit your entire
database architecture
so the database team is walking in
saying we just need to upgrade in
version 11 to version 12.
and it's going to take so many hours
over so much time
and information security comes in and
says oh this is a great opportunity
we haven't been able to look at our
Oracle databases to see if they're
configured properly let's do that now
it's only going to double your time and
your budget
but that's okay right
and then we are surprised when they get
upset or they they struggle with what
we're asking of them
next bad processes
sometimes we're just throwing things at
them without a good well thought out
process that actually works we look back
at that vulnerability Management program
I talked about that existed when I first
arrived at this company
um
there was no process
it didn't work
they hadn't agreed to anything
um
in time
once we've built a good process
that their leadership especially their
senior leadership c-suite leadership had
agreed to
it made it much easier to be successful
in that in executing that process
because we're not going up to random
system administrator and saying all
right you got to Pat your sister
tomorrow
no we're we're doing something that's
normal that's expected that that their
leadership has bought into
uh in ways that perhaps
they may not have in in the past
you know something that uh
tends to go along these lines is you
know we like to put our our web
application review steps right at the
very end of the process the end of
application development before they go
live
and then that process somehow ends up
taking four to six to eight weeks and
they're sitting there sweat pouring off
of their faces because the press release
says they're going to deliver on a date
if they can't deliver on the date they
don't get their bonus they lose their
job
right we don't understand that we don't
think about that
but it happens
that's why the next item
risk assessment gaps this kind of
follows along the same lines of
requirements but
when we don't measure risk or we don't
communicate risk to them clearly
or our risk decisions don't match up
with what works in their brain
we can lose trust
example say every two weeks
when the latest Chrome update drops it's
emergency patching time
oh because
every single Chrome update
is critical
every single one
in fact just about every single browser
update is critical if you look at CVSs
score
but if you have to say the sky is
falling every two weeks because Chrome's
getting updated but no one's actually
getting hacked it's not actually
impacting the business you may be losing
trust
we also don't think about acceptable
risk in our business in the I.T world
there's no way to eliminate all risk we
have to be able to accept some amount of
risk now that should be an educated
decision made by the people who have the
authority to make that decision
but often in information security we
don't like to accept any at all
and that makes us the house of no
anything comes to you nope I said you
know it is our way or the highway
and in the end
if that's how it works
they're going to take the back roads and
they're just going to skip us all
together
so let's talk about a few treatments how
can we do better here
um
there's some behaviors that along the
way can help us
to
to build a stronger relationship with
our partners that that's founded on
trust
number one respect
we need to show them respect
if we go into better than now greater
than thou holier than thou mentality
with our partners
we're building those walls up they're
going to try to run away and run around
us
we need to assume that they have
positive intent we may not understand
their intentions we may not understand
their incentives and we'll talk about
that later
but we need to assume that they're
starting from a good point they're not
always and that's okay
and we can deal with those those moments
uh when we need to
but we need to assume positive intent
that's hard I've seen security
architecture teams who are in the throes
of a Warfare
uh or at least what they felt like was
Warfare where in their minds every
application developed out developer out
there had very negative intent
I don't believe that was the case
I think they had just had they had built
up a negative relationship over time
to where neither side trusted each other
at all and nothing got done
if we treat them as allies instead of
enemies if we bring them into our
meetings ask for their opinions their
their ideas ask them to help designing
Solutions
we might actually learn something
next communication
we need to shut up and listen sometimes
I've heard I'm not a c so I've never
been a seesaw but I've heard that one of
the most valuable things the CSO can do
is to walk into their peers offices and
shut up and listen to what their peers
care about
and I believe that
if we are trying to understand what our
peers care about what drives their
business
what they're trying to do what Their
roadmap looks like
and then using that to inform our
roadmap and our decision and our our
design points
are the likelihood of our success goes
through the roof
we need to have honest and direct
conversations with them about risk
and we need to listen to them when they
push back about some of our risk
assessments because sometimes they're
actually right
when I first took over this
vulnerability Management program I was
relatively new to the security industry
and I went down the Chrome is an
emergency patch
Road
and I was fortunate to have a system
administrator that sat me down and said
Tyler is that really the case
is it really an emergency patch
and when I sat down and really thought
about it I had to be honest with myself
and say no it wasn't
now is it something we need to
prioritize and make sure we get out
there in a reasonable amount of time
sure it's not an emergency though
and a lot of the things that we call
emergencies really aren't
one of my big struggle with the the
common vulnerability scoring system that
we use today
is that we don't think as often as we
should about environmental risk we don't
think about the specifics of how the
that particular risk impacts Us in the
organization we see CVSs 9.8 or 10
depending which version of CVSs you're
you're using and we scream patch now or
we're gonna die
but most of the time that's not actually
the case
we also need to help them understand how
their implications and their how their
actions impact risk
uh
I've seen a few cases where
when we talked through the outcome the
output of say a penetration test
and say because of this
the the attackers were able to do that
and and maybe go straight to an example
in the code or on the system
uh I remember there was a major
uh vulnerability years ago that impacted
our backup systems
and the vulnerability was so reliable
and the people should say the POC was so
reliable that in I could type out a
single line of code and have you know
hit enter and be root on whatever backup
system I wanted to be doing that in
front of them and saying this is the
risk
I'll tell you some backup admins were
scrambling to try to get that fixed
because we brought it home to them
if we can help them understand where
we're coming from it makes a huge
difference and their willingness to work
with us
same thing with any penetration test
output uh a big one nowadays that a lot
of organizations are struggling with is
credentials stored in in source code
repositories
if you can run a scan and show that
there are 50 credentials out there that
work to get into your AWS environment
Etc
that can open some eyes
and perhaps help them understand why
we're doing what we're doing
next we need to consider their
incentives
what is driving what they do
what does their bonus depend on
will their boss deny their bonus if they
don't deliver a particular project on
time and infosec is jumping in saying no
no no no no no
you can't do that
there's no way you're going to deliver
that on time because we have our
requirements
now sometimes that's the right answer
it's not always though
what does their boss care about
because most of the time
they care about what their boss cares
about our infrastructure team there are
two things that he cared about was email
up was the internet up
if either of those was answered in the
negative
it was all hands on deck
so can you help the boss care about what
you care about
can you speak to them in terms of what
their boss cares about
a lot of the time it's availability for
infrastructure teams at least right
well availability is on the CIA Triad
and if we talk in terms of availability
it can help convey our message
but change absolutely starts at the top
those incentives need to come from the
top ideally from the c-suite if not the
CEO
next we need to look inward we need to
look at our processes to be honest with
ourselves about whether those processes
actually work are they doable
do they actually address risk
or are they simply something to make a
compliance person smile and Nod right
now we have to do our compliance things
there's no question about it but how
many of these are paper exercises and
how many of them actually impact risk
let's be honest with ourselves about
that are the things that we're asking of
them realistic
do they real are they really going to
have the time to do this
uh do we understand how they're going to
impact things
and our risk assessments accurate
if the sky is always falling it's never
falling
crying wolf
doesn't work
after the first time or two we lose
trust
and number five
help them look good
if we make them look good then they're
going to be incentivized
to help us
a number of years ago some of you may
remember a particular Citrix netscaler
vulnerability
uh that that became a big thing right
before Christmas this was somewhere
around oh 2019 period I think
and this was the real deal this was
something that was easily exploitable
um netscaler a lot of the time is on the
Internet by by Design it's just what
what it does
and so we ended up having to ask our
Citrix administrators to work
on Christmas Eve Christmas day to patch
this vulnerability
and you know what it hurt me to do that
because that's the last thing I want to
have to ask of anyone
but we did and they did we got the
vulnerability passion within two weeks
organizations throughout the globe were
getting hacked through this
vulnerability
it was the real deal
but when we limit
what we're doing to the real deal we can
we can make a lot of difference
now that Citrix admin who was working
those long hours on Christmas Eve and
Christmas Day and a couple days
afterwards
we have we were fortunate we had an
internal program to be able to give a
spot bonus to someone
we were able to give that person 500
dollars
to say thank you
that same person
a year or two later
reported pen testers out of the boo they
saw something weird
and they challenged the pen testers
and helped us block what they were
trying to do
these things work if we can win allies
across the company
they will tell us things are broken
early
and we can fix them before it's hard too
hard to fix them
some of you may be thinking but Tyler
does that mean we have to be a pushover
no it doesn't not at all
we can still be hard on problems
while being nice to people
do we have to condone bad behavior
absolutely not please don't
but we can condone bad behavior
while fighting day and night against the
true threat actors that are out there
will this lead to worse security
outcomes
well
sometimes being mean gets you results
really quickly
but that tends to die off
even quicker
we can build these relationships the end
result will be far far better
than it would have been if we were jerks
about it
so in summary
most people are good
infosec is hard it's dang hard
relationships are hard too
but if we approach things from this
mentality of we're in a war
they're blocking our battles
their enemies
then that will sabotage what we're
trying to do
if we treat them like allies if we help
them to understand where we're coming
from and we try to understand where
they're coming from
we're gonna win a lot more than we fail
and we're probably going to win a lot
more than we do today
so
just be excellent to each other that's
really all you need to do
we'll leave a a couple moments for
questions or thoughts if anyone has them
um
final note here I work for Red Canary
this is in the sales pitch I love their
core values
to try to do what's right for the
customer and we're kind and authentic
and that is a value that I I have seen
uh demonstrated day in and day out
if you want to learn more about this
topic or review some of the stuff we've
taught I've talked about uh I wrote a
blog entry to go along with this if you
go to Ray canary.com
you'll find that blog
um
and you know we'd love to hear your
thoughts and experiences so I'll open it
up if anyone's like would like to throw
anything out
all right go ahead
favorite books is the question uh I
would say one that I'm actually reading
through right now that I find a really
good example of this is radical candor
um radical Candor is about combining
being direct with people when they need
it with
really showing them respect and kindness
along the way
um I think it is a strong
uh approach to solving problems in ways
that that don't burn relationships
another thing I'll recommend is actually
learning about negotiation I went I had
a an employer that was kind enough to
send me to a negotiation course for my
annual personal development a few years
ago and that absolutely changed how I
how I saw working with our partners
that's really where the the point about
thinking about incentives comes comes
from uh you can negotiate far better if
you understand the the incentives that
that uh that are driving our other
people
so another another question yep
communicate with them
especially with certain companies all
those girls I just described in 198
so the question is how do you
communicate these priorities outside of
security
outside of I.T I think these principles
align to that perfectly and and what I
what I say when I or what I mean when I
say that is
if we go to say a manufacturing Boston
we try to understand what's driving them
and what their goals are
and then we start talking about how
security can impact those goals and how
we can help with those goals
I think we find that we have a lot in
common you know there may be heavily
focused on certain aspects of it and we
may need to tune our our approach to
certain things uh to meet what they're
trying to do obviously operational
technology is its own Beast it requires
its own approach but you know in a
hospital environment in a uh you know
any sort of environment that isn't
focused on technology those same core
values can apply if we show respect to
our peers if we're trying to understand
where we're coming where they're coming
from and we communicate with them if we
listen
um I think we can achieve a lot
any other thoughts or questions out
there
oh go ahead
so the question is how do we incentivize
security incident reporting
um I think there are a few ways we can
do that one of them can be to help them
understand the impact of security
incidents maybe have demonstrations of
of things that are happening when they
click that link what actually happens
you know get one of your red team guys
maybe or a red team person if you want
to operate a consultant this is what
happens when you click click that
phishing link
um
another way is to
talk about
maybe some of their personal challenges
and how it impacts them personally and
there was a you know
we for an education program a couple
years ago we talked about how to secure
passwords and focus but on like on purp
people's personal passwords at home how
they could use I think we were talking
about keepass at the time
and there was a tremendous amount of
interest because people are worried
about hackers getting into their bank
account
and so if we can talk to them in in
terms of the things that they care about
in terms of their day-to-day business
and help them to really understand the
attacks that they're going to see
and the types of things they might
observe I think it can it can help
um one of the things that uh I think
he was the second keynote we had this
morning talked about a lot of our
training doesn't necessarily align with
the attacks that that people actually
see I think if we if we can align that
training to the things that they're
going to encounter in their day-to-day
business
and especially if we stuff that they can
encounter in their personal lives
that will make a big difference there
all right any other final thoughts we're
at uh last five minutes here
if not we'll close it out thank you
everyone for coming along I'll be around
the next few days either walking around
or hanging out of the ray Canary Booth
uh would love to chat with you
[Applause]