to do some quick announcements all the
contest repin running right now if
you're doing demo party make sure you
get your entry into arco by 4 p.m.
something like that are goes out by the
pool
there's the hardware hacking lockpicking
and wargames villages over on the other
side of the hotel so be sure to check
those out there is also a hidden contest
and mystery contest you might say it has
something to do with FM radio I'm not
really sure how that works I believe
this gentleman here who can teach you
how radios work as a radio so be sure to
check that out that's fun contest that
hasn't been beaten at DEFCON to work on
and other stuff I'm told it's not that
hard people are just not motivated so be
sure to kill it here and put another
feather in our cap era where one coming
up next we have hotel bravo talking
about sex baby second health care so
take it away
alright so I talk is let's talk about
sex baby let's talk about healthcare
information security and health care and
you know Herrera hotel bravo for 55
years now and doing it a major health
care institutions obligatory disclaimer
because I was told by our lawyers that I
had to do this
views and opinions shared in this
presentation represent that of the
presenter and do not reflect the views
and opinions of any other person or
entity so anything I say up here it's
you know don't blame anybody else
so what the fuck am I talking about if
you are lazy and the program then here's
what's going on but i wanna talk about
and high-tech how will screen Phai how
much does it cost for stolen record who
wants it
you know what's it worth everything
going out and about biotech devices
scary shit that we all see all the time
but don't pay attention to and at the
end we're gonna talk about little bit of
hope we can do in the future to maybe
fix a lot of the ship so high tech for
those who don't know if it was enacted
in August 21st 1996 to cut back on waste
and abuse and health care does not
really work very well yes it's also an
availability of medical records for
patients and provide privacy guidelines
for those records high-tech was an
amendment to the President Obama's
stimulus package is no 9 it was designed
to give him more teeth and it does give
it quite a bit of cheese because for the
most part
HIPAA Sox so how much more teeth this is
a news clip of a news article from it so
apparently in alaska mental health
facility facility got fine $156,000 for
failing $150,000 for failing to
safeguard patient data that's what they
say and this is just for the settlement
this wasn't the initial fine this is
what they said aloud in court the reason
for this was because they were running
Windows XP so OCR came in and said hey
you have a bunch of unpatched systems
out there that don't receive patches
anymore you also didn't sign up for
Microsoft CEO extended service that's
fine
and a little bit about it so by law if
you know if you lose more than 500 or
more records for people you have to
report to the press you don't have an
option in it you have to report it and
the press doesn't really get anything
wrong i mean look at you know of
anything right now let's talk about that
as dirty sons of the Chequers Inn yeah
thank you for the picture so let's talk
about the big moneymaker pH I so for
those who don't know still in thi health
records can go from anywhere from $7 a
pop to about a hundred bucks can go even
more kids records you know kids don't
check their credit history or anything
like that but it all depends on the
record the source and information on it
so like is saying you know mental health
care facility you know the doctor's note
about pay my patient is clinically
depressed that doesn't really go for a
lot though if the patient high-profile
patient but it all depends on the source
you know what's on the record so why
does everybody knows you know tax fraud
everything you know because the health
record has your social security number
date of birth address height weight age
blood type anything part in your health
history that you gave to the doctor or
patient health record has that already
down and stored digitally health records
got it I mean and people are taking the
stuff we just had their first marriage
as happened what was it like to 3 days
ago its gold these guys are staking the
ship and they're doing all sorts of you
know tax fraud you know and I do that
it's it's great and the thing is we are
not like number of you try to change
that I'll take about a year two years to
fix so now let's talk about in the long
for a while now who's gonna cost you the
most money right now if you work in a
hospital who's gonna be the one that's
gonna screw you over the most
does your doctor is full of fail doctors
generally have this idea in their heads
that digital record is not equivalent to
a paper record so you will have cases of
doctors
downloading six seven thousand thousand
different patient health records all
their patients all legitimate access
they all have complete legitimate access
to the stuff downloaded to their laptop
walking outside of the hospital and then
the laptop got stolen or they so I mean
that's a big problem and you know if
it's unencrypted then you have to report
it as a breach and if you've reported as
a bridge and OCR comes in they're gonna
find the ship is going to cost you a lot
of money so your doctor you gotta watch
him and you know owner same thing goes
for nurses to nurses have access to
these patient health records they will
do the same thing they will download it
because I just want to help out the
doctor with his research in you know
obesity whatever they'll take it all
downloaded to lose it it's so noticed
you want to protect yourself at least
really just encrypt everything doesn't
matter what it is
encrypt it I'm not taking a shot
so the best is yet to come ok do anybody
know who these people are and you there
ok so some of you know those who don't
know these are the people who actually
store your health records for hospitals
don't really story there they go to
these information services providers or
whatever to start all there and you know
these guys are the ones who hold your
records and they suck they make money
not based on how good their software is
or how good they protect your data they
make their money based off of how much
it's going to cost you to get rid of
them they go through the mccarthy
approach to get themselves in the
attached themselves to your network and
then they say well you wanna get rid of
us well that's going to cost you you
know a million dollars to get rid of us
and you know that's not good at that and
you're like well it's gonna cost me
million get rid of them and I'm not
really gonna save all that money so I'll
just keep them around and their security
is absolutely terrible I've had people
you know from different companies have
done you know done engagements against
these guys in there say they're
absolutely horrible it's a mystery why
there hasn't been a bigger breach then
you know right so now we're gonna go
into
of the scary shit that happens out there
were gonna talk about some of the biomed
devices
biomed devices pretty much from
pacemakers to infusion pumps all this
stuff is network and it doesn't have any
type of real security standards on there
i mean we remember Barnaby Jack talk
about hacking wireless pacemaker and you
know that was a lot of fun but for the
most part stuff like that has really
changed you know nobody wants to change
it because there's no real benefit into
changing it really doesn't have any
rules when it comes to security in
BioMed devices they there's no
regulation there's no there's nothing
they should stay here a couple of
guidelines that we want you to follow
but that's not a deal breaker for us you
know well still you know sign off your
crappy infusion pump out there and let
you sell it to mom and pop you know
hospital or whatever who cares it's just
recommendations and the FDA really
doesn't say anything and this all these
recommendations and everything will only
apply to stuff that's about to come out
of the market or stuff that's already
going through FDA approval so you will
have and this is not uncommon biomed
devices that probably been sitting in
your hospital for ten fifteen years and
the hospital does not get rid of it
because it costs too much money or they
want to get rid of it but the clinician
is like hey I don't wanna get rid of it
I'm used to seeing this device or
sometimes even clinicians when they
change hospitals by the freakin device
themselves and take it with them to
another hospital simply because they're
used to it works on cutting out
but yeah they'll just keep it and take
it to other places and then they just
plugged into the network says you know I
want to be able to you know reached all
these patients and see how they're all
doing from the comfort of the golf
course you know and they security is
reckless and it was you I know is you so
I don't know if any of you see the
saudis TV they got published last week
so there was a device that had poor 2300
pin no authentication at all and you got
root shell yeah that's not uncommon and
also this fix they're not going to be
able to really fix this so you want to
kill somebody just look up the CD you
can probably find some of these devices
but yeah it's it's it's not good because
government sucks when it comes to
regulation when it comes to regulation
so for all the old devices out there any
major patches any major software changes
to any type of device has to go back
through full FDA approval you can you
know a cycle which will take about two
years just to get the room which is why
you have instances of hospital still
running XP because they have no choice
they have to wait for the manufacturer
to come out with something that can run
on a Windows 7 or Windows 8 device you
know they have to wait as these guys
have to wait for the FDA to say yes or
no and if the FDA says no and they have
to get you know recreate the software
again and then send it back to the FDA
and wait another two three years just to
get this proved it's a pain in the ass
minor hotfixes though I do some minor
bug changes and things like that that
stuff will get approved in a couple of
months
weeks maybe depending on you know what
you're changing what you're doing but
major stuff has to go through full FDA
approval and it's it's a nightmare
anybody who works in BioMed field knows
that getting stuff for the FDA is a pain
in the ass so let's think about the
scary future ahead of us because of all
these problems so we're gonna go a
little bit into the just a little bit
imaginate you know imaginations we're
not going to be too far off of what
could possibly happen but you know this
is kinda think about this so things are
pretty scary I don't know if anybody saw
that last year in a poll gave a talk at
some police security conference or
whatever and they say that the world's
first cyber murder
gonna happen in 2015 I'm honestly
surprised it hasn't happened yet it
probably has just nobody said anything
orders just probably no way to detect it
actually happened so when this happens
you're gonna have to call in these guys
CSI cyber yeah because they're gonna get
all the Sabres and solve all your cyber
crimes and don't cause for being so yeah
let's use our imagination
I love you to your my one and only one
alright so let's use our imagination
just for a little bit when it comes to
biomed devices so you know a lot of us
in this field we know like criminals
they're only gonna go after profit so
yeah we like to say about hey we can
kill people and that's awesome in all
but you know is the criminal really
gonna bother to actually do anything
about it so I just think about this
let's say you in fact 10 infusion pumps
30 40 maybe and you got you can do
anything you want with them right who
cares right you know I'm not get any
profit then let's just do this but if I
in fact forty fusion pumps to senior
hospital staff hey I've infected these
machines infected this number machines
to tell you which ones but I got them if
you don't pay me $1,000,000 gonna start
killing people one by one
crazy but that's kind of like a locker
right around somewhere you know it
exists and it's the same thing you know
we're just taking the whole concept of I
have all your very very valuable
information encrypted and I'm not gonna
give you the key you know X amount of
money we're just translating it to Milan
devices saying I've now infected all
your machines if you don't pay me I'm
gonna start killing people and then
you're gonna have to explain to the
press and to all of you know the
patients families hey I didn't want to
pay a million dollars so that's why your
pet you know your mother your husband
your wife your kids are dead thats yeah
crazy room right so there's kind of hope
for this whole thing so you guys
should come to the dark side I know
banks pay more money than anything
hospitals in a pay you just the way it
works is because for the most part they
don't need us
hospitals I've had clinton you know the
nation's come to me all the time and
they make it very clear to me we don't
need I T and you know I T makes things
easier for us and faster for us and
allows us to deal with more patients but
a lot you know when it comes down to it
we don't need I T
you know we can take care of the patient
with you know rubber tubing and syringes
we can go back down to that so you know
but you know I T and you know we help
them keep things running but the whole
concept of information security with
healthcare is very very new for the most
part most hospitals did not have InfoSec
department and if they did it was just
one guy who said no to everything and
got overruled all the time so he was
just kind of a figurehead to say yes we
have an infant department it's just this
day
but thank you anthem hospitals and
health care providers are running
crazily scared they are throwing money
at Investec it's amazing how much money
they're just here you go
just protect us tell us everything's
gonna be ok but they're looking for
answers but they don't know where to go
to and there are larger charlatans out
there you all know them that are going
to you know promise you this big magical
box that's going to solve all your
security problems and they will fall for
it a lot of these people they are in
that scared they will take anything but
you all can shape the competition to how
it goes in its infancy we can actually
set a lot of the rules and policies that
allow the rules and policies regarding
healthcare in InfoSec so I mean a lot of
people say you know dealing with
clinicians and doctors or whatever a
pain in the ass and yes it is but no
answers just got a you know shave shower
for a bit I know it's kind of hard for
some of you to even do some of those
things put on a clean bunch shirts made
yourself semi presentable actually make
yourself fully presentable for crying
out loud
not hard and leave that big giant ego at
the door because if you think you have a
big ego doctors got a mere one because
hey I save lives
you just type on a computer all day but
I save lives
I went to a doctor a friend deal with a
with a doctor who she wanted local
administrator privileges on her machine
so she full-on went if you don't give
this to me I'm gonna quit and if I quit
who's gonna take care of the patients
well she didn't get it and she also
didn't quit so but no doctors you know
they have to detach themselves from the
patient they can't cells they can't get
themselves emotionally involved with
patients because if you get it yourself
emotionally involved with patient you're
not going to survive so but some of them
take that to a very extreme where they
just think as patient as machines in
something to just be topless so don't
even bother trying to fight the doctor
just try to understand their position
give them data give them facts there are
more open to fax and data than anybody I
seen because in the end their their
scientists they get it but yeah you show
them evidence they'll change its gonna
take awhile it's going to be at a
snail's pace but things will change you
know we have a way to do this we just
gotta put the work into it so that's all
I got
thank you and enjoy the next talk unless
anybody anybody anything yes rack give
me a standing ovation ok well yeah enjoy
the next time
you have a question I'm not short I'm
vertically challenged I mean I only have
half an hour here i mean you have
anything to add Chris or or you know the
line somewhere else that's what I
thought anything else anybody have
anything constructive to say comment yes
my mommy says next year again anything
any constructive criticism or anything
that you want to add a not about how
young I look or how short I am I get it
I'm young I'm short let's move on
alright alright alright I'll drink to
that
yes yes it this way if you have the
lawyers you can get away with anything
you just have to get the company's
liability but your name is still going
in the paper and that's gonna get going
to cost you the most money it's not the
fact that you have to pay all these
people for you know credit monitoring or
anything like that it's the fact that
your name is in the paper and if you are
a large hospital that relies heavily on
donations you're screwed so yes I do
your hand right here on capitol
Australia see how the individual you are
you were at the mercy of person who's
holding the knife and the place where
you're at so for the most part no can't
really anything you can protect yourself
because you can ask to have your patient
records removed and probably process
that in a year that anything else
it would all depend on the information
on there like a transcript or whatever
if it's you know if somebody really
wants it then you can be about 7 10
bucks or whatever that just a transcript
of some type of like procedure that's
usually chief
the stuff that gets you know 250 $20 is
the full patient record time thank you
very much