acts up at this early in a second
welcome the next time we have a couple
first time ever and I had to apologize
to the students for quite a lot of it
because what's in the book is all
fiction there's
her practice is well-defined an app
developers just completely ignore them
and don't do any of it for example off
fictional product to make sure possible
through us and apathetic a customer
service likes a Twitter without handling
and Twitter password but nobody uses the
old last right through the handle the
password and rolling around reach
dealers I can't find an example of
anybody actually using a bother writing
it but maybe for some future generation
of people that care more about security
number one because cheaper it is much
much less safe than iOS to an outrageous
extent entirely because of decisions
made by Google to keep it free and open
and that makes it free to do stupid
things you really shouldn't be doing and
they happen a lot for example apps have
re-signed but they don't have to be
signed with a real public your typical
you can just sign most of what was the
point
I can even download somebody else's take
off their shoes or modified put on
myself right back on now if you leave
the original app on it'll say hey this
new app does not appear to be a proper
updated the previous on the singer's
first of all fixed them show up and show
official app store but they don't
actually keep out these other Layouts or
very well they've been humiliated with a
series of disasters so they're forced to
cheat a little tougher every time about
policing yet but you know I'm just
guessing you know sort of like a
religious issue was doing what they do
but it seems to me like that started
with open source says that you should be
able to do anything you want and they're
very reluctantly will be over to Apple's
position where you should be like a
child playing in a walled garden or your
parents keep all the bad people out
which is a whole lot cheaper of course
for most users the mig Android debug
bridge let you debugger device and send
data back and forth very nice and makes
it possible to push things onto the app
on the Android device pull files back
from it
observe the logs anything for the logs
must be published on the internet I mean
well I fractional jet relook at Beauty
available to every option available to
computers connected to the Vice show one
of the fundamental rule is never log
sensitive information you'll be hearing
more about that you can install things
you cannot execute commands which is
finer now Android app isn't apk file
which is just a container with a bunch
of files inside it and you can do static
analysis on it far easier than Windows
binaries Windows binaries when you
decompile may turn into a simple
language which is relatively difficult
to understand what their stuff turns
into smalley code and all you need is
this apk trouble free open source
product machines homework to play with
this strategy Trojan Android app so you
just run this thing and it does it's
magic and change this thing is just a
whole bunch of little objects and here's
judy Ameritrade a financial stock
broking stock trading at
it disassembled and I see all their
source code you might notice this is
really friendly but schumer API build
config account manager manager there's
nothing to stop me totally rear code all
the names of variables in such regions
Bank of America uses the standard
obfuscator called ProGuard which is
built into Android sweet Android
developer suite and completely useless
ProGuard is like a security guard locks
after doors negotiate as you can see all
these things are still readable ab&c an
ALS a whole bunch of just alone like
activities enrollment business credit
card details activity just sitting here
on the rest is like BRB SBT so it does
remove some of the names of the files
and change them but at least the
variable names readable so what's the
point of that and all the important
functions
original text lavatory name and you
might wonder how bad is this Molly
Cognos molly is
bytecode and so here's job and her two
small producers so if your name here put
password there turns into username
password it's really not a whole lot
harder to read than just a job it's a
little bit strange one thing you have to
get used to it you only have 16 local
variables and the local variables or
goldie in the perimeters are called p
and they come at the end and they count
against the total and some apps actually
used 32 of them but the second batch
cannot be used directly after key copied
unaware of the first 16 to use them but
you know ninety percent of the crime
everything you might want to do to take
over the air
understanding much of that I learned how
to go about three things it's Molly and
I
show then you do all you gotta do is
recompiled here apathy control you build
instead of taking it apart and then you
shine with yourself psyche and I can you
put it back on the phone so did you now
showing anything sensitive in the log so
you can monitor along with a green truly
Android device monitor and she things
appear in a log but the whole lot easier
to just do from command line with adb
logcat because then you can use drip
drip filter pension funds the ones you
like it so here I am looking for a
vehicle IRA or various this is actually
very interesting this is one of the very
few successes from work i'm talking bout
region one of the people actually patch
their app there are three or four of
them which surprised me because most of
the people are part of the stuff you
would not talk to me and the ones that
didn't talk to me to not passed yet but
over the last couple of days I said well
before you talk about the shoot anybody
wishing that if you did actually passed
their stuff without telling me anything
so I'm kinda pleased to see that they
are all just ignoring its like I thought
track by decompile disassemble you
ensure anything you want Trojan coli
keyloggers you can find out what
encryption method Richard I saw him at
bsides this showed us how the games with
this is actually pretty easy I don't do
anything hard nothing I do committee
harder than about 20 homers I'm so so
over the Bank of America
install an Android device then you use
these commands to get it back to the
device you can play with it this is the
shell command lists the packages on the
device and then I used to find the be of
a show it has a funny name calm in
Philadelphia
that I used to find out the exact passed
away apk file which is the single file
it includes the entire app and then I
just pull that filed down should know I
have it on my computer now all you do is
use and what that creates is this whole
restructuring measures to bring it up
live here of course I read it all over
the last 24 hours to check for update
should be pretty fast because originally
focused on financial and here's the
latest one Bank of America 500 migrants
ten minutes in my hotel room so I
decided to only talk about this part of
it rather than trying to do it live show
you this is the apk file it comes down
when you just get the store has a few
XML file she can see you can control the
structure and a lot of files that are
going on up here but all the code is
this Molly directory and you can see
what they've done here being a coach and
custom code here from Android libraries
here in America orange involved in
various different people have
contributed to this code the huge
libraries and rolling here here's the
custom stuff they wrote e-commerce and
in particular willing to find the one
that's funded Trojan here just
journalists of life everything I'm sure
show you his website which is
wifi there goes the job down here all
the security results I'm going to
portray this is the landing page least
all the rest would go to load slow I'm
gonna look on my slider got it see you
can shoot for this stuff with Greg I
usually look for password if that
doesn't work I look for user agent your
idea a few other things and that doesn't
work at the start wondering if you get
routine looking at things and when
everything fails I wrote a triangle
python script about 10 lines along the
Trojans every module in the hole at
short runs slow and the Wardrobe dreams
and every single routine load puts a
little of everything runs and then
against the login screen after login see
what Roger that point to try to find
what part is likely to have the
credentials anyway this one here
smelling combi of AECOM author charities
enrollments
I think I'll just stick to the slide
ruslan saying she got in 2012 file
business credit card details activity
that's the one I found that handle
credit card under Steele
when you look at the code and this is
what it looks like now this is the
glorious other skater function is now
named else that whatever its original
name was but the string still called be
a part of me but this year is still
called set card number that I thought so
this is all the small Leone know how to
write
slightly more this but not much change
the number of local variables so I have
another one to work so before it was 30
V wanted V two variables you can use in
this region and i dont wanna step on one
of those changes on a break
changed it to five so now I can use
these for with impunity and that held up
not using 33 and here's the main project
I always use only thing I figured out
how to do I forget why maybe I copied
some bloggers are you can make a
constant string and you can put it into
law but this just makes a log this is
the name of the item NSW so I think this
thing in 30 is a strength and looks like
it has some of your card number so i
just want to see what it is like being a
Georgia card number right there
301 down here that just sets CVV
pretty good so I don't that one out and
actually the only thing I'm worried
about you when you see a function like
this to resolve those in the one on the
right anyway so I'm that's the game last
night you rebuild the thing with Java
jar and was also in keeping you just
can't change by the way
ATK cool you should put it back together
for those who don't know what they're
all about I thought somebody actually
think something the first time that
happen
complains about everything seems to work
so let's play with these things it's
easy to see what it does look at the log
Wildcats will start with this one shows
you everything is going on that Android
device launched the Bank of America app
going by which is trying to charge
capping China still drunk cause this is
the Trojan
this is a common problem
enroll in banking that's what I want to
do get started with a small business
credit card charge my credit card number
the other social security number gets
dumped in a long because this is a
modified at this thing is communicating
with the Bank of America shares
cheerfully and dealing with it as it
goes by the Bank of America just don't
care it might be worth mentioning that I
told them about the show and got no
answer all these people announced in
February March and most of them don't
respond at all when you talk to him and
ones that do just trying to make
promises you don't come true
the Bancorp the doctors to show you
different categories intrusions that I
made those that were interesting Bancorp
is neither she case in Bancorp the usual
thing called the security alarm module
which meant to this kind of Trojan
wouldn't work they don't actually load
the password in a single variable that I
could fight but I can catch the
keystrokes 1234
so much that will do really
Point Capital One Capital One world that
is developed and it captures the
keystrokes here I had destroyed
everything and then I noticed the same
thing every time I saw that ok gonna be
flapjack and the password is password ok
you get those key numbers are not a ski
they are some nonsense Google made up
and they put them on a page so i cant
find where they have like 10 per page
for 255 you have to scroll down to put
them back together but anyway it is
possible to turn those ridiculous things
back into letters like this 29 30 31 and
so on the password is included in that
nonsense just in a slightly irritating
manner so it does sort of proved the
point of course you know any code and
then recompile it ran that would be
enough in principle to prove that the
developers made a serious error they
should have led their code but my entire
contribution to this business theater
the point is you impress people and they
all care if you have some theoretical
problem they want to see you really
stolen credit card number they can
understand that's why I will try to make
really get something real so some trust
I was not going to just don't trust I
was working on the top 10 banks but I
put some of the information on Twitter
us just a SunTrust customer but
everybody ought to be both important so
let's take a look at SunTrust and
they're friendly judy's had responded by
reported to them and their should talk
to media should only other portable
really fix that but we're not sure when
that happened yet but he said it's not
under current active attack which is in
2011 maybe they have things down anyway
SunTrust unusual ideas user user
passwords later 11 again and here is
what SunTrust gives me all over the
place when I handed you was Trojan all
the use of the premises being set up the
network layer one hears the name and
password and user idea what I did here
was chosen the routine creates HTTP
requests and change parameters that's
why there's all this other job this is
the value and name of GDP perimeter
being said I but it could not capture
the only thing is that many developers
include many regimes they don't you sure
you find $100
all the wrestler like she called they
brought in the valujet anyway so that's
the game they're so drinking drinking is
when I found out yesterday actually so
let's go back just plain old logcat
everything happening on this device I go
back here
trade can just kind of stopped rolling
stock market trading activity crash this
one actually mean it when it crashed
this is the Trojan death and it won't
launch anymore and if you want to know
why you can see right analog right here
runtime exception just do it again
fatal exception their fatal exception
Thomas Dekker mobile Activity Log In log
in and up here we're going to see
verifier rejected clash login login and
that's why I put the Trojans so what
these Dec Jackley what these guys have
done now is they put in some code
notices that this module has been
altered and refuses to start and that is
exactly what I told him to do it just
seems to me the whole thing now I don't
know how they did it
comment about this year ago I wouldn't
be surprised if the
progress because that's all security
ever going to mean heart that's all you
can never do that will slow down people
are probably more perfect solutions but
at least they did something which I
appreciate my general summary page up
here we go
so this is the first time doing here is
talking about these things you just
believe police have not been patched
this 1 a.m. chant lack of protection or
you can modify the code so that's the
first we'll look into here because
basically every effort has to be
something like eight of the top 10 banks
nine of the top 10 stockbrokers seven
out of the top insurance companies all
have a strong show you something like
eighty or ninety percent of all apps or
bowling alley earlier the Bank of
America Corp Capital One chase the ones
being green
actually fixed and she and Wells Fargo
Wells Fargo probably because of my
students is like close to the head of
security there will be some trust
promise to pick just one thing it was
kind of entertaining was Charles Schwab
is vulnerable ish and tried to contact
them in turn into a real sure about the
way we mentioned here which i think is a
really bad idea is absolutely none of
these people have anybody million
reporting process far from bug bounties
or anything
there's not even any address to send the
things you sent your company not common
just bounces with a very few exceptions
so they're so far back in the dark ages
there pretending that they have no
problems in which is unlikely to be
anyway
options but in a charles schwab is
notably not lose exceptions
approaching the Charles Schwab and then
I tried to tell them they have a email
form which is just broken mirror
Christensen Email Security but that just
now she's of course I found another
email format
UK office which doesn't work either so
that I sent to the International Office
Schwab and I was able to send email
pounds but then I found a website the
chest the whole team lead roles rather
ignore everything comes in every email
address you just totally waste your time
so I switch to something which I have
done several times with great success
which as you look at the CEO on Twitter
and then you treated please problem I
have actually never failed with this
approach I don't like it because it's
tantamount to full disclosure on public
moment because I'm not willing to bother
she owes over nothing to create
background noise if I average reader
she'll anybody can guess exactly what I
have to say and that's of course what
happened
Swift on security of course figured out
how to say no so this is like
operational security you know
when I never had a way and this is a
fundamental problem we'll never fiction
I have one counter example coming up
later anyway so we contacted me and he
put me through the security team and
they sent me to the right person and he
said oh for God's so anyway all these
trading after vulnerable and
however is one of the few that did
pictures and here's the others are going
to make those she only three people
actually fixed a nap now you'll never
stand here and insurance companies
Geico and Intuit TurboTax get yellow
because they didn't fix anything but
they do have a page report problems like
oh has a very nice pages are you a
security researcher lift as you
understand what we are but then I shall
make normally do nothing and one of them
I think it was actually promised that he
would have it out in the may update but
then they just did and I talked to the
security guy again over he told me they
were going to obviously the codon
you know it's not hard to test
everything I know electronic book to do
it for homework I mean I didn't get rude
discussing with them but you know
employee to do something you don't have
to test to see if they did it anyway
back to hear more categories of trouble
to talk about one defense that a lot of
people told me if this doesn't even
matter Trojan don't really ever gonna
happen you're just making it up it's not
a realistic threaten I don't think so
because you might reasonably say she if
this was an iPhone none of this would
happen because you have to install
things from the store and Apple actually
polices the store if you put a provision
happen the story you kick out just as
Charlie Miller and they're not messing
around and just doesn't do much that
they don't clean the story well and
people install stuff that's not from the
store but if everyone was just talking
to the store then Google could control
this but they're not very interested in
doing another did the Droid dream was to
be a Trojan 2 2011 but their application
verification services just fantastically
an effective this is effective as
compared to all the other any viruses or
just the bouncer thing is just not very
successful
anyway you can protect yourself here one
thing you can do is obviously your codes
which very hard to read and find where
to put the Trojan that helps all is not
a very strong defense they're also
products you can buy that will block
reverse engineering make a pkg will not
work can get pretty expensive the and by
the way Jason actually works this is
what you have now and this is what all
the variable names of turned into this
garbage fee that would irritate me I
might not get in should not write this
talk about had the lead role like
garbage volatile
such a reasonable obfuscator and two
thousand bucks and another protocol Park
San which one would talk to me cause I'm
not gonna buy it now must be even more
expensive and they claim it has multiple
layers of validation and verification
checks so you can't do you compile lists
up at all
recognizes already compiling jewels
breaks them all and I imagine it's
probably true they won't give you a free
samples tested but you can totally buy
products to prevent this and I'm
wondering how these people to in
business since nobody seems to care
but apparently some of them actually
patches so it seems to me that there's a
slow awakening that is actually problem
here anyway so actually as far as the
last one lakh a binary protections
should then I started noticing a look at
one of the most important work from
shirt in 2014 surged actually built a
special gadget called the tapioca I
think using a Raspberry Pi or something
it was a girl like a wifi pineapple with
them in the middle attack that would
then put a whole bunch of invalid
searched every website you went to sleep
could see if any of the Android apps
would accept intelligent hypocrites and
had all kinds of errors expired wrong
hostname and LGA and so on and they
found 23,000 vulnerable apps and they
notified all the app designers seven
months ago and they published the entire
listed on the internet so I was looking
at this thing she was interesting I
wonder how many people actually patch
their stuff so I started looking through
the page here and they're starting to
get me in trouble so this is why I said
to myself as I do not need to do
responsible disclosure shirt already did
responsible disclosure seven months ago
if they don't listen to surge they're
not gonna wish to be so these guys are
fair game that was Lampasas so your
pictures are actual financial stuff we
like daily downloads led the spreadsheet
to 23,000 things to chest person
actually testing 12 had the most
downloads because he looked important
like OkCupid safely in charge and these
are susceptible SSL man-in-the-middle
attacks and then we'll get down to the
one that showed stream actually think it
was possible PDF reader cuz I got
embarrassed to show you how this works
this one is slightly more complicated
very much more complicated because I'll
do anything so you have to use a proxy
war because I'm using a different wifi
which one of my dresses
ok 161 131 ok everything's through 168
11 31 in port 8080 and I'm running group
here is listening on all addresses
including that one 131 show I have a man
in the middle now if you wanna used
correctly you have to install reports
leader richard jacket in your device
should we trust it and if you don't if
you don't know what you're doing and
Stalberg incorrectly and you get these
warnings every time you try to browse to
secure site but that's what I want so
now I have put them in the middle attack
that does not have a LG a showed no
secure connections can be made from this
device right now so if any of these apps
make secure connections their life and
of course they do so here's the history
attempting to connect Asia GBS resources
and these aren't getting anywhere
couldn't get through what's clear the
old stuff and play some games here she
we did some trust in TradeKing here's
pic charged I don't know what they do
whatever is needed it badly HTTPS
connections here she should be post
connections going through sharing some
data but my device so they're making
these HTTPS connections now the port 443
is open and you can make the connection
but there is no good and the obviously
just don't even check it so I can find a
login button someplace where login again
putting layer one fool and I trust you
here and sign in and it'll be right down
here someplace where we are I trust you
later wonderful you know show
they check it appears as using what they
think is HTTPS but they just commented
operation UBS validation probably just
so they could test it they just never
put it back in i mean i dont to another
developer I don't know exactly what
leads to this traditional think a lot of
them do and you know I'm surprised that
Google doesn't block you from the store
for stuff like this I think Apple would
I mean they could just run a test that
could be in Belcher maybe I'm just
underestimate the difficulties but he
seems to me like they could be about you
if you have a good kick you out of the
store and you know what kind of fun here
suppose you're traveling with one of
these public service ads she Google+ I
can't get in and that's because picture
art is not as stupid as they could be
when you click on these external links
they appear to be launching an external
browser which is probably the default
browser and see the default browser is
smart enough not to let this happen
we're going to see that is not always
the case anyways I'm able to steal
picture credentials that I got Institute
which is something related to Instagram
whatever that is I just market and here
they are money to login show I'm chest
user later one Password one login don't
bother remembering that wouldn't be
secure and there it is just you 2011
stole my time in the military so they're
just throwing the password on the ground
like they don't care who hears OkCupid
and she OkCupid used to be vulnerable
and they patched it is one of the
services actually paid attention so I
appreciate that they no word so I
haven't tried now and I'll try to shape
up my car to get to the personalized
section where you sign in a safe way
user com
my dog's name and there goes that stuff
all over the world and then it went to
serving the Sherman Oaks that's no good
which is evil
it should have told me you know they
can't get there from here because
something's wrong with your network
connection so there's the game there
Pixar is 200 million each OkCupid
actually fixed it simply told me
1,000,000 but you know there are a lot
of like more than a dozen on that list
there that I tested and show them that
was pretty entertaining I said well you
know the only thing occurred to me is
you can check the spreadsheet that came
from a search you can sort them by
category and there's a category called
medical and he seems to me like some of
those guys might be covered by hip and
I've had pretty good luck in the past to
getting attention by violations
especially if you go right to the Fitch
which I haven't done with these yet but
I have gotten far enough to get some
attention so I just took the same
another reason why anybody ever cared
about this is because Dan Goodin at the
technical wrote this stuff up
show there's actually an arch technical
articles about this one which had the
first part of these things we talked
about the fact that these crimes haven't
patched their thing even seven months
after being told by surprising to me is
that some staff secure was a security
product which we had this problem and
they did fact picture pretty quickly
cause I'm pretty sure bill using and the
folks at Mobile PDF reader had social
networking options because this is
pretty fun there were two or three
things that this kind of stuff you if
you're determined you can call other ppl
services chip so ok
so far more PDF reader I can harvest
credentials here but then Fox it can
connect to cloud readers and here we are
open a local copy this page since the
internet doesn't work remember where I
find it was this one this one there we
go I should be able to run local copies
of all these things there are now 10 K
reader million downloads and she fucks
it can connect all these services to get
the PDFs you want to reach and when you
do that it's just not going to launch
the default browser like it should
are used to system routines it uses
their custom junk they wrote that
doesn't work so this looks like a
browser but they wrote some version of a
browser that ignores church if package
so I can steal your Dropbox password and
your box password and your Microsoft
past as you connect to the Microsoft
cloud and so on the exposure all these
other passwords used by connecting
future on each occur custom code show
when I put that on Twitter and they
actually passed that one pretty fast
anyway let me go back to my list here so
the medical apps the next thing they
want to look at it as it seemed to me
like you guys violate HIPAA now I'm not
a lawyer but looked at hit shows you are
supposed to ensure confidentiality
integrity and availability of medical
information if you are a covered
provider industry categories uncovered
providers but pharmacies are included
and so are doctors so there's something
here called gene EMG and this thing
product you use to manage your health
and your medications your vitamins into
this thing
shining using email and I can steal the
credentials
and what jeanne and he claims is that
the patient is not a covered entity the
patient is allowed to you something
insecure to store their stuff and
therefore this is not a violation of
HIPAA and I looked at the third category
covered entities and I thought maybe
they included but I don't really know
but I said you know what your break SSL
anyway but I got no answer beyond that
distinguish our lawyers answer to their
ideological going shut up anyway but the
other one was entertaining was back to
my slides here
noticed this one called lowest bid now
this is the spreadsheet from church from
seven months ago
here's the medical category and a summer
cold lowest mid corporate so I went
looked at lowest midcourt richard hirsch
GMD it has lost mid corporate now jeanne
indeed responded immediately when I put
this on Twitter we are told by HIPAA
Security go away
well that's an interesting position to
take lost med contacted the college I
sent them an email telling me about it
and they ignored that and called the
president of the college and demanded
that I can assure the college
orientation and then I should pass the
information on to me and I replied in
writing saying why don't you put
whatever you have to shake in writing on
the phone and then I'll run it past my
lawyer and we will take an appropriate
response and suddenly they got polite
and said well you don't we think we're
probably not covered by it though
because there's nothing personal in our
product and that might be true but take
a look at these guys she account just
these guys to thoroughly because without
a valid credentials I can't see exactly
what they do once you get inside but
let's move this thing and go here
his lowest mad this is a corporate
products that is used to buy medicines
and you're here we are using and
password my username is just user and
chest and there it goes tanning tests
user just be a sort of injury early so I
do not know what's behind this i assume
the list of Medicine you're buying and I
think there is a sort of disingenuous
issue here about how I've only still in
the password that stop P that's not
medical information I see what's behind
that word but anyway I do understand the
whole point of lawyers just lay here
anyway
genealogy which is more the same really
oMG is a product you use you keep track
of your symptoms and so on there
something called my Genie AMD which i
think you can use to order medications
would make it covered by HIPAA but maybe
not
and anyway to login looks like yeah you
already have an account please delete my
old data I tested it earlier and I have
to clean it after each test for this one
GMD cleared it ok and now here's gene
EMT stuff now when I go to my GMD
just sign up and shut up this way in
terms of use which by the way I don't
need to see the region which is
entertaining picture user ok well we're
fine
sign up and of course that is available
to be stolen on the internet and then
it's gonna ask me this stuff blood type
gender are you pregnant zip code you
know this is PRI but anyway they're
going to argue with a tougher crime and
I don't know they may slide on hip but
I'm hoping there are some motivation to
actually fix their junk anyway so
excited you know I thought shirt caught
them all with their automated process
but then I just tested some random apps
and they were vulnerable so I don't know
how certain system where they added you
vulnerable in the last seven months it
might be the answer but I started crying
a lot of apps new ones I found a lot of
a border policeman middle attack and I
contacted him saying I think they're
violating HIPAA and one of them really
takes the cake for Blue Cross Blue
Shield of North Carolina and the reason
I can talk about it because these guys
had the worst illegally but they're the
fastest affection so you picked up
within two days which was yesterday I
was able to actually talk about it now
the rest of the stuff I have to wait
another month before you talk about what
they have to actually connect mobile
instantly connect mobile and those
things
Facebook Twitter and YouTube critical
supply not verify the Jetta good I told
them and they fix it in two days and now
should you try just says the connection
is not secure they're really very nice
so the developer is really a hero
responding quickly to a real and lasting
just right got 10 minutes not sure one
thing at the end I thought you to kick
out of I was trying to do insurance
companies and insurance company called
AIG did not have a nap but they had some
weird angle DIGE Mobile guard showed you
buy their insurance you want to protect
your phone itself after install the
security product on your phone to
protect it which I guess let me remote
wipe the road found and that product is
fantastic you I was your little all been
talking about you when I Trojan a nap I
put the password in the log because
that's so ridiculous that proves that
I'm able to destroy the app so I wrote a
Trojan for this one but the password to
log and then I looked already look
so it all anyway dude you know I have
this special a person to be insecure
that I should do for homework
dude I could just use your app like the
example that comes pre Trojans and so I
contacted them and also has local
storage of all your data is stored your
security question you should answer
European in plain text on the device so
anyway there were four versions of this
thing and 341 going to have enough time
to demonstrate this one let me take a
moment to make it quick going through
the proxy cuz it makes the reasons we're
done with that part here's mobile rescue
let me delete the data from a rescue
only get to put indeed with your first
got to do is get rid of the proxy which
is occasion I'm just connecting directly
to the internet now let's get the log
going by which looks like it is going
right and I think the thing to search
for for this one to avoid getting a lot
of junk is in code ok and code ok so now
you start this security product protects
your phone mobile rescue I've agreed to
this whatever it is activating the
product
they meet up in what if I change the pin
to something real secure like that name
there we go up in 1337 in case you
didn't get it there it is again and now
I'm gonna putting more stuff and that's
pretty interchange I contacted them and
they said that they perished and it just
like they said it was your old
production of new products to the better
but I kind of doubt anyway I got
anything else you i think thats all I
want to show you those things all
feeling yeah so you got any questions
solutions code but I don't think
I would like to know what they might not
be verified the name on the shirt I
would not catch that but but still I
just used these things and what it
appears to me just a lot of a comment
about all delegation tired I just left
it that way because you can use it for
years the customers will not others
quite a few I cannot just in this manner
because they do bypass the proxy HTTPS
out so that's another reason why the
test because they put a real device in
the middle so they have no chance to go
past it
test and its relatively sloppy but I
don't know if the case but you have
mentioned that using the default browser
could solve a lot of this I think injury
default browser doesn't do checks so if
you get your hands on a little search or
enter key still not in the middle with
an expired certificate in the Afghan
actually go out and check for that even
if uses default browser Google Chrome
browser that may have changed but I
think before they told me I did not know
that the start of every app provides a
number of local variables such a
standard thing that just says what the
name of the module is analog and