welcome to the next talk if you think
this guy socks and 100 bottles personal
this is my entry will be doing this out
of the pool area for till we get bored
of it the coming of Nexus dan Taylor
with how not to impose sexy big round of
applause on my talk is actually entirely
full of fail so this is for fun while we
were setting up this is an ongoing piece
of research which I might actually talk
about this is anybody heard the stories
recently but that sign in Atlanta
Georgia that goateed these are other
signs in the country that are still
vulnerable to the same attack and just
for fun and how to meet right so I guess
today we talking entirely but mistakes
which is something I i've seen very very
rarely in InfoSec in its entirety
Wednesday night made Wednesday
co-workers have made once a clients have
made employers the company in the public
stuff that are seen on Twitter and in
the media you name it just like this
giant flaming failed talk all talking
about mistakes that are entirely
preventable and could have been
prevented with no effort basically so
this is about this story about me slide
you people if you want to stop me on the
air that's how this is an important part
of the important part is that when faces
problems and everyone knows how to deal
with them several years ago for me but
it went to DEFCON you may remember that
Adam Savage actually took the stage and
he presented specifically on the topic
of how failure made him the manual and
how failing fast and learning what not
to do next time with Intermountain
jail mike is fail anyway yeah so so
taking his philosophy degree I am
searching
heart talk to basically articulate sort
of gift then conditionals for security
problems where the van is your company
will end up in the news or gets hacked
to oblivion or goes out of business or
have you are male strains and upon taste
in so the goal here is effectively to
help every effort to help out the crowd
by process of elimination so if I can
show you what not to do it'll help
narrow down what you should do so
instead of telling you what to do or
what school also know I stepped over
here on a land mine and blew up my legs
don't be me so this is actually really
need this is a tumbleweed minesweeper
that guy in Kabul built it's made out of
bamboo and like these little things and
invented and it's carried by the wind so
he's let it loose in the deserts of
Kabul and it runs over land mines and
takes out my mind is really cool because
it helps keep things like kids walking
over to land mines and pets and other
people or have you like it's a
minesweeper and it's entirely automated
you just let it go into this is pretty
cool I thought that was pretty
inspirational and I thought that was
very
parallel to the talk show in my in my
security experience i've i've had
experienced quite a lot so my intention
here is to basically show you where I
stepped on these mines and how my legs
got blown off and all the colorful fun
backs of my legs whereas others do the
same where saw you know creators and
other little flags are left by other
people were mines were and effectively
this is sort of the world on the same
team in the room we all have the same
goal that's all Internet together and
the first really fun talking point at
all I mention is that there's a lot of
people that have come from the military
and that believe that because they are
rumored Robert Reichert in something in
the military had absolutely nothing to
do with computers that they have like a
golden ticket to work in information
security and yeah so I want to start
with like a hypothetical story so let's
say that you have an FBI team manager
sheriff I T manager of Fortune 500 I T
manager a startup DevOps Guyana
Pentastar all walk into a bar together
and they sit down and start talking
everyone works for an organization that
runs Windows stack right Active
Directory exchange I S you name it so
the pen tester says hey did you guys
hear about Ms 1500 34 that new I asked
denial of service vulnerability that
came out like two months ago the DevOps
guy says yeah we have combined are
running on top of Long Tan Sri kata
we're watching me get dropped by idiots
in China that are attacking us and our
tools are all adding it to a firewall
rules and it's really amazing it's all
three you guys should check this out its
book its built-in security and and you
know you know props too late for helping
us out with that the FBI agent folds
arms and says the sheriff nervously
folds his arms look at the FBI guys'
what he said the Fortune 500 I T manager
says oh man law enforcement looks all
twitchy and nervous I better not say
anything without talking to counsel
independence is fucking all of you guys
have sent an email in the last week and
your mail headers tell me you're running
Exchange like this shit isn't a secret
why you making it a secret
like you know in meanwhile the SCA in
the GOP are looting everyone in stealing
shit male schools are showing up on
paceman while you have one guy in the
room saying we should all work together
and everyone else in the room saying no
that's classified so that's contributing
to the problem so hiding mistakes
because they might make you look bad
when the prices over at massive
compromise your generally gonna have a
bad time so classifying things a secret
only to claim that you have secrets
doesn't make you look cool it hurts you
and makes you look desperate for
attention so we're all the same side so
let's take that into consideration as we
roll into the stalker so we thought we'd
large ridiculous public fails you might
recognize a lot of logos on this slide
and so these things are effectively
large how not to enforce a sort of
posters for everyone to follow right
solicit this list of companies are
getting bigger and every year it gets
bigger and bigger in the last five years
we've seen effectively more than
doubling of massive public breaches
year-over-year and the overwhelming
majority of these were preventable
everything from preventing very simple
single injection to looking along files
to storing data in not plain text
having competent staff is usually a
really good one even including doing
intrusion detection and monitoring
traffic like a base 101 level so this is
a fancy graphics that I didn't make in
this is just from April 2015 back to
2013 so this is two years of data and
this is like millions of customer
records that were owned because of
simple stuff and this is only the people
that chose to disclose and this was only
the things that affected customer
records of your credit card or something
like that right so clearly what we've
been doing now
hasn't really been working at that have
not been as effective as it could be and
obviously the definition of insanity is
doing the same thing over and over again
and expecting a different result so
should consider doing something
different we're getting better but we're
still hampered by various wet blankets
the following is a compendium of
specific examples of when doing
something specific examples was
something that was done
effective security in a very negative
and dramatic way these examples will be
from a variety of perspectives
the pen tester the atty Dept networking
team the vendors and things like that so
the goal here is not to the goal here is
effectively to describe what not to do
in any given scenario so we'll start
with massive engineering fails lack of
foresight deliberate misconduct
charlatans his employer's reasons
outside of security why security wasn't
a consideration and there's a lot so
sadly I can't afford to issue everyone
in the room helmets I really hope you
brought your own so first we'll start
with deliberate SSL man in the middle if
your organization decides to man in the
middle
SSL connections and the argument is that
it's for advertising marketing or
collecting user data as a security
person in the room effectively it's your
job to tell these guys this is a really
bad idea we should consider not doing it
some of you may remember an incident
when a company called superfish recently
basically installed or less malware on
every Lenovo laptop that they were
shipping their excuse was effectively
that they wanted to do what Google is
doing and USL man in the middle to
capture the things that people are
searching for the text that people
worshiping back and forth to the
internet for whatever reason so that
they could be targeted for they could be
targeted for advertising purposes so
superficial didn't take into account
what would happen if bad guys actually
found their cert and the bad guys did
find their search and the bad guys
misused their cert and they were more or
less shamed off of the internet publicly
so lesson number one don't invade
people's privacy for monetary gain stop
it you can if you can't stop it make it
clear what people are doing is bad news
in trying get it in writing
also don't be surprised if your tickets
hijacked and is used in a very evil way
because you didn't consider that you
were enabling attackers to do the same
people stuff you were doing for the
purposes of advertising for fun you know
we're not going to happen this weekend
here in the user's computer in addition
to the music right so while back and a
lot of you probably heard this one
already
Sony had the genius idea of installing
malicious code on audio CDs I would
install itself on the computer if people
were putting their audio CDs in the
computer to you know rip music I listen
to it or have you so it would phone home
intelligence on the user and it would
modify their computer to prevent it from
copying audio and other things like that
so again if you ever seen a meeting with
someone suggests we should install
software on your on the customers
computers for the sake of DRAM and copy
protection you're effectively if you're
the security person the room it's your
job to yelling shouting make a scene is
this is really fucking bad idea so as
the attorney would put it let's not do
anything that would get a sued so lesson
number two
straightforwardly just don't install
malware and our customers machines right
simple you think this was in Florida
right so you know when you have the
typical
jealous spouse mode where you know I
can't I can't feel safe and secure
unless I know everything anybody in the
room remember Carrier IQ karaoke was fun
so like watching your users type on to
their mobile devices is dropping their
keystrokes isn't really cool no matter
how you try and slice it awhile back a
company called Carrier IQ did this with
Android phones the same way the
superficial this with the Lobos they
installed software at the factory before
it was sold the phones are sold to
consumers and companies like Verizon and
AT&T ship these phones to consumers and
it was installed by default it turns out
later the Carrier IQ is funded by a
company that was known to be a CIA front
fork interesting research they also got
effectively shamed off of the internet
so listen to three simply don't log your
customers if they find out that your key
logging them you're gonna have a bad
time so I know another great point here
is if you're if you're if you're the
blue team person or if you're part of a
blue team in an organization might be an
idea to take into consideration people
leaving password files on their desktops
or in file shares with just like a text
file or Excel spreadsheet full of
passwords I can tell you from personal
experience that I love these as the bad
guy when I'm paid to do a pen tester
assessment and I lose somebody mailbox
right behind us find these uncertainties
desktop it is supremely helpful to me as
the bad guy so routinely folks at work
in offices right password on sticky
notes or are they putting on a white
board with reporting on file-sharing
they put him on
file shares or you know text files on
the Desktop PC five places so another
thing to consider here is that
effectively your inbox is also an easy
easy storage solution for this sort of
stuff and the main company file sharing
is because everyone has access to things
like that at least one employee has done
this at every single engagement ever
conducted and it's been super helpful in
every engagement ever done so in usually
it's been like the head of development
or like the second in command of I T
like somebody that should know better
and every single time it is it is one of
the huge leaps and bounds and I can make
it to go from barely having any access
to effectively owning the whole company
another really fun thing here is that
organizations that set like your typical
you should change this password like
welcome 123 year change me or what have
you
a lot of organizations will set a
password like that like Tuesday cash one
or Monday at five or something like that
and people will never change that
password when it comes time to change a
password like a 90 days 480 days were
over the past policy says if the change
passwords they just changed the number
on the end from five to six so really
easy to guess really easy perforce you
know or maybe this one case the specific
guy he's Microsoft OneNote and he had a
OneNote files full of all of his
credentials for all of his networking
equipment on the database servers all
the production gear everything in in 10
and he I guess you had like something he
he chose his zip up all of his one notes
into a zip file and then email them to
himself and I found them so I went from
one day from 10 cool official one guy
and have a shell in his box 200 now have
passwords to the entire infrastructure
like in one step
I went from like I now have access to
now own the whole shop so you know don't
don't presume that your email box is a
safe place to store clear text passwords
and exploit them and then I'll talk
right so lesson number four with Stephen
Colbert got it right
like gee passers like dick pics don't
leave them lying around for people to
find
presume people will go looking for them
and when they're found your gonna be
really embarrassed you're gonna have a
bad time so almost every company
averaging four as well as sony has been
in the news recently has had this
problem and it's something that people
talk about in the office but I heard so
much like in talks the notion of a file
share conundrum is basically you have
like four terabyte array and everyone in
the company has full read-write access
to this array and everyone reads writes
stuff like a char finance the board you
know the executives they all work in
this giant Open File Share and everyone
has read write access to everything else
so you have like desktop backups and and
people's a very bright of other backups
in people's personal stuff all lives in
the huge file share so you catch it
after hours and just run a search on it
you-name-it passwords passport photos
driver's license photos people's
personal stuff mortgage documentation
like stuff they shouldn't be work in the
first place so it's kind of a gold mine
there I found things like bank transfers
for half a million dollars and up with
signed like people signatures and the
names of everyone who's on the board I
found documentation for companies that
have sold or bought either component of
their business or bot whole other banks
and all that documentation was just on a
file share that anybody could read so if
if if you presume that the attackers are
at least as good as us it's gotta be
considered that this is probably one of
the first places they're gonna go look
so take that into consideration if you
have any leverage in your organization
over the people that keep track of what
goes on these mammoth file shares you
know if I'm the bad guy who gets hired
to attack your shop that's one of the
first places I wanna look so segmented
in some way probably be a good idea to
like rap your file shares and granular
British permissions of some kind at
least down to like the department to
level me look what happened to Sony
that's exactly what happened the
attackers got in I found this giant file
share with everything I just alluded to
this number five
wrap huge file shares with permissions
of some kind right so this is a really
fun one this is a big winner have seen a
bunch of places
network equipment that runs day today at
ninety percent CPU or 90% TCP session
saturation some of you might know what
that means in the crowd but for those
that don't let me explain some
networking gear has a low ceiling for
how many concurrent TCP sessions it can
handle and when that reaches its limit
it starts to drop
sessions that come in which means a sage
sessions Die video sessions died VoIP
calls drop in like the network starts
getting really flaky inserts misbehaving
and this makes people angry especially
if you're using voice because like
important drop down stuff stuff goes out
in a bad time so if you're in the
networking group in your knowingly
letting your gear run that hot you
should strongly consider resigning
especially if you're part of a billion
dollar publicly traded company you're
putting the entire organization at risk
on a daily basis I understand the
budgets can be tough but knowingly
letting your run
knowingly letting your hardware run that
hot is putting effectively the entire
organization at risk and if you're in
charge of security or in charge of
networking in that organization the last
place you want to be a satin for the
board explaining to the board
why you knowingly let the router that
connects your office to your datacenter
run in ninety percent CPU and you did
nothing about it and then it continues
to go down in the developers are having
trouble aboard an ass like why are we
letting you be in charge of our
networking gear if you don't give a shit
about it so the other fun things to do
here is if you're on the security side
of the house you'll hear from the
networking site of the house that you're
not allowed to scan that particular
piece of equipment you're not allowed to
scan that segment of the network because
you might bring something down what is
generally a gigantic indicator of luck
if you're fifty thousand $100,000
$200,000 firewall can't withstand me on
a laptop with nmap get out like I'll do
you not working
get out your an idiot sorry leaves like
lesson six if your firewall can't deal
with an apps can get a new firewall if
your network engineers try to defend a
position in
anyway by running gear at ninety percent
saturation and somehow they claim it's
ok get you get your network engineers so
and then on the same sore on a slightly
different side of that coin the more
than just an organization that
deliberately runs its gear at ninety
percent CPU or 90% TCP session
saturation specifically so that they can
claim security can scan this which I've
encountered multiple times it's so
sensitive you can't stand it no we're
not allowed to do ought to this
equipment
monitored by security or nothing on the
other side of the link is it is allowed
to be accessed your skin because it
might hurt firewall you've experienced
this new organization then you're kind
of dire circumstances because as a
security professional in the room you're
literally at the mercy of a group of
people who have positioned themselves
between you and being successful at your
job so far in every case i've seen this
weird about it the people in charge of
the networking equipment are under
qualified or have no place touching
networking equipment to begin with it's
a precarious place to be in because
you're effectively you're successful in
your job is being limited by people who
look won't let you touch gear that
you're responsible for in terms of
security so you have to it's a really
bizarre place here and you have to deal
with in their social engineering the
group into letting you conduct scan
somehow or or to replace underpowered
equipment so it's just bizarre like
suddenly you can't just be security
engineers from now on I have to be a
politician you're up affect your
effectively up against people that are
like career politicians they will
fiercely defend themselves because their
goal is to hide the fact that they don't
know what they're doing and your
security scanning will illuminate the
fact that they don't know what they're
doing so they will fight tooth and nail
to keep you from doing your job because
it will prove that they're not doing
theirs so don't let you know lesson 7
don't let the dirt metastasize that
cancer grows deep it's nearly impossible
to get rid of dole it under qualified
people dictate how security works a tall
order I know but I have the burn scars
to talk to talk about it so cross
contamination is a fun one network
segmentation is really simple to tell a
very short story one last engagement I
did there was
or on the building that had itself veal
and a to the production equipment which
basically means all of the fun security
implementations all the policies that
were written all the rules that were
thrown down the governance department
had all this oversight their months and
months and months of planning to come to
create an environment where you can
safely get from the office to the
production equipment and some way was
entirely circumvented by the network
group because they decided that was too
much trouble and they were lazy so they
set up everybody on a particular floor
if you were on that floor you can get
directly to like production production
database servers production web server
so I popped up on shelves on that floor
like what do you do why you wasting time
with policies are going to circumvent
the right so it's it's on practically
every assessment of ever done there's
always been some sort of backdoor in
this regard there's always been some
sort of bizarre network segmentation
like they just didn't say anything cuz
nobody is there's no oversight typically
you know the security department or the
networking Department tend to be sort of
the top of the stack there there's
nobody cares nobody cross-checking the
work necessarily in this year
organs big enough to have multiple
networking departments or multiple
departments in most cases 11 so they'll
do it the gonna get away with it
nobody'll notice until some asshat like
me comes by and test and pointed out so
less than eight effectively don't trust
host on the land just because they're
all the land if a bad guy gets control
of that host then the bad guy has
control can potentially get control of
everything that the host can touch so if
you have bypasses on your land you're
probably gonna have a bad time so here's
a passer use let's let's let's beat a
dead horse let's let's beat a picture of
a dead horse to beat the guy beating the
pictures of dead horse pressure to use
is hilariously old topic that somehow
always keeps coming up with the
introduction of a tool like me gets past
three years really becomes a problem
because
instead of dealing with short password
you can have really complex passwords in
their 30 characters long before using
the same complex password on hosting a
as host B which is a different domain
but the passage of the same and I use
many cats to get pass for a I'm going to
use that password to try and get a nose
be so for those not familiar with me
that's basically what it does is it
explains a scenario within Windows that
causes windows to store the clear text
version of your password in in RAM and
it goes to ram and just so you don't
need to crack passwords really much
anymore if you have access to the domain
controller you can you can literally
talk from the domain controller to host
and say hey host this powershell script
and it says here passer and have fun
with him so it's really need it helps
considerably one yes I just mention 11
organization was able to jump from there
from their corporate to me into their
super secure production to Maine because
all of this means reuse the passwords so
I own several workstations in the
several relations got me multiple sets
of credentials to talk to a lesser
number nine don't use the same password
for Active Directory has your Cisco
equipment or other demands if your vote
for my assume that your login creds get
compromised as well and if your login
credentials are compromised you have to
assume that if they're being used
elsewhere in the attack was gonna figure
that out
abused it this is a fun one
I was actually I see this in back in my
system in days so it's really cool that
your boxers have five thousand days of
time and it's really awesome that like
yeah stability but you're running kernel
2442 to that means it's trivial for
people to break into it and I've seen a
lot mainly financial organizations that
they have this abject unwillingness to
reboot anything especially if it's for
the sake of security or patching they
appear to be like completely overtly
allergic to rebooting so while not
rebooting certainly have time it tells
the attackers how older infrastructure
is greatly aids into breaking into those
particular systems so a fifteen year old
operating system Java and Flash from
five years ago any virus hasn't been
updated since 2006 and this list is long
and hearing ridiculous the most recent
occurrence of which I saw was an
organization
15 or so founder switches as their core
switching fabric and they had to reboot
of them in three years so the last thing
they did them all at once and the reason
that I was able to sort of discern that
fact was that they they after after this
incident which happened they admitted
that they run this script every night at
midnight which connects to the switches
and pulls config off them with taxing to
strip at his age and showrunner never
put off to file at some point we got
called in to do instant response and
every single switch went down in a row
one by one until all fourteen or fifteen
soldiers were all down and as it turns
out that they there was a memory leak
that was released several years before
it had been so long since they had patch
this which is they don't they denial of
service themselves because of their
unwillingness to patch like critical
infrastructure within the organization
for something as simple as having it in
the ass and it cost him several million
dollars because they were hosting people
that do stock trading sadly the
engineering people on that organization
are still there and they weren't fired
on the spot so maybe there's another
opportunity for that particular monster
to show its head so less than 10
stability is more important than uptime
reboot his shit and patches or you're
gonna have a bad time so this is a good
one
organizations that spend all of their
man hours meticulously grooming Office
documents usually for compliance audit
reasons instead of actually conducting
any kind of security of any kind there
is no they're not actually doing
anything in the documents are claiming
to do and from what I can tell enough of
the auditors don't bother looking past
the documentation to validate that stuff
is actually happening that a lot of
places get away with this they spend all
their time to the security organizations
spend the time with their faces down an
Excel and MS Word and never in a shell
or you know writing code so when Oregon
I'm aware of would take pen test report
and create an action plan from them and
then when they realize how much for
remediation was going to cost they spent
a month
strategically changing the language of
the report and the language of the
policies to make it look like they
passed all the
auditing so like here's a hundred and
thirty page pen test report they
literally did next to nothing they
changed the policy and they changed the
audit requirements so that they just
barely passed by the skin of their chief
and somehow this is ok and the like
we're doing security no I need scotch
desperately so they just squeaked by
spent months changing these documents in
like shops like sry the security
reactions tumblr exist so lesson 11 if
you actually have to do stuff you
actually have to do stuff to make
security work none of that stuff that
happens in MS or none of that ever
happens in the MS sweet like she just
happened in office it didn't happen in
exchange doesn't happen in Excel happens
in shell prompt and happens in code and
happens in hardware no Microsoft Word
documents Excel spreadsheet has ever
fixed a security posture pro problem and
I never will so please take this into
account when you go back to work on
Tuesday and shake people shaky cam
anybody that's familiar with the term
defense tration it's also an option so
these aren't the droids you're looking
for a good sometimes the answer is
literally running Junos so from time to
time
security researchers will feel generous
and they will find something that they
decided significant and they will submit
your organization the good guy types
will contact the manufacturer of
hardware software and they will say that
there's some sort of critical
vulnerability just to help make life
more secure sometimes offender listens
and sometimes I don't raise so building
up the whole responsible disclosure
discussion this is an example of when
they don't listen to design manufacture
some of you may be aware of at this
point a small one of these massive LED
billboards their configuration is
basically a cradlepoint modem or some
other piece of consumer equipment as the
gateway to the systems are on the sign a
Windows XP box XP emphasize a can access
camera that are sitting behind this
piece of consumer year the company such
default passwords like a lot of them do
and in this case they have two options
one of them is we will take care of the
sign for you and we will be the
custodian of the things that go to it
has not publicly accessible and the
other is here's a sign have fun so
anybody here but that sign in georgia
recently being kinda yeah so there's
this giant like two hundred foot led
billboard sign in Georgia that somebody
found the credentials to which I want
you are really really bad I won't give
you guys the credentials but if you can
find the company name then you know the
credentials they put go to hop on the
sign in this really popular corner in a
suburb of Georgia and it made the news
and people are saying that the FBI and
DHS were involved and blah blah blah
blah so this screenshot here that I have
was an email response I got from the
company to whom I tried to disclose the
problem I think this came in two days
after the sign had happened and on April
8 originally was a month before anything
happened I wrote them as a long email
saying hey founder signs on the Internet
they're all default Reds like this the
pic the cameras that I had up before I
started speaking where several of those
signs the cameras are minimal if you
know the default credit to the camera to
know that if all threads to the sign and
the cameras and I can this is
interesting the cameras are running
embedded Linux over maps and Metasploit
has nips payloads the cameras if you
login as admin have an upload
functionality so if you do the math
MSF mixed a load upload run you have
root on a camera none none of these
things log there's no friends it's
happening here you have like the corner
botnet the corner but it was like tens
of thousands or hundreds of thousands of
compromise can I think there were
cameras on the internet that were doing
some bad guy and there was entirely
because you know cameras default
passwords no logging no security
fun times so this is this guy is
credit he actually called me like
several days ago and he says like I just
want to make sure you understand I'm in
the business networking site of the
organization I don't work on the signs
that the whole different apartment I'm
not sure why they don't want to talk to
you but I wanted to let you know that
there is at least some people in the
organization that care about this stuff
just sadly not the people that matter so
much so this guy went out of his way to
help so I have to give them credit for
that I wanted to assuage any internet
iron that might go his way for not
helping he's he's in the position of
there's another part of the company that
made a mistake and its hands are tied
all you can do is suggest stuff and they
just ignore him so like less than twelve
what a security researcher contacts your
company to tell you about a problem it
means not only does that person know
about it means many many many many other
people know about not saying anything in
in the deliberation that I've had with a
different people on the internet and
Twitter and this guy I'm like this 6
through the seventh person to have
reported this problem to them I just
happened to be the lucky lucky lucky
enough to be the last guy who reported
it to them before there was a big PR
thing like goats on a sign in downtown
so it's the only reason my name is
attached to this in any way it's a
really good idea to take these security
folks seriously if they contact
organization and try and tell you that
their stuff wrong they're trying to help
even if you don't intend to fix the
problem you might want to police take
them seriously because stuff like this
might happen where the researcher will
say hey there's a company that I tried
to help and they literally give no fucks
and that's a problem for a lot of people
expect people that spent maybe hundreds
of thousands of dollars on these mammoth
signs they sell their what they're
usually telling you is at your your
pants down and you should probably see
about pulling them back up so I know the
guy did was to help a company
establishes its stock they had a
moderately to develop security program
and they had a saying they had some
procedures in place and things like that
but during that game there was one guy
who would log into the same highlight
2,000 to 10,000 alert in the same and
just delete them like at a time like
control a boot so I thought was pretty
astonishing and I sort of one white in
the face when I found this out I watched
her do it over and over again every day
so I'm fairly certain the guys still
works there
astonishingly and this guy would just
leave thousands of alerts without any
review whatsoever of any kind of course
as incidents would happen there would be
nothing in the tool that we were using
to track networks forensic happening so
we'd find compromised hosts and then be
no evidence to speak of how they are
compromised hosts they were talking to
on the internet and we're pulling your
hair out trying to figure out where you
how many hundreds of thousands or
millions of dollars were spent on this
seemed to love how many people have
full-time jobs doing nothing but
maintaining this tool and here in 19 the
song just deleting all the evidence of
bad feeling in the entire organ some
people are scratching their heads the
bad guys get stuff how do they get past
our tools and it turns out when you
pointed a guy on staff and say maybe
this guy is actively helping the bad
guys don't like that so much against a
very colorful
lesson 13 make sure that your security
staff knows that there are consequences
to helping attackers especially if
they're doing it out of their own
laziness in situations like that it's a
good idea to make an example out of
these people I mean it's it's mean but
put yourself in the sea so position
yourself as the guy that needs to talk
to the board
you're gonna be sat in front of a board
of people that are conducting the
business and you know they have tens of
millions of dollars in budget and you
have to explain to this this board why
somebody on your staff was actively
deleting evidence that would normally be
used to find bad guys that committed
felonies so you're gonna have a bad time
and now the fun part the penitentiary
fails let me play you the song of my
people getting so we move on the part of
the talk here we're talking about
attackers failing really really hard
it's easy to talk smack as pensioners
really easy to talk smack about about
customers and clients that that fail
miserably and how they're doing security
wrong and things like that and huge
public engineering feels like I'm
described from the point of view
attacker but make no mistake the Act
hackers have derp to the have quite a
lot of derp let me sing you the song of
my people so as it turns out using mass
can on a client probably isn't a good
idea if you have a trench all the way up
firewalls I have deep packet inspection
turned on or next-generation firewalls I
have a bunch of bells and whistles
turned on
literally never take into account the
fact that firewall is going to get
scanned and not always by the good guys
so it's it's it's entertaining for the
folks in the room that remember when
sinn cookies started making it in kernel
like they were invented to fix this
problem and now the vendors have undone
that they've been trolled zine security
in the kernel for the sake of adding
line items to cheat for firewalls now
there are all vendors actually think
this is a security feature to like to
listen on all ports for example if
anyone has ever asked and I think
checkpoint is one of them and a couple
other ones that they think that confused
port scanners your porch and something
and I'll tell you that every single port
is open to that end map that fire was
gonna have a bad time so lesson 14
presume your plants have guys on their
team that run their gear at 90% presume
that nmap Dashti for will take it down
infrastructure also realize that some
genius firewall for world's firmwares
will create sessions for UDP traffic as
well so if you do a UDP scan that's
another sure-fire way of ending up
having a bad time so as a paid attacker
you also have to take into consideration
that not everyone is going to properly
configure web servers are logging
servers are things of that nature seems
database servers in almost every case
pointing a web app scanner at a site and
walking away is generally a bad idea
especially if the extent that's the
extent of the work that you put into the
test if let's see what's happening on
the back end is that every nearly every
40 for 500 200 and every little log
message that you're creating is landing
in a log somewhere and if the client is
following the frustratingly bizarre
school of thought where / var some for
some reason a two gig partition you're
going to fill up the partition with
Apache or nginx logs and it'll cause the
pasta tip over the same goes for iOS
hosts who make a 10 gig D Drive and for
some reason stick IIS logs on the D
Drive in addition to other things like C
so usually one of the boxes go down
during a penthouse clientele after the
bad taste in their mouths and you're
unlikely to see return business
especially if you cause a production
outage so less than 15 don't throw the
kitchen sink at your client unless you
know that they can take it make sure to
ask questions during the scoping call
about how they're logging is configured
where they store databases find the
system in the setup was to give our
petitions and shake them there's gonna
be a lot of shaking on rare conditions
when a customer has externally facing
assets configured to authenticate
against Active Directory you run the
risk of a locking users accounts if
you're if you're doing brute forcing of
any kind and causing outages you're
trying to boot forced some person in
finance and they're working on the
company's quarterly budget and their
machine locks up because their account
is locked
they're gonna get angry about it I'm
pretty sure it's rare to actually find a
shop that has this type of setup
forward-looking brute force exchange
then it will cause people to come to get
locked but they are out there and I've
heard about them you run the risk of
walking the count the risk of locking
the counters higher if you do brute
forcing from the inside
to be sure almost everything on the
inside is gonna have to authenticate
against Active Directory you lock
accounts very very quickly I found it
easier to use something like me catch on
a shared workstation and work your way
up to being a domain admin than it is to
try and brute force anything to begin
with what ya doing admin and all the
credentials you don't really need to
brute-force anymore as if you have to me
that mean you could just targeting
workstation users say I want that person
spreads and give them to you to listen
15 hit them where they're soft not where
they're expecting you should really be
kind of a last ditch effort to begin
with so occasionally mistakes were made
perhaps you're using a system that's
perhaps using a system that
configured using multiple identities
perhaps in on the system using to
conduct fishing expeditions campaigns
and perhaps the drop-down window that
you select Change Idec your identity is
directly above or below the one that
you're using normally day today so maybe
one client accidentally fishes and other
maybe you send the fish from your
personal email instead of the big 12
you've created these things tend to
happen the fun part about this is that
companies rarely actually follow up on
the phishing campaigns if you count the
fish came from looks legitimate they
will presume that account got hacked and
they will not think anything of it if
they even have a response it's usually
just adding a filter to the mail server
or whatever mail processing systems that
use to make sure that that center can
send to the company anymore and just
drop the mail although if you've been
hired to do the sneaky sneaky and you
out of health
you might see points against your the
report it's definitely not a big deal if
you get the access you need a way
meaning if you if you get access to an
organization and they catch you haven't
done the things you did you have a bunch
of shells and doesn't matter if you're
already all over their land to listen
over sixteen details matter when you're
pretending to be somebody else like this
all is said and done last year don't
fuck it up so this is the fun times with
physical assessments it's a good idea to
gauge if the tool that you're using is
the one you should be using to do the
job in this case if you used the wrong
tool on say it kensington laptop tether
the tubular kind and you destroy the
lock you've now basically permanently
tethered this laptop to a task or worse
if you destroy combination lock that
keeping shed shot or get shot or
anything like that you basically
permanently shut the lock until Apple
cutter gets involved so let another 17
don't actually turn to walk into an
insurmountable obstacle make sure that
you don't overdo it so many Web
applications have admin functionality
for GV management and other towards
functionality that will touch files
checked all the things on the back end a
lot of what a vacation scanners will
just blindly scan every single foreman
hid everything a button for the sake of
testing if you put those two together
get deleted database deleted databases
arbitrary files written to the disk
partitions mountain to mountain all
sorts of weird bizarre stuff that's not
supposed to happen
backups of nothing overwritten fields in
the lot of mayhem so this sort of stuff
is why people in the security industry
make fun of what we call scan shops
places that just pointed a scanner at a
website or or or piece of infrastructure
and walk away and you know the work
companies are just run at rule against
the site they call that a penchant for
those thoughts like those sorts of shops
tend not to get a lot of return business
number eighteen don't nuclear customers
web app because you see about
configuring your scanning tool ask these
sorts of questions during the scoping
call because this sort of gig this sort
of mistake could cost the company the
gig or cost you your job and it will
definitely cost you return business so
when communicating risk to stakeholders
or in plain English when telling people
who are responsible for things that
those things might have a problem that
could ruin their day or month or weaker
here it's important to be very selective
about your language I was told a story
once by someone that involved finding
one billion a school system the
realization that this could turn into a
gig then approaching the school and
saying something like and I quote I
found you guys have this huge problem by
how the solution but I'm not going to
give it to you unless you pay me I
forget the exact details since this was
several years ago but I think the words
blackmail or espionage reused and the
guy didn't have a good time no less than
eighteen words mean things they really
do no matter how much you flaunt your
disregarded the English language the
rest of us actually use it the precise
with your words otherwise you're gonna
have a bad time the fun part about doing
attack simulation is the part where you
get a letter absolving you have any
crimes you commit on behalf of your
company for conducting this assessment
it's kind of a get out of jail free card
there really handy to have on your
person if you're doing physical
assessments gives you legal permission
to attack the company like a real
adversary would you wait at least on the
go away in these types of scenarios you
have a physical letter to carry around
in case you get caught so you don't
actually go to jail and a smaller
engagements like extra
the customer typically asks for the
source IP address so that they can
whitelist did or put it in a separate
pile in their learning tools to make
sure that people don't actually conduct
incident response on it sometimes they
do depending on how black bag you this
engagement is renting engagements are
supposed to be healthy and when you're
doing any of this kind of work stay in
Scopus generally a really really good
idea so I heard a story about a guy who
decided to go away off restoration
during web application pentosin since he
wasn't getting his rocks off doing the
web at penthouse he decided he throw ins
and social engineering for free
the short version that went terribly
terribly wrong he got caught and was
basically fired on the spot leaving his
company to deal with the legal
repercussions in a very angry customer
because they thought they were being
attacked and this guy basically
conducted committing felonies because he
thought that it would make him look
better on Pinterest no less than 20
scope is very important especially on
engagements were few people know that
you're coming only give the customer
exactly what they want and what they
paid for anything extra in this case is
like your stylist giving you free extra
work during a haircut
just leave your really pissed off so
it's it's routine to see attorneys
getting involved with reviewing
statements of work in the legal
documentation pertaining pertaining to
Penn tests and especially the wording
and a lot of the details and talking
points the pitfall you can get into his
attorneys realize that they can wedge
themselves into the process and charged
extra hours by changing the wording of
documents in question to specifically
caused the documents to need further
attention by attorneys
specifically if you find that your
statement of work for penthouse
magically now includes instant response
or mediation after the attorney reviewed
it you should make it clear that those
are not typically part of a pen test the
typically separate engagements and they
cost extra if you may also like to
change the language in the contract
protecting you from those ninety percent
DCP section session network and herbs so
they'll try to make that your fault they
will try and put into the document that
if you tip over a firewall you cause
production outage that your company will
be held legally liable even though we
know full well that they're 9% TCP
session that worked for running the shop
so if you breathe on her own little over
then suddenly have a
legal so lesson 21 if the attorneys are
involved you gonna have to put on your
goggles when you're in the documentation
after you get back to the lawyers it's
not uncommon for them to slip something
in there and hope that you don't notice
and so now we have effectively 2021 land
mines let's talk about what happens if
you step on one so if your organization
has a huge failure and it's not on the
news yet there are several ways to keep
quiet or at least lessen the blow if
customer data was leaked then you're
legally obligated to disclose that there
was a breach if there was no customer
delete it then you're not legally
obligated to disclose so this can go go
two ways one you can try and hide it but
when the news finds out you're gonna
look really bad to you can cop to it and
don't lie about your capabilities the
public would rather hear yes we got
breached we know what we did wrong and
we're fixing it stay tuned for an update
on what we're trying to do to improve
our security posture but then you
actually have to deliver you can't make
a statement like that and not deliver
otherwise you'll likely become targets
again shown me if I had to guess I'd say
that Home Depot and target are also
being attacked because of their
lackluster public responses to breaches
don't make yourself the target by lying
to the press
don't talk to the press in the gym they
say something reassuring bland corporate
statement still the attackers that
you're only doing the bare minimum and
companies that do the bare minimum just
continued to get owned in large
organizations there's generally a PR
oppressed department that will do all of
the interfacing with the press for you
if you do your best to arm those people
or that person with the proper
nomenclature to sound to not sound like
an imbecile in-camera the better those
folks look the better your organization
looks and the better you look there the
public face of your response effectively
if you take the time are taken to
conferences teaching how to pick locks
make sure that they are aware that
hackers are actually scary and there
were friendly people they will have your
back and they will take the time to get
it right so attitude counts for a lot
more organizations appear person who
does all the Interfaith Council I if you
if you get on stage
and in front of the press and you angry
or you sound defensive sort of goes back
to the last talking point where you
sound like a lackluster landed public
response or if you don't own up to being
alone and releasing tens of thousands or
millions of pieces of customer records
you're going to make yourself targets
you're telling secondary attackers that
not only do not care about the first
attack but we we continue to get
attacked which basically means other
attackers can continue to harp on your
company and they don't have to fear
incarceration legal recourse timing
matters especially when you talk about
public beaches and talking to the press
if you know that you've been breached
and you have a company blog you wanna
issue periodic updates and how you're
doing in the remediation faces
especially if customer data has been
touched its pointless to try an issue
holler empty bland corporate statements
that mean nothing if you want to avert
the press digging into something that
you said vaguely to try to hide the
truth than you want to make sure that
you give the public what is reasonable
to believe that they want before they
actually have to ask for it
give them a reason to think wow these
guys are on top of this very likely come
out on top
have a plan for when something breaks
take the time to come up with scenarios
of what would happen if and play the
part of the bag I have a written plain
English and for operations team to
follow if anything happens if it doesn't
have to be formalized it doesn't have to
be stand for the company logos as you
can literally just be a turnover with a
bunch of talking like bullet points I
just have to be wordsmith for
consumption in literally just have to go
to the people that will be doing is
response bullet point list preparing
even a little bit goes a really really
long way during instant response so
during a breach nerves will be afraid
people will be stressed and they will be
shouting and likely panic people would
interrupt you with lots of questions and
demands for status updates and during
all of this will likely be pressured and
suffer some level of anxiety it will
help to have sources to look up findings
here is a great one
Intel . critical stack dot com I didn't
put on the slide if nothing else to
start with looking a firewall logs and
outbound traffic on port that your order
doesn't use our country that your or
countries or doesn't do business with if
neither of those pieces of data if you
have neither of those then you want to
get something like security onion
or on some box and you're gonna put it
in line with traffic as quickly as
possible and listen to a top so you can
see what's actually happening so here's
a total of all the lessons learned have
two minutes so please take a photo or
finally for the slide or something up
for a moment but this is effectively the
TLDR for the entire talk to Cassie says
they get jail card only protect you from
company claims and not state claims she
something that makes the state of the
federal government angry they get into
jail card doesn't really help
thank you very much for allowing me to
come here and you guys