hey everyone thank you for joining us
today
my name is anthrax and that would be our
host for the day at Hardware dot IO we
come together to put our brains into
discussing the latest innovation in
attacking and defending Hardware the
objective of the conference revolves
around key concerns related to hardware
wrong way and related protocols today's
webinar is going to talk about denoising
of tempest images on efficient optical
character recognition by Santiago and
yuan they put our researchers at
technology and innovation Institute of
Abu Dhabi so a quick announcement for
the format of the webinar 30 minutes
would be the presentation and 10 mins
would be given for Q&A
all those participants who have joined
us and would like to ask questions to
our speakers you could ask your
questions in the chat option on Zoom and
they would be answered at the end of the
presentation
I would like to also thank both our
speakers to present this latest research
of theirs on our hardware or tile
platform because it's yet not published
completely in a journal there's a
pretext available for download I forget
the publication house but I will get
back to you on that very soon
quick announcement about our upcoming
webinars we have two webinar scheduled
this in this month on the 6th of July by
ma and followed by 30th of July by Alex
so if you're interested in this topic
please join us as well as after this
presentation we expect you to give us a
feedback so that whatever your life what
you're then like that will that was
improve for future webinars and last we
have our upcoming trainings for
schedules in the month of September we
have nine amazing hard way researchers
presenting and delivering and sharing
your knowledge to the community so
please join us for now yuan and Santiago
the stage is yours ok thank you very
much
and Trish so good evening good evening
everyone I will share my screen so
please excuse me sorry okay so as you
said today's webinar is called deep
learning based on the noising of tempest
images for efficient optical character
recognition this consists on two parts
the first part is going to be presented
by me and the second part by one so in
this first part I'm going to present a
little review of what is tempest the
history of tempest and how we can cook
we can reconstruct a video frames from
remote video interfaces a remote display
monitor so the first part from
electromagnetic emanations back to video
frames something about the history of
tempest tempest is an acronym for
telecommunications electronics materials
protected from emanating spurious
transmissions it is a United States
National Security Agency specification
and NATO certification and it
established the requirements for
military equipment protection against
unintentional electromagnetic emanations
zone and Liberation's
so it has been known by military
organizations as early as sixth as the
60s of the past century that
electromechanical devices emanate when
intended electromagnetic signals or
sometimes also sound and physical
vibration and with from these emanations
information can be recovered so this is
an info a security leakage this was
known by the open public in 1984 when
the Swedish government
issued a thin book page booklet with
technical details of how this phenomena
worked at the time and in 1985 a BIM
Banach publish an unclassified technical
analysis of the security risks on CRT
monitors in air in the early 2000s
Marcus Kuhn demonstrated that this also
happened on LCD monitors so whole is
what is happening so we are connecting
an external display monitor with a video
interface the two most known build
interfaces at the moment are busy and
HDMI and the information that is
traveling through the cable from the PC
to the display monitor is also
transmitting electromagnetic
electromagnetic waves if we capture this
this electromagnetic emanations we can
reconstruct video frames
I want to splain you how this is done
but I will explain you with BGA I think
from my point of view it's easily easily
understandable this phenomena from the
VGA point of view but this also happens
with HDMI this phenomena happens with
this point of interfaces and also with
our other interfaces like D V I so how
this is happening we have this connector
a VGA connector the main pins of this
connector are the blue green and red
channels also we have the result of
synchronization pulls the vertical
synchronization poles and for example
let's assume that we are transmitted
full HD resolution of 1920 pixels per
1080 lines at a frame rate of 60 Hertz
if there is this is our solution and
this is our
fresh deflation rate the pixel clock in
this standard is going to be one hundred
and forty eight point five megahertz
this frequency is important we have to
have in mind this frequency but in
reality we are seeing only a portion of
the screen a portion of this data
because in reality the total quantity of
data that is being transmitted is 2200
pixels in in width and 1125 lines in
hive so why is this happening because
the display monitor needs this like
blank spaces to synchronize its internal
clocks so we have this horizontal
backwards this horizontal front porch
this horizontal synchronization
synchronization pulls the vertical back
porch and the vertical front porch and a
vertical synchronization pulls so in
total we are having this amount of
information okay
also it is important to have in mind
that BG is an analog transmit and analog
video interface that means that each
channel is transmitting from 0 volts to
0.7 volts sometimes larger more but
normally this is this is a standard and
to transmit up a middle tone red we will
have to have go into the middle of the
range for example here we are
transmitting 0.35 bolts and green and
blue channels must remain at zero volts
if we want to transmit a pure red tone
and we have to go to 0.7 volts and green
and blue again have to remain at zero
and this happens also with green and
blue channels so the combination of
these three channels and enraging from
these zero volts to 0.7 volts is the
weak is what makes the pearance of the
of colors in each pixels in each pixel
so we are appealing this line by line by
line in kuala scholar rasterize it be
your interface
so we here we can see that we go to 1080
lines but we have also 36 lines for the
vertical back porch and 4 lines for the
front vertical front porch and 5 lines
for TC Clint synchronization pulls in
this standard for example the pixel time
is more or less 6.7 nanoseconds
a line is 40 micro seconds a 4:14 excuse
me microseconds and at in the total
frame is going to be transmitted in 16
milliseconds here we can see also what
is happening when we are transmitting a
grayscale from black to white for
example in white we have the three
channels going to the top of 0.7 volts
but but in reality this is very real we
win we will never achieve these square
shapes of the signals so reality every
pixel has more or less these different
forums and the pixel shape is something
we normally don't know for example here
we have two manufacturers all different
graphic cards and for example the green
and the black shapes are for our throat
meeting at exactly the same frequency
same resolution and not transmitting
exactly the same information but you can
see that the pixel shape is really
different why is this happening because
from the manufacturers point of view
what it is important is to ship
appraises voltage at a precise time the
rest of the pixel shape it really
doesn't matter so this is something
important to have in mind because at the
end we are dealing with a very complex
system what are the difficulties for
capturing the video frames a first of
all we are we all really know the
spectral density of the source video
signal hey we don't know the pixel shape
we don't know how what data is being
transmitted at that point in time and
this also is barra into all the
time so this is a one difficulty also we
don't know the characteristics of the
transmission line we have we know we
have a cable but this cable normally
what is in in length in longitude and we
cannot characterize it and we all know
how this acts as an antenna also and the
signal symbols in this process are very
low power as I told you the peak voltage
for a wide-scale is 0.7 volts and this
grid impedance in the system are more or
less in the in the range of milliwatts
so also we have electromagnetic
interference from the Biderman and we
also have a transfer function function
that we normally don't know now we add
the at the receiver also we are
transmitting Tricia a we have three
channels that are transmitting it's one
each a sequence of data information and
this probably goes to a construct or
destructive interference so these are
the difficulties that make the since
system work like work like a block black
box but we also have some advantages for
example we know that there is a
streaming a constant streaming of video
signals at the moment the display
monitor is going to stop we will not we
know that if we are seeing information
we are between video in the explained
monitor is because there are information
traveling through the cable also we know
that there is an underline central
frequency and this frequency for the
specific case of the full HD is again
one hundred forty eight point seven
megahertz at 60 Hertz of refresh rate
this frequency we also know we it can
prove that the spectrum of the baseband
signal
is going to be repeated itself at the
harmonics of the of this pixel frequency
and we also know that the one width of
the received signal is suspected to be
less or equal of of this frequency
finally wheaton we also know that there
is a correlation ship between the
amplitude of the signal and the
intensity of the pixels in the
transmission in the india in the
transmitted data this correlation ship
means that it is not equal but from this
we can reconstruct behaving so what tool
we are using for this and normally we we
can use an SDR the main reasons are
because obviously because they are cheap
but also because they have they can be
tuned in a wide range of frequencies
from 1 megahertz to 60 Hertz for example
this one and they also have a lesson
bandwidth for these tags mmm for example
this one has a 20 megahertz of bandwidth
maybe this is not enough to recover the
whole spectral density of the base base
band signal but it allow us to recover
part of the information so we did a
little experiment here in green I am
showing you the harmonics of this
frequency of foolish D again 148 point 5
megahertz here is the field the second
theorem so in a harmonic and in blue I
am showing you the quality of the
recovered video frames so at the phaser
money we can see that we can recover
somehow the information also the quality
is not very good at the second and third
harmonic
we are not easily we can not recover
easily the information may be there is
there is interference in that part of
the spectrum but at the fourth and fifth
harmonic the information can be
recovered easily who does the look this
look here we have a reference image here
is how it looks at
at recording at these Philharmonic and
you can see it there is information
there although it is not very good and
the second ceremony you cannot see
anything but at the fourth and fifth
harmonic harmonic you really can see
that there is a reconstruction of the
image there okay so how this is done
here I'm showing you the spectral
density of the SDR centred at 610
megahertz and you can see that this is
all the energy that is being transmitted
by the video interface why do we know
this because here in this waterfall plot
we can see how this was transmitting
information here we turn off the play
monitor and here we turn it on again and
we can is evidence that the energy goes
away and comes back so how do we recover
this and as I told you the amplitude the
envelope of the baseband signal is
related to the intensity of the pixels
so at the end what we're doing is an and
AM the modulation and this is something
that is trivial on an SDR because in and
as here to obtain the amplitude of a
baseband signal we only have to obtain
the amplitude of the in face and color
to information of the of the SDR so once
we have our set of amplitudes we have to
go to a process that is called Rho
sampling for example imagine we have
this reference image and in this
reference image if we are sampling at 20
megahertz if you do the maths you will
reach to a point that per line we are
obtaining 148 samples but in reality we
know that one line is composed of two
thousand two hundred pixels so how do we
convert this buffer
into this buffer okay it's a matter or
something where we have to feed the data
in this buffer maybe repeat for example
this may be something like a fourth 15
times but somewhere but maybe the first
sample 15 times the second sample 14
times this is done very carefully if you
don't do these very carefully in a
synchronized way you will not be able to
obtain your video frames here you can
see after the resampling a process we
can see that there is something there
but it is very ugly
it is terrible how do we improve this we
use a serial of post-processing steps
where for example we use low-pass
filtering out again frame averaging and
we go from this to this which is a lot
better so anyway at this point the frame
is still not synchronized because we are
not seeing you can see it is not
organized that we have to find this
point and after finding this point we
reorganize the information we start to
explain this plain that at the beginning
of this point so now here I'm showing
you a little spring man with it they say
that the setup here it shows an HDMI
interface and we can see that at 5
meters we were recovering video frames
it is everything here that we can see
what the display monitor X is is showing
so the conclusions of this first part
are we cannot recover color but this
doesn't matter because for the covering
text the the system is very suitable
because normally text is a high contrast
information you know text is black in in
front of white background and this tool
will work very good for this so having
this in mind I give the floor to hyung
who is going to explain
we can recover text from this so thank
you very much okay thanks Santiago I'm
gonna show my screen now
okay so hello everyone again thanks for
attending this webinar now I will that
is that I will show you how to process
the intercepted images and so that we
can obtain sharp images from which we
can actually extract information
particular text information so I will
start by explaining first most important
concepts of this deep learning and why
we are deciding to go with a data-driven
approach then I will go through the work
with conductor to capture the data train
and evaluate the models that we've been
working with to pre-process the images
so that we at the end can extract
information from these images so first I
would like to start by briefly
explaining the classic approach to
programming with a with a simple example
in the field of image processing let's
say we want to segment or extract the
position of this red ball in the image
we can do this simply by taking the
information from the image that is in
the three color channel that are
represented by three matrices and
defined fixed thresholds so that we can
extract the color and then calculate the
center of the particular color this is
something that works pretty well that
can be done easily but then what happens
if we want to for example detect another
color or if the lighting conditions
change there's a lot of things that can
change in this setting and the threshold
that we defined from the our knowledge
of the image and of the color that we
wanted to get will stop applying so this
is something that happens a lot in
real-world problems and in particular in
computer vision problems
so now following this classical paradigm
in a particular case several approaches
have been studied in the field of image
denoising in general these approaches
rely on the knowledge that we have
of the particular images and of the
noise distribution that we want to
eliminate so there is one of the state
of the art classical non learn
approaches that's called collaborative
filtering and we can see how this works
in in these images it works pretty well
for the removal of additive white
Gaussian noise but if we try to process
our intercepted images with this we get
some pretty poor results and this is due
to the fact that these images are
distorted by several effects that are
not only additive Gaussian noise and we
don't know the distribution of these
effects so this doesn't work in general
for our particular case um then if we
were for example to take one of the text
image and additive white Gaussian noise
with a distribution that we know then
this algorithm would be really good at
eliminating that noise it's only because
we synthetically added a known
distribution of Y tau from X so this one
applied for four images that's why
that's the main motivation to go with a
data-driven approach and so different
from the paradigm of defining hard-coded
rules we have the paradigm of much
learning where what we do is based on
data we train or adapt mathematical
model which can be a neural network for
example we are that we train its
parameters so that it performs a task or
resembles a function that is described
by the data that we're giving in so for
example we had the problem common
problem in in image processing in
computer vision which is called image
segmentation which basically consists in
taking an image and labeling each pixel
depending on whether it corresponds to
let's say a person or a motorcycle or
any kind of object
so this is a problem that would be
really hard to solve by classical
approaches so what we do here is we take
images then we pass it through a madman
so Network which initially has random
parameters random waves then it will
perform a prediction which will be
really poor then we can compare that
prediction with data that has been
previously labeled then we compute an
error or loss and through a learning
algorithm or an optimization algorithm
we update the weights of the neural
network so that it does a better
prediction so the idea behind this is
that the more data that we show to the
model the battery will start performing
all of the better it will start
resembling the data and this works
pretty well in a lot of for a lot of
problems and has made it possible to
tackle problems whose complexity was
impacts it was impossible to attack with
classical approaches so for example this
tweet says gradient descent can write
code better than you in some cases or in
a lot of cases that is actually true
but of course my coloring is not a
silver bullet to be it's mostly limited
to certain domains and regularly those
were capturing large amounts of data is
feasible or and where the task
complexity justifies capturing all these
big amounts of data so now we have like
I mentioned before what one of the most
common models that are trained through
many learning are neural networks and to
understand their networks we must first
understand the perception which is
simply a mathematical model or a
mathematical function which computes a
weighted sum of a series of inputs and
the capacities sum through what's called
an activation function and there behind
behind this weighted sum is that we can
tweak these parameters so that they
perform the function that we want them
to as good as possible so a really
simple example
for this is linear regression we we
train these two parameters which are the
slope of the core and intersection with
the y-axis so that they are as close to
a given data as possible and something
that's really commonly done also another
problem that can be solved through one
of these perceptions is the promote
linear classification so we in the same
way we will try to find the parameters
that describe a binary decision line
finally some really important part the
perception is the Sigma is the
activation function on one example of
this is for example the Sigma function
which is widely used for example to
transform this course that we can get
from from these equation that defines
the decision boundary to something that
is closer to a probability is bounded
between 0 on 1 so that if we get a data
point that is on the line for example it
would give us a score of 0 and it would
give us a probability of 0.5 which makes
sense if we have two classes fifty
percent probability of belonging to a
certain class and then if their score is
large then it will give us a body closer
to 1 or 100 percent but what happens
when the phenomena that we want to model
with these neural networks are more
complex and have nominees one is well
it's not is basically adding more of
these units more of these neurons and
perform and do have several layers of
this so that we can achieve these
nonlinearities and to train these models
the the procedure basically can be
summarized in first computing a loss
function that tells us how good our
model is is describes the data how close
it is to the data and then we use
gradient descent for that we calculate
the gradient of the loss function with
respect to the parameters of the model
and that will tell us that
correction in which the weights should
be updated so that the model performs
better or or it has a smaller loss so
that's that can be seen in these figure
here for example we start with random
weights and a high loss that means our
model performs poorly and then as we
move on it starts moving in the
direction where the loss decreases until
it reaches an optimal point of course
this is not always that simple
there can be local minima or other
effects that that affect this but that's
the basic principle now that we
discussed neural networks how do we use
them for image processing usually it
well it becomes almost impossible to use
this type of more to their perceptions
for images mostly because it will
require a large amount of parameters and
also there's no important fact and
instead statistics of natural images
away in variants which are intrinsic
correlations among pixels that means
that if we have an image of a cat and we
move the cat inside the image it will
still be a cat or if we rotate the cat
it will still be a cat so that's where
this operation emerges and this type of
neural networks merge the convolutional
neural networks the commotion works I'm
going to eat a bad it can be it's
depicted in these figure here will have
what's called a convolutional kernel
that slides through the input or through
the image basically and computes output
and it does so sharing weights among the
whole image which reduces the parameters
and takes advantage about the fact that
of there's these intrinsic correlations
between pixels so basically what
convolutional neural networks end up
doing is learning hierarchical
representations of the images so for
example here in this image
classification task they'll learn to
first detect edges then detect more
complex shapes
blobs and then at the end in a deeper
layer they will be able to take things
like eyes or mouth or other types of
objects and by extracting these features
then we can do real interesting tasks
like image classification and this is
one of the things that make this type of
models to explode basically and to have
a lot of people using them in the
Philips computer vision is that in 2012
and the progress and the advancements of
GPUs made it possible to use these large
models that emotional networks to
process images and it allows to allow to
increase a lot the performance of these
type of models of image because any
modification test so since then
convolution learners have taken over the
field of computer vision basically ok so
now after discussing these topics we go
back to to to what we actually do to
remove the noise out of this images
which is what we care about so we follow
is we first capture the data and for
this we do is we have these images these
base images that are displayed in a in a
monitor and they have these calibration
patterns here
then we intercept these images through
the process explained by Santiago after
we find the Centers of these images
through trash folding and we align the
Centers of the intercepted and the
original image this allows us to get
aligned pairs of images which is really
important because originally these
images were misaligned displaced and
resized and then we will we do something
called data augmentation which allows us
to have more data and more variability
inside between some of the data so that
we can our model is a even better at
generalizing for new types of data mmm
then once we have this data we what we
do is basically trainer model and in a
fashion pretty similar to what I
explained earlier is we have this set of
nice images we pass them through the
neural network this gives a prediction
which
at the beginning really bad then we
compare that with the original images
and then these gives us an error we
calculate the gradient and then we do
gradient descent to update the
parameters of the model and it starts
doing better and better and this process
repeats for all the data a lot of times
and then once we have this model what we
can do is inference which is basically
showing you images to the model and it
will perform the task on these new
images the connection test the first
architecture we tested was based on the
work by MA on deep learning based scan
texture blurring and these basically
performs pixel level regression so
bypassing the noisy and original images
this model learns the inverse of the
noise transformation that order yeah the
nice transformation that the images are
subject to due to the interception
process so it does the inverse and then
it predicts the original image from the
noisy images since we're dealing with
regression here we use mean minimum
square error loss on a pixel level and
we can see how these loss decreases when
we train this model so that means this
model is actually learning to make the
pixels of the outputs more and more
similar to the original to the original
pixels and so particular is about this
model are the it uses residual receiver
connections which is something really
important in most of this type of models
to allow to allow us to train these
these big models without having the
gradient die in the back propagation
process which is a particularity of
these large models so these residual
connections are really important and the
second model that we tried was is called
FC Hartmann and he's based on the world
by child on if he
image classification it basically has
that encoder/decoder structure this
means that we take the image and we pass
it through a series of convolutions that
reduce the dimensionality till we have a
feature map which is way smaller than
the image and summarizes the important
information about the image which is in
this case the pixels that are texts for
us and then we pass it we do a
decomposition process to sample again
this feature map into an image at the
end there we have is pixel labels so it
will tell us what each pixel what class
each pixel belongs to whether it belongs
to a character or it belongs to the
background and we use cross-entropy loss
in this case that's the last we use and
we can see in the plots how first loss
is decreased and how also they are
curacy for each one of the classes is
incremented that means we're at the end
we're detecting pixels that belong to
the characters with a 60 percent
accuracy which is we'll see what that
allows us to do in the next slides
finally once we have these models that
are able to be noise intercepted images
we're passing through why we use open
sewers OCR model also see our algorithm
which is called tesseract and this one
is basically has four main steps
the first one is adaptive tree falling
which is probably what he has the most
trouble with when we passive the
intercepted images because they're
really noisy then it does officially our
analysis to find worth it
text is where issue each line is and
then it does a baseline feeding to
correct this cue of the images and then
it passes that through an LS TM which is
another type of neural network of
recurrent neural network that also
slides through the text detecting each
character and
particularity here is that each
character detective serves as an equal
to the next step so that text has
certain yeah it has so that the output
of the previous of the Korean character
being detected is an input to that for
for detecting the next character and
then these are the results we obtain
we're measuring how good our denoising
is using peak signal-to-noise ratio so
we start with an average SNR of seven
point seven point three six three and
these decreases this improves using the
convolutional neural network the first
solution in our network to nine point
seven but it's even better with the FC
partner to this level of twelve point
four and we can see some examples here
of how different types of input
intercepted images can be denoise
finally this allows us to perform OCR
and the metric that the metrics that we
use here are basically precision recall
f1 score and accuracy and we can see how
there are original images of course have
a really high accuracy and f1 score
these decreases normally when we do when
we try to do OCR with the intercepted
images it can barely detect any
character and then it improves a little
with the first completion method where
we we saw if there's only improves along
with the FC hartnett so our regression
your network or we can run the worse way
better at at this task in this
particular case and it's even faster
because it's it's a smaller network at
the end we can pass new images the noise
them and extract actual text from all of
these images as you can see in these
examples
so we have to wrap up the traditional
methods make it difficult to process
these intercepted images in our work we
have created a a set of 18 around 18,000
short and we see image pairs are aligned
two models were trained first the
denoising the blurring conversion neural
network which performs axilla
progression and then the FC heart net
which performs pixel level
classification the results as we saw
improve the Pearson R and the best
results we obtain them for the FC
Hartnett and finally this allows us to
perform character recognition and the
results can be seen in the improvement
in the in the f1 score and accuracy in
the character recognition and something
that these proofs is that information
can be effectively retrieved from e/m
emanations hence this is today an active
security threat these are some of the
references and I thank you a lot for
your patience and your attention
thank you very much Santiago anyone for
this amazing presentation we have few
questions in the chat but you know I
would want you to keep it short and
quick maybe like in five minutes you
could answer those questions if you have
because just to keep the interest of
time so you could have a look at the
questions yeah yeah I have look what
some of the questions so first question
I hope can we protect the hard work from
the stated attacks please share the
common standards an operating procedure
squish are effective against RF attack
so I will say that
maybe shielding filters in past luncheon
and hardware level between the cables
and the impedance of the screens and in
pants of the busier interface of the
computer are the main tools you have to
protect against this as I told you
tempest standard is a military standard
and it is known Ultimo also small most
of it is secret it is known that this
equipment is very expensive so you
cannot protect as a military as a
military level protection but maybe in
the short answer is maybe if you have a
next branch display monitor go with the
excellent cable that will help you okay
how far was the air from the cable as I
showed you it was five meters a
curriculum and we used to recreate the
struts of information I told you it was
an easy are the horror horror you
capturing the HDMI signal through the
hot air F it is very strange because
capturing the wire signal seems not
possible to hack RF it is possible maybe
and when you are thinking HDMI as you're
thinking in the digital interface and
will it is true that the clock of this
digital interface is 10 times faster
than taking a pixel frequency for
example if I have full HD we are
transmitted at the pixel clock frequency
was 148 measures and for transmitted of
transmitting and at this resolution on
HDMI we have to achieve a clock rate of
1.5 gigahertz something like that
but anyway that that's not what mean
what we care about because we are anyway
trying to get pixel shapes so again this
works the same as VGA so the language
will be the same and I can assure that
with these words also on HDMI
so what happens when we are there are
multiple screens in the salon okay with
multiple screens that depends on then
there on the antenna if we are not using
a directive antenna probably there will
be constructive and destructive
interference between the several display
monitors and several video interfaces
that are transmitted at that time but if
we are using a detective antenna this
could work this is an experiment we are
going to do in a near future so can you
please share the stud bust a guideline
with equipment part numbers okay the
clip - I told you was an SDR you can use
a hack RF and there is an open-source
tool you can use for this it is very
known we're developing our own tools but
hey I don't know if I can share the the
open-source tool you tell me if this is
possible in the chat it's okay yes you
can yeah I wish I will share it in the
Mon in a moment so what is the minimum
size for okay does I things a question
for one
you
what is the minimum size one you can
recognize with the FC Hornet um this is
a tricky one because the minimum size we
recognized was 30 points and that's a
little big but it depends a lot on the
hardware you used to capture the actual
images because if you have a really good
hardware and you work a lot on that part
then you will have a really good
reconstruction otherwise you will have
so much noise that it will be impossible
to recover any data thus the snr would
be too bad so it depends more on the on
that on the snr than on the on the
actual size that the limit is more on on
what on what type of data we can capture
with this setup and the next question
was is it better no what is the minimum
size on it already I think this was for
you to do yeah is there a better and
more secure standard other than HDMI and
VGA I will say no I think these
principles are the same for all of them
I have not tested but for example VGA
and HDMI are so different and anyway we
can reconstruct via frames so I will say
there is no secure there is no small
secure being interface for this against
this this is the last question that you
have yeah okay thank you very much thank
you everybody who joined us for today's
webinar amazing presentation Santiago
and you are all those who registered
today and attended this amazing webinar
I request you all to please send us your
feedback and what would you like to you
in the future series of hardware or i/o
webinar I'm pasting the link of the
feedback in the chat option so you can
quickly use it and this presentation is
recorded
and it would be available on our YouTube
channel after some editing work as well
so yeah thank you all and stay safe
but thank you thank you bye bye