[Music]
hello everyone
we are back with another cool talk for
hardware dot io webinar
friends we have announced six of our
speakers
who will be presenting innovative new
research related to hardware security
for our upcoming hardware dot io
conference
which is scheduled on the 1st and 2nd of
october
do check them out and if you are
interested in any of our upcoming
trainings
please do register i will be posting the
link
later in the zoom chat today
we have veronica kovac who did her
masters in computer science with the
focus on cryptography and security
[Music]
previously she worked with companies
like tesla
mitre sourcefire and also with the nsa
she now runs her own security consulting
firm called dark mentor llc
veronica is going to talk to us today
about finding
new bluetooth low energy exploits via
reverse engineering
multiple vendor firmwares for those
who are new to hardware dot io webinar
if you have any questions
please use the zoom chat window to send
them across
after the presentation veronica would
answer them
so without any delay let's welcome
veronica
to begin her presentation
thank you ant for the introduction and
let's
share my screen here
all right can you see my screen all
right
yes good thank you hi i'm veronica so i
don't need to further introduce myself
but
uh fans interest me very well that the
information i need to
share about me let's see
and now i'll focus on the uh the content
so
for the next 40 minutes uh let me start
so two years ago i really wanted to
do something new that i had not been
worked on before
so uh two years ago i started
researching the bluetooth
and the for the next 40 minutes i will
share my story
from knowing almost nothing about the
bluetooth to finding remote
execution vulnerabilities
all right so let's see what does it take
to start from the scratch to researching
in a new area like bluetooth so at the
very first
i start with researching the related
bluetooth
security researches from like different
conferences
then i read i started reading the
bluetooth specification
and as many of you already know this
really large specification that
has more than 3000 pages but i didn't
need to
read all of it but i mainly focusing
on the like protocol parts that
programmers often likely make
mistake while they are implementing it
at the very beginning i start with the
uh looking at the bluetooth classic but
then
there was like a mid 2018 but at the
beginning beginning of
2019 i was focusing on the bluetooth low
energy
and this talk we're focusing on this ble
field only and
why i was looking the specification in
just like any other specification
in many cases the words are not
clear enough so i look for the uh
open source implementation and for the
bluetooth classic i couldn't find any
but for the ble i found zephyr and
apache my new nimble
all right and here are
the many protocols the bluetooth
specification defines
multiple protocols like here and these
protocols
can be divided into two layers the
that belong to the host which is you can
think
as you know smartphone or the uh
pc these protocols always uh
reside on the course
platform but on the other hand there's a
this link layer protocol and then d5
layer is always end up residing on the
controller device itself for uh
performance reasons
and the spec also defined this host
controller interface so it
specification defines how this hci
should be implemented
in order to communicate between the host
and then controller here
and this case is for the actual duochie
configuration
as you see there is a host chip and then
there is a controller chip
all right for help on the other hand for
the single chip
configuration that you can often see on
the iot device
the entire these protocols end up
are located inside the controller
device itself and in this case the
specification actually didn't define how
this ht
ci has to be implemented so it is really
up to the
implementers so implementer can choose
they can use either memory queue or they
can choose just not to
have explicit hci layer
all right when i started uh this
bluetooth research in mid
2018 there was there was like
around an hour around here i actually
counted when i based on the public cv id
account
there were 132 cv ids that
the vulnerability has found on the uh
upper layer protocols
but they were literally zero
vulnerability has been found
for the controller specific layer
but right now actually this uh slide
step
was made two months ago but i checked uh
two days ago i count the cv ids again
so there are two more cv ids has been
published but
i just didn't change this slide just
because the fact that
i uh the fact that there is only three
proven ble rc vulnerabilities are out
there
here what i mean by the uh proven is
whether or not our researcher
actually has published the proof of
concept that
can overwrite program counter with an
attacker controlled value
so there are vulnerabilities in this
controller layer got 14 this one is
included
in the bluetooth classic and then ble
but there's only three out there
and one is a bleeding bit maybe some of
you already
have hero which is army's armies uh the
company armies founded and
two other the proven rc vulnerabilities
are the ones
the one the ones that i'm going to talk
about today
all right so now why on the attacker is
interested in this you know below
hci layer protocols
let's say on or take a phone there are
always specific vulnerabilities
in the bluetooth stack but then what
article can do is
he can only target a particular class of
the devices
right if you find the on the pc he
cannot move on to the other mac
because the mac os is different from the
pc
but what about iphone or takeoff on the
vulnerability in the controller layer
the attacker can then now attack
different classes of devices it can be
car it can be those pc or the medical
device or even it can be on iot devices
so it actually it's it's attend the
devices the attacker can attack and then
do further more dangerous in operation
afterward
and today i'm going to talk about the
full vulnerabilities but i'm not going
to very detail about
all of the vulnerabilities doesn't
require any authentication or the
pairing
so it is actually hardening at this very
upfront the protocol is actually quite
important and i prepared two uh
demos for the two uh rc
box now
let's take a look at how i actually even
ended up finding this vulnerability so
as i mentioned
i didn't know anything about the
bluetooth so first was i need to set up
my lab
and here there's a two development
boards here
and in my lab i have more than a dozen
actually development boards but
these are the only two uh development
board that i'm going to talk about today
and while i'm working on working with
the development board instead of the end
product is because
it is easier to uh actually debug
and in the developer actually there is
no like a security mechanism has been
implemented onto it yet
so it is easier to work on
however at the same time this uh
development board is very representative
to the end
product and i will show you like here i
found a vulnerability in the rom code
that means any product we're going to be
have the same
code
and now this is just sharing that it
will be very handy to
for you to have in your lab is
uh when you are familiar with the
software development the easiest way to
debug is a print app
just like that when you work on the the
hardware code
like the firmware then this you diesel
you basically print
and you will need the usb tools serial
converters and i do recommend
to have one that has the cts rts line
this will save you time a lot
right and then you will want to have the
hardware debugger
again here there's openocd i have it
and there's a jailing but this one this
case this one is education
education license one so if you are
working on this
device directly if you are also doing it
as either hobbyist
or you are a student you can use this
education license however you are doing
it for profit but make sure that you get
your commercial license
and i tend to use zlink more than the
open ocd just because
it just it requires a slight more work
to have
uh openocd work at the very beginning
but
if you're familiar with this and then
there is no difference
well like me as a hardware developing
hardware hacking it's not naturally a
hardware hacker but
i have not done it this low layer then
just it's easier to start
with the j-link uh now
next is the uh the usb controller
i think i have a uh folder
uh and when you're running the filter
there should be a way over
uh soft uh way of power cycling with the
software
so i have it this way here and i use the
uh controller when you when uh check out
the github it
has a list of what kind of usb help this
you know software supports
and another one is this over here this
is another controller with a manual
button
this one actually very handy to have in
your lap
next so now when
working with this uh wireless actually i
found very interesting because you know
when you send some stuff but you don't
know whether you actually send me any
packets or not so you do want to have
some sniff or
a way of to see actual packet has been
sent on us
and i used uber tools and sniffle
but there are many sniffers so
you can you know i'm not just doing
surveys because
i'm saying that there's a lot of
sniffers but these are just the only one
that i use
for my work and ubertus is very easy to
use and have a good
console display however this software
has not been updated
so you can use this one but if you
don't have any of this i actually
recommend to have this board
and use a sniffle and actually sniff was
introduced
at the end of last year at the hardy
order i o i really appreciate that one
because because of that one i found
a bug in my father and i could actually
fix it and
i could verify it was working and
his acting was a con and he literally
was interested
last year all right
next all right and for the actual
package generation
i use the this nordic device here
device here and i at the beginning i
start with the
nrf 52a32 that is just because when i
check on this zephyr
and minute i found that there was a lot
of documentation there using this
hardware but guess what this because
this one is an older device that's why
you know
always documentation works this way
right when they write the code then data
micro
documentation and then usually unless
something dramatically changes the
documentation is there so
that's why there was just more
documentation about this board
however when you use this uh board
you have to basically uh connect this
usb to serial converter into this you
know single pins here
so later on you'll find that it is very
cumbersome to move it around this in a
board with attached tools in
many lines so i later on i found that
if i use this another 50 to
840 i didn't uh i didn't need for this
wire with a single pin and because there
is a
this board supports a virtual comport so
i could use just usb cable one cable and
you can see the uart you know debug
messages so
it was way more simple so again if you
do not have
oh actually this code i don't want to
say
i would recommend you to have this yeah
that is because hold on a second
uh and do you see this like a line
i see something yes i can see the green
okay how can i remove this one
uh that should be in your
anecdote uh with an eraser or something
you should have that
[Music]
in this one here oh on the tape yeah
let's see
erase okay all right
so let's see okay should try not to then
touch here
all right all right so now it's already
right okay because i was thinking
okay so since it wasn't removed good um
so i just talked about the hardware now
you will
need a software right to actually
generate the packets
and i already released this jp nimble
which is uh a modification of
apache minor nimble i made a slight uh
modification is because apache nimbo
is supposed to be follow the
specification
and he's doing great job of following
the specification but as a
you know we are looking for the
vulnerability it means we want to
generate the package that doesn't comply
with the specification so i had to
make some modification so at the moment
i released the
this code is actually just a i extracted
some code from my father
so at the moment it uh the one that i
under github has
a way to generate arbitrary packets
for the advertisement channels
but for the data channel packets i will
release at some point but
just it's not there yet but i will lose
at some point
so let's see yeah
so and for this one how it works is
it comes with the two parts one is the
at the formula that is
as i mentioned is a apache nimbus modif
modified of
code and i added some custom hci command
here so and i have a there is a host
code which is written in python so what
happens
is when you generate the uh arbitrary
packets using this python code it
comments to this formula has sent this
firmware
send this packet to the victim
this is how it works
now we are done with the other setup
let's check
the our victims the first one is a texas
instrument
wl1835 mod so
this board was it was the very my first
development board i i got this supports
in boost classic and the ble
and if this board is a development board
however it does not have any jtag or
the serial white or the
swd uh pins are not
exposed so means there is no easy way to
debug
but however i found a way to develop and
i will introduce
in the following slide and
this particular board actually for this
one i couldn't find
uh it's called former easily so i
end up later dumping it the memory from
this
rom and uh by using actually this uh
there is a
wl link wireless tool that is given by
the ti
and you can download this one from the
uh ti website
and it comes with many utilities but i
use the
the hci tester and then the lower the
most
and i will show you in the following
slide
and this case of this ti device
it actually belongs to this duology
configuration
so under this device itself it has only
these low layer protocols
and you can think of this one you can
this low layer is you can think as
blue z in the ubuntu so and they are
communicating through the
hdi layer here
and as i mentioned i could
i didn't have any formula with this
device so how i did
i dumped the memory was there is a
vendor specific
uh command there's a hci vendor specific
read memory
so i could see this one in the ti
documentation
and i could see the uh what this actual
code is
in there one of the supporting files so
i use this uh
command on my ubuntu and actually dump
the entire memory so i now got the
firmware
handy and i analyzed using the uh
ida pro and
okay rather than reading this one i will
show you the one of the
as i mentioned this you know the ti
device does not have any jpeg so
the very key moment i could actually
understand this
cut in the context of the the wrong
content was i actually identified i
could
identify these log functions and there's
a one load function and there's a lot of
wrappers
which i will show you here
and uh the details about how i found
this low function is in the white paper
because if i go through it it takes too
much of a time but let's say i
identify this low function so when you
open this you know just
uh memory dom in the ida you'll see
nothing because there's no symbols at
all
so once i identify identified here
here i could basically
rename this one this is one of the log
wrappers basically there's one
again load function and there's a bunch
of wrapper functions
and after i identify this one that this
low function
turns out to be basically whenever this
low function is called
it will set the level there's a normal
log level there's from one to six for
this particular ti case
and when you receive this uh log id
here r0 is yellow id
and then it adds 30 text 32
to 35 80.
it adds these values inside this wrapper
function
and expect two uh parameters for this
format string
as you see here how i identify it what
is right now i know the low function
and there is like a il i5 i believe yeah
there is a list of strings you can see
this what strings
is based on this number by adding these
two numbers
then now based on these numbers now i
see
which string is being used and i made a
item
python script and i labeled it this one
in this entire format
um not entire just places that i'm
interested in
so based on this i know this string log
information
now i get ah this function is
you know lm true um perform command
function name
by just you know repeating this process
i could understand this you know
uh what rom is actually doing here
all right so basically okay
all right now as you usually when you do
this
this abundance research static analysis
is
make some many times not enough because
by just reading the code is hard to
understand or it is
sometimes it's unclear whether you know
you can reach the
code path so i made the folder
and i could actually generate an
arbitrary code and i could actually
uh see my code has been executed in the
uh
rom code by by patching the
uh this binary and i'll give you a
little bit more detail let's see
okay let me introduce you this one first
as i mentioned this uh
uh bluetooth low layer protocols
uh is located in the rom but there
is a way you can patch it and if you
want you can
uh look at the cortex m3 manual
and there is a section called a flash
patch
and breakpoint unit and you will explain
in very detail how you can
patch this in a rom card and by
uh patching the rom i could see you know
what kind of register you know values
are at the moment in some code when some
code i executed
let me get some water
okay and another thing i found is
while dynamically analyzing this rom
there is a
actually it's easier to show you the
photo
so this one actually show when you hear
this is the one that i actually making
the proof of the concept called
so there here is that the pc value has
been overwritten to 40 on 40 and 41.
this is a
thumb mode and if somebody uh
some of you are familiar with this on i
actually overwrite this one to 40 on
korean 41 but because in some mode
actually the program counter becomes an
even number
right and when you see when i didn't
patch or then i didn't manipulate this
in the rom
this is the output you see in the lower
this is a ti's
utility chest utility
and here you don't see that much of
context
what's the status of this board
at the moment of crash but as i hear
mention i actually the reverse engine
default handler
and i found that i can
oh um okay i could see sorry it was just
too big too small
previously again i made it the bigger as
you see this one's again a foreign 41.
and i found that this one here memory
okay let's go back let me explain about
the uh
the patch one first okay here
as before this logo didn't show that
much
except this one is a 4141 but i patched
this wrong card
so the actual vulnerability is in the
mem copy so just before it hit the
you know the code they caught just
before it
could execute the uh mem copy i actually
the
hook the memory
so i can see what's the source address
and then what's the length that is
fitting into the main copy
and this one is showing the uh this is a
source address and the second one here
this is the length actually been fitting
into
the uh mem copy and i will explain a bit
more uh the disassembled assembly code
in the uh
soon but let's see
next one is the one about the fourth
that i just mentioned
without uh changing this kind of flag
you don't see any detailed information
at the moment of crash but
now i know this and the fort handler
checking some in a flag
and if this flag is set then you will
dump all the register
in the register information
informations and then stack and if this
photo doesn't show that but there's a
you know hip
contents as well in the following
now let's talk about the uh the
vulnerability
and in details and actually i found
these
vulnerabilities probably at the end of
the 2018 but
as i said i was just studying it so i
found it because
i'm familiar with the reverse
engineering but just i didn't know how
to you know
deal with this in the develop a
bluetooth development board so
at the time i found the main copy
the other main copy there's an integer
on the floor but i didn't know how to
reach that code and
later on i found i made a photo
then found that oh there's a crash oh
and did the crash actually end up
then i know integer on the floor that i
found a while ago
when actually at the time i was uh doing
the bluetooth classic
research rather than the bld but
anyhow but it turns out the packet
that i generate was exactly the same as
a bleeding bit
and i it's maybe some people say oh i
read about the bleeding bed
and this was exactly the same field
however the code is different in the in
the case of a bleeding bit
uh vulnerability was a hip overflow but
mine is a step overflow which means as
you uh
know step overflow is more dangerous
because you can
attack it more reliably than the ship
and i report this one may 22 20 uh
2019 and it was fixed in november 12th
and let's see when the attack happens so
when our device start looking for what
is it where uh
what kind of nearby devices are there
then oteco just said
here's the advertisement this is it
basically as you see there's
no other no traffic is any uh
any uh transaction is required before
attack
basically just a victim needs uh
need to uh which is the only
precondition is
big victim should be in the state is
scanning
looking for some other you know
bluetooth devices you can think as you
you know you open your your smart phone
and then you just search in the you know
headphone that's it then i'll take a
send a malicious packet
and now let's look at the
assembly here a bit so the first here
uh stack the
code here just locate the stack memory
space as a
tool hex to see which is do you remember
in the one of the previous
slides okay maybe that's a good idea
it was a i overwrote the length as fc
which is fc is you know greater than the
2c so i was actually overriding the
other
stack memory and
actually vulnerability as you see here
is the one here
r6 has the uh a packet length
it is a packet length field and i can
and there is a
no condition before this uh sub
subtraction here so when r6
value is basically uh smaller than six
then there's an integer on the floor
which means this r6 becomes really big
number as an ffff
in the next uh instruction tool is
it actually do it by extension what it
means is it
make zero uh make zero into data into
the three most significant bytes and
leave the only the least
combined as it is which becomes like a
hex fc
and based on this and calling convention
the main copy
expect is length either as a r2 and
source is
r1 which is a hip address
and our zero as you see here
is a stack memory uh address
so this one end up basically inches on
the floor
leading to the step of overflow
and this is an on uh packet
information here an autek attacker can
basically
set the header type of zero and the
length
field is a true and simple is that
right and then just put you know what
whatever the payload two bytes
and why this is happened i mentioned
this when i was looking for particular
places where the developer we're gonna
make a mistake
based on the bluetooth specification
all the advertisement packets expect at
least
six bytes right so developer may think
okay
there should be six bytes and based on
that you know
assumption they made a call and then
this kind of mistake uh can happen
i mean which i should not have provided
more but you know it happened
so i made the proof of concept and then
overriding the program counter
with the podium 41 actually was easy but
when i actually made
uh try to make uh actually exploit it
was hard because of the uh
existing background about ble
traffic so i come up with an attack
scenario
is a quiet place because of too many you
know background
uh traffic i could not reliably
uh make the exploit working so what it
means is
i can toss all the nearby devices
and there's a lot of more those uh
box than the actually rc box or even the
failed rc box can be used as a
you know those attack so what i mean is
this attacker here want to attack this
device here
but there are so many you know nearby
devices
what you can do is you can just toss all
of them
and send the attack payload
however i'm not on a rear attacker and i
cannot kill all my neighbors
bluetooth devices so what i come up with
is
i have a bucket and specifically i had a
paint pocket
so i made i just uh you know further
cage
out of this paint bucket and you see it
was not enough i couldn't end them you
know team 40
wrapping it and here's my devices which
is a wrap
media paper and tinfoil and this fabric
is artificial fabric
so by just wrapping it up a lot i could
control the background noise
and i will show you the actual demo here
and what happens is now i have a two
actually different machines
and i set up my jackpin in both and
i send the attack from you know over the
air
and now let's see and if you cannot hear
the audio please let me know
and oh this video already have the audio
included so i'll be actually i'll stop
talking while
i'm playing this video
before launching an attack i'm going to
show you nearby ble devices
and you don't see anything with the name
pond on my
neighbor has a smart refrigerator
and i'm going to use btmin to show hci
command and this event to
see the states of the victim
and i'm going to attach the victim
device to this host
and here as you see the host use old
patch
in order to initialize the victim so
this a device still vulnerable
now i'm going to comment for
the victim to start scanning using the
hcl tool here and launching the
attack over the air from actually
different machines
oh now you see there are some hci event
and it actually just uh
reporting the received package to the
host
and uh the author actually succeeded
because
when i scan nearby device again
you see pawn but this victim supposed to
be scanning only
all right i hope you enjoyed the demo
okay next one since i don't have enough
time i was going to skip this of
vulnerabilities
there's a slightly different but if you
want to know the details please check
out my
paper and now let's see the next
target which is the silicon labs
ef uh efr 32mg 21.
i picked this development board because
this
board supports the extended advertising
packets because i wanted to actually
extend my forger and i
needed a victim basically so but this
board is actually
good to debug because it has a data
enabled
you can actually use the gdb to debug
this device
and the bluetooth statistic comes as a
library
and very good thing is it has a symbols
so it's easy to
not easy to say but you know it's easier
to debug
but bad side is you know there isn't
going to be any
novel reversal engineering tactics for
this particular device
and this device belongs to this
dimension the single chip configuration
so entire this protocol resides on the
controller device and
when i uh extend the uh make the
extended
advertisement packet uh fuzzing i had to
actually change the
uh change the my photo lag from
especially because the
at the time i was using the zephyr but
zeppel didn't uh
support the extended advertising
advertisement so i switch it from zephyr
to nimble
and i would start pointing it and
actually find the ghost ball in almost
immediately
and i was in some more days but there
was nothing
that's happening so at the time i think
it's then you know really maybe
the the science code is very good
or my frozen is wrong right so as i
mentioned
at the time i was using the uber tools
but i could not see whether
my package which is really has a really
large package
i couldn't see whether it is valid or
not but i was very lucky that the sniff
was uh introduced at the time at the end
of the 2019 so
i used a c4 and then i could actually
see that when i make really
large advertisement packet it was not
actually being sent
and because of that i could actually
have to debunk the
nimble and it found that i had to
actually arbitrarily increase the
uh scheduler so that the large packet
can actually be sent
so i changed nimble code and
i found the crash right after that
and here i mentioned there's two
vulnerabilities in the design lab
whatever
uh center board the first one is it was
a
dosbox and i'll show you what this is a
memory before
floor i'll go very briefly
there's an image on the floor and i can
make this
r2 value which is a length value really
large
but i couldn't actually make it as rc
that is because
when you see here this r2 value
there is no changes until it fit into
the main move
and before actually the device crashes
i could not have actually uh have a you
know control this on the program
encounters value that means
this is not going to be the uh rc bug
but the dos block
the difference i was just pointed here
uh quick is this one is that the ti code
there was in case of a ti code there was
a unsigned body extension so before
the the chip actually crashes i can have
a little bit of control
but put this outside this case this memo
i couldn't so it one is
those but the other there is
another bug that is a capable overflow
that
and as you you know hip overflow is
often complex so i'll go very high level
briefly
so when this developer received a really
large packet it actually
fragmented into the smaller of the
buffers
and buffer size the hex 49 which is a
weird value
to have you know the actual size of the
uh
memory chunks but anyway the
they manage this in a large uh packet
into the smaller
chained memory uh memory uh chained
memory link
and while they are doing it they made
some mistakes so i end up could
uh override uh well from one memory
chunk to the next memory chunks
metadata and i could overwrite the over
idea
or memory pointer and this is uh
how this packet looks like is uh i put
it as
this is the extended uh advertisement
and this uh there is
included extended advertisement there is
a
nested extended header inside this
payload
and i could set the value as a 3c that
ends up as a crash
and without the detail however i will
show you the cool demo that
i explored this you know that board and
i make the
persistent payload and let's take a look
at this one
so for this uh particular demo case i'm
attacking from the different machine
but there is a controller well i just
put the
debugger attached to the device as i
said this is a single chip configuration
entire protocol is residing on this uh
board but i just connecting to the gdp
just to check the
status of the device and here i'm
remotely
attacking the device and persist by
building the house
so i'll show you the actually how the
persistent work in the demo
i'm going to connect gdb to the victim
device in order to just see the state of
the device
and the client is connected to the gdp
server and i'm starting the
uber tools to see the bld traffic
and i'm starting generating the
molecules packets over the air from the
different machine
and you hear you see they're still here
advertisement
this victim is supposed to be scanning
only
and this share code what it does is once
it uh
exploit the device it reset the device
now i'm going to turn off this victim
device
and it's a little bit slow because i was
recording and i was typing as well
now i'm going to clear this left lower
screen in order to show that
when the victim device is off you will
not see any advertisement traffic
coming out of the victim device
i'm restarting the uh overtooth
and the one you just see is just a
render background
traffic and i'm going to
turn on the device again
now you still see this advertisement
packet
that proves that the exploits persist on
the device
all right i'm going to wrap up with the
uh uh
secret bluetooth security challenges so
they
all the uh low layer device i have
looked at so far i never haven't seen
any
and actually low layer protocols have
any of these mitigation
techniques implemented on it and another
thing is as i show in the demo
uh if on end product didn't
uh enable this a secure board an
attack car can persist on the device and
in the
in case of many chips out there it is
frequently indicated you know either it
does not have a secure
book implement it at all or
this you know and the product
manufacturer didn't have it enabled so
either
didn't have enabled it at all so
it is uh but i see the more newer chips
actually have the secure button the
security set but
still there's a lot of uh way to go
and another thing is now i found this rc
box but then
what does that mean i was trying to
assess the actual
impact of it but it was very hard
because i don't know whether this
what kind of end product using these
particular chips
and it can be just simple as a bulbs or
it can be a medical device if it's a
medical device
then even those having those
vulnerability services can be very
dangerous
and often in a case of the customer list
the event is not going to share it
because that's the company's
secret and by looking at just web
searching
it's very limited that you know you
cannot actually see the
whole you know complete picture of what
kind of end product
right using what kind of chips you know
out there so
this is a big challenge we need to
solve somehow but yeah you are going to
require very you know
or cheap vendors and any other you know
bluetooth device manufacturers and
their help and you can find here more
information
in this github address here and thank
you for
listening to my talk
thank you veronica uh i like those two
cute puppies in the last slide
uh yeah it's time for questions and
answers uh
we have a few questions uh let me read
them out for you
what what what is the tool which
displayed all the
bluetooth logs that you used
oh the at the ti case
right i believe so this was in the
middle of the prosecution yeah
okay that was the uh the when you go to
the
ti website and or you can search for the
uh there is a wireless tools for you
know wl
18 you know modules basically
it is a texas instruments uh provided
tool
so you need to actually register and
then download from their
website all right uh what kind of
mutation did you use
for fuzzing the packets
mutation i actually do kind of very uh
kind of kind of easily it's still
effective as i i use the uh
enumeration rather than just any i know
specific algorithm without using it
but i was focusing on the at the forcing
the field that
you know developer could probably gonna
make a mistake so don't be the first
all right uh can you share the link of
the white paper
okay picture or listen
when you go here okay
it's on the github.com on the github
and there's a publication report
all right yep uh so yeah uh
i think that's it for the question and
answers uh thank you so much
uh veronica and thank you so much
audience for being part of this webinar
we will be recording this and uploading
it on our youtube channel for future
references
uh so yeah thank you everybody
thank you have a good day