[Music]
hi everyone
thank you for joining us on this tuesday
evening i hope you're all doing well
before we start the webinar i'd like to
share some hardware io projects that
we've been working on in the past couple
of weeks
first of all we open the registration
for our berlin online trainings which
will take place in january 2021
we have announced four hands and
trainings which can now be checked out
on our website
also this year we are providing
organizational support for iot security
foundation's virtual conference as a
gold sponsor
which will take place at the beginning
of december
please keep an eye on our social media
platforms because we are giving away
some free passes to this conference
moreover since our fix-up was very
successful during our netherlands
conference we will run it's for
two other conferences as well pain and
space
if you're interested in professional
networking please sign up to fix up
links can be found on our social media
platforms and
on our website
coming back to our webinar today we have
ellis assistant professor at pasau
university with us
who will present her research on
hardware acceleration on reconfigurable
platform for efficient cryptography
design
as usually today's webinar will consist
of a 30-minute technical talk followed
by a 10-minute q1 day
if you have any questions please send
them across the zoom chat
and we will answer them after the
presentation is complete
without further delay i would like to
invite you alif to start your
presentation
thank you very much for introduction
share my
you can see it right
okay great um good yeah so
everyone who's online and also probably
later watching
uh to attend my talk today uh which will
be on hardware acceleration on
reconfigurable platforms for efficient
crypto
so it will be uh i will go
over the details of it later uh it will
be a bit of
basics it would be boring for some at
the
beginning but later i will focus on some
different design i'll be other
exploration
on fpgas
but first i'd like to give some personal
back
to explain like why
or how i'm like placed with this
i typical engineering especially digital
design for hardware design
um and also later masters in
cryptography
so i actually from that point on
combined both
so i focus mostly on design
uh exactly on crypt further
i did my phd in gohan it was resourceful
each other's
mostly known name is lightweight
cryptography
and following my research at the
university for my phd
i switched england and also during my
study
from consultancy and later at infineon i
was mostly focusing on
design and evolution of uh thank you to
my crypto course
later i decided to go back to research
so i switched to
the university of kefir and after my
time in
sheffield just recently i switched back
to germany
thank you intelligent system
i am uh mostly uh interested in
design and implementation of crypto
primitives like
birth city years life-based cryptography
hardware security
especially from my time at infineon side
channel attacks on
security and nowadays security of
intelligence systems using ai machine
learning applications for security
okay so uh today's talk
as i told it will include some basic
information about hardware exploration
and reconfigurable platforms and later
some research details on how we uh
approached or how
these platforms work
uh initially i will give some hardware
exploration details when we use them
and then uh why reconfigurable platforms
are actually interesting
for us research and
i will talk about the need
for this cryptographic book by for
design and actually
the efficiency metrics related to this
example and that i'm going to
give okay firstly
if we focus on the need for hardware
acceleration
uh in general we can generalize that
any computation operation can be
calculated
sorry could you get a little bit closer
to the microphone because you're okay
i i'm also hearing some or like seeing
some notifications about my internet
connections
unstable so it may be related but as
well so sorry for that
okay thank you is that better now
yes okay perfect uh so yeah
again starting from the beginning of the
slide
um so if we talk about the need for
hardware acceleration
we can generalize that any computational
operation can be calculated fully in
software
on cpu that's mostly done it can also be
fully run in custom hardware or it can
be a combination of both where we use
like with the extraction set extensions
where we combine
the best of hardware and software
specifically try to define what hardware
acceleration is especially in the
code design approach it's using
computing hardware especially tailored
to perform from
earth on function efficiently than it
would be
in software cpu and
when we want to use hardware
accelerations is actually especially for
computationally heavy applications
and if you want to compare advantages
and disadvantages of
a hardware and software approach here
of course this depends like what we
select is depends if it depends a bit on
our
application or our need if we need
some rapid developments lower
non-recurring engineering costs or
easy update or patching potential
if you start to talk about a heavy
computation
we need better performance faster
computation time
uh low power consumption and
like figured before before that
application
with maybe even increased parallelism
then
software start starts to have some
disadvantages
hardware platforms start to be more
advantageous
in french cases uh
so some applications
that is like interesting for hardware
platforms or
acceleration hardware platform are
computer graphics
especially the gamers with more
processing applications recently
especially
artificial intelligence applications and
for a long time used in cryptographic
applications
and such platforms so for example as
hardware gpu is graphic processing
but it doesn't mean that it's just used
for computer graphics
but for example there are certain
cryptographic applications
for example person attacks which can be
performed on gdp
or certain dsp blocks on
hardware can be used again for some
cryptography operations
uh but here today uh i'm going to talk
more about like azig
or fpga parts and just the fpgas
and because asic is quite
reconfigured later
but field program data is a
terms where we can actually later
program
uh but before going into that
um i would like to focus a bit on the
cryptology
uh applications again so as i told you
there are different
applications cryptology or cryptography
one of them
cryptology there is like a cryptography
side and cryptalization
these two different applications areas
are actually interesting for hardware
platforms on cryptography side
it would be implementing so yeah
but encrypt hardware based encryption
and also implementing certain
cryptography
applications or algorithms as
accelerators
for processors or instruction set
extensions
for processors here
transit extension with the commercial
example
there can also be secure crypto
protesters where processor
unit itself is also secure through
general
and also some uh other hardware blocks
like
or for team generation could be possible
et cetera
and for the cryptanalysis part actually
we will talk more about the custom
algorithms and implementations of these
cryptographic algorithms
for example i can go home
at a time there was a coca-cola engine
which was used to break
this algorithm uh on
like with a very deep uh budget i think
it put
around thousand or something i'm not
confident about the formation
[Music]
and its successor was reverend so
this was a special platform uh
you because you attack algorithms
uh but there is also a third application
area which is
less explored or less used uh and in
this talk i would like to talk a little
bit on that side actually
uh this one is hardware architecture
to help designing it what does this mean
this is not necessarily about
implementing this is
really designing the crypto algorithm
itself
and uh for this part of application
we would actually need flexibility in
design why
because generally when you
let's sort of cut some hardware it would
mean
looking for some sort of
cryptographic algorithm that's why we
might it
may need to change or try different
parameters
in this search architecture uh
we may have some search con constraints
so we
may need to update these constraints
depending on the context
of first or the design
we may need to update the elimination
so if we are looking for a certain
photographic building block we
check its quality for security
and then we may need to eliminate uh
quality
change the elimination and quality
constraint according or we may need to
add
some more constraints uh but
in general recall figure about
reconfigurability and i said like
software is
easier for that but we still need
hardware acceleration
and even rapid development in front of
project
uh tail or it's not good enough so you
buy a new search
constraint again but that's why we would
still need
uh to be fast that's why we need
hardware
and this is the reason i'm sorry
it's the reason why we would opt for a
reconfigurable hardware platform
is fpga efficiently
um and in this cryptography design they
i will
put on block ciphers and metric
cryptography because
this is a example we have at hand i also
mostly focus on symmetric cryptography
in my carrier so
we will look into the block side so
uh before starting just to give some
details about
block ciphers like very short
fulls of block site that's especially
aes here
in the figure um it has
like different uh 128 bits data size
with different key sizes
um there is also this which is still
used in certain settings but not from
standard but edes is still
used in some some applications in in
certain like political people out there
for example for glock ciphers they are
quite
popular as an embedded application
get more and more pervasive uh present
clefia
prince and krypton are some examples
note that the
metrics about being blind faith or
resource efficient here are
what sort of uh metrics we're talking
about
we may talk about long sleeping area
especially
targeting hardware applications
uh so a smaller area smaller silicon
areas
like targeted here it could be low
latency
so um computing the result the
encryption result as
soon as possible maybe even one clock
cycle
depends on high performance low energy
and power especially
low energy if we talk about some
ambitious applications where battery
power is
important so we would like to stay there
and also if you talk about software
implementations
you may need to have log instruction
and like in current title account
uh so coming back to blockchain first
there are different design approaches
actually to defeat the target
come up with a nice hyper design uh
it could be blocked as a substitution
permutation network
from espn or faisal network or
additional rotation exhaust approach
so here like the aes figure for example
here
is the substitution permutation that
we're getting an advisable
permutation approach a
different way but here you can see in
the figure
substitute bytes the step is actually
performing
the substitution because the nonlinear
operation
introducing the confusion algorithm
uh this is actually the interesting bit
for hardware
targeting algorithms because this can be
the heavier part
so that's why generally low area
targeting cyphers would try to
give this part keep its part as small as
possible
while still keeping the security correct
uh in so here shift rows mix columns
are especially but these are uh
introducing
permutation which is linear layer
and this is bringing the diffusion the
algorithm
and this part may be heavier ford
software of course like
it can be difficult for software as well
but still as lookup tables
we can easier implement this one but
permutation can really be heavy for
software
for example uh if we look at lightweight
present cipher which is very good at
hardware
so it's a low area low cost piper
but if we want to implement this in
software it's a
permutation layer cost for one round
144 clock cycles this is
on 8-bit atmel 80 mega 8a
microprocessor so it's quite uh
closely in software but that would
actually be just wiring in hardware
so uh that's why we should try a
different approach for
better design and implementation of
and that's why here we will focus on low
instruction
and inherent height.com in our research
problem
okay uh so as given in the present
example
uh our targets so we will
we will use uh atmega8a as a
microprocessor platform here
and our target is to achieve the lowest
possible infraction
or cycle count in the in our block fiber
design
and uh this actually the cipher that we
designed
in the application uh it's named pride i
have heard that which is specifically
targeting software implementation
uh in pride as we are targeting software
implementations
uh we in the overall design we targeted
or we took pixelizing into account so we
adopted
a bit slicing for efficient software
implementation
and if you look here at the figure so
the l here would define our
linear layer mathematically and it's
called block interleaving construction
mathematically and you you see p and p
inverse particle
needs additional permutations are coming
for example
from lysine park so just how we uh
put our uh
in registers brings us some additional
permutation at bar design
and uh what's interesting here for the
rest of the blog is
actually the metric part the l1 the lk
for a quite large metric that you here
how we implement l is actually
done in four matrices
uh so we defined a linear layer as a
matrix multiplication
a linear operation as well and as the
state
in pride is 64 bits we
we talk about four different 16 by 16
matrices linear matrix multiplication
matrices here and it would be
used to multiply so for example
l0 would be used to multiply r0 and
r1 registers like
similarly r2 and r3 are used for l1
and l2 l3 so on but we would
have a matrix multiplication like in
four
constant operations to perform the whole
linear layer operation uh
so here what's important is in how many
instructions we perform these
uh l zero through l three multiplication
and this was a research quest question
for us we
decided to look for efficiently
implementable li
uh but the question is uh the question
is looking for the efficient
uh linear layer or the people that
implement a good implementation of a
layer but should we look for the
cheapest
implementation of the given linear layer
l
or if we should focus on
some certain number of instructions and
then we check
if the linear layer being produced at
the end of the
operation is good or not
so that was actually a better approach
to cover
a better source face so we don't
actually miss any good
linear layers like to our best
because we of course have to restrict
some parts
but the result of this or the answer of
this question gives us also the number
of clock cycles
for speed and number of bytes for the
code class
um in order to perform this
search as i say we have to restrict some
parts so that's why we say it's a
limited
route for search for these efficient
permutation mattresses uh we decided
we'll form
the 16 by 16 binary permutation or
linear mattresses
four of them we need four different uh
not repeating each other and this search
was actually inspired by the
s box the substitution layer uh
10 years ago uh in their case they
actually performed the third
on cpu so their first phase was not
uh so large
and it also it was taking more time so
in order to have a faster search and a
larger source space
and this time targeting the linear layer
we opened for the fb
platform um
so we want to perform the search
for the 16 by 16 matrices but our
initial
search effort feel the fact that 16 by
16 was also
uh quite large yeah so that's why we
actually had to think the 16 by 16
uh mattresses in eight by eight form
so we would look we would uh look for
eight by eight
even instead of 16 by 16. we would
combine
four different abcd namely abcd8 by
eight
mattresses to make up one
16 by 16 matrix and then we would also
have another 65 okay so
we are looking for many uh eight by
eight mattresses
first to build a good 16 by 16 matrix
and then from there we
reach to the main 64 by 64
linear layer large matrix
so here the idea was to uh
you remember the research question we
want to answer like
in how many instructions we can achieve
a nice
a good uh linear metric
and that's why we had this sort of uh
like flow where we first have an input
and then
we perform the first instruction
it generates a metric and
it proceeds so this result proceeds to
the next
instruction and then the matrix is
updated there
and it continues here's the example
given
until eight attraction so at the very
end
so in this example it's the eighth
interactive interaction
uh at the end of this parametric
number of interactions we will take the
quality of the
metrics you will see in the next slides
what i mean by
quality and then if this is good for us
then we store this uh and then look for
others
uh and later bc if the combination of
or eight by eight matrices for 16
uh in our constraining what we
actually focus on of course we have to
limit number of possible instructions
yeah so we have to perform a combination
of everything
but of course not all of uh instructions
are relevant for us
so for example here in the able to see
like the definitions of
avr instructions which even includes the
end operation but
for our linear layer search even though
our our architecture
like also support and
we did not include it in the number of
possible
so we focus mostly on instructions
giving
some linear output yeah and here if you
look at
uh for example slab it's the easiest
operation to
see like what we're trying to achieve uh
so you can see the operation uh
that we are trying to swap the
levels of the bite yeah so the the
least significant nibble and most
significant nibble
would change places and if you have a
look at the input output part here
you'll see what it means in terms of
life
if we have uh eight bits bytes like from
x7 to x0 you see that
the actual change so our implements
from x7 to 0 and then the output would
be
x3 to x0 followed by 87 of x4
and uh in general to show like how this
looks
in interaction metrics we were talking
about slap so let's have a look at that
one
uh you can see here i don't know if i
will be able to
show this but here you see
that we have a four by four
block which is all zeros and then
another four by four block which is also
as well normally uh before the swept
the original uh operation original
metric
would look original matrix part would be
here so
this part is four by four with plug it's
fact
with this one and then this one
the left one that left lower one is
switched with
the other one so normally we would have
the diagonal of
one here but as we change the
nibbles it's uh now here
and here yeah so that we can have our
massive multiplication
correctly given the x cube x3 to x0
and x7 to x4 result
okay well here um like
further constraining involves limiting
the number of used registers as well
so we limited the number of use
registers to
two state registers and four
temperatures because
there is no end that one can include
this one more which would increase the
complexity of but we limited this
uh from our experiment based on our
experience
from the experiment at the two state and
four temporary registers
and then also taking into account the
attractions i've given you before
be tried all possible combinations of
these attractions and registers
save the generated mattresses
like which are providing an appropriate
code
and then in the last step we checked
which ones are actually
giving the least number of interactions
so here like when i
say when i say we use a limited number
of registers
before the first instruction we actually
even use just
one register because there is no need to
use other ones but it's not possible
yeah so you don't
have any any other use here and at the
end of the first instruction
there can be like two more
so it's growing like by instruction
and at the end of third instruction
actually all
four temporal registers are possible so
that's why we reached a maximum here and
until the end or one before the end
we continue with four temporary
registers and in the last instruction we
again have four temperatures
as input but uh the last
one would be just one output so again so
we have
one two three uh four and
five different structures you can see
here
the possible instructions include like
for the first instruction
for example we have move clap
shift and i think because
this is another operation i think was it
i think uh and in the first one we are
vomiting
rotate because in this case
a colon the shift operation uh
so we have six possibilities with one
eight and
uh sorry one source and one destination
register
and then in the second one we have 18
plus one
plus one being here the clear
interaction and we would have to do
force and uh two i think here there's a
title
for that two destination registers
and in the third instruction it grows
like the number of instructions grow and
also
like the force registers growth
as well as nation and we have 33
plus one and the one before
uh last would be uh
like like fourth uh source registers in
the
case of exo it would be like and
destination registers also change so we
have
48 plus one possibilities here of
combination
and in the last one as you remember we
have one destination
and a certain number of uh
meaningful expressions
okay so having a general look at the uh
or in computation time and resulting
matrices
uh if we have if we look at an example
of fixed abstraction like computation or
search
uh for the first one we have six
possibilities then 19 34
49 49 like twice repeating
or fourth and fifth one and then we have
the
seventh one yeah this would actually
give us uh like approximately two to the
power of
26 like complexity
so this is actually doable but you have
to remember that
is actually just for one so we are
repeating this number
like four many different files yeah so
we are repeating the same
and i'm checking if it's good and then
storing or not storing according to the
quality check and here you can see like
what i mean so we are following
the number of attractions quality matrix
would be if the determinant is
fine yeah so we are taking the
determinant of the matrix
we are checking the linear and
differential branch number
of cryptographic characteristics
and there are also like other small
like constraints here but these are the
most important ones
and we think if everything's okay
and then according to results we also
have the count of the number of
meaningful
matrices we found so these four are
nice uh mattresses here and also we
store account
of how many of them we actually in order
to perform the search we used
two different uh xylic vertical
available ones at our hand but of course
now
uh vertical and organizing like
different fpgas are available for this
uh and finally we ended up with 36
instructions to implement the whole
linear layer
remember 144 instructions and compare it
to the 36
fractions so it's quite a saving and
actually so this l01 to 3r for
16 by 16 like e
and you can imagine that when i talk
about
seven instructions to build a 16 by 16
matrix i'm actually talking about
combining
four eight by eight matrices uh a b
c d is making up the seven here yeah
and inverses are also calculated so we
also uh
cost of inverse as a metric in our
church
okay uh the general results for pride
as i say the linear layer would be 36
instructions
xbox was also quite cheap with like 20
attractions per round
and regularly update an addition
so we have 68 instructions for one round
of
right so as you see it's again way
better than
the linear layer called the form round
of present
and the cold size would be double the
thighs because it's like
a stupid and
if we compare private other ciphers
actually the best one would be
stake here because uh it's also specific
for proper implementation using the same
microcontroller platform
and it follows a different impact
contraction which is
addition rotation xor so in that sense
we are close to that in the
traditional design because substitution
permutation
so this was the specific
cipher like right it was specific for
eight platforms but
uh current work uh and also like from
future directions
that uh involves uh
pivot platform because 8-bit platform is
not very realistic anymore
so nowadays uh i'm i mean
it might be actually looking at
searching for efficient players which
are targeting implementations on
curriculum platform and as open first
platforms are
more attractive especially five uh
read private interaction set is
our target initially uh but of course
32-bit third
is quite difficult even on
reconfigurable hardware so
a good starting point actually to look
for nice mattresses would be
uh maybe looking at what's good
cryptographic which
mattress constructions have good
cryptography characteristic
and start with them for the
search so that you you limit
the space in a meaningful way
so uh that would be all i think
i'm nearly on time so i thank everyone
for the attention
and is there any question or any remark
there are three questions let me read
them out for you
is it that along the main atmega cpu
you used fpga for achieving this
accelerator
actually we used mostly fpga
and so at mega was
the targeted platform so
we did not uh even like put the
implementation on the uh mega chip yeah
it was so we use the
design uh platform for that so we
wrote our assembly code we simulated
we ran we took our numbers but the main
target for the main hardware we really
at hand was actually
fpga vertex
all right uh there's another question uh
in the hardware acceleration platform
you mentioned
asic and fpga what matrix you use to
choose out of these
for example if it's reconfigurable
we do go with fpga any other metric you
look for
and how things differ in case of puff
so um of course i mean it changes
according to design but
let's say they are really uh going for a
low power design
or or if we know that
it's not a search uh architecture or if
the search architecture
if it's you know that it's not gonna
change ac could be actually a better
idea but
it would take a long time to get the
silicon so you have to plan very well
yeah
so generally it would be the cost
it would be the like power and area
budget
and how fixed you want
all right there's one question from
david what was the utilization
uh percentage of vertex six
clbs for the accelerator
it's a very good question uh it was not
so bad so we could actually fit uh
like a few of them i don't remember the
number i need to take the
paper for that uh i can also point you
to that later
uh but we were able to fit like
if i'm not wrong like
two of them and then we also used two
different platforms
go to different vertex board but we were
able to actually fit as much as possible
from this bus the utilization was also
another metric
in order to make the search as fast as
possible
we also tried to make many
third chords uh like
as small as possible so that we fit more
of them
one fpj and then we can uh maybe
run stuff in parallel yeah so this was
one of the metrics
thanks for the question for reminding us
it would be also nice if you could point
us to the paper
link or documentation yeah actually
i don't know i don't know where where is
the best uh
to share this but it would be the the
paper
having all the architecture details is
in a reconfig conference because
focusing on fpgas like configurable
computing
back in 2013 if i'm not wrong
uh the bright cypher paper
is actually taking the results and
presenting
cipher design and how to implement that
but architectural details were given in
that reconvic
reconfig paper in 2013
and if i'm not i mean
if i'm not from probably these details
i haven't uh mentioned anywhere else so
far so this is the
first place i talk about that it's
generally i present pride and the
results but
the architectural details are generally
like
omitted so it was a nice platform to
actually share all these details
and hope it was clear because it's
quite interesting generally for people
to hear like okay
so this is for software implementations
but you're using a hardware platform
you're performing your third so
it's complicated to explain maybe i hope
it was
absolutely it was amazing to have you
present your research
uh and maybe what we could do is uh
over email we could exchange those links
and then when we upload this
webinar on our youtube channel we can in
the description have the links uh
reference as well so for people to
you know read it later yeah but uh thank
you so much uh elf for this amazing
presentation
and thank you all the participants who
joined us today
if you have any feedback do let us know
where our feedback form and
please give a shout out to our speaker
for this amazing presentation
on social media if you like it yeah so
thank you so much everybody very much
also for inviting me
uh everyone for joining and also for the
questions if there's any feedback i am
more than happy to answer like offline
online
however you like for sure thank you
for sure uh andrea uh had some technical
difficulties so she
had she just disappeared also i'm just
replacing
her okay all right thank you so much
bye