[Music]
hi everyone welcome to another
harvard iowa webinar and thank you for
joining us on
this tuesday evening we have just
finished
our hardware io training and conference
netherlands edition
virtually it was a great success we
believe
with more than 300 attendees of coming
from 60 different countries
and today we have a very special guest
with us
patrick kylie patrick has more than
nearly two decades of experience in the
information security industry
and today he will talk about reverse
engineering uh
uds and firmware on the tesla model as
battery management system
you probably already know the format of
the webinar
there will be a 30-minute presentation
followed by a 10-minute q a
i would like everyone to write their
questions
in the zoom chat box and
so without any further delay uh let me
invite patrick to start his
presentation
okay hello there let me get this uh
presentation going
okay excellent
hey bear with me one second here so i
can move these around
okay great so uh this is a
project that i started um
well over a year ago um i was interested
in just trying to figure out how the
battery management system worked on a
tesla model s i was fortunate enough to
have
access to one that i could tinker with
and um
had root access already so i could peer
quite a bit underneath the hood of it so
it was uh
of all the things that i've worked on
and reverse engineered it was definitely
the most complicated but um i learned
quite a bit
was able to figure out
a lot of hardware components as well as
both firmware and software so it was uh
several different kind of domains and
areas that i had to work on and figure
out
but it was pretty rewarding because in
the end it made the car faster
so a little bit about me um i'm uh
patrick kiley principal securi
security consultant at rapid7 i'm a
member of the penetration testing team
uh previously i've released some
research in avionics security
um obviously like the tesla model s i've
done research in internet connected
transportation platforms
um and then you know hardware hacking
internet of things
uh can bus a lot of the the subjects
that i've
done research on and that i'm interested
in
so uh kind of the topics this is a brief
overview of
of what we're going to go over today i'm
going to go over the architecture of the
model s
the the performance in ludicrous
timeline it's it's important to
understand that uh
ludicrous was announced after uh the
performance models were released and
it's critical to some of the uh
components that i was able to reverse
engineer
if it was done in the opposite order
it's it's likely that
it never would have been successful just
because there wouldn't have been as much
information
out there some of the data that's stored
in toolbox which is tesla's diagnostic
application
used in their service centers and by
body shops
how he's able to extract firmware um
the uds and odx routines those are all
can bus
type protocols that's on top of can bus
and and work
and allow you to really aid in reverse
engineering what's actually going on
when you're
inspecting the canvas modification of
the current shunt
the then some additional firmware
analysis and
where i can take it from here some
additional next steps so
i and then one of the things that i'm
going to really add to this presentation
for those of you who actually saw
some similar work that i've released in
the past i'm going to talk a little bit
more about the security implications
of many of these various features that
we go over
but a little bit about the model s this
is the
model list that i was uh inspecting the
the newer ones that are run
running autopilot 2 and later have a
little bit different architecture
but overall the um the basic layout is
the same
so we have the central information
display
which is also what connects to the
internet and then we have the instrument
cluster
those are running the same version of
firmware but they're just they have
slightly different versions
different versions of hardware on them
but the firmware that sits on them is
otherwise identical those both connect
via usb ethernet internally to uh
an ethernet cable that connects between
the two
um that's really critical for those who
have actually hacked the the vehicles
the fact that there's an exposed
ethernet connection
that they can tap into and inspect the
data going back and forth
the both of those connect to an internal
ethernet switch that's on that central
display of the model s
and those connect to a security gateway
so
uh the security gateway is a lot like a
vehicle firewall
it's not as intelligent in the file it's
more like a packet filter but an ad does
act as a security device
that sits between the vehicles can buses
and the uh the infotainment and um
basically internet connected parts of
the vehicle itself um and then
from there we have the various can buses
there's the um
other can buses for like the chassis and
the body and a few other
private can buses but the one we're
really interested in for the reverse
engineering of this project is the
powertrain canvas that's called pt
um mccain contains the battery
management system the drive units which
are basically like the motors on an
electric car
thermal controllers and other powertrain
related
charging anything that's related to the
powertrain is connected to the
powertrain canvas
it's a standard bosch
standardized can bus that runs at 500
kilobits per second
um uses differential signal signaling
11-bit arbitration ids
and does support uds that's uh really
critical for some stuff that we're going
to
talk about later so uh here's some notes
about this so this is a really good
architecture
if you if you follow any of the modern
automotive
platforms you'll know that a lot of them
are actually implementing this
idea of actually having a security
gateway a security device that sits
between the obd port the infotainment
system
and the various vehicle can buses this
is uh because of some of the
well-publicized hacks
against vehicles where they've been
compromised remotely over the air and
then controlled by sending
signals onto the can bus the security
gateway is basically part of a
defense in-depth strategy to
prevent some of these attacks from from
actually happening it acts as a
filter between these so you cannot
basically
do some commands unless you're
physically on the exact canvas that you
need to be
so it's a really good design but some of
the other stuff had some issues so uh
the tegra 4 actually had a hardware
level flaw
in the bootloader that was publicized
well with a nintendo switch it's the
exact same
type of device so they actually switched
a couple years ago over to an intel
atom-based
system and then the model 3s is
something totally different the model 3
uses
intel atom and it doesn't actually have
those uh separate devices between the um
the the main screen and the uh the
instrument cluster of course there's no
instrument cluster on model 3 but on the
newer versions of the model s
the instrument cluster is just a display
from the main computer it's not a
separate
computer entirely so there's that uh
ethernet's no longer exposed but the the
good advantage for that tesla has on
this
architecture is they can patch it over
the air and you'll see that when someone
has actually identifies a flaw
you'll see the the revisions in later
software actually take care of that
and in some of the more recent ones
they've actually started to do things
like
implement hardware encryption and
some other capabilities that actually
make hacking
the the underlying linux operating
system much more difficult
so uh this is the hardware component of
the battery management system this
actually sits
inside the battery pack on a tesla model
s
model three actually has this inside
what they call the penthouse but it's
also
kind of inside the high voltage
component of the of the model
3 and it's the model 3 is also tms 320
base but
it's it's a little different in how they
actually laid out their architecture
so the main processor on this is a texas
instruments
dsp digital signal processor
called the tms 320 c2809 you can see it
is the smaller chip in this um
sample board that i have down here that
i got off of the salvage unit
uh but there's also a hardware backup
the hardware backups and altera
come cpld complex programmable logic
device
it basically acts in case there's some
type of software flaw
that you won't have unsafe conditions
that exist inside that battery pack so
that
the cpl dx is a backup and
you'll also notice that um there's
expose jtag that was um
pretty interesting it's something i've
been looking at uh it's uh
this particular version has the jtag
headers that i've actually attached
but it uses a standard uh
texas instrument style jtag connector
which is is useful and i'll kind of
cover that in a little bit
but a couple of the other really
important components of the battery
management system
there's a current chunk the current
shunt is a really critical component
that i'll kind of show you in the next
screen that's this device
um a shunt is used to measure current by
uh having a known resistance and
measuring a voltage drop across these
two uh
terminals that you see next to the
contactors that
current shunt is something that has to
be modified for this uh
reverse engineering work there's a
pre-charge resistors the way it works is
one side of the contactors opens up the
pre-charge resistor
slowly normalizes the voltage so we
don't have inrush current and
some damage from that and then the
second side of the contactors is opened
once the voltage is normalized across
those
two terminals of the contactor and then
we have
all these uh battery management boards
that are uh in each of the 16
battery modules these have lead
resistors so that the um
the batteries themselves the individual
series packs of
of batteries can be normalized and you
can have a pretty even voltage across
it i'm monitoring the model s it does a
really good job of actually managing
the the battery voltage and and keeping
it consistent um i've
seen at most like a tenth um one tenth
uh sorry a .01 volts
uh difference between any of the
batteries it does a really good job of
actually maintaining the
level to keep it consistent
so um a little bit more about the bms
again tms 320 uses a ti created language
it doesn't use linux
it doesn't use anything that's that's
basically familiar to uh
you know someone who's hacked any other
various operating systems it's its own
language
the development environment that's used
to develop it unless you're using your
own
tools it's called code composer studio
it is a free download from texas
instruments
and then it does have like i showed
earlier it does have jtag
that jtag however is protected by a
128-bit
code security password so you have to
have that code security password to read
protected areas of memory to do any of
the other various jtag related
functions on the unit um but the
firmware itself is not encrypted
it is pretty well stripped though i
couldn't find anything useful in the
other
firmware hex files um but
some people have actually been
successful at modifying it there are
stories out there about how people have
increased the power on the model 3
and then turned around and sold it uh so
some people have actually figured this
out
um not on the model s the work that i
did used
capabilities that tesla tesla already
did um i just managed to reverse it out
of
some of the other stuff that i'm gonna
go over in a minute
and then of course the the data sheets
for this device they do show the layout
in the memory map so that there's quite
a bit of information
you can actually get about how the
internals of this uh
this system work
so a little bit about ludicrous um
the performance model 85d was released
uh
in the end of 2014 but ludicrous was not
amount announced until about six months
later
so they had the hardware they had it
well out into the industry for about six
months
before ludacris came out and this is
important because it actually involves
some hardware changes
you had to replace some contactors
inside the battery pack that i kind of
showed you
in the previous screen and you had to
replace uh the fuse for the battery pack
itself with uh
one that actually could fire more
quickly they call it a pyro fuse it's um
a component that can handle higher
current and then separate
the two halves of the battery more much
more quickly
but the really the important thing to
notice here is ludicrous are released
after the vehicle is released
um and then the uh the p85d and the
a few p99 90ds the only vehicles that
really required hardware changes
all the other vehicles uh to add
ludicrous they were controlled by a
single line
stored on the security gateway all you
had to do
was you had to add the line performance
add-on
1 to the file internal dot dad
then reboot the gateway and you have
ludicrous
there's there's no signature uh no
encryption it's incred controlled
entirely client-side
um but i have been told i haven't
observed this directly because i haven't
really hacked on a model 3 or the
mcu version 2 of the model s that
they're
using signed configurations now so this
is no longer possible on the newer
models
um but on the older model s's all the
configuration of the car is controlled
entirely client-side
now that's not to say that tesla doesn't
know when you make a change
this configuration file does get
uploaded to tesla on a regular basis
and i've also heard from some people
i've spoken to
at tesla that they get alerts when
people change
their
internal dat files and they don't
line up with what they are expecting on
their on what they call the mothership
side
so uh what about the upgrade um
the older vehicles obviously it's quite
a bit more complicated
you have to do hardware you have to
modify the current shunt you have to
re-flash firmware
um and then finally you reconfigure the
car at the security gateway
so i did this on a donor vehicle this is
the the donor vehicle up on a lift
you can see the battery pack right in
front of the the tires and the
rear subframe this is the battery pack
removed
from the vehicle and this is the uh pyro
fuse you see up here on the left
and the uh the uh module with the
battery management system on the right
see the uh the fuse that's in the car
right now that you see in this picture
is actually older
fuse before it's been removed just where
the protective cover has been removed
where you see the tools right there next
we have
a close-up of one of the contactors
and the current shunt this is the the
new contactor after it's been installed
and then you can see the current shunt
it connects right between the contactor
and the
the rest of the vehicle uh close up of
the bms a little blurry apologize
um and you can see the uh the
headers right there for the jtag are on
that one uh already as well
so uh what about firmware so we've got
the the hardware so we've got the uh
contactors there uh we've got the the
pyrofuse is placed here
now we need to talk about how to do the
firmware so
tesla makes a diagnostic tool called
toolbox
toolbox is a python written
executable that runs on windows um
the important files within toolbox are
contained in these
uh files you see on the right called
scrambles these are encrypted
plug-ins they have the dot scramblings
extension excuse me they're
encrypted rest and then as they're
needed they're decrypted as the
application loads
and the toolbox application was designed
to operate standalone without a
connection to the internet
therefore you can reason reasonably
believe that everything someone needs to
decrypt these files would be contained
on a laptop with the functioning toolbox
executable
you know getting the scrambles
themselves wouldn't help you but getting
a full image of a laptop running toolbox
should be able to figure this out and it
turns out it was
relatively easy someone else actually
did this work they just
shared with me how to do it and then i
proceeded to look at the individual
files so once you decrypt the files you
can then
uh run a python module called uncompile
um here is uncompile six and you
actually see the full source code
with full comments of the author
absolutely everything
um everything that you need to actually
see
the and follow through the various
routines
here we can see that here's uh some
source code comments that actually tell
you
how it works tells you okay
the first verify the vehicle can be
configured for the desired config
for ludicrous mode the vehicle needs to
be all-wheel drive and have a battery
pack config
supports 1500 amps plus current
discharge
so this is actually the routine to
change the performance add-on
instead of doing it manually at the file
it's a toolbox routine to change it
but within these toolbox files there are
also all these variables so you can see
their qt resources
data name and structure you can extract
these out
and then from there run bin walk against
them
once you do that you can actually
take that binary data and extract
even more information including firmware
so the firmware itself
for all the information that you need
was actually stored within the toolbox
executable
and this is uh so hw id that's the
battery pack id from 57 to 70
this right here tells you how to change
a battery pack to support ludicrous
power
you need these three files and it tells
you exactly where they are
you need this gateway application to
calibrate the shunt
you need a bootloader updater file and
then you need the bootloader itself with
the new hardware id
and the source code comments told me
exactly what i needed
so um a little bit about this obviously
leaving source code comments in place
and then compiling uh there's a security
flaw there
leaving the bootloader firmware embedded
in the uh executables that was probably
something they had to do very quickly
and
didn't necessarily get the chance to do
security review on i don't know i wasn't
uh
privy to those conversations but i
imagine that there's there's a better
way to do this
rather than leaving every single copy of
toolbox out there
but some other stuff that's included in
the toolbox the full dbc files so
database can files
were included within all these toolbox
files as well as all the uds routines
and then another thing that they could
have done is using a
application language that was something
different than python python's very
easily reversible if they used something
that
could be more easily obfuscated and then
had stripped everything out with this
reversing effort would have been much
more difficult
up to the point that it's not something
that i would have attempted
so uh all the instructions to actually
upgrade this process were stored in this
here we can actually see what's
the pickle file that actually has the
database can files
there are also odx files that define how
to calibrate the shunt
odx is a uds format for storing
diagnostic routines
there were files that actually stored
all the calibration data needed
uh for the firmware and it was just in a
python pickle format
then of course there's all the uh the
text comments and data structures that
offer clues to the process so
just by following the python executables
finding the appropriate modules and
uh reading the source code comments
we were able to figure this out
so for those that aren't aware of
how can and uds work there's the can
protocol which is like the network
protocol itself
but on top of can so it's actually human
readable there's a descriptor file
called dbc
and then for the diagnostic routines
there's a uh
a scripting file in um
h in xml sorry called odx or gmd
so i used a commercial tool that we had
a license for called vehicle spy
to assist in this research identified
that these arbitration ids 7
echo 2 and 202 from the bms
identify the max current as a static
value
and then there's uh these other ones 232
two from the drive inverters they
identify the max power which is a
variable
and it's based on state of charge
temperature and uh
how much power was used recently by the
vehicle um
this is these are some of the uh dbc
files after they've been imported into
vehicle spy and actually
listening to the vehicle you can see
where they actually take the uh
hex values and decode them so we can see
uh within this how how much torque how
much motor rpm
this is from the uh front drive inverter
with a little bit from the uh
the rear drive inverter di is the rear
drive inverter gis
is the front drive member and uh
from these uh you just import them
directly into vehicle spy
if you need to edit them because you're
uh wanting to to pair them down you can
use a free tool called javascript or dvc
editor
but what dbc does is it turns this this
is just the raw hex
into something we can actually see and
you can see right here uh 232
um max regen power max discharge power
this is before the uh
driving mirrors are engaged this is just
uh standing
power 18 kilowatts but you can see how
much
more easier it makes to understand
what's going on when you actually have
these dbc
files uh in place
here's the dms power
decoded this is after the upgrade was
completed you can see
15 16 amps 1516 amps
and uh drive power max 200 front drive
power max 297 kilowatts
um this is a interesting note that i
made
that uh when you select ludicrous plus
which engages the battery heating
you can see that actually tells you that
it's engaged the the direct signal and
battery heating
that immediately the power went from uh
439 kilowatts to 452 kilowatts
um this was just seconds after one
another so it wasn't uh any other
variables the the pack temperature was
the same
22 degrees celsius same state of charge
uh just immediately there's more power
available
uh this is a uh p90 dl
uh was just uh examining it for uh
differences i had a friend who had one
so we
plugged into the can bus on that and
just looked at how that one was a little
bit different and we saw the same thing
now the stated charge on this one went
down but as the battery was heating up
we saw that more power is available this
one went all the way up to 480 kilowatts
uh for the the max discharge power and
that was at 31
celsius from uh 22. so between 22 and 31
celsius
power went from 454 to 480 and even
state of charge went down about two
percent
okay so uh earlier i talked about odx
odx is the diagnostic routines and this
particular
uh one is what is needed to calibrate
the shunt as well as
do some of the other capabilities
the ot odx routines define things like
security access so
one of the things that we noticed right
away is that
all tesla modules use a static seed and
key for security access
this is a a big flaw
and actually have a little bit of a typo
here it's actually the vehicle sends
zero zero zero one um and then the key
the answer to that is actually the xord
hex 35 response to that but
every module always sends the same seed
it's zero one zero zero zero one all the
way up through zero f it's it's a static
seed and then the response is always the
same so all you have to do is program in
static response to the ascend
and you are granted security access and
you can actually see
with the key you get a good response
back 6706 it actually grants access
so using vehicle spy it was actually
trivial to set this up
um all i did was uh set it up the
request to send say give me a security c
because you need to actually request the
seed and then respond with the
the static key
i'm going to skip this demo right now
because we're running kind of
skip close on time but if you check the
the car hacking village videos you'll be
able to see this exact same
routine run all i did is i imported it
from that
so this is just a video of that i'm
going to skip over it
so having a static seed
key is the lowest possible security
protections you can put on a component
theoretically the module should send
rotating seeds and then you perform some
algorithm against it
but in practice the seed was constant it
was always the zero zero zero one
and you can see that the key is just
simply an xor operation with uh
x35 um so zero zero zero one becomes 35
uh et cetera going all the way up
through um
zero f either way it's a very weak
protective mechanism
ideally there should be some crypto
involved here
involved in the module that makes this
much more difficult
but it's not it's static
so uh the other thing that we had to do
this uh the current shot itself had to
be modified
um there's a wire that
connects from the shunt to the
the backup device if you remember
earlier i talked about the cpld
if this wire will remain connected after
the firmware update then the bms would
generate alert and refuse to close the
contactor so the car would be dead
i found this out by running through the
upgrade process on a bench version i got
a bench bms i got a bench
central display connected everything up
ran through the firmware upgrade several
times and then just
monitored using the dbc files for the
for various errors that i would see
but what this also meant that is that
once the car was up on that lift and
those new components were put in there
um the hardware and firmware had to be
done at the same time
and here is the how the shunt
calibration itself works so we had to
cut the wire
then we actually had to calibrate the
shine and
this is the uds routine for that so we
read data by identifier
um and then from that we actually get
these values we get the hardware id cgi
1 ciu1
the crc value and serial number then
what happens
is that serial number is
red from the pickle file and
the cgi 1 cau 1 values are replaced
along with the new crc
and it actually writes that data
to as a routine control as a
31 uds response so uh after that's done
um it's written like the shunt's been
recalibrated from there
the firmware can be reprogrammed uh
again
i'm gonna skip over this one uh car
hacking village video
i'll make sure that we link that at the
end of this chat
actually has this uh same video running
so just to give an example here are a
bunch of the other
odx routines that we were able to
extract out i only needed those two i
need the security access
read shunt and calibrate shunt but
there are a ton for pretty much every
other single routine that you can
actually run on a model s
these are just the ones for the bms
there are a bunch for all the other
modules as well
uh things from like calibrating the air
suspension to
um you know making modifications to
other components that i wouldn't even
want to contemplate unless i
really dug into it but they were all
stored in these odx routines
um on the vehicle along with descriptors
on what they were for
uh so here uh i actually
looked at how the uds firmware was a
little bit different
um yeah we got a little bit of time for
this so we'll go ahead and cover this
um the firmware updates are stored on
the model s
in a directory called deploy seed
artifacts version two so
a module be like dms and then id would
be the the bms id
and then this file right here version
map to tsv and
identifies the firmware file for the car
they're all stored in hex format this is
kind of a breakdown of how
hex format works so we have the size and
hex
the address of where it goes in memory
uh the record type
the data and then a small checksum
from this i was actually able to import
it into uh
ida pro so from this i you can actually
see
the address where it actually sits in
the memory map off of the bms
and from there i was actually able to
import this into ida and start to look
at it i haven't gotten very far with
this yet
because it uses its own assembly
language and i'm not
that great with assembly but it's enough
that you can actually see the code entry
point
and you can actually see what's data
versus what's code
uh this section where it says data it's
because memory is dual map this is
actually
executable code um sorry let's get back
over this uh
so that's not actually data that's
executable code you can see some of the
uh
jumps here uh but
one of the things i was able to notice
is that
in the various versions of the firmware
there weren't that many changes this is
uh
two different versions of the model 70
bms
firmware and you can see uh just
comparing the two
the changes were minimal um same thing
about the bootloader
we have a bootloader for 57 versus the
bootloader for 70.
the crc changed but um
beyond that it was just a few hex
characters that identified
one bootloader from another one so it's
really really small
amount of changes to the firmware itself
from the various pack ids
one of the other things i found out is
you could take these various versions
and actually find out where they
sat within ida pro
so once you basically took the hex files
imported them in
found the code entry point you can
actually see where the data sat
so i'm making some progress i just don't
have it fully reversed yet
um so we did the upgrade process
flashed the bms updated the internal
that
redeployed the the firmware um and then
uh drive away right no that's not what
happened i actually had
to tow the vehicle from
so after we did everything it failed it
wouldn't accept the uh the new firmware
it started giving me errors from the bms
had to tow the vehicle from california
to nevada where i actually did the work
uh wasn't terribly expensive but it
still was painful and
and nerve-wracking
but we're able to get it done but what i
figured out is that
the gateway itself has a secondary file
that it uses for validation
this uh file is called firmware.rc
i'm assuming rca is not short for crc
because it's
filled with csd values and the gateway
uses this as a validation check for the
components so if you go in
and you put in a new drive unit that's
running the different software the
gateway is not going to allow the car to
turn on
because the firmware broadcast from that
drive unit is going to indicate a
different crc from what it expects
um found some references to
to this file in the error logs
so i went to the gateway and i requested
this file i noticed it
saw the bms you can see line five here
says the bms
was wrong for what the actual firmware
should have been for the vehicle
uh so all i had to do was go in here
replace the bms line
recalculate the crc which is a jmc rc32
then put the file back on the gateway
after i did that the car woke up
the errors cleared and we now had a
ludicrous vehicle
so uh here are some notes i made that's
the power
before and after the upgrade before it
was 1305 amps that were available
after it was uh 1516.
for some reason uh after several
firmware updates it dropped down to
1492.
i i don't know why still trying to
figure that out i've seen other vehicles
that don't have that uh
extra you know 24 amps missing but uh
still it was quite a bit of an increase
over 1305.
um so it does seem possible to increase
speed beyond low request that's kind of
like the
the goal of the other stuff not sure
i'll ever actually do it on a vehicle i
just want to see if it can be done
but there's a guy out there who's
actually taken a rear-wheel drive p85
and really increased the speed uh beyond
what it what it should be we just need
to find those variables within the
firmware up them jump them up a bit
modify the crc values the problem is
it can be really dangerous to do so
these battery packs they run about
twenty thousand dollars
uh we're already dealing with pretty
high current drain
um you could end up burning up the drive
units igpt's which
is really bad you could pop cells in the
battery pack or worse cause a fire
the other thing i want to understand is
what those shunt parameters actually
do i i think cgi is something to gain
but i have no idea what the other one
does
uh here's some the reference material
some of the acknowledgements
uh bitbuster he allowed me to use his
garage
in rancho cucamong to actually do the
work and uh
any other information beyond that i want
to say thank you for
listening to this presentation so i know
we've gone over about five minutes but
uh
at this point i think we want to open it
up to questions
um hi yes thank you first for your
presentation
um we have one question asking
the firmware was not encrypted and not
digitally signed
uh so the firmware that's that's kind of
a rough question i'll try and answer
that in the various sections
the firmware for the car itself the
entire max firmware for the car
there is a signature process for that
there's an updater process called cid
updater the way it works is
um it checks with the tesla mothership
it downloads firmware onto the vehicle
and then it does go through a signature
validation
on older versions of the vehicle there
are ways around that
but it does actually do a signature
check on that
for the rest of it it appears to just
use the crc value i'm not actually
seeing
anywhere where it indicates the actual
like drive unit firmware
or bms firmware has any type of
signature
beyond the crt check that i kind of
covered uh near the end of the
presentation the gateway itself uh
does appear to have some checks and i
think newer versions of the vehicle
have moved towards both encrypted and
signed firmware
uh but i know unless mcu one
versions of the model s there's still a
lot of hacking that can be done there's
a lot of
ways around the various security
protections that are that are on the
vehicle
okay thank you are there any more
questions
okay i don't see hey let me um if i
could let me uh
get that car hacking village video real
quick okay sure
so we can include that in the chat
value
sorry i should have this book marked but
i don't
okay
okay so there we go
that's the uh the the deep dive that
actually shows those exact
videos that are recorded of the the two
various um
uds routines actually running on a bench
version of the battery management system
so you can see those
okay thank you for sharing the link with
us yeah
are there any more questions
no i don't think so oh yeah
can you please explain how were you able
to make out
the uds routines
so how i was able to decode them
the uds routines were actually stored in
odx files within the toolbox firmware
those odx files could be imported into
vehicle spy
or you could if you're really good at
reading xml you could just decode them
yourself but
it was just a simple matter of importing
those odx routines into vehicle spy
and you can see everything you can see
what all the routines meant and
what they were meant for as well as all
the descriptors but they're really just
xml files so
you can kind of poke around them
yourself they're just
not as easy to read as if you import
them into a commercial tool that's
designed to run odx routines
does that answer your question
all right excellent okay
if there are no more questions then i
would like to say thank you for
uh having this uh webinar
and guys if you liked today's webinar
please
leave a feedback for us i have shared
the link
above for the or the feedback form
and also if you are interested in a
social networking session please
sign up for a hardware i o fix up
okay thank you all thank you