[Music]
so we will talk about era of shadow
games here is like a very generic
plantation which will introduce you all
the this the aspect of radio and what we
can do with software definite video so
let's let's go so just you know for to
introduce myself Who I am I'm Sebastian
Dudek I'm the founder of don't-ask
we're doing a lot of research on radio
trainings also hardware and software
division use tools we interesting about
SDR at a hardware Arif ID Wi-Fi a lot of
technologies so whatever frequency of
radio frequency has a lot of history it
was like she also created so in variety
it was you sorry you know right you for
rather radio navigation jamming bulky
bulky and so on now we be doing we we
can see it in a lot of aspects like
wireless television mobile phone
satellites access control systems for
example now today which is like a lot of
numerics thanks to GSP which is the
digital signal processing and also we
have to know that in each country the
emission and the reception is regulated
by your country so if you want to to
emit our receive signal in each country
you you have to have a license for that
you know if you you want to use only the
reception know you can always yoga with
the rod the low but now if the emission
is something else so if you viewer tends
to we meet I'll just know be aware that
it's not allowed in your country also
radio of characteristics in review we
have to be aware of many characters
characteristic sorry as the the
wavelength the celebrity of the other
radio wave the period the frequency
which will also determine which which
also device I will use
which antenna I will use how far we will
go my icing now so this is a lot of
aspects you to techy backgrounds are
working with radio also to process the
signal we have to represent it in time
domain so we have two main step to do
it's the first do something which was
for all the continued singer to
discrete-time signal and the
consideration which yelled the value
discrete the binary number Daenerys like
you know 22 bit floaty number and then
also when doing the sampling there is
something important to you to be aware
of at the beginning it's the Nyquist and
Shannon theory because if you've done
don't sample enough you are like for
example just you know you you're sorry
up I'm trying to it's oh sorry I was
like just trying to use that's so error
in that example it's an example when the
sampling do something
there's new questions something for
frequency is respected so we can see
that the signal is processed very well
but in another example we can see that
we have some Allison aliasing here
because the Shannon frequency is not
respected and so this is the main things
to know when we attend to processor
signal at the beginning while using a
radio also there's a lot of tools in
radio we we are we need to use like the
DFT which is the discrete Fourier
transform which allows you allows us to
to know the the composition of the
signal and also see at which frequency
we we can we can have the signal and how
what are the Al monix that are
interesting to use TD here
and also in radio you know why we we
should be interesting in radio because
there is a lot of targets the targets
are the following like the access radio
access controls the mobile phones
navigation systems autonomous car in the
short system so radio can be very
interesting to study because of that
because like for each system there is
like we can find a lot of numerology
relatives too if drooping replace our
injection relays jiaming dose and so on
so there's a lot of university to to so
to find in this system and now we know
that a lot of system use radio with the
radio system to communicates so this is
a very interesting things to know as an
attacker because if you are if we all
out you choose sniffer signal a week we
are able maybe two if drop senior
replace it or also inject some traffic
to control a target so this is why it's
very interesting you know also as a tool
before we it was like very complicated
to interact with a signal but now with
the the yes dear the software definite
radio we are about you to do all the
work with just a little device which can
be generic or specific to to to some
frequencies and does audio digital to
analog and also the analog to digital
conversions every from liquification
mixing and a lot of stuff and the rest
is done in the software part that means
that you do all the modulation on the
motivation and so on so you can studio a
signal at a very low level and there is
a lot of devices available in the market
here are just known exists exhaustive
list here where you can find some some
you know some reserve that can do a lot
of stuff like this do the USRP but also
cheaper ones like the ref but there are
f2 also here and there's also the SD
just also a little bit cheaper and if
you want to do some minimization with
you if you want to do some very
minimalistic device you can also use the
exterior X which is also a very very
generic that's also to be a being Geryon
generic other cost it has a cost with
the price but also a cost with
performance and some some generic
purpose devices are not sensible enough
to to be able to capture signals at some
some frequencies so this is you know
something that can you know can happen
also if you want you to choose a device
also just you know don't look just on
the supercut supported frequency which
is interesting at the beginning but also
if you are allowed to to do the full
deep lexing and also look at so the this
sampling because as I said before
sampling frequency is very important to
take in accounts while doing processing
the signal so this is an other stuff to
do to see also this clock stability and
then the other stuff like the price the
the the antennas present and also
something interesting or form
forwarding all the samples to your
computer and backward it's so important
you to choose the right abuse interface
because if you use for example USB the
tubers like you know very slow to to
forward all the traffic to the device
and also to up to all the traffic so you
know look at all these specifics before
choosing your one device then you have
to choose an antenna as I said we have
to take in account characteristic of how
radio wave but also as many a
characteristic you can find with antenna
they are usage frequency the
polarization the directivity the
dimension in shape world and so on so
everything can you know each
characteristic can have an impact
of you in your capture or well when you
want to interact with a signal when you
want you train to do some observation in
the air are they are they are like very
very good spectrum analyzer like this
one which caused a lot of a lot of money
but when you you don't have a lot of
money I prefer to use for example a
cheaper cheaper device like the air
effects power which is like a gadget but
very useful and also we are also
practical because you can transport it
everywhere you can just show the kids in
your pocket and you can so do some
observation but I know yes I know it's
you know it's sort of jig gadget but so
very very useful sometimes then also you
can so to do you observation using
easier with G critics and also offer a
software like H as their as their job
and so on it's also other tools in
Windows for example here first which is
their their chopped off so for Windows
here is also a very very good spectrum
analyzer because it allows you to detect
some pics if you are interesting if you
don't know where to look and you just
want you to find some interesting
frequency you can always use this dist
analyzer to find some interesting pigs
there is also the sick digger which is
used for reverse engineering but also
for reverse engineering you will see
another tool which is very practical and
in which I use every time when I deal
with very simple modulations ordinary I
use like a new radio but there is no
this not only neural do you have also
photos days do you're also red oak as
the rare but new radio is like no the
most use a software so software this
near review software to control the
devices and also you can you know
control if you python in or see most
boosts in pythons you could you can
create signal and fro graph
and also we can do it's also in the in
suppose blues it has a schedule which
allows you to start stop and wait for
operation so this is no this is a little
schema in the rights and how it is
composed then if you want to create a
flow graph you can use you can do it but
by the end that I don't recommend it so
mainly I use the new radio companion
which is very practical to build all the
blocks and create you FRA graph and
process your signal at the beginning you
start with a source block then you use a
sink with a 52 to know to determine
which frequency is interesting
interesting interesting for you sorry
and then now you can you can do all the
stuff by you know accusing some
informations after doing some process
when analyzing the signal you have to
determine the frequency so you have to
look at the shape also to do see the
motivation and sometimes if you deal
with very simple modulation you can
perfectly see that you are dealing with
a s key or a whiskey and other than
other modulations sometimes the shapes
is complicated so you have to go deeper
by looking at the transmitter specs so
sometimes you have to see the the the
chip specs and also using the specs try
to demodulate it they modulate the
signal
sometimes the chips also use different
types of motivation so you can you don't
know yet which color modulation is used
so sometimes you also do some brute
forcing you can also then use the blocks
to you need to process all the signals
and then at the end you have to decorate
with so the signal genera also protects
it's little bit protected just to check
if there is no error on the on the on
the codes and so on so you will use like
assuming / one like which is under that
but then Manchester and so on so these
law a lot of also of work to do on
decoding and also on interpreting the
signal because of also the application
layer to decode
then like said before alternate targets
use a RF communication attacking them is
very interesting because no all the
audio signal are broadcasted in the air
so all you have to do is listen by two
to find something interesting try to
deny modulated take out it and then see
if there's some leaks or something you
can do if there is no for example
application layer encryption of any
other things that you can play with or
you can for example replay the signal to
see what happened if the if the targets
will try to communicate with you or or
repeat same packets so there's a lot of
of place to do and then yeah I was like
I was like not motioning the tools but
so about reverse engineering this is a
very useful tool if you want to deal
with simple modulations like s key FS
key for example and this is particularly
in for a very simple modulation
particular you just what you have to do
it sometimes you auto detect all the
parameters and while while while opening
a file I capture file and then you will
have all the information decode it's
sometimes you have also to do some
manual configurations but that depends
generally it's automatic you know
January but sometimes you have to also
to do some so many other things and then
you you are about to decode simple
modulation is Kiev s key so this is a
very practical cool well but also these
like very good parts in this it's the
analysis which is not in the slide but
the analysis part allows you to also to
to assist you while decoding some or
some packet so you can also do all the
reverse engineering after the
demodulation
she's quite good example of target so
here we will see some targets so we have
played with an Assyrian so what we can
do with those targets you have like
firstly we have very simple devices very
simple
that depends of the of the other devices
but so generally in industry all
scientific and medical frequency bands
you can have like poem materials dual
birth alarms two remotes and a lot of
stuff that's you know sometimes a lot of
times then do not implement a lot of a
lot of features to protect the signal
sometimes you have also running codes so
that depends but generally you can
easily decode all those signals and this
is the kind of subjugates
device you can find like you know
remotes for error rules parameters you
know this is like you know a very old
technology that is commonly used but
slowly is is replacing by a by other
technologists generally a new a new
targets you can find some some
protections like roaring codes and other
things which which are used to protect
the the messages from you know from if
dropping or replaying attacks but that
depends also on the on the price of the
device which frequency you can find in
the those bonds so if you can find those
frequencies now may be aware of those
frequency that are commonly used but is
plenty others that also find in this in
this category also in more using the own
mobile network if you if you want to
play mobile network targets you have
like a lot of targets like intercoms
delivery pickup stations
electric electric counters counters
cameras alarms cars so there is a plenty
of them as you know let's let's see the
intercom that's used today because now
interrupts
not wired they use remote the remote
communication like gsm 3g 4g or Wi-Fi so
we can do a lot of stuff like for
example for intercoms that are connected
to the the mobile network as your we can
for example try to catch the the the
intercom using the handler behavior and
then try to try to impersonate a
resident phone to open the door and so
on so these like a lot of play to do if
you want to detect those kind of
intercom you can detect it by some
modules that are exposed externally like
that and why intercepting the resident
phone we can for example while you are
trapping the the intercom to your
network you are able for example to see
it's interesting call it number that is
used by in the intercom to call the
residents and by impersonating
impersonating this number you are you
can you you are about to open the door
of the of the front door and go to the
residency so this is the kind of thing
that you can do with the mobile network
devices including all the devices like
also I mean say also you have alarms and
so on if you want for example to
impersonate a new number or what you can
use by example with liberties it's true
to do this configure configuration which
allows you to but the the written form
and associate it to you IMSI and then
you weaving in tag with intercom urges
to register to you to you to you network
and also you attacker phone registered
to the network you are able to
impersonate the number and then open the
door after after after pushing the
button that's is supposed to call the
residence to open the door you can also
open with by sending the SMSs and also
other messages over SMS so our alum
station
how it can be how it can be like very
different yeah I was like our stations
not this not this light is not good I
was like sure I wanted to talk about
also 3G and 4G targets 3G and 4G 4G
targets pretty the same but it's used 3G
and 4G but that means that you have to
do mutual notification attacks and that
is not it's very complex and not
possible so what you have to do with
many to break the modification by Dan
graddic the signal and then you are
about to trap the intercom which you use
3G what is in person important also to
know here is is that preaching in Forge
intercom but also I think for 5g and
others will be able I bought you
communicated communicate with intercom
sunrise server which means that also
this server is used to configure AIT's
the intercoms remotely so the intercom
are always like pulling the
configuration from the server and it's
also supposed to be a managed by an
administrator which can be the residence
but also some specific administrator and
that the disk this this centralized
server can be managed via yeah the web
all over daenerys like you know a simple
web interface that that allows you to
manage all the inter comes here you can
manage and that you can for example in
that specific scenario you don't need to
any SD device to do that so you can find
maybe a vulnerability on the web server
and target other the resident of the
intercoms that are connected to the
server for yeah what is set for 3g and
4g targets is like a used me to
ratification so it's difficult to spawn
a station at this level so it's
difficult to you to trap and come which
use region for you so your to doing
great it's using the GSM communication
how to do great it it's not a simple
things but so you can
use some jamming attack I like for
example bring your Chinese device to do
that very cheap or other devices which
are a little bit heavier and difficult
to to bring with you and less mobile but
you can also perform that in SDR I know
that scene has the room it's complicated
because edge devices cannot Jam all the
the signal in the same time but so you
can also proceed with some small jamming
attack which means that for example I've
created a tool which aims to map all the
these cells interesting cells and then
use those cells that I target to jam
them so I just you know focus on
specific frequency to jump so this is
like no we this is what I called smile
jamming it's like well jamming just you
know at the time each frequency that's
are used by an operator for example so
you have also to target specific
operators and with one device or two
device you can jump pretty easily
without having to bring a very very
heavy jammer with you intercept cows is
very interesting because if you know if
you don't know yet you have a v8 system
which allows cows to to do all the
infotainment all the stuff like you know
you can also play with applications you
can you have also Facebook Twitter on
that and we're intercepting this
communication you can find interesting
things because we can see all the
application that are at a communicate
with servers some servers that you can
intercept and then you can see some
interesting IP calls for example when
the the IBA of the car wants to upgrade
his humor and all you see here is that
he's used also HTTP and not not
encrypted layer so yeah that can be very
interesting interesting if the the
application layer is not encrypted as
well also what is interesting that in in
this industry
you can find a lot of interesting things
like all the injuries because no those
devices are not old but it's like you
know example it's not that those devices
are all but the D concepts is has been
for thinkit's before and is maybe you
can find this system from ten years ago
that are still in the market and which
is interesting that for that is that for
very very new cars you can you can find
some old Android and by by just finding
this kind of Android you can you can
just think about how much severe you can
use against his own rate for example we
we know that's a decent rate is doing
some requests to web request so we can
fight we've had Java Chris JavaScript
interface interface a severe air so you
to get our ego remote code execution on
that and then attack the the a be a part
of the car you can also attack for
mobile network by using the the software
drug which is called DSL service LTE
which has a serious UE which is like you
know a software emulated user equipment
and now allows you to go with very low
level and try to find some some bugs in
in the mall by operator apart but it's
like very complicated because in these
parts you even maybe if you if you about
you to crash a cell or I don't know you
are not able to debug what is happening
in the cell path so this is like no but
this part is interesting if you are able
to debug the the cell you are fudging
but in a lot of case it allows you to
see what happens in a low level but in
the baguette but not more about my
grades
it's smart with many about the issue in
the past about power voltage if
we look at the history it's also an
interesting thing because I choose an
interesting nice drink and interesting
our aspect of the power communication
and yes it's it aims to manage all the
the small-scale energy production nodes
and it includes a lot of targets you can
see in the white like smart meter smart
appliance real energy resources and so
on Allah also cows
if you want to Deckard so this signal is
not as easy because there's a lot of
process to do about the OFDM
demodulation about that what many views
is a specific device that is about to to
be plugged and for that if you are if
you interested you can see the the proof
of concepts on v2g injector which is a
tool that is made to to to penetrate a
network that is established between a
cow and a charging station remotely even
even if you you can you can even use it
in a residency that is connected to the
same electric electric power network as
a smart charging station and you can use
that taught to do that but if you want
to go deeper in radio energy you see
that in the power line communications
the signal is superpose the data signal
is superposed to do to the power pole
line a power line to the power sorry so
this signal you can find any in many
frequency between 1 2 8 and 30 megahertz
and this is the kind of things you can
see what we've done
I have like an intern before when I was
working for sylheti who made a small
modification on the the plc and this is
a unplugged PLC that was made that was
modificated in a way to plug an antenna
and that way we were able for example
true
an oscilloscope today that you you see
that some some tiny palumbo of home plug
home plug line communication devices
could be seen like that
so we then try to process it using the
same implementation as the wine project
which is called the you see which is the
Wi-Fi there we new radio implementation
of the Wi-Fi sorry which allows you to
do all the demodulation for Wi-Fi that
this implementation you can also use
against Chelsea but trying to do that
with an old us a PVR we didn't had a lot
of success so we try to also reverse
engineer the Defamer to understand it
and also you see that there is in an
interesting thing which are the SPI of
the other of the power line
communication that allows you allows us
we inject some some code on the in the
ROM and then we can for example you do
some introspection but in radio some
researcher also makes some very good
work on that by using a blade Arif for
example and in v2g they were above
example to to sniff the home plug
Greenfield frames that are slower than
complicacy
in residences but but it was like a very
good research because it it proved that
remotely in the air we can we are about
to to to do with dropping remotely and
they also publish a tool to do all the
demodulation and also to process the
signal in a way to get a were shocked
capture recap capture about error
fighting if you we want to go very
deeper and in a low level it's like we
have to deal with with very very
specific devices but no but when you
don't have specific devices
that's our Allah that allows you to to
capture those frequency on between
hundreds 25 kilowatts and 13 megahertz
so you have to use an up cover to do
that and that way we are able to snip
those frequencies using the heterodyne
and then you know we can simply D
modulate the signal which is a ski in
example so we can always go deeper we
first year we can study every signal and
also including air Friday but if we want
yeah it's like you know I didn't choose
the direct Peter for that but if you if
you want to study the rare Friday I also
suggest you to look at the proxmark
which is like a very generic tool it
allows you to also to study other air
Friday aspects on 'life HF and tags and
winners I tell her it implements a lot
of technology also to decode demodulates
and to do all of the work also it has
like a lot of tools like automatic
search for technology and also auto
pound features to automatically find
Keynes fine keys for example in Mifare
classic bags so tella it has a lot of
features there is like there is like a
lot of others technology like Laura
bluetooth ZigBee so as I said as there
is like a way to do everything you want
we have just you to you have the the
main prevents that it takes time to get
into it but once you are you know once
you are like more use of it
you all are you allowed to do everything
you want so I suggest you two to work on
it it's a very for me it's very very
interesting and a very interesting
subject so if you have any question
please ask and I have I have finished
for these little presentations
and I hope that's I was like clear
enough about all the aspects but is this
pickle also too to explain all of that
so in a small small in a short period of
time but so if you have any question I'm
pretty easy available so if you have a
question please ask and thank you very
much thank you Sebastian
I think we already have questions coming
up in the chat so if we can go to the
chat you will see a lot of questions
coming up
that's weird because I don't see maybe I
have to split off stop the sharing maybe
better like that so if you open the chat
window yeah there will be few questions
in that it's your things so no hi it's
about saying thank you very much fold
okay
may I ask what kind of sitting hardware
and software you will recommend for
exploring gsm word please
so yeah Bob if you want to study the GSM
parts precisely you don't need you don't
need exactly the USRP stuff but you can
already use the blade RF which is quite
cheaper than the other than us RP and
that will allow you to work work on that
but just be aware because maybe the
better of 2.0 is not reported that she
had bit yes but I'm not sure right now
because I have only the diversion one
but yeah if you want to do that I work
among you
using the yet bit years because a bit
years with letter F is is very good to
study all the GS m aspect any resource
yeah there is like you know I think that
all the resource can be found in you
know a lot of websites I think that's
there's a lot of tutorials I also try to
to get sometimes to do some resources in
my blog but is yeah there's there is
like you know some some websites like
cig wiki that you can use for example to
get some resource on a lot of signals
because because it's like your library
with a lot of samples you can find in
the air so if I recommend you to if you
not sure about a specific signal in a
specific frequency you can always look
at
see wiki website but also captures in
github and other tutorials but yeah it's
difficult to to recommend one precise
resource is like also a great cause cut
gadget which has a lot of resources to a
lot of introduction about Reggie of
stuff there's also my training which is
like intense in four days where I I go
through all the aspects of radio but so
many also in the office in offensive
parts which aims to to explore the
targets we are targets and how to
interact with them and how to attack
them so so yeah there is also my my
training that I promotes sorry but you
can find pretty much a lot of resources
everywhere but so if you not sure about
so one signal what's missus fix you know
maybe try to you look at sig vici for
example or get terrible I don't know I
to make sure which will relay attack
here really attack attack stats when for
example you want you you have you are
like in my demon in the middle position
for example you have two targets and
what you are able to do is to with the
attack for example to change to do some
bit flipped or change some specific
aspect on the corrugation of the the
packets that are ascended or example we
can try to just you know to swap a
little bit the packet that sent it from
one client to the server or you can just
relay them to two for example in the
scenario of of cows for example if you
if you have a batch tag that is supposed
to open the car you can also really
relay the communication between one one
interceptor and the DA layer that will
that will open the door that's that can
work for for for a lot of technology
like maybe normally for cars
but that depends also on the technology
because while I was like speaking with
Philip and another guys who does the
training in RFID about is it possible to
relay simply the communication between a
tag and in an access control he said to
me that so days like also a timeout that
is has to be respected between the tag
and in the in the reader so it does not
work for for a lot of it does not work
for some technologies but for others
technology you can always try to do that
and what evolutions testbeds
test beds for test bits I recommend that
depends of the technology we want you to
do you do to study if you want to study
for example RFID I recommend you use for
example the proxmark and then you can
you can also use another FPGA we just
also the RF part that allows you to do
they do really attack but also for other
technology you can use usurp e and try
to relate the communications like for
example just you know using your source
that so will will capture the messengers
and will relay them with another antenna
which will transmit the signature to the
device pretty far away to try if the
relays work or not but that depends
always on the technology
see see wiki exactly how can we go about
using my attack on the Wyatts IP
surveillance come on IP servers own
server arm surveillance cow I can yeah
you can can try to to fetch the the
modem and the y5 mod and Wi-Fi issue
modem that is used by the device but
with IP services come I recommend you
maybe look at the double layer that that
allows you for example to spell hot
spots
that's all try to to reach the
application part because I think that
maybe the application part can be more
interesting than the radio path the
radio part for IP svenska come can be
interesting maybe for or if you have if
you can find a vulnerability on the on
the Wi-Fi stack but also maybe try to to
do some Daniel services but I don't see
any other attack like like that maybe
there are some butts or means like
mostly about trying to find an ability
on the Wi-Fi stack and do some marginal
in your off services thank you so like
you say there is a ski is a ski FS key
but it can be decoded easily is there
any technique that you can make it out
to decode without some info can you do
in by degrading to GSM yeah so I mean
that's SKF risky how no easily can be
easily decoded
but all those does modulations ordinary
this is the application part that can be
used to encrypt the communication or to
protect you know product the
communications from configuration
confidentiality so can always use make
use of the application power to do that
but so to make the decoding harder is no
it's
it's going like you know we're gonna
play with the cats and the mouse so are
generally dealing with those modulations
no it's a pretty easy for for someone
who is used dealing with those
modulation and organization but you can
always always try to complexify the the
communication that I using encryption
and other things but in the upper layer
and what do you do I'm into the red the
GSM what I meant is that yep
I present it's presented it's very
quickly done reading the communication
is like to jam the communication of one
specific frequency for example and for
the mobile part if you operator use for
3G this cell which is connected which
connects the intercom or the mobile
together you can for example try to win
to detect the the channels that I use
each channel uses a specific frequency
and there's maybe two three four around
and you can just detect them and then
jamming jam then in a way to you just
you just make the the mobile think that
there is no 3G or 4G T cells around and
like that the if the mobile is a and can
communicate in gsm 3g 4g for example if
I drunk read if I I just jam 4G and 3G
frequencies the mobile will just see the
GSM frequencies and the GSM cells which
means it will just look at the GSM
frequencies and then you can for example
use they will get bit years to
impersonate a BTS and intercept the the
communication with that being the
strongest BTS around the the target
so is there a particular good device for
CPR sniffing please I think that's the
the good device and I'm still working on
it and yeah I didn't had the time to to
to do that so we are to release that but
I'm still working on the device which is
like a deaf kids Cpl deaf kit which
allows me to to change you just inject
code and also date data in memory
demanda dynamically and allow me to also
execute what I want in a Cpl I think
that is
no you you have different kind of simply
the stiffener I mean yell cedar sniffing
device you can do that so with bladder F
with the the tools that that was that
was presented before all you can use or
deaf kids but so we're using the deaf
kids you have to do a lot of work by
reverse engineering the femur or by by
trying to inject some some code to be
able to to do all the introspection but
so this is always a lot of work to do
but if you want to do that in radio you
can just you know I will just publish
the slides from the this session with
this webinar session but you can
directly try to reuse the tool that's
that's all that was presented in the Cpl
part in the radio separate parts you can
adapt it to unplug to domestic unplug
try to if you if you can you worry about
you you sniff some packets but of course
or home plug for domestic home plug it's
very difficult because it's not like
it's not like your home plug green tea
which is like very slow and it's it's
supposed to be green so it's a it is
like a slowest communication so it uses
like you know very also lowest
frequencies but but domestic home plug
use higher frequencies like and and some
you have also two samples like what Eve
80 80 80 80 megahertz of sample so it's
no weights a lot and I know and to do
that to do Steve that you you you need a
very expensive device to Steve that but
for what for home plug Greenfield
generally you can use a simple braid
area for a USRP and try to sniff them
thank you I don't know if I was clear
but because I have like a lot of things
in mind but I'm looking to our question
have you considered what benefit you can
have from rap playing machinery
automated data analysis from signal as
it simplifies it speeds up and so yeah I
think that machinery is like you know
also may be the future of when decoding
some signal example if you not able to
if you want to reverse engineer
communication even if used for example
the urh tool you decayed communication
sometimes is a lot of structure you
cannot decode and by you know doing a
lot of capture and trying to find some
interesting pattern using the matching
matching learning can be a lot of you
and be very interesting to do so I
consider it very much to do audio
analysis work
Erica fingerprints what do you mean
about fingerprints error fingerprints is
that so just like is it the messages
while which are sent over the air
25 device yeah very it's very I think
that's you can you you can maybe also
consider a machine airing if you want to
to notify some some devices over the air
because like that by studying just you
know the communication after the
demodulation is very difficult to do
that so yeah I didn't try to do all the
sorry I didn't try to to do some
identification in devices but you can
find you can maybe find fingerprints
after the decoding and finding some some
codes that are centered in the
application part but so like that in
radio is a lot of work to do maybe went
to to see what how the pram was ascended
and maybe also what's the symbol rates
which is which is use or is like a lot
of work to do and without the matching
machine learning I think that's it's an
impossible work to do all very very very
complex
- elf but every few apps does the a
curve that depends how camera feeds
goods for for many purpose but many I
suggest you to use bladder F if you want
to artwork on very video you know we
complex signals like for example mobile
signals which are which is not no it's
not possible to do example for other
hacker if I try to power supply my
computer yeah
thank you you have any question any more
question so I think we are running out
of time here
Thank You Sebastian for the presentation
and all the answers to the questions
from the participants
[Music]