[Music]
hi everyone welcome to hardware eye
webinar today we are also streaming on
YouTube in addition to our zoom webinar
and please welcome our speaker for today
a Bradbury Brad will present the current
landscape of global IT security
regulations and he will talk about the
continued in fragmentation and
surprising approaches taken by some
countries and Brad is a CTO of IO XT in
this role he leads the ixt security
products supporting the IO XT alia
alliance and he is highly versed in many
IT protocols and their associated
security models so the presentation will
take around 20-30 minutes and they will
have a questions at the end so please
feel free to send to Brad any questions
in the chat and he will answer them
after his presentation so Brad now stage
is yours you can start your presentation
all right well good morning everyone
here we go
so I'd like to sort of start out the IU
XE alliance where basically the global
standard for IOT security but what we
really are is two hundred two hundred
over two hundred device manufacturers
retailers basically the ecosystems
network operators and and service
providers all really working to address
consumer security concerns what we
really did was we develop a IOT security
standard based a lot on what we were
seeing happening out in the global
regulatory markets but then also what
are our board companies and and such are
using in their own ecosystems and the
core thing that we did was we developed
a testable and scalable security
standard that really applies from light
bulbs to set-top boxes the cars and cell
phones now the reason for all of that is
really sort of
talk about what's happening in the
regulatory space and you'll see sort of
why industry went in this direction but
let's you know start out with a little
bit of you know back to the future and
where this all began so you know the the
real shot that went across all the
bowels of the governments were the Mirai
botnet attacked back in 2016 so you know
a couple of interesting facts is sort of
looking back through this write quite a
bit of stuff was really written on this
but the interesting thing about this
attack was really it ended up being only
about 23 different manufacturers so you
know it just happened that this 23
manufacturers had a whole lot of volume
and could really go and you'll drive a
lot of chaos out there the interesting
thing about that though is prior to
their attack what they what they were
trying to do was they wanted to hide
their activities so they actually
released the source code into github and
then soon after went and it launched the
attack was also sort of interesting just
literally last night I did another
search on github keep in mind this isn't
a terribly scientific approach but
there's now 850 repositories that
contain some form of Mirai and even the
the rate of growth really surprised me I
had recently looked at this back in
November and there was only about 600 so
people are still using this framework
replicating it and expanding so this is
really the the seminal activity that
woke up a lot of governments and said
you know we should really start doing
something about IOT security yeah here
we go so just back it up a little bit
right so you know the Mirai attack for
those who weren't where was really
Japanese give a name for the future and
everything so means a little bit more
now that I got my screen share and I
thank you so much so this here is what
we really see happening in the US for
regulations and what I want to really
focus on was the
the fragmentation here if you take a
look you got States going to the left
and you know the federal government
going to the right everyone's trying to
do their own things but as a result of
the mere I attack California was one of
the first states actually go and and get
a get a law in the books now the
California bill was sort of interesting
on its surface it tried to do a pretty
decent thing it just said no
pre-programmed passwords so you know or
at least if there is a pre-programmed
password on the on the first login you
have to change so that that would
actually make it you're pretty
straightforward however where they
started getting into more interesting
troubled waters is they added the clause
reasonable security so you know the
challenge with reasonable security of
course is what is reasonable and at this
time when this went through there were
no federal guidelines nothing from this
nothing really too terribly published
you know there are a couple Federal
Trade Commission actions that were taken
against some people that people were
looking at but this this is for anyone
here in the United States state bill 327
it's sort of the big call to action as
we got to be a little bit more careful
and and help try to define these
reasonable security things now what's
interesting for those who may be in
other countries you know the United
States has this regional you know state
versus the federal kind of thing what's
interesting with the state is once one
state does something well then another
state tends to pick it on up or again
being right next to California just sort
of looked look to the south and said hey
that that looks like an interesting
thing but then they went and expanded it
so what we really see is you know this
example of they they follow through with
the same your pre-programmed passwords
added you know the same reasonable
security issue but then they even went a
little bit further talked about you know
generation of new means and then sort of
a half step backwards where unlike
California where you know this law is
going to be
in California Oregon said this law is
here unless there's a federal regulation
now another couple of interesting things
that came out of Oregon versus
California was Oregon went and and
started defining a little bit more the
type of devices so you see down here and
a what they really did was they said
these IOT devices were born target just
personal used so this isn't per se
commercial or things like that
the other interesting thing that they
did though is expanded from just talking
about internet protocols to any other
address and included the indirect
communications so these things start
pulling in other protocols like ZigBee
and z-wave and things like that that sit
behind the Gateway so the challenge here
though is with 50 states each of these
states started doing different things we
see continued fragmentation just as a
little key here the the bullets here
with dark lines around them have all
been enacted the dash lines are still
being discussed and everything and we
see things like in Virginia now they're
going even further and saying the
password should have you know so many
characters so many numbers things like
this you know from an IOT standpoint
this becomes rather troublesome when if
you're trying to you know ship a
connected light bulb and it's going to
Mississippi and it has to have a you
know 15 character password versus going
to Minnesota and it has to have 15 plus
special characters so these are the kind
of things that really have us concern
now on the flip side Congress finally
started taking a look at this but for
those who follow politics in the United
States here we've got a very fragmented
very politicized environment so sure
enough Congress couldn't just settle on
one idea they watch two different
potential bills now neither of these
bills have been enacted yet they've gone
through committee more on the IOT and
Monaca which really is just sort of a
half-step forward this act was really
meant to say anything that the
government purchases must meet these
security requirements but in the United
States this gets to be a bit of a
slippery slope when you look at how much
stimulus money goes into things like
solar panels and things like that and
exactly where this would be applied now
what we also see with a lot of these
early regulations and as they've moved
so in the early regulations as I
mentioned things like Virginia is saying
how many characters in a password the
original IOT Improvement Act had a very
similar thing they explicitly call out
in the the bill what kind of security
features had to be there
now the real challenge there is you know
think about it if we barely can get
anything through Congress do you want to
have to go get a bill passed to change
the length of a password so instead what
has really happened is the latest
version of the IOT Improvement Act
basically said security guidelines
should be followed from nest so thus
we've seen the latest movement here NIST
IR a two five nine which I'll get to in
a second they went and they tried to
define what security should look like
for consumer and commercial products the
interesting thing with NIST is NIST is
not a regulatory body they're just a
standards organization typically their
stuff is written as best practices and
such so even looping back to sort of my
opening statement about the iOS the
Alliance and that testability this is
one of the things that we actually see
as a challenge coming out of this
approach is when you write a best
practice it's not necessarily a testable
standard but let's take a look at an S
stuff so on its surface
NIST really settled into six core items
device identification protection of the
data software updates you know
configuration protection of the
interfaces and then a cyber state
awareness now what's interesting is if
you look at what's
in this side versus the European side
when we get over to the European side
you see that beast who don't necessarily
line up which does cause some issues for
any one ship being globally and
everything but the other thing that I'd
like to sort of point out so this this
the NIST IRA 259 was published just last
week there's a couple of these items in
here that are concerning and I I
definitely would recommend folks taking
a look at things like that device
identification so clearly pinning device
identity when a when a product enters a
network right you have to build a route
of trust and all this that's important
but on the flip side should every single
consumer product have a unique logical
identifier so these are some of the kind
of concerns from a data privacy you know
even thinking I'm looking at GD P R and
some of these other things if every
single device has these unique
identifiers and if they become immutable
what does that mean in the long term
another couple things that are sort of
surprising in this in a 259 is
requirements here that the cryptographic
keys can actually be adjusted by
authorized entities so you know that and
along with the ability to do software
rollback those two things would be
concerning for for most folks running
large ecosystems and everything right
typically rollback attacks are
definitely you know an attack vector
anyone who can downgrade a key length
and that's you know we've seen those
kind of issues come on up in some of the
latest Bluetooth attacks and things like
that so I just want to caution you know
those who are tracking this - absolutely
watch for some of these kind of things
and you know encourage encourage change
where possible the good news with this
is this is not per se a regulation these
are still just best practices or
guidelines
so flipping over to Europe Europe we see
things a little bit cleaner there seems
to be less of the fragmentation between
at least you know the local countries in
the European Union
essentially the path that we see
happening and the dominant regulation
that's come out is the en 303 six four
five that really traces its heritage
back to the iot code of practice that
the UK government put out through their
Department of digital culture media or
sport or as they like to call themselves
or the department of fun so these guys
are right if you think about why would
it's the sport group we looking at IOT
security well really it comes down to
digital rights management through the
the media and broadcast protection so
that that's the heritage of where that
group started but what they really did
was they they came up with their 13 core
principles and from these 13 core this
is what went in to en 303 6 4 5 these
mostly stayed intact but like any
committee work once once things got
started they quickly expanded I think
the last time I looked at this I think
it's about 60 different sub elements
here at its core what we see is the
three primary things no default password
a vulnerability disclosure program and
having devices as upgradable as a matter
of fact in the UK right now there's been
some announcements that they plan to
introduce into Parliament some kind of
regulation enforcing these three items
so I said on a surface this all looks
great some of the challenges though on a
global nature is first and foremost what
you really see between the u.s. approach
or I should say the North American
approach and the European approach is in
the European side there's a little bit
more of a consumer focused along with
data protection so things you know very
much reading on
gdpr where you've got to be able to make
it easy to delete personal data along
with ensuring that the data is protected
like I say on its surface that's that's
all good but then there's some other
things as you get into some of the
details where companies are going to
actually be asked to disclose what
sensors are in their devices what data
is in the telemetry information you know
things that get to be a little bit more
difficult especially if you've got deep
supply chains and everything another set
of features of this that Elise is just
some caution here is the scalability of
some of these so you know we all know
that validating implicated super
critical to do but in practice and in
scale how do we verify all of the IOT
devices meet these kind of things you
know even even things like minimizing
attack surface once again that's that's
definitely very good security best
practices but then as you look at it
from a testability how does that happen
in practice and in scale so flip it on
over to Japan Japan last year took a
really different approach to the problem
so essentially what they've got is in
the build-up to the Olympics they were
very concerned about what was happening
in the network they were concerned about
a mass botnet attack and so the approach
that they really took was instead of
encouraging change or regulating the
devices that went out they almost took
more of a policing approach so what they
did was they they gave some of their
agencies the permission to scan
everyone's network so anything that was
in your home and publicly connected they
would scan against the known username
and passwords then where this gets to be
sort of interesting is they would do the
scans they reach out to the Internet
service providers the Internet service
providers would tell the consumers that
they
have a device in their home that appears
to be hackable and then also there would
be support to help people work through
this so this made the news pretty big
when it first got announced what's
rather interesting just sort of looking
through where they're at the first six
months of this project I I forget the
exact number but it was tens of millions
of devices were scanned and what was
rather interesting about this was about
a hundred and fifty notices per day went
to the the carriers and the ISPs so it
wasn't an insanely large number but a
hundred and fifty devices per day when
there's something like cameras and
set-top boxes and DVRs you know these
kind of things can really sort of pile
up and wreak havoc on the network now in
practice what's sort of interesting is
this year is and luckily I believe I
removed all the account information this
was a similar thing that that AT&T had
sent over to my dad a couple years ago
very similar AT&T detecting something in
the network but you know I question when
you send something like this to a
consumer what actions do they can they
take right are they are they empowered
to actually take action here so no I I
had gone and visited my dad and he
pulled out this email and said hey I
received this you know AT&T says
something in my house has been taken
over but what is it and my first comment
as I read through this is I said well
dad you you received this in October he
goes yeah and I go well it's it's June
did you do anything and it is kind of it
was well I didn't know what to do so I
just filed it away until I could talk to
you in person and see what's going on so
though the the policing approach is
interesting the real challenge to any
kind of consumer especially with any
amount of equipment in the home is what
exact actions can you take so pulling
back up to at least where the iox
Tijuana
really took this so what we did was we
looked at what's happening in those
regulatory bodies we still see some
pretty large philosophical shifts
between the policing approach of Japan
consumer centric approach of Europe and
more of the minimalist device centric
approach of Europe and really tried to
build a set of standards that sort of
weaves between those until we can see
some consolidation around there so the
the core message here is there's still a
lot of work to be done I'll back up here
to the latest area that we see is we do
see the current fight for global
regulations has actually been moved up
to ISO I think that's where we're
probably going to finally see North
America and Europe come together it's
still a little bit unclear on what kind
of enforcement we're going to see out of
that but I do hold hope that and Leeson
ISO is a national I'm sorry an
international organization that is
really at least set up for this but I I
still am holding my breath to see
exactly where this lands so with that I
like to open it up for any questions I
think I'm supposed to look in a chat
window right yes thank you very much for
your presentation yes gonna open the
chat window and yeah people can send the
questions over there let's give them a
few moments to type it in sure thing and
as a as two people are thinking that
everything yes I you know I I do
question the approach of you know
sending grandparents email address or
emails that talked about an IP in your
home has been hacked it's like that bad
email I love to just say because it's
one of those wonderful actions like what
do you do about that right so got a
question here
how are startups and large manufacturers
digesting different standards and then
what is working for them and what are
their concerns with respect to these so
there is a a challenge for the startups
for sure you know at least I'll give it
a little bit of a pitch once again for
what the iOS the Alliance is is we do
see unfortunately the regulatory game is
is mostly a large corporation game
obviously the meetings are open
happening all around but it is a little
time consuming to you know spend time in
London and in DC and especially with all
the travel constraints but anyone can
attend these meetings it just takes some
time what we do see is large
manufacturers typically already have
their own security standards so what we
see is quite a bit of positioning of
making sure that the regulations fix the
minimum bar and don't go too terribly
far so from a start-up standpoint that
would of course be a very big concern is
if the bars raised too high does this
add too much time and cost to their
products and then what is working for
them and what are their concerns so the
the biggest concern that the
manufacturers who we talked to is
essentially the fragmentation so if
you're building a device and it needs to
be sold
you know globally just dealing with all
the different plug types is a big enough
challenge but if each especially in the
United States if there are 50 different
IOT regulations that is a real big
problem for companies to scale the other
thing that we see is as all the
organizations started we all agreed at
the high level but as we start working
down into the details you start to see
some drifts in different directions so
really as of today both the North
American and European standards are a
challenge they don't align in the same
direction so that would be the the
biggest concern that I see from everyone
and yes I'm sorry I didn't mean to laugh
on this one is there a regular
regulation that states oh that
cryptographic operation should be done
using dedicated hardware accelerators or
would a certified software
implementation suffice I'm sorry where I
thought that was is even on standard
based cryptography is a challenge
internationally you'll see that some of
the curves that that were pushed in
different countries aren't universally
recognized what we do see though is yeah
should dedicated hardware accelerators
be used for the most part everyone's
leaning towards that that's where we
should go one of the biggest challenges
and even in the iOS D Alliance we had
this discussion around should secure
boot based on Hardware root a trusty
baseline and the core problem that we
have with this is hardware root of trust
processors and dedicated hardware
accelerators aren't universally
available in all these small CB radios
and in the the little tiny sensors that
have to run off coin cell batteries for
ten years so this is this is where the
real balance I think most people have
multiple levels and they're encouraging
folks to go to hardware base
accelerators but when you look at all
the all the things in that IOT it's it's
a real big swath to go from the set-top
box all the way down to the lowly light
bulb and it's the light bulb and these
low end products that are concerning to
set that bar there all right all right
well I definitely appreciate being
invited on and able to talk to everyone
you know if there's any other questions
you know feel free to reach on out and
you know I I love to talk about all this
fun security issues thanks a lot yeah
thank you very much again for your
presentation it was really interesting
you
[Music]