[Music]
hello everyone we are from baidu
security and have long been committed to
research in ai security
today we're going to share a new
research topic about wi-fi mesh
in this topic you could gather concepts
principles of wi-fi mesh besides you
could learn the attack services of this
scene and get some high risk security
vulnerabilities in the real world
let me introduce our four speakers me
luigi is a security researcher of vital
security he's interested in bug hunting
and fuzzing he recently focuses on lt
mobile security and wireless security he
reported several security issues to
google oracle android vendors such as
mediatek xiaomi oppong
dongshinku is a security researcher of
baidu security recently he focuses on
iot security and awareness security
yeah zhang is a security researcher of
baidu security he's interested in
reverse engineering and bug hunting
recently he focuses on iot security and
fuzzing stuff
he reported several issues to apple
google microsoft
in one is a security researcher of baidu
security he focuses on automated
vulnerability detection technology such
as dynamic symbolic execution and
fuzzing now he engages in fuzzing ai
frameworks and wi-fi protocol
we'll share our research about wi-fi
mesh in five parts
in the first part we'll introduce the
background wifi mesh we'll introduce
also introduce the main role in this
topic easy mesh which is a certification
developed by wi-fi alias we'll introduce
the history of easy mesh
in the second part we'll show the
progress of easy mesh we'll introduce
the architecture of easy mesh also we
showed attack surfaces in the whole
progress in the third part
we will introduce a tool named mesh
father and share our design idea and
show how this tool could detect security
issues automatically in western mesh
in the fourth part
we'll introduce the security issues we
found in mediatek
mt7915 chipset with much further
in the last part we'll put forward our
suggestions and direct our future
research
what is wifi mesh first the mesh is a
common technology of network view
by using mesh several access points
could get gathered and serve as the
steam network
compared to the traditional wi-fi
network built technology mesh has the
advantages of being more reflexible more
reliable faster
it also has the great features of
self-organization self-management and
self-helping
so wi-fi mesh plays a significant role
in the future scene of internet of
everything
so what is easy mesh easy mesh is a
standard certification developed by
wi-fi aliens
easy mesh has goes through three
developing stages since 2018
2018 the vendors developed mesh in their
devices themselves
so the devices from different vendors
could not get in charge by wifi mesh
there is an urgent request for standard
protocol to help vendors to get together
so in 2019
wi-fi wi-fi aliens design an
easy mesh r1
which introduces onboarding and auto
config
it also claims to use
1905.18 control protocol to implement
most of the functions of mafia mesh
network control
in 2008
wi-fi alias upgrade the easy mesh from
r1 to r2
in this version
easy mesh gets more features
it is worth mentioning that
the easy mesh introduces several
security features such as the integrity
and authorization no message
up to now dozens of mentors dozens of
vendors have got the certification of
the easy mesh such as media tech huawei
city and so on
so let us introduce the architecture of
easy mesh
here there are two key links and two key
roles
first the two key links the front four
link is the link displayed in our normal
eyes which our smartphone could find it
automatically and get in touch with
internet
second the backhoe link is the link that
could not be searched in the normal
world it is a hide ssid
it is designed for mesh networks only
next let us look at the two key roles in
wifi mesh
the controller is the commander of mesh
network it could send controlling
actions to other devices in mesh network
so by sending some specific commands the
mesh network could reach the goal of
self-organization self-management
self-helping
the agent is the executor of the mesh
network it could pass the command from
controller to finish task of the network
controlling and feedback the results to
the controller accurately
so we will introduce the progress of
network build
the whole progress of network build
could be designable as two parts
onboarding
discovery and configuration
first we'll introduce a morning which
will help a device to join a mesh
network
here we call the device which wanna join
the net network net mesh network and
enrollee device
the onboarding progress is implemented
by protocol
named
1905 push button configuration
the 1.05 push button configuration first
code has three
features
feature one if the device needs a push
button in the real world
feature 2 is the 1905 ppc is based on
wi-fi protect setup
feature 3 is the 1.05 ppc space the type
lens value
so we could see from the picture photos
1905 ppc designs multi-ap
extension in the payload which means the
enrollee device could get back for
access id and password for 1905 pc
the whole progress is shown in the in in
the right picture
first the two devices need a push button
after that
the two devices are in the state of
network field
next the enrollee device follows 1905
ppc and goes through m1 to m8 and gets
the background ssid and password from
existing agent
finally the
error device could get in touch back for
ssid and join the mesh network
successfully
here the progress of onboarding is
finished
next we'll introduce the progress of
discovery and configuration
by finishing onboarding the enrollee
device needs to find a controller to get
configured with the mass network
by using the 1905 controlling protocol
first
the enrollee device sends a 1905 package
to figure out if there is a controller
device existing in the mesh network
the type of the 1905 packet is ap auto
configuration search
if there is a controller existing in the
mesh network the controller will respond
and ap auto configuring for
configuration response to the every
device
so the enrollee device finds the
controller successfully and the progress
of discovery finish
next the controller gonna configure the
enrollee device it will pass some
significant configuration patterns to
enrollee device
such as password access control list
channel of communication
this is implemented by the type of ap
auto configuration wi-fi sample
configuration as shown in the picture
right hand
just the two progress m1 and m2 and the
last the enrollee device go gets
configured and transferred to the new
roar agent and will act as a member of
the national mesh network
here the whole progress of network build
complete
we have shared the core progress of the
network build next let us look at the
network control the management and
maintenance action are really important
parts of mesh network
it is implemented by the protocol of
hbo1905.18
the actual
e1905.1a is a protocol between the
physical layer and the network layer it
defines the controlling technology in
home network whether where is or where
in the mesh scene is
1905.18 in the payload and easy mesh
describes several controlling protocols
such as device binding device
configuration and device management
the whole protocol is based test lens
value
here we list some of the protocols in
easy mesh and through the type multi-ap
positive config request as an example
the multi-ap policy config means some
strategies in steering policy on mesh
network the command is 8003
we can know the type is 0x89
and the length is 21. the pillows are
shown in the picture left hand so each
so each pic each package image network
control is just like this
so we have shown the principles of mesh
network field and control so what other
attack surfaces the two basic attack
surfaces are network build and network
control the two key protocols are 1905
push button configuration and entropy 1
and 0 5.18 control protocol and the
protocols are based the type lens value
so
uh they may have
maybe have memory correction and the
person trv block and very suitable for
fuzzing tests
here look at the attack surface of mesh
network build
first
attacker disguised a monitor's enrollee
device to attack the existing agent
it could send the more form package in
the progress m1 m3 and 5 m7 of 1905 ppc
could trigger the security issues in the
tre process in existing agent
next an attacker could disguise a
molecular existing agent to attack the
enrollee device
it could respond to more formed package
m2m4
m6m801905 ppc
could trigger the security issues in the
tlv person in enrollee device
here let us move check the attack
surface of network control
an attacker should join mesh network
first and disguise monitors controller
and existing agents to send a malformed
package and this may trigger the
security issues of the controller and
existing agent in tr repair person
the picture right hand shows we use the
command ap auto configuration wsc
message we fill the length of ssid to
0xff which is 64 bytes longest in normal
also we fulfill 0xff to the payload of
ssid
from the packet we capture you could say
our payload
x0xf fulfills the package
this is our euro to a normal device
so let us introduce our automatic bug
hunting tools we name it much father
we will introduce it as four parts
first the architecture of much father
second the strategies of mutation of
tappan's value third how we fast
network built last how we first network
control
and there are two subsystems in our mesh
further 1905 pvc fuzzing and
ih4e1905.18 fuzzing
the top half part is our design of 1.05
ppc fuzzing subsystem
we choose the wps
data between devices in the real world
as our original data the original data
will pass through our tlv mutation
subsystem and use the h0 2.1 packet
publisher to send packets
by the way our monitoring model will get
in touch with the uit port of the device
to capture the crash loads
the second half part of is our design of
1905.1840 subsystem we implement most of
the control protocol described in easy
mesh
also the original data will pass through
the tre mutation subsystem and use the
1905 packet publisher to send packets
and we design a special mechanism to
monitor whether the 1905 diamond is
crushed or not
due to the implementation of the target
protocol is based on hybrid value we
could design a growth
group of strategies to help funding
first we mutate the lens field by
changing the lens to a two-shot value or
two long value
we may trigger some memory correction
such as a two-shot value could cause
out-of-bound read or integral overflow
too long value could cause auto
boundaries security issues
second we could change the block of tlv
randomly such as randomly add randomly
delayed and this may trigger some
logical security issues such as bubble
free and use after free
the picture in the left hand shows the
two shortcuts in the real world the
picture in the right hand shows we add a
tre block randomly
we could cover most of the issues in
persian tra in the strategies upper
now let us
let us see how we foster network build
about the following hardware we choose a
ubuntu pc or
raspberry pi 4 we also buy a usb wi-fi
adapter to help sending
their 8-0
package
about the fuzzing software we choose an
open source tool or wp supplicants to
modify to build our further
the reason is that the wp supplicant
supports the 1905 ppc protocol
originally
so we could put our fuzzing strategies
in several stages of 1905 ppc and
this could help us to fast network build
stably and efficiently
as we mentioned before
there are two
potential victims in network build one
of them is an existing agent we could
build the following pillows with our
specific tools and could cover m1 m3 m5
and 7 progress
this picture right hand is the captured
crash world that we triggered in m7
this is an auto boundary issue in which
the existing agent handles the mod forms
package incorrectly
our method of the monitoring is just to
pin the target existing agent and
connect to uart to capture crash loads
so another weak team in the network
build is the error device
that has not joined the mesh network
we disguise a ridiculous existing agent
to foster every device
to keep the inverted device being in the
state of joining
mesh network we add a scratch in the
every device just as we shown in the
picture left hand
we need to inject our
fuzzing pillow in the progress m4 m2 m4
m6 m8 successfully
the right hand picture is the captured
crash log we triggered an out-of-bound
right security issues in the
progress m6
here we also use the method of the pin
target device and get uart crash lock
in this part let us introduce folding
network control we chose macbook pro as
our hardware
hardware because it could support the
package sending in h4e1905.18
about the software we choose an open
source pyl1905
which has implemented some of the
protocols of control
this is a great piece of news for us it
means we just developed some of the
protocols of easy mesh and add our
mutation strategies we
so we could first network control easily
in the monitoring part
a special mission we need to configure
out we need to figure out if the module
handling in the handling the
h4e1905.8.1a package is a diamond
so we could not capture the crash in the
uart port and also we could not send a
pin message to check the diamond is
alive or not
so we use a 1905 topology curry message
in the easy mesh which is described as a
message to detect each other in 105
diamonds we could easily know the state
of one and zero diamond is alive or not
so when we post a fuzzing pillow
our father
will post a package of 1905 topology
queries
it got feedback it means the 1.05
diamond
works normally if not
there may have some been some problems
in the 1905 diamond
we will save the fighting pillow and
wait for the diamond to restart
next my partner don shanku will show you
the security issues found by meshfather
in the real world
hello everyone next i will introduce
some security vulnerabilities we
discovered during the security audit of
the mt-791 fellowship
those vulnerabilities can be roughly
divided in two categories in terms of
causes
firstly memory corruption one
abnormalities mainly due to the lack of
validation when processing carry packets
windows often introduce such
vulnerabilities
when implementing wifi mesh protocol
stacks
such as stack overflow and hip overflow
secondly vulnerabilities that varied
security principles mainly due to the
validation of safety principles defined
in the using mesh standard for example
the backhoe link and the frontal link it
will be accurate in a wfm mesh network
we chose the middle attack mt7 number
failed chip
was our research target for weapon mesh
mainly based on the following three
reasons
firstly the
mt-7195 is world's first single chip
weather 6v1 plus and the bluetooth file
combo solution
the chip integrates a dedicated rf
receiver with zero-width dfs channel
monitoring
industry first
that brings faster highly reliable and
easier to use connectivity
secondly the weapon mesh solution of
mt79 fell chip has obtained the easy
mesh
certification of the wifi
thirdly
mt-795 was a cost-effective wi-fi chief
is adopted by many wifi6 wireless
routers
those advantages are very beneficial to
our security research
in our security audit of the weapon
match solution of the mt-79 fellow chief
we found some security issues which
cover the network build stage and
network control stage of the wifi match
process
a total of 19 cvs was obtained
mediatek had fixed all the security
issues and released the corresponding
packages
first of all
i will introduce two memory corruption
vulnerabilities
cv3500
we discovered in the mesh network
builder stage attackers can use these
vulnerabilities to remotely trigger auto
boundaries in the adjacent network
result knowing the wifi password
the device will join the mesh network
through the 1905 push button protocol
as can be seen from the code in the
figure
after the piece ap received the wc
packet it directly passed the process it
resulted validating the data packet
the trigger point of the vulnerabilities
is a memory crop operation here
the target address is a 16 back area and
the corporate data and the list are all
passed from the wsc packet
when attackers send a careful
constructed wc package with an error
industries greater than 16 bets the out
of bounds red can be achieved
the picture on the left is a crash log
triggered by this vulnerability
cv37566 we discovered in mesh network
control stage an attacker can use this
vulnerability to remotely trigger an
auto bounce back in a recent network
when the wifi mesh network is
established
the ipc manage the mesh network through
the 1900 file protocol earth can be seen
from the code in the figure
after if she received the 1905 data
package it directly passed and processed
its result while dating the data package
the trigger point of the vulnerability
is the memory cops evaluation here
the destination address is a 33 bed area
the copper data and lens are all passed
from the 1905 data packet it has not
undergone any verification
when an attacker sent a carefully
construct 1905 data packet with a ssd
lens greater than 33 bets and out of
bounds wealth can be triggered
the picture on the left is the crazed
logo by this vulnerability
next i will introduce a vulnerability
caused by a violation of security
principles
in the using mesh standard
the wifi mesh network is directed in two
links front hall and backhaul the
frontal link is used for normal network
communication between the device and the
ap
and the background link is used for
transmission of mesh network management
data between the aps however in this
mesh implementation front and back links
are not strictly isolated
common devices that send a false mesh
network management messages in the
frontal link will also be received and
processed by the hp nominee
therefore the attacker can pretend to be
the mesh network manager as shown in the
park and send the 1905 data packets from
the frontal link to block the specified
device from accessing the net the mesh
network
from the hd serial port logo it can be
seen that after running the park when
the specified device is connected to the
network
the request to join the network will be
ignored by the apg
causing the device to be unable to join
the mesh network
for the repair of the above mentioned
vulnerabilities we have the following
suggestions
for memory corruption vulnerabilities
caused by processing theory packets we
recommend to pass the data packaged
completely
then check the tab and links one by one
and finally process the return and
discuss it when the list and tab check
fails
a good example is wpa supply control the
figure shows the process of wsa
wpa supplicant processing tre package
which follows the process of passing and
the dispatch and the relation and
processing
for vulnerabilities caused by violation
of security principles
there is a section in the easy match
version 3 standard that specifically
described the security capabilities of
1905 protocol for example to accelerate
backhoe and frontal link
and the integrated code which is an
integrity transmission counter used by
sender to prevent reply attacks
and also encrypt a 19-0 fail particular
layer
we suggest that when implementing easy
mesh vendors showed a bad better easy
match standard and implement the
security capabilities of the 1905 boot
code
next is a summary of the whole topic
in our research on fms we discovered a
new attack service
attackers can launch attacks on the
devices in the mesh network during the
mesh network build stage and network
control stage
in this regard we develop the mesh
further which can automatically mine the
security vulnerabilities introduced by
windows when implementing easy mesh
in practice we found some security
issues and option 19 series
is a welfare mesh solution of mt-795
chip
and we classified the vulnerabilities
found and gave the corresponding repair
suggestions for future research work you
have the following plans
firstly use much further to mine the
vulnerabilities of other user mesh
vendors
many other windows wifi chips have also
obtained easy math certification in the
next research we will verify whether
there is a mesh implementations of those
winners have similar problems
secondly eastern much farther to adapt
to some windows unique smartphone mesh
solutions
many winners will
have developed their own wifi solutions
such as qualcomm's qsdk
in the next research we will also
conduct security audits on this type of
fms solution
thank you everyone they're both with all
the content that we share today
[Music]