[Music]
hi everyone my name is taoi and today
i'm going to introduce our new research
about the windows repairs points our
topic name is from logic to memory
winning a solid tire in replace points
you may not be unfamiliar with logic
issues in our
points actually there are many far
redirection bugs in recent years but
today we are going to talk something new
solid tire here is a perm which has two
minutes the first is the default card
game on windows we will introduce how we
win the card game in pantone 2021 the
second is gemstone memory corruption
issues in replace points are also a
gemstone mine for researchers we'll
introduce all details about this new
attack surface
we are security researchers from pallet
networks we do new attack surface and
system internals research from both
offensive and defensive perspectives
we are msrc top 10 researchers
and we got several hundred cves in
different applications
we are pontoon winners and have spoken
in many top different conferences
besides we are also patent inventors for
new defense and detection techniques
here's our agenda there are two main
parts the logic back in replace point
for
pontoon
and the memory corruption back in parts
points
the first part will show a zero
geological vulnerability which bypass
all current mitigations with undisclosed
exploit techniques techniques and wins
windows eop category in ponton 2021
all details including finding the bug in
one day with a unique vulnerability
discovery strategy root cause analysis
winning a seemingly impossible risk
window stably as well as how to make the
exploit stable enough
for the pantone context will be covered
the second part will introduce our new
discoveries
on this never disclosed attack service
for memory corruption eop backs in
repulse points
including the new attack service
internals
the interesting memory corruption
vulnerability examples as well as future
accounting insights in repulse points
first what is repulse point
it is a collection of user-defined data
which understood by
application which
stated the data and a file system filter
which read and process the data
every
replace point data has a reports tag
which represents a type of repulse point
you can use device io control to get set
and delete replace points
there are two
famous repulse points symbol link and a
mount point
there are many file redirection bugs
by using
those two replace points
it is firstly inspired by a gems for
show and in recent years there are over
hundreds of fire redirection
vulnerabilities and overtaking the wild
vulnerabilities
from from them
here is a classical redirection file
redirection attack you can see low every
low privilege application communicated
with high privilege application
with alpc rpc and com
in high privilege high privilege
application to file
operations with high privilege on low
privileged user controllable files or
directories
if
they are redirected to high privileged
user controllable files or directories
such as into system file then low
privilege privilege application can
operate anti-system file indirectly
this will lead to elevation of privilege
info league and the dos vulnerabilities
since there are too many file
redirection bugs microsoft put huge
efforts to
develop kinds of mitigations to cue
these bad class
first diminish the attack surface
cut off the connection between low
privileged applications and high
privileged applications
second operate the file correctly either
by operating the file handle directly or
with correct correct impersonation or
verify if the file has a symbol link
third
prevent the file redirection techniques
directly you can see there are many
restrictions for soft link command point
and hurling creation
it's very effective
even all mitigations mentioned before
are bypassed
low privileged application can operate
anti-system file
but microsoft also did some mitigations
to queue existing easy ways to execute
the code with system such as
queue the ad agent method in diagnosis
service
i have to say the microsoft strategy of
making exploitation harder is on the
right way
microsoft took actions in each step in
the full exploit chain
after combination of all mitigations
logic backs in repressed points are
decreased a lot and the exploitation of
logic back become more and more
difficult
so is it still possible for
a stable exploitation of the logical
vulnerability in repulse points to win
ponchon
the answer is yes although it's very
hard
let's start the whole journey for
pantone 2021 and see what kinds of magic
over there
unique vulnerability discovery strategy
generates unique vulnerabilities as
early as six or seven years ago we found
an interesting thing that engineers are
not good at with doing things
they make mistakes when they doing
revert repair reinstall redefinition
reset and so on so forth
in the past there are several hundred
critical
vulnerabilities in
different applications in this bad class
for example ie browser renderer engine
under redo rcu vulnerabilities
we found over 100 use of the free
vulnerabilities
from them
besides
the flash action script browser
javascript engine redefinition
rce vulnerabilities also a lot of
vulnerabilities from this
and there are also eop vulnerabilities
in this bad class a classical example is
windows installer revert
eop vulnerability a patched five times
eop vulnerability with five cves
we believe there are still many redo
bugs now and in the future
with this unique bug hunting strategy we
found a reset back in microsoft solid
tire collection in one day
you can see when we open app settings
for solid tire there's a reset button
after we clicking the reset button
ipvx service will do some interesting
file operations
under user directory with the system
the file
operations are from
set name secret info
and
it operates the
user controllable normal user
controllable directory with the system
so we confirm it is a vulnerable for
directory redirection attack
for root cause
abbax service will call add package data
access helper function to deal with
the
reset
operation
it will firstly impersonate itself as
system
and then call this function
finally it will call apply security
descriptor function in this function
genome secret info will be first called
to get the acl
for a normal user controllable directory
and then attach
some
ecls
to the existing
pcls
after that
apply the updated scl
back into the same directory with the
surname secret info
if we redirect this directory to other
places
cnm screeninfo can override
the acl of a b3 directory
let's review
the
vulnerability
from the
exploitation perspective to see if it is
exploitable
you can see in the app
user application if we reset the solid
tire you can and and the fpvx service
will call get name screeninfo and send
sending screen info so the direct
exploitation strategy is due for
redirection
in the right time just between canyon
screen info and the surname secret info
but there and then
cnm screen4 will
override the acl of the redirected
target file into system file
but
there are two challenges
the first
is there a way to redirect the directory
to a file
second is there a way to win the shot
release window stably
upload could be an option but can we
trigger our block just after get name
security info and do file redirection in
the upload callback before sending
security info
after more investigations we found two
challenges
we we found more challenges
for the file reduction we don't know if
currently existing file reduction trick
can be used for
directory to file redirection
besides
we are not sure get name secret info and
a synonym screening for
work for
both file and the directory at the same
time
for risk condition
no upload type can block read attributes
on directory by gangnam secret info
besides we cannot change one point
inside the upload callback when it is in
use
and last we need to run the exploit
automatically not just
manually click the reset button
to overcome all challenges mentioned
above we need to revisit the
vulnerability and check all file
operation
precisely first let's take a look at the
exploitation of the running part
the reset button has a corresponding
powershot command to do the same thing
we said ebbx package
but it is only supported on future
windows versions
the good news is we figure out
the reset
operation is e-code
uninstall and reinstall the better news
is we can split file operations
precisely by splitting
reset into uninstall and reinstall
we extract important file operations in
uninstall and reinstall in uninstall
there are there is only one file
operation deleted directory in reinstall
there are three file operations create
directory canon screen info and the
synonym secret info
to avoid the noisy file operations we
start our thread after uninstall
and try to win the risk when finding
vulnerable directory creation so there
are three
possibilities the risk threat will be in
with windows 0 1 and 2.
you can see the wrist window 0 is
relative long and the wrist window 1 is
very short since there are much more
code between credit directory and
gangnam security info then between
getting secret info and a synonym secret
info
as we just saw there's only one function
calculate scale between get and set
so the possibility that the risk threat
is increased window zero is much higher
than in risk window one besides because
we added
the critical priority for the risk
threat
the prob the probability that the risk
thread is in risk window 2 is very very
low
so
we only need to deal with a risk window
zero and a risk window one
let's firstly focus on the risk window
one when the wrist thread is in wrist
window one it is perfect situation we
expected the only change we challenge we
need to solve is directory to file
reduction
the good news is the existing mount
point and the object symboling trick
works for
directory to file redirection the only
thing
the only change we need to do is
to create point for the parent directory
of the vulnerable directory
besides get name screen 4 and send them
secret info do not
differentiate
object name it means
both file and the directory work for
those two functions at the same time
it is perfect for file redirection
attacks
after solving the risk window 1
let's see how we overcome all challenges
and bypass current mitigations and
finally set the upload successfully and
get a 100 success rate in which window
zero
we need to redirect the same vulnerable
directory to different targets in
different time
we can create a mount point for the
directory if it is not empty or in use
so we use a dangling mount point
technique it's like the dangling file
pointer in use of free
exploitation we can point it to any
different location
in any time we want
the first reduction happens when
creating the vulnerable directory the
vulnerable directory will be created
under a fake publisher
application directory after redirection
we will show other redirections in the
following slides
to succeed to set the upload for the
gangnam screenflow we need to redirect
the directory
to the file otherwise all our block
will not work for gnm secret info
we did the redirection in the wrist
thread
since it is running the release window 0
we can finish the redirection
successfully before
get named screen 4 is called
since
get named screen info use read
attributes to open the file we found two
types of
uploads level one and a batch of block
can block file operation when opening
the file with
read attributes
so we can succeed to set the level one
upload
on the fixed file beforehand and the
wing get m secret info is called the
upload callback will be triggered and do
the third time file redirection to
redirect the vulnerable directory to the
target into system file
then
synonym screen4 will override the acl of
the target file with normal user fully
control privilege
this is the whole view of how to win a
seemingly impossible risk window by
redirecting the vulnerable directory to
different targets for three times
first for create create directory second
for genome screen for in the wrist
thread second
third
for
synonym secret info in upload callback
now we have 100 success rate for the
risk window zero and a one
and the probability of
risk window zero is very high so the
exploit success rate is very high even
for one time running
actually the exploits succeed
in one trial in most of time in a vm
with a two-car cpu
after we succeed to override the ac air
of the nt-system file we need to find a
way to execute the code system
there are two known tricks left after
mitigations print config and the type
lib file sysfx ui since both both of
them are existing
techniques
we are not putting more time under on
them today
now we can elevate the privileged system
but the stability is one of the most
important things in ponton because you
only have three chances to try
we use a rerun until success
strategy in our exploit it continually
uninstall and reinstall the solid tire
application
there are lots of things need to take
care for example we need to put the
initial setup thing information into a
config file otherwise we cannot get them
anymore afterwards
besides we need carefully
deal with each field situation and
do the
uh
correctly uh cleanup
for
all of open things
like handle symbol link mount point
thread directory upload and so on so
forth and last we also need to
deal with
many corner cases to make sure
our exploit can handle everything
under all of current mitigations the
exploitation logic is very very
complicated you can see there are many
modules in our exploitation
but it works elegantly and perfectly
today we are not going to explain all
details in our in each module
only two things want to mention the
first the first
we have a module to verify if the
acl overriding is successful
if not we will wrong we run the whole uh
process
until it's success
the
second thing
is the we have a reason thread it is
very important because the success rate
depends on if the wrist thread enters
into the right release window
talk is cheap show me the demo
you can see
you can see uh
it is a windows version prepare for
pongtong
and we are
running the
xy under normal user and run our
exploitation
on installing
and
read thread is running
reinstall
and success
you can see a
system a cmd pop-up
if we check the pro command
you can see a a system notepad is
running under section zero and this is
the system cmd rounder
running under
session two current session
our exploitation only wrong once and
succeed
perfectly
we have introduced many interesting
interesting things for logic issues in
reports points but the story does not
end here microsoft stopped granting
bhagavantis to the file rejection bug
class and it is releasing more and more
mitigations to kill the backlash fully
it seems to be the end of the repulse
point year but things are not always
that easy we found a new realm which is
never publicly deeply discussed before
the memory corruption plus in replace
points
let's start from the new text surface
internals first
pass point operation
as we mentioned before divisor control
can be used to set get and delete your
press points by
setting the corresponding device out
control code
and there are other arguments in vessel
control function
input buffer output buffer let's see the
repairs data structure first
there is a four bytes replace tag which
represents the type of
replace point data
and then
two bytes of data lens two by three
observed after that
there are
undocumented data buffer
for generic reports buffer
actually there are 54 repulse point tags
totally
one point and the symbol link on only
two of them
there are others
uh other interesting report reverse
point tags
uh such as wci
which are designed for windows container
it is a relatively
new thing on windows for the left 52
price points tags
what are they used for who use them and
where they are used is there any unit
new attack surface among them we will
see in the following slides
before exploring
more details we create a vulnerability
model first
you can see
a low privileged application
communicated with high privileged
application
by alpc rpc com same with before
high privilege
applications has a module to process
uh repulse point data it will firstly
read repulse point
on
low privileged user controllable files
or directories
and then
if low privileged user application
write the repository data
to those files or directories
then
low pre-privileged user controllable
data will be written into high
privileged applications as data input
if high privilege applications do not
process
we passpoint data correctly or carefully
there
are
memory corruption
bugs possibly
and it will crash
high private
privilege applications there is a way to
write data from low privileged
application to high privilege
application it is where the new attack
service is
after creating the
vulnerability model we start to find
some targets to diving
there are two ways to find the targets
dynamic and static
for dynamic
method
we use progmon to monitor
some system events if we find
a process with a
system
a system process
access a normal user controllable
directory of file
with open repose point option
it is suspicious
and worse to take a closer look at to
see if there's a
we pass point data processing module to
process replace point data
for static we
we write a adder python script to find
the following code pattern
in the code it's very simple to
understand create file first and
uh
call director control to
get uh
your passport and data and check the
type
process the
replace point data
sometimes we need
women you combine static method and a
dynamic method to find and confirm the
targets after finding the targets we can
do bug hunting by clear review of
fuzzing
we have some interesting findings with
only some initial investigations it is a
total total new realm the code for
replace points data processing is not
well evaluated and the vulnerability are
very straightforward we pick some
interesting memory corruption but
examples to show today
there's a one function containing three
types of vulnerabilities
integer flow out of bounds rate and a
risk condition
more interestingly the similar code
pattern appear in multiple modules
the vulnerable function can be triggered
by
desktop bridge activation
you can see desktop ad breach activation
app communicated with app info service
infoservicewith.com
and here's a call stack for
a client client com client and a com
server
we use the following code to create
client
create.com client to communicate with
with the
app info service
there's a com class named
desktop ebbx activator and there's an
interesting interface in them in under
that interface there are two
methods we call activate method with
local bridge and microsoft office hub
as parameters
you can see in appian for service
there's a
function named launch
process with identity to
deal with a com request
then it will finally call wcp or
passpoint
this function will
read the replace point data on the
normal user controllable directory local
cache with the system
more details for wcp reader passpoint
function you can see firstly
create file
for local cache
normal user
controllable
and called device or control to get a
replace point data into a fixed
um
output buffer to be mentioned this
the
this output buffer is a fixed sized hip
with a size
zero zero zero zero we will introduce
later how it leads to a lot of bounds
read vulnerability
after that the code will check the type
you can see here
and then process the data
so we can
set the repository data
with a following code
and we set a reposit tag
with the wci link
and then only two bytes of normal value
and we will see how a literal out of
bounds write a vulnerability
wci really requires point data function
is responsible to process through
passport data
here is
the replacement data
read from the
local cache directory
and then
here
is where the integer overflow happens
there's a
plus
operation
and uh
for fff plus one six
but the
the buffer lens variable is two bytes so
it will
generate a very small value 1 5 then the
code will allocate a heap with this size
1 5
and
put that that
heap
as a destination buffer of the memory
copy very small heap
but the memory copies size is
controllable in the
passport and data
it is set to ffffff so obviously this
memory copy operation will
lead to out of bounds right
vulnerability
in the crashing fall we can
see
more clearly
the destination buffer size 1 5
the copy size is fff
obviously
it will crash at a memory copy
if we use a following code
to set a replace point data
we'll see how
it
can lead to a lot of bonds read the
vulnerability nothing special we
previously called only
slightly change the two bytes of normal
value
the same function
same
uh
also wcp read the repository to read the
replacement data
and here is a fix for the integer flow
and
pay attention here the saucer dress soft
buffer is a fixed hey fixed size hip
with a size uh f
of
4 000
as we mentioned before
as a
for the memory copy but
the copy size is also controllable in
the
replacement data
we set it to ff10 so if through the
memory copy it will be
out of bounds read the vulnerability
if we check check the crash info we can
see also see more clear
you can see the
source buffer size of memory copy is
four zero zero zero but the copies size
is ff one zero
will lead to other fonts read
vulnerability
it's a
risk condition it's a payday that we
can't talk
more details about it because it is
still vulnerable
we may feel the slides for this part
when we get the chance in the future we
have seen one function containing three
types of vulnerabilities but more
interestingly the similar code pattern
about the repulse point data processing
appear in multiple different modules
abbx deployment server wci and so on so
forth
we reported our findings to microsoft
some of the cases got a fast response
and highly evaluated with back bounty
since they are totally new and valuable
to microsoft
but in the meantime they also silently
patch some of our cases maybe your
also have similar experiences
from
microsoft
the impact under this new attack surface
almost all current and the future
mitigations for logic bugs in price
points are useless because memory
corruption bugs and logic bugs
are from totally different dimensions in
addition the memory corruption bug has
the native code execution capability no
matter the vulnerable code are executed
with system impersonation or not in the
system services and a successful
exploitation lead to privileged
elevation to system
directly
for future bug hunting
i think we should a good example in our
topic find the target curve view of
fuzzy
create a
once
a new attack surface is open there are
always many low hunting fruits it is
much easier to find easy bugs under a
new attack surface than finding an
interesting new attack service itself
we believe there are still many not well
evaluated code left in this new attack
surface
to summarize
our we intrigue we introduced a story of
two solid tires in our topic in the
pontoon journey we introduced a unique
bank hunting strategy we use it to find
the microsoft solid tire you set back in
one day and it can also be used to find
more redo bugs in different applications
and components
in the in the exploitation part we
introduce some useful and universal
exploit techniques which can be applied
to similar exploits for mitigation
bypass in the future
in the other part we introduce a less
recognized solid tire
the new attack surface for memory
corruption bugs in repulse points
hope you can get some inspirations from
our topic and win your own solitaire in
the reverse points in the future
thanks
for the amazing previous work maybe not
all of them are listed here but thanks
to all
also thank you for listening and
attending
questions
[Music]