[Music]
hi
my name is
together with me is sagi
we are both doing uh security research
in uh strike
and jarvan contributed to the research
significantly but it is not here right
now
so
uh let's see
so the talk today is about a
a technique that is
quite
overlooked it is called this injection
in the context of this technique we
establish meet them
and we convince the machine that we are
the domain controller
we will see that this technique is
useful both in the context of kerberos
or cement element
without the main authentication protocol
in active directory environment
okay so the plan for today talks and
first
we present mtln
we'll introduce the protocol we'll then
see relate to the known vulnerabilities
and mitigations
and then we'll see a
new attack
in a
that is mtlan injection and afterwards
we'll switch over to kerberos we'll
introduce the protocol we'll see related
vulnerabilities and integrations and
we'll see
uh three cases training cases
now i just like to mention that the
impact of
vulnerability of technique is a really
costly mode
involving different vendors and products
and
i'm sure that
you could find more
so what is the ntlm ntln is a legacy
authentication protocol in epidiolectomy
it was largely superseded by kerberos
it's
in the style of challenge response now
when a user wants to authenticate to a
server files he sent a message about its
capabilities
and then there's a random challenge from
the server
and the client responds with the
response to the challenge based on the
users
now the server
relays this authentication to the main
controller
since the server doesn't avail of the
using password
now the domain controller approves or
rejects the session and
and
provides the
session
so
okay there is a one thing to note here
and you can allow a server signing
client signing
use the most secure settings in gpu
still
nothing in ltln or dss api the
encapsulating protocols
will prevent the option of impersonating
the destination server actually
the identity of the server does return
in the challenge message
but due to i guess some canonization
difficulty
clients
don't compare it with
what they expect
and
and that means that
a malicious entity can send a set up a
server and provide the
award responses to the
requests
so let's see how it looks and now if a
client wants to
connect to a server it first send and
the negotiate message edition
intercepted by an attacker
that sends a challenge
uh now as mentioned the client machine
does not verify the target name
and sends back a response now the world
server and
should have a valid identity in the
active directory
username
it must be a machine but
it could
then
relay the session to not really
delay the session to a dc and
get
the session key
and so and then it is able to
a
further request from the client and to
inject malicious data potentially
now
this technique kind of resembles a ntlm
delay but
there's a quite a difference and in mtl
and relay the
authentication is relayed to another
server that is attacked actually
but in our case
we attack the client we inject data
notice that
there is uh
nowadays a protection mechanism against
ntl and relay
which is the server signing in plans and
and only
and it's only possible in
unsecured settings or
quite well cases
so um
actually the classical case of this
attack was discovered by luke jennings
and
it involves a group policy update where
an attacker can intervene in this
process and
for example
update the
logons to it or something similar
to achieve a remote code execution
and
the fixes
by microsoft follow this attack are
really specific to policy
and
first group policy retrieval can no
longer be done with ntlm that is
held up in
and and south sea and then
and then secondly and smb and that is
the protocol that is responsible for
obtaining the group policy files
uh is
blocked from a usage on certain
paths
and okay so
let's now see and
a new contribution
so
it's about the azure vedic connect and
just generally and as you will be
connected
as well it's part of the vision of
seamless sign on where the
a user can use its internal active
directory credential while surfing on
the web to access
external resources such as office 365 or
some
internal applications
without the need
of a vpn or something similar
and the way it works is the following
we have
as your ad connect server on plan
that
on the one hand
that leaves the password information and
other data
from domain controllers on the network
and on the other end
upload
this information hash to the
azure active directory uh this way you
actually directly is able
to verify
authentication requests by users
and the thing is that
there is no verification that the domain
controller is a real going controller
which means that
an attacker could intervene in this
courses and send
a fake password updates
so how it works and
we should have a full meeting between
the ad connect server and the dc
now the ad connect server tries to
communicate by kilograms
but since scalables failed we make it
fair
it reverts to a ntlm and
at this point and
the attacking relays
ldap packets to the original server and
only and else
msrpc packets that are
a
domain application now the way to
retrieve the passwords is
by using the domain application
waterproof dlsu api
and
by answering with a new malicious change
to the
directory we can introduce effect
password into the database
so
let's just now
see the demo
so here we see the titles view
and
we want to inject password ntl injection
into
this
account ek test
and clearly it says the puzzle is not
mtlm injection but another puzzle
so now we have the
two things that we do
we first have a modified version on mini
caps
of new caps in the window above and
secondly we have
ldap relay server on the window below
and
now
we wait for the symphonization to occur
and
it usually takes minutes or two but i
sped it up and
now and
okay we can see that
a new change was pulled
and so
we can try to
connect with the new password
and
now
we try several times as it takes time
for the password to be uploaded to
a azure 80 times so let's try
okay not yet
okay
so we have a lot in the third time and
now we can look at the network packets
so
we can see
that the packets that return from the
attacking machines
are the
domain application packets and we'll see
this this is that forward station zero
one is the
attacking machine and and the
ldap is returned from the original
domain controller that is
that so
this is zero one
so
now we've achieved the account takeover
essentially and
we can do what we want
with
that user in azure
so uh
the
response of microsoft is the following
they did not consider the vulnerability
and mostly because it is ntlm and they
considered it rather a configuration
issue and partly because it requires
meet them and meet them is considered
an elevated position
and okay while we strongly agree with
the microsoft recommendations here with
the
tool for any situation on us and we do
think
it should be considered the
vulnerability and sex accordingly
uh it was to mention that there is also
plenty of research
we meet them
and and plenty of ways to achievement
and like a slack attack outsourcing and
so on
so
it's really practical
and i'll stress again the main point
that
there is
really no protection mechanism against
this attack that is built in and by
default
and
there might be specific solutions
so
and
let's
now switch over them to sagi you will
explain about the killers
thanks a lot and now let's see how we
can use the dc injection technique with
canvas
first let's go over some basics
kerberos is an active directory
authentication protocol it was added
some time after until then
and its main goal was to make the
authentication process more secure
the capitalist authentication process is
divided into three parts
in the first part the user will pull his
identity to the domain controller
and in return the domain controller will
return a ticket value ticket or digital
insurance
next when the user wants to access a
server
it will go back to the domain controller
with the digital
and ask for a service template
in the service ticket request the user
will include
service principle name which is
basically the
server name
and the name of the service it's what it
wants to use something like l.o.6
after they assign the tgt the controller
with return input in servers service
which the user will then use
when contacting the server
the tdt is encrypted with the server key
since it's intended to be verified by
the server
when the user establishes a channel
against the server it will send the tgs
the server will then be able to verify
it since it's included with its secret
and also
it can take from it a session key it was
also shared with the user and they can
both use that session key to establish
a
encrypted channel in other particles
and to have some more background on our
attack let's first talk about cadence's
protein
and case is putting within an old attack
technique that was used in bypass
authentication
on network equipment like vpns and
followers
a user logs onto server using plaintext
credentials
and the server uses those credentials to
generate an earth request
an attacker using newton intercepts
that request
and returns effect with life
basically the reply is fake since the
attacker doesn't have the necessary
secret to create everyone
and also the server doesn't have the
necessary secret to validate the reply
so it just removes the users of them
to mitigate this attack another step to
the authentication process was added
now after receiving the air supply
the server uses the included tgt
and ask the demand tutorial for a
service sticker
with which itself is the target
but the domain controller returns a
valid service ticket and since the
target is the server itself it can
validate the ticket and know that the
user ended the one controller on january
and only then it can improve their users
this process of asking the service
ticket
to serve
is usually done with the spm as folks
so as we are saying we cannot manipulate
the authentication process itself and
the tickets
so what can we
do let's take a look at how a typical
workstation
enumerates the domain and selects the
the desktop organs
so the process itself of the
immunization and the disease selection
is done using the
combination of dns queries and other
searches
unauthenticated searches and regard
until the dress this is chosen
only
then a network demonstration will be
established against the chosen dc and
some messages will pass over it
this is the most crucial part since to
the order to establish a network session
and reply to messages the target server
must have the client machine circuit
that means
it's a general and decent
so
as we have seen the process of selecting
the disk itself is not secure unless
some form of validation is done
afterwards
so what can we do with this
we can convince the client machine that
we are the dc
and we can afterwards we can just delay
all kinds of requests so to release this
then when the client wants to ingest
data from the dc our safe disney we can
sell anyone this is data once back to
the machine
let's take a look at the attack here
the current machine starts the this is
selection process and we inject our
circuit dc
then when the autocad authentication
process starts
you just relay all the messages to this
day and then back to the client
until the authentication finishes
and again the process of asking the
teachers for hosts will work since uh
the this is genuine and we return a
visit tjs
then when a client wants to
ingest data from the dc
uh
weird this is so we have the target
service it needs so it's us it asks for
a service ticket
and since our machine is a valid machine
in the domain and we have re-registered
all the students who need
this in resells the ticket
and the channel will be established
against our dc with the chosen protocol
note that the channel can even decide or
encrypted
so what we need for the attack to work
we need an application that uses canvas
that ingests data from the dc without
validating it
and of course those
does dynamically sense for disease and
does not use a fixed list
we will also need a man in the middle
between the dc
between the client application
and at least the dns server
and lastly we will need a
valid machine account in the domain with
the ability to register
the experience we need on it
and this can be achieved by using the
machine account for auto policy which is
turned on by default and
allows any user in the domain to create
up to 10
machine accounts
after creating the machine account a
user has asked the permissions to
register
almost any type of spns on that machine
except a few that we will mention later
let's see some real-world example of
this attack
the first one is azure ready connect
yes it has already connected again
it's basically the same scenario as the
others already described
but this time we will inject this using
kernels instead of antenna
and we won't show a demo for this
because it's identical to the domain is
already shown
but it's worth noting that when
requesting the one replication
has already connected is these two
special streams
these sdns are protected directly
directly
and to be able to register them you must
have full control over the machine
account
that's why we can't use the machine
account quota tweak
for this attack and this makes the
scenario more difficult to achieve
our second example is there will be
center
administrators use the center to
centralize the management of the
e6 servers and the underlying virtual
machine
this center supports windows
authentication
and it it allows the digital snappings
to
add security works
this that makes him vulnerable it's
vulnerable to
this injection
which results in physicist connection
and let's see the attack flow
we depart our little machine and
register the needed sdns in this case
we log on with the rpg and village
account to the recent
worldwide
recently we started the authentication
process
which is
we have already discussed we relate to
dc
then when assessing the user privileges
this center needs to translate the id
group names to their respective
securities and security ideas
in this case we can intervene in those
adult centers and return a fake security
system for instance when
this center wants to translate domain
admins to security we can return the
security for domain users which results
in every domain using
images in this center
and let's see a demo
and socially so this demo we don't we
don't have the attacker's view so i will
try to describe what happens behind the
scenes here we have a
recent machine which we have already
written
and
now we see the configured walls was on
that machine
we see that we have configured an
administrative world that is marked
through the ideal zero means
and besides besides that there is no
other world map
meaning that so the main user to be able
to log on to this server it must be a
member either directly or indirectly or
not next
now
let's
select an add
without privileges
here we have a regular user
that is only a member of domain wizards
okay
so
let's log off from this center
the solver we know i will mention that
in the background we have two boxes one
for ldap and one for smd to send all the
all the requests that are done by
receptor
we use that add-on proxy to answer adobe
searches that are uh right now and
instead of returning the allergies for
the nervous so we have abilities we
return the idea of the main users which
as you can see
allows regular user to log onto the
machine and is now a school
administrator in this center
our third example is the untrust aid in
which
added region it is a mac and linux
machine to join
this allows us to consider
privileges for instance civic villages
using id security works
and this application also is honorable
to this injection which results in
previous escalation
the tax law is basically identical to
what we have already shown in this
center
except in this case
uh by default
after joining the domain
linux allows any domain user to do ssh
machine
but of course that user doesn't have cd
privileges
then
when we try to do sudo
we
but this scenario is pretty much the
same
let's see who has sudo which who has
shooting machines on that villagers on
this machine you can see that the third
images are knocked to two groups the
mirror means
and nothing else
so
let's log off
and you see we are using the regular
visual again
and it doesn't have any privileges
except for the known reasons
and now we will
do ssh using the user
which as i said is what works by default
which is no surprise but now we are
trying to do sudo and
let's see if you
succeed yeah and regular user which is
just a member of the learning of limits
now has two different images on this
section
okay
so how can this attack the initiator
when our application
is just data from the dc we must verify
that this identity first the
verification can be done either by
establishing a networking session
and sending at least one message over it
or by using lds with certificate
validation
another option is to use canvas online
but we haven't tested it
as a side world windows gpo is still
safe since the gpo client does not pull
any gpo unless there is an active
network on session against the chosen dc
let's talk about the vulnerabilities
so microsoft
on the ntln injection as ryan has
already said it doesn't consider it is a
vulnerability
but
it did issue a guidance
on how to disable the ntlm for the
service account
from the kernel's injection microsoft
actually issued the cd and already since
the issue
beyond trust for elder dwight
has acknowledged the issue and are
working on six and the same with the
real world the knowledge the issue
working on six and has
issued the security advisory with the
temporary work right
somewhere closing remarks
uh securing protocols from vietnam is
very hard as you've seen
and because of this
we believe this specific issue is very
widespread
and we believe that lower a lot more
applications will be found that are
vulnerable to this type of attacks and
cameras is not validating this identity
properly so it's up it's up to the
client to do so
and as we are seeing gss api either
encryption or signing does not guarantee
protection from non-individual attacks
some tips from different for defenders
always enable the server can sign in if
you don't do so you only expose yourself
to lots of more simple attacks in what
we have already shown
uh as we all always say monitor when we
do something in traffic
and plenty of critical servers like
azure radio connect like vmware
the same is rewarded in the wrong
controller
regarding curves injection
monitor for suspicious experience for
instance a regular machine that has an
elder stm is suspicious
and in general just
try to avoid doing with them
thank you
[Music]
you