[Music]
good morning everybody i'm dario nizi
and today i'm going to talk about my
latest work lost in the loader the many
phases of the pe file format a work that
i conducted with mariano graziano and
janik fradantoni from cisco dallas and
david balzarotti from eurekom which is
also my home institution
as the title may suggest today we are
going to talk extensively about the pdf
file format so i think it's worth to
give a little bit of background about it
the p-file format is this de facto
standard for programs in windows and it
is based on the old microsoft dos mz and
the coff file formats
the p5 format defines the headers which
are data structure the two data
structures that we find at the beginning
of each program for windows
in fact each program starts with the mz
header which is there only for
compatibility reasons nowadays it's only
used to locate in memory the starting
offset of the cff header this other
header contains generic informations
about
the program itself such as the
instruction set for which it is compiled
and the file whether it is a standalone
executables
or
dynamically linked
library
after this uff header we find the
optional header whose name may actually
sound a little bit misleading because
this header actually contains vital
information without which the operating
system would not know how to load the
program in memory correctly
such information are for example the
entry point which is the address of the
first instruction in the program
the section and file alignment the base
address at which the program prefers to
be loaded and the data directories which
have specific rules roles
which play specific roles in loading the
file in memory such as the import table
the export table relocations and
certificate table
after the optional header we find the
section table
which defines the program's memory image
which means which
represents how the program looks like
once it's loaded in memory each entry in
the section table defines a section
which is a contiguous and homogeneous
portion of memory that shares the same
permission level in terms of read write
and execution
each section has its own starting
address and size in memory its own
offset and size within the file
the p5 format supports up to 2 to the
16th power sections because 16 is the
number of bits in the number of sections
field in the coff header
now while we were studying the p
ecosystem we found
two interesting things
the first is that there is not really a
reference implementation for how to
parse correctly the pe file format and
the second observation that we made was
that the specifications or do they make
a very good job in defining the headers
and their their structure
and their field and their possible
values for each field they are not
really comprehensive they do not tell
what it is to be considered a valid p
file or an embodied one
or at least they don't do it in all the
possible circumstances
now when you take these two things
together some problems may start arising
for example the fact that there is no
really a reference implementation means
that
we're implementing the same logic over
and over again is the de facto rule for
the pe ecosystem
while the fact that these specifications
are not comprehensive enough
means that a lot of room is left for
implementation choices
when you combine these two things
together you end up with discrepancies
which are slight differences in how two
pieces of software handle the same file
as given as an input
but are these discrepancies really a
problem what are the implications of p
discrepancies well let's try let's try
to make a case for the severity of this
problem by means of two examples
first
imagine that you have a program that
runs under windows 7 but not under
windows 10.
well these of course already break
backward compatibility which is
something for which microsoft has spent
a lot of development efforts to maintain
throughout the versions
but it's even worse if you have a
dynamic analysis sandbox which runs
windows 10
well suppose that you want to analyze
this program because you suspect it's
malicious well your analysis sandbox
simply cannot run it cannot analyze this
program because it's only only runs
under windows 7.
another example take your favorite
reverse engineering tool and imagine
that for this program it gives you the
wrong mapping
now imagine that you are already working
on reverse engineering this this
program
only to find out six hours later that
your
the mapping was wrong basically you for
six hours of your day
you were just staring at ghosts
this is even worse if the reverse
engineering tool is used as a
part of a steadicam static analysis
pipeline basically each other analysis
which rely on the wrong on this wrong
mapping may be biased as a result as you
consider as you can already see
the p discrepancies are
problematic especially in adversarial
settings like malware analysis and
malware detection both static and
dynamic approaches can be evaded using p
discrepancies and even
endpoint protection software can be
bypassed you know through p
discrepancies
for example
just a few weeks ago the google threat
analysis group discovered malware
families that were exploiting exactly
something like this
in particular they were exploiting how
the operating system and openssl
parse the certificate table in a pe file
since openssl is used in a lot of
detection tools
this malware family was able to
completely bypass the detection by these
tools
while still being able to run
under windows
now our work is by no means the first
one to take of the problem of p
discrepancies but all these other works
that when published or have been
conducted before only scratched the
surface of the problem in our opinion
they only documented single-edge cases
and nobody really did a systematic study
of this problem
[Music]
and that's exactly what we did in our
work we provide a systematic approach to
find discrepancies in the pe54 in the pa
system
let's have a look to the big picture of
our work
we start with some software that we want
to compare
we reverse engineer it to
model their behavior especially how they
parse the pe file format
and then we feed these models to our
analysis framework which can operate in
two modes
the first one is validation mode which
given an unknown p file and the model is
able to tell us whether this unknown p
file is valid or not according to the
original software without running the
software itself
the second mode of operation of our
analysis framework is generation mode
which given the models can create
automatically valid test cases which are
files that the original software would
consider as valid the generation mode is
actually more powerful than that it can
also create differential test cases
which are files that are valid according
to one of the
original software but invalid for
another one
all right let's now give a
more in-depth look of the constraints
modeling phase of our work
in this phase we want to collect as much
knowledge as possible about the
operations that the original software
performs on p files given as an input
through their parsing routines
while we were performing this phase we
realized that there are three types of
operations that software usually perform
on the input files and those are
structural checks in which the software
validates the file from a structural
point of view
for example they check that all the
mandatory headers are within the file
that the magic numbers match and
everything on this line then we have
compliance checks operations in which
the software validate the program from
an operational point of view for example
the operating system may want to check
that the instruction set architecture
of the program matches the one of the
machine onto which is about to run
the third type of operation are memory
mapping in which either the program is
loaded in memory as in the case of the
windows program router
or the tool create an abstract
representation of how the program looks
like when it's loaded in memory such as
in the case of reverse engineering tools
now it's important to highlight that all
these three types of operation can be
somehow deconstructed in a set of
constraints on the original input
in order to
easily
encode these constraints we created a
language a custom language
we have different type of statements in
this language and each of them try to
solve one problem that may arise during
the reverse engineering phase
the first type of statement is input
declaration statement
let's have a look to what we try to
solve with input declaration statements
here we have the original program that
reads the input file from an external
source
in our language we model this with an
input declaration statement in which we
create a
symbol of a symbolic variable in this
case we call it input file that we then
can use in our model
the second type of statement is symbol
definition statement
with which we create new variables with
mnemonic names whose values are
asset are given by a set of mathematical
operations on the input file
in the original program for example we
have that the original program we is
creating a new uh variable called mz
header
that is taken directly from the input
file we model this in our language by
introducing a symbol declaration
statement you see we have the mz header
to which we assign the um a value which
is computed
using the original input file as an
input
the third type of statement is our
predicates predicates are boolean
formulas that can evaluate either to
true or false and these predicates can
either be
terminal or non-terminal
terminal statements
try to model those constraints that must
be met by the original file in order to
be considered
valid
for example in the original program here
we see that it's it is trying it is
checking that the magic number in the mz
header is exactly m that
we can model this in our language by
introducing two terminal constraints you
see the term keyword at the end of the
statements is what
is what defined a predicate as terminal
then we have non-terminal predicates in
our language and these are very useful
as preconditions for conditional
statements any type of statements in our
language can be conditional and the
peculiarity of conditional statements is
that they are only executed if their
precondition is true
for example in the original program here
we have that
the software is checking that the
section alignment
is greater than a certain value if this
is the case it will perform some
operation operations and at a certain
point it will check that the number of
section
is equal to zero if that's the case the
file is considered invalid we can model
this in our language by first
introducing a non-terminal
predicate
see that there is no term keyword at the
end of the statement
and then a terminal statement which is
also conditional
in which we check that the number of
section is not equal to zero
in our language we also model we also
support loops which came really handy to
handle those constraints that the
original software
enforce on
each entry of a table like structure
such as the section table
we also support structured types and
the cool thing of our
language is that you can define your
structure types using c like
syntax
all right let's now give a look to our
analysis framework starting from the
validation mode
in validation mode we want to determine
whether an input file is valid according
to a model or not
and we can do that by means of the
procedural interpretation
technique
that consists in evaluating each
statement of the model using the data
from the input file
[Music]
the file is then considered
valid if all the terminal statements in
the model are true and invalid if even
one of those is evaluated to be false
now let's move on to the generation mode
generation mode is more complex than the
validation mode in fact we start from
some models but we cannot really
generate files directly from our model
so we first need to translate them into
something onto which we can work
mathematically and we do that by
translating models into smt problems
the smt problems are then fed to the z3
backend which is based on the sm1d z3
smt
solver that the tip that the three
backend can perform a lot of tasks for
example test case generation
differential analysis differences
enumeration and corner case generation
let's have a look to them but first
let's have a look to the translation
phase between models and smt problems
translation phase is based on the
equivalence between each type of
statement in our language and smt
problems
and
statements in an smt uh problem
input degradation statements are
translated into new and constraints bit
vector
symbol and predicates become new
mathematical formulas to which we give
mnemonic names
we handle loops by unrolling them up to
a certain number of iterations
and we translate structured types
into offsets and slices in the original
bit bit vector
once the translation is
finished we take all the
terminal predicates and we combine them
together in logic conjunction this
creates the statement that the smt
solver needs to assert in order to solve
the problem now it's important to
highlight that the solutions of an smt
problem
created in this way are p files that are
valid according to the model so they
respect all the terminal predicates
all right but how can we use these smt
problems for creating differential test
cases suppose that we have two models
that for which we want to create
differential test cases we take the
first one we translate it into its
formula we do the same for the second
model
then we take the two formulas and we
apply this um
logic operation take the first we do a
logic and with the negated version of
the second formula
this gives us a second smt problem
which solutions are
files that respect all the terminal
constraints of the first problem but
they break at least one of the
constraints of the second problem
actually our analysis framework is also
able to tell us automatically which are
the broken constraints in the second
model
this came really handy for
when we were implementing the
differences in enumeration technique
with which we want to find all the
differences between two models
this is a heuristic iterative approach
in which for each iteration we solve an
smt problem that asserts some of the
previously negated constraints in the
second model this drives the smt solver
to find new ways
and new discrepancies between the two
models
in our analysis framework we also
implemented the corner case generation
technique
by which we create as many samples as
possible that are actually also
structurally different
to achieve that we leverage the
non-trivial statements in our models
for each iteration in fact we try to
assert different combinations of
non-terminal statements these result in
files that are structurally different
because the
original software would would use
different path in the in its code in
order to validate them
our analysis framework is also able to
generate samples that have customized um
customize the code
in um once it's loaded in memory
we do so by adding constraints to the
section content
of the original sample
and we're actually able to create
samples that execute valid code with
this technique even an hello world
sample
[Music]
all right let's have a look to some
results and findings of our work
to begin with we modeled this software
and we compared these these uh software
artifacts
the windows program loader versions xp 7
and 10 both the kernel space and the
user space component
we modeled claim of v specifically its p
parsing format specific signature engine
vardari 2 specifically how it handled
the memory mapping operations and yara
in particular its p module
[Music]
our tool actually found discrepancies
even between different versions of
windows
we found five of them in particular now
i don't have the time to go into details
of all of them or just mention one
briefly which i like the most and it's
uh the one about the relocations so
basically windows xp and 7 allows
executables to use any type of
um
architecture specific relocations even
though even if these are not actually
supported by the
architecture on which the program is
about to run for example in windows xp
and n7 you can use mip-specific
relocations even if you are running
under intel
executables that do this are discarded
by windows 10 as invalid
our tool also found discrepancies
between windows and claim of b
we found three of them in particular
again i don't have the time to explain
all of them uh we'll just mention one
which is we will see it's important in
uh in a moment it's about the number of
sections claim of the expects the file
to have at most 96 sections while
windows does not really have this
constraint
all these three discrepancies were
acknowledged by the developers of claim
of vs bugs and they are working on some
fixes
we also run a differential analysis
between the memory mapping operations of
all this software and we found one edge
case that all the tools we analyzed
handled
incorrectly in particular when the
section alignment is smaller than the
page size
executables with these characteristics
are mapped by windows directly in memory
as they are completely disregarding
their section table
radari guarantee nfv on the other hand
still infer the mapping of these
programs using the section table
we could not find any documentation
about this behavior so we were not
really surprised that the tools got this
wrong
so i've looked to one notable test case
that was created by comparing the memory
mapping operations of windows and radar
in particular
this is the optional letter of this test
case as you can see the section
alignment is four so it's smaller than
the the
the page size
the entry point is at this address which
means that the test case will execute
these two instructions which are
basically just return 0 in in c
this test case also have a one section
which start at this address
now you can notice that the section
table and the optional letter overlaps
our analysis framework actually
loves to do
things like this that you don't really
find in normal executables
now when you run this test case in
windows
you have something like this so as you
can see these are the very same bytes
that we saw before because the pro the
program is mapped in memory as it is and
in the last line we can see that it's
already executing the instruction the
first instruction that we um with which
we
customized the
text code
when you open this in radari on the
other hand you find this
so radar is not able at all
to find anything once the program is
loaded in memory
[Music]
all right we found these discrepancies
and we asked ourselves is it is there
any
way to find out whether malware outdoors
are already knowledgeable about them and
if they are already um
exploiting them in the wild to answer
this question we run a
virustotal live hunt
for which we created yara rules that
match all the discrepancies we
discovered
in our work except one of the
relocations due to technical limitations
of vr
we run this campaign from the 7th to the
19th of october and we estimate to have
scanned something around 5 million
samples during this period
now we were reported with we were
prompted with 467 samples that match at
least one of the yara roots we provided
and it's important to highlight that
all the rules that we provided measure
at least one sample
the most prominent about the
discrepancy seems to be the one about
the section alignment with 301 samples
matching this may trigger different
mappings in the software
the second most prominent discrepancy
seems to be the one about the 96 96
sections for claim of v with 77 samples
matching the corresponding error rule
we actually analyzed some of them
manually
and we discovered that they had 97
sections exactly which you know
to us seems that it was probably done on
purpose
all right let's now give a few more
words and a few takeaways from our work
so i believe that
the most important lesson that we
learned during our work is that there is
not really one way to enter the vp file
format and even if you want to consider
windows as the reference implementation
of how to parse the pa file format then
you should also specify which version of
windows you take as a
reference implementation because as we
saw all of them have small quirks and
small edge cases that they handle
differently
we believe that we need more clear and
more formal specification for the pe
file format and we also need a publicly
available reference implementation but
this of course takes time so in the
meantime we advise developers of
security tools to model more than one
version of the windows loader possibly
asking the user
which one to employ for their analysis
for their analysis
[Music]
we believe that our language and
framework is the reverse engineering
effort to build these models and that's
the reason for which we um release
everything as open source both the
framework and the models you can check
it out our github repository
all right with that being said my talk
is concluded so i
will gladly answer your questions if you
happen to have any
[Music]
you