[Music]
hello everyone and thank you for joining
us
my name is shir shilta mari and i lead
the security research team at with the
cloud security company
with me on stage is a launch hindo
alone leads our data and threat research
team
so i would like to welcome you all to
our talk about cloud vulnerabilities
today we would like to share with you
our idea on a unique identifier for
cloud vulnerabilities
we will talk about why we believe such
an identifier is so important
why it's critical at this point in time
and why an open database for cloud
vulnerabilities is necessary
so the outline for today will start with
discussing vulnerabilities in the
pre-cloud area how vulnerabilities that
are not related like to cloud handled
and i believe that it will sound
familiar to most of you then we'll move
to introduce you to a new type of
vulnerabilities cloud vulnerabilities
will
explain um what is different about them
and why they need a new system to handle
them we'll use three different examples
of vulnerabilities each one will
demonstrate different aspects of the
issues that cloud vulnerabilities raise
then it will move to a solution proposal
and this is actually something that we
walked with the community we have a
community of people who care about these
cloud security issues and we'll
introduce you our way to solve this
problem
lastly
we'll talk about what can we as a
community do in order to um to help and
solve the cloud vulnerability issues
so just a word about us so we are from
wiz with us a cloud security company and
our mission uh we say usually say that
it's to make the cloud less cloudy we're
trying to solve problems in the cloud
as part of that we do cloud
vulnerability research and in the past
year we had some very interesting
findings and you might have heard about
them
we had a session yesterday about chaos
db one of our findings and the important
thing is that when we
investigated these issues and found the
vulnerabilities we understood that the
csps the cloud security the
the cloud providers they have um i mean
there is some gap in the way that they
handle these vulnerabilities and this is
what we are going to talk about today
so let's start let's let's say just
imagine for a second that i'm a cso i'm
on my first day in a new job and my
responsibility is to make sure that my
organization is secured
so
if i go for
software vulnerabilities you know
there's i mean we have some solution so
you know that i have a patch management
product and usually
it goes it checks the softwares of a
software that is installed in my
environment and it compares it with a
database the cve database uh that i'm
sure you you're familiar with and if i
if this the version of the software that
i have
is listed as vulnerable i have to patch
this software and this is how i
mitigate the security issue this is how
i'm safe
but what about cloud vulnerabilities
there are some vulnerabilities in cloud
services
and the cve system doesn't cover them
so if i
what do i have to do so i read about
blogs so do i have to bookmark every
blog that
that
that is talking about these issues and
you can see some examples here to
mails or blogs that about the cloud
issues but none of them is is is uh
centralized in in one place and if i go
to my cloud security team dude did you
receive a mail like this an action
required from aws do you remember this
mail do when when you got this mail did
you did you remediate the issue
this is a
this is a problem that we see today and
now she will
start walking you through the issue
thank you
okay so before the cloud was introduced
companies and organizations were fully
responsible for all aspects of their
security from physically protecting the
data centers for maintaining security of
their network devices and also applying
security patch
to any type of software
but in the cloud
things have changed
companies no longer own physical data
centers they no longer own um servers or
network devices they share these those
services all those devices with others
in the cloud companies no longer
maintain their own storage or database
solutions
they use clouds managed services instead
so
in order to split the security
all the services the cloud provides us
as users
are no longer under our control and
therefore the cloud service provider
must be the one that's responsible for
protecting
those services
in order to split it in a convenient and
understandable way
the cloud service provider
made the shared responsibility model
now the show responsibility model is
pretty simple
everything that is owned and
in control of the cloud vendor
it's their responsibility
the cloud vendor is responsibility for
doing the physical security of the data
centers to maintain the network devices
to protect and maintain the managed
services and so on
on the other hand we have all the
responsibilities within the user side
everything in control of the user like
software
operating system configurations
identities access controls
all those are in the responsibility of
the user
and we as cloud users we need to be
responsible to maintain update apply
patches
on that side
so we've been using this model
for more than a decade
and it works pretty well
but we discovered that sometimes
it has cracks
and in these cases the outcome is messy
and dangerous
over the last several months we conduct
extensive cloud research and we found
critical vulnerabilities across
different cloud platforms
what we learn is some is that some of
those vulnerabilities
are not simply in the i mean
the responsibility of the cloud
providers
but fixing them mitigating them requires
the user intervention
now
this sometimes could be a bit confusing
how come a vulnerability
that it was in the cloud provider it's a
cloud provider vulnerability how come
that the user need to fix it how does
that happen
so we learned that cloud vulnerabilities
are quite different
than software vulnerabilities
in some cases the vulnerable code is
running on the cloud provider side so
users cannot patch it
and sometimes a provider find it hard to
change the vulnerable behavior
in their own code because users are
relying on this behavior on the
vulnerable behavior and if the cloud
provider will change the behavior of the
service it could actually break the
user's environments
in other cases we see that cloud
vulnerabilities could also exist in
cloud configurations
and in default configurations provided
by the cloud provider
now this is a real change of perception
for users who mostly treat dangerous
configurations
as
misconfigurations and we came across um
cases where configurations that was
provided by the cloud providers by
default to users
and cons and used to be safe
turned to be vulnerable
so most of the times these
vulnerabilities has no cve or any other
identifier and no severity scoring
and we discover that most of the time
cloud users are unaware of those issues
there is no official source or database
that lists them and the outcome is many
affected cloud users
there is actually a new middle zone in
the middle of the show responsibility
model of new cloud issues that we didn't
know exist
it has many kind of vulnerabilities that
there's no standard process to handle
them
these vulnerabilities does not fit in
the classic show responsibility model
there is no identification or
enumeration for these issues no severity
scoring and users find it hard to track
in the tech instances of those
vulnerabilities in their own
environments
so we would like to follow with you on
three real life scenarios that is based
on our findings where we found cloud
vulnerabilities that was not handled
properly and users tell me still still
be exposed and vulnerable to this day
the first issue
is vulnerability we found in aws uh it's
a confu it's a vulnerability class it
was affecting four different aws
services and we introduced it in a
previous black hat in august like usa
so the source of the vulnerability in
that case was that amazon provided
customers
with a default
vulnerable configuration
aws mistakenly provided users with over
permissive resource policy
allowing other aws tenants to perform
read and write operations on vulnerable
users
now the vulnerability made many cloud
resources exposed to malicious actors
and allowed those actors the ability to
read and access
to actually access and manipulate
customers data
the vulnerabilities are pretty simple
here we can see a vulnerable policy
that was issued to the serverless
repository users in amazon
and as you can see on the screen we have
the
policies that is in response that is
responsible to integrate between the
serverless repository service and the s3
bucket of the user
and the problem with that policy that it
allows any serverless repository user to
access the bucket
now this was very surprising and we
reported this to amazon
and when we disclosed that they took it
very very seriously
they conduct some service changes and
they add scoping conditions to the
serverless repository service and also
in the documentation
and they replace the old policy with a
patched one
and now when users come to use the
service and they get a documentation
it's guiding them to add the scoping
conditions and if they copy the default
policy it's already patched
additionally they also emailed
vulnerable customers about the issue
and this is the email i received in my
private aws account that tells me that
there is an action required and i need
to update the bucket policies for my aws
serverless application repository
so
amazon did a lot of things in order to
accumulate this
vulnerability
but
in research in research in a survey we
conducted
we found out that 90
of cloud users
are still vulnerable
even though we reported this
vulnerability almost a year ago
so how come so many customers are still
vulnerable to this vulnerability
so surprisingly aws cannot update and
mitigate
the
current policies of users aws cannot
edit and apply the scoping conditions
themselves on user's configuration
because
changing the user configuration could
break the environment it's actually
changing the behavior of the resource
and if the user is relying on this
functionality it will break their
environment
so users must apply the scoping
conditions themselves on their own
responsibility
so aws emailed vulnerable customers
right they send them emails they alerted
them please update your policies
could it be possible that users just
didn't treat that email or ignored it
wait you is anyone like is there anyone
like heard about this issue before or
like do you have an aws account that uh
okay no so i don't know if it means that
no one heard of it or no one received
the name
[Music]
so
let's see
let's start by asking yourself who is
receiving these emails
is it the it manager of the company or
is it someone in the r d division
we saw cases where it was developers who
were receiving those emails
what would they do with them i mean at
best they will send it to someone in
security but it was those emails will be
forgotten
another issue is tracking let's say the
email does find the right person in the
organization
how would they track the remediation
process
how would they prioritize it
security teams have so many alerts
vulnerabilities and incidents to handle
so how should they prioritize this kind
of email
is it critical
should we stop everything and mitigate
it now
maybe we can postpone it i mean there is
no severity scoring so you have no idea
and another issue is tracking i mean how
can we
track these issues
how can we know if it's already been
addressed in the organization how could
we know if someone already patched the
policies and scoped them with the proper
conditions
so the thing is that users simply lack
this information they don't know and
this is because the whole process of
mitigating cloud vulnerabilities
not really exist
so let's summarize this example
we learned that cloud vulnerabilities
uh could exist in cloud configurations
and remediating it requires user
intervention these type of
vulnerabilities cannot be mitigated by
the cloud provider itself and it
requires the user to take an action
users have no process or methodology to
identify prioritize and track these
vulnerabilities this is a new kind of
vulnerabilities usually we are like we
used to that we know about the
vulnerability we know about the software
that is vulnerable for a specific
version and we know that it's our
responsibility to monitor that and go to
fix it but when it goes when it comes to
cloud vulnerabilities the process does
not exist and people just don't know
that the cloud could be
vulnerable
and the result is that most users are
still vulnerable
and okay let's continue with the next
example
thank you
okay so the first example was about the
configuration now the second example is
about cloud middleware so first what is
cloud middleware
cloudwood delmer is a collection of
software that is used to integrate
between customer vms to cloud managed
services
and
like
what does it mean sometimes when you
deploy some of the cloud services in
order to manage your vms they need to
install some kind of an agent um
and and this agent in many cases is
installed silently you don't know about
it so one case is the
omi omi is a very a popular agent used
by um
by azure on linux vms when they want to
manage linux vm
and we we know that it's like
60 of uh azure customers have this uh
this agent um
so
we found um four vulnerabilities in omi
without them oh my god because
we thought it would be funny and
the worst of them enable a remote
attacker to execute code with the
highest privileges on on a vm uh root
privileges and
it put thousands of consumers at risks
at risk because this agent is really
really popular
now uh
microsoft let's see how they handle it
so uh they published it they issued four
different cves so it's something okay we
know cvs um on september 21 is part of
patch tuesday one of them was in rcs i
told you three lpas with even they had a
severity and they asked the customers to
update their omi agents
but as i told before customers didn't
even know that this agent exists in
their environment
and
i mean it's a
you know it's something really weird to
us i mean oh please update it but you
don't know that it's there and there is
this tweet by kevin it went viral and i
think that he summarized it very well so
microsoft don't have an auto update
mechanism so now you need to manually
upgrade the agents you didn't know
existed as you didn't know
as as you did install them
now this is not even the end so we
believe that the real turning point is
that eight different azure services were
impacted by by this vulnerability and
some of them are really popular like log
analytics azure automation sentinel and
more and usually when we work with cve
we correlate it with cpe the common
platform enumeration and this is how you
know using the cpe you know how which
products are affected by the cve now in
this case
the cpe must have been the vulnerable
azure services it is really i mean it is
really unprecedented to to add to a to a
cve the services that are affected by by
it but we we believe that it is must
have been done in this case now today
actually when you go to the cve page uh
on on the msrc's portal you can see the
names of the services but initially when
they published it it wasn't there so
if i summarize
the the the problem is that microsoft
had a cve
but customers didn't have any way to
know if they are vulnerable if it's like
if this issue is relevant to them and
which azure services are affected by
this
by
by this vulnerability and eventually as
i said microsoft responded it took them
like two two or three days after patch
tuesday and they had
sorry they had this um guidance that
they published and they decided to to
deploy auto update for these agents i
mean
we have to say like
they responded well but it took them
three days
but
this response came after this
vulnerability uh has been exploited in
the wild malicious actors so understood
the issue understood that most customers
are vulnerable and there's a an exploit
that they can use
and and they started
exploiting it and consumers were at risk
so let's summarize it
first so we learned from this example
that vulnerabilities can be found in
pre-installed middleware so you know
shear showed us before that we have the
csp side what is in the csp ownership
and we have the the user side but there
are some another you see something in
the middle that is um the software that
the csp installs on the user machine on
the on the machine that the user manages
so it's it's a quite like a new
situation and we need a system we need a
way to handle it so first we believe
that we need identification it's not
only a software vulnerabilities if azure
services are affected we need a way to
to identify it we need a way to have a
unique identification and we got we can
just treat it as like the issue with the
omi that affects some services it's it's
really difficult to discuss it this way
then we need better transparency we need
microsoft to tell us
when you have this vulnerability all
these services are affected
and then there should be an easy
tracking system
in in if you went to your azure portal
it was really difficult for you to know
that you are affected that you have now
machines that are vulnerable and we
believe that it should be easier to
track and understand whether
you have this issue
lastly remediation so in this case um
the the i mean microsoft asked customers
to remediate it themselves and change
the way they uh
they
their guidance a few days later and we
believe that for the cloud we deliver we
should have a very um like a clear
process and it doesn't have to be a
process that we think about only after
the vulnerability was released it should
be a process that you know of because we
know that the cloud mill the cloud
middleware is there
for the third example let's talk a bit
about
chaos db ksdb was an unprecedented
vulnerability cross-account
vulnerability in azure cosmos db and
just yesterday niran sagi from our team
presented it here in black cat
um
so cosmos db is a very popular managed
service um that is used among a lot of
azure customers
and the case they be incident
vulnerability was that customers access
keys were accessible and made it
possible for malicious actors to perform
read and write operations on their
databases
so when we disclose this issue to
microsoft
they handle it very fast in a record
speed and they remove the vulnerable
feature within 48 hours
but
customers access tokens has been exposed
and had to be revoked and regenerated
so
the thing is that microsoft cannot
regenerated keys of their own customers
because if i'm a customer and i'm using
this key in my production environment
if microsoft if azure will revoke it it
will break my environment
so this is why users were required to
take an action and regenerate their own
keys so to inform the affected users
microsoft emailed them and urged them to
regenerate their keys
the thing here is that people receive
this email that requires them it says
action required and
actually it's not the email this is the
psa so they received an email that says
um action required you must regenerate
your keys
but it didn't damon was lacking a lot of
information
microsoft at the beginning didn't want
to publish anything beside the email
like this blog post and they didn't
disclose the type the time frame well
customers were vulnerable and they
potentially exposed
so the remediation process was a bit
unclear people really didn't know if
they were compromised if the keys were
compromised
many users that did not receive the
email were very confused they tried to
figure out if they had the vulnerable
feature enabled in this case it was the
jupiter notebook
it was very hard
even impossible to detect
so microsoft saw the gap and they
decided to do to publish a blog about it
but it was still lacking a lot of
information
and in addition as we mentioned in the
previous examples this issue just like
the others he didn't have any official
identifier or detection rules which make
it very hard for users to remediate and
track the process how do i know if the
keys in my organization has already been
regenerated
if i'm a new cso that chemistry
organization i don't know i don't have a
track of that when the keys was
regenerated
so all those questions could not and so
easily
so if we summarize this example we
learned that leaked access keys could be
handled could not be handled by the csp
alone and requires a user intervention
there is no detection rules or guidance
for customers which was making which is
making the very hard to treat and track
those issues is there is no standard of
how to handle this kind of issues
and again
users need much more information and
much more transparency for club
providers
so
to summarize the
the three examples
the first thing we
learned is that there is no standard
notification channel
cloud providers use emails and internal
dashboards to notify customers
but this is not it's barely enough
they use the same channels to notify a
lot of things not just security things
and it's very confusing because who is
receiving these emails in the
organization if if they send
non-security stuff so i want my i.t to
receive it if it's security stuff i want
to receive it
moreover security people often find
themselves confused and like the ability
to track and remediate because they
don't have a process to handle those
emails
another basic a big issue is the less of
the lack of standard severity scoring
um
because those emails usually contain
like
critical or action required
it's not enough for us to prioritize
those emails and we don't know where and
when we should treat them
and again we come back to transparency
we believe that some of those
vulnerabilities we never heard of
because usually we get the emails the
action required emails only if the csp
suspects that our environment is
vulnerable right now but what happens if
my
environment will become vulnerable in
two months
if by accident i will apply a vulnerable
configuration
i will not receive this email again
there is no continuous process to to
track if those
vulnerabilities affecting me and the the
the the transparency issue is that we
don't have a database that lists all the
issues
with as cloud customers would like to
know about all the vulnerabilities not
just the ones that affect us today and
right now
and all the vulnerabilities we show you
it's we know all the all the details
about them because we are the one who
found them and we disclosed them with
the vendo and we pressured the vendor
and we got a lot of details from them
but we believe that other researchers in
the world also report card
vulnerabilities and we just don't know
anything about them
okay so um now we would like to uh to
move in these are the five points so
shiro explained them brilliantly now um
first what you need to remember this is
what we want you to take from this part
that first vulnerabilities are not only
in code and software vulnerabilities can
be in configuration um
related to keys and many other issues so
this is one thing we have to remember
and this is why the current system the
cve system doesn't cover other
vulnerabilities
then uh there are five five things that
we want you to remember what we think
that we lack today the identification
tracking system transparency
severity standardization and remediation
steps
now on top of that when this
previous like the last slide we've got
what we need for every vulnerability but
we also need
one place where all the vulnerabilities
will be
stored and all the information about
them will destroy the centralized
database and it must be public for
anyone to use
for cloud users who want to track their
own environment and for security vendors
want to integrate it with their
solutions
this database can only be fed
from the cloud providers themselves
and we believe that it is the shared
interest of the cloud providers and the
cloud users i mean this is the way if we
do if we have this collaboration and we
have this all this information public
we will be i mean we will all be more
secured
and to give you a taste of how it should
look let's go over the third example the
cursed db example um
and let's see how let's imagine together
how it will look like so first of all we
have an id so we chose a just a
random identifier for it
and again it's it's difficult when
microsoft wrote about this issue so it
was regarding the issue on cosmos db but
you know what happens when there's
another one if there's another eastern
cosmos db how do you know which one to
treat it's really difficult to reference
them this way so first we give it an
identifier
then as she also explained we need to to
have
a system to decide and determine what is
the severity of the issue because today
we get you know you get a mail with
action required a severe issue or just a
configuration issue we must have some
kind of a system and for the cve for
vulnerabilities we have the cvss system
which is kind of
an agreed way
to uh to rank different vulnerabilities
and now if we have one vulnerability in
cosmos db and one in aws i have to know
how to prioritize which one is more
important to handle and this system
should be universal for all csps
transparency so here for transparency we
have a few different uh
points so one we have to know which
product is affected for so for casdb
it's the azure cosmos db it's quite easy
but if you remember for omi the example
that i showed
it was more difficult and you i mean you
had different services and microsoft
didn't even publish it at the first
place
then since for cloud services there is
no version when you use a cloud service
you don't know what is the version
because the code is running uh
on the csp side
so you have to let a customer know
to give them the tools to know when
he was affected or if he was affected
and
for that we we suggest using the time
effect and i mean it's writing a time
when uh when if you use the service then
it means that you are affected lastly
the risk what is the risk i mean you are
vulnerable what could have happened to
your data it has to be really clear and
really uh understood and for kills the b
for example at the first place microsoft
didn't even want to publish any any
anything about it and we believe that
the transparency and that customers will
be able to understand the risk and and
choose themselves i mean it's not only
up to the csp customers who have the
power to understand whether they i mean
whether the information
was compromised or whether they have to
to take some actions in order to
remediate it it's not only the csps that
you decide about that
and remediation um we showed you each of
the examples we showed you required
different remediation actions and you
know with with software it was quite
easy you have a cve and you know if you
check if the vulnerable version is in
your organization if you have it you
patch it and then you are safe
unless it's exchanging then you are not
um
and and uh
yeah so
you must have really clear remediation
steps um to to help customers understand
how to remediate the issue because
there's no standard in that
and there's another item that that we
thought that could be if we trying to do
things better maybe we should have it as
well
a way to detect it so
again for cloud
cloud services it's quite difficult to
find i mean
how i mean if you are vulnerable or not
because it can be configuration it can
be if you regenerated keys so we propose
to add a reg rule rego is is a cspm
language i don't know if you know but
it's some kind of a script language you
can run it in your cloud it makes some
checks and can tell you if if your
configuration is is uh is okay or not
so we propose if we do we are trying to
do things right now let's also
ask for four rules i mean how can i
detect whether my environment is is
vulnerable or not
and here you see this is some kind of an
example for for the table uh this is how
the database would look like we will
have different issues and this this one
is only a mock-up it's not it's not real
um but
but you'll have all these issues this
information will be public and
everyone who starts who wants to
evaluate their security posture will be
able to use it and also cloud
some other security vendors will be able
to integrate it with their products in
order to help customers secure
themselves
and there's actually a funny story about
that so i don't know like how many of
you here are um like uh really our
practitioners who have to keep
organizations safe but um we showed it
to someone who that it is is a real job
and he asked me how can how can i get it
like where does this database is located
and we told them that we did it only
like to
demonstrate but but i think for us it
really showed that there is a need
for this database
so let's get back um
if you remember the beginning of the
talk i was a cesar in on his first day
of uh of the job and i told you that if
for cloud vulnerabilities i don't have
any way
to check whether i'm vulnerable or not i
don't even have a way to find which
which what is the latest cloud
vulnerability how do you do it
um so if i have now this database and i
have all this information
um i believe that it will make a work
much much more easier and i'll be able
to ensure that my organization is
secured
more easily
okay so what's next so that was i mean
we tried to explain and convince you
that there is a problem we propose the
solution but how do we i mean we don't
want to just talk about the solution how
do we make csps make these changes
so first we would like to um
we would like to ask you to join to our
community we have a slack community with
a group of people that really care about
this issue and would like to promote the
initiative of a cloud vulnerability
database open for all we have more than
130 members
from all over the world and from all
over the industry from finance companies
security data fortune 500
and
all of us are thinking together in the
slag group how to promote it how to push
it and put some pressure on cloud
providers and make it happen so that all
of us could enjoy this database so i
would like all of you to think about
joining us
and join us with the initiative
yeah and actually a lot of the ideas
that that we shared with you today and
the way we understood the problem in our
proposal is based on discussions and
meetings that we have in this group so
this is like there are people out there
who care about it and
and believe that the problem uh
that it's a real problem and they are
ready to take action and speaking of
that we have other projects i i mean we
we are not the only ones uh who work on
that and there's also the csnf project
and there's csa the cloud security
alliance they have photos for unified
cloud identifiers miter the the
organization that uh works on like the
the real the original cvs they are now
trying we're actually working with them
on on
on how cve can be applied to uh to the
cloud
but the bottom line here is that there
are many different projects and you know
none of them has succeeded in in
changing reality and we believe i mean
it's okay we're trying to collaborate
we're actually working with with all of
them but it takes time and we believe
that it's not only up to some people who
think about it it's about how the
industry reacts and we really want you
that that the next time that
you receive an email from aws
uh about an issue or an email from azure
about a cloud issue
how about to reply and tell them okay
i don't say why there is no
identification to this issue how can i
track it how can i make sure that in six
months
this issue doesn't uh repeat in my
organization ask for more details and we
believe that all
all these questions it can make them
understand that we care about our
security and we want to know this
information
and
yeah so
yeah okay
so the the bottom line is that the power
is in your hand and we believe that the
way the real way i mean we have this
proposal we we are going to promote it
and
we really believe that we should have
more power against the csps and we
should be clear that we want uh we want
more security and we deserve more
security and
we this is the way the path is to make
them when you sign the next deal when
aws how about bringing up these issues
and asking them and if we'll keep asking
them these issues we believe that
eventually the issue they'll start there
reacting and we will be able to more
secure
yeah during our disclosure when this
closed vulnerability to aws a lot of
time when we see that they don't publish
enough details or when they don't um
tell how to track it or give remediation
guidance we put pressure on them because
we know how important it is for the
community and also for our customers so
we see that pressure actually works so
we really want you to guys to put some
pressure on the cloud providers and this
is the only way to make it happen
thank you very much
um
so we would like to welcome all of you
if you want to read about
the if to see again the presentation so
we have it as a blog post on our website
we also have the slack group we
mentioned earlier and we would love all
of you to join
and you can also approach us on twitter
and ask us questions if you like and
also questions now i believe yeah yeah
and uh thank you so really thank you for
for attending and we would really love
to to engage and hear your comments and
i mean you can now just not ask
questions that if you have a comment
it's it's also okay and we also like to
thank blackhead for hosting us and it's
been a pleasure for us to to present
here
so now questions and comments
yeah
sure
so uh thanks i like the initiative hence
the comment um
i would like to comment on the first
issue that was the aws correct yes yeah
so um
of course the cloud vendors need to take
some responsibility
uh i think that was a
good example of a very irresponsible
email because it did not mention i'm not
if you can
just show it
did not mention the word vulnerability
right
uh it was worded to me like a marketing
email
hey dear user we have now added features
it does mention the action required but
let's see yes yes it does mention
actually required yes but what action
why would i take action should i act on
a new feature that they now have
released that i could potentially take
into use and and and and have fun with
uh it does not tell me that there may be
a potential business impact to date i'm
using so this is worded in a way that
they clearly they're trying to wash
their hands of this this issue so so i
think the the
your your 130 plus working group i will
join that and comment more there but but
um
do any of the
cloud vendors the providers uh
participate in this because if they
don't change their wordings in their
emails
i think it's an indicator of they are
not interested in providing this
information that would be crucial for us
to actually understand if it's a nice
feature that we could now act on or if
it's a vulnerability with a business
impact
yes um
all right thank you
um i would say that the
we do have some people from the cloud
providers in our group but
they're not representing the cloud
providers some of them are just
personally um taking um the initiative
um and regarding this email amazon did a
lot of changes it's not just html they
also had configurations but i agree that
the wording here is very
soft yeah and what's your name
no what's your name
and it's closed okay okay so you can
tell me
later because what we expect to see you
in in the community but um
yeah we were also walking like directly
for example like we are meeting msrc
today i mean we also have other passes
because you know that we know that it
might be difficult for them to be part
of this uh
community so we are also working like
directly with them and we see that they
respond and they also care it's
something difficult for them but they
also care
so um i
i think it's a great idea to have a
place where you have the missing
information that you have mentioned
i i question though the idea of having
yet another new identifier as opposed to
simply enrich cve because
i mean it's quite funny for me it's kind
of back to the future because 30 years
ago i was involved in the discussion to
create cve so
cv is just
just a key right it's just a number
the goal was from the beginning so that
it's the simplest it can be with zero
information just an identifier so that
as many others can actually use that as
a foreign key as a unit united pointer
yes and now if you try to come up with
yet another identifier then it it gets
things confused you you gave this
example of mi which has
a cve number
so
then
what we would have one in your system
and another one in the
you see so i think it's um so yeah it's
a bit confusing if you want to have uh
your unique
identifier so we don't claim that
we don't really it's not that we need a
new identifier the thing is that cv is
not just an identifier it's also a
format a standard and it has certain
fields and certain integrations and not
always it works um it's fits for cloud
vulnerabilities but the thing is that we
don't we don't um claim to have the
solution
yeah it's just like a community
discussion and extending the cv is
one of the one of the good ideas that we
that people consider in the in the
community yeah we're actually going to
present it i'll just say so we don't i
mean we suggested you know and identify
which is not severe because we know that
there are some people like in our
community that really don't believe that
this is the path to the solution and i
have to say that i mean eventually what
we first need is an identifier and i
really agree that it might be confusing
i mean we don't say we must have a
different identifier and we are also
going to present this meeting to mitre
like to the guys who work on cve as part
of their uh um like extend in
discussions of cv to the cloud so we but
in we know it takes them time they are
more like uh takes them more time to to
react and change
and we believe that we need a faster
solution so
we don't know exactly how how is it
going to look like and i really agree
that it will be confusing to have
another identifier
but so we we're more like a
generally speaking that there there is a
need for identifier we don't like
it doesn't necessarily have to be a new
one yeah i mean i i'm not in favor of
extending and extending i think cve is
already it should have remained what it
was supposed to be just an identifier
with a clear description
and then have as many as other as many
as we want other databases that that
point to that and complement with the
detection with the severity with
whatever and i think what you do
separately for cloud is great
but um
because if you if you keep enriching cve
what's going to happen is you will have
the same thing that was happened with
the idmf for intrusion detection at the
ietf which is like this huge standard
that took three years to just uh reach
some consensus
and that nobody uses at the end which is
which is kind of stupid yeah
thank you thank you and i hope you also
join
the community
um first of all thank you it was
brilliant um i'll also um join your
group going back to your proposal i was
curious you mentioned five different
items or categories what led you to
select these five in particular
you're referring to a notification and
that's very yeah
so i i think uh this is what we came up
from the discussions we had so in our
group we we took some examples and
additional examples not that these only
three and try to see
what uh
like which different categories do we
need to have there and again we are not
saying that these are the only five or
it must be only these five or maybe
there's one that i mean doesn't even to
to even be there but uh
um
but i mean this is how we we saw that we
can analyze the issues and provide the
best information for them and of course
if you have you're thinking else and you
have a different opinion we'd like to
hear that and and to change it and i
assume that since cloud issues uh vary
and there are like very different issues
so we will probably need i mean some
some of them won't have time affected
and some of them will and maybe they
will need more details for a specific
new type of issue that we've never faced
before so it it has to be like
like an agile walk and
that we'll learn from
thanks thank you
any other questions
[Music]
you