[Music]
welcome everybody to our presentation
called we wait because we know you
inside the ransom negotiation economics
my name is bobinhock and i'm a cyber
security analyst at fox iit i've been at
several departments now
and i have a background in criminology
crisis and security management
i'll give be giving this presentation
together with zong you
so you please introduce yourself
okay thank you pepe um my name is dong
woo and i'm the guy who really tear
ransomware apart
and i'm working at the threat intel
department as a threat analyst so my
daily job is reversing the malware
building automatic analysis platform
thanks
so
let's set the stage what were we talking
about
um i want you to imagine you're the ceo
of a company and it's 1 30 on a saturday
morning and you just received a phone
call from the head of your rt department
when you arrive at the office he tells
you that your company got hacked and
infected with ransomware
after assessing the damage and
assembling your crisis management team
you open the ransom notes the demand is
three and a half million dollars
you feel your gut sink in your stomach
because you spent years trying to
building your company from the
and you think about all the people who
work for you and all the families they
provide for
the ransom note contains a link which
sends you to a tour website where you
can chat with the people who hacked your
company
but after telling them that you need
more time to even start thinking about
making a payment
all they respond with this we wait
during uh this presentation we will
present you the answer to the research
questions we asked ourselves
but first let me explain why we did this
research in the first place
we all know that ransomware is a big
problem and we don't see it getting
better anytime soon
so
when a company gets it with ransomware
they find themselves in the middle of a
crisis and one thing that makes a crisis
more manageable is to have as much
information as possible
so we asked ourselves what information
can we provide to companies who get
hacked or the people who try to help
them
and
we strongly agree that not paying is
ultimately the best solution and we'll
give examples of why because we
investigated that
however
in the second half of the presentation
we're also going into
the situation when that's not possible
when paying is the only solution
so we did research into the question of
how adversaries set their price
and how information and symmetry
influences the negotiation
furthermore we asked what strategies
are there that can be used during the
negotiation to lessen the damages
well and just like with any other
research project we needed data to
answer these questions
and so you will now be telling you more
about where we got the data
all right uh well thanks for ben so
before we jump into details i'm giving a
short introduction of a ransomware
negotiation page and it's processed so
after a victim
copyright passed the url in the ransom
nodes into the tool browser it directs
the victim to a page which has the
initial price at the left hand side
and in this case is
300 000
and also there is a
dialogue session in the right hand side
which is for victim and ransomware
adversary to negotiate the final price
so in this research we focus on the
final price because in our opinion for a
financial motivated attack the final
price the final ransom cash in is
represent the profit baseline in each
attack
all right let's play again think
ourselves as an attacker the originally
ransomware we are going to make profit
as long as these factors can be taken
care carefully
these factors including
the final price should be high enough
and also there should be enough
percentage of victim pay in the end
also our cost cost for for hosting
malware for penetration testing and
developing tool sets should be
covered and last but not least the risk
factor shouldn't be ignored
so what makes this business
complicated to drive is these factor are
intertwined
now here comes a simple decision problem
we need to make
so given that the ransom price versus
the willingness to pay has a negative
correlation
it means if the price is
higher than less people would pay so
would you choose a business model that
only a small number of become paid but
each payment is significant
or on the other hand as a lot of number
of victim pay but each ransom is smaller
okay i hope you all have your best
strategy in your mind so the question we
are answering is how about the actual
ransom actors
how they play this game
in the real world
we try to answer this question by data
in this research we use major two
ransomware negotiation data set
collected by ourselves so within the um
left the first one we have
negotiations and 70 of them
decided to pay in the end
so um
apparently the
um
sorry
the ransom paid in the first data set
they are the data was collected back to
the um mid of 2019 and at that time
ransomware has just started so
this group is one of the initiator of
the ransomware epidemic
on the
right hand side on the other hand this
statehouse that was collected at late of
and at that time the ransomware attack
has become more professional
and
we test our hypothesis in the first data
set and
figure out how the adversary set the
price and also we carefully study the
second
data set to
um
to think of our negotiation strategy
because
when the second data set is collect the
ransomware negotiation process has
become more professional
i'm introducing a metric useless
interest in this research coherence and
over revenue
this rental over revenue is how the
percentage of revenue was paid as ransom
in the year the victim got reached for
example in our
data set the victim company who paid
roughly 100 million at that year
uh they they earn roughly a million
um us dollar at that year and they pay
around 36 thousands so for every median
they earn
600 and
363 us dollar was paid during ransomware
again
so with all the data calculated it is
parted to the figure at the right hand
side surprisingly most of them are in a
certain range it gives a sense that
there is a baseline
to dive deeper into the result we
further divide victims into two
subgroups according to the victim's
annual revenue interestingly as we can
see
at the figure at the left-hand side the
data is quite compact especially when
the company earns more than 100 million
so what does this mean
well the data shows if companies
they earned similar revenue and they
both got infected by that actor
and they both decided to pay eventually
they are likely to pay the similar ratio
in ransom
besides we
found small and medium enterprise
company payloads in absolute values but
relatively higher in percentage of their
robbery
and we are still studying the reason
behind it
so the results suggest the baseline of
the final ransom price within actors
might exist
the revenue the size of the company
these two factors are important when
actor is labeling the price
of course the visibility of the data is
limited so we don't expect it all the
factors can be exhausted however make
this result
worrying as
attacker always know how much a victim
would pay beforehand it is because a
victim is likely to be forced to play
this game for the very first time
on the other hand the attacker has been
playing this all day long and they know
what's in your hands
well
even we got these results the second
half of this research is going to talk
about the ransomware negotiation stretch
so but why
i have just told you in this situation
victim can't win
so even though play paying ransom is the
best choice and uh
we also realize there are worse scenario
that only to pay is the choice
so
um in this situation people will be
talking about what we have learned from
the success and the value story of this
reason where negotiations
thanks you
um
so
what can we do we just learned that
adversaries have quite the advantage
during negotiation
however
luckily the adversaries are also just
humans and humans make mistakes or are
able to be influenced into making
certain decisions
unfortunately
today we don't have the time to explain
all our findings but
we have chosen to highlight our most
interesting ones
if you want to know more we will be
publishing our full research paper soon
so keep an eye out for that
the first strategy i want to discuss is
be respectful now to some of you this
might sound obvious to some of you this
might not sound obvious
because you could say well
why would i be respectful to someone who
hacked my company and that's right a
crisis can be an emotional roller
coaster there's a lot of stake and
owners of companies can rightfully get
very emotional
however we have seen multiple examples
of victims getting frustrated or angry
in conversations
resulting in chats getting closed and
good luck getting your files back then
so you need to take a step back and look
at the ransomware negotiation as a
business transaction hire outside help
if needed but stay professional
being kind will lead to a better outcome
this is a quote i want to share with you
from one of the
negotiations we looked at and
well this was uh
there was a woman doing the negotiation
and she said since i learned about your
very positive reputation in providing
decryption keys
looking forward to hearing your thoughts
respectfully and then her name
just as an example of how
to
keep it professional
the second strategy we wanted to discuss
is do not be afraid to ask for more time
adversaries will usually try to pressure
you into making quick decisions um this
is often done by threatening to leak
documents or by doubling the ransom
after a certain amount of time
and the more stress the adversary can
impose on you the worse your decision
making will be
however
in almost all cases
from the second database the adversary
was we're willing to extend the timer
when negotiations were still going on
um
this is a quote from a negotiation that
was already two ways uh past the timer
and they asked for more time because
they
well they needed to pay 12 million
dollars and they didn't have it at that
moment so they asked for more time
and after this the adversary replied
saying that they needed to make a
payment within 24 hours of 1 million
dollars
and they would get another week for the
rest of the 12 million
and the victim replied that
they were saying well
they were really trying we've been
working all night together defense to
buy more time and we aren't there one
million dollar isn't isn't going to be
possible right now
uh team please give us some more time
well this went back and forth a couple
more times
but in the end they got the timer
extended uh for more than a week
and they ended up paying only one and a
half million dollars instead of the 12
million which was initially asked
so you can really see that
there's some
there's definitely some leeway with
these negotiations
so don't be afraid to ask for more time
the third strategy we
wanted to discuss is promise to pay a
small amount now or a larger amount
later
um this is quite conflicting with the
previous ones but
keep in mind that you can negotiate for
different reasons if you want to
uh stall for time use the previous
strategy if you want to pre pay now get
your stuff back together uh because you
know you don't have backups for example
and your business needs to go get going
this is a strategy
that will suit you
um
so why does this work well as i've said
earlier
hackers are also just people
and everyone who has seen the
marshmallow test if you haven't go look
it up on youtube it's great
um
if you have seen it you will know that
people are not that good at delaying
gratification
and furthermore um you're not just
dealing with a single person actually
company
most of the time
there's an entire network of people who
will have been dealing with you
and often the negotiator himself will
also have a boss who tells you who tells
them what to do
so these adversaries they have an
incentive to close the deal quickly
move on to the next target and earn more
money
this is an example
from a case
in which the initial demand was one
million dollars and the company ended up
paying 350k
and this is the not the victim who's
saying this but the adversary
and he said i spoke to my boss and
explained your situation to him he
approved the payment of 350k
uh dollars there will be no more
discounts raise your price price by 50k
and we'll close this deal now
so you can see there's there's an
incentive on their side uh and a boss
apparently who needs to talk to
so this is a tip that really works
if you want to get it over with quickly
but pay less
then the fourth strategy one of the most
effective strategies overall is to
convince the adversary you can simply
not pay that much money
in one of example
a company was asked to pay two million
dollars and they asked for a discount
but then the adversary gave them a 50k
discount and they ended up paying 1.95
million dollars
so well they quite quickly got a
discount and well that seems like a good
deal
however
there are
also a lot of examples in which much
less has been paid after more drawn out
negotiation
for example the previous case which we
just discussed um
the initial demand was one million
dollars and it was stocked down to 350k
and there was also one
uh in which one million dollars was
talked down to 150k
and this is a quote from
a case we worked out completely in our
paper
and in this case a victim successfully
talks down a ransom demand from 30
million to only half a million
and one of the things you can see what
they did was
well they kind of threatened to accept
what will happen
if they didn't get the description key
at all
um
and this was rather at the end of the
conversation um
but that really drove the message home
that uh
well they couldn't pay and they were
accepting what would happen if they
well they didn't get the decryption key
at all
and now you might think but surely this
doesn't always work right
with song you just told me that they can
look at our financial statements and
decide we can pay more
and we thought the same however
adversaries very rarely made remarks
about
financial statements and we speculate
that this might be because the ability
to hack a company
and the ability to read and dissect
complex financial statements
might not have as much of an overlap
it was even one fortune 500
company case we analyzed um
where we saw that the initial ransom
demand was close to 30 million
dollars and even they managed to talk it
down to 14.4 million
so even if you're
a fortune 500 company there is still a
lot of room for improvements
the last strategy i wanted to discuss is
that with the risk the rise in cyber
risk we also
see a rise in cyber insurances being
bought
um
and while we don't want to go into the
debate whether that's a good thing or a
bad thing
um one important strategy we propose is
to keep it a secret that you have a
cyber insurance
because if the adversaries find out
the negotiations will become a lot more
difficult
so and this is one thing they did notice
uh and did talk about the adversaries
and i want to read this quote to you uh
yes we can prove you can pay three
million dollars contact your cyber your
insurance company you paid the money at
the beginning of the year and this is
their problem you have protection
against cyber extortion i know that you
are now in trouble with profit we would
never ask for such an amount if you
don't not have
insurance and i want to give you another
one look we know about your cyber
insurance let's save a lot of time
together you will now offer three
million and you we will agree i want to
understand i want you to understand we
will not give you a discount below the
amount of your insurance never if you
want to resolve this situation now this
is a real chance
so
as we said if possible do not tell
anyone you have cyber insurance keep
the files
off your servers
print them out i don't know but make
sure nobody finds out so keep that a
secured especially the amount you're
insured for
so
to conclude
what we have learned is that ransomware
negotiations are an unfair game
adversaries can learn from previous
experiences and they have more
information about the victim than they
know what to do with
however
they're still just humans and we can
take advantage of that and depending on
what your goal is during a negotiation
we've provided you with different
strategies to gain back some of the
advantage
so let's take a look back at the
hypothetical case we opened with
we wait that was their reply after you
told them that you need more time to
even start thinking about making a
payment
and now after the investigation is over
all the systems have been restored it
became clear to you that they were
indeed not in a hurry
they have been in the company systems
for three weeks prior to rolling out the
ransomware
they had access to all your internal
documents including your financial
statement statements
they knew everything about you and you
knew very little about them
they waited because they knew in the end
you would pay
but how much did you end up paying the
full 3.5 million dollars they asked or
did you pay less
or did you not end up paying at all
the end of the story
will not be told by us but by the
countless of cases that will continue to
happen in the future
and we just hope that by sharing this
research we can add some fuel to the
defending side
we have demonstrated how powerful the
adversaries can be
during the negotiation but we've also
tried to create a safety net for the
unlucky victims we've fallen
thank you very much for listening to our
presentation
[Music]
you