[Applause]
thank you so I am Richard fubar I am
going to talk about capturing wpa2
enterprise credentials with a PI I am
the principal software engineer at North
Dakota State University down in Fargo
where I do Identity and Access
Management and federated authentication
so standard disclaimer bla bla bla bla
bla
I'm university so they don't care but so
first your question you might have is
why am I doing this with a PI and why
not a pineapple well because of $35 pi
is cheaper than a pineapple I'm a
software engineer I'm not network or
security or a pen tester so if 35 bucks
was easy the paddle just picked it up
yeah um and so everything I'm describing
here will work on a pineapple and
probably will work better if you're not
familiar with the pineapple it is a $200
I believe for the cheap one Wireless
testing device to compromise stuff and
test Wireless so 35 bucks is cheaper
than 200 so before we go into talking
about captioning enterprise credentials
what are Enterprise credentials so let's
focus on the two types of WPA see if
personal which is the uses of pre-shared
key which is what you're probably
familiar with from home you just have
one pre shared key and you share it on
out and it works great on all the modern
consumer devices and by that I'm talking
televisions and Roku's and chromecast's
and I have it's not my network because
once again I'm not networking right but
we have 3000 people living on our
network so some of the stuff I say might
sound crazy to you from the corporate
side because you operate completely if
we have 3000 people like living on our
network and so personal exceedingly
common there are some systems out there
they can do a pre-shared key a unique
pre shared key per MAC address and we
have that so students can put their hue
lights on the network or the Roku's or
their insert other fun things on the
wireless network so yeah um
alternatively you want to do enterprise
which is much more difficult Roku don't
support enterprise but it's one for you
when you want each user to have their
own credentials
this makes it so that you can do
identity access management much easier
when somebody leaves you don't have to
go back to every single other device and
reset the pre shared key when someone
leaves because they would know what the
pre shared key is there are two types of
credentials typically maybe I don't know
but you have using a password which is
what you're really familiar with and you
can go against something like open LDAP
or Active Directory and then give your
x.509 certificates once again I said
here's the two types this a little bit
more um the x.509 requires public key
infrastructure to sign the certificates
to generate the private keys to validate
it it is just a cert that lets you get
on the network
and so with that if you managed to
somehow intercept the traffic you're
intercepting a cert and not somebody's
Active Directory credentials that could
be used to gain access to anything else
that Active Directory lets you in and
then the other option I said was using a
password so perhaps we can do something
with that so here's how you do it on a
PI there's a project out there called
host APD and that allows you to
effectively run a access point off of a
computer so on a PI what you could do is
you could install hostapd and instead
have it Alfre up wireless over the wire
wireless card and then you you know jack
into the wire the actual connection it
would act as your access point the WP e
stands for wireless portage edition so
you know it's good how you do this it's
nice and easy
um you install Kali on your favorite
Raspberry Pi three B's these are kind of
what three four years old now they're
the easiest ones to do the three B
pluses don't the wireless card changed
and I I'm not quite sure about the for
statement I got there it it probably
does I put my for to other use but you
have to if you're using one of those you
need to pick up like one of these cheap
little USB for some reason what's is my
back wasn't my backpack little Kanna kit
wireless dongle and that works just fine
so you do sudo apt install host a PDW II
because I don't do root on Kali I use
sudo and open SSL tells you is gonna
take a long time to generate the search
for Jose
I'm a Linux admin by history I'm used to
open SSL Tommy's get to take a long time
and it takes 30 seconds and it's done or
or less this has taken me like 40
minutes this is this is a long time this
is like keep checking back like maybe I
should have actually installed screen on
this thing so I can disconnect because
I'm doing over SSH you've killed the
HTTP when you're doing this when you
actually start trying to launch it and
it's not DHCP you're killing Ehrmann
check and that takes down DHCP so if you
have it headless on your network like I
have and then the next day you try to
find it it doesn't have an IP address
anymore so you maybe want to give it a
head or static you go into the
configuration file you maybe edit the
SSID see target SSID you want and then
you watch and you watch credentials come
in assuming you have something that's
gonna attack that this is one spot the
manual edit SSID I haven't used any of
the modern pinapples I'm guessing they
can probably start figuring out which SS
IDs people are looking for start just
automatically attacking it I believe
this one can only do one at a time you
maybe can't see that that's it working
for some reason when I punched it in and
just did things my username was terrific
gdv but I'll go into the details in a
moment
so what are we attacking here we are
attacking peep using mschap v2 so mschap
v2 we're continuing the trend here
talking about stuff that comes from NT
days this is from an t4 s before I guess
with 98 so it's rather old peep is from
2005 it's an industry effort so we're
not talking anything modern and so the
abstract oppresses of what's going on
here with wireless is it the device is
looking for SSID you probably all know
perhaps better than I how it goes about
and finds that SSID but it's finding the
society that it wants to talk to since
an anonymous outer identity in plain
text over-the-air to the radius system
connected to peep radius is the
enterprise authentication system that is
used and it's in the plane it just goes
out in the plane and presumably anybody
can see it and it goes to the system
this third middle one here might be
something odd for people in the
enterprise but it
the connected radius system figures out
where it needs to send your credentials
or it can actually can proxy you to
other radius systems which is something
we do and so you may or may not be
talking with the radius system that's
connected to the access point it creates
a TLS session between the device and
radius whatever and radius you're
talking to that you've been proxy
through and then the identity itself is
sent in the plane so you username is
sent in the plane and the creds are set
in mschap v2 so host HP d WP e we act as
a destination radius system and we can
get the username and the creds so we can
see here that it the username is
terrific gvv it spits out and I'll go
over the challenge in response this is
for a different sort of method of
attacking I'm assuming you see the
cursor on the screen maybe that but and
then this is John the Ripper format here
and then hash cat Bowl that format and
so you just grab those things and throw
them into your favorite cracker
obviously out of Pi I we are doing a
hacking lab that we run around and do
things with and on the PI we you know do
a pre-populated word list because a PI
is not gonna crack passwords very
quickly so there's one called asleep a
asleep I don't know how you pronounce it
first developed in 2004 by Joshua right
we end up with control with the random
value and so what it does to
authenticate is it des encrypts the
number three times using parts of the
ntlm hash and your ntlm hash is 16 bytes
and so does 7 bytes 7 bytes 2 bytes so
that third des is a 2 to the 16th
combination so it's really easy so now
you only have to crack two Dez's and
it's the same random so you get the same
sort of information out of it and you
can start doing a dictionary search so
how do you defend against this sort of
credential grabbing and using peep and
the answer is you don't use PP you see
TLS and I'll get into the challenges
behind that in a moment
so things that you could do and you
probably should but the clients can be
configured to validate the radius
certificate the
being presented to it so you think of
your web of trust sort of thing in TLS
over the web over HTTP you're validating
that the cert is in your trust path this
wouldn't even have to be in the truss
path you wouldn't want to have the
wireless devices trusting the trust path
because anybody could come up with
something but you can provide your own
certificate and when you configure the
clients you can say okay only talk to
this sir so then it would an attacker
spins up a system on their pie or the
pineapple it won't connect because it
doesn't match the cert and Apple devices
do this by default so when you first
connect an apple device to one of these
networks it will prompt the user to
accept that certificate from the radio
system so that's kind of good for Apple
um however I'm sure you can figure a way
out to a social engineer and make it so
people go through and click that button
if they see it that does protect an
apple from you know just somebody just
walking by or driving by and grabbing
credentials from a phone it just happens
to use an SSID and tries to connect so
that would protect you there but I'm
sure you give so little engineered well
your certificate expires you have to
teach all your Apple people to go
through and hit the button to redo it
Android and Windows carnem our helpdesk
yeah they don't do any of that by
default you can manually install the
cert but that's an extra step
I've got 14,000 students that have
sometimes can't follow the certificate
installation instruction is a very per
operating system because with Android
it's all over the place so it's really
bad so it's really only a partial
solution
the other challenge we've had is that
you corporate people like to lock your
machines down and so when those
employees that you're paying to take
credits from us come on campus they come
on with a laptop that we can't just sell
certs on to make it trust our network so
that's a challenge so eep TOS this is
it's secure but it's difficult to
support I think it's actually older than
peope it was like they're very one of
the first ones you need public key
infrastructure to generate and sign the
certificates Apple devices use it
profile and this we used to do this
method it worked really really well I
thought anyway the profile will get
installed bring in the certs do the
trust we could have a wipeout
like our of sign up SSID that worked
quite well windows and Android devices
are much more complicated they yeah
sometimes it lockdown by the enterprise
to bring it on and you can't get custom
certificates it's just kind of
problematic to get this to work it's
like when the oldest standard since
unfortunate that it's a pain to get it
to work
Android appeared to be all over the
place sometimes it would work on devices
you know work on Samsungs without LG's
or Samsung's would break all of a sudden
I know with my own phone which I've ran
a nexus it back then it during operating
system updates all of a sudden I would
just stop connecting to the network so
that's not fun it's not a good end user
experience incurs a very high cost what
am I being back here with this radius
certificate I guess I didn't mention is
that setting this up is really really
easy to do to speak by hand and so even
if you do have a process in place and
documentation or install or something
like that to get that certificate in
there so it's pinned
there's nothing guaranteeing that the
end user will do that every time because
all they get prompted for it is username
and password and another username and
theirs punch it in a way they go so you
aren't guarantee that you have a good
process to put that certain place that
that cert is in place so they'd only
trust the correct radio system unless
you have some sort of enterprise
management software on top of your
clients which once again we don't so
just talking about proxying
authentication this is a capture of a
map from canary which is your research
higher ed research group up here and all
these pins are an SSID that I can
connect to this is called a Jerome it's
kind of cool so ed Jerome is a giant
project with entities in 101 territories
basically countries that allows students
faculty and staff to connect to wireless
networks at other places so
theoretically I try to get it walking
past the University of Winnipeg and my
device didn't want to connect us I was
just walking past but theoretically I
can get on their network with whatever
permissions they give me using my NDSU
creds so what ends up happening is I'm
presenting that outer identity I give it
some baloney thing that says at NDSU the
edu
and it knows to route from here probably
up to the Canadian national probably up
to G Alan and then down to the US
national and then down into our radio
system as those proxies around it's
quite awesome it's it's great it's I was
able to grab Wireless in the airport to
of Oslo and museums in Europe and I had
really slow internet connection at my
air B&B and Riga and my phone was just
like bogging it down so I wouldn't find
a university and let's grab their
Wireless so the challenge with this and
with all these especially in higher
education is that we see lots and lots
and lots of devices we have about 11,000
devices connected to our network every
day that vary and from laptops to cell
phones to IOT devices to who knows what
and so just trying to figure out how to
manage all this is challenging and I'm
sure it's challenging for you guys as
well that's really all I got I don't
know how quickly I bless you that but
many questions thank you
[Applause]