thank you thank you hello everyone thank
you for having me here good afternoon
this is my third time speaking at the
long con previously I talked about
passwords and ntlm relaying so I'm going
to talk about my other weird obsession
which is evading antivirus for those who
don't know me I am
Travis freezer as my contact information
and since my last time speaking I've
added a little bit to my alphabet soup
because as we all know he who dies with
the most certifications wins so I'm well
on my way to total victory I figure I'm
actually here in two capacities first I
am the chief IT security consultant for
Merlin Merlin is the the chief internet
and Internet services provider for
education in Manitoba and in that rule I
wear pretty much every single InfoSec
hat imaginable I do forensics
penetration testing incident response
policy you name it but I'm also here as
the co-founder of Flying Fortress IT
it's a it's a small firm I founded with
with my Kimbo where's my keys back
there's that guy back there and together
we try to offer a cloud and InfoSec
expertise to small and medium-sized
businesses generally you know the sort
of organizations that could really
benefit from having such a professional
available but obviously can't justify
having a full time professional on staff
so if that sounds like you or somebody
you know come give us give us a call and
send us an email come talk to us and
we'll see we can do to help you out
speaking of mic I could use it a beer
might give me give you a 1919 awesome so
anyway no not for you
now one more obligatory slide before I
get into it and this this should go
without saying but sadly it does not the
things I'm going to talk about here are
starting starting to veer a little bit
into some of the dark arts right I'm
gonna be talking about generating
malware and bypassing antivirus and
tries to say please please please use
this knowledge for good not for evil
and if you
do use it for evil you you didn't yeah
Packard that if you do use it for evil
don't blame it on me okay now this may
this may immediately raise the question
if this can be used for evil is it
ethical for me to be sharing this
information and to that I say yes yes it
is and it's not because I have no ethics
it's because the sort of things I'm
telling you are sadly not particularly
revolutionary and it's everything I'm
saying is stuff that the bad guys are
already are already well aware of and
are using and are using much more
advanced techniques now the point of my
talk is more about them as much as I
hate the phrase it's about raising
awareness of the limitations of
antivirus and in relying on it as part
of your network defense okay onto the
meat
I'll just over the background on the
various antivirus techniques and how it
works
so antivirus Jim Willie uses two kind of
categories of techniques uses kind of
more static analysis and dynamic
analysis so starting with the more
static analysis the more the most basic
way of detecting viruses involves
signature based detection now this can
be as simple as simply identifying a
malicious piece of the malware and
generating a signature for it like like
taking the md5 sum of the entire entire
file sharing that amongst all your
endpoints and if you see that particular
file hash you know it's malware flag it
block it won't allow it you know
obviously that's very easy to bypass you
know just tack some no bytes on the end
or or change the byte in the file and
you have a brand new hash but the
reality is this is still a very
effective way of detecting viruses and
probably you know more than 90% well
thank you that didn't take forever but
don't know what service anyway yeah so
we the most basic is yeah just hashing
an entire file but you can also generate
signatures and thumb prints for
individual parts of the file the various
sections or strings or even individual
functions and coal blocks in the file
can be fingerprinted and signatures can
be generated for that starting to get a
little bit more dynamic code we start
looking at various heuristics so in this
case what we're doing is we're analyzing
the file and determining how much weird
is in it and if there's enough
weird is in it the past a certain
threshold we flag the file and say hey
this is probably malicious now it can be
things like if you see a lot of knobs in
a file a lot of weird strings uncommon
library calls or even if it looks like
the binary was generated by an uncommon
or a rare compiler supposed to you know
something like other than Visual Studio
for example that could mean the file is
itself somewhat suspicious now obviously
tuning these scores could be very
challenging but I'll put that threshold
too high and you start missing malware
put it's too low and you start
generating a lot of false positives
which are almost as bad as letting bad
stuff through in the first place right
next to in the word the more dynamic
sort of thing we can start doing
behavioral analysis on the malware this
is basically asking what does the
program do when it's being run what what
kind of weird stuff is going on so if
you see suspicious activity like a lot
of weird DNS queries or other network
traffic
certain library calls if it starts
reading and writing to files in you know
census locations like sequel and Windows
I mean that's weird
flying that stuff it's and something
something weird is happening or or even
things like if it starts modifying its
own its own executable code the old
instructions that's where it's
monitoring keystrokes it's pretty much
guaranteed that if your program is
monitoring your keystrokes it's probably
malware and should be stopped now one of
the downsides of course to behavioral
analysis is that it requires that the
malware be run before you can do any of
this analysis right so at that point
your computer's already infected it's
kind of too little too late in some
regards and that's where the next kind
of technique sandboxing comes in and and
this is kind of doing the behavioral
analysis in kind of a
trolled environment before the binaries
actually run on the host and this can be
done sometimes locally on the host or
the big you know hotness right now is of
course running it in the cloud okay so
enough about that on to some of the
tools for generating malware and
bypassing antivirus so basically I'm
just going to talk about some of the
popular tools I demonstrate how to use
them how to actually generate this
malware and then I'm going to tell the
samples that I generate and upload them
to virustotal
to see how they do it by passing
antivirus now virustotal a big asterisk
here virustotal not particularly a
real-world application so just because
i'm getting past something on virustotal
or not getting past the thing i
virustotal doesn't necessarily mean
that's what's going to happen in the
real world but it is convenient and I
don't have a lot of you know time or
energy to do all that so I'm just
going to use virustotal and with one
more caveat if you are you know trying
to create your own malware and bypass
antivirus cuz you know you're on the red
team engagement or or whatever don't do
that don't upload it to virustotal
virustotal is notorious for sharing
signatures amongst the different vendors
and you know what you woods by passing
antivirus today i'll blow dis virus toad
well tomorrow now it's being caught so
so don't do that anyway onto the tools
also to start with MSM venom MSM venom
is the payload and malware generator
that comes packaged with the Metasploit
framework now a Matthew in the last
presentation talked a bit about
Metasploit and some of its limitations
it's not as sophisticated as some of the
commercial Suites out there but it has
the advantage of being open source and
therefore free and I am a cheap-ass so I
like it anyway here's the basic usage it
is a command line tool so you're running
a MSF denim and then I specify list
payloads right and this gives me a list
of all of the payloads that MSF enim can
generate there's something like I think
there's 350 different payloads some of
the more interesting than others but I'm
not going to go through each and every
one of them so once you sorry
MSF venom also supports a number of
output formats these are the actual
binaries that it generates when you use
the tool and you can see them by
specified
your list formats here so you can see
various binaries you can do dll's a
laughs exe is of course another binary
formats it also has something called
transform formats so in this in this
mode when run it doesn't generate a
binary instead it outputs the payload in
a format that you can then integrate
into say a C program or C sharp or bash
where you can either do you know
additional transformations on or you can
incorporate it into you know a larger
exploit or malware suite if you want
okay so once you've selected the payload
and here I've selected just literally
the most basic payload you can possibly
imagine uh reverse a TCP shell of for
Windows right it connects back to the
attacking computer I get a command shell
I can run basically you know cmd.exe
sort of sort of stuff and then just see
what options it supports as I tossed the
list options on the end there and this
tells me the options I have available
exit func you don't need to usually
worry about that too much but I have to
specify the local host the the IP
address that I'm connecting back to you
as well as the port that I want to use
so here I've actually this one's a
little bit small I apologize here I've
actually run the command so MSF venom -
key there's my payload the the host I'm
just going to use 1.1.1 for example
purposes that I'm connecting back to
port 9999 for the port to use and then I
specify - F the format is an exe file
and then noteworthy here is that MSF
venom creates its output to the
standardout so if you actually want to
capture the file and not screw up your
terminal I need to I need to pass it
into an actual file at the end there
I've just called a payload Exe so how do
we do well not so great this very very
basic payload was caught by 53 out of 68
different AV suites that virustotal
uses so from the you know red teamers
perspective you know that's not very
good we're not getting past very many
but at the same time when you think of
this from a blue team is perspective we
are using literally the most basic
payload that msi venom can generate and
fifteen antivirus Suites didn't actually
detect that yeah so let's see were there
any notable ones in there a few I don't
know if anybody uses malwarebytes just
may have heard of it but it did not
detect our payload there's a few caveats
here I've asked mobile for instance
you've probably heard of avast
but their mobile antivirus is probably
tuned for looking at like AP AP KS and
that sort of thing so you just have to
understand some of the context here same
with the Symantec mobile insight it
didn't even analyze the file right
because it's looking for mobile
applications as opposed to Windows
executables okay so MSF venom also has
the ability to use what are called
encoders now encoders are not really
intended to be used for antivirus
evasions they're more about you know if
if you want to create an exploit and you
can't use any null bytes or new lines
for whatever reason the encoders that
you help you kind of get around that by
substituting by it's using you know xor
encoding and that sort of thing so here
are some of the encoders that it
supports you know that's blocks or
countdown all sorts of interesting stuff
I would draw your attention to the
Cadogan I write it at the bottom there
that's a very popular one it has an
excellent rating for a very good reason
it is quite effective
I think it's Stan I think it's Japanese
for something like like I don't care or
it doesn't matter or something like that
it's your name but anyway let's go ahead
and use it same sort of format MSF venom
is my payload I'll host l port Exe but
then I'm specified with a dash e option
that I'm going to use the Chicago gain I
encoder and then again dump my payload
to a file so how does that do well not a
whole lot better
we've gone from 53 to 52 we're making
progress but it's pretty slow so who
else did we catch if we've got an
additional bypass EGH ambit I know if
anybody's heard of Egan but I sure
haven't so I'm not consider that
substantial process progress I'm so in
addition to this MSF venom you can
choose a bunch of different encoders and
actually chain them together do multiple
iterations but in general encoders while
they were once effective at getting past
antivirus they're less effective today
the antivirus suites are kind of onto it
and they're not really intended for
getting past antivirus right they're
about
you know changing your payload up so to
avoid certain bites and that sort of
thing
so it's not really an effective method
anymore unfortunately okay on to the
next tool I'm going to talk about
packers for in specifically I'm going to
talk about upx so Packers are a utility
that you use to to take an existing
executable and try to get it down to a
small size as possible it does this by
stripping out as much metadata it
compresses it as necessary and
what-have-you and the goal is to get a
small executable like if you're if
you're serving up an executable on your
website you want to minimize the amount
of bandwidth used or maybe you want to
fit your executable and like a you know
three and a half inch floppy disk right
it's why you do that but you px can help
you if you need to do that now because
but during this process of stripping out
the metadata and compressing down the
file it has the side effect of
obfuscating the actual payload that's in
the executable so how do we use it it's
pretty straightforward you px - oh
there's my payload output name payload
input name packed it no problem
how does it do Oh better we're down to
we're down to uh 46 right that's we're
making progress here it's uh I think
that's better than it was last time so
well did we get past now any big names
no big names stuff that I haven't heard
of before where there's there's max
secure or secure age or or my personal
favorite superantispyware has now been
bypassed so I so if you're using super
antivirus that you need an additional
reason to not use it there you go
but anyway it was the end X that came
who started talking with Yandex earlier
that's ones on there okay so that's GPX
let's go back to MSF venom and it
specifically I want to talk about
templates so when you're generating an
executable file with MSF Denham
it has a built in default template of
what an executable file should look like
all the you know header information and
better day than all that that it
uses now because this is the default
template that ships with MSF Denham most
antivirus vendors have become fairly
well tuned to that they know where to
watch for it and it's less effective if
you're using the default template so if
you specify your own template of what
next
we'll look like you can often improve
your bypass rate that's what I've done
here same-same jazz at first you know
miss fnm there's my payload I'll host
teleport and all that jazz but now I've
specified - acts for a template oh it's
an ax and I've grabbed a vanilla version
of putty Exe from the internet and we're
telling it to use that as the template
for my for my payload I've also added
another option there a - K that stands
for keep the original functionality of
the template so this is a really useful
feature for OPSEC because what it's
doing is that in a means the resulting
payload payload v dot exe will still
behave exactly like it's still putty but
it will include my my malicious code I
was essentially backdoored this
particular executable and this like I
said is really useful for OPSEC you know
if somebody clicks on putty Exe and
nothing happens
party doesn't come up that's a bit of a
red flag right and and sometimes the
most effective form of antivirus out
there are the users themselves you know
sometimes the least effective form of
antivirus is also used for themselves
but if you're dealing with a
particularly a technical target this can
go a long way to helping you at least
get past that level of human interaction
so anyway how does it do when we do that
actually that's a pretty substantial
improvement we're down to 41 out of 67
are there any big names in there let's
see yeah we're starting to land some big
fish we got we got McAfee who has
probably heard of McAfee and Trend Micro
are now being successfully evaded using
the technique of using a different
template now remember you px that we can
often use you px to to kind of chain
techniques and and improve our bypass
rate but unfortunately when I try to use
you px with this new payload payload 5my
I get an error it can't can't pack it so
there's a bit of a limitation sometimes
with these tools they don't always work
nicely together it's nice when they do
but you can't always rely on that so
anyway on to the next tool the next one
we talk about is called a veil evasion
mmm-hmm pardon me there we go
so validation there's another popular
open-source tool it was used to be a
real big name and antivirus evasion a
couple of years ago the author was
regularly putting out new updates
usually about once a month and every
month they'd be these new evasion
techniques and the antivirus vendors
would have to scramble just come up with
ways of detecting these new these new
evasion techniques now unfortunately I
don't know if the author just doesn't
time or lost interest there haven't been
any significant updates to veil evasion
in a couple of years so it's kind of
fallen by the wayside it's not as
effective as it once was but let's just
try it out anyway it's still a useful
tool come on Ariel so when you run it it
actually has it has a command line
interface as well but it also has this
nice kind of menu driven interface which
couldn't kind of help you help guide you
through the process of generating now
we're using a veil evasion so here's the
main menu my type of list in my payloads
here are some of the payloads there's
about 30 40 different payloads here's
just a selection I'm gonna use this one
down here
the c-sharp hazard CS downs vertices
sharp based meterpreter shell using a
reverse TCP connection meterpreter if
you're not familiar it's kind of an
advanced type of shell that's enjoyed by
red teamers because it has is a little
functionality that's useful for anyone
doing a penetration test and similar to
a shell but it's a litte bit more
advanced so anyway once you select your
payload that it gives you a whole bunch
of different options that you have this
is your typical ones you know L host L
port and Jack Shea method a compile to
exe is nice but I want to draw your
attention to a couple of other ones here
including like say domain username and
then that sort of thing so these these
options are very useful for helping to
avoid sandbox analysis because when you
specify these options it will cause the
payload to only execute when it sees
that the domain being used by the host
matches what you specified in the
malware so if you specify like my domain
or my user the payload only executes if
it sees that the user is my user on my
domain
so that's what I've done here I started
a set a bunch of basic options my domain
my
I threw in asleep so it waits five
seconds before executing the payload
that's another way of getting past
sandboxing sometimes and use the Aria
encrypter that's just another thing to
kind of help a bypass so I generate the
payload
I call it payload seven how does it do
pretty good actually we're down to we're
on to 25 are those 69 antivirus suites
detecting our malware we're past the
halfway point yet we're better than 50%
bypassed so rather than go through that
the screen shot again I've just kind of
highlighted a few of the big names that
we've now successfully evaded with this
particular payload obviously Avast AVG
BitDefender clam baby and for the net
these webs are probably ones probably
names that everybody here will recognize
notable ones that we have yet to evade
from that list include Kaspersky zone
alarm nod32 and everyone's favorite
Windows Defender we still have not
bypassed these these particular Suites
so what else could media well let's
bring back upx try to pack this one
unfortunately upx doesn't support dotnet
files which is when you're using the
c-sharp c-sharp payloads they come in
the down that format and you px can't
really do anything with them well that's
unfortunate however what happens if we
change up the specific payloads
sometimes just using a different payload
from a particular tool can give us
better or at least different results
it's not always important to have a
better results so long as we're
bypassing additional antivirus Suites
that we weren't bypassing before right
it's important that we have a way of
getting past any particular antivirus
suite so anyway I've chosen one that's
based on Python rather than in c-sharp
and this supports a compile to exe
format for Python it makes use of PI
installer to change the raw pay the raw
Python payload who into an actual
executable that's obviously very useful
if you're attacking hosts that don't
have the Python runtime environment
installed so same sort of thing I set a
few useful you know domain username
generate all that jazz and how does it
do 26 it's a boats about the same a
little bit a little bit worse but do we
get past any new
antivirus Suites that we weren't getting
past before that's the key question and
yeah we got a couple on there so far all
getting past that and nod32 it's a
rather popular one that we're again now
successfully bypassing so even crossing
nod32 off our list we still not getting
past Kaspersky zone alarm or Windows
Defender well let's bring it right now
I'm going to talk about shelter shelter
is another popular tool it's not open
source but it does have a free version
as well as a paid version the paid
version has additional features like
doing using dll's and that sort of thing
but the free version is also pretty
effective it is limited to 32 bits
binaries but you know that's okay you
can still make use of it so shelter is a
dynamic shell code injection tool and
the idea is it injects shell codes into
existing 32-bit Windows executable it's
kind of similar in in principle to when
I when I specified party dot exe as a
template for MSF denim it's kind of the
same idea but it's doing it in a
different fashion with some very
important differences so shelter makes
use of the existing binaries structure
it doesn't you know add additional code
segments it doesn't you know allocate
additional executable memory or anything
like that and says what it typically
does is it scans through the binary and
tries to find what are called code caves
places in between functions and code
blocks whether it's like kind of dead
space and puts the shell code in there
so it leverages the existing executable
code segment without having to make
additional function calls and those
things are often out to trigger a B if
you're if you're allocating additional
executable memory or changing execute
permissions will often throw up a red
flag so it gets around that
okay so shelter um again you can run it
from the command line as a command line
interface but like veil evasion it has a
lovely little menu driven interface
which will help walk you through the
process of creating creating your own
malware but I'm gonna run it straight
from the command line with the options
because you don't need to see all that
other jazz you know I specified a basic
reverse TCP shell ill host import I
specified the - - stealth functionality
and that's similar to the
- k option for MSF then I'm where I'm
telling shelter to keep the original
functionality of the original binary you
know for OPSEC purposes and I'm going to
use putty dot exe again so it runs
through 33 out of 69 not bad taking a
bit of a step backwards but again the
question now are we getting past any
additional antivirus Suites
we weren't I didn't I needed to slide in
there apparently but no we weren't
getting past any new ones that weren't
getting past before but bring back her
old friend upx take the the output the
putty Exe and create a new putty - dot
exe and let's see how that does yeah
we're down to 23 that's not bad look the
same as before but were there any new
Suites were bypassing and yeah we got a
couple we fact we've nailed some of the
big names we're now bypassing Microsoft
we're bypassing Kaspersky and we're
bypassing zone alarm so at this point
I've kind of knocked out a lot of the
big names that I had targeted before and
we're especially real to get past pretty
much any big name antivirus vendor just
by varying what tool and what payload
the belief we've chosen so one other
thing you can do differently I was using
putty Exe for my you know seed
information but that's my original
binary but suffice it to say I'm not the
first jackass who use putty dot exe and
and been throwing a payload in there and
uploaded it to virustotal
and because putty is a very common
binary to use for those purposes a lot
of antivirus vendors have kind of become
wise to that and they have a lot of
signatures and stuff that they've tuned
specifically to catch putty right so
what I went you probably can't see that
but what I went out and I found pretty
much the most obscure binary I possibly
could it's some like random custom calc
allocation for Windows 90 Windows XP or
whatever and I used that with with
shelter and by using that instead of
putty XE I was able to get my detection
rate down even further to just 19 out of
68 1900 68 antivirus tools okay dr. Emma
says Emma in version 5 SF venom released
the included the ability to increase
your payload and you can use AES RC for
XOR or base64 encryption to to basically
obfuscate your payload no the idea is
pretty simple
encrypt your payload and then write a
routine that decrypt your payload and
then officially runs your payload and
this is good against some static
analysis but obviously this is going to
help you very much against any sort of
behavioral analysis because even change
the behavior of the program very much
unfortunately while the MSF venom will
encrypt the payload for you you have to
write your own decryption routines I'll
kind of show you what that looks like
real quick basic formats the same MSF
venom there's my payload l host l port
I throw should Cadogan I in there
because why the hell not I've chosen RC
for for my encryption routine and
specified a key my key very creative RIA
and I've actually told this time to
output it in the C format because I
meant as I mentioned you have to write
your own decryption routine so I need to
actually take this code put it in my own
program to decrypt it before I can
actually run it so that looks kind of
like this there's that's the payload at
the top there there's my key main void
allocate the memory and decrypt it and
then do some function pointer magic to
actually call the code directly how does
it do on its own not great
thirty-six out of 69 it's not terrible
but it could be better now again this is
this is kind of a simple application of
using encryption you can combine it with
some of the other methods I've talked
about and you can probably get a better
result than this so anyway this is just
a small sample of the tools that are
available I've I've not touched on
theirs there's tons out there
sharpshooter puppy and X crypt all sorts
of different tools my sure cobalt strike
has something I'm sure you know Matthew
or or Tim could tell you about some
tools that they know about that I'm not
even aware of for obfuscating payloads
helping them to bypass bypass antivirus
yeah it feels like every five or six
months somebody comes up with some new
hotness new tool for for bypassing
antivirus and then another couple of
months go by and the antivirus vendors
catch up and you know the cat-and-mouse
cycle continues
and continues just briefly I'm going to
talk about some of the advanced
techniques I'm not gonna demonstrate
them because sometimes they're just a
pain in the ass to do but they're there
and one of them is just using really
really big files now this used to be
much more effective you know ten years
ago or so whereas a lot of antivirus if
it's all like a like a 500 megabyte file
or something like that it just wouldn't
touch it
right and that sounds ridiculous but it
kind of makes sense when you stop and
think about it right because if it had
if you had to scan the file from start
to end a whole gigabyte file that's
going to take forever and if there's one
thing users love complaining about its
how their antivirus is slowing down
their desktop right so they can't they
can't have that and but even nowadays
even though it's more sophisticated
there's a lot of an anti-virus might not
scan it from tip to tail but it might
disable some of the some of the more
time-intensive scanning techniques even
virustotal tops out of five hundred
fifty megabytes you can't upload a file
larger than that to virustotal and when
i uploaded one 470 megabytes a 12 of the
antivirus vendors just said yeah we
can't process this this is this is too
big it actually generated a false
positive that way on a bond the binary
that I knew was clean so that was that
was a little weird but anyway like I
said this is used to be much more
effective in you olden days nowadays
less so the other technique you can use
is called separation and the idea is
that your payload is in exists in one
file like say a DLL and then that code
is then called from another file from
say like an executable file that loads
that DLL that you package it together
traditionally antivirus pays less
attention to dll's
again not as much the case as it used to
be they're getting they're getting wise
to this trick as well and it's also more
challenging for a red teamer or malware
author to deliver because now you don't
need to just get one file to the users
you have to somehow get get to code
signing abusing code signing many
antivirus suites aren't as rigorous with
signed binaries if they see that the
binary is appropriately signed you know
they they kind of wait they're
heuristics core is a little bit
differently and you can sometimes
exploit that to sneak your pillow
passed antivirus it doesn't even
necessarily need to be a valid
certificate or signature on the file
just the fact that it has it can
sometimes cause antivirus to kind of
slacken their response a little bit and
it is easy enough of course obtain your
own code signing certificate and then
just get it signed beware though if
you're not using a valid server
signature the user of course will get a
warning on Windows and that comes back
to what I was saying about users being
sometimes the most effective and also
the least effective form with antivirus
out there okay so the takeaway is that I
have for you from this talk couple
number one just about any antivirus
suite can be bypassed given enough
effort and time now the techniques I've
demonstrated here are not super
sophisticated the bad guys the guys
you're trying to get into your network
they know all sorts of advanced
techniques that I haven't I haven't even
talked about here and the point just
being you know don't rely on antivirus
as the sole line of defense in your
network it's not you know it has some
value but if that's all you got going
for you you're gonna be in serious
trouble
don't anybody takes any notice of your
network and wants to put any time or
effort into into getting in point
takeaway number two for the red team's
Rickon and research are keys to success
knowing what antivirus suite you're your
target is using is extremely important
because then you can target your
resulting binary against that antivirus
suite for helping you get past it right
you're not wasting time trying to get
past all antivirus Suites which can you
know time is money and that's what
you're billing your clients and they
don't want that so it helps you focus
your efforts a lot and not waste time
and resources the the third takeaway is
to don't not use antivirus even though I
just spent the last half hour talking
about how any antivirus suite can be
bypassed enough time and effort it's
still it's still really still very
valuable it's still something that you
should have on your network and now
there is an argument especially recently
that having antivirus running on your
system actually increases your attack
space right there's the antivirus has to
run in an elevated position in order to
do what it does and I don't wonder what
the suite it was me it was malwarebytes
I don't remember
had a critical vulnerability which
allowed an attacker to to leverage of
the antivirus suite to gain system level
privileges
it was Symantec okay I'll take your word
for it
but yeah but even with that in mind it's
still better than nothing and the
reality is antivirus is great at
catching that you know 90% 95% or or
higher of the generic you know malware
that we see every day right all that
that gets mailed out to a billion
different email addresses antivirus is
great for that right and catching that
stuff is important too so don't not use
antivirus last last point I want a less
takeaway I have is websites like
av-comparatives yeah they're a total
joke I don't know if you're familiar
with them but it's like a it's a website
and there are others like it I see you
there Jay looking very good today by the
way yeah yeah that's super worth a
couple extra minutes I figure right okay
all right
AV comparatives is a joke yeah it's a
website for comparing different AV
Suites and trying to evaluate how they
do which ones better at detecting now
where and all that and they're just
a total joke like for instance according
to AV comparatives Avast has a ninety
nine point three percent online
detection rate there's September 2019
test but we all saw how long it took me
to come up with malware that's still the
right past Avast or avj right so it's
kind of like what are they what are they
really evaluating you know these numbers
are largely meaningless right and and
the look and the approach that they're
taking of taking a suite of known bad
malware and seeing you know which
antivirus captures which it's just it's
really the wrong approach for evaluating
your antivirus so that is everything I
had to say apparently I got five minutes