home home
home
call me
of
ap for the ER methods of copying high
security keys
be lost Film Festival take place tonight
in the pavilion movie area that's on the
second floor so if you wanna check out
some minor
films that all the whole conference is
always tend to have some interesting
flex
am Sunday from 10 a.m. until 1 p.m.
you cannot come to the sixth floor sir
or chrome
to take I what are the FCC ham radio
exams
so if you want to get your ham radio
license I'm you can do that at this
conference
also out DVD sales of all the talks
I at every discussion that goes on at
this conference you can fire DVD right
out here in the vid
vendor area on the 18th floor I'm also
some people think wired about the
bizarre artworks that are hanging up at
the different
the different rooms those will be for
sale
at the end of the conference I the
artist to put those together
I am Rob T Firefly and grey frequency
am did those are the kinds their hearts
and
couple people who inquired about
purchasing them there's a
thank you I've done a lot of duct tape
was involves I'm with the assembly have
it but I'm
those will be for sale so you can go to
the Info Desk downstairs
and give your name and say that you're
interested in and taking one is home
with you
others a dual purpose to this as well
which means they don't have to load them
onto a truck in
taken back home so you can make your
best offer
also just a reminder if you could set
your cell phone to vibrate too so it
doesn't
not disturb the the conference remember
there's these
Zeus room down the hall which is the
fourth track there's a lot of really
interesting discussions going on
and their I right now it's the OLPC dem
I'll
whatever that is and and at three
o'clock is hacking
digital player pianos which I was
unaware that they were still player
pianos but I guess those are called
iPods now
alright
you know what a conference be without
power point actually
thank you
all right we're gonna get started
I'm I've known very wells for several
years and
he has hooked me up with a fantastic
lock picking set
thats could come in handy quite a few
times I also if you follow some other
more geeky blogs every now and then
you'll see his name mentioned
I as he's discovered some amazing new
lockpicking hack these guys
are at a lot of hacker conferences
around the world and encourage you to
art check out some locks I'll some pics
dole guide you through some other tricks
on on
up picking those locks and down in the
lockpicking village on the second floor
I they've got sort of a workshop and you
can also buy some at the lockpick sets
I highly recommend them om this is
methods of copying high security keys
with very wells
and han Fei who was a
sitting down there inexplicably alright
given for burial else
that's a warm welcome thank you very
much
I'm a know what works on Friday
a world there were some technical
difficulties the
so we decided that the first part of the
presentation
I'll do it by myself and a when does
time for questions on will sitting next
to me to maybe on some of your
technical questions that you have a.m.
but I'll
oh and that then you don't worry you
know you you you will not miss him that
much I hope
those on Phi
okay a
autographs after the session for him but
anyway okay here we go
I am dot the the thing s a as was
explained
earlier I've done quite some lockpick
presentations
a.m. and I decided it was time for
something new i mean
I always try to to come up with a new
thing
to talk about in the locker area and you
can keep
you know going with to a a lock picking
a lock bumping and all that stuff
but I thought you know let's let's do
something that's I think not being
talked about much
and it is copying keys coping high
security keys
and how easy and difficult this is to to
actually make copies of
of piece of metal because that's
actually where the key is am
so first things first what actually is a
key we all have several keys on a
keyring
but what does a key do and how does the
key
operate and why can one key operated the
look and the other key cannot
while they almost look the same and
that's simply because in most
mechanical locks the key push pins
to a correct position and if one of
these bins is not pushed correctly as I
will get back to later
is annoying how do I turn this off
okay
yeah so I am thinking of how can I
disable my wifi network
anyway don't pick me please
ok anyway what would a key mostly does
is
inside the mechanical lock it will a
moved from elements
and unlock it if one of the elements in
the lockers not in the correct place are
in the correct angle
a.m. the look is not going to operate
and
yeah that that's what it does no
when I'm doing a presentation I will
talk about
locks in the american way the American
protocol
the way the locker is this is for
European look this is not standard
because in Europe
the look is mounted upside down but in
US the looks are mounted up and since my
first experience was with american
locksmith books
you know I always follow this protocol
because this is how I grew up
the so that means that we have a house
plug in the pin and we have bottom pants
that are actually in the blog
and we have house bins that are actually
in the top so if I say it poppin
I mean pins that are in the house I hope
that's clear so
a.m. if you look inside the lock you see
the
blue top been and the Reds bottom pin at
this moment the core
cannot turn because the blue bin is in
the way
only when the key enters the lock and
lift up
this a is reppin only at that time
the core can turn at this moment the
blue pin is in the way of the
of the court turn and thats you know
basic
lockpicking the very basic stuff and as
I said I've been enough for many many
many years and that's a look big village
downstairs with 20 people
30 people teaching you how to pick locks
are locks work so I guess by now
everybody understands this and have nots
you know she was downstairs and we'll
explain that a little bit deeper in
detail
a.m. having said that you know this is
one more image
of a correct key in the core
where you see all the pins all the core
pins on one line
and if you then remove thats key a
little bit
then the bins get out of alignment and
the first been
as we say sinks into the core meaning
that the
the been on top of that will germans the
second
to print will actually stick out of the
core a little bit preventing
it from turning it so now it has turned
into an incorrect key and I'm going to
turn this off
even if it takes me one minute because
this is not nice
yeah i i help
system preferences
what go back to the rescue
is a buck somebody I dearly love
special
10 network right II 10 network right
shipment
okay here we go
well at least you know now we got rid of
that annoying thing and I can really
focus now on
a on the presentation a.m.
what's important to know with keys and
locks
in the mechanical domain is that its all
fixed size
so the pins that are in the lock the
pins that are preventing the look from
turning
if the the incorrect key is inserted
a.m.
have increments and most of the time are
then steps the that these bins can have
so you can have a really long been
then it's a position 9 if you have a
really short been it's either 0 or 1
and this spinus you know if you can
identify the length of the bin
you know the combination of the lock if
you noted in
in in gate number one is a pin 5
you know and and that is by part you can
cut the key to that height
a.m. this actually is a screenshot from
computerize key cutter in a in a in a
locksmith shop
so if you know combination of
of the the key you can just enter its
and a insert a blankie and the Machine
got
the key for you on on croat house is
possible anyway
turn off grow okay
I i think it's done I am
okay so so having said that you know
it's very important to realize that
the the Dept in a key are not random if
you if you look at
these keys a
I'm date they have fixed
steps and also the spaces where the cuts
are in
is also affixed length now
what what methods did the look industry
come up with two
protect people from copying keys the
the most clever one is Dave they do
bet on two tricks in the key so they
have some better that mechanism that
will do something extraordinary that
they have a bet and on
a and in that case you know only they
are allowed to make
the blank so it's a legal protection
it's not a a technical protection its
legal protection
a really a locksmith if he makes
patented
be turkey is really in a lot of trouble
because you break a better and you're
not doing something naughty its
um another thing that they do
and and it sometimes combined with
patents is editing
a a special elements in the key
that a key cutters normally cannot copy
so its first you know we started with
these dimple peace the
the the keys to the holes in them and at
the beginning
you know for locksmiths that was really
a big deal because they couldn't copy it
but then a couple of years later there
was so much demand for a machine that
can do that
that they made a machine to copy dimple
keys and then
they made impulse that were not fully
drill and you know it's it's a whole war
going on between the
manufacturers of these machines and
block industry they also like to
at you know thinks that's that a special
to deadlock sliders magnet
cuts in an angle floating elements I'll
get back to that or later another thing
that they do is assign
and exclusive profile the profile is to
shape of two key
so if you look at the tip a few key you
know I've I've noticed that in
in the US it's mainly a straight line
with maybe one or two small
angles in it and that's nothing unlike
in Europe where
you know key go six ek from one side to
the other
and really has a lot of different shapes
but but I've seen that in the US lot of
chalet keys in the Primus keys no not
prime mister
quick sets it's all a straight line
would maybe one or two
so that's nothing special the
mmm but what what looking she does is
they assign a special exclusive profile
an exclusive shape of the key
to specific locksmith they say okay
listen we will
you know give you this exclusive profile
it will not be for sale for anybody else
a.m. we will just not handed out to
anybody else
but that doesn't mean it's protected by
patent you know if I
want to make that key you know did is
nothing legally
as far as I understand preventing me
from
copying the piece of metal if there's
not bet on them
but yet that is done often especially to
you know bic
dealers big locksmiths that have their
own profile
or to a project you know if you have a
school
or hospital or whatever they will get an
exclusive profile
that can only be sometimes even
requested only by
the the keys can only be made by the
manufacturer
and now these methods
mentioned above were only prevent copies
made at the local hardware stores or at
the
you know the local locksmiths because if
you really determined I don't know if
you read
the latest 2600 magazine I wrote a small
article on
copying piece that a little bit
difficult to do
a was a youth experiment so maybe you
want to read it up
a.m. but if you really determined you
can make
copies of metal pieces pieces of metal
because that's what the key is
and on and I have been in a lot of look
pick to a locksmith
a a lock manufacturers a
in love companies we looked at No me
think
drifting off um
we visited a lot of lock factories
and if you see how keys are made the
keys are made
you know one second to keep such the
really
grain and other fees metal really fast
and so if you expect
essay look company that you know thing
that you can make in one second with
your
with a high-tech machine somebody else
can never copy you know that that's a
wrong assumption
because it's at the end of the day's
only piece of metal
now the most simple way to
to decode a key or two to copy a key
is to look at the key if it if it has a
registration number like a sh4 force
lake or
whatever you know if you can identify
what type of blank what I've profile is
used and it's mostly
written on the key a and the next up is
to just
measure up the depths of guts and if you
know dat
you know you can go home you can never
file you can have a blankie
and you can cut it or if you have access
to computerized machine
you can cut it and it's really nothing
more
then you know if somebody can determine
how deep a specific gotti's game is over
a.m. if you don't have something to
measure to keep by
and you have access to a key that that
you want to to copy or that you're
interested in
a.m. in high security keys is really
funny because
they have a lot of sex act lines
especially in in Europe
and as you can see on this serving
hausky there's a lot of lines as a lot
of
you know changes in the profile going
from left to right
and you can actually use that's to read
the key you can say okay the first cuts
is actually the right in the middle
of the first groove that you see and
the second cup is actually much deeper
a and a third garth et cetera et cetera
so with these lines you can moralist
identify
roughly even if you don't have axis2
to something to measure it the
what the combination is and and and and
a skilled look bigger
especially you know people from to in
Germany
if you if they have a peek at your key
for one second
you know it's its is lost I and no i lo
lo hi lo
okay that's it you know and they don't
know what to expect and
that really is intelligence dent in your
system is compromised
if people with some knowledge look at
Yuki stand
now another way to make copies of keys
if you
you know if you if you cannot take them
with you ace to make detailed photo I
mean for the cameras getting smaller and
smaller
or a xerox copy a.m. and xerox copy ng
really worked well a its its and almost
one on one copy you can go home in
you know measure it and and have a look
on where on the lines
cots are and as you can see here on the
on the
on the cars look this is just a standard
photocopy just
you know the first run I I just made a
photocopy and as you can see
a once you for the copy this key you can
spend
three months you know figuring out how
to make a piece of metal that will fit
the lock
and how to cut it exactly do that Dept
but at the end of the day if people have
access to a mechanical key
for a very short time the whole system
can be compromised
another method that I heard of
know if you don't have access to a 20 X
machine and and you really
our focus on getting a copy of the key
is too impressive
into your arm for as long as you can
and just give it a try I mean you know
don't don't do it for 30 seconds but
just do it a little bit longer
and just see how long it takes for the
the imprints
to to finish it really status on quite
some time
a.m. having said that you know this this
even gave me some bruises afterwards but
but you know afterwards you can identify
more or less how deep they are
even even if you have to guess a little
a
it's it's still interesting yeah
wait to to do it now
if if and exclusive profile issues
in a in in in the key system
you have a problem going to get the
original
key to make your your your your your key
from
and its so funny that over the last days
I've spoken with some people
a one was 17 your year olds a engineer
that said out it's funny that you say
that because when I was in high school
you know I wanted to have a copy of the
march to keep
not to do anything illegal but just to
explore a little and to make my life
more comfortable
and he said what I did was a I called
the generator that
Mikey was inside and at my door was
locked
and he came with the march to keep and I
took a peek on the march to keep
and so on what positions it was
different from Mikey
while you know that's that's amazing
a.m.
and then he he recognize more or less
where the
where the cuts were that were different
and then he
the removed his look from the door and
look at the bins
and laid him out you know we just took
his own life above the door
to a look at the pins and said okay on
these two positions
Mikey is too deep the key to the head
you know couldn't be turned into a march
to keep because they were too deep
so what he did was he used solving Iran
filled up
the the the keys which folder and you
know we had to score and we could file
until
it was a perfect fit and he had a march
the key to the system
and he gave me the march to keep a he
was kind enough to give it to me and I
don't know if I can put it under your
butt let's let's just
you know going to presentation and we'll
see later if I
if I if I showed him but it was really
funny and that's not the first time I
heard
the people actually fill up existing
peace
would be some metal to to create a blank
that way
and yet the key that you see here is an
asset to be in which is very high
security
very accurate lock and hun and I once
had a bet with somebody
that he said you cannot copy this key a
and what we did was we bought
key at the same shop where he bought it
and they all have the same side bar code
which is the most difficult thing
and we filed the petitions that you know
his key
had up and what I actually used is
I use pieces of a nickel to got fee
shaped
pieces and sold them in with hearts over
so use a little bit different
technique but at the end of the day if
you can get access to
any key that will fit that lock you know
if you have time enough and if you're
determined enough
the mechanical system will lose after
all it will
a now there's a little story from the
Netherlands
a a I think about 15 years ago twenty
years ago
there were phone phreaks in the
Netherlands that a
wanna that have access for a very short
time
to the two key did you see above
the the look that you see above in a in
the green
RR national phone companies green did
that the caller
a.m. and what they had actually worse
and
econ lock and I can lock a.m.
is not only just your your straights a
key or even if it's a 660
but they have little wings on the site I
don't know if you can see two weeks
on the site of of these book both the
suan
the Sun and what it is is that on the
site
there's actually elements winks that
push away
locking elements in the side of the
of Turkey so there's a row of pins on
top
and there's a couple of pins on the site
and they all have to match
now they could not get copy of a a
of the key that goes in even if it's too
low should have a problem
and date date that they want to have a
copy of that so
one of their friends was mechanical
engineer
and he said are no problem I'll make
that key for you is just a piece of
metal
and that's what he did this is a is the
picture
the measure stuckey in 3d and he
a a push to put all the measurements in
is
in its equipment and out came the this
key I don't know if you can see it
but this is the is not the original key
because I'm
never had access to that it's an a
similar key
that haz weeks so if you can
can see it I'm and and this is the the
copy that they made an
year when I first saw that you know I
said I gotta have a copy of that key and
not
because I wanted access to that phone
booth but because I thought it was such
a great idea
that somebody was actually skilled
enough to just
take a %uh blank piece of metal and you
know
said this machines in and do some magic
and then
make a blankie its II funded really
amazing
and even for me that was an eye-opener
that that somebody actually
did that I mean that you can do that
theory yes but that people actually do
that that's
amazing to me now
these were all the the the simple
methods to
to hack around a little bit with keys
and
but you know sometimes the min
you have access for a very short time
and
one of the things that you can use to
make a quick
pro-peace that are highly accurate is
with clay its its you know very simple
idea I think we all as a kid played with
clay and put something in this or the
impression
and that's basically what this kid us
this is a kid from
US the toolmakers organization for for
locksmiths
and its I don't know what I paid I think
150 200 euros something like that
and it's even overpriced if you look at
what's inside
well you know it's it's a very simple
steps
but is really very accurate so what's
inside
is some baby powder issue can see
and and I'll get back to that later the
to to
white things their
are little clams that's also why this
kid is called clam
and that's actually what we will use to
make the impression of
of the key there some play inside there
some
low melting metal inside there's a
candle inside
and yeah basically that's it
I think you can more less imagine how it
works I had the idea
to you know be really daring and and use
this
this video stand to to do it step by
step
but I decided not to do it because
technique is not my best friend these
days
I'm so I decided to just make more
religious order photo
to a thing on how this works
so if you wanna make a copy with this
clamp kits step 1:
East to to take one of these clamps
and open its get some of the clay the
more than of just makes it the bits
and and a few key ready
then you separate the clay and you fill
out the two halfs
of the climate is really straightforward
and really simple
a.m. and then with the I don't know how
you called
but than you separates the remaining two
top remaining layer
with with that knife with that sharp
edge
and you did on both sides
and what you can do is if you would now
close the clam boats sites we stick
together
so it would not be possible to remove
them easily
and that's when where the the baby
powder comes in
a.m. you apply generous amount baby
powder on both halfs
on one of Iraq's meted out on one of its
its it's there by the way I flew in with
the stuff through customs hours like
you know from Amsterdam with the bottle
of baby powder and plastics
play a its
but they've worked out in under let me
im I'm always surprised if they let me
in but
but anyway you you can see what is going
a.m. then what you do is you gently
Press the key into one of the hops you
don't want to push it in
2d you just wanna push it in to the
point that it doesn't fall out
so you have to make it stick a little
bit is what you do
a.m. now then you know I can make then
stepped in closing it but this is
yeah a close to clam
and you really press tightly
now if you then open it again and gently
remove it you can see in and I don't
know how
good this be Murray's but here on the
screen you know it's
really really really accurate the
impression
that has left in this silly clay and its
it's nothing special I mean it's
probably something that any kid can make
for for for a couple of books
but thats that's what you do now what
you do afterwards issue close to clamp
you heat up some of the metal you pour
it in while it goes in UTEP it a little
bit so the air bubbles come out
and then you have your key I mean I
could have made all the steps as well
but then you know my two hours would be
a by now so I decided to
let you have something left for your
imagination
I'm so we tried this
the on a wide number of of
of keys especially since we came here
a hum was huge collection of locks
picked up some office
most high-security locks from Europe
from the US
and a.m. that worked in almost all cases
in almost all cases we were able to make
impressions of this piece of metal
push from low melting madeleine into the
impressions and have a working key
sometimes is required
little scraping off edges you know
little
sometimes it's not perfect a
but if especially if you scrape off some
metal and you have an eye on
one were to scrape off the metal you
know you will
definitely be able to make it but in
some cases
a just work straight out of the box
nothing fancy
so this isn't easy way to copy
keys even the high-security once as you
can see no
a some people have been bashing on
medical all-conference Oh I thought you
know we might as well include them
a know but who I think medical actually
makes
very good looks and its
yeah almost a pity that these guys are
are
in that corner that they are in now
having said that you know
the that things are as they are and in
high security applications
they have a serious problem as far as
i'm concerned. the
the medical ok the that you see or the
key
has got angles and cups and that that's
the thing with medical don't only live
bins to put Ishan they also rotate them
in a position
and we were real curious if you know
with the simple clay
impression gets if these angles would be
a a correct and
it it works we did have two
to modify the little bit at position 5
that the metal was not perfect their so
you know
to be honest it didn't work out of the
box straight away but with a little
modification it work
and I'm quite confident that you know if
you tried more
if you get a little bit even more
experienced with using this
that that got that you have a a fairly
good chance of
of making an impression making a working
key this way
now another a key that we copy is the
chalet Primus
and slick primis is really
top-of-the-line at the moment I think in
the US it's one of the most
difficult to manipulate lock
I'm and also the key copying you know
they're very proud of
on showed me a brochure saying often
imitated never duplicated
a and and they are rights it's a very
very very
high tolerance lock
so if something isn't right the look is
not gonna open
the the
sidebar profile that you see over there
actually picks up a PM which to specific
height
and to a specific rotation these are
called the fingerprints
and you can see them here hopefully and
it's really an ingenious system on on
locking and unlocking and its is one of
the
one of the top line and hun wrote an
article about its
a a 0 its still has to come out to see
more information on our set to in
systems part 2
and I think you know only a part 1 right
now it's okay sir
well later you know if there's time left
I'm can on some of the questions or talk
something about
now the the funny thing is that
we we managed to make a copy of this
slick Primorsky and a.m. as you can see
you know it it looks it looks the same
a.m.
but what was really funny is that there
were actually holes in the key
where this angle gots are at
at the bottom of the key
but still the keyword out of the box
without any
modification you know it work and we
really surprised by that
but sometimes if the the metal in the
key is getting very thin
the the liquid metal that you're pouring
in cannot fall in
all the way or you know doesn't get in
all the way and even while tapping its
sometimes you know the metal is not
there
but in these cases still the key works
now wanna for my personal favorite locks
is
the Fr 3k yes it's a look that's mostly
unknown I think
to people in the US its
it's it's like a watch almost it's
really high precision
it works with sliders so there's no pins
but their sliders that have to be
elevated to specific Heights there's
multiple tracks
as you can see in the key tree KS tents
for
that I could fancy staying which means
in German three curves system
a actually the only using to to
really a of variables but
its it's a very sophisticated key and I
was really curious
if we could do it with the simple clay
impression in kids
if we could make a copy of that and
we also succeeded in making a copy of
that now
if as you can see the same thing
happened as with the Primus
and that's that there's actually a whole
in the key
um can you see that at the did
of the key that there's there's a whole
Kiyoshi and actually
that those this a few more I think also
a and
anyway we we tried it and also this key
also open the lock because at the end of
the day
the slightest have to be put in a
specific position and it doesn't matter
if there's no metal there
as long as the sliders are being pushed
a a
in in the correct position and the
distance in the in the middle of the key
is really really close
so it's it's actually quite logical that
some of the
the places are that there's no middle
there
but the bottom line is that if you go
to a look shop you say I want to copy of
this key
they will look at you really funny you
know they say its
its its not a blank that I have it's not
even a system I know
and even if I know to system you know
how am I going to make these groups with
different depts
it's it's a really complex system yep
with this kids only 150 euros are two
hundred euros wanted to pay
a you can make a copy of this key
relatively simple and straightforward a
having said that the question is how
many times can you use that key
you know we we tried it a couple of
times and after opening a couple of
times
it already started to wear a little bit
because these luxury high-security
locks now
the application with this click it is
that you can open the lock couple of
times and
the basic idea is that you make a copy
on a key machine later so it's just to
preserve
the the cuts in a key and for you to
bring it to a normal copier and in being
able to cut it
so if you have evil intent and you know
you have a x2
really interesting key and you want to
open once or twice the lock
to to steal stuff for that it's going to
work
but if you're going to use it on a daily
basis
and a you know you have to open the door
multiple times a day
good luck it's it's not really the
going to last that long I think and now
we we started with the public protec
a.m. its wanna Ponce favorite looks
a.m. and we also tried
with the clay kids and it came out just
fine
but we also tried it with another
technique that we used to make copies of
high security keys
because we could not copy all
the keys not all the high security keys
and I'll get back to why
it didn't work but this actually
a a copy made of from avoid protec
key to a system that works with discs
you could just see
but this copy is not made
with clay this copy is made with
silicone and its action the
something that's used in the dental
industry the
now I told you about my clay kids that
worse
maybe 200 euros this also
kids with silicone impression silicone
based
and that kids is much more expensive
what you see here I paid 500 euros for
and it was still
consider the bargain a.m. this can make
me approximately I think
would worsen 35 copies 35 keys
I can make with this get so it's
it's not it's not cheap but it's very
very very
accurate and as I said it's
based on and
technology from the dentist area
and what you have is the the blue stuff
on top and that really is a big a big
part
a.m. and that actually is a silicone
a a liquids
and these other two bottles that you see
here elements that you have to mix
with that silicone to make it harden so
the the silicon from the from the thing
you can just four
just assess if it is words it's not like
water but it's it's it's almost like to
but if you mix these two other elements
with it
within 10 minutes it will are going out
so the whole idea is
to make the the silicone
on the spot to mix it a and then use
the this which is actually the heart of
the system
it's a really heavy duty hi decision
high-precision clam and this
clam is used to to clamp the key
while you poured in the mixed silicone
material
so you first you know you fix a
the the key to the
to the top part a.m. and then you put
to claims together you mix the material
you pour it in and then with the with
the leftovers
you paint the key a little bit you make
sure that there's no air bubbles in
there
so if you have these blue you really
apply it as
as well as you can to that key and then
you stick it in and
a a let it wait for 10 minutes and if
you don't
remove the clamp after 10 minutes just
his heart
peace of silicone
rubber actually that's what it is it
feels like robber
and it's not stiff it's it's flexible
a yet it is extremely xx a
that the only problem is is that Yuki
still inside and
you know how are you going to get that
out the
as I said after 10 minutes of waiting
you can open it
and with a knife and that's why you know
to steal
shape is so important you got away you
you you makin
decision into this a a silicone
part and you can remove two key now
if you if you got
precisely you know we could to work out
just fine and
you can make really really really
excellent
Copics of a of high security keys
with it and it can even do some keys
that you cannot do
with clay for instance since we came to
the US we want some high security locks
a one of the high security locks is
sergeant que solo
and with a search in case a look their
spins coming from three sites
in from the left from the right from the
top a.m.
you can see over der on on the left that
that is the case that's what the key
looks like
and its also in high-precision lock
you know the slightest ever will
a a not open the look anymore
am we tried with clay and interesting
thing with clay is that if you
make a copy with clay it will work fine
except for
the site bins Bence that are on on the
site here so it's not the pins on the
top it's not the pins on the bottom
but on the site as soon as you remove
claimed if you open the clam
you will destroy your your impressions
from the side
because and with the silicone based
material
you know you gently cuts at the edges
and it work work out just fine because
the because it's it's flexible
a.m. we managed to make copy works fine
and that shows that that with the
silicone thing you can do
key stat: cannot be done in and in a
different way
a.m. on an IV said that Vienna
couple of weeks ago maybe months time
flies
a.m. and there's a company called Coba
and if you talk about looks made like a
watch
you know these locks I made like a watch
its so xx
so precise its really really really
one of the most for
high tolerance locks that I know the
they have more than one been in there
they have sometimes up to 22
positions where bins are from four
angles
and the pins are really small and really
pointy
and if you try to pick its you know we
we
of course tried to pick it if you put
tension on you start breaking in and out
the the local absence start to run less
smooth
it's it's very easy to disturb the lock
by
if you damage it or you know if you do
these kind of things
it is very difficult to pick it it's
very difficult to manipulate it
and it actually was the reason that I
bought this
silicone impression Inc because you know
we were going to the factory and I just
wanted to have something that I could
break the locks one way or the other
so yeah this is what I did
but I was I was really annoyed thats
a.m. I couldn't make this key
with my click it because what happens in
you can clearly see it here at the at
the bottom now
a point about for you
as you can see on the previous cream
that the pins on acaba
are got on a 45 degree angle meaning
that if I put it in a
in a clam and I remove it a.m.
uses with the case old but then much
more severe I will distorts
the the gaps and especially since it's
such a high security
high tolerance lock a.m.
IIIi I couldn't get it to work and it
really frustrated mean I really tried
you know with different angles with the
click it but it didn't work
a.m. butts with the silicon kits it
works
and the they weren't happy but yeah you
know that's life
a no but seriously I mean you know it's
its
it's the top of the line of European
high-security locks
and you know that day they should be
able to take them in
so a.m.
that more or less converse the
I'm the
the thing with I did with its our own
little research
on on high security locks copying there
is a difference that I want to point out
between
clay and silicone the clay kids
if you prepare the clay and you prepare
your clam
and you somehow managed to put it in
your pocket you can make
an impression of any key did you can get
your hands on in 10 seconds
you know you put it in you squeeze it
you take it out gently
you stick it into your pockets carefully
and
you know of you go and and you made your
copy
the disadvantage of that kid is that
it's not as
accurate as with the silicone based off
but it's still very accurate and I
manage to cope
almost every key I tried with that so as
long as there's no
45-degree the cuts in it or
groups that are in a specific 45 degree
angle if it's
let key the most the time place is good
enough
now the advantage of silicone is that
a.m. it makes very high precision
copies if you should write the but
it slow it takes you 10 minutes drive
to let it dry you have to mix it on the
spot
you cannot you know have premixed so you
have to mix it def you alls
small little chemistry factory with you
a.m.
so these are the two differences
in the system now the locksmiths
also have a new toy the or new they have
a toy
that they use for copying high security
keys and its
and is it's called easy entry machine
and easy entry machinist
really a nice devices really great in
invention
what it does is it scans the
the upper side of the key thats never
cut
because to cut always starts off a
little bit away from the shoulder
a.m. and it scans that part
of the key with a very thin feeler and
then
you insert the blank that has no caught
in it at all
with the smiling face and then the
machine starts making the cuts
like it scant and you know after
a couple minutes you have a a blankie
to dads to the to deadlock and the nice
thing about this machine is that
even for intelligence agencies and entry
teams
have a special module that if you have a
picture
for key way that this small Photoshop
like
image where they can just roll the line
of that
that profile and they will cults %uh the
key
even if they don't have access to the
original blank or the original key
so that's that's really in a very nice
way
unfortunately is a little bit above my
budget so if
if if people here are into
you know milling machines and
computerize milling you know I
I'd like to have a talk with you because
maybe we can do this thing open source
and just I I would really like that to
have at the end of
mechanical protect its keys enough is
enough a.m.
now this is actually where hun Compton
where some
for anyway a.m. if you want you can
you can say something about sure okay
just on these are
used this shit
these are these awesome looks out my
collection
and a.m. I these are keys which are
impossible to copy with this silicon
well with the clay kits
reasonable reason why they are
impossible to copy is defect
that they have movable elements what ATF
magnets in them and a.m.
you can't see for example the know to
look Beltre
left above everybody knows that present
interactive
element in its and to some party in the
Lok must be lifted up
to for release a certain been to let
plug rotate a.m. another trick we see is
another tick we see for example
are okay
is for example the fr MCS that says
that's a cylinder with for make its
units then we have to
okay 8 make a scene if
then we have debris car number one which
has a floating element
element in it in the top then we have
the if a hacer which have a floating
or a spring element in the table to keep
the pointed very
here number three no no bilo bilo bilo
that one and I'll
the tip dip you see that dip that
dip is sprint and therefore
that key cannot be got beat by molding
a.m. we have here to buy lock also
the know what I think by a lot of
americans be loader is
an element which to rotates or or
makes a 90-degree rotation to push
something in the Lok
the and then we have to motor
which he had a number one which have and
the micatin its and the most curious
thing
the the most to lose key I found in my a
collection was the number Fife and each
with a simple looks
zipper locks so it's it's the same thing
you close your offense which
and as you can see here
it's a key which exists of a
a lose elements just like super
flexible the elements which go into the
lock
and which go into elaborate in the look
and then it moves that way like a fish
and then it sets depends
so it's it's a very extreme and strange
look
it's a it's a main effect which does not
exist anymore because looks were too
expensive
one a.m.
I don't know if you have more sheets
from the body
okay then I can go from
okay so on can you hear me no
put okay does work
I'm dock so the these are some
a keys that you know we couldn't copy
with this technique
having said that a.m. and I stand with
that
no matter what you make mechanically if
you have a mechanical key
and I'm determined to make a copy a copy
it
you know that's it's just a matter of
time
all these keys are made in a factory in
couple of seconds
and then you have a lifetime to spend on
finding a way to make a copy so they
cannot win that game they can make it is
most difficult to us they can and I
think that for instance the number five
the the FR one with the magnets it's
really one of the most difficult ones
you should to a look it up on the
Internet to know exactly why because
so long story but it's it's really
secure lock and so are most of these
the here I'm
okay now people that know me noted I do
a lot of lockpicking
and you know the part that we just had
its
exactly one hour was about
a high-security locks a and making
copies of its so that was part one
another thing I want to tell you what
I've been up to
in regards to looks is I'm
impression Inc and it's with everything
that I do
it said look opening technique called
impression ng and
the last thing I did for for the last
two years his impression in person
impression ng
just as with 3 O's have to you know you
have to practice over and over and over
again
I've been practicing a lot
a.m. so what is impression Inc
a.m. impression ng requires that
you have a blank you have a file
you have some patience and some skillz
a.m.
I brought with me a book from my good
friend Oliver Dixon who
interested me in this two years ago he
finished his book
a I went over
I looked at it he explained to me how it
worked and
you noted was also the first day that I
opens a lock
with impression Inc and the nice thing
about depression is that's
a.m. at the end you will have a key
so once you have bypassed the lock
with impression Inc you have a working
key and it's very useful for locksmiths
and non-destructive entry team so
government deems that
you know are are allowed to search your
house or place tougher your house or
whatever
allowed to open your locks a.m. and I've
learned that this is actually a method
that's in use up to these days because
it's such a powerful technique
to open locks a a secretly
it's not like look picking you know that
you can just more or less
start and and and it the new minutes
open some locks
it requires quite some skill and
practice and
but the upside is that if you succeed
you have a working key
and so you only are
challenging the law once if you win you
have one forever
well would lock picking if you open the
lock is great you can close it and then
you know
you have to go all over again
a.m. it silent a and it's possible to
come back later you can you know work on
impression on look for a few minutes and
then
go away and then the next day dude a
couple more minutes
and for you know for for non-destructive
into teams that isn't
appealing thing that if you try to pick
a lock a.m.
you know if you go back to the lockers
reset
a.m. so what is impression Inc
I'm now this slide is from
different presentations or remember the
binding been make much sense because I
didn't talk about love picking up
a.m. but what happens is that if you if
you have a look
and in this position you want to turn it
to the rights
the look is not going to open because
the blue pin
is in the way right blue pin is
preventing the lock
from turning and that's actually a a
what we're going to use
in impression in a.m. this a few very
simple tools that you need
in order for successful impression ing
at them to do it
a you have file that's very important
you have some good lights some clamps
a.m. all explain what's reported with
depression is that you have a blankie
and that you have clem to hold that
blinky
and what you will do is you will insert
a blank into the clamp
and if you stick it into the look
nothing will happen except that all the
pins are raced as high as you can
this is suspended blinky
and if you look on the top of the
blankie
you see it shining its it's got the
silver
colour to or chrome nickel chrome no
chrome
layer on top and with impression it's
important that we
brush that off so with a very fine file
I make the surfers one smooth of
of you know so I remove the Hartshill
for layer
and get two brass and the and make it
once moved line
of of Bryce well then do
is I insert a blank into the lock
alternate 22 rights
and by turning to the right one or two
pins
will be jamming the lock from opening as
we know we look picking
if you turn to the right it's not all
the pins that bind it's always one or
two
maybe three beings that bind so you turn
it in
to write been say okay you know I'm
stopping you from turning
now with impression ng you start
rocking your key up and down a little
bit now it's its in the
locketts in the keyway so there's not a
whole lot of play
you notice only a very minimal movement
that you can make however
the pins are jam between the house and
the core
and if I try to make a movements you
know something has got
is as gotta move so it's I did to keep
his gotta move for its dependence gotta
move
well I use a little bit more force to I
will actually lifted bins up just a
fraction of a millimeter
you know it's very little however that
will make a dent
in the middle and it will tell me later
page you know this is where been is
jamming here comes in
a after this round of you know it
shouldn't be key
turning to the left making a few
up-and-down movement
turning to the right making a few
up-and-down movement because if you turn
the key to the rights
this other pins binding if you turn it
to the left because
that's the way with the in perfect locks
you know how they all work that's but
I've been talking about for years now
that these mechanical tolerances make
is why
the steez looks can be picked so if I
plight or to the left
I get other marks than if I plight or to
the right
and if I look at my blankie a
under this little magnifier with
indirect lighting I have
or I use it under DL is
spot in the US Steel fluorescent lights
the troops yeah
okay fluorescent thing is if you shine
on the blink directly
it's coming back to your face and you
can see the very fine
marks the to make but this is actually
and image of a of a key that's
gone through the first round impression
ng and you can actually see
on the side of the blank I want to 345
cuts
so that means that I can actually see
all the pins
we're preventing the law from turning
when doing left and right a.m.
which is exceptional make most of the
time it's like
3 or you know three or four
but this in this case you know we've
seen all five
and what you do with depression Inc is a
this is this by the way I a
microscopical few of
what's going on and I'm not sure how
well you can see it
but that's really a clear mark and most
the time
that's that's not the case but the Marco
that you see over there
is typical from from from what its
from from what a real impression mark
looks like and by the way these images
are from the book
from all over the deck so the guy did
taught me aboard a few of these books
with me so if you're interested you know
I have only a few of them
with me so if you really want we can
talk now I can
so you can book a.m. but what happens is
that
I see that the smooth better and he's
disturbed
I see a dot and where she did not
ifile and I have my round file and where
I see
mark I will use my round file and got it
now I can cut its in two different ways
I can use
caliber and no two steps increments
as we've seen from one of the first
lights it's all fixed distances
I can use the caliber to say okay this
was a cut 0
we now go to got one and do it exactly
as you can
or you can say you know I don't minds
these these exact numbers if I see a
heavy Marco go deep
ever see a light mark I'll take it
slowly and you know that's where the
practice crime scene
a once you learn how to read these marks
you know how to deep
you know how deep to file a.m. and if
you see Mark
you file them away if you don't see Mark
don't touch it
that's the basic protocol in impression
ng
a if you are looking with your
with your little optics and you think
is a mark horses know Mark is this you
know maybe pollution
uses what what is this don't touch it
if you will file it away a.m. the
the the the bottom pin will
go be low shear line and poppin will
start to bind
and then you lost you can never go where
back up again so
you have to be careful whatever you do
you know don't file too deep
because then you lost for ever you
cannot win the
game refreshing anymore a.m. if in doubt
leavitt because once it you know if it's
a five pin lock
if 4 pins are in a row you know the
number five will scream
with a very big marching okay here I am
you know this is where you have to file
and if it stays that be uses the market
said no mark
leave it like this a another thing that
you
you have to train with impression is
don't use too much force
I mean Israel relatively easy to break
the brush blanks
at the beginning you know I broken like
like like matchsticks
but now I hardly ever break them anymore
and that's because I've been
practicing a lot
this is actually my first successful key
and I was really thrilled
that after meeting with oliver I went
home and I tried it
and my first ride it worked as you can
see
there's a little crack here on the on
the shoulder side
so you know I was lucky that the key
wasn't too deep
if the key has got a lot of $19.8 sinem
it takes you much longer to do it
a.m. but for 12 months after my for
successful key and that this you know
pressuring approaching a freshening I be
making at least one
successful opening a day with this
technique just
because I think it's so much fun it's so
nice to be able to do it
a.m. and II study the subject it's not
only
that if I have a blank I can open the
lock
it also forced me to study you know
what looks are out there what is a
popular
in the Netherlands what do you expect if
you go to a door
because nowadays ices 24-hour look
service
in opening doors people lost their keys
and if it's in my area
they sometimes give me a call you know
okay that sounds like a very nice guy
you know go help him out so we don't
have to drill the lock or whatever
a and I have with me 50 kilograms I
don't know how much it is in
inbounds but fifty
it's a nice fifteen 15
okay this is thirty-something bounce
a.m.
with key stat: have strings of three
keys for
for profile that I'm about to expect if
it's not a popular pro
profile five or six when is a popular
profile
a.m. because you know if you spent three
keys on a lot you don't open it
it's at least 10 minutes per try you
know that's that's the bare minimum
so if you haven't opened the look of a
thirty minute with impression ng
its were its uses anyway but a
and I've been quite successful in this a
a the times that I open these locks in
the field
is between 10 minutes and thirty minutes
and the people are really happy
you know that I I'm able to help them
doing that you know some eyebrows are
being like
what's this guy doing but if the door
opens and you know
nothing is damaged the most the time
happy
a.m. not interesting thing is that
this technique works on wide range
flocks offer was one of the first people
I think
to find out but maybe I'm wrong but at
least it's he's the one at that
told me that it also works on the
bookies
as we learned you know these these for
instance the cicadas so
sergeant geisha locks they have pins
from three sides
a.m. normally the holes are drilled in
the key
but with impression ng what you do issue
just file
over the whole length of the blank
because what you want is you want to
keep
to go deeper you you do not care that is
not the nicely drilled hole
the key is in the way and it just wants
to go down and
it there's only one roof bins for side
you know so its it's no problem to
to use a file and would like that and
people look at you really funny if you
if you have one of these keys with you
and they used to seeing no drills whole
and yeah it's but it's it's a really
powerful technique
that if you march 3 you know you can
open a lot of what we did
including lever locks dimple locks
and its really a fun challenge for me to
do it and
I hardly ever practice picking anymore
because I'm
I'm really obsessed a little bit by by
this
so if you have blinky you know any
blinky
especially the high security profiles
you know come talk to me
all I'll trade you /url work something
out with you
a and
that that's that's that's the
presentation and it went
relatively fast so we have for quite
some time for
for questions under you wanna join
what do you want okay if you're
interested on can do a small
presentation about the special ok
that's the robot the key system so i i
think that
maybe that would be a good idea
sorry i am.
let's say that were asking questions
until the setting up his laptop
and somebody assisting with setting up
the laptop
last technique you showed right the old
school way of doing that was to also
take a match and deposits carpet on the
key
that's correct and that way you could
see this a little easier how does that
compare to what you doing here at every
witness
oppression into the what what you're
saying is indeed
that the old school locksmiths and it's
also the booklets that I read
they use a kennel and the what is called
carbon carbon C you can apply at the
carbon that comes off of the the flame
is used to Lekan the layer
on the other hand all the for found out
that if you have a brass blank
the brush is much softer than the bins
in the lock
and they will make an impression because
you noticed you pin
is bound and you going to push it up
with something that's much softer
it will make a mark so so there's no
need in using
eating or carbon or whatever
into that and I i noted in the books it
says you know use a candle and do it
but he tried it for a long time all
these techniques and
you really study did I mean you should
you should read this book it's is really
good
a.m. and and it's it's not necessary if
you have a
brass blink right maybe the blacks were
weren't brass backed yeah maybe fits
Stihl you know it's much more
different more difficult to mark but
think thanks for the question
curved use really all
word walks like
of lost long
nowadays use carbon or car magic marker
whatever
the pic force pushing down is enough for
I rub off sharpy's the market overall
you speak all always work
I a question about the magnetic ease
okay on when you see the magazine side
is the only thing that you have to worry
about larry is it either just
or minuses organizations the nice thing
with the magnetic key system from ever
what you're talking about is around
magnets is that inside
is a disc and the disc is on a spindle
so it can freely rotate if you insert
the key
it will take this freely rotating disk
and it will position it in a specific
way and on
one part of this there's a little cuts
into this
and if although this Caroline and an
I have with me a cutaway version of this
system
so if you if you meet us downstairs at
the lockpick village I can show you
the internals of that lock and you know
it's it's a beautiful piece of art
great thank you York
Eric very little Eric I
okay have you tried modifying your legal
high-security
hope one
cake to do you second guess you could
use a dirtier the country
it's not possible you the USB plugs into
the USB port
yeah I I love you I i love you too
yes so have you tried modifying your
high security key copies
so that they will trigger the moving
mechanism
or have you tried using a a picture
paper clip for
in Chennai you that that's actually a
really good question
I wanted to to do that I wanted to have
in this presentation
a key a a that was one of the key set
that hun said
could not be done and indeed you know
whether moving element is drilling the
way
and make some paper clip Dutch above the
the the line but the simply was not
enough time
but I'm convinced and that's again what
I say you know if it's about mechanical
locks
de Luz its you know if you wanna make
mechanical piece if you wanna make peace
metal that will operate deadlock
it will work yeah as thing the more tour
with them magnet in the key I have
little magnets
great their cup the show it's it's its
now it's it's it's not a big deal new
showing the
silicon morning as wonder if that gave
of any smell that may give you away
when you're using that technique a when
when I was first
showing it to harm he says feels like
I'm in the dentist now
if know it's also it's just that it does
have a a little smell
but it's not like in a chemical plant or
anything it yet
you said that the click it had a problem
with the
the key he made didn't last very long
visit you would wear way when you put it
in the lock
a there's a a technique that used for
modeling
where you say and a pox a to you feel
them all the party many fire in the
other
and I think you make it something a bit
harder cuz I eisin that's like letter
pewter
or something Lee pretty soft yeah well
I'm thanks for the advice I will
definitely look into that i i havent
heard about that but it makes a lot of
sense
to use only proxy and having it hard in
out I just repeat the question because
I'm not sure if
a but I I will look into that
what's the name of the I I'm not sure if
it has a name but if you look up
aka its use for like making figurines
and things
okay thanks I'll look a look that up
that that's a familiar face coming up
now
alright will first thing is coming media
said
actually I've got the impression excuse
the pun it on a call at such
that you don't actually use the clay
open anything im
you're making something with some other
material so I'll sergei's
soon that would be so where should be an
issue actually I think about proxy bid
rocks myself as a possible to make an
actual key
its Kim the minimum quite strong now
different different
question on okay you talking about
especially power
s also look on multi-part product from
be somewhat he said
anti I have a very difficult time
understanding you okay let me take you
make the question short and brief
compact thing clear:
between more time your me back miss to
close
house at a better 23 de vere okay with
my question was but this was
okay it's a fancy product using mixed in
I parks
I mean a silicon mix my question is what
about normal
RTV single part apart I mean this
electronic you might use for other
things such as squawking or other things
they're pretty robbery as well would
probably still hold on an angle
have it right something like that
because that would be a lot cheaper and
I C span probably be a lot simpler to
work with if we have the right
characteristics
so the more common aim would be to do is
carry able to be a pocket with that way
by mixing stuff for anything else
you lost your know it's normal to look
on the two but a one-part product you
don't mix anything
nobody getting all the hardware store
use a quarter past
top or whatever still so a chorus of
three robbery it was still survive does
angled cuts I would think if you get a
good one
maybe I dunno you might be worth trying
got set for as far as the market marking
materials from freshening
I never found with modern locks much
lock
with dumb with the sort method but
actually marker if these are
a good permanent marker start some walks
can be helpful me I'm for things I said
I found in fact can be useful sometimes
but I'ma lock
okay on I'm wondering what kinda medals
you use for the clay molding
a.m. dead it's a good question no I
bought
these kids completes and it's it's a
relatively soft
the metal that will melt at very low
temperatures like
like with with the candle so is it like
let me think
its it's probably some compound would
lead and sink in
or
what's what's what's what's a caller
what's meddler or you're gonna worry
okay thanks Eric
right on ok what are your views on the
electronic authentication over keys from
the locks
in with that extra layer of security so
even if you did
copy the key with you your message that
you talked about
in the key would still not over nor its
ok that's a good question because
I specifically said during my
presentation mechanical locks mechanical
locks pieces of metal and chemical
mechanical mechanical no
but but but you're right because there's
now a lot of electro mechanical locks on
the market
and they obviously you know in theory
would not have these problems that you
could copy them because
the challenge response cryptography in
these chips is really strong
in some cases however if people a read
my
my weblog problem weeks ago there's
there's people out there with
very very sophisticated clever simple
techniques to bypass some of the
electro mechanical locks and a at this
moment as we speak
you know we're in close contact with one
of the biggest
manufacturers who have an
electromechanical ok
that can be bypassed with the simple
ring with a few magnets
if you twist the ring in the area in the
surface of
this electromagnetic lock it will unlock
the electronic part because would not we
don't know exactly why
that happens it could be that the little
motor that blocks
the the
lock by turning is magnetic field around
will actually removed the blocking
element or
it could also be that by inducing
magnetic
changing magnetic field and if this
coral anywhere on the POF
of off thats you know if the unlocking
mechanical
electronic element current could be
induced
on that wire and all of a sudden you
know things going can happen
that so its nice to think that
electronics is the answer but I think
that we're just at the very beginning
of where this is going and this is not
anywhere near
solution that says of used electronics
it's rick's forever
but it definitely is a good help II
definitely have to say that
that but that's the the best defense you
have at the moment thanks
yeah
kinda lost my voice her soul okay but I
am
I use to make small molds for car parts
&
I would take arm goal pager
what with the vibrate molded and hold
that up next to the mall to those porn
madeleine
and it vibrated what kinda by take the
bottles are other
the mold when I was pouring in I don't
know if you could use that with the key
or not but
that makes a lot of sense thanks did
everybody get because it was actually
quite a good idea
to use a little vibrating element on
your key mold
then if you insert the metal the whole
thing is already shaking
you have to be careful with your fingers
though because this hot metal
is hot but the next said question by my
work key
I was under the impression it's the
emblem ass fucking
that you get their different
combinations that you could
different you could set the lock itself
with different combinations like mines
green tea
I'm a boss has the red key I'm how would
you go about
up finding which Q work with that
particular bach
special one that was hard copy like this
one a.m.
well this this been a whole discussion I
think maybe four years ago by
met blaze a mark Tobias who found out
the way
to you know if you know some keys
animosity system even if you know one
how to crack March the key systems and
how to calculate
the monster in a system what it looks
like and most of the time if you have
access to one key or from marcia key
system
and this is a general speaking a.m.
then than the system uses compromised
and you know you can
you can open all the doors if you are
determined enough to
to do detect s
blaze into buyers have laid out even
with the
the side pens that down you need to find
a blank I guess
well I would expect for horses for
courses about about making your own
blanks and stuff
so the the blank is not the problem
I mean if you are determined enough its
own is only be two metal with some
groups in some holes consonant is
nothing more nothing less
and it takes determination especially
with the mall to look interactive look
that you have there
right I don't say easy but on the other
hand you know if you would give the key
to me for
for 20 minutes or no for for 20 seconds
I make a detailed photocopy of it
and I give you a week later I give your
key when I'm back in the Netherlands
and i jus reads how deep it is and what
combination is
am most likely I mean I cannot say with
100 percent certainty but
with a high degree of secure certainty I
can make that
that key for you without seeing data
over again
my you sir Skyler
a very as wondering
do I companies implement things in the
locks is particular pins
anything like that to specifically for
impression oh yes
there are some things a for instance
dome
makes a pin that is a bottom mushroom
been all the mushroom pins are toppings
normally
a.m. and we picking it's very
frustrating because then you pick and
you have no idea how
the locus turning but actually the
mushroom been is in the way
Ando makes these pins bottom pins with
impression you never have problems with
mushrooms
as a matter fact if you look turns like
it's
its in a mushroom it's an indication
okay dude you went too deep
because now you have reached in a pin
thats normally on top
of the bottom pins it's not so good I i
think it's a clear enough
I think a.m. so that's that's with to a
impression ng and and
key specifically or been specifically
for that purpose
so and I've also seen them in French
locker I think for ships
also has them time
Mont next I'm
um at the noticing that allow the
European keys are actually
will be more secure than once the United
States just by
just representation for example no I'm
wondering
how easy is it to import European marks
into United States
meaning like by one from Europe getting
mail to me
United States a.m. well you should talk
to him about that
on lisa is a %uh expert on that field
the also can maybe deliver some US
shaped I security locks and after the
presentation
just meet up with him done says it
looked at Village and
it will work out I think it yeah
okay why
Canon City come
my english is not to do this from Bari
I suppose we'll go to gretchen okay
I'll this sheet I found now its she'd
a.m. which demonstrate the floating
thought
in the key for the protection against
molding
I don't know if people are interested if
they want to know how that works
yes okay
a.m. not woken we Okun
imagine this is a dome each system and
there is a floating 5 in element
and floating element in the key on the
left side
you see the key with a blue ball bearing
on the right side
at errol a you can see
expect chamber where r wrecked pin
and the Reds top and the button pin
amounted in if a the spring
pushes down the here
pushes down
a the toppin and the rotation is blocked
if I insert the correct key there is a
blue ball bearing
the group or ball bearing lifts up the
the the bottom pin and we have she line
this is clear okay the trick is
that the ball bearing has a certain
diameter
so that you have to correct height a to
create a she line
if you look on the left a
picture or a picture in the middle you
see ball
blue been in the preps yeah we see that
this Plurk is stock it's a fixed
block a.m. this block
a.m. grievance did if you insert the key
which is not the milt deep enough
does not go in the whole way you
understate
and on
on dippers to keep there is partially
the the the key is milt in
deeper and because the key is milt in
deeper
it can go under the blue pin here
so everybody understand so that
now you can insert the key and
an the but
if you insert the key the wat I'll
pointed out is Matt
if you
insert the key a.m. deflation of the key
is the tight
this this height I issue mules
understand that and because the height
is
not deep enough this reppin
rest below
yeah and because stepped rest
been rest below there is no she like him
and therefore it does not rotate and
the most clever trick is then the ball
bearing the ball bearing
has the right height but
how do you get that's right height on
the right position
if there is if it's been you understand
and therefore they made a time when the
blacks
so that the ball bearing
good go under its com at the correct
position
and lift the red been is this little
okay this is a is an example of an
floating element
iniki the
in this is an example buddy show
before the this easy entry picture and
the the easy entry pic the easy entry is
milling machine and it
it measures the profile of a key
so so it's Ken stuckey
here and it put it somewhere in the
software
and then a mill is activated and it
makes a copy of the key here
it Mills those tracks on the key
so that the key will fit in the lock
and a we visit the the company gay gay
gateway is a a big company and a
there you have to text keep the next key
way on the left site
and you can see in the circle undercut
yeah it's it's a it's a it's it's a part
in a key way which takes out
if you look straight on the key you can
see that the key looks like this
that's an origin okie if you
den skin dickey which with at the easy
entry
you scan the key like this
yet but if you scan the key you don't
scan
the whole apart in the key yen
depart dust machine Nazi sick leave
and because dat machine
does not see that part he just makes a
key
like this so
the black part is so let yeah dusted
keefe
does the disc e fit in the black yes or
no
now okay so there were clever guys
who set a.m. effete does not scan the
doc part here
ifile
the whole pie two-way and then I get
this key correct or not
to does this keep fit in the keyway
okay now this key fits the keyway
correct
but
gay gay was clever and they did not like
that
no because otherwise not people could
copy the key
and we see on the left we see the
original key
and we see that undercut in the middle
we see the key made with the easy entry
yeah
and on the left right side we see the
key
where we have filed away despite
we all see that and
gave me was that clever that they insert
at an extra slider in the lock
and we can ship we can see that on the
left picture that slider
their is blocked by going further
because of this fighting the key you see
on the left but you can see it you see
that that the red slider
it cannot move to the left side yeah
if I now have easy entry
key which is to a
faked and I milt this away the slide it
goes in
do we all see that
and then the rotation of key will be
blocked after ninety degrees
okay this was just a short what
with the same a.m.
week didn't
we didn't find to wait till now yeah
okay keep it in the middle
with you know show we make two questions
later
okay I show you in short some
experience with it about them peace room
I'll desist
been s Cuyler refer to this is an
example of an
don't mix and I think it's
now you can see details of the prince so
let it be
I'll
and here is what I 16 to start my talk
I'm
I have stream a.m.
in a moment much
okay easy and now I now want to sell
something about the hockey s look
a.m. and RTS stands for
robotic robotic key system this
RTS system is developed by states and
concepts
it's an inventor and listen Stenton
nearby New York
and it's the world its its wheels first
open source looking system and I am then
referring to the key and then referring
to the key
the key is motorized as you can see
there
and and therefore we call it also
a robotic E and the cylinder is purely
mechanical which is on the left a.m.
with these robotic Tyler you can rotate
the discs in the cylinder
so that the synagogues open this lock
was first presented in snake in 2005 the
G Lee we have with two the big event in
the Netherlands
that a Dutch Open during that event
the people from France Germany United
States
United Kingdom and the Netherlands
condemn
lot of lock pick a sandlot lock and to
just its
and inventor demonstrated their his lock
that was in 2005 and people could play
with a look they could give comments on
the look
they could try to manipulate the look
and the inventor
went home with a lot of good ideas and
US clever enough to implant to implement
these improvements its to get a better
look so that it was more
covered entry secured a.m.
okay a.m.
the most strongest point about this look
is thats
there is no hole on the inside you can
see the
you can see this part on this great part
comes to Tyler that's the tip of the
dialer
and if that dialer is placed
on the cylinder it starts rotating
and just like a combination lock of the
safe was just like a public protector
the disc start rotating
and one by one they getting the correct
position so that the looking back in
dropping
yeah its it's a very special mechanism
now
these are some over thoughts the the
inventor hat a.m.
he wanted to he developed this look
in first instance for to the to
for the container transports
a.m. because he said there were some
problems with the contains
a.m. there were case of P lost et cetera
and you can imagine if you have a
container
you ship this from China to the United
States
how do you den Handel with the customs
on route because as we all know
the customs a has the authority to open
to to inspect the container between
China and America and the point loss
you could put the below commit a padlock
and then you put the key from the pet
luck with that container
and then somebody could open the
container with a look remove stuff from
its and closed container again
and place the key back so that was not
the solution
because it could not be tracked at the
container was opened
if you put a lock on that container
you sent to keep to China or to the US
and customs will check
that contain it to have to cut open the
lock so
that was also not the solution and
therefore they came with seals
very clever solution
but and if you use the seals
after use they are at you can throw them
away
and they are not trackable they are hot
to track
and these were reasons to invented the
hockey a system
these are
the pots in the cylinder I will go to
dry address less to say about this I
think this picture is clear
and Dez either boss in the cylinder
the in detail I want to show how to sit
in the works if I get this on
okay
here
here I have to salinity my aunt
incredible here
here I have to sheila Marie my aunt and
the first thing what we can the first
thing what we can see
are the discs and locking bar in it
this is the front of the cylinder
and this is what we call the manual
dialer
dismantled either
them is xx Lee a.m. the dialer
from a safe we can place these dialer
on RTS still in there
and if we rotate the dial we can see
data disc start rotating I think
most of us are familiar with it
combination safe locks
this now if you have a combination safe
locks
a slocum you normally count till three
ordeal for
and than US had all the disks and
their curious if somebody's how many
discs are in the look
cough some people will sync up how many
Fife I thought there were
fix okay now I rotate this look
and you can imagine a.m. the
lost this so the discs the
nectar the disc on the right this
in the front of the Lok will be position
first so
and I wrote take no further and you can
see the chamber watergate I rotate its
it's a little bit stuck the first disc
is now aligned
can everybody see that okay now that
means that we now
make 546 rotation back and then
than this next disc will also be aligned
everybody see that
shopping of West you see it's okay
now we try to the we rotate to the right
and
and this way we can open the lock
missus Henry or not yes
is to secure or not yes it's secure
because if you can if you can manipulate
it's hot too many plates that 7
or a six-disc safe lock is already hot
too many later
safe lock with three discs yeah
so this is a very secure lock but the
point with this is the
the minimal dialer is not handy because
it it takes the time to rotate
that the combination and therefore the
invent the game
with this thing
and that's what he called the robotic
dialer and
I now will insert a robotic are on the
look and then we'll see what happens
okay
to top screen wait a moment
out Alka
now I do it again
and we can see
that looking back goes in and
this is one of the nicest things about
the robotic a system
because normally used dialer to open the
lock
yeah but if you don't have the
robotic Tyler you only have two manual
dialer
it's possible that you get
combination from somebody and that you
can rotate it by hand
here I now I now doubt the combination
for you eight cell
it's now fully blocked am the cylinder
does not rotate
you see it blocks its stock its stock
I I pushing the top of the Roman
rebutted either
we see the key
the the disc rotate and the look is open
yet point which is system is
that a.m. dialing instructions can come
in by GSM or by GPS et cetera
so this is the way customs can open
deadlock on the way and
get there is a lot to tell about there
is a lot to tell about
the how to look exactly works because
they only shalt
how to open it and and
I think I can invite everybody to the
to the lockpick village there we have
John Laughlin
John Laughlin is one of the inventors of
the system he has
some stuff with him so that everybody
can play with it just like a snake
and maybe drop people who have
fine too weak spot or whatever when side
okay
now this was other questions about or
other questions of
then go to the mike
do
standard combination lock techniques
apply
to opening these types walks for example
thats
that is an extremely good question and I
have an extremely good answer
no as we all know
the everybody who has styled a
combination lock
knows eat rice he rotates three times
right
two times left 1 times right one times
left
and the community and the look is open
yeah that sustain that rotation
of a combination lock and therefore in
the mocked
we have tireless the stylus are out a
medic devices
which you can mount on the safe and you
let it
3-4 days rotate and it dials exactly all
the combinations
with all the possible combinations yeah
and this is way too many plates
locks a.m. all
if we look at two discs of this lock we
see
at the eight holes here
yeah
there are eight holes in these eight
holes you can
mount the screw and
you can see this crews here the Spruce
have to function of the flight and the
flight
in to in a in the combination lock
it's a fight which takes out on the
taste if I now rotate
the first disc long enough then the
screw
comes at another screw or another flight
he gets the second disc
and the 2nd district also rotating now
that's taken they start rotating
it step by next fly as you can see here
and at a certain moment all the 54 60s a
rotating
and because you can
very the position of the fly
because you can't put the fly all 8
different positions you also get
different
rotation better yet so
the rotation better is not five times
left
four times let right three times left
two times right
because of the changing of to fly
positions
and the it's a very strange
experience with I had to but I doubt it
because you have for example doubt it I
four times to the right and then take a
number
and at four times to the left and I'll
number for
me while it is normally four times to
the right
and three times and it two times and
then one times yeah
but I it finds everybody to come to the
lockpick village
and then you can see it yourself yeah
other questions is there a date set when
these will be available for purchase
can you repeat that duck
available for purchase purchase
a.m. you can by now
inventor has made hundred of these locks
for test purposes
et cetera and he also has to cut away
for Shin with
the manual dialer and I thought 425
dollars you can buy the lock and 450
dollar
you can by Tyler and and yes only made
they are all number uniquely and
a.m. I think they are collectors items
and they also now be side effect that
they are collector items
they're also nice gadgets and nice
toys for the voice then
so really come to look like phyllis see
the look yourself
and I think he has brought ten of these
locks with him and that's it
then a.m. I'd like to point out that
I'm as with every year for the
conference we
have made the special pic said design
that specifically designed for these
conferences is the last hope
we decided to make something when you
know when is the last
think that you might have to a.m.
to to let you into your own house or to
assist other people
it's a credit card sized except a where
you can
breakaway the parts if you really need
them
I'm going to leave this one intact a and
yeah
that they're also for sale you're on a
conference and
inches it's it's a very nice design
because
the corner of of the the pic said are
also tensioners
so if you break it out there's an
11-piece pick set
left for you so might be fun to to pick
one up at the
points okay
then a a.m. when I'm doing sales here
I might as well talk about March book
a on medico a
it also covers quite a deal on key
control
a duplicating keys you know
making making copies of keys at your
that they don't want you to make copies
of
so might also be good investment
if you're into look i think is it
a.m. thanks a lot and hope to see you
at the next hour
coming up next in this room for those of
you that have ever traveling got one of
those really nice notices that your bags
then rifled through by the TSA
I was a gentleman who put a camera
inside his bag and film with the TSA
did with his back so that's up back damn
how did the TSA and the airlines managed
to do that
your pockets that are being here in just
a minute