this
I was listening to that help
again
did it was heaven hell yes I
I'm where the families is america yeah
thank you all for coming out
we really appreciated we we really
appreciate that they are you all chose
said
not see the good stuff that's going on
the other tracks and instead Europe
suffering through this stuff with us
yet because of class for being here
it's very nice that's why they didn't
have a third track that I wanna put
anybody against us it's cool I
understand
yeah now we told them it was guaranteed
audience you know but okay I'm
I guess I guess we'll start with the
introduction thumbs I'm a
I'm roti Firefly I have somewhat active
and
various scenes I'm to the far right here
is starting with me now starting with
you how because that because we love you
and if this is murdoch
are thank you guys my yeah
we'll I love you till I wanna be your
best friend and I'm serious when I say
that
and I also accept donations I broke my
arm three weeks ago fifty-five thousand
dollars
I told him before the bills to Canada
but they're not gonna so
I'm gonna pass my boot around later just
like jello did a few years ago
so please give us money many fifties and
hundreds
speaking 1500 that to my immediate left
is um eyeball greetings fellow humans
um I'm I've all I %ah
me and yeah what's up with you guys
but and on the other side here we have a
side pocket and though
the me worry people well my
was is this is the chinese army's yes
exactly
I'll okay well I like the life K the
thing
okay I'm week but had a little go
good
just have to you
change
good
go
the
this
you
to
go
good
go the speed
to
good
the good
go
good
to
go
good
the the
so hi everybody my name is a sidebar and
things I've done some you know say the
hotel
stuff in a lil being on the I will be an
appealing for the help that we like the
prank phone calls a film on since that
is me Rupp
I'm yeah I'm up
I I'm what we saw on the video there on
Thalie photographically altered was red
box chili pepper
who is our Lord and Savior and strong
arms demagogue
worship it was sorta like a Warren Jeffs
in a sense then less is the full
economic sense but like
cultish leader sense mean less he's a
tireless
I mean I only have 3 so but
it's very much a Tom Cruise so I'm
what else we got and we can tell you
guys about that P L E radio
which is an hour from online radio show
or
podcast as the kids like call it
nowadays um
I think I think said this is even
the I think I even knew him
but I'm Conor may I can fill a time by
telling you a little bit about the other
area
ophelia radio by it's not like it's on
weekly or anything like that
I
game pretty much whenever bread decides
to it
stir up the pot and find new content for
him to
replace I guess like the prank calls
that that I
that are featured on our site they're
kinda re captain read under PI radio
I I know he added me and
eating a popcorn and overpower have a
dancer which I
I mean didn't necessarily not happen but
you know what can you do
a lot of them I know we had one that was
on a
that is on our voice identification are
authentic Asian never going to be there
I guess leo is are looking for so
in you know a lot of this is based on
the
fact that he can get his stuff together
used
unfortunately it's member da fam know
and I am NOT
what but I could dismissive alright from
you think map it stands
when City manana
gets way you
CDs yes a feeling radio is a very very
interesting thing that we've done on the
way to the prevailing
you know hopefully love a few samples to
assure you it's really exciting stuff
no not be admitted during the disc
swiping sequence
wife Livia people be amended until then
a
detainees will be donated to charity has
such nice people own
it's all gonna Murdocca broken on the
Fed's time they is Brad boxing
somewhere in Kansas is somewhere in the
feds came they really beat him that he
was with the guys on the image that if
you have any money please
give it you must be really needs the
research we might die in two weeks it's
it's creepy
and I'm still trying to get one others
cope with the pay phones from Las Vegas
so
min who were maam
if anything was the stuff he was getting
beat up for the stuff I did but
you know no ever found that out in no 10
ever will
room like it so families America started
to at the scene
roughly fifteen years ago I'm sorry by
Red Hot Chili Peppers
in the then thriving text seen seen on
during a time when everyone else was
there to being all shady and elitist and
you know we're gonna be still upon you
some information in this and that
um he decided to come out with something
that probably dick
proudly declared how much it sucked and
I'm was followed mostly at mostly stuff
that
wouldn't or couldn't work or you know
was a little to no use whatsoever
and I'm and in the fifteen-year-olds
just
heated up they ate it up with spoons I
was why this fifteen-year-old I was too
and
you I was running a spine but yes I
could stage in
he was still being built in the garage
with power tools back and I'm
history school yeah
coming to the old folks you can't kids
in there
dang fangled Texas scenes very good
want you you
it is the magic box making sense I know
it's sort of like a public I was going
on
my twenties my name is Brad and I have
two kids
and I spend them everywhere I go and
okay I think what we have here is a
possibly an excerpt from Kelly radio
if it here almost
so up show the audio yes
is there def relay operator anywhere but
KFK by
has it now college says fuck that shit
go ahead
have but I O
I think what was it night two or three
years ago I
CNBC did a a did a piece on corporate
terrorism
about about corporate terrorism in
Denmark juan Martin Indyk a or another's
chain stores
and I guess so what if the end CNBC
staffers summer someone up on the phone
losers out or Walmart H
and I did a did a quick email with with
Brad the
the the administrator that over its not
a
windows ninety its cruise ship on its
designated time
I they did a a they they call Brad they
brought him in for an interview for CNBC
talking about the prank calls that we
did the the forty prank calls that we
did for
for wal-mart word people callin thinking
that they're gonna be getting the
Walmart they're really talking to me
so so what they'd
what they do is they play they play a
couple they cut they play a couple of
the prank calls
and basically the CNBC hosts lands as a
score for terrorism and how
how were nothing but but but bad people
and
you know you'd expect my countrymen on
Fox News by CNBC you know you can't
really
you really want that to happen by me
when
when I got for me when when I corporate
terrorist but not not anymore I did not
imagine salon change am an honest
still in SA it's a it's a it's a it's a
legal gray area got to tell you that
maybe if we all wear like V for Vendetta
masks or something other than that right
we have the protest something religion
as a
really is another matter yes I but I
when we're getting back to the early
radio
montana your you'll enjoy it trust
exchanges especially be seen
obvious other movie sneakers welcome for
that our
can't make it better and isolated and
out the back and it is now using voice
application to verify the customer's
identity
to access their account a customer has
to say pass plays into the Sun
but as friends goes like this: adult
high-priced is my password
for security reasons I make sure I can
take a cab ride
activity clearly K at that hour
my voice is my ass white a customer
records their boss Redknapp friends on
Twitter account
libraries can validate the town
Wednesday count as once validated the
customers transfer to a bank employee
who will do anything on the Capital One
including going over charges on the bill
and Lorraine or removing thomas'
tomorrow attempted to access the
customer's account about a dozen times
using different voices to trying for the
system
but nothing worked parity where he could
try again
because I couldn't match your voice with
the one we have on file it looks pretty
much just like the concept indication
the mini Snickers
might bring a toy company has to speak
the name and friends
my passport funny what's more the
Martins friends need to bring continue
to lose my brother sins of it so we can
go back to Panasonic answering machine
at the time company stuff from
case what's this mean my voice is my
passport verify any
some surprise for tidying up to
so you get this girl got game with the
guy and she gets into some
goods required for the past four days
into the tape recorder
by doing things like this I talk to me
you know my I really last the sound of
your highest
and spun
word our list last
some this where of our no
I have no you wouldn't know why I will
try my actually found what
iight I would really
like to hear you save
where past hi passport
her
you its I of after months by Starbucks
community together with have included
that sounds like this
hiking fears Francis
by Voice despite passport fun a person
that works perfectly manageable broken
glass at a spy playing a tape recording
was braced
so I wanted to see what does come with a
trip to work on but can to customers
the combined with the Canadian I would
just make a phone call to them and can't
remember what I needed
grant put
yellow for
for hey this is I I
I just about the topics they have our
best
yeah quite a bit overdue I'm for what is
overdue
they had yeah points in the win by
access rivers I don't I never got a book
so
the horrific event you know
which one but use a voice to win but I
have no books from the library
responsible that's not my town
well yeah for check-in check-out about
two months ago
Domino for from the top polls by Ernest
Hemingway
no I have no box below
government library for some time strange
because I didn't use my card for
quite some time it's just use the word
my
guns used two times in the past race now
only four minutes left
from for you to come over my daughter
are you for or use the computer their
bid for
I have been over for a long time at the
sheets you have a password on our
computer
from I don't think so
you don't think so the choose a password
on the computer
got after and it's not now
its battle bent reduce your computer's
OST fuck out here from the top hold back
on
hemingway no no ever heard of that one
no nano I C
okay overall look into this send with a
if you work for you could you give me a
call back from you know where to find
the owner for them
for dinner for which works well free
why I know where that is clean up once
the
yes because for the from
the swimming pool is yeah exactly yeah
yup
know I love been over there free time
put up
not imply for pickup
from blue box containers 3.4 per day
I but there are no I have your pro-bush
Murtala
strange yeah and and I'm
you know where this location at that for
years and you from the Bell Tolls
no no no like I would have no interest
them
in giving it up for I can
defile overheard just the way it was
wrong and getting my book
sagged if I could I would if I were
looking to see what is
llama for the name you said you wouldn't
know be interested in getting which book
whether
your 1024 such event for whom the film
holder
got only one with multiple
yeah tractor gonna I cannot give you
have a call back which
we recommend you know because I'm gonna
take like your library card hope to see
you
whether chose over work good to your
phone number even though
Russia on america libraries it
do just a minority don't hun
the one and the press at
I'm see yeah and there's the rub
graft after out crime okay I
hmm and then it's I extension 113
extension 11 3 right my
but you have to make some prepared for
us publicly announce to you for the same
person he would just one call
12 months Obama produced this
yeah no like boys like housework
some for partition system
a few drinks obviously don't match have
leslie probably work with his original
passphrase
much cum confuse the system and also
complains down three times in mind and
with the title voice recording time
police
times not peace so it's not going to
have the best sound quality
but let's try it out and see how it
works welcome to back our
can't make it better I can take it from
there
if you go to come back Press for
okay to an agent for security reasons I
will try to educate your price:
activity clearly say an hour
my voice aspects I for
I and its takes
your boy have been up to
says healthcare as you
it works perfectly a compact hybrid
times and each time it worked
after party must these ones I was
transferred to an employee
a couple of little stuff tried to battle
my town by asking for my address postal
code
and the account number on leslie's bill
but I had a miserable night rd party
make out with my place so I didn't see
massive need to do it again
doubles in place agreed good business up
with my cousins in town
every employee I spoke with was able to
see that use the euro suffocation system
carbon please we're going to do anything
I asked them to run leslie's account
from going to the bill to making changes
on the town
if I wanted to I could add Funds to his
account is connected with themes
added to remove features and I could
have asked them to go over lesley stahl
calls
some companies have been talking about
using on seven occasions since at least
the early nineties when I first heard
about it
but this is the first time I seen any
company actually use it
and it's a good idea in theory the
problems that actually removes a layer
security
not me I would need to get personal
information about wesley texas is
account but now I don't even need that
instead you just have to make a phone
call to him and get him to see my words
1 I'll take my body wants to make this
from carl s when you look at the tape
together
and he pretty much anybody would shop
for this camera is on the phone
it yeah here
that's there was a you yeah
and this is why we are awesome
yeah this is just a small sample have
those are the things you find those yeah
I'm a radio yeah
Magister not just that but not not just
that made immense things that might be
stupid
you know think they may be stupider yeah
only but the you know he's got a very
nice voice so even if you don't like
what he's talking about
you can just listen to him savitz Sox
a gonna tell me said that you hate me
anyway
go ahead i buy my my house but the
government has no burns like me
that to we were already followed by
Agence deal we don't need any more
stress
hope it doesn't come after this panel
he totally does see yeah after after our
panel you can stay tuned for agent steel
who is %uh you know very interesting
talkers not not this renovation feel
this by agent steel
so you know but we got next
try to get try to get that CNBC on CNBC
clip for Ghana
nothing that we just have the idea year
okay he said the idea for
yeah again
I'm basically a basically what they're
talking about the the prank call that
that that
that they're gonna be featuring I guess
on the on here we don't have the video
which is probably for the best because a
SN video sucks
heavily on air it's just CNBC you know
awake something I don't see every day
anyway
so it's basically Brad looking at the
at the camera Lake deer in the
headlights you know just not very good
on TV
he's not you have very photogenic I I
wish you just play the videos you could
see brad's amazing impression yeah he
made was pretty good grade by its
principal is talking to unlock
yeah but basically what they're what
they're talking about is this a is this
Franco added to a Walmart
where basically move
a how can I explain this the
they people call Walmart the the main
number Walmart and they get
night a customer service representative
but me or bread
and I you know they play they play a
couple the calls
from that and then bred discusses it and
again the guy girls and for being a
basically a and he covered terrace you
know
this definitely not gonna rock you
anything but
Liam you're good I and let's go its
on the money tonight forget
made-for-t_v_ you put all the complaints
you won't believe what some critics are
urging shoppers
thing coming up on the money nightmare
for walls are there's like 30 seconds
offers yes and Lucius you never hear
bashing walmart has become an art form
but you won't believe who's taking on
the retail giant now
and craft the way they're doing it bush
well as we told you earlier a california
jury tonight a warning 172 million
dollars to thousands of employees at
Walmart stores
who sued saying they were denied lunch
breaks also from the Walmart file
running amok in stores coast to coast
there is a group called
only losers dot com and they're taking a
new approach to living there anymore
for all your help ranks in one scam a
group hijacked the phones at one Walmart
actually taking calls from some
unassuming
customers take a listen damn PL yes
borrow
happy you have any commit so it's always
or or higher
I where I
I'm reported yeah
mark arm ok you almost
fed
here W
I i've your part yeah
joining us now Brad Carter he runs phone
losers dot com and the anarchy a your
local Walmart page
a brat death had to come up with this
idea speaker wisely
from there was a couple sites already on
the internet and their
late 90s and I'm we just capitalists
altogether
and maybe one day you can read site
where people can so that things
adonis and the list could I have looked
at the list is SEP quite like the editor
a wide variety of pranks from
perfume bottles to computer screens i'm
curious
offer the phone prank how it is you got
past two
the store security to be able to take
that call whoever Dwight was that did
bass leaving yes I we just kinda drifted
from department to department in
pick up the phones as the calls came and
in recorded them from the store
we have another call somebody listening
books call initially for directions I
wanna have letter may get a chance to
hear this
okay I'm crying opposite direction to
come here store
okay I'm coming down now over 100
we were taking off but very what you
want from
market they went out current market who
may not have
human cd20 impair your workout no come
on guys I want correct direction how to
get to the store
if this reminds me of some other morning
radio where they have a RvB prank
callers want to be favored
and choices for morning radio
entertainment
however bad there is also legal
and certainly ethical issues associated
with the
either destroying property or from im
we're presuming to be an employee when
you are not
where is the line between prank a.m. the
law and we just
kinda often think about that we're just
going two hundred
time to time we get all this in the mid
90's and had
how did you take over the overhead
paging system this is how we discovered
the
paging code that they use to get on the
paging system we called in from the
outside and ask them to transfer as to
that extension
and that put us on the overhead paging
and we're able stay on for hours just
telling jokes and seanangs imitating and
wanted to say on the air
now how much of this was for fun
and how much of this is because you have
a a particular
I'm issue with Walmart I'm
at same or less it's pretty much of a
fine if thats
I don't have anything personal against
wal-mart I don't like them too much
better
you know i i just we did offer fine
helps
so what are those big you did because it
was there to do we we called Walmart an
awsome for comment they were not
familiar
I'm with your activities and so they
didn't give us a comment although I
imagine
there are no real time to watch their
televisions tonight Brad a pleasure to
have you with us thank you for your time
we appreciate it
thank you well in basically that's a
that's how it went down girl unlike a
like a if I can terrorist or something
and
we weren't in the store obviously I
basically what we did it was a it was
all social engineering we did nothing on
site
a basically we do we'll call we'll call
customer service line
for business business line and say hi
this is the manager you know it the
Walmart in Gainesville or something do
in Florida anything
and a you know air phones aren't working
or not getting any calls into getting
any calls out
we need to have calls coming in to get
them forwarded to maybe like a home
office is some kind
it's a yes sure you know them you know
that as I get the manager's name
the district managers name is usually
good to have both those things
I and then jizzster there was a okay
will give us about 50 minutes they call
they would call you you know it the
whatever number you did what we did is
we set it up to a a conferences
teleconference that would terminate
silently
so it would just be me and him on the
line there we hear the click
every new customers online and then we
can just talk to them
so you know there's nothing on site it
was nothing like that
so yeah
and it is a hero I notice that we're
just talking about you so yeah
now misgiving yes okay
I think so I'm saying yeah yeah I just
while so it
you guys know that as you can tell by
his vice president very educated
intelligent very
smart man very calm that's them is
listening to this is me
yeah yeah by the way he says it as much
as he says he loves you on thank you for
coming to this panel is really great
then he said some really disgusting
things that when I can repeat
cement all your moms in a so it's going
back to
such as an a-hole going back to people
people that you can pull pranks on
from I thought members have this lovely
subculture we have
from we've we've always found targets
for our vitriolic I like Walmart or
you know movie theaters or you know you
know God or whatever but the
he's really something to bring but I'm
you know the another another another
occasional target
and I want I won't say this is a regular
thing but it's a fun when it works out
is I'm love you so a we we decided to
I'm we became kind of you can kind of
known for putting out that tutorials for
various things and Dom
just that just for the sheer hell amid
we decided to put together a tutorial
that did not work and um we might get up
and decided to
basically see who had the who would fall
for that so I'm
week she shouldn't should be for say
that before all this happened hard
mmm feel right now gotta keep going yeah
that before all this happened we had
there is a video there was put around
over
love a bread and and his friend Raj 05 I
A
be going to a Taco Bell and attempting
to order food and then for some reason
using modified ham radio equipment
and bad they were able to then overpower
the
in the Taco Bell radio receiver in
you know speak on the on the speaker box
which made so yeah you might have seen
it on YouTube with a bunch a comment
saying oh god there's no fuckin way they
could do this what a fuckin lie it's
photoshopped
things like that you know saudi families
pixels
it's like a I seen these before yeah I
can see the pixelation so
basically that's what's been going on
with it had been around for about three
years it may be YouTube rounds about
sixteen times in you know sixteen people
saying look kinda radio can I do this
I april fools bread made this retreat me
this video so
press play now now press play press it
I summer but just I love choco
Tahoe is a humble
rules of my jump on Google money-maker
nice huh
want to
done
nice Ochoa back in 2003 we need this
video that showed us screwing with an
attack upon striking frequencies
after we done did nothing with them for
a few weeks we decided to go through the
drive to ourselves
with the camera and family man and his
reaction last modified and I so tech
messed with my order here
and
God
per share like embed has been well spent
it on Facebook
dig I don't you want to come and
separate sites
and it's caused a pretty constant flow
you know to me
a pass-first millions of people asking
me how to do it
service manuals and show you how to even
eat a proper
frequencies are pretty much done a fast
food joint in your town
don't you come here and talk to me like
that why
got some but heck yeah okay
guy
good you're bound to find something as
Cartier cvx.n
and that's what we used to take on the
topic of frequencies the problem with
using AC is the price
the cheapest I could find one is
probably two hundred and fifty dollars
then you have to modify it
than most people just aren't comfortable
opening up a two hundred fifty dollar
piece of equipment some ushering in our
county parade
a penis to get started this you only
need two things:
land is a CB radio it has to be attended
a CB radio that has beautiful number
display on it
the second thing and is called a 6.55 36
magnets custom
I don't know what happened to my husband
the CBN radio pull out the existing cost
one-sided
all possible CB radios use the same
frequency of course the inside
which is a 1.73 magnets custom replaced
acosta with are 6.5 536 make its crystal
replacing the crystal inside will
actually triple the frequencies
I just happens the policy but he was and
remains the drive to restaurants
broadcast on
reverses the polarity to Tennessee
should be
thought someone might have something in
mind into place got
12 probably less than 10 bucks before
spot staff spiner heat
you should be able to find one man from
the 50 or 60 bucks come to
when investment Kinko's is good to cost
about 6.55 36 minutes in slightly more
complicated
which one are you can buy these crystals
from so you have to take
does a defense that uses them already I
believe you several has twice as good
use these kind of crystals
most common one even funny and he's a
toaster
from national tests were manufactured
after the nineteen eighties will happen
in his group's inside them
attached to pass through super you can
assign an apparent as you should
easily be able to plan out there
fitzpatrick I'm going to be using a
walkie-talkie CB radio
it's a realistic TRC to know something
from your site
to spent the crystal lattice
first thing on particular escape
clinton's to unprofor
if you tryin to green retired
summed it up a bit got to escape
just come from you speech since taking
them out
perhaps griping and types of possible
before
picking up a pair of with what my first
rehab
posters manufactured after the nineteen
eighties had this crystal inside them
the used as a safety precaution and the
cantata concealed heating coils inside
the test
sustenance crystals and he has plane for
Houston Chronicle such as I
geyser a heater UConn and even in your
electric stove
much to type of you should be able see a
circuit board inside
good
on soccer body preparing your crystal
measures to keep
connections to meet the cost of perhaps
very very basic stuff people
attest to my stomach without the
crystalline solid
but it's not a month instead of thinking
about us
the federal taking a CB radio
should be just as easy as taking apart
the toaster mysteries and publication of
inside you'll see a circuit board its
because the on-site look exactly like
the custom printable toaster
the only difference is the ones on Obama
frequency
most apostles just plugged into a socket
something happy Easter Sunday 1921 in
as you can see it. AC 2007 it was
plugged into a socket right next to the
transmit button
so anytime this man outs Greg Nickels
terrain
but the lady does not make a difference
from this open and what's really plugged
in
after that's done in December your CB
radio and you're ready to start having
fun
afternoon sleeping with you smart people
to conceive the channels anymore
1727 group range
by replacing the customer insight into
CB radio you've actually tried to bring
your CDs capable
ever seen and transmitting on I just so
happens that 6.55 369 it's not something
he needs to be able to listen in top two
tries to frequencies
once you find us to stop he popped
on certain post I put into a chance and
to keep on talking
16 question it's as easy as pressing the
tab key
in saying anything you want to them
censure CB radio several times not
problem employees headsets the customer
should only be able to hear you
you're trapped between and not the
employee inside
and good
and you
like it
go
and that's how you do it
if you're lucky enough to have a CB now
cheap and complete this project for
pretty much now
money from the German swimmer be sure to
www that found losers that word
or come see me in the studio good
morning have a lady who topped with a
drive thru
some years ago in K
K
a
in
it
kaelin
hey okay and okay
or in
yeah
okay
a
in
hey in
there
him
in
%ah
yeah
yeah all
okay
all 11
in
okay in
yeah
in
okay
%ah
in
yeah
on in
in
everyone
fell for this and they were mad I
why that you're too did is after this
video went up is that a bunch of us some
love these
that some users who are in this cutting
it to you we went on to
the main website you too today
everything and the pretended that this
actually did work
in like set photo evidence and showed it
ended example so many people did this
and they got mad we got tons and tons I
hate mail
and even death threats even audio death
threats I believe and
you can also this other website and
laughter as a sophomore back to you that
if you want help us out there find this
video on youtube and leave a comment on
about how well it works for you
it's not awful that people can follow
the russians probably I
everybody who %ah says it doesn't work
you know I visited and not pay any
attention to our
how it's done if you don't get a crystal
every tester on bernie as I think it's
all you want
and help and you'll get great toe still
baptist
to some he switched
certificates which okay scheme
for those of you who remember these ads
will play that's really quick and
because it's terribly clever
here going around at-bats like this guy
that I'm product that's right side bangs
settlement conferences groups like comes
out as bad that imports
like well screamed the power
my friends
mom well that settles back morals
weekends with you and a friend wanna
a back together fumble at the lapd
fans their hand
began to I don't know is that I was the
parables and bring him home
my name is Michael use them and
apparently I know it may seem like
you're kinda wrapping this up early but
I
you know agents deal is on after us and
I'm seeing a pretty big I
a pretty big gathering for them for them
and for us oh those people for us
yeah have been notified thanks guys
inlaid actually works
rate which is actually really
intimidated by Agence till we don't go
home from the kind find our house is
gone
so you know or have a second level
attached to them
but so me that have been there at times
but I'm we will be we will be up on the
mezzanine later on purpose going
straight there from here we have a
lovely
from uses America t-shirts and will be
will be giving them away for correct
answers here
fifty in these things will be giving
them away for granted the trivia
questions
and we will also have some DVD this
effort to give you some freebies and
I'm I think we're actually doing a book
signing will resign other people's books
so a that Stephenie
baby I got you Picasa sign a CD
living/dining the name on it if you like
call them if they decide 2000s ballot
fucking yes
have some now it on Yahoo make some CDs
back a brotherhood and Richard just
small UK
especially a decade yep
got I these are also I'm very well
mostly by our guests ho
okay it's funny you've got pounded ok
the to
you bridal I'm no no no
if they were great at a hotel down but I
think we're gonna cause that by the way
you guys are lucky because pran
anonymous and the same building and I
think that's gonna come up this
I nothing good guarantee something
someone or some offenders is gonna be on
fire by tonight
exactly exactly I'm so
a quick laugh what we lack in content we
make up 43 should
just a quick yeah
who do you love but this is the only one
washable something red to
and photograph got hey yeah I think that
you're interested you guys gonna kinda
bum rush the stage for these days I'm
not gonna throw 'em
by plac these hell yeah it's
good people trying to develop so
efforts the weather perfect health yes
its
yeah everything works OK
help recovery of with you
shy guys here at CNN stoker's paper
figures spade a spade new york
workers wanna want to be related to me
he's too many
slickers yeah rather have to spend as
much easier right
yeah you guys you guys the chetniks
rescue
got Press aspen's
from Yahoo thanks bro but you guys came
out
thank you for coming out what is morning
here
don't forget your G after the show held
I know if I will then there's your me
some new stuff we've only heard about
the world-famous not kevin henthathen ok
ladies and gentlemen
continued wet snow
space by please come up here
come on please Hey
grab guys I just want a smartphone
welcome back to make it in any way gonna
be ok
yeah yeah I
unless if you do certain tricks first my
shirt guys CEO
are by the way are you doing everything
all the DVD's from
30 days coming up the stairs people
sitting now you're not hesitate
yeah pick a favorite female year TPT
go the way we do have a bridge if you'd
like to go on they're just going to run
at 989
I'm 272 7425
if you'd rather just wait a couple
minutes then there are the last
remaining told to them you know me and
you get to talk to people tonight they
have a hell on the brouhaha give your
own private presentation and that was
9 89 272 7425
glass its neighbor his
if thats I packet that really just a
risk
sprayer I
about everyone clapped around our house
and love you so
but I
way to 35 and ladies and gentlemen yeah
100 okay guys stay where you are Richard
II agent Steelers are coming up next and
I'm not there yet rated got Fastlane
I not doing other in the
see you guys on the mezzanine yeah I
heard that still
yachts he's never going to salsa
security and I
your addresses so please give that to
him please thank you
it was from the space guys is next I
think I month