so warm
thank you all for for cum
this talk I was worried that they're
only going to be champ evil in the room
because
and savages next door %uh but i really
appreciate your a
you being here um because I think this
is a really important topic
and the fact that you're here I helps
demonstrate and the fact that we're
that that I got to speak about this at
this conference helps demonstrate to you
our political system that there are
people that are concerned about that and
that is really important that's really
what I'm trying to do here
%uh so be over the basics
a US Customs
is randomly searching the contents
electronics devices at US border
checkpoints
I laptops PDAs cell phones digital
cameras
up you may be asked to review your
encryption key to them
I'm there are consequences if you do not
they could detain you they could sees
your device
I'm sometimes items have been seized
and return without explanation weeks or
months later a
the Association up corporate travel
executives which is kinda this lobbying
organization that tries to make
life easier for business travelers they
did a survey of their members they had a
hundred members respond to the survey
and seven %uh those respondents said
that they had had electronics seized
from them
by US customs at the border so these are
your business traveler's
a and I'm custom says
everyone is subject to risks CBP
inspection when they arrive in the US
about so I think
maybe twenty thirty years ago I we had
two things going on in this country we
have a drug or
I'm which are created what some people
refer to as the drug war exception to
the Constitution
a certain things are kinda overlooked
because %uh that system fault it was
useful for them to be able to
aggressively prevent narcotics
trafficking I'm at the same time
um the technology the people had access
to at that time
you know has has change dramatically I
today I people have these devices that
are increasingly powerful
have increasingly detailed records love
the correspondence
their thoughts arm and their their lives
and they carried them with them all the
time and that's really a new development
and so the policies that were developed
during the eighties
to deal with the drug war don't
necessarily make sense today with
today's technology in today's threats
are and so I'm there was a
you know get to this are a little bit
later but there was a Senate hearing
about this very subject a couple weeks
ago which is a positive development
on there was a guiding Peter Swire there
from the Center for American Progress
and he said this is an issue which may
be mobilised to preserve army of outrage
techies
well that sucks right so I that's why
I'm glad you all
are here and II it certainly
makes me angry I N and if it makes you
angry to you then then maybe we will
mobilize and and do something about it
um so well I'll get to that in a sec
so I before we get into the details I
was her personal story
I was once the subject about random a
border search by US Customs
I had been in Australia this is prior to
september 11th
I was on vacation and unfortunately I
had to cut my trip
up 'em early because I had a death in my
immediate family
and so I flew back to the United States
has flying into LAX
and me in my %uh sister were randomly
selected for search
at the border a and I'm no needless to
say I was kinda in a bad mood
a and you know I've got this these
people have decided to go through my
stuff and going through my bag right
and they hold up every single object in
the bag every
pair of underwear every t-shirt i holed
up in the season skiers
is this yours is this yours is this
year's
n it the the way that that questioning
work kinda freaked me out
because you get rolled into this sort
have automatic response
after the 20 or 30 s piece of clothing
is held up
you just gonna say yeah it's mine gets
mine
yes mine without paying attention and so
you know what they want to grab
something under the table on show to you
might say
match mine without really looking at it
first a
and that kinda bothered me wire--the why
the using this
assertive a a lot a system of
questioning that seems particularly
designed to elicit
and incorrect or false confession so I
was kinda pissed off
and I'm thinking I'm an American citizen
I'm on US soil this is the US government
that searching my stuff I was randomly
selected what's up with that
this should be a violation why Fourth
Amendment rights and I went and Google
that yet learned two things
the first thing is that Beanie Babies R
public enemy number one
I I what the first place I went was the
US Customs Service website
on this was a few weeks later after the
smoke cleared from everything I was
doing when I got back to the states
and the am the a
the they have a fact and the first item
in the fact on US Customs website at the
time
was why did you see is my beanie babies
at the time beanie babies were really
popular
and apparently there was no license
international distributor for them
then people would go over to taiwan or
whatever and the Red
be a bunch of look-alike beanie babies
available for sale on there would be
cheap and they take a
greatly by a bunch of them and bring
back in and they get searched by customs
and the BBB's would be seized
us so you know and I want to be fair
about this
obviously the US Customs Service is
looking for terrorists
%uh but the vast majority uva
above those kinda stuff that ends up
getting targeted by these guys when they
do the searches
is israel unilaterally property law a
and I i'm gonna get
into that and in more detail later on ad
hoc a but I think it's important to
understand that
arm as far as I know other two
terrorist um a discoveries that are
they're worth noting the first one
occurred in the year two thousand
are at New Years there was a guy coming
in a
in Vancouver on some ferry from Canada
and had a bunch of explosives using
drive down blow-up LAX
and a they've they caught him I'm
there's the information about that is
sketchy but
ugg its its did does not appear that it
was a random search
they had reason to suspect the guy and
the guy acted suspiciously when I
started questioning him
and %uh eventually they because he was
being suspicious and I think you try to
run away
they decided to go through stuff and
then they found explosives
um the some the second case I is a case
that happened inner
I'm see home um a said Minneapolis for
Minnesota
I'm the he if they had a guy
that they found for the system called
eighty ass which is a profiling system
so instead
again he was randomly selected for
search he was chosen by this profiling
system and there's debate about that
profiling system too but
in any event um they went through his
laptop and found a couple martyrdom
videos apparently and information about
how to create ID's and so
the use that as an example by this
profiling system works they might have a
point
the profiling system might work I how
neither of these people were
were found through random searches and
the question is
you know how likely is it that they're
gonna find a terrorist through a totally
random search purses
what impact are these random searches
going to have on people's freedom
so I'm the other thing I learned to are
I guess and I will I believe when I have
been search that it was a violation my
fourth member
right so I dug into this and I I learned
that the fourth member doesn't work the
way that I thought that at that
%uh this is the fourth amendment and it
says the right of the people to be
secure in their persons houses papers
and effects against unreasonable
searches and seizures shall not be
violated and no warrants shall issue but
upon probable cause
whitewater ball I hmmm so
the way to read this apparently is to
think about it as two clauses
the first clause says the right of the
people to be secure against unreasonable
searches should not be violated
the second clause says no warrants shall
issue but upon probable cause
but it doesn't say that you have to have
a warrant in order to poor form a search
for the dust work is required
in order to make a search reasonable.
apparently me
two hundred years ago we really didn't
have police the way we do today and the
founders didn't really consider the idea
that you might have police you might
need to do things
with out a specific warrant um
authorizing what they're doing
and so I'm they just sorta crafted it
this way and it at and over time we've
we have these these police officers the
that we've
these police forces we've developed and
we've given them from official 14 they
do all these things that require them to
perform surgeons
and and the result is that there are all
these cases where the courts have
decided to work isn't required
so I am one of those cases the border
search case in a media back to these two
case precedents later on in the talk
um but there's United States persons
ramsey in 1977
searches made at the border reason we're
simply by virtue of the fact that they
occur at the border
on because the reasonable work doesn't
require no unreasonable searches and
seizures
are and then there's this other case
from 85 routine searches
a person's effective entrance are not
subject to any requirement reasonable
suspicion probable cause or what
up I'm going the wrong way and you that
way
I'm so in addition business later on
they develop this
in the eighties the developed this up
this distinction between routine and
non-routine searches
routine searches can beef performed
random non-routine searches require
reasonable suspicion
the question is what is a routine search
and what is a non-routine search
and what is reasonable suspicion and
those are things that are still
sorted being defined I so do
when we ya got started with this an 85
the Supreme Court held that reasonable
suspicion is required to search
travelers elementary now I'm
this individual was smuggling cocaine in
condoms that they had swallowed
and they were held by customs for a few
days and hopes that they would expunge
them
I from their body I'm and the Supreme
Court found that
they couldn't do that at random they had
to have some reason to suspect that you
had swallowed cocaine balloons before
handcuffing you to a share for three
days us so
I'm dots a you know it's not reasonable
suspicion is not the strongest standard
in the world
it's not the same as probable cause are
here's an example from a court case the
suspect arrived from
Columbia they were traveling alone they
had only one suitcase they nothing to
declare
was a young clean looking attractive
woman wearing a shoe loose-fitting dress
from
reasonable suspicion she did in fact
have cocaine taped to her admin
at demand so arm
so you know that's not a very sort
stronger
basis for suspicion I'm and of course
this is the way whites get a row did
you these people going to court over and
over and over again with different
judges with the guilty party in AC we
had reasonable suspicion because I've
XYZ ridiculous criteria
and the judge either has to say wall
okay you had reasonable suspicion or
they have to let the guilty party go
and so generally speaking I'm they say
okay fine we're gonna cap that is
reasonable suspicion
and over time these things begin to
become contradictory I suspect was first
so the plane
class to the plane the plane from Middle
had one way tickets round trip tickets
a nonstop flight changed planes from
traveling alone
traveling with a companion acted
nervously acted Newcombe
we've I am years 01 other thing I say
but reasonable suspicion
suspect arrived from Germany am
traveling alone had only one backpack
and no items requiring customs
inspection
was carrying a laptop iPod Cell Phone
laser pointer radius Karen of electronic
parts and components and was wearing a
t-shirt that said 2600 the hacker
quarterly
reasonable suspicion Ceram
this is not a very strong standard so
there's two questions well one of them
is
do does a does a laptop art is a
forensic investigation laptop
um is a routine search doesn't require
reasonable suspicion
and I'm this is really the open question
today
are the most recent president is from
I the United States Supreme Court heard
the customs agents me would move the gas
tank from a vehicle crossing
international border in an effort to
look for contraband
and they may do that with at random I'll
so arm you know is a laptop
more like we know we know reasonable
suspicion is required to serve summons
elementary canal
we know it's not required to take the
gas tank of the car and take apart
what is a laptop search more like I
don't know it I guess it depends on
what's on your laptop
%uh the reasonable suspicion is such a
weak standard
you know who cares who cares if they
require reasonable suspicion white
there's two reasons to care
the first is that the Canton happen at
random if they require it
which means it will happen less
frequently and won't be quotas
I think that the randomly searched the
bags have about
are one to two percent of everyone that
comes into the United States
%uh so if you think that there's like
three other people on a 747
then that's like three to six people of
every plane
um so thats actually pretty frequent I'm
if if it if it requires reasonable
suspicion that you won't have that
nearly that many people being searched
a and I'm the other thing is that if
they can't do it
at random the making dua to everyone and
so so you
you've got the solid state storage
devices coming out I'm
you know say you know you have some
breakthrough in technology
and it becomes really efficient to
duplicate a hard drive you can do it in
a few seconds
let's say that happens I if you bring
arm all address questions after the
after the talk but if you you know if if
we get there
then you can have a situation where
people are bringing laptops in
and all the contents are being copied
I'll
and so warm that would be a quite scary
I think
a so before I get into our
there's the recent court case on this
issue I wanted take a step back and just
look at this legal framework because
I'm not sure that what was decided in
the late seventies and early eighties
made any sense
if you go back to this case that I
mentioned in 1985 it says
routine searches are the person said if
accident rates are not subject to
any requirement reasonable suspicion
that's what they say
that's the time when they're really
officially said it was 85
rRNA reference this footnote in not in
the
in the Supreme Court decision footnote
says see United States v ramzi
and a buncha dicta thats my warning I'm
details when the supreme court has this
issue that they're assessing and
they decide to say something about
something else
and it doesn't relate to the issue
they're deciding it's not really
I'm necessary hope for their holding but
it's an indicator for future with a
conserved how they might
how they might I'm make a decision and
there's all this dick to around border
searches where
US Supreme Court was talking about
someone getting search and they make
this comment like more of this was at
the border it would be different because
it wasn't
this is how we're gonna do things here
um and these these comments were sorta
brought up that that made various times
in history Supreme Court said things
would be different at the border
as a justification for the idea that
there are no rules at the border
Armando much for that makes so much
sense I but it makes the most sense to
focus on
the actual place where they were looking
at a broader search and made a binding
decision about a border search
and that was USB ramzi and USB ramzi
they said the congress
they're trying to justify the idea that
they don't need a warrant at the border
and they say the congress which proposed
the bill of rights including the fourth
amendment
to state legislatures in 1789 had
some two months prior to that and acted
the first custom statute
in out alive 79 and this statute custom
great in customs officials Paul
full power and authority to enter and
search any ship or vessel
in which they shall have reason to
suspect any goods wares or merchandise
subject to duty shall be concealed
so Inc in in 1789
they passed this law that said that the
customers can search things that they
have a reason to suspect
might contain contraband and the Supreme
Court is using that law
as a justification for a policy in
nineteen
85 that says that no reasonable
suspicion is required
in that to me is fundamentally a logical
I'm
if they're is a historic basis for the
assertion
that that the founding fathers did not
believe the customs officials needed
reasonable suspicion that fourth
amendment required reasonable suspicion
to border
it certainly wasn't established in this
case I'm and and there's more research
that needs to be done but unfortunately
this is what has happened
you have this court that makes this
claim and a couple of other courts
reference this in
they make little modifications to it and
now we have this policy that says they
can be random searches and that really
came outta nowhere as far as I can tell
on someone with the more about
background in the history of the
the founding of this republic might have
some interesting references that relate
to it but no one has done any
that research as far as I know I'm so
here's a Supreme Court case that
well no it's not sorry this is a court
case that's going on right now
are it was recently decided i buy the
night circuit appellate court it is
still sorta been process and I'll talk
about its status %uh but it gives you
good example of how these things happen
I'll US persons on old on July 17 2005
this guy came in LA axe
I'm from the Philippines he was selected
for secondary screening
a he was vacationing for with friends in
the Philippines
um they asked him to look at his
computer he booted it up
%uh there were so Kodak pictures in
Cuttack memories directories on his hard
drive
they started clicking on the customs
agents started clicking on this folders
and opening the pictures
and one of them had a picture that
depicted to nude women
now a pic no one has ever established as
far as I know import that those
are women were not adult women are in it
and what are the
I guess that's how important has a
footnote in there in their decision
where they say
customs did not establish that the is
that this was child pornography as far
as
um as far as anyone knows those were
picture for adult women
up in any event the the investigator
called
a %uh the Department of Homeland
Security and Customs Enforcement and all
these people came in the question this
guy for several hours and they started
going through sup up in more detail in
virtually they did find child
pornography
a so this since the this raises the
question Nov
you know how many hours love
interrogation what you got if you happen
to have a
the porter a legal pornographic picture
on your hard drive
um in this case he also had illegal
pornographic pictures on his hard drive
on so he got charged I and he was
convicted
and then know that the district court
%uh however decided that term
a so there's this force month had okay
switches from 2004
um and and it it to it it decided that
term
%ah you know it was legal for customs to
take the gas tank of a car and take it
apart
I look at its contents without any
suspicion they could do that random
on and there's two different courts here
who have serve decided this
Arnold case on the basis of that that
gas tank decision
won the Miss the district court with and
they decided that that the gas tank case
implied that there are certain context
in which you have real privacy interests
that might require I'm a heightened
suspicion from custom service before
they can violate the privacy interests
and so they decided that reasonable
suspicion was required to search the
laptop
the night circuit arm meet another
or that they they have a different view
really the opposite view based on the
same case
I'll they I guess prior to 2004 had been
employing
this intrusiveness analysis to determine
whether or not
you know a search was justified at the
border and
they felt that this gas tank cases
served throughout their intrusive this
analysis approach in that they had to
allow any search for property
and so they said reasonable suspicion is
not needed all these laptops searches
are legal
with no reasonable suspicion at all I'll
so I I don't agree with this night
circuit holding and I'm gonna pick it
apart a little bit
I'm they say I'll the they talk about it
as if its property and the people who
support this policy who want these
random searches happening
they use all fours montano into contact
with the talk about
property in general and that case if you
read it very specifically limit itself
to the context vehicles and searches
vehicles
I'm on wiki pedia it says %uh
complex balancing test to determine the
paraphrases the the Supreme Court cases
complex balancing test to determine what
is routine
and what is intrusive have no place in
border searches irv
property in a property in brackets in
Wikipedia
the actual word in the Supreme Court
doren in the supreme court decision is
vehicles and not property
and so it's possible that this and this
this rule only applies in the context
the vehicles and doesn't apply for
laptops at all
but the sort of the circle logical
sleight of hand is
used in order to expand the scope at
this decision
%uh the the night circuit the
the the force montana okay said that
there were context in which a search was
particularly offensive and therefore
would require reasonable suspicion
a search of an alimentary canal for
example %uh the night circuit
decided that um that that the
particularly offensive or did not apply
in the context of a laptop search
in the the reasoning the use was sloppy
the
the they compare it to this case
involving a mobile home
and there's decision that that they
could search a mobile home without
getting a warrant
because mobile homes are mobile and so
if there you go to the park if they want
to search this mobile home
and they call into our to get a warrant
someone to drive the mobile home to a
different jurisdiction
and then there were or apply know what
people search in anymore %uh so the
the court decided that they were able to
search mobile homes without getting a
warrant but they still had to establish
probable cause in order to do it and if
it turned out that they hadn't really
establish that
then retrospect the evidence would be
for an out-of-court
I and but um you know in that case the
person was saying we need to work
because
its mobile but it is my home I am so the
plights now since laptop
who said it's the same situation it's a
because you can carry it with you I'm no
warm no suspicion is required to search
in that analysis that
analogy doesn't make any sense I the
first is the fifth
excuse me my thoughts trying out a
little bit something was going water
that would be awesome
um but anyway the the first issue is
that
um a vehicle
a even though the vehicle are was
readily mobile and therefore they
couldn't they didn't have to go through
the process of getting this warning
which takes time are they still had to
establish thank you very much the study
established probable cause an order
search the vehicle standard suspicion
didn't change
because the because the mobile homes
mobile it was just the process that they
had to go through in order to establish
that standard
that changed in this case there's no
time to lay involved in assessing
whether or not reasonable suspicion
exists versus having a random search
I'll so the whole concept that that time
delay could cause you to have the object
move to a different jurisdictions
doesn't apply here it so it makes
absolutely no sense
duh to to use this this precedent in
this context
it's almost it's really confusing to
read it almost confusing to explain
because
because it it makes little rational
sense it's for sloppy
I I personally have this this opinion
that
the 9th circuit they got this case the
saw this guy he's a pedofile he was
traveling overseas he might've been
doing it for in order to molest children
he's really a bad guy
a they got this case arm you know
there's evidence against him
and then they have this this this
constitutional appeal where they say
well they shouldn't be able to search
his laptop and they're like
whatever you know I I just don't think
they took it very seriously and that
kinda threw together the sloppy decision
that says
you know case closed he's going to jail
and and
I i don't know if they took it very
seriously I have heard this rumor
I'll that that and I i SR confirm that I
i really am not aware so I don't know
exactly how this works but I for that
they've
decided to do an on blank a a review of
this decision
and so the night circuit might be
issuing different decision in this case
I don't know why they're able to do that
but there was after this decision was
handed down a few months later there was
a Senate hearing
and so they might have said you whew
wait a minute maybe someone does care
about this decision and hey which was
that we did a real sloppy job with it so
maybe we'll go back and take another
look
up arm so mmm
my problem I hope all get to that minute
actually
I'm there's this other policy
development in addition to that case as
far as I know that case was decided by
the night circuit tonight circuit said
laptop searches are legal
and everyone who wants reading laptop
searches is you know celebrating that
decision
some people have come forward in the
Senate hearing in spite of how sloppy it
wasn't said
we think this was a very good decision
%ah um
the other shoe is this
anti-counterfeiting trade agreement
which was leaked to the press on May
22nd
it's this treaty and we all know that
that one other things the intellectual
property interest will do is is getting
international treaty signed that defends
their interests
I'm because once a treaty is signed all
these countries are are are beholden to
a two to enforce it
and arm it gets approved without going
through the normal democratic processes
in each others countries
%uh so you know Congress doesn't
necessarily have the same kind a debate
about enforcing a treaty that they would
if these people
should have proposed the same rules as a
local like I'm United States law
so one they're trying to do that with
this any cut any counterfeiting trade
agreement and
no one's really sure exactly what this
thing says are
I'm there were just some details about
it that were leaked but
not the full taxed I and were there's
this
get a data card Asus newspaper they part
they said
this deal would create an international
regulator that would turn border guards
and other public security personnel
into copyright police security officials
will be charged with checking laptops
iPods and even so your phones for
content that infringes on copyright laws
such as rip CDs or movies
at so you know I think that if they
looked at your iPod that there's no way
they could tell
that those mp3's were legal or not but
if they get in if you they got your
laptop today when you're running bare
share something like that
you haven't outgoing director an
incoming director in this but your files
and directories
you know I think that that's probably
reasonable doubt that you had shared
those things
so I'm you know there really are they
may be really be talking about having
custom searches
customs official start searching laptops
for mp3's
half so what has happened will there or
not the case gets
appeal to the Supreme Court I mean it
will be appealed to the Supreme Court he
get I hope so
but it's possible that they won't arm
everyone will
apparently there's been a there's been a
few decisions that have related to
laptop searches and
I'm for various technical reasons no
court
a throughout a laptop search I'm this
decision was
specifically about whether that laptop
search could be done without reasonable
suspicion
and the court did not throw the old the
the at night circuit
you know I upheld the search and so a
lot of people were thinking what the
supreme court's not going to take this
because on there seems to be a consensus
across districts again that's a
that's a few advocated by the people
that like these laptops searchers
and it's possible that because there is
a Senate hearing about this that may be
the supreme court will take it
we'll see on they get to decide are
The Washington Post has reported that
law firms are asking employees to travel
to keep two laptops
a travel laptop that doesn't have any
data on it hand and when there when
they're
traveling overseas the only put the
information on that laptop that they
need for that meeting
um some other corporations are doing
similar things
Jennifer Granik posted advice for
travelers and you talk about that a
little bit more detail
are the EFSF wrote an open letter to
Congress shortly after the night circuit
health handed down the moral decision
and they said hold a hearing
and and what's awesome is that they did
the Senate held a hearing on June 20th
%uh so that's that's great news I'm and
the FF is also out joint filed a Freedom
of Information Act two to learn more
about border search practices
well there's some there's a a group I'll
there's a group that represents
muslim-americans that testified at the
Senate Judiciary Committee
and they had a lot of fun ver
interesting testimony about
the kinds of things that their members
happens subjected to
there's an example if the guy that wrote
an editorial for the
up a the Toledo Blade a
that was critical of US government
policy and he showed up at a border
checkpoint
and he was searched in the border guards
like to picked up this
editorial started asking him questions
about his political views
um so things like that are are pretty a
pre questionable and so on
on Thursday there some additional
context around that's where they they
think that certain people are being
unnecessarily
and unfairly single out um so
before we go on with the the policy
discussion you know what can you do to
protect yourself from getting
your personal stuff searched at the
border I one thing that people wonder is
we're all just encrypt my files right
well they couldn't as I said earlier on
they can ask you for your incursion keys
are there was a federal court that ruled
recently
it's not the Supreme Court but they've
they ruled that you have a fifth member
right to refuse to reveal your password
its you know you have a right not to
incriminate yourself
but there are people who don't agree
with that ruling or in care she's a law
professor at GW he's very smart guy
but up you know he often I think
sometimes he he sides with the
the authorities used to be a a the
public justice prosecutor
but he said the the password itself is
not incriminating only the information
to protect
and so the fifth amendment can protect
the password and
that's his I don't agree with that
reasoning but he he's a serious guy has
seriously be that argument
and that argument might 0 end up being
upheld by the courts
um so for now its its it's an
interesting
subjective if it comes up again the
course will consider a further
a the agents could detain you for days
I'm
they could seize your laptop and send
you on your way they seem to do that
rather frequently
even if they even if we don't have an
issue where you refusing to turn over a
password
um they can also deny you entry in the
US they could tell you go back
um its I don't know and and no one has
delved into this into much detail
if you are a US citizen its apparently
difficult for them to absolutely deny
you entry into the country
I'm sure that the customs agents could
tell you to get to go back in
yeah so
to eight with that could be an
interesting a occur for full if it
actually occurred
um so there's this thing called
TrueCrypt that that term
people are using II with this is my
personal view and TrueCrypt
and number one customs forensics agents
are computer savvy the certainties
aren't
she points to bed I trigger can be
detected
even in travel mode by inspecting the
registry if I was a customs
agent and I was expecting people to do
this I would look for that registry key
a the the trooper bootloader can be
detected just released this new version
through capital I should have a complete
operating system that hidden in your
bootloader select Set but of course the
the bootloader is a in going the master
boot record on your
on your hard drive and they could check
for it with the with a friend 6 wall so
they can detect that you're using this
and so what do you what happens when
they detected well you can't deny that
there's a hidden no answer hidden file
system
and they can detain you a and that they
could detain you for several days hoping
that your fess up
%uh so that's on that's not fun and I
don't recommend I def we don't recommend
lying to customs
you don't wanna become the murder for a
order searchers
um the other thing a the other thing I
mean there may be other steganography
that's more effective depending upon
what they're looking for in with her
what their techniques and tactics are
and I don't know what their their
techniques and tactics are necessarily
arm are I kept out this guy's last name
a is so horny in so kahan
aka Christopher so kahan this is a very
sort of practical approach from a
logical standpoint
he said that I wipe your laptop you know
encrypt your data and put a file server
and then go we're going
download this encrypt the data block
over the Internet
the crib that use it and then reprinted
in rio uploaded and what your laptop
again for your back on a plane
this works I'll and and this I what I
like about this is it really points out
the absurdity of this whole policy
because you can use a process like this
to completely avoid having any
information with you when you physically
cross the border
but this is not a this is not a very a
practical
way to approach this problem for most
people it's very very slow
%uh in it in its a um it you know it's
it's very difficult to to to live this
way a
but I think we should do instead is
advocated policies change
I that's really why I'm here I we should
not be afraid to fly overseas with our
laptops
I and and I also think that it's
important to get the policy right we
constantly in the scene
get into these situations where we think
the government is doing something wrong
it's what we do is we develop these
technologies that allow you to get away
with it anyway
and the problem is that that the bad
people there are bad people out there
are bad people who end up using these
technologies to
are and the fact that there's a lot of
innocent people using them great all
discover traffic for the bad stuff
right a so if we actually had good
policy
that said that you know we were not this
is America were not randomly searching
people
%uh innocent people wouldn't feel like
they would need to use TrueCrypt a
and I'm you know it the fact is that
term we wouldn't end up providing tools
to people who are actually up to no good
so I'm you know i i think that their
there really is a good argument for
for getting the policy right um and and
I have several arguments on a present
them
I because those view her interest in the
subject to go out into the internet and
at least one of you is going to end up
in an argument with someone about this
so should know with the would sure some
hear some ammunition for that
a pending argument the first is that I
love the there these guys say will
Customs has this historical
ability to search any piece of luggage
coming into the united states and
a laptop is no different from a
businessman's briefcase it's the same
thing
and we should use the same policies that
we always have I will I disagree with
that computers are not just like luggage
by default luggage contains nothing and
you only packed the things you want to
bring in your trip
computers containing everything the
canteen all your correspondence
all your personal information and and
the only way that you can Collins them
for trip is to remove things that you
don't want the customs to see
%uh that's a totally different process
and it's actually very difficult to do
I'm technology has changed the scope of
personal information that people carry
with them these devices is
X massively expanded over the past ten
years
hand and as I said earlier these drug
war era rationalizations that we need to
search the stuff in order to find
cocaine
you know just don't make sense in this
high-tech context it's completely
different
um John Perry Barlow once famously said
in this is Ben
paraphrased by a lot of people you can
have my encryption algorithm when you
pry my cold dead fingers from its
private key
people do not want to show up at the
border and have some customs agent ask
them for their Krypton key
day you know and and frankly I can
understand the
in the indignation of people who would
save you know fuck you I'm not telling
you what my password as
I'll that's why it that's my privacy or
violating and you know unfortunately
people who
who do stand up to these customs agents
and say no I'm not giving you my key
you know they might end up getting
detained they might end up having their
equipment seized with the same time a
kind understand a perspective I think
it's
you know to a certain extent it's a
brave thing to do I'll
you know it and um Peter Swire from CAP
when he was testifying at the senate
amid he drew an analogy between this
debate in the clipper chip debate from
the early nineteen nineties
he said this is very similar we're
asking for access to people's private
information we're asking
for access to their crib today to and
you know people might
necessarily resist that pretty strongly
I'll
you know I don't believe that the fourth
amendment with the Fourth Amendment says
I think that when the fourth member says
unreasonable searches that means no
searches without a reason
means no random searches that's what I
think a I certainly don't think
that there's some integrated the
sovereign to rain we search people stuff
that applies the United States
I'm if it does exist it certainly has
been proven by the case presents that
that that we have I think a very sketchy
I showed you in this presentation why I
think they're sketchy
I and and they're from the late
seventies and early eighties are not
from
you know the 1780s I in the law on the
17 eighties
required reasonable suspicion and I
think are require reasonable suspicion
that
I and further more random searches are
inefficient this is something even
though
the the conservatives on the site on the
in this debate will concede that that
you know this is not the right way to
find terrorist this is not the right way
to find
drug traffickers you should find you
have a reason to suspect people you
should focus limited resources
on the people that you have a reason to
suspect a
this is this is this what I what I
consider that most gapping form
in the reasoning behind this entire
thing people don't smuggling formation
in laptops the smoke alarm over the
Internet
I'll we all know this if customs were
real was really working on some sort of
copper hits a plan to prevent the
smuggling of illegal information
they would be surveilling international
telecommunications links and not
searching people laptops the border
this whole thing is just a loophole in
the law that was created the final
product
to applying laptops is not a
comprehensive policy
with their going out there and trying to
prevent information smuggling it bears
no resemblance to such a policy
are this same in with information that
they claim the right to investigate
when it on your laptop at the border
would be protected by a work requirement
if it was being sent over the Internet
the the Faiza
in particularly the recent update defies
a even made this
me this this what reform more onerous
for the police that was before with the
car in the context of American citizens
a so so it makes absolutely no sense
that that if I send it over the Internet
they have to get a warrant but if I
bring it on
on floppy disk they can take a look at
it that's ridiculous a
and so I I advise you to do I two things
the first is
potentially contactor congresspersons a
and and you know be respectful when you
do this don't be an asshole
no one likes assholes I'll you know 3
if you're talking to remember the
central district many a
thank them for holding a hearing it's
very important they did and in
do you know on both sides of the aisle
other perspectives offered at that
hearing were very balance
%uh there's concern all around about the
privacy issues here
senators have blackberries and they have
laptops and they get searched when they
go places like
china for example and they're concerned
about that and if we do the same thing
in the United States would have a hard
time arguing the tradition do it
and so I'm this is something that is
really a concern for them and and and
that's one of the ways we might win this
argument that that those people share
our same worries
I'll you know tell them that custom
should not be allowed to perform
searches of laptops without reasonable
suspicion
it's very simple unreasonable suspicions
on a very high standard
it's not going to stop them from busting
bad people a and and I would also ask
you to tell them
that customs must perform privacy impact
assessment we don't know
how many searches are really going on we
don't know how many people been targeted
we don't know how much equipment seized
we don't know if the date on that cures
been copied or how long it's been stored
who's being
whose has access to it but it's being
used for are these are very interesting
questions
are and I think the public has a right
to know is there some
the huge are you know hard drive
repository somewhere in some customs
%uh building that has all kinds of hard
drives from the
seven-percent a business travelers were
having their their laptop seized
I every once in a while there should be
a mining the stuff is that happening
it could be and no one knows because no
public communication has been issued
about it so
we need to know a there's that the
Center for American Progress watch this
campaign
on Thursday its called hints of my
laptop dock
harm %ah the what their
this is like up server a serve a writing
campaign you you go to the website and
there's a form there and you can fill it
out and click send
handed sends comments to you the US
customs service
%uh in it asks them to perform that
privacy impact assessment that I mention
are there's a guy from cap here on he
told me that they have had
1700 different people sign up
a use this form in the past you know few
days the stings looks like Thursday or
Friday
us so that's pretty impressive I'm you
know if if
if we go out me mention our blogs in
like
a you know you could see a substantial
about people a
I'm North responding to this thing and
and that could have a big impact on
the perception that this is a niche
issue I'm you know that people need to
understand that
that there are a lot of people were
concerned about this are fortunately I
along those lines there was a also a New
York Times editorial about the subject a
few weeks ago so that was also help for
I and so well II before I i going to
questions
I i have one other comment about the
subject in general
and that is that you know people always
say you know I with
if you're not a criminal you've got
nothing to hide you know why are you
concerned about your privacy interest if
you're not up ten
no good right um and and a you know I'm
iris really thinking about that as a
ritz presentation so I wrote this this
this
ending comment and I think you know its
it's not really about whether or not
you've got something to hide
its it's about whether or not you have
to think about it I'll
a criminal lives life looking over
shoulder he doesn't he knows he's up to
no good he knows he could be targeted
for
because he's up to no good he knows
people are gonna be watchin em
and so he's got a costly a you to take
care of everything that he does he's got
a look and see if he's being spied upon
and
you know put things on urs mattress
Sarah yes to live in fear
a min users 11 for is up to no good a
business in people
should not have to live in fear a and
and and if they if there is a
if they're if they're being targeted by
the police at random
the mean you have to think every time
they do something you know
is this something that could be
misconstrued by the police when they go
through it are they gonna
they can get the wrong idea about us you
know what are they going to say if they
look at this maybe I just don't want you
know this item on here because I don't
want some
summoned some customs agent to look at
it just because it's I it's personal and
I
you know i i don't feel it's like it's
any other business now I think about it
every email I send every
every documents for my hard drive I
think what is customs gonna think about
this when I see it
and overtime you know this becomes
disorder self-censorship mechanism that
becomes in green people's heads
sir this is what happens in a press
societies and people become
a very paranoid and and the fact is that
they're
their their lives become diminished they
become dominated by the sphere
and and that's really what we're
fighting at it will change the nature of
our society or change we r and and and
that's why we can't allow this to
to go on so that's that's that's my talk
um so thank you very much for your time
is very important
the draw here listening listening to
this and that you took time out
to focus on this because it helps
communicate that this is important
I will take questions if you gottem some
ok solak question
arm there's an interesting approach to
data encryption that applies to the
subject
and there's a I Linux kernel module that
implements
it's called a rubber hose encryption
aren
the idea is today you have to pry the
keys
one day d crips the data in such a way
that
it's fake data and it's what you want
their depicting party to see
and then you have your real by the key
that the crips your real data is so i
was just wondering
what your opinion is on that approach
that's I mean it devil's in the details
and so I'm not familiar with that kinda
my droid have to go look it up and thank
you for
for mentioning it but it to it all
depends upon
up you know whether or not they can tell
that that tools running
if they know that tools running even if
they don't know um
that the that their secret data there
I it implies that their secret data
there and that gives them
a pretense with which to put pressure on
you
and the perturbing be be very
uncomfortable even if they don't
end up reading your your private
information might be better off having
them go through your email them to have
them put you in a room for three days
so that's something that that you are to
consider
I'm for fall excellent presentation
thank you thank you are just one quick
comment this doesn't change the problem
affected by any means
but may help somebody in a pitch I've
had my laptop searched randomly
several times in the airport I've never
had my flashdrive searched if it's in my
pocket
goes through with Mikey is nobody ever
bother so you know 12
20 gigs will fit in something like this
and its
it's never been searched yet so you
might wanna put your crib that stuff on
here and then your
less important stuff on a laptop for a
trip
I am i nichols et with the Center for
American Progress I just like to fill
some folks in on some details with the
I hands off my laptop action campaign if
you go to the page
%uh right now it pretty much just asks
for are
a bunch of your personal information so
I'd like to tell you what
radically for I like your address and
name and stuff like that
basically what we what what we're doing
is is where we're are very strategically
pushing them to do a privacy impact
assessment are specifically the CDP
upper management we're targeting the
are Commissioner Deputy Commissioner
chief-of-staff media relations and the
international travel specialists
and %uh basically if we can get them to
do a impact analysis we
we force them to talk about it and the
discussion space grows wider and that
will all play out on the hill better
are we directly talk to are the
lawmakers on the hill about this as well
it's not just
email flack and if you sign up for the
action campaign
down the road whenever we have to make
our next 30 jerk move like maybe six
months from now it's not a privacy
impact assessment were looking for but
it's something else that we need to keep
it moving
will email you back and tell you hey
this is the next thing you can do to
help this process along
are the numbers I got recently as OVR
Friday afternoon we had
1700 respondents if that are follows our
normal trends
it'll be about 7,000 by the end of the
week are so I really want to encourage
you to sign up for this
are we do really safeguard your privacy
are we think the odds have you winding
up on some type of watch list because
I've
getting on this action campaign is very
low and frankly if it happened it kinda
be a strategic win for us because
a lot of media people are on that are on
that seem less a lot lawmakers are on
that list and
a a lot of Pol you influential so just
thank you for your support
and and this important issue
hi thanks for such a a looser talk but I
am I I came in a bit late sometime
apologize if you dressed as but regards
the efficiency a random searches and
suggestion that we
you know you target people who are
suspicious and behavior and
you know is is have you heard the
carnival booth out with them and how
that might be
displays a weakness in that kind of up
screening so it was a very briefly the
idea is that
terrorist and operate in cells and this
is used as an argument against some %uh
that don't fly and profiling activity
so if normally USART randomly 5 percent
the time
you think I know on the target the bad
guys who list and I gotta do
Ste to my resources so that you know ten
twenty percent out the suspicious people
get searched
and only two percent of your regular
folks get searched
and then what happens is the terrorist
cell can go four dat start sending
people through clean
just absolutely no they're not really
about that is fine on the country
and eventually they will work out which
one of them are flagged in the system
for which one of them identified as
suspicious
and which one or not and the problem
happens is them because you no longer
around
researching you've dropped your chances
of detecting them from
120 which we five percent to maybe 150
which would be you know two percent or
something similar
so in that case and i cant for random
searches as opposed to trying to
more targeted searches such interest is
here response was to that
this interesting I i havent to so that
did you see the carnival booth
up
okay I well um I i yah I don't have a
key in the answer to that
um so you know I one thing I will point
out
is that there is this thing called ATS
which is automated targeting system
it's a pretty basic profiling tool that
customs uses at US borders it looks at
things like
when you buy your ticket what your name
is um you know what your what phone
number you gave
what address you gave it cetera et
cetera on your undertake at
it's been the subject of a fair amount
of controversy there's we are conflicts
between it and you privacy laws there's
privacy groups and US you who thought it
was a a
too expensive are and at least a few
years ago I think some changes were made
to I'm not sure if everyone's cool with
it now or not
up but you know they'd they did identify
one individual
are who came into you I %uh the United
States in in minnesota or Minneapolis
nurse Minnesota a you know through
through this process so
so they did identify somebody this way
the
the number I've terrorist in verses the
whole number people that are traveling
in this country
every day is extremely small and so
you know it you you may find that it's
very very difficult to to to actually
happen to find someone repulsive what
are the mir using when you really look
at the the real numbers but a
II will take a look at it thanks for
bring that up
I appreciated your presentation as a
civil rights and criminal defense
attorney though I wanted to point out
that the distinction that you made
between I
innocent people having a look over their
shoulder and criminals
you suggested on might have to look over
their shoulders
i think is too fast so and maybe you you
were thinking in terms of
real criminals hardened criminals
terrorists but apart from the fact the
criminals have rights too
of course the distinction between
criminal an innocent
on is much more nuanced than really
breaks down me not only do we have
I increasing numbers flagrantly
unconstitutional
criminal statutes in this country these
days measured against any
any reasonable standard of what's
constitutional means so much so
I me really gone through the
looking-glass even in trying to discuss
these things
on in a kinda constitutional framework
I'm but they're there
myriad ways I mean you know this isn't
the the place to address the myriad ways
in which
on seizure a private material can be
used against people
who are technically technically broken
laws under some stature but used for
really insidious and military is
purposes I mean probing
you know what what really announce to
thought crime in prosecutions the target
people for ideas in speeches
I'm and constitute full frontal assaults
on the first amendment is this
I I absolutely agree with with I think
both the arguments for making I think me
two distinct ones
are I guess the reason I can focus on
them in that particular statement is
that I think the people who raise the
objection that if you're not a criminal
you've nothing to hide
you know believe that the police are
always up forthright in what they're
doing
a and and believe that the laws that we
have are always reasonable
are and I neither those assumptions is
cracked but
a you know i i think there are you even
if you accept those two assertions
that there are there reasons why you
might reject a policy
I've freedom searches and so basically
that's the reasoning for
for the way they represent things but
thank you thank you for saying that
I just once it's really not at the
border anymore
if you're traveling a college student
upstate New York Syracuse and where
their
if they're not very white author Asian
if they're dark
they will be pulled off that bus the
CEREC use bus station
that's a long way from the Canadian
border by Homeland Security
and custom and they will ask you for
your papers
%uh there was a a decision that said
that the the border zone
extends to several hundred miles outside
order
as long as like its customs officials in
the are they claim to be on some sort of
Porter related business
them you know like the pool this
specific hotfix was a car that was
pulled over
vermont like a hundred miles from the
border a an eight they argue that it was
a border search well I'm a professor at
the University up there
and they particularly when for anyone
that was for looking
and they went down the aisle the bus and
said where are your pet perks
their to everybody so
I now but there was the students got
pretty test of a meter
they were very shocked at that served as
to be aware
runnin close to then the time folks but
all
the questions until they kick us out yep
I got okay one more special quick
questions one
sorry want
all which well than a I came
fear from Chicago via Amtrak
and in erie pennsylvania Border Patrol
also gets on the Amtrak train
and asks everyone me you know are you an
american
in if you say no they asked for your
papers you know can make stand
searching your stuff to that till when
you're
why not near a border that's a that's an
interesting question
I hadn't I didn't know that I hadn't
read I've never read a case
about that a but that that implies that
the question hasn't been answered
so so it may be but something that could
they could at least get away with until
they had a quarter told in the couldn't
yeah are so well anyway I guess I gotta
call this but thank you very much for
your time and I'll be happy to profit
good
not really a question just just a quick
comment missing
is