New York you almost made it through the
first day
it'll be dark soon but don't leave
there's plenty more common
check out the Robert steals
books if you like got the DVD purchase
area is gonna be selling them through
midnight minus a minute or two tomorrow
night when the heat is on for hours
multi-hour spy improv tel aviv exciting
later on tonight got a couple things in
this room in the fourth track
we got a extravaganza
film all high the things going on make
sure your
plan to hang around up next is
understanding
complexity ressie some
locks I think is Marco get your name
the white talk to my sorry another
yeah welcome everyone thank you 30
good afternoon everybody I we're gonna
talk today about
undoing complexity and high security
locks I'm great turnout this afternoon
thanks for all common
I'm we were talking a little while ago
about how to start this off
and we thought we started off the way we
started off an 18-month Odyssey
research project that ended in the
release of a book last week
on cracking medical high-security locks
many have you this morning word John
King's lecture
on asthmatic order and this is a
continuation I
and so what we really thought we would
do about to start the
festivities this afternoon I'm we have
and let me introduce everybody this is
Tobias blues man s my co author
are our medical book I
toby is from Venezuela lives in Miami
and as a locksmith for
about what twenty years fifteen years
your steers to be
yeah is no longer working I and
and work for a medico art dealer for
about ten years and is intimately
familiar with medico
I had actually contacted me a
in my capacity as a lawyer a couple
years ago
on a decoder the the reinvented for
medical and we became
really close friends and embarked on our
research project this is Matt fiddler
we've lectured a number of times here
before
and so we're gonna talk about the real
world of high security and I'm doing
complexity
what we thought we would do is introduce
this
I'm we have some medical cylinders here
both profile from Europe
and US these are all six PN medical
locks they're all factory standard
this 16 actually is a the
profile so nurse from Europe for fiber
in the US for 6 p.m.
I we've got a a deadbolt so under
and we've got a mortise cylinder these
are both 6 p.m.
here we're opening these were bumping
now you have to keep in mind these are
bomb proof locks
I according to the manufacture we're
opening these with one
a4 keys that we derive from our research
little virtually open any
biaxial RM three cylinder in the world
that's non master key aide that lock is
open
now I what this this here's an
with everybody medical challenge us and
so there's nothing in these locks
I this is the same kinda lock that the
12-year-old girl opened at Def Con last
year when we spoke out there
this is a high-security medico cylinder
bombproof math and Toby has got
a profile so longer and while these guys
are opening those were gonna try to open
this one
and then or explain why it so difficult
and we thought we'd begin this way
this what's up
help her do this while
talk and then we'll explain why this so
that that's how this research project
began
I I had met with medico a
we used to be are really friendly basis
a long-term
I not anymore unfortunately
I'm not really our desire but that's the
way it turned out
and so Toby and I embarked on an
18-month project
once we figured out that we could bump
open
America so under as we go through this
medico had a press release on August 4th
after we introduce general into the
world at Def Con
I medical announcer locks were bomb
proof
I am not okay now
let me explain to you Toby just open
this lock normally we can do this
in about 15 seconds training
okay because I'm I'm a little bit
disappointed that's that's our normal
time
I the distinguishing feature how many
have you read John's lecture this
morning
okay good show good show up
this lock has four AR expand Senate
these are these are the AR expend so we
loaded the seas were supplied to us from
a senior representative medical I this
is a brand new profile so under
for AR expense one would be enough
there's 40 from
we can routinely open this we're not
saying we can open all of them
but if anyone in the security field or
that has security responsibility here
thinks that air expands our the
answer they're really not it's the
and have the beginning rather than the
beginning of the end
and so they it is a problem it does not
solve all the problems
and so what we're gonna talk about today
is reality and high security locks in
complexity
Matt switches over I'm so it
as as Mark said we're gonna go through
some background will try not to
duplicate too much that john didn't come
through his talk
I bullets let's get to some mechanical
locks are typically
the for security fair barrier I as John
talked about and people ask questions
you know what what locks Ron Jon's house
I often they're the only security
barrier barrier
on and you have to ask yourself you know
what are you protecting I and what sort
of time axis
we should be considered to to have
protected an entity
I most locks to appear secure
as you look at these locks as you look
at the profiles of the key ways to them
they look very very difficult I but many
are not
I you have to understand the ratings
were gonna get into some the
you l 437 be hman and see ratings
and what those mean for high security
locks and I will dive into the layers
security I relieved the methodology by
which
we're able to go through and
systematically defeat these locks
I will talk about disclosure full
disclosure
on and you know the impact you the
manufacturers to the consumers
on the manufactures don't often no I and
often don't disclose these defects on
you know the question to you is is why
someone else just
open on I am why is this important well
many of you r are in it. and from
from an IT security perspective I'm it's
incumbent upon you to
protect your your information your your
server rooms
I so it's so it's important that
that you realize the risk posed with
certain locks
what the standards mean and what it
means 10 this is especially important
with high security locks because they
really are used for critical
infrastructure
I the White House Pentagon royal family
in the UK
I weapon systems these locks are relied
upon the keep people
out and so they have profound importance
and you really need to understand that
everything that glitters
may not be gold and I think it was side
Doug fair to say you know talked about
defense in depth multiple layers of
security but security clearly begins
with a lock I'm so for us
as researchers we find lakhs puzzles I
am
the more clout complex the more features
on the more difficult they are to open
I but with that comes from more
complexity comes more bucks more
vulnerabilities and more exposures for
us to uncover
I all them are apparently secure many
these
I thirty-year-olds designs
on to to our knowledge some %uh these
have never been discovered some these
vulnerabilities
and I my comment on that actually
medical was a forty-year-old design
it will it's the ostensibly the best in
the industry
and it took us a long time but we found
a design I won't call it a flaw it's a
design
issue that's a vulnerability that had
never been exploited be four
and we figured out there was twelve
steps so we went through to exploit this
lock
and we never thought we could do it we
actually shared all our results with the
company
every step of the way they never would
confirm or deny anything
so we just kept open in their locks and
Keifer and kept proceeding
and now of course it's a big problem so
the important thing is just because
everybody tells you it's secure
and there's patten's don't believe it
always look at it was skepticism there
so very good locks out there
I represent some lock manufacturers here
and in Europe
that make really really good locks and
you know we can't find the flaws but
that's not to say they're not there but
always view with skepticism next slide
it well and one last point II and the
last bullet is that you know of in
there's cops made to 2 Kos in
implementing these designs so
a very expensive what did block to
manufacture they may add at the last
minute implements I'm very inexpensive
components and often those are the ones
where it were able to exploit
right and it's not apparent at all
and and I make one other comment if you
if
probably many have you ever read it on
my blog we posted
two editorials about responsible
disclosure which will get a little while
but Medical has now recognized the lock
support community
and what John King D A the editorial the
way posts it it's not due to altruistic
motives they did it for a reason
the I work irony is that many of the
Loch sport enthusiasts and hackers and
IT professionals and security people
are the ones that have to find the bugs
that the manufacturers cannot find
and so it's been a long time coming Matt
my gave a lecture four years ago where
we proposed a joint partnership between
manufactures law enforcement
and the hacking in Loch sport community
nobody would buy into it so
it's coming of age and we need a lot of
diverse very clever people looking at
locks for vulnerabilities
its its the thing to do so you need to
understand the difference between
conventional on high security locks
I and what that means conventional
cylinders obviously our easy to pick
and pump open if you go down to the
village you'll see I
and and learn how to pick in and bump
open many many conventional Saunders
there's no key control so there's no
patents protecting the
the key there's no proprietary key ways
I or additional restrictions
I in a very limited forced entry yeah
conventional locks
are everything from quickset I'm to me
arguably the worst lock in America but
they sell 'em everywhere
this is what general and open two years
ago at the Afrikan
to the higher security lock with the
conventional locks are very limited
security capabilities and you need to
understand that
and so were differentiating I'm because
summer you folks in your job to select
high-security cylinders
and in many cases and and let me tell
you the next book
is about multi lock the first book was
about medical
they're not the only high security lock
on the block and lots of them have
problems
and so we're going to talk about so that
that the sanction you understand its
conventional walks can only go so far
in protecting you and they can be bomb
there's no key control to speak of
there's a lot of problems but they're
more more there is less expensive
so I threw up I'm on the screen is more
to cylinder this more cylinder and
I don't even make it out right on the
tip of my finger here is
I U L with the little circle around it
this is a you l 437 rated lock
and what that means is I there's high
high tolerance is to it there's
I resistance to forced entry there
certain security pins in it certain
hardened anti drill pins on in must
resist
forced and covert surreptitious entry
for a period of time
and risky control requirements against
that but as you can see we began this
presentation
I work pretty easily cop how's that
that's a couple seconds to Bob open now
again that's not all of them but
I and that particular lock which happens
to be a mortise owner we're going to
disclose next month a very serious issue
I'm that will allow that to be opened
very easily
0 go so I'm layers of security and in
this is
really critical to understand the layers
of security the layers
inherent in Medicago and how we're able
to expose
and tear down those layers much like you
wouldn't software and exploit them
I'm obviously each one is a separate
point of failure the add additional
complexity and with that comes
additional vulnerability
on we're gonna show some pictures here
up different at
layers of security or components
inherent within
high-security in conventional security
locks
sliders sidebars check pins there's a
whole host of additional components
that can be added to high-security
cylinders I to increased
their their resistance to attack
I so it go ahead art well
from an engineering standpoint when we
look at layers of security when we want
to attack a lock and when we started
with our project we sweet we looked at a
number parameters
and obviously we want to know how many
layers and the ability to exploit each
design feature
and if they're integrated layers of
security or are they separate
how they work in the Primus for example
there's two
independent layers of security I this is
the shins
conservator Saudi I'm there you go thank
you
I'm in this leg in this lake primus and
OSA locks there's separate layers of
security with the site bit mailing
their ego I'm so the key is very
different than medical
in medical everything the cuts are both
angled and vertical
in in one combined cut in the %ah saws
an app lawyers and some other locks
their separate functions we went through
a really detailed analysis when we
prepared our book
to tell everybody that different so you
understand the pluses and minuses
four different kinds of high security
locks so when we got in the medical
you'd understand what's good what's bad
okay so convention layers of security
there's really one
and and we don't need to dwell on the
slide but
I it's the sheer line and that's a a
that you can't do anymore with the
conventional pin tumbler lock
them maker sure line so you can put
mushroom when security tumblers like you
see on the left hand slide
the the green lock I that's a mushroom
p.m. to make picking more difficult
these locks that we've opened today by
bumping
all have at least two or three mushroom
pins in a
and so we've and and I might tell you
that
toby's best time at lockpicking up a
6-pin Medicus owners 27 seconds
mine is about they had two minutes but I
don't pick locks as much as Toby does
by bubble water but I don't pick up so
the the bottom line is on conventional
layers of security there's really just
one that you have to understand and
that's why they could be bumped open
now more layers of security these
5 pins on top or AR expands which we
just bombed open
the user medicos answer too high
high-security
and these as a point of history
were created about 1993 1994
in response to a very sophisticated
attack that came from Europe
using wire probes Sol these pains again
though
its jet it's another layer of security
but sorta but not exactly
the other layer security in the medical
m3 you see at the bottom which is the
step
on the side of the key it does not it's
listed in their patent is providing
another level of security
it does not a paperclip or a piece of
wire
that offsets a slider 40,000 seven-inch
its that layer of security is gonna
and here here's a I image of the
paperclip inserted
into the net medicare so under fire as
very high tech
now the paper clip doesn't open the lock
the paperclip
neutralizes that particular layer of
security
okay next slide
okay so again wire harness high-security
locks important to a lot are you folks
because
you have critical infrastructure that
means protecting
as assets people and you need
to rely on them us when you do not want
somebody that an hour that's the bottom
line
they can hack into your systems all they
want but if they can enter into your
server room
or your credit card room or your cache
folder whatever its over
and so high-security locks you specified
because
love the standards that you well and the
builders hardware manufacturers
association promulgate
because you don't have the ability to
test your own locks so they do it for
you
and publish standards the problem is is
as we work very well documented
the standards don't address all the
issues and that
really is a primary problem and less
you def unless you attack the lock the
way the standards address it
they won't even look at the method of
attack we broke the deadbolt
the medical deadbolt last year with the
two dollar screwdriver
we filed a complaint with you well they
wouldn't even address it they said
it's not in the standard don't talk to
us about it change the standard before
we look at the lock
and so it's a perfect catch-twenty two
next
okay so critical design issues again
there's multiple security layers the
question is
is there more than one point a failure
and this is really critical
because each security layer must be
independent
the security layers all operate in
parallel so if one fails you still can
open the lock
so when medicos case there's three
security layers in their latest
generation
we've neutralize two out of three pick
the third like a conventional pin
tumbler lock
or we neutralize all three next
three design factors the standards
require three design parameters for
high-security this is what you guys are
were I relying upon
and that's a resistance to force entry
their resistance to covert and
surreptitious entry
and their key control or as we prefer to
call it
he security and key security means you
can't knock off the blanks
you can't replicate the key issue can't
duplicate them
and you can't simulate I'm so when
you're handed the key
as an employee ever high-security
facility
the assumption is that you can't go down
to the local locksmith or hardware store
Home Depot
and duplicate that key well
that's a real problem so Matt bring up
the
this is a medico deadbolt so wonder
where the paperclip in it
and the simulated key that we show you
how to do for a dollar
this war bypass any medico
m3 keyway even the most restricted
key ways that you guys think our
proprietary restricted nobody can get
our factory controlled don't believe it
the problem is there are layers of
complexity when they came out with this
lock in 2003
they white and that the key way by seven
thousands over the edge
what is seven thousands mean well not
much to you guys but it meant a lot to
us
because we get sticker little simulated
key and
and and actually duplicate a working key
like it's in that lock
and bypass every key way which means we
can make bump keys
we can make coat setting keys we can
make the actual key for the lock
no key control major major probs
as we know up the fastest way to open a
lock is obviously with the key
whether it's replicated simulated or
duplicated
now so so the slice pretty interesting
and and we give a talk time last year
or the year before on standards I'm you
ellen Beach MA
and we details and provide matrices that
that depict the time I the certain tools
that are required
I to you for that are accepted by the
standards
on sofort for forced entry I well for
covert entry it's 10 or 15 minutes
depending which standard
on but the to restrict the text tools
that can be used
so as Mark said the two dollar
screwdriver that was
I fashioned for the for the deadbolt
attack
was not considered to be acceptable
because it wasn't in the list tools
an annual does have a requirement that
all the criminal sign a form that they
will follow the
mandated to our requirements for
breaking in the locks
so that I guess you don't have to worry
about and in regards to bumping the
stick
the standards don't contemplate future
attacks
so as far as zero-day attacks they don't
exist in the standards perspective
its has to meet at matrix has to meet
two-time criteria
the certain tools and method by which
they they apply those
otherwise I it doesn't apply
okay so attack methodology here's what
you ought to come away with from the
standpoint
don't assume or believe anything
when a manufacture tells you they're
locks are bomb proof
don't believe it if their pic resistant
pic proof
take it with skepticism it's not that it
may not be true in certain instances
the problem is that a lot of
manufactures a lot a high-security
manufactures
cannot open their own locks
they may come they design um they all
want engineering school
they make things work really well and
reviews are very high tolerance locks
these are not
simple locks but they didn't grow up
breaking things
and that has to be an embedded thought
processes lots of you guys know
in order to be able to crack locks their
proposals
and they don't hire design engineers for
the most part
that know how to do this me here's the
theory
medico does not know how to bomb open
their own locks that's where this all
started
and it was suggested to some but their
senior technical people
watch the video of general and the
twelve-year-old
she figured out how to do it they
haven't
and this is the problem and it's what
everybody at risk
okay so here's here's really
our primary role the key never unlocks
the lock
and everybody says what does that mean
the key doesn't unlock the lock
the key actuates the mechanism that
controls the bold or lapsed
if you can get to that and circumvent
the actual internal locking mechanism
you're going to open the lock we call
that mechanical bypass
and bat is what we did in the medical
debt bold attack
that they had to urgently change the
design their locks not once but twice
and before they got it sort of right and
so
the lock never unlocks the lock and if
you can feel
any the internal components moving
against other internal components
you're going to open the lock eventually
and that was our first see Hobbs a
famous American locksmith a hundred and
fifty years ago
the figured out that program okay so
very quickly medico is the dominant high
security lock manufacturer in the US
they started forty years ago
they own they own seventy-plus percent
above the high security market
in this country they also sell all over
the world and mainly in the UK and
France
I South America and really there relied
upon
this is the price this is absolutely the
prize
that everybody's been trying to go after
because it presents such a problem the
covert entry teams
so that is one of the reasons we went
after it
I really it's because they told us we
couldn't do it
and and they were really were good
friends of mine
and they said you can't do this
okay so we went and did it and we kept
doing it and we kept getting more and
more sophisticated
but that the medical history from our
standpoint is only part of the issue
what you guys really need to be
concerned about is the methodology of
how
we did it and that's really what we
outline
its where we started and how we worked
our way through the problems because we
had the crack their codes
we had that we had to overcome a lot of
difficulties
with in order to come up with four key
so we're open all their locks
we had the crack their colds to figure
out how to make four keys to forty-six
thousand different
combinations and so we figured it out
because there were some
there was all kinds a design issue so we
figured out how to exploit
so the bottom line is medico came out
with their original lock in 1970 their
second generation in a dev
about 85 call the biaxial the third and
current generation came out in 2003
which is called the m3
which has a little slider which we
bypassed with paperclip
in 2006 bumping was introduced to
America
I the announcer locks were bomb proof in
it was revised to virtually bombproof
now
it's virtually resistant
and you know actually matt said we
should raffle of one other copies of my
book
you're somebody would really come up
with the best definition a virtually
resistant you get the book
and and our last slide will show you how
we're gonna do that
I so and by the way medical has made no
public statements
at all since we started this go
so deconstructing lessons have security
what did we learn from
this 18-month Odyssey I
we discovered serious vulnerabilities as
I said what we really learned in
confirmed is don't believe anything
anybody tells a
about high security locks and
there's serious potential security
issues
and it it really and a result of course
in us sitting down and really developing
how to do this
and writing about go or
so why is this important on you know as
we said the methodology the
the approach by which you can go ahead
and look at something that someone tells
you is is not possible is not doable
I'm clearly the appearance of security
versus the real world
I am medical claims that that these
locks are our bomb proof
ultimately changing several iterations
on their knowledge representations above
what these locks can do is
is critical to to how you assess these
many people rely on a manufacturers
claims
and again rely on those standards and
we're here to tell you that's that's not
true
I'm again we want to demonstrate our
methodology will go into the four
components have that
coming soon and is obviously advocating
sick more secure lock designs
on medical meet many many mistakes they
fail to listen
on we believe and as john I'm
spoke out this morning and when we
further talk about the air expands
that there's been embedded problems for
many many years
on the problems got compounded as we
said as additional features and
functionality
to extend patents in to increase
security in the locks were
added additional water abilities were
added as well
on the field to connect the dots that
they weren't able to duplicate
you know throughout this exercise over
the last 18 months they've been briefed
even notify they've been contacted
they've been proven provided all the
details
above our findings and they couldn't
connect the dots yeah
the and this is the best in the industry
honestly
and they're really good company but they
didn't listen it's Erica
its and they thought they knew
everything and they thought this was
impossible that we were crazy
and you know I kept on that may be a
separate incident but we're still open
your locks
okay so here's how but we always did
maintain our sense a humor throughout
this project
even if they didn't I medico invented
the twisting PN
it is a brilliant design it was one of
two that i think is the most innovative
in this century unlock design
and this is just a photograph a biaxial
key
showing the angled cuts and the the
cylinder the bottom
this is a video that we did on the
multimedia addition of our book
at shows how we set the side bar code
and the little red angles
core on the on a key next to it
correspond to how the their
angles are set to open the lock okay so
again
there's three layers of security in
america lock because it is high security
one is the sheer line two is the the
sidebar
which must be retracted and is
controlled by the angular cuts
on the peons and three is the slider and
as we showed although they claim in
their path the sliders a security layer
that's theoretically to through but it
can be bypassed with a piece a wire
40,000 since the course just happens to
be the normal paper clip
there's also a are expand so how do you
open a medical Lochiel if the plans
you rotate that means it worse a slider
and the lock opens very very simple
so this this is a cutaway that Toby
produced
we shot a macro ever this is a biaxial
I showing and zoom in on the channel's
man real quickly
okay so you can see number for the
lavender arrow is the channel in the
peons that actually john is probing with
his pack
and the the sidebar lake which is a
yellow a row number three
goes into that channel when they all go
into the channel
the plot the sidebar retract and the
blood can turn okay and and this
this PowerPoint to be available we don't
expect you to follow all over
but we use it really for lecturing and
you guys can have it
so and week we just need to say the
sidebar
is medico security so if you defeat the
sidebar you defeat the lock
and so that's really what we
concentrated on it was a very
complicated problem
if you guys like really intellectual
puzzles
that have real world security
implications your love what we've done
I we had the crack the sidebar and how
to get the side bar code
because we can walk up to a lock and
open it with no
prior intelligence we can't pick at we
can bump it
we can create a special coat setting key
for which we've applied
for several patents that one of these
four keys
well virtually open every medical lock
in the world
that's their favorite term so
thats thats the sidebar is their
security
and it's a 40-year-old design that
really has not been changed
in forty years and I gotta tell your for
one minute
when I went to medical as a lawyer to
talk to him about
hopis decoder that he had invented
before I met him
yeah I do like that and their senior
technical guy
looked at me we were having coffee at in
a row and a locksmith convention
any says you mean that crackpot
from Miami he doesn't know anything is
used a thirty year old technology have
wires to probe are locked keys in
we're not dealing with them and so any
you need to get all the toby is
his email addresses crackpot its
security dot or
I third yeah okay slide
okay so this is how up the plugin
sidebar these are all the pins are
aligned
and I think we gotta zoom in so there
you go okay
so this is what a medical lock book blog
looks like
that is capable of being open the pins
are all aligned its share line as you
can see
and all the gates are aligned with the
legs are the sidebar so the sidebar
is being questioned by one over thumbs
so that that blood can turn
next like this slide that is locked
the pins are up and down which would be
in the plug in the shell
and as you can see the the channels are
not aligned the pins are all twisted
so that this law cannot be open go ahead
I'm so again what we go through the the
different attacks on the exploit
vulnerabilities
I am reverse engineering is Mark spoke
about the details are on the book I'm
not trying to put the book although I am
I but I there's a lot of detail there we
don't have enough time to talk about how
the the side bar code enumeration in
codes and keys were created
on us we got here
I design enhancements for generations a
lock by action on m3 and their new
bilevel oxo again
and I'm and beating this to death but
the introduce introduction
up additional features and functionality
to add layers of security or 2x 10
packet
on patents are mexico's is largely a lot
of trouble and I might make one other
comment if any of you have integrated
their new
by a level lock which is they're cheap
and
medical clone that has a sidebar that
isn't one
I you need to really understand that the
implementation have
via level in an m3 system can lead to
the compromise if your entire facility
because there some design parameters
that we discuss we won't do it online
that compromise the security because
they can be visually decoded
with a little poor scope that we show
you how to do that in a video
and so the problem is every time you do
a new iteration of a lock
to extend your patents you can cause
yourself a lot of trouble next
okay so we exploited all the design
features we will
basically week codes the design the coat
regression how the geniuses
at medico in the nineteen eighties
figured out the coat progression all the
crypto boys
and the key building design tolerances
and all the keying real rules we took
all this data
we mixed it all together in our heads
and we figured out how to use it against
up
and we open their locks by designing
exploiting their best design features
next okay so the results of our product
project here's the payoff
go ahead so the payoff is the title the
book open in 30 seconds
on covert and surreptitious entry in
in as little as 30 seconds or four Tobi
27 seconds
of forced entry multiple techniques I am
32nd some much less than that
I and and it does truly affect millions
and millions a LOX
and complete total ownage I love key
control
said a word on it and his work
he's from connecticut yet understand
alright so the this a picture before
code seven keys
these are the four keys to the kingdom
as we column and
and these will and you'll notice there's
a specific lack of code detail on these
keys
so you guys can take these images and
replicate them so easily
I'm these keys as I said well virtually
open every one other non master kit
Saunders
that were produced according to the
codebook there's one codebook worldwide
pre December 2007
so if we demonstrated early in the
beginning the results the project
I'm with pumping we can rule reliably
bomb open
virtually all biaxial in three locks I
am
produced from monkeys on medical blanks
on
and simulated blank so do you have that
one you're with and that's really the
problem because we have the capability
creating any blank for any medical
m3 in lots a biaxial ox we don't have
any restrictions we can also go
extrapolate the top level master key
to own a system and in a restricted key
where proprietary cue a system
this is a big problem because if you've
got access to keys it's a primary
requirement
to crack the master key levels the top
level master
and as you all know if you have the TMK
you own the system
so the first rule is you have to be able
to get the blanks
okay and this is what America bump key
looks like it's a very complex key
you guys can come up here afterwards her
I think we got up we got a signing
in the back so we'll show you the locks
or gonna be the lockpicking village all
weekend
if you have any questions but this is
what the key looks like so
this was gentle and last year at Def Con
when
this little 12-year-old who had been
become a star at 11
she opened the medico cylinder several
times
at Def Con last year medical said no way
this is a phony lock this is a phony
demonstration
so we see all the locks an hour after we
did this
sent him to some forensic experts and
they validated
this was an off-the-shelf standard
locked opiate pain that
to medical codes no problem
so key control key key security as you
said a total compromise a key security
duplicate Rep you replicate simulate
keys
for at virtually all in threes in some
by execute waz
on restricted proprietary and we talked
about the widening of the m3 keyway
that allows us to to introduce on many
other
the keys or planks I we could produce
bump keys and codes and keys
so this is this is a critical picture
here and you can see in this
a in the cylinder the red line
indicating how we're able to you up
wrote in breach that key way the
interesting thing about this picture is
the standards mandate
parecen turkeys that anyways the words
crossed the center line at least twice
to the so you can't move a pick up and
down
and so we don't know how they're meeting
that standard we're addressing there
right now
but this key way we can stick are
simulated Blanken
no problem that works like a factory
original
okay and and this is a simulated blank
an m3 this is what our keys look like
when we simulate them it's a dollar
blank we go through all through this
piece a cake no problem and again even
with the
reduced with on the simulated blanket
still maintains the rotational angle
able to rotate the pens and open up the
block
looks coming around it
you're so is so we show that show the
the paperclip I had to explain this to
mark he had no clue who MacGyver was but
I am
this is a truly that the security of the
m3
who is MacGyver cook I'm
okay so picking I'm again in as little
as 27 seconds for 6 p.m. lock
arm this does not mean high security
standards now again this is not every
lock
these are very very good locks but
we can open up and we can pick
individual plans without upsetting other
plans
would basically figured out how to do
whatever we wanted with these locks
and the real problem that you folks
there's a vulnerability that we discuss
at length
that will affect every system
that house Mata ko where you have a
problem with an employee that may breach
the security within a secure area
they can take their office key and go
use it
to pick open another office and this is
a very
very serious vulnerability most attacks
come from within
i'd I work a lot of investigations its
from within
and so the ability once you're inside to
go open a rear access an area where you
don't have authority to be
0 problem if you know how to pick locks
and this is not
a problem I can tell you that
Toby was recently at a facility a very
high security facility
took the director of securities change
key
went into from another office and opened
his in 35 seconds
now can he do that with every lock no
can I do that no
but it is a serious serious threat the
you all
need to understand and be educated about
so this is one of the the locks it was
using the video demonstrations
I in the book and CD and clearly Toby
spent way too much time cuz it's really
damaged
I
raining steel applies yeah I hope the
rating still applies
we've we picked medical locks with
standard X
nothin special no sophisticated decoders
nothin
we're just open up going so we talked
about the top level master key and
ownage was something else I had to
explain to mark by Tom its
total on each of the system and we can
determine the side bar code
I where multiple side bar codes are our
employees as Mark said use a change he
wants
from one facility on totally on the
system
of forced entry techniques a lot of
these I am aren't necessarily provided
in detail in the book they are available
on the government CD
I but we we have released information on
on the the phone abilities inherent with
the deadbolt I thirty second bypass
and there's multiple hybrid techniques
180 be developed was a reversed picking
technique
are more to some ramen interchangeable
core core locke says Mark described in
in a month we're going to be releasing a
very very serious vulnerability that
affects Miley
millions and millions and millions and
millions of locks and can be carried out
in about
ultimately in about 10 seconds so this
is the dead-ball
that we open with the two dollar
screwdriver in twenty-five cents where
the materials
priceless priceless here I
I only with mastercard I this is a
mortise cylinder and this is what we're
gonna be talking about next month
and like I said ultimately about 10
seconds this lock is open
and so again patten's
here's why here's really the role
patents don't mean anything
the patent office does not issue a
patent based on security or insecurity
have a lock
the issuer on on obviousness on utility
and that hasn't been done before and so
it doesn't have anything to do with
security that's what the manufacturers
claim so you need to understand the
parent verses
actual security so forty years of
invincibility doesn't mean a lot for the
next like
saw let's talk a couple minutes and we
would
urge you to read the editorials about
responsible disclosure versus
what we call irresponsible
non-disclosure just
we think that the lock manufacturers all
of them the do high security locks
especially have a duty to tell you if
there's a problem
as a customer and as a locksmith and as
a dealer
it's your security it's not theirs so
we're really pushing this concept
and making an incumbent upon the
manufactured to tell you what the
problem is
and to fix it so if medical release is
there a rx pins
in all of their locks what about the
millions have locks that are out there
that they knew about this problem since
when they started selling a our
experience what about
all those locks why didn't the White
they wait 15 years
honestly to fix the problem if in fact
they're gonna fix that which
is our information so we think there may
be responsible disclosure
on on your part if you find a flaw our
phone ability
in a new lock we don't think it has
anything to do with
anything in lakhs their out there are
ready unless they're gonna go off pay
to fix up it doesn't help you to tell
the manufacture about the problem
if you've already got the locks
installed
so again we think they have a duty to
customer we covered it in a very
into very detailed editorial so we won't
do it now so we can take a couple
questions
and this is this is the last frontier
this is what I ever did to earlier
the last thing that we have to crack and
we're gonna use
maybe the Enigma code machine that do it
is the figure out what virtually
resistance security means now we think
it might take a couple years
to work our way through that because
unfortunately my brother lawyers were
involved
in drafting this meaningless language so
if any of you have any suggestions
please
email us to questions when what and
and so we'd be glad to take some
questions for maybe six seven minutes
anybody have any questions
thank you
up
my favorite locks I are I like Primus
I like ABLOY and I love ever
MCS from Austria the magnetic code
system
we used it as V model in our book
because it is absolutely control if you
don't have the key to that lock your not
going to open it end of story there's
for embedded magnets
8 rotors two sidebars it took 10 years
have joined engineering were two
universities in Australia make the lock
they're not available in America yet
we're working on it
they're a terrific block very exactly
virtually resist verse
now they're now they're virtually
resistant but to answer your question
for strong I don't know where medical
was gonna go with mechanical locks and I
i really wanna stress
I've always love their company I think
they got great technology but they did
not
listen and it's a forty-year-old lock I
don't know mechanically where they're
going frankly I don't or
any mechanical manufactures really going
two minutes go ahead
next question what obviously over the
past decade there has been a rise in
electronic access control systems
and I was wondering if in your hands if
your experience there's been
if hardware mechanical systems have had
a decrease in importance
and how you think the industry will look
at another 20 years it's going to look
really different
let me just address one thing and maybe
I could talk to offline
for most of these electronic access
control systems
there's mechanical Saunders as a bypass
because everybody's afraid of electronic
failure so what r you know what and
there's no water trail on the mechanical
locks
so what are you gaining it twenty years
it's gonna look a lot different
next I you mentioned that the rotating
pens as one of two
above the greatest innovations in your
opinion what was the other one
mas Hamilton the XO seven XO a tax on
I'm
okay thank great lock very last question
last question for those of us who
acquired m3 cylinders before December
um would agree kim
solve the problem at least in part
can you solve the problem is that your
question
right by reaching a if the code but
prior to December 07 yeah
well let me tell you first of all we can
crack their locks after December 07 it
just takes is a little more work
but not much its sixteen keys were we
will all that down with intelligence
gathering to
after two keys and so the problem has
not gone away
if they implement if you put a are
there's two answers within it
body and they are experience and
we have a list have safe site barcodes
we've put out now they may violate
medicos rules
but we can't open and so that we felt we
had a duty to do that
if medical window we did most
importantly do you know why you can't
open them
do I know what why you can't open those
ones Korea
yeah we know exactly why why is that
shit up yeah okay why is that Packers
because our code setting keys won't set
the proper side bar code we can become
but it it may take us more time rather
than walking up with the Kia picking up
thank you
yup thank you all very much will be
offline
where are we riser