one our at and and for Sam s the person
as well
say don't let us out in the midwest that
often but some
this is freak sconce and jail Wow said
there's a lot of more people than I can
expected to see for such
Kenneth tough act to follow as sour
Ramban their
I so I have a presentation with me act
as we fight or run laptop but
I'm gonna start it anyway because I know
that the sites are in my head and you
can just ended officially follow along
cuz who the hell means power point or
anything like it
on so we're going to take you back to
in is something that actually is still
an active and ongoing seen its the cop
seen
and that's a Canada critical four-part
what it is to be a freak from a social
perspective at least
um there's obviously a lot a technical
freak stuff that has spent available
this weekend and I'm sure we've gone
over it but cops are an area that
really a is hasn't been captured by any
the talks so far and I've never really
talked about this before cuz I don't
wanna
we even handicaps I'm hoping that that
what happened this time
um so what sick of I'll
let's kinda take you back to the
late 80s and early 90s were you know
what I this got started
said to be clear cops existed before
that freaks would meet on loops to talk
and
so forth but re the you know toward the
and if the 80s like
86 87 88 is when
the big teleconferencing got started so
at this time
there was no big internet series have
choose
um there was sad no
real a seen as far as being able to meet
people
electronically I you actually kinda that
other freaks
you know and percent at 2600 meetings
and the like so what we had back
I'll late eighties was 2600 magazine
some 2600 meetings put it I some
up things along the lines up like
you know local I you know Computer Club
said there was pretty active one
that you know you may have heard of
Steve Wozniak was involved with that
down in Silicon Valley and you know he
was one of the earlier freaks
um but there wasn't revealed that the
kind of online community see
had now the closest thing that we had at
the time was PBS's and you probably
you know sketch how did I think at 37
hour-long documentary on
on the PBS seen that stacey has for sale
this weekend its
said says what
your okay okay yep arcade I see me shit
about running Windows
um so there said there was
there were some free PBS's at the time
but you know basically just to capture
the
the way that you interacted wasn't
things like higher see it wasn't things
like message forms that wasn't a lot of
the things that you had now so
you really need to put yourself in that
space to kind of understand what the
scenes about
so I what
what is sick of while a cop is basically
a thing you can dial into
I'll where you can %uh talk to multiple
other people all at the same time and
and I try to type my password at the
same time
there's you know that there is never a
hope that I've done where things have
fun on time
and this is actually I think the first
not the first equipment malfunction I've
had either self
still see um no no no no no
so have Parker turn your mic on so let
me introduce somebody who's on the stage
with me I
who Iran and grab my laptop on
okay hey guys so whoever's running a
beacon and can we want these
Mikes turned on somehow now
are you may have to just come I'm know
yet that worked
now my talk now
ok through talk now to it as my
conflates yeah
yeah sorry to be the at the CAF
operators front
I okay are we to a video
now function f for to have it here
how many hackers as a take to get it all
look at that
we have video you're a
yes its first step yeah okay so we
already covered this slide their side so
how do you mean other hackers
PBS's cops all that sort of thing
I and so 2600 at the time was more of a
free publication and so
there was like a real big hardware
hacking scene in the late 80s but
there was you know basically as far as
what we did it was more freaking
I it and that's what a lot of the
articles if you look at all the issues
if I 2600 magazine covered
up blue boxes at the time I'm sure
you've all heard a blue box especially
if you were at the F
history freaking talk this afternoon
this still worked
for the most part and a lot of people
are using
I'm if you don't think it would be the
ass you could I landed at that rate is
300 1200 2400
yes which is good enough for tax but not
really much
in terms of downloads most of them were
long distance just does anybody
raise your hand if you remember like
actually getting a long distance bill
over a hundred dollars
I don't know got my long distance so I'm
surprised actually that we have that
many people but
if you were a PDS Aesop especially you
were to cut your custom to getting a
phone bill at least five hundred dollars
typically any given month
I'm so toll charges for real people
wanting to find ways to avoid them
legally or not
was actually I you know a fairly big
deal and I got busted just so you know
it's kinda like
reveal my a chip bet you can do the math
I got busted in seventh grade
for blue boxing and for all that coats
if anybody remembers what on that was
us so class in 1992 still internet
access wasn't where the available there
was a big debate raging
on the internet which was still largely
an academic and government network at
the time over whether to let a a while
on
I they probably shouldn't have I
PBS's will really in their heyday and I
got in on the game I was running
a the been DDS which had kind of a
secret area for freaking stuff
in at and wheres and the like and it's
kinda funny cuz the dark tension and I
will fall
and Seattle and we traded
messages back and forth since we had a
really network and
and a lot of had a lot of the same users
who read it or tension system
and 2600 not to be outdone ran EDS but
with a twist it was the 2600
Voice PBS and so if you didn't have a
computer you could call into the voice
PBS and you could participate
in an online message for am sorta except
you dial that
um blue boxes by the the early nineties
week mostly gone to digital switching
and so
for the most part you could still doubts
of the
c5 networks in some foreign country side
you could
about of China direct for example but
it was pretty obvious card like the
techniques that you know people had
learned
likey you note I'll Army recruiting and
and blue box %uh for that
to offer their toll free number largely
didn't work anymore
are red boxes Saab still didn't work and
in fact
a la Turk also the 2600 Voice PBS most
of them is my gas
were made by Red Box I made more than a
few of them from
the pay phone at the school a block away
from my parents house and
it was considered like you know we have
netiquette now one other pieces at 2600
Voice PBS at a cat which was widely
ignored was
don't low tones into the phone like
making fake quarters while you're
leaving a message
on the boys BBS CP listening to a
message somebody saying something and
then at United cuttin'
these to posit 25 cents for necks one
minute and you know
somebody deposit if a quarter and then
cops I
which we talked about already II began
to gain in popularity
but their work were not a lot of
conferencing systems at Alliance
teleconferencing run by AT&T
was the primary one that people were
using I
and these things were very expensive for
you you know typically you would pay
forty to fifty cents per minute per per
participate so they were kinda aim too
high and businesses
so why if you're a freak would you wanna
cough
well it's a social thing I you could
talk to other people who had similar
interests
I on the phone nobody knows that you're
a 16-year-old pimply faced store can you
know Wisconsin somewhere
and very often %uh when you get a whole
bunch Shiv
people with the phone and a big ego and
a lot of boredom together um some
hilarity ensued
so on barcode got into the CAF scene
when he was in high school
and you know what was it like barcode
coming home from high school putting
your backpack down and calling the caf
well I thought you were six feet tall
and black the first time I heard your
voice on the 5th
yeah I am this Sat you know telephone
voice that's kinda intimidating and
big and nobody knows that I am
you know at the time 18 and 210 pounds
and I had the same voice then as I do
now of course I don't
talk like that anymore but at no i think
is right it was a
very much a social thing and I'm in
Sacramento specifically which one
get into later which is why I'm from we
had a pretty active
at hacker community I guess you could
say this is
just around the time is twenty six
hundred million other started in one is
at ninety
green 94 some 2600 no no no no and
Sacramento
on Sacramento yeah I think was I T three
and a
the room reason we probably got into the
comp says because the
a lot of them are based on a sacramento
there is a telephone company out there
that was
somewhat less than responsible with
shred in their trash
if that would be a MCI with that yet min
and under and the profit a red for had a
ultimately somehow up and see an hour he
was gonna hold up some other confident
Voser just boys pressures that they'd
set up for this multi-level marketing
companies
and by the time I first call an I don't
remember what the hell was going on the
first time economize conferences but it
certainly wasn't something wrong
wouldn't have kissed him yes so if any
if you think that Amway serves no use
for anything
they were a great source 0 Kos in the
early nineties cuz what they would do is
they set up these teleconferences and
they have all these am way people call
and
and they do you know they're big amway
wire I'm eating like
working to sell stuff in working to show
the plan show the plan show the plan and
we're all gonna be on the time in
yacht and we're just gonna be with rich
device in shape and Andolan selling
amway and then they'd hang up and we'd
call and then start
3 wing McDonalds and asking them to take
their
registers apart but you know anyway I
also found a thought it was interesting
that they would set those comp sup to
use for an hour and they would be up for
six
just yeah yeah this is true well
sometimes he said
you know these guys would I'll like I
will be on the CAF you know doing
something and then
all of a sudden like eight people were
joined and
you know it'd be like hi this is bob
from tulsa oklahoma and I'm here to talk
to you about to
melaluka today and you know like
sometimes has happened at awkward times
like when we were three weighed with
you know like airlines try to get them
to you know give us free tickets or
something
I so yeah I guess that's a waste nicely
in a prank call so
um one of our favorite companies to
prank was
OCI and this was a an alternate operator
service
so you know about I before I send and
you know the baby bells and the large
long-distance companies like Sprint and
so forth while
there are a lot of providers that we
call tell us these providers that
basically existed to rip you off when
you made phone calls on your calling
card from pay phones by hoping you
wouldn't notice that it was like some
sleazy provider instead of the real
phone company in
OCI was pretty much at the top of that
game
and the great thing with those CIA is
they had this toll-free back door number
that you could dial into and get an OCI
operator
and they had no idea where you are
calling from there was no way an eye on
this thing so
um you're leaving of one important part
of information which is that OC I had a
very strict policy that their operators
could not hang up on you
without manager approval yet yeah that
was the other best part
so it was pretty interesting you know
they could only make collect calls and
the like but
you knowi we call OCI and
asked them all sorts of really unusual
questions
and we try to make collect calls to you
know very unlikely places that they
that we knew they couldn't make calls to
like Libya um
it probably sounds less funny than it
was but
just put yourself in that place your 16
year or so years old you're on the phone
with a bunch of your friends and your
calling somebody that can't hang up on
you no matter how ridiculous
the proposition that you put across the
line as and
you know it really is a lot of fun even
now because they still can't hang up on
you
of yet so I'll 1 800 288 2880 by the way
I
for for a CIA if you if you want to try
your hand with them 200
flee it's there was such a so put
yourself back into cellular phones at
the time they were all crackly analog
and we didn't have
the nationwide cellular networks that we
do now
so often you travel from one city to
another and your cell phone wouldn't
work
and you get put through to this Sat
thing called cellular express where for
the mir
low low price if I think $3.99 a minute
plus a
five-dollar setup fee and who knows what
else I you could make
you know domestic phone calls on a
crackly analog cellular
outgoing only arm wall that was really
fun because they had a back door
toll-free number two and they also
didn't know where you were calling from
they just thought that you were calling
from some part of the country
York in so I'll
magnate one other freaks that I was on
one other conferences we
called quite a bit decided to become Bob
the
operators friend and so he call up um
usually at least 15 times a day and
sometimes more than that
and he got to know every single operator
in this Saturday and find out you know
what even with the layout at their
cubicles was because he just call
incessantly
and ask so many questions that they
eventually just started answering
everything he asked and then he'd call
and verify with other operators at
different times of the day
and you know if if anybody gave them
false information call until he got the
operator the cave in fake information
and say
Welch on you lied to me you told me that
the share next door to you was purple
and I know in fact it's blue
on you know why would you like to Bob
the operators friend and you know it it
eventually got to the point that they
knew his voice so well that he'd call up
yeah and they'd say hi POB the operators
Rohit he challenged and I have to say
first of all that this guy was just an
epic prick he was the worst person I've
ever met
here's his his everything that we all
try to convince
everybody we're not where he is actually
a unethical
compare you suggesting I saw a real
truck SIII we're getting to the point of
what why is in federal prison right now
later
but not a joke but she would I would be
in the car with this guy and he'd be on
you know random cloned prick found three
of the day and you would cause I would
listen to him do this and he would call
OCI
he would say do you know who this is I'm
by Tegan and sailors were sooo
everywhere that I was going and he and
and they would say
Bob the operators friend is a risk of
the operators friend
good I'm not gonna bug you anymore
today's summit another operator and I
just
anyway it never ended and I'm want I'm
glad the guys in jail
we're getting way every day though the
reason that we're glad he's in jail has
nothing to do with Bobby operators
friend which was really funny by the way
and nobody does stuff like this anymore
I don't think
maybe they do um a while tech support
was an endless source of amusement it
didn't used to be
thank you for calling a 0 air support
this is
gym it may I help you on it was a
I I don't know they with apologies any
Indians in the audience with a thick
accent
you know was faced and in Dulles
Virginia I believe and so you get
somebody who spoke English
and who had been trained to be really
nice to really dumb
people on the phone because that's kinda
who else customers were
and you could call up and saying
now Opteron the Las saddam
the and her weapon average bang and you
know when I
clicked on the program banked on nothing
but
baby been the lots on my pickup truck
flash
and I think kayo well-liked you know
done haywire my wiring on my 68 ap
one ft and you know it
there were at this was some this was one
other tech support call so we put
through like we try to convince a while
that somehow like
they were I messing up our pickup truck
and they try they would actually
very very very very you'd spend a lotta
time you know trying to convince us that
we shouldn't sue because there's no way
that they could have done that
and you know the these guys which is
take themselves deeper and deeper
um it was pretty funny like they offered
to have the legal department call once
arm Waffle House now that may be seem
fairly unlikely it's like this
chain in the midwest ive waffle
restaurants
and the plae
evidently like one of the ppl a member's
I don't know quite what the story is not
be doing a panel later see you might ask
them but my understanding of this is
at one point somebody from the plae went
to Waffle House and didn't get good
service from one of the waitresses there
and so having gotten the name of this
waitress
they just called her incessantly for for
months
and asked for all sorts of questions
like you know
I'll well I won't get into the kinds of
questions they ask good start yeah
yeah I cuz this is being %uh film 10
idoney myself in any trouble
but and then the last one and the price
not but definitely not least that
you know came to mind as far as prank
calls was Fred Meyer
now %uh Fred Meyer received you know a
wal-mart is Fred Meyers kinda like a
wal-mart accept that at the time they
sold random things like lumber and
I'm you know auto parts arm but
you could die a lot Fred Meyer and if
you convince them to transfer you to a
particular extension then you would be
on the announcements
in store announcement system for the
store and
you could make any announcement you
wanted over the phone
and everybody in the store with he read
all throughout the store and there was
no way that they could make
this stop except by powering down the
phone system which nobody knew how to do
cuz
AT&T ran it and they had to get AT&T out
to
power the system down so you would you
you were guarantee that if you got
transferred to this particular extension
which I won't
say is 909 thousand on here I
then I 0 wat I I didn't say that
%uh it's something other than that I'm
sure arming
yeah they would put you on the in store
system and you know so
it was great to make ludicrous
announcements did you know
that if a price if some I am gets
announced over the in store system they
legally have to honor it
a so there was an absolute run on
bananas one day like people went bananas
for banana so I'm
they were only nine cents a pound it was
a great deal
I I think they sold completely outta
bananas in the
to wallet and Fred Meyer I'm get I had
nothing to do with that and when they
shut down as extensions a
there may or may not have been some
people that climbed another for the
billion and stalled BBS underneath the
air conditioning unit
all that was it the same way but that's
a different story it
um yeah PBS's by the way K you know
anywhere that you had a computer and a
phone line you could set one up and it
didn't necessarily need to be your
computer or your phone line
%uh as long as you had a way to power it
and some phone line to plug into you
then it was perfectly possible for BBS
to like say be clipped into like a
credit card verification
a line at a Safeway that never received
incoming calls or did it
yeah um so we get into the mid 1990s I
by the way that those that PBS I i heard
might have contains some very illegal
stuff
um so in mid 1990s cops are like really
starting to blow up
I they're gaining popularity in business
everybody's using them at this point
and so well anytime something gets big
people old like
last start packing those things and so
hacking teleconferences really gain a
lot of popularity
I why it's why stop they started
monitoring conferences periodically
because
at some point some percentage
the percentage if legitimate conferences
was eclipsed by the percentage a
fraudulent ones
so they started shutting down hacker
conference is pretty quickly
arm so there would the check propulsion
labs in Pasadena Calif had a bridge that
they only use during business hours and
after business hours it was full of
freaks
the there was a phone company called
citizens utilities see and California
that ran a buncha bridges that we were
in. I
there was a company called rebel that's
still around if you got a talkie dot com
Taal Kedi
com that company still around the store
run
I recreational teleconferences but
the problem remember it long distance
cost money at this time we didn't have
the summer but it's all plans that we
have now
they were almost all long distance so
well there's ways around that
you know you could set up a toll-free
number for instance arm
so of course toll-free numbers if you
set up a toll-free number that means
that whoever has the toll free number
pays the bill
and we didn't wanna tell so
the best thing to do is to take a toll
free number maybe the belongs to
somebody else and reroute it somewhere
so I a tiny mega elite who was a pretty
active freak at the time I
yeah he's mentally-retarded and I he's
only really good at freaking but he's
very very good at that and social
engineering you still sort of
semi-active in the scene
on activism he literally brute force is
for yeah I mean this guy's gets my hand
if you are at the toll free: panel
earlier where they were demonstrating
like you know scanning with Tone Loc
arm make a leech just you know dials by
hand
each number and listens to what happens
there's no no automated techniques for
this guy but he finds a lottery the
interesting stuff
and then he's you know like I said he
say he's mentally retarded so he doesn't
have a job he has literally
all day to do nothing but sit on the
phone and talk to anybody who answers
and try to be their friend and he really
does want to be friends with anybody
talks to you
arm so and you know I'm not talking
smack about the guy like I
you know that's just thats that's just
kind of the world he lives in
so he found it phone number that was
part of it
balk account belonging to a paging
company and its fell twenty 150 say
and he likes phone numbers that spell
interesting things and he was kinda
really interested in the occult at the
time
so he found that and it went through
this disconnected pagers so he knew that
it was like
0 and I any hundred-number that was up
and then it went to something that was
disconnected
sorry I did a reverse lookup which you
could do you through certain throughout
you know certain a number's called dress
pork numbers that were operated by
various long-distance companies
and found out that a long distance
company called will tell which
is the most ghetto long distance company
that ever existed it's a it's now back
in its second incarnation
but they got their start by running
fiber optic cable through disused
gas pipeline in oklahoma it was like
kinda want to those weird idea some
cowboy hat that actually turned into a
phone company
arm and he called up there knock and got
some good ol boy in oklahoma to reroute
that number two
the rap why and the rap line like
if you called it if you did any checking
at all you would never reroute anything
there because it answered
what's up you reached oh crap line
eighty its Rob all
time ok wait till we don't take no
collect
third party or credit card calls you
know and it's like it was basically like
you know this it was the rap line you
know it was there was it was all about
hip-hop and
yeah every time you do to agree is this
yeah work on site yet there P
you know no legitimate reason ever toll
free number there ever and it would be
obvious to anyone so
you know this guy just reread it through
didn't check anything
and so this number was up for literally
three months
and like you call it and it would be
constantly busy the rap line was
constantly champ full love like a
combination of hip-hop people and freaks
which was kinda strange
on the the dynamics got to be a
especially when it came to arguments got
to be a little bit interesting
arm but eventually will tell figure out
what happened and they didn't just shut
the number down
they did it one batter they were really
mad so
be routed it shoot this internal I
recording
that was a special disconnect intercept
that somebody some engineer and
the wall tile lock set up intentionally
and it said
welcome to our long distance service if
you're experiencing difficulty
completing your call
please hang up and dial 1 800 I'm a
hacker
and we've got your number thank you
I think that she love has a recording at
that around somewhere still
but on anyway so
in them in the background like the
cowboy who started will tell was me it
was making a deal with another
cowboy named Bernie Ebbers who was
building a company called worldcom that
then became one of the largest stock
frauds and in the US history but before
that happened
worldcom ended up acquiring will tell
and some
enormous crazy all-stock transaction
website
I know whether the cowboy got out in
time before that happened or what
Tory care but the end result was the
will tell engineers
left in the world com engineers came and
then one day the world com
some worldcom switch engineer found this
and thinking that obviously it must have
been some some
active sub your subterfuge your
sabotaged by the outgoing will tell
staff knew they were losing their jobs
he did the only logical thing which was
to route the number back to the rap line
which of course was where it should
offend
so it was up for another two months
before you actually worldcom figured out
that no
having a toll free number the rap lane
is in what they should be doing and
that one away arm so
01 Tripoli magnate magnet the guy we
talked about earlier
and he really wanted a number that
spelled his name so soon as the ATT a
prefix became available he set up a
subscription fried with MCI
now unfortunately for magnate MCI was
really wise to this kinda thing so
although he managed to get the setup
slip by them
they had a verification team that would
go through into quality assurance later
and so week later got shut down
on and then I somebody who's not me
I
attached a
a toll free number spelling 100 g/l bond
arm to a different bridge and
so basically like identity theft
everybody knows what that is now
but back then like the idea of stealing
the identity of a company and signing up
for service on the existing account
which is really easy to do
like you know you have an existing
account that belongs to some company and
you just want to add additional services
all companies always wanna so you more
stops so it was really easy to do that's
and if it was a big company could be a
while before they noticed and I
and shut down shut it down and this one
lasted for six months at least
on so in the meantime
I I was living in or you can and had
some friends wanna firm's name
the felon and he was a felon then
and he's much more of a felon now and so
we'd go out and we'd actually call each
other and say hey let's go out and
commit felonies tonight it was very
casual
arm so yeah it to unfortunately the
statue limitations i think is passed for
most of that stuff but
I do what you gotta do you think I think
I while you know they're
we we live in an your tires retroactive
laws were like you break the law of your
corporation and then we're at
retroactively pass a law like granting
immunity and then
you know that Patriot Act in
retroactively extended the statute of
limitations for a lot of stuff so I
think it's just a matter of whether
that police want to arrest you now on
but a guy named
well I'm not gonna say his name here cuz
there's people that might want it but a
secret service agent showed up at the
2600 meeting in Portland which I started
by the way
arm and was looking for the profit and
around that time I thought it was a good
idea to get outta town so where do you
go when you're from
Oregon and you need to get outta town a
small town in arkansas it's a good place
to live low
I was right down the road from poker
hollow
in a place called toad sack which is
down the road from pickles Capen yes
these are all places
i've i've been there they're actually
agree of yeah
yeah bar-coded K actually came in
unrelated a reason
tote sack arm so yeah anywhere
at that point I there was a lot of stuff
going on and so we did
I am there was a lot of cloning that was
happening with cellular phones
arm one thing that was a popular device
was called the TDI
and so just a quick crash course on
a analog cell phones there was no
security anything that you sent through
the air like your yes and your men para
like
everything having to do with your phone
just got second Phoebe Anna Claire
and so the obvious solution
that congress came up with for this
rather than mandating digital technology
that would have been more secure is they
made it illegal to listen to certain
radio frequencies and I'm sure that we
all in this room would never do anything
the government doesn't want in that area
arm so if you had a Radio Shack scanner
that wasn't even modified it was just a
little older than
the current year and you had a computer
with that piece of software loaded on it
you could just are for yes and N percent
on the day and
yes and in Paris like basically all the
information you need to clone somebody's
phone
um you sir for this are the air all day
long and so that kinda happened up
we were in Las Vegas and I remember
sitting in a hotel room with you know
this guy and a couple other people from
oregon
I at Def Con too I think and
you know we're just I have never seen
yes and in pairs
come across a computer screen as quickly
as on the Strip in Las Vegas it was just
pam pam pam pam pam pam am
it was not specify where were you gonna
go add to clone cell phones except where
people are making a lot of phone calls
arm wanna be a carrier's there
who is the carrier that had to recall
announcements you remember that was in a
Las Vegas
on but eventually they got acquired by
sprint but to
they they had some really awesome
announcements when you call that it was
it a good candidate to
and then your call cannot be completed
as dialed please check the number and
try again
this is a message from cellular carrier
Las Vegas with there were okay 906 you
want to clone a phone
and that was so the most preferred model
since you could
ticket ship out replace it with a
different one that had been programmed
with software that would allow you to
very easily input
yes and in pairs the you start with addi
aircraft from other sources and their
code lines
where people post yes and in Paris PBS's
that will follow these things
arm and a Motorola break was another
popular
phone because it was a lot cheaper you
could pick him up and pawn shops for
like 10 bucks at the time
and all you had to do with sas/sata RAID
to a parallel port
you could program through your computer
and so you know me being broke
that's what I used on at the time there
were manual billing arrangements you
didn't have this electronic billing that
you have now so
you could go like trashing for yes and
in Paris like
at a cellular store somewhere and say
mississippi down the road from Booker
hollow
and then it you could take those pairs
up chu sayin like you know Seattle
and you could use them for a good month
and then when the bill for a billion
dollars like
got mailed on paper on like seven
hundred pages to the cellular carrier in
mississippi
only then with your yes and then pair
get
killed so you know having a pair that
would last for a long time was kind of a
big deal
arm so there were a and B sides on
sailors you would have some a site
carriers that interoperate it's sorta
than they could you follow me roaming
and there were peace i carriers that use
a different system
I be site used a system called mobile
link
and the ace in general and then the
a-side use a system called the NEC and
on you know now you just flood get on a
plane land fire up your phone it works
and you don't have any the second
generations but
some a side carriers operated service on
both the A&B side and US west cellular
was one at these they operate in a site
system in Omaha
in a b-side system nearly everywhere
else so if you took
a carrier's I yes and men para and you
operated on the opposite system love
them
that was even better because you can
receive incoming calls in your market
and you would never ring the other guy's
phone so you could
and you know another the system's other
tell was followed me
roaming linked up so it was kinda fine
like I you know sailor freaking was a
Wis gave I'll a lot of opportunities for
a interesting stuff
arm the felon one of our friends side
who is still active on tell a friend
I cloned I think hafer from a high I he
was
kinda in business for himself sort of
and got a little busted for that and
then what are the best prank calls that
we made with soya
you know be string called and I it took
off
and I'll we made a call to the white
house
and needed a urgently speak to the
secret service to find out
on you know whether or not the president
used amway products
you know this was this was you know
after one of those amway conferences
this was something that we really really
need it now so
arm they asked for a lot of information
personal about ourselves and I'm sure
whatever we told the most accurate and
then told us that it was not ever
business whether the president used
amway products so I think president
clinton
definitely used amway products I and
immediately after that I've never seen
any s and men pair killed so quickly
like
you know 10 minutes later peace train
call back into the CAF any psych
then 4q man but he is seven pair got all
them got all toasty matter what the hell
you do whatever we call that number man
it was pretty fun %uh so
I then kinda things came crashing down
and some of us started going to jail
I and this guy is why the ones you like
cop busted
I barcode maghame doctor havoc on %uh
passed in the same week
I so like the other thing that kinda
keep in mind is that the feds are a lot
more clued now than they used to be
like some phone shenanigans their
typically Wellington not
really get involved with if it doesn't
really have anything to do with
terrorism
like you know stealing money or anything
along those lines arm
back then if you were hacker you were as
good as a terrorist as far as these guys
were concerned they had not been trained
they didn't really realize second you
know crimes with computers for the same
as crimes with other crimes and they
didn't
for crimes with other mediums and they
didn't really understand like what
computer crime wise
so you're dealing with a very very
aggressive law enforcement
I atmosphere and the other thing that
was kinda fun was there was a lot of
infighting like the FBI and the Secret
Service couldn't make up their mind who
was
responsible for what and so sometimes
you had people getting busted by
both law enforcement agencies on
successive days for the same things and
that
resulted in a lotta cases like not
coming off very well
so the fed's to their credit have much
more of a clue now than they use to see
you really have to take yourself back to
that time
um but by code now he probably %uh to
talk about his past year I had a jump in
here I got it I gotta take five minutes
from here
so summit to work on Seattle
2008 and the profits about to go up and
give the stock
and he says I'm gonna happen to give the
stalkers and that's great was about
as I was about that thing where mom
about the shower gunpoint
0 that's that's cool
so a but it did get me thinking that I'm
trying to deal delineated hacker
generations
you can come up a lot always adore you
can say oh the you know one generation a
Packers existed before
you know your mom had an email address
and that after that it's a next
generation are
before you know pick pick any type of
major topic before you know
they're charging for domains but I think
that
a really good way to delineate
generations akers
is the point at which the fed's stop
being the bad guy
or we stop being the bad guy to the
Fed's and that
was relatively recently am obviously
there's still
many exceptions to this rule but there
was a point
not long ago where who is we know but us
in Sacramento on this is a story in
specific in its own and Brees is very
quickly
but in Sacramento in the 2600 mean
started
we had an incredibly adversarial
relationship with with the cops
basically
that choices are meaningless Sacramento
County hi-tech Crime Squad
newly-established had something group
for now there's a good reason they're
established to be fair
so internet segment was extended with
relatively sizable
and everybody there was up to some sort
of shady BS in many ways to be perfectly
honest it was
these are very shady people including
myself to a certain extent
but one particular thing happened and
inside you know about this is something
you want but there is a
gentleman named Josh Cohen his nickname
was pactel
rest in peace and she
stole something in the seven figures
love
hardware from Hewlett Packard and sold
it to
the mop and he was it part in the 2600
chris is this
did not bode well for us as soon as this
occurred we became public enemy number
one
and the form this high-tech crime task
force and they were
actively surveilling is this isn't like
my was paranoid things like they
actually had people
with for like what like telephoto lenses
on the other side item of my choice $600
million and we would walk right up to me
like 20 2007
yes so the spot the Fed contested Afcon
yeah like
isn't a joke well it started out being
real well and sand to be fair the San
Francisco ties Xmen also had people
surrounding us just as they were jerks
like that and they decide to come get us
which was actually pretty funny
to be fair so I what spot the Fed who's
a fad
richer and Anya nice a
but it still won't tell you wanna they
one of the side effects
if this was that beam you know young and
green
arrogant at week it was kind of an
ongoing court where
where we would do things to aggravate
them there are two things aggravate that
aggravate us and they even would send
undercover officers to the median
but we were you know we would invite
them back to the afterparty
run their plates find out third cops and
walk right up to me I can I'm
your cop and they're done I'm not
milliliters
this says yar and
and then like that very much never been
like three times and some point you
figure like God you know use someone
else's car
nice based in like three times like that
in the same six-month period so
K and and the the thing that really made
things worse was that once I'm there is
a particular hacker that
as have a retaliatory think he pulled
the blueprints
love the lead detectives home and
xeroxed you can still do their public
record for now yes xeroxed them
and brought in the 2600 his hand them
out and of course there's a cop there
and that got back very quickly and
and this happened in a very strange time
for an organ a rapidly fast-forward
through a crazy sequence of events
a couple friends of ours got busted for
some pretty strange tax
one thing that happened was a friend of
ours accidentally and it's actually
the truth heap heap was trying to break
into a system now is international
needed
but he didn't know is that the system
was actually some sort of control system
for it damn
yeah I was a SCADA system like
controlling the Columbia River Oaks so
so the secret service or if you are
somebody got called and he got busted
for this and this
I'm really in it too like it was the
RCMP that one after yaa and so you got
busted
she kind of gives information ever not
really is actually really call Diane you
tried
you know can't protect everybody but
that led to the CAF
because he was coming into the car so
Wiese the comp started getting monitored
by some sort of law enforcement agency
in one by one they start picking a soft
and we knew this was happening and
it started with a guy named magnate
which we who brought up earlier
magnate is just the worst person ever
and he really want to get caught like
everything he was doing
thank you sis down he really was the
worst person ever he really wanted to
get caught
he did really i mean this guy was like
on a clone phone and a
stolen Buick driving over Middle Road
cons throwing up like a
fishtail sparks my name on the freeway
with both fingers up at the window I'm
here's little
this is not a fake story it was between
Sacramento and low to high
he actually did this a and then just
play it claimed anger ignorance I was
having a seizure or something and he's
got away with it
great-great-great the SRS so health
sheer
he you he gets busted
surprisingly enough while he's driving
around is literally on the car fuse I'm
going to Taco Bell to try to pull some
sort of scam and he drops
and we get really suspicious because
some other people recently dropped
and we call his employer the next day
find out he had shown up for work
callers he was still in school college
school found out he hadn't shown up
and at that point we knew we were
completely screwed and that was it
and sure enough magnet gave all of us
out hit by name
give up my home address in totally don't
all have our docs and we knew this was
happening this is
three days for Def Con for so I've never
met the profit in person at this point
we are going to
I don't know about these guys but I went
into complete fucking panic mode I'm not
gonna lie I was absolutely terrified
it was really scary to think like these
guys I've been doing wrong things are
clearly wrong
I wasn't stemming from people I was
going credit card fraud I was actually
on the scale of things kinda okay but I
had done some things
and these guys were coming to get me and
they knew where I lived my brother
called me and said there's like
old men taking photos of our house from
a from afford
and I said well yeah stiff so we are
going to Def Con for
completely paranoid getting have a
rental van driver the middle of the
desert
and essentially have this Frank
conversations am i okay what we all need
to know cuz we've
we've been incredibly vague over the
phone for the past couple weeks in
paranoid can get our story straight
go back home I get back to Sacramento
and a week later
they literally came through the windows
and I'm at my parents house I wasn't
there I was
on my way to a twenty six hundred
million hands
and they knew what they were doing
damage is gone there they pulled my mom
outta the shower they do the opposite
totally over the top
and this is this this is so funny I a
Cayman believe it actually happened my
brother
is sitting on the computer in the house
and his plane
Police Quest crap
now gets better to get better and they
they bust and they didn't know what I
look like I don't know how that's
possible but it looks like and they
the my commands as detective has has web
and my brothers three years younger than
me says freeze map
my brothers fucking brilliant he's goes
I'm Matt
and he walked into the room like I
its affect now haha
so same so the Kahala not not my brother
the Cahaba Park Saturday remotely to my
brother at the keyboard
I'm thinking mass Falconbridge you could
just like next time I get posters are
from a Mac delete everything fuck and
smash it
I could I couldn't believe it said they
gonna my room and in my room of course
they found my
case or ban with I do you cables hang in
there because the week before I threw my
heart racing
god damn Lake knows I thought they were
coming so it's you I throw everything
out
and hang out they did get some stuff I
mean eventually was prosecuted but what
we'd agreed to before this
very apparent is that we're we had a
phone tree
in Sacramento we doubt we'd all agree
that if somebody got busted we call the
host seriously like i neva slippin movie
was that I will call the next guy
you say stupid phrase and on now and the
phrase I swear to god never said this in
public and I can't have much to say on
stage
the phrase which which we thought was
totally brilliant was how are your
mother's
flowers yeah totally inconspicuous if
you call someone say that right
so I sci-fi I actually did in this is is
it
to be fair it worked I called my my body
pegasus is in the CNS I saw him and I
didn't you say hey what's going on so
it's not an issue
no thanks I said yeah man har har
mothers flowers and he just goes
silent because we've never talked about
it and she goes
the right man here gotta go and and to
be tera
to to be to be terribly serious that
actually work today it was the end of
the PBS seen in Sacramento
that day which have to obviously you
next and that he called all the other it
was a
very devious heavy at the time he called
all the other pvs operators and
everybody call everybody
and like 15 major major for
Northern California like no hacker PBS's
went down a day and never came back up
and those guys but their computers in
their car and left
and and and so I brought a cassette tape
thingy to my
interrogations which I was interrogated
a pizza parlor without a lawyer present
to a shower and sleep I responded
everything with I plead the fifth i'm
talking you
for Expo above are I tape-record
everything because I wanted everybody to
know that I wasn't gonna rat them out
and I didn't I didn't say anything and
the Sacramento bus
stop to me but before this had happened
they basically at
over the past several years busted
pretty much
all of us for something and so we had
this the sacraments $1,600 group which
with all these people in it and get back
Pepe con got busted for the tower
records thing I went down for a year and
Josh was in federal prison
everybody was everybody was gonna bust a
magnet was gone
missionary care about and and we all
thought you know
this is can't this can't go on like this
bit it was gives a characteristic over
something that doesn't exist anymore
they look at us as the bad guys and we
look at them as the bad guys so to speak
we were had an adversarial
relationship and that is a generation a
Packers that
that existed in that time frame that
if you if you if you came into the scene
and I'm not trying to say this in a
negative way
but for people that enter the scene and
at that time
the relationship with the government
with the feds are the cops sp wasn't
this
in this adversarial manner you there is
a segment
there's a way that we thought back then
it just doesn't exist anymore and it's
it is very positive now I'm very happy
that things are like they are
but if you weren't there for that it's
really difficult to understand what that
was like because what you're talking
about judges who didn't understand what
you know was
your parents in an email address you can
nobody understood when you went to court
when I went to court and I've got a
Chino
I'm trying to explain the stuff to a
coworkers it they were the courts be
honest was very cool with me try to
limit on my own story
it's kinda like wall so what did you do
yeah and they they were asking us is
opposed to the prosecution sometimes
like
what went on did the district attorney
and walking orders to get me on three
felonies and misdemeanor
I was suppose to be in jail so I was 18
and no computers to I was 21 or
something like that I walked I was
fucking terrified about this literally
absolutely terrified
shaking in my shoes completely scared
and by the time I got in there I started
a cow walk them off through what was
really going on
I swear to God before a workout room
first of all I got off with one
misdemeanor 50 hours community service
true and
but but
which the district attorney was slightly
less than pleased about
but the bailiff like turned over to me
and he said in my side like this thing
is over in his post
my am I have little anime is this
reference was a look at times I look at
I'm
he's you know anything about how I
yes Mac and I said
I look at my lawyer milers I'm as a as I
said
you guys like spots ok
I Kenya
can can use like can you tell me how to
fix it
Mike flock you're going to have to fix I
go over to your house we wanna do
discover old
and but yet as a
if asked for a couple years you know one
thing I don't want to clarify about what
that with the proper was saying is that
there's a couple things that you never
do
ever ever ever ever ever you never ever
ever screw with emergency services
doing brand called ever never sworn I
want never Smith was controlled never do
anything
and and actually that segways 39 yeah
and
that it is a present-day that segways
right into magnate and I wanted to let
this point because he's the one that
knocked me out so this is a guy that
basically in archives and marching out
walking a third-rate
so this is a guy that that are added you
how to the cops and and he
you might have seen on CNN a couple
months ago a that there is some people
busted
it is a front-page stuff for slot in
where you do is avoid
use VoIP you do this a nice move and you
get SWAT call to come somebody's house
that guy on the front page CNN Jason
Trowbridge
magnate to get Sam Gagner Cassady gotta
about 3-4 weeks ago he just got
sentenced to 16 months in
in a federal prison yeah
so this is our last slide 9 being a
being asked to wrap up very quickly but
fast forward to today cops their dime a
dozen long distances affectively free
and we still use them
um because it's still a social thing
up a lot of weight freaks hang out on
the tele freaked out or Kopf and
you know if any of you are interested in
enough weight
that's a great place to get information
it can hang out with us
I but there's a dark side white and that
is that
it's a very new technology there's it's
very easy to gain access to ss7 and do
all sorts are really nasty shenanigans
like swatting
and I do I love you know it's wanting us
yes now okay wall the I'll give you a
really quote quick nutshell us wanting
effectively when you call 911 your anime
which is your phone number gets
transmitted to the PSAP and I wrote a
very very detailed article about this I
think
two issues ago at 2600 I write telecom
and former college by the way
I'm so go pick up the issue if you're
interested in this but
affectively if you call op I am and
you're using a certain way
certain set up VoIP services you can
scoop somebody say and I
and make a 911 PSAP think that sums
hostage situation is going down cya at
somebody's house
and they'll respond with you know arms
cops in a helicopter and other things
that you would hope that the police
would do if somebody were holding you
hostage in your home and they were armed
in crazy
on and you know people very easily if
you pull this kinda sad
could could be told in you know E they
be entirely innocent so magnate
the guys 29 years old and he still doing
shed and up so he got in in with the
couple love
you know younger hacker younger freaks
rather
they started pulling these kinda starts
and I you know that something the you
deserve to go to jail for like five
years isn't absolutely
alright I think we're done and next up
there's a yes social engineering
panel of some kind which I think we'll
see a lot of finite that we gotta
manual and men that can on it so last
8-10 thanks
just a
just a quick reminder we don't have any
paid people that pick up after everybody
so if you could take your
beer bottles in your forties and you
heard
your various caffeinated beverage and
beverages and make sure to put them in
the trash cans that be greatly
appreciated
a social engineering is next
cheap