vitamin retirement retirement sorry
against you earnings standards I don't
even
yeah marriage is great law radovan
with PGP verses PK I up
okay so it's getting it started
this is PTV versus picky I I would
assume that you know some basics
I'm not gonna go over any kind of real
detail and we could talk for free
few protect me I've got some links on
books
and web sites that you can look at for
all in agreement medical details
%uh we're really gonna concentrate on
the trust issues and their relationships
with NPK I'm pgp to whom I
right now I am the director of security
assessments at gen-i security solutions
we are a security consulting firm in the
Washington DC metro area
%uh yet director doesn't mean much we
got seven people the company
so you just a fancy title I've
participated in the FA Trophy Cam
working group
thanks to be in the DC area the US
federal government has one of the
largest pecan pies in the world
thanks to the department of defense and
the federal bridge we provide consulting
services for very large enterprises with
pecan ice
arm summer who actually rival federal
federal a PK I for size I'm a number
certificates issued other most that has
to do with lost tokens and
broken tokens rather than actual size
%uh I do occasionally depend testing
still I'd rather him or a bit by
have my background is in pen testing
unfortunately kinda move to the middle
management
by it it pays more and which each
started a family to support %uh and also
you know I do have a
masur science and information ever come
from Carnegie Mellon the
I and II program which is now an NSA
approved
security program which what my opinion
doesn't mean much
you so when you talk about
real quick public key cryptography I
some other key management
p2p it became pgp and DVD I'm primarily
focusing on OpenPGP
which is the open standard issues now
I'm in the same with PK I and then why
would you choose one over the other
each has its strengths and weaknesses
and what are they
so publicly to talk for free
has you get two keys Republican your
private their mathematically related
are basically you have trapped or
functions which are one-way functions
that have a key to go back the other way
basically
if you know the public key it's very
very difficult
mathematically and computational needs a
lot of computational power
to get the private key even though they
are related so
it is possible arm but with key links
that are in use today 1024 2048
very very very difficult other keeps
getting easier
every month as we get more as we get
more computing power there's or other
them center in use
our essay is based on competing factors
Desa an album out
are based on computing logarithms both
of which are complex problems
so just the other than you use just a
case what problem you're trying to solve
basic premise is that one key
undoes whatever the other one does so if
you encrypt with your private key
you encrypt with the public key your
crib with your public key you encrypt
your private key
so that's basically the relationship
with your public and private keys
if you want more very detailed
information on public he could talk for
free
the hamburger but I could talk free is
free online I have the URL
and actually I check my boss is if I can
upload these to our server
after the year after the talk and you
guys down to the slides
um also the prosecutor book
with onions Ferguson a brief shining
bozos
you know I actually recommend the
product could talk if you look over the
implied
photography book because he applied for
Tiger fee is how to implement them
where's the practical photography tells
you you know what the background how are
they were developed and things like that
so for people who are just interested in
learning about the could talk for free I
recommend cock
Murphy you when implemented go for it go
for the Red Book to public key
cryptography is little different from
symmetric key a TSX Adara
because allows for digital signatures
you basically you sign me
you signed the private key and that's
your signature
a lesser message integrity use hashes
with your IP signing passions with the
private key people can tell if your
message is changed or not
on also it sober supports key exchange
um most public he could talk free
actually
we exchanging emails somebody using one
of these methods
you're actually not encrypting it
asymmetrically or cooking at securing
Christine
a key asymmetrically people D Kripke and
then use that symmetric key
to pick up the rest the message so
just because the metric is still faster
and public public he could have you what
you do is exchange all these keys in
in with in bad in bands manner you don't
have to call somebody on the phone and
say what's your key
you can be you know publicly on a
webpage key server whatever
us additional soldiers are using private
key encrypt them
I using compassion not the actual entire
message
Fresno on a PDA Shin I send you a
message signs
I can't later say that no I didn't send
because theoretically I'm the only one
who has my private key
and since that's a sign is my private
key I said
and as a message integrity so people
check the hashes
hashes don't are exact then the message
changed in some way
either start to be issues with that with
collisions in Shaw 1
so as of now can't do known
collisions but in the future may be able
to
so how do we share our public keys given
to your friends
cigarette USB stick publish my webpage
use key search PHP Q servers now so you
can also use X 500 held up directories
and all these ways you can share any
publickey PDP or PK I
and the public so your keys a public
does not matter who has them separate
one case when you wonder about them
so but what about all the public use
that you've collected
are yours you know if your friends are
the ones you download it
how do you know that the person that you
have
public e4 has the corresponding private
key
and is who you think you are well this
is how pgp Invacare different
they deal with this differently for PDP
and I said this is OpenPGP mostly pretty
good privacy
1991 by Phil Zimmermann I it's changed
quite a bit
since he created it others really to big
changes starting with 26 earlier and 26
and later
I'm have quite different algorithms
renounce and by the PTP preparation
which actually does
still dies published pgp
software desktop enterprise level
software
OpenPGP US 90 F working group created in
1987 so that PGP stayed open and did not
have problems with Network Associates
just not wanting to deal with that
on RC's 48 eighty and 3156
are the Tuaregs seize the deal with the
PDP if you want more details
and like I said earlier i'm talking
about. OpenPGP so which is the %uh stand
ETF standard so both MPTP NPP
PGP Corporation support the traditional
Web of Trust
method you know it they also actually
support a hierarchical model
I was talking to some friends earlier
and they had no clue the p2p could do
some stuff about talk did
you know it's is in the code he should
have been a key ring
I you have at least two one private one
public he can also have multiple
however you choose it mostly boastful
accuser exchanging some kind ad hoc
manner
he servers web pages so
like I said yet he servers and you to
use likes what he server you want to use
this is an example of the trusts created
using sick to die
this is mine and the kind of cluster in
the middle there's actually from the
hope
2004 key signing party seeking to see
you know raise in a related there and
then I've also
you know like said you know what college
did master seeks kinda other group of
friends
but I hang out with um when you validate
an icky
with pgp and this is you know you have
to use it
as to send somebody a cryptic message or
to check their signature
there's four levels of trust and this is
a using up the trustee me commands
in a GPG if you don't trust them
you know if you trust them if marginal
trust are you fully trust them
by default your own key is a fully
trusted you on the private key
everybody else by default is don't know
if you actually use update
trustee v you can set in order to
validate a key
YouTube he requires enough ballot keys
or
and blacks ans the key be invalidated
must be within five keys
your own now these a DVD defaults you
can change them
eighty-plus requiring wanna Kiev
directly site
so if you signed your friends key it
trust fully
one fully valid he must have trusted so
if you're you fully trust a friend
they sign a key you'll trust or you have
to have three marginally alan keyes
sign in so you marginally trust three of
your friends
and those three friends have signed a
key then it's going to be fully trusted
says example here you know have Alice
Bob and Charley
are people I've signed and
I marginally trust idle you know
for whatever reason I don't press and
check ID's I just
Martelly trust they're they're okay
people but I'm not going to trust them
to
sign for me in check ID's so all three
of them signed an
I'm gonna considered and a valid key but
only Bob and Charley inside Eve
so I'm not consider even valid key
and that's about how GPD doesn't
so what happens you know you have these
little keys where do you find them
I've signed Allison also signed bobbin
bobbin signs Charlie
where do I find the link between Allison
Charlie
I don't know who bobbitt's how do I find
his key
well yes it really sends me a sign email
I don't know where it rested or not
because I don't know who bob is
I have to find somebody has to tell me
about Bob ski so I can have it in my
keyring
you know you have to ask alice about it
I access Charlie
who he thinks might lead back to me is
really no
good way a building pass with PGP
yes it's on your keyring you can build
the path but if you don't have these
people on your keyring
you not be able to build that path this
kind of this is where the major problems
with the decentralized love trust
is that there's no go to place to get
all these keys
he said you know most major CAE servers
are linked together but not all about
so what if I use once a key servers and
charlie season another said accusers
I'll never find
so another thing that OpenPGP supports
is actually it does support a
hierarchical model
most people use the webcast live trust
mile I'm like I've said
I have talked to some friends who use
pgp for ever they didn't even know the
option existed
there's no central authority you you are
the central authority
for your weather trust so I decide how
much time i trust icky
and I decide how many how I decided went
Howell what I'm gonna require from
people for me to sign their key
so if I want your passport to sign your
key
that's my standard but how many people
want a passport psyche
you know that there's no standards
identity verification
could be I know bob over in q3 okay
because I'm up ski
wheres my company never seen again
actually works for a company
you know okay so basically
you know there's two types of things in
a p2p signature that everybody knows
you just sign it uploaded to key server
you know trusted
fully largely are you don't trust it
where the case may be
so when I psyche I'm saying that I have
verified this person's identity
whatever my idea verifying its
so I'm I trust my friends to verify it
somebody else
so there are a few friends I trust check
ID's and there are some that
I don't ans you know
once it's gone past my group of friends
I don't know what standards
identity are
Canada really end up with the one little
change you to your friends
maybe one more one person middle
so but and like cases yet a key same
party
have two people on the my web address
for the Hokies same pretty
never seen him before never seen them
since
but I take their ID if he say Murray I
was I signed their key
I don't know who they are I don't know
that I can trust them to sign other
people's keys appropriately
yes they did the same party but does
that mean they do it all the time
Anna so you can't extender trust very
far
you can't have two get added your group
love
close friends good other groups get a
different love you go to a different
2600 meeting in our six panorama pressed
but was the people I know aren't
terribly comfortable doing that
cars talking to people I'm
check so the other kind of signature and
he did his trust signatures
it's not address command you can only do
it for the Edit he commands multi-site
and I'm not sure if you guys can read my
my a screen capture their
that's actually what happens when you do
it he signed on its key
ask you to trust them are Julie Reed you
trust them fully
and ask you the depth of trust how far
do you trust this person
it can be you know 0 or it can be you
know
500 whatever you want the
0 means you don't trust at all one means
you trust them
but you don't trust them to trust check
identities anything above
wind means you trust them to check
entities and whoever
they sign a check it it's it's basically
a a measure of how far you trust people
how far down the path you're willing to
trust people
you can also restricted by doing so if I
say
I trust up bob from Company A to sign
all Company A's
a data works I'm signatures I can say
okay bob can only sign a dorkus
So You Think You Can restricted by to me
but basically when you do sign it was
the trust signature you're saying
you trust this person to verify somebody
else's identity for you
you also a allow them to make signatures
on your behalf
basically so you know when PDP makes it
past
filling algorithm and takes you and your
friend button together
there's no you know it's basically the
same thing
as far as the p2p is concerned path
length obviously changes
um you just become a CA
up sites you come here in CA I as a
near-death
tells you how far you trust your friends
friends so
I send somebody that's a depth one they
send somebody else's. adaptive to
and so on that this measure change
thanks
any revocation the PDP up for CF
actually generate revocation
the canoe PG manual recommends you do it
as soon as you generate your actual key
I don't know too many people who do and
if they do they have no clue where they
saved it when they actually need it
so and when you've lost the key and you
haven't ever generators revocation
information
you can't you no longer have the private
key you can revoke your key
even though you know it's been
compromised suspect it's been
compromised
you and only you can revoke your
certificate
I can revoke a certificate for you even
though I know you lied to me
I can revoke my signature on your
certificate
there's only there's only two commands
that won't let you and that's and our
sin and RT sign
and he's not a vocal signature
non-verbal trust signature
and if you use those I pity you you
should always be able to revoke your
trust in your friends
no matter how good friends there
yes I have an issue with publishing a
revocation information how do you tell
all these people that may have your key
you have no clue who educate because you
put in a public place
that your doctor's your key yeah I
put it on your any website put on the
key servers and it's not a key server
most people are likely gonna pick it up
assuming they refresher keys every once
in a while
by it if somebody is talented of your
website much you really go back through
56 years weblogs how do you know who's
downloaded
seek notified them and
you know when you upload it you don't
know who has actually site you made it
may or may not know who signed a key
it's likely because you probably had a
show your identity to them
but that's not always the case I have
actually seen people who've randomly
psyches
he servers just because the name looked
familiar
I'll so how do you tell these people
that have signed rookie that you were
able to keep
he's no longer good so he serves the
best method right now
well what's the problem with the TV
lacquer standards
for identity verification you know in
the US
driver's license passport
school ID her company ID maybe
you know what do you find acceptable may
not be what I find acceptable
you know how do you know what other
people are doing further down the chain
you trust you trust sign some money how
do you know what their identity
standards are
you have new contract with them to hold
them to the standards
so if they just most the time I checked
identities and then just that one of
time they don't
you know it's kinda a trust issue with
your friends
reefer trust is shaky you know when you
when you say
somebody else can act on my behalf in
all situations
legal in the real world online Dec
cetera
you have issues you know a you no longer
have
om you no longer have control over your
key and what your trust this
you basically publishing said I trust
this person to
act as me you know and if for some
reason you
get upset have a fight whatever
you have no clue what they're gonna do
now
thing is that pair that person's likely
never ever use a trusting nature
facts how many people here have actually
used trust signatures
in Fiji beer GPD get to 3
for people a group maybe 50-60
so coming up heard about them before now
you
okay quite a few more so
I guess that is really not that popular
but PDP is a very flexible model you
have control over
your little gir and you can trust or not
trust the man who choose
still have problems if I need he's in
the middle between you and whoever is
sent us a message
elsa revocation indications a pretty big
issue
yeah I actually solves a lot of these
and brings its own problems
so it begins public key infrastructure
it's a base RFC 5280
which just came out this may I you guys
probably more familiar 3280
which is the previous version x5
inaccessible X 59 the ANSI standard
I use the certificates you can actually
use hardware tokens
and if anybody knows I've heard her
talking for PGP and like to hear about
it
I don't know one and if there is one I'd
be great because I'd like something that
can store both my PGP key ring and my
hardware certificates on the same token
your certificate policies
and you have directories as well kinda
comes as part of the whole
infrastructure part it's primarily
hierarchical model
it does actually support a Web of Trust
like model using cross certificates but
that has
really big interoperability challenges
%uh
certificates are public keys that have
been signed by another entity
so want somebody assigned here your
public you become certificate
whoever whoever signed it doesn't matter
Certification Authorities actually issue
certificates
so they can issue certificates to other
certification authorities make an issue
end-users use people like you and me
a root CA is a special type of CA that
has a self-signed certificate
this is the ultimate trust through a
hierarchy
so this is the kinda machine that's a
you know most of them
no network now reports actually a pox it
closed
there start offline stored in a safe %uh
a lot of them use harbors her security
modules that have 45
key cards an order to boot up the
machine you actually have to have
safe three of the five yr for the five
keys in order even boot up the machine
used the keys for these
so they're they're quite there there
there though weak spot in the higher
in the trust hierarchy yes have
supported CA's
these are Certification Authorities
don't have a self-signed certificate
or where the self-signed certificate
does not and two is a certification path
I'm a CA foreign and you can have
multiple certificates
issued by multiple issuers I'm so it
makes an interesting graphic Jer
a validation path is a chain all
certificates
from one that you trust to the one
you're trying to verify
validate so now it has to go back to a
brute CA that you trust
so validation passerby completely
different for everybody because not
every trust the same
CS any also have the revocation list
also known as a CRL
to list them all certificates that a
particular CA has revoked
so this is the publication method to the
interesting parts in X 59 certificate
on the required parts are subject
anarchy
issuer and their public key a validity
period
so how long is a good for one disturbing
goodwin's and being good
and a CRL distribution point where am I
gonna find revocation information about
the certificate
certainly interesting optional parts are
key usage an extended key usage
I can tell when I sign a certificate as
a CA
I can say this review is only good for
encryption the certificate only get
additional sighing
thus it is only good for authentication
and there's also the code signing
certificates or something you might be
familiar with
certificate palaces are also optional I
can assign a policy
to a certificate saying this certificate
follows this particular policy
and I talk a little bit more about
policies later but this is basically the
rules
at the CNN the other interesting part is
the authority information access the AIA
field
this says where to find information
about the key that's lying to me
so it safe I have end user certificate
my AI in Miami I A is gonna have
information %uh CA that signed me
so can't go find this key as we solve
the many you know where to find the
middle keys from
general hierarchy has a root CA I like
is that usually offline
locked in a box right maybe once a year
to issue a CL
issues certificates associates these the
ones are actually online and doing all
the certificate issuance
the sub CA's issue to people or other
CA's I mean I've seen
as in Iraq is five or six deep I don't
know why but they have a 160
pass validation this is building the
path
yet to start you start with a
certificate that you're trying to verify
uses the issuer information the AIA
until finds one
until find some CA that you trust just
keep going back up the hierarchy
to find something that you trust then it
checks all the certificates and that
path
at least a good are they revoked
eccentric
can actually be quite a lot more
complicated than it sounds
graph problem um and
has cycles and it's so you're it's
actually because specifics to
659 you're actually talking about 3
spanning under them
so it's not a complete but it is
difficult um
but I S if you really want to learn
about past building %uh RC 4158 actually
tells you it to you how you must do it
but it tells you here's a really good
way to do it
and in fact most if the most mostaert
vendors who do you have validation
actually follow 4158
so so the key management picky I
supports key escrow
was key escrow store and storing your
key
CA keeps a copy of your key which is
good for
signing that's a good idea because then
you lose Nana Peth in
but when you're accepting you're working
for a company
and you have documents you like that
your hardware token
any really really need to get to this
document to send it here class
US the CA and say can I really pretty
please having
option key back I'm so that's one of the
reasons and the other reason is the Seya
companies so they can always on encrypt
what people have been corrupted in a
company
arm certificates are published in a
central directory
all c8 certificates are published
end-user certificates may or may not be
depend on how your how you set up your
structure
and that's just so that people can find
your CA certificates
Ana CA should have tried have published
and follow
estupida policy this and such a policy
there is actually a RFC that tell you
exactly what format it must be an
its has that that's 36 37 and that's
just so they can compare them
between CA's easily skies exactly how I
don't you verification is done
what ID's are acceptable how many pieces
a baby you must have
who is allowed to do the at any
verification
as well as how machines are identified
especially you know
pk has used for SSL Certificates how do
you identify machine
machine can't you know come up and show
you is ID
so most I'm actually have human sponsors
and human sponsor must do the utmost
you know they they actually identify the
human sponsor UN-sponsored yeah I'll
talk for this machine this EP is a
public document
anybody can read it so
like is that I have a link to Verisign
if you really want to read their signs
which
yeah unless you guys have been mucking
around in your trust fruit store
love either Microsoft ehrlich's you
trust us
just because it's there even Firefox
Mozilla have it
so you know it might be useful to read
up some the CP's is all the CA's
you trust and see what they're doing to
check people's identities
check certificates most CA's have yearly
audits
spire certificate policy they check you
know
this there's a big hug there's also some
call the certificate practice statement
which is okay here's how we need our
policy that I was never published
because has information about where
things are stored
what typeof algorithms are you said
kinda confidential information that
if what if it was leaked or shared
so they could easily break into the
system's so the almost never find those
online
%uh you can actually get a hold of them
if you have some kind of corporate
relationship
with the CA they are shared
but there's a yearly audit to say okay
does your CBS master CP
and then actually are you actually
following your practice statement
tonight following your policies
so when you trust to see a you can
actually request their audit
you might not get the details on the
idea but you at least get yes the eye
passed a guest
fails so you can say are the following
what their CP says
SEM E and I have a field trip auditing
their friends
yes
some other done by the company
themselves are most are actually
required to be done by third parties
you did accounting firms do it
our company actually does them um and
there's a lot of companies that do them
federal PTI has a whole list companies
that they will accept on its from
so it's really what you know
you wanna pick somebody in the third
party that you know other people trust
to do the on it properly summers always
an independent third-party audit
some other smaller CA's may do internal
audits I depends on what they're used
for
all the big CA's to third parties
I can talk about the root CA protections
%uh hardware security module these
things these old boxes that hold the key
so never actually in the computer some
of them have temperature and motion
control so if you bought that box you
just wiped out the key
arm so these things are like very well
protected
you log in more than like twice without
the right password got a lot going on in
just a race the key and
see you later root CA um
yes
scary she feels the temperature spikes
most most ritzy A's are actually offline
and you the cards that are required to
put up this hardware module
are in them so they actually aren't
using those protections
most the time except once put it up I
if you are actually running and HSM in a
environment that you expect the heat
despite
I you gonna leave your key there are
there are backups
depends on what vendor you by the ages
some from and things like that s
rate ESA
you guys have modern equipment let you
know beforehand
but basically if you get outside of the
approved operating conditions is the way
to key
its business so people can take the box
you outdoor
with it so MPTP
which has variable levels of trust you
the trustor don't trust
speaking I certificate there is no in
the middle there's no marginal trust
it's all for not just all pecans weapon
mod
also known as Prosser to fight is one is
little boxes
you know bloop bloop PK I read picky I
green PK I
by different companies corporations her
you wanna magid
have decided to trust each other for
whatever reason eyes example say the
blue
certificate is air the blue CA is a the
is the FDA
and the red and green are a
pharmaceutical company
who wants to work with the FDA to some
electronic documents
well they need to make some kind a trust
relationship it's a lot
for anybody who's on Windows
administration it's a lot like a cross
forest
trust but there's a lot love policies
and politics to go into it
where the problems are discussed
certifying
is that policies don't always match up
if you have one CA
who wants to peace is a vindication and
one CA who wants one piece
identification
this policy is not match up and you
actually not an issue across certificate
because you can't insure that your users
that you have the same identity
verification across-the-board ICA's have
multiple policies
so you can have like federal bridge has
four policies basic low medium high
and you actually can cross certify at
one or more of those levels depend on
how you
define your certificate policy so that
kinda
helps the you know disparities and
identification
politics cross certifying with another
CA
just brings two organizations who may or
may not trust each other may or may not
like each other
together to try to figure all this out
and actually do the talking about the
technical part takes about five seconds
their estimate takes about 3-4 months to
actually go through across certification
I'll
pastel issue becomes much harder because
as you see there are no cycles in the
graph
so you have to worry about the cycles
and there's also interoperability
problems
so there are multiple vendors have CA
software
Microsoft entrust be trusted chosen
security
take your pick there are multiple love
them they don't
all fall the spec big surprise
um and in fact the specs not all that
detailed
there are some areas that are you have a
choice should me
you know must extra and we grow certify
you gotta work out all the technical
details
and make sure that 11 user on
PK i won you know wants to talk to peak
at to use user
that the actual gonna be able to build
the path gonna be able to talk to the
directories have begun a leveled
query the CRL 6 enter a say
you have major problems on the technical
like I said the technical issues
probably all that you can fully resolve
those in about a day or two
was a politics you still at months arm
so why do you want I mean there are
major house across our two guests so why
do you wanna bother trying to use them
what very few people actually need to be
involved only the owners
a PK I usually aboard %uh
Google owners once you know they really
want to have to be involved
they may bring some technical people and
answer questions and do the work but
most
is very few people are involved but
everybody as parties pick as benefits
from
it's not like 0 you know I did attack
every single person
because I want sexys like you wouldn't
believe me
just you know 45 people have to get
together actually do the work
everybody trusts everybody policies are
matched to each other so that the
consistent
and I was talking about earlier the and
it is very cation is not the only thing
has been mapped
it's also the physical security in the
CAA's its CEO Tom
how you know how many keys are required
to bring up the hard or soft hardware
security module
you know that two keys at three easy to
keys at five
how do you bring that up all that stuff
has to be kinda ironed out me figured
out before you can get across
certification
but their maths eventually and so
everybody knows that I have a
certificate with this policy
its gonna map pretty evenly to somebody
with another policy
and you guys never even see this part
it's all done in the software
expands Web of Trust for each user
and healing have to do anything lets you
run the CIA
cell house revocation and he can
even the user or the CAA can actually
that the certificate
depends on the policies some CA policies
don't let the user about
certificate must be the CA that does it
varies wildly
how to find the revocation information
is right there in the certificate
CL distribution point I say I want the
revocation information for this
and you go to this all that turkey ready
to go to this web page
and give me the CRL the CA issue serials
on a regular basis
um you usually i've seen on a six hour
when no I've seen a month when know it
depends on how sensitive it is that the
certificates be
you know active you know if it's
somebody's revoked certificate
how long can you wait for you have a
problem so that you can change it varies
wildly
see rose can be huge
would you love to Dallas 6 make file
every time I checked some a certificate
see if they revoked or not yeah I do
this on a regular basis at work
because whatever clients as a six make
cl5
so what are the ways you can get around
that is OCSP online certificate status
protocol
said one little packets as is as good it
sends you a packet back it says yes
no you trust it's also signed by the CIA
and
by the OCSP responder so you don't have
you can't trust it
by default the CRL assigned by the way
so you know that it actually came from
the CA that issued
the user the key does not control the
revocation information
I can't say you know go to cat5
for my revocation information 1c4
actually signed by Mikey
its associated with that information
there
so the user can have circumvent
so why would you want to use pgp a peek
at through quick
season is set up anybody can do it not
that difficult
does not require entire infrastructure
here I
is calling infrastructure for a reason
you really need all Eve the Armenian
order for people to trust you read CA
you need to have those protections
around
it's best suited for informal group
close group having points is
I anybody can become a CA is interesting
actors
so if you do wanna go the hierarchical
model you can it's there
just make sure you know what you're
doing make sure you really trust your
friends
make sure you trust your friends to
trust them if you're going to use this
the T sign
and if you want the variable trust you
gonna have to go PDP
there is no variable trust in BK Heights
if you do it that's important to you
you wanna use pgp so why would you want
to speak at
SSL I there is no free GPS is out
its it's also difficult based so
if you an SSL certificate you have to at
least be part of the a picky I and some
point
distribution keys certificates and trust
information to a very large number
users you talkin 20,000
hundred thousand five hundred thousand
users that you need to distribute this
information to
you're gonna wanna she's picky I because
you only have to worry about controlling
the route and maybe the subordinates
and you don't have to worry about you
know notify all these users
the things we vote because the
infrastructure takes care for you
you have more control over your
subordinates
so if you don't follow their policies
you can revoke them
service on my friend doc ski and I find
out he has been checking ID's
you know i cant it's very difficult I
can move my signature
by it I it's difficult to publish that
information
so you know it's it's have a difficult
revoking the GP
PK I actually allows legal dockets I am
in both europe and the US
AP ki i've a signature from eighty
trusted CA
whatever you define as a trusted CA is
actually considered a legally binding
signature on a legal document so
that PDP does not share that status is
right now
so that's great for is that
pharmaceutical companies so many
clinical trial data to the FDA they can
sign it and say
yes I checked it I you know I support
this information sent the FDA
that is actually legally binding
signature
cell to have any participating pageview
GvG
download it you know Kennedy is probably
the most popular there are others
generated keys make friends start
signing
post key signing party I'm
you know I'd actually I'm not going to
sign a key because I haven't changed my
key
mean yet I just got married in change my
name so mikey has been changed yet for
PGP
you know tracing center means likes get
your getting friends together have a key
saying hi it's not difficult
it's fine have a couple beers with it
beers and pizza
and then publish a key to a key services
you can use it
so happy participate began there's a
republic
keep PKS cáceres wanna
I V use it please donate I am not sure I
can assign a hundred points
so if you fill out the documentation I
can assure you if you find me later
basically you have to build up a certain
number of points by getting your
identity verified by
multiple people are by no trace in art I
actually went through the trusted
third-party model
where I had a good to know race they had
a check to pieces I T
and I had to send them off to Australia
to the state CA sur
they signed the 100 150 points which
makes me to share
and because I want to the process I can
now verify people's identities
are unfortunately I can't make you to
share I can only assign up to 35 points
per person
so you have to find to other assures as
well
I'm if you know if you want to go
through that process you can go ahead
and
you can talk to me there you those also
the thought whether
trust I very similar concept but is from
my thoughts
you can get a peek at a certificate from
their sign for a fee I think it's
fifteen back
you see fifteen box $14.95 418 only
singer
basically the check your email I'm in
the car charger 15 bucks for that
privilege
I and it goes progressively up from
there %uh if you want your
organizations verify Verisign
they're gonna charge about for five
thousand dollars
so but they really actually like jacks
off
according to their CP up private no
private pecan ice
you can make your own open S l's a great
CA
not a very good interface but it works
um
unfortunately probably no reason to
trust you accept your friends
I is where most self signed certificates
on the internet come from
your player might have a peek at I of
you work for federal government
I love the big pharmaceutical companies
have them a lot of defense contractors
have them
schools have for school employees
are and actually a lot of countries have
in Taiwan and China have their own you
guys for government
and so does Australia so you know
every also part of a trade or
professional organizations they may have
their own PK I
in order for you to get a certificate so
if you remember you check your
if you really want like a real pic and
certificate I don't pay Verisign your
couple hundred bucks
check with your employer your school you
know any professional organizations your
part have
and you they my house we can I they can
sign a certificate
cell any questions
yes
what happens in the CRL distribution
point changes basically
you get a I have no clue what the
revocation status is this certificate is
I'm not going to trust it what most
people do is actually a big deal
wanna see LDP changes I'll of course
you can change DNS you know you got it
she died hearing other shit up change
the DNS
that's one option but if for some reason
you know the name your organization
changed
you have to reissue of the certificates
so
you would actually like what you
actually deploy enabling the PK I
you're probably gonna spend six months
to a year
thinking about all the stuff what
happens if zips
CLEP goes down what happens if the root
CA gets flooded out what happens
if the data center gets blown up
yen-dollar has stuff
you know basically backup disaster
recovery planning that worry about
so takes a lot of planning to do it in a
whole infrastructure
my son other hands
okay
okay so what you're saying is that there
are there's a a working group in the
ITTF
thats I will is using PGP for
can you tell us so if you examine that
like
you know the status is again a teacher
US fully supports so some back there
yes
it just means that you'll that is that
that he will validate for you
so that when you check in email the
signature shows up as valid it does not
mean that you fully trust Nike
if you fully trust one key
you know if you sign Bob's key and Bob
you know you fully trust bob
then yields trust Nike Obama signed
the Sun other hand yes
PDP harbors records
who has those colonel cuz as
okay said they smart cards from a
company in Germany sink
crypto current concepts
and some is game you know that exult
over which i think is now jim also now
supports the PDP hardware I think token
a they all smart cards are they also USB
format okay okay
and ice on other hand back
it is
it public service announcement protect
your privacy you secure online backup
ok
okay
City uses DVD agent I actually is like
open to see some smart card
algorithms for talkin smart cards if you
push hard enough you can use your key
p.m.
player that good
his DVM doesn't have native support for
SSL
which gets freaky on their so yeah
in the questions or comments
thank you all very much life
his literally I they fit the time off
from john also