a catalyst are most known as richer
Cheshire
and as one journalist put it it's not
his real name is not even israel's gonna
let's see if I can find my talk to do
Churcher medalists dot com slash
mobil oil though HTML are there it is
programming your mobile phone for
international calling
things you should know about your phone
are
submission talks which can be found at
this page if you printed out
you can you ve copy the pages well
well over and talk about the day are
simple
little mobile phones I don't like the
term
cellular phones so describe the
technology
and technology confuses most people
euros just call it mobile phones
that's all they are other the Telus
on that the towers have a cellular
pattern to them
the public really doesn't have a need to
know there's no need to confuse and
they're confused enough
already my other pet peeve is when
people
us they all call the 800 number no no
please get in the habit they are tall
free numbers they are
terry cloth 800 888 877
866 855 with more to come they are
toll-free
area codes up star correcting your
friends that usually
helps me to remember it myself the
numbers look as well
well let's start off with placing a
mobile phone call
overseas I'll the United States
12 we invented the phones so we're
number one
actually so is Canada and most European
a country code 1
is designated the North American
numbering plan
first laid out by the Bell System in the
nineteen forties for internal use
starting the fifties they started
releasing is the public under the trade
name
direct distance dialing well
what's the the International
Telecommunications Union
is really gotta go to arm find out about
such things
so they're running out to a website in
Geneva Switzerland
where we find recommendation
he 1.1 Stuy Town 164
now the International Telecommunications
Union is united nations specialized
agency
they speak to sovereign governments on
since telecommunications is run by
governments and most
I've world except the US a few other
places the thing is you cannot tell a
sovereign government what you can do
you can only make recommendations
course these recommendations pretty much
have the force of treaties
well if we follow our way through
are will find that eventually reach a
place
where there are PDF
table of contents and eventually you get
to a place where they want to charge you
for copies of the recommendations when
you're seven government not a problem
but looking for a list of the
International country codes
and up comes the page with a nice IQ
logo
to you
jus UGG here we go and its gonna cut it
when it works
26 Swiss francs to see that ch
the two other country code for
Switzerland F for frank's
so no we don't want that thank you very
much
so let's go to the PDF version you
so Wikipedia page for eat out 164
and all down the page it gives you all
sorts of information about the stuff
and the list of country calling codes
zone one being the North American
implant area
us to mostly Africa summer weather guy
wins 3&4 Europe
three is mostly Northern Europe for is
southern Europe pfeiffer Mexico Central
America South America
a french-american dependencies there's
one off the coast of Canada
that has a 52 Southeast Asia for zone 6
Russia and Kazakhstan for zone 7 East
Asian special services for age
West South and Central Asia the Middle
East was on nine
so you can all just visit Wikipedia
for that information muncie
control that he gets back now I don't
particularly care for PowerPoint so I
write my presentations in HTML
I'm what I can't do is that like my head
lice to
the next headline so now we speak about
country exit codes now
what they want to call a friend in Paris
well thats country code 33
one for Paris 555 2368 what's a
arm from the US i would tell the North
American
exit code 011
33 for France one for Paris 550 2368
let's say stop off in Heathrow on the
way over in london
their I knew to use 00
33 one 555 2368 because in the CP
our country's and that is the committee
for European posts and telegraphs
arm what telecommunications accuse me
I'm
I harken back to all them times arm
that's their website they're 00 is used
in europe and in most of the rest of the
world
well that's fine and dandy but I wanna
put one phone number
in my contact list in my mobile phone
for this but you might in Paris
the trick is to use the plus sign
in the nineteen seventies the IQ came up
with this as a method
for mentioning a our country's exit code
before a
country code and then the city code and
the number
and so you have business cards for
example like this
a plus one 311
Phi Phi 5236 a and all your phone for
his work knows that number as being the
number
on the number plate in Bell System ads
from say the nineteen thirties on are
the voices 5552 3689 area cuz came along
these
311 which is never been a record never
will be
et cetera are so
along come mobile phones in the nineteen
nineties so you know
we've got the site you standard that
says just for praying about business
cards
use a plus sign and since all of our
mobile telephone switches are
software-defined
what what we just use that same plus
side to be the
love the country Xoco he does reach up
to the network
are pulled down whatever country exit
code you need in that country
use that and put the number through
it made sense they did anyway
so I what you can do is in the contact
list love your overseas correspondence
take out the 011 replace 011
with the plus sign character it will be
on your keyboard
either on the zero or on the one you may
have to hold down 20 to get the plus
sign
or I love some other will trick but it
will let you put a plus sign in there
for one thing your carrier was that
revenue for that overseas call
so I can make sure that their phones
have a plus sign in their
are the wireless carriers will tell you
to dial
the country exit cooked but not putting
your concept was
up for example let's just take a look at
how sprint so those things
I am naughty to put it into
the contact list how do I make an
international call
arm and let's see
that's control shift plus is a
when calling country country dial the
access code plus the country code
are common in the country blah blah blah
are
die over plus key to automatically or
dial that country's access code
to go they will tell you to dial the
plus key
the other countries well they called
access code CR
code exit the country's network plus the
country code plus the phone number
answers provided Nokia GSM phones first
post key twice into a plus sign appears
on your phone's display screen
so tell you how to die out there with a
nap when you put it in your contact list
I'm the guy telling you put it in your
contact list
in no matter where in the world you are
if your phone works in the first place
it will put the call through
see the nice thing is I can just click
on the things in my HTML presentation
show you the different pages arm
no horizon again
as your four years ago talk about
Verizon back medicine as a direct
assistance after I can find my phone
book
they're going such good put 2011 plus 44
all that well over 13 years at local
number well
keep in mind the rise in has CDMA phones
so their phones won't work overseas most
places so they may as well just 30 2011
they do have a couple things they call
world phones
arm a major investor in Verizon Wireless
is an outfit called Vodafone and they
are very big
in Europe in the sewer markets so
they have special arrangements if you're
going overseas to use Vodafone service
Vodafone is in many places around the
world the
arm there primarily in Europe so I
understand it
and other you have a presence here
through Verizon
and group wrong button hang on
no I don't want that now thank you very
much
phones you know back on the road again
so extras
okay so as seen on the phone body mine
actually met you are
went to China and got the manufacture to
make
the hope badges he was in China about
his TV B Gone
work with them on our badges as well are
the RFID badges
so while he was there since his on
mobile number I'll hit send to mobile
number of his Chinese cell phone when
he'd rented over there r2r
our list i text message m and ask that
you please send me
all the digits as they show up above my
phone number
and he told me that my phone never came
back 001
321 my four day recur plus the rest my
phone number
00 being the exit code from China
going to a North American 10
was remembered plan was American number
and then my number
when he responded to me are
in my caller ID this text message came
from
011 which I'll was the exit code for me
if I wanted to reply to him
86 for China plus the digits of his
phone number
so again the PLO signed should be used
because up that way the phone call
or the text message will go through no
matter where it's placed
in the world are here's my rant about
never calling it an eight hundred-number
because of all the various
toll-free area codes that are available
and
are dial the exit code followed by the
country could remember as you would from
on an international call from that
country by the way back up here
I had an example love a British phone
number we're gonna have that now
arm here plus 44 for the UK
but on UK business cards what you'll
find
is they have a zero in parentheses
and this is part of the eye view
specifications well
arm a number for the national service
love your nation's phone network if
you're in the UK you don't need the 44
country code of course
but you do need 0 in front of the number
to access
are what was then an STD standard drunk
dialing
I think with the controversies have
sexually transmitted disease are not
using that particular
acronym anymore but arm
before the standard truck dialing is it
was called at one time you need those
euro before the City Code
778 in this case and and the residue
number
so this year was used in the national
service
today you could probably get away with
just having the PLO's 44
778 14 you know
and the number in your contact was
without
08 they have it work within England I do
not know anybody I can has to try that
for me
so I can't be certain that but are I
would
there's a that the its our sewer
networks over there
are cognizant love how to set things up
for international dialing will others
through
see arm
just other stuff I spent a year as
a technician for prize where was done in
Florida and/or
one thing you like to recommend people
was it is not a good idea to talk to
your mobile phone
why what's plugged in just for battery
charging reasons
are if you should you should it was only
for better solo you feel the call
because of
on most other powers provided the reason
being
the lithium-ion batteries in the mobile
phones
are have a limited number charges to
them
so your jacket in you have a full charge
when I talk on the phone
while you're talking the charred
overcomes below a threshold
but says 0 well I start charging the
phone now and there goes another above
those funded number charges gone away
I reaches the top lawyers still talking
so it stops charging
and you're still talking in you know
using up some battery
if you miss later the threat against oh
I guess I could start charging again now
and there goes another one of those find
it never a charge is gone away
so you should I unplug the phone when
you're talking on it
on what's the charges solo you'd be cut
off
I like to use Bluetooth headsets
I've lost mine this weekend serves a
but arm Bluetooth headsets
use low power to go from your year
to your phone which is within 30 feet a
view Bluetooth
on the works of range about 30 feet and
um using your it's a lot closer to you
than that
usually holding if or it's in your
pocket or whatever else
it doesn't take that much power to get
there compared to the amount of power
going from the phone
to the nearby towers
I don't know about you I'm a little ham
radio operator I like having that much
transmitting power that close to my head
so I much prefer Bluetooth headsets to
having the phone at my head
in fact what actually this is its it's a
long story what got you fun but usually
it will do that I'll put it on speaker
phone
with looks bigger on the other side up
the handset and I'll talk this way
because I can still hear program the
whole the phone is close to my head
when I don't have the headset had
are any questions
its yes
up my web address here is a Cheshire
catalyst dot com chce
SH Irie cata
lyst dot com and the pages slash
mobile dot HTML and
I'm now let's see we can probably not
this back a bit to just bring up home
page
and making sure the surface since 1975
now I have a friend we refer to as
subtlety impaired is now the term I use
is because the FBI know that you are
agencies
but he didn't notice till the server
wasn't couldn't figure it out just
hearing it a soldier server some who
watches you over your shoulder
as you surf the ARPANET crossed out
internet
I just had throwing I'm so old school
though
you know did have the ARPANET way back
when on
and then somebody asked me about ok a
question about my leadership position in
the
computer hacker community so I came up
with this I am NOT a leader
I'm a loner with people who happen to
follow me nobody in mind have a pipe up
and certainly this John Quincy Adams
quote if your actions by others to dream
more learn more do more and become more
you are a leader
well 22 is more by accident than design
in my case
I'm also
I needed some help to get here and
ahead my so my neck ties I'm debates
I so the longer work for prized roles in
longer have to wear ties
and I've amass a small cluster telephone
ties anyone here when you have my
ties I saw three of them okay
I have the ship these I was there for
get home %uh
this rustic wood products gotta 80 s sex
on it
our satellite it's got a large block one
GPS a whole buncha eighties technology
arm this one you'll notice has the
ability is the
symbol upside down I happen to have them
with me
and the few that have not been sold on
eBay are now available
if you look up to me after the talk also
I do have
arm time for show-and-tell
I've got my little ebook
which is basically a bunch of my web
page is all one place
collected from my various web sites yumm
we have an awful of you have
with case being fit
secured by well I still have to force
drivers
I had the CD-rom fifth
thrown back to you earlier so I have a
cd-rom version of churches book and the
book is called
of course their secrets there in the
manual on CD-rom or on flash drive
1 gigabyte flash drive cd-rom for 15
flash drive for twenty and
see me after the talk are any further
questions
general yes
the question being about the overall
theme ion batteries and how many charges
do they really have
are generally it's got about a year's
worth
others pose less about a year to year
and a half and if you can go two days
between charges as your last that much
longer
so now that I've been able to figure out
no
and while working at Verizon I know some
people coming back
with batteries from brand new phones
within a month and
I suspect may have just been a bad
better batteries out a career
you're mostly all Samsung phones so if
you do have a major problem with a
battery
uptake Apeksha carrier and and complain
and you know the technician does it easy
on you may just what yet battery
to rise and we had a times field was six
months old we give it was of a new
battery
you know so on so forth but that was
pretty much up to the discretion of the
technician
yes
would
I don't believe in a personal question
no
else
okay well got some extra time
arm couple years ago when I was here
what's the
back go where we were talking about rise
in
up now that talk six years ago was my
directory assistance
talk that's not what I'm looking for
right now
arm flash Talk
job HTML my talk two years ago on flash
sucks
for advertisers guess what it still does
I am what really
really got me pissed this year now over
the past couple years I get these the
email from Pepsi
with all these contests and things I
click up in all of those once I get
there get flash forget gonna
so I get gone but this year they're
stepchild
Mountain Dew as a website
that they put up as a promotion called
all school or new dot com
damnit my computer is
old-school and I can't see your flash
site song as if I can gets over to ever
does gauge
magazine this week and talks to me about
that
know about that let's see now
are because Greg had another speaker are
going on you to be needed to install the
Flash was just see
all school warned you
dot com me actually work this time
yep but you see how long it takes to
load the dam software
to to run the thing and
how much of this crap you are really
want to see anyway %uh
just type in rules going on
rules the PHP I found out
with police but you look up the rules
without having to put up with all those
stuff
well maybe not taken again see what
happens
okay forget about it
we're gonna go back
it's taking over my machine okay
so much for that
okay
there is a website
called flash sucks that work this is a
great site because it explains
that it's a great tool if used well
but it sucks for visitors sucks for
disabled people and socks for search
engines
is ever housing agencies should know
better and I'm very proud to say
the right down here my webpage
is way too from flash Sox dark work come
back to my page again
%uh but also on this page if you wanna
be in control a flash
you can go to flash block that must have
dug word
and download a flash blocker
because a lot love the love the flash
stuff just really don't need arm
when on my web pages
is I used to have single racing dot com
I now have ATT 31 reason dot com
you 8031
dot com are cuz I was so grateful to
both ability for my phone number
which I believe I'll explain on
my phone numbers 32 one liftoff and
that's because it's my a rico
knowing that no time arm but they're
kinda you to me in the days before
number portability I was always great
for the possibility
which has now morphed into AT&T so I've
I keep a fan website
love the the team up
since a member but ok racing family won
the race I love to cook or
0 400 you can know click this get a
coupon for free coke 0
why you'd want when I don't know arm
but down here
I want a few places even the fan web
sites the key factor the associate
sponsors
and ask our because it's all over it has
been really
my interest is in the cars go fast in
turn left my interest is in the
advertising arm
there's an all fashions concert called
the use map
where I can click on something here and
this will go to the snap on website
I can click here to go to the GM card
website
and that seems fairly obvious
I kind with the Easter eggs with you
click on Jeff Burton signature appeared
go to Jeff Burton dot com
unfortunately his needs flash so
I like to say that they're saying get
flasher get gone
and I guess I didn't have the right
version of Flash
since arm didn't come up
yeah he doesn't have flash
so I MUST HAVE not have the right
version
own Fairfax prevent the sofa bring a
pop-up window so they do not countenance
the things you know
you but he's our driver this year's was
born and
to a if you're into NASCAR The O'Jays
you dot com
is where things are are informational on
NASCAR
and okay I guess is
not working this week what is a bye week
for NASCAR I'm running this week
arm and a clever thing I do
if you do a year
view source on this web website know the
Allstate 400 coming up it doesn't have
finishes or exist because as run your
our book
if you do view source
control all-state
you'll see I've got the races for the
rest of the year actually
in this file but
remarked out my regular cell phone as my
Treo 650 about the SIM card the other
one because
this one is church's the SIM card from
churches line in here need for pretty
keyboard for messaging
through involves record nations weekend
artwork
the trio also has is an FTP program file
transfer protocol
i can download the webpage at around the
phone
and send it back up course love
I can't always get to it in time I would
like to you
was what I like to do is
up actually change the finish position
at the Cup points and add up
the the series total for the year
be four jaise ki sent me the text
message with the results
and have it up on the net while sitting
at my local bar watching the race
who also knows a little dots down here
the first up is where the entry list
will be
if you look up its are entry underscore
with Doug HTML
if I actually not this back from slash
twenty to slash
19 for the 19th race last phrase
that's popular with the entry was for
the last race
and if we want to we can go to
lineup there was the lineup for the last
phrase
these are all drive just changes the
race number
so anyone who wants to do i hack around
on my webpage
will find that these dots go to these
other pages if I haven't gotten around
to
updating the page they want the
information they can click on the docks
and do that
I was there for hackers to find
I just cuz you know if I'm too lazy to
get the information that has to be able
find the information
so you'll have to forgive me and simply
ego tripping here
and I thank you for your patience your
question yes
since I have not travelled overseas in
more than a decade no I have not done
the research on No
putting other countries and cons SIM
cards into my phones
what research I have done is just
swapping swell SIM cards
in my phone and mine isn't unlocked Treo
so I have put T Mobile cards into work
and they've worked
here in the States I my love what's what
between to AT&T phones
and so now you know the winds are swabs
are so I could %um
where do you do heavy-duty data on the
other guys line
I can do it and that's what the SIM
cards back and beyond
on my line again I am right now I'm I'm
on Twitter from you adjust for the
weekend cuz -ism hope people on Twitter
and so I wanna buy Twitter a change
which phone number
it was going to do so is back on the
phone with QWERTY keyboard again
and I'll go back change the phone number
there
that's what the SIM cards and I'm back
on still the same funds
will be keeping track of things but
other funds if it's not unlocked phone
particularly
it will accept other SIM card so I
assume it would accept them
for overseas use as well I haven't seen
any
I don't know political problems but I
have a travel and I haven't I would look
into it
are living in the Cape Canaveral area
Port Canaveral is a major cruise ship
port
we have a little cyber cafe
on the side of the local mall where the
little just the buses
poll up with the cruise who are off duty
from those ships
it's their cyber cafe to go in they buy
a phone card
I think we also buy SIM cards in there
and you know the place calls all over
the world got phones all over the place
for people with this phone home and for
those who have cell phones that they
want to use
%uh they do sell SIM cards as well so
you know major international cities
gonna find places like that
he writes a ask the concierge you know
in this hotel
and I'm sure you can point to some work
overseas same thing as the concierge yes
or do I have to tell that I get an
you to force me to ego trip %uh okay
well back around September 98
the public the Florida Public Service
Commission decided
that they had just put 407 up their
regular exchanges like everywhere else
and they had to hold the Public Service
Commission hearing they put a little
notice other newspaper which I have the
catch
by look at my schedule now go to work
that night sorry
sewing up well nobody else might either
and when it finally have a newspaper
that there was a Public Service
Commission hearing about flee the area
code
huge uproar over and I'll tell hasset
well they decide to schedule a
second-round
up hearings so it's going in orlando is
gonna be
others Thursday then I can work that day
to you
well if you're going the extra trouble I
said what's good about the Internet
and footsie being a phone freak I know
there's such a thing as
Nampa .org the economic benefits tration
never that work
up and I'm let's see oh there's the list
out there you know the list to a new
jersey joe to DC blah blah blah blah
and the gaps are marked available for
geographic relieve
okay and if you are marked are easily
recognizable number
these usually ends in double digits 43
problem okay so we're going to have a
listener come across 321
wine is that strike a familiar all of
course countdowns
women I live in the countdown camp with
the world
K I want that number
time to bring down the web browser time
to bring up the word processor
and begin preparing my testimony for the
Public Service Commission hearing was
held in the Orlando City Hall
in the city council chambers I was
dear shiftless I meet it was too obvious
well it was too I've used it somebody
who was both the phone freak and a space
cadet
it was not obvious that anybody else in
the room until
I got up to preserve my testimony I want
I pointed it out
there was instantly obvious the one
Sherman although
the one commission members that you know
we like to have this kind of sugar
coating
to put on the bad news the people or get
that they have to change your area code
this is a great idea and the really
interesting thing
was that the chairman of the Commission
came up to me
after the meetings which is that you
know sir
we went in and good and we requested
such a list as you provide in your
testimony
that you got off the internet and they
told us it was proprietary
I want to thank you very much for your
testimony
and you know what mere personal
conjecture
I think she went back to name for I
think you read the manual I'm
I got as the area code thank you
and that's pretty much the story are
well but I wake up one morning and of
course voice and NPR's Morning Edition
I with morning edition I'm so bad I
answer their pledge funds so most things
though pat dougans local guy on morning
edition that you may know the name for
myspace coverage
they pick that up nationally and
pet starts off the day by saying it's
official
the next area code will be the last 32
just a dash notes here when the
yes okay I got it it's mine what I asked
for it they approved it
exit my area code right but I share
there was one thing I wanted so I doubt
the number
the number you have reached that also
body is not currently in service
cool I ran down to the kiosk at the mall
hi I'd like 543 8633 please well she
cause a problem with her oh I'm sorry
sir
but the boys in Melbourne tell me that
that number is in the middle of a
hundred group
and a corporate rate its totally
unavailable all
okay so I go
high-power the web browser males are
good luck a
her okay all about the company up
mark feat was present at the company
that might be nice to know
from but I don't have his email address
is certainly not your his bio
and 00 press room okay let's go work
over the press releases before I ever
was But the 3G %ah
there it is the email address book
publicity flack
first name on his girl s name at %ah
come close to mark under square feet
were at their mister fiedler
blah blah blah my Rico blah blah blah me
a please their 5438 633
so that as a about over first 1999 my
phone number will be
3 to one lift-off sended
ha I look at my watch in at 6:30 p.m.
on a Friday I can't possibly your
phone's going till
what bind it probably Tuesday
Sunday afternoon thing you have new mail
sure about people on it and so I got
phone
you
other questions to thank you very much
thank you said