all right when it started with the next
panel just a couple reminders all the
discussions you can
purchase on DVD so if you missed one
it's in the next room I couldn't decide
which one you want to go to
I'm you can buy both and on DVD
the burned right after each session and
are available right out there
also please keep about this space clean
pick up after yourself turn your mobile
phones to vibrate
so is quite helpful and Dom
please I the the hotel pennsylvania's
been quite nice to us so please be nice
back to them and keep the hijinks
outside the hotel
I E turning off televisions with
a infrared devices that you might have
on your keychain
things like that would be greatly
appreciated
I but let's get to the next discussion
these guys
I have been in many hope conferences and
I personally support their efforts
financially
I as well as you should I cents
the nineties when radio stations and
radio conglomerates who had
12 stations 18 stations are suddenly
able to by every station
in town and form what are called
clusters
which I always add an extra word after
cluster
I'm radio has really taken a nosedive to
what it used to be and that is a a
mouthpiece the community
and the from EDS radio project has spent
fighting for low-power FM stations and
has been doing radio barn raising its
and have done at least eleven
but right now I love I set up radio
stations
in communities for communities as
opposed to
more crap for Clear Channel oMG this is
petri dish and Steph 99 that from me is
radio project
good morning good Saturday morning
I'm Stephanie this my friend Pete we
work with an organization called the
committee's radio project based in West
Philly
and it's not as Asian that helps
community group all over the world other
radio stations
so today we're going to talk about how
to teach technical topics
non-technical people we're gonna eat
talk about some other chicks that we've
learned over the years to get past those
like
googly eyes that happen when you try to
explain something he really excited
about 12:30
I and help how to help people get over
their fears and maybe even get a little
excited about technical stuff
so a look at a map about my background
at any UNIX nerd for about 12 years
a sold-out chance for a live audio
recordings have
like technical courses into designing
products and I didn't realize that I
wasn't expected to learn this on our
system in the office so
in them next thing you know the Nexus 7
and I work for the university's
up pennsylvania where I'm also working
on a master environmental studies
and um but the reason I'm here has a lot
to do with the previous radio projects
as a volunteer at a tech trainer over
the years about the hacking 02 11 makes
it is really big antennas to set up
studio transmitter links with farm
workers in Oregon
as hell to middle age women how I'm in
South Carolina
create their own Ethernet cables efforts
with the community center in the ghetto
love
there'll be Kenya and watched their
low-power radio station go back on the
air
after week sitting down and seem like
the trance innovation happens there
and have worked with students volunteers
who went into workshop
not knowing like and defense cable from
a twist tie in coming out my climbing up
the mixer
so I've been able to witness these like
a lightbulb moment so much that you
start to turn
and see that magical moment when someone
who's deathly afraid of technology
starts to understand it
that like K I edit this isn't that hard
murderer doesn't hands-on so I'm excited
to share what
but that had the things that have worked
and have worked over the years
some all
y'all are gonna have to forgive me
because I came down with them
some a call the other day and sell ALM
you'll just have to listen kinda closely
kid all that sultry and our
so up from EDS was started about 12
years ago
calm we so we build radio stations about
how far work is
is technical training and physically
building radio stations
and about how is trying to change the
laws that govern radio
and actually make that process more
clear to people to you how to
how to affect government how to change
%uh change the rules by which the Salt
Lake
on we have to start from the ass is a
pirate radio station
that I was involved with called radio
mute me home
there's a couple people around here that
were that were involved in radio Muni
it was a smallest of the station
basically came from a group of us who
are
activists who I worked in different
movements I'll
im aids in odd and housing
environmentalism against war and
but while all of us kept on coming up
against the same problem again
again which is we would we knew that
people cared about the issues that we
were talking about that there was no way
that we could break
into that up mainstream media and we
start to realize that in fact that that
the media
was owned by the very corporations in
many cases that
that you're opposed to and are we
figured out
that there was no way that we are going
to to win that game I'm
when they owned I the means through
which most people
learn about these things so the site
starter on not about that ever been on
the rate on
on the radio none of us knew anything
about radio
home but now we we got this
transmitter kit from somewhere and we
tried to solder it together and
you know we thought a written just
sharply lower upton
totally didn't work at all and then
we've got another one and we
blew that one up to you but eventually
after
I'm a number of tries he finally got the
like little working
20 watt transmitter that suddenly start
broadcasting across Philadelphia and
then
within a few weeks on we had
%ah sixty or seventy programmers look
coming on
from all different social movements all
different styles of music that were
never on the
on the rate for was out really really
thrilling up project for us
arm and arm
strangely enough odd you know I mean I
was a pirate radio station so
so we could very well arm you know go to
jail or get ten thousand dollar fine or
get the government confiscates
confiscated we ran for about a year and
a half and finally the FCC did kick down
the door and take take away the
the pair transmitter but some really
strange happened on the way without
which was that actually
that chairman of the FCC Saurabh changed
his mind about
about pirate radio and he
started saying before I leave office I'm
going to make sure that there is a legal
way for these people to do this
and arm so from EDS I
we decided well like you know someone
that powerful changes that my job to
likes or
someone's gotta be there to hold them
accountable so we started legal
organization
with the call upholding FCC accountable
and making the very
most out of this sore this this
opportunity that was created
on so we've been building the station's
ever since and the way that we most like
to build
radio stations is with what we call a
radio barn raising where we bring
together
about 150 200 people for a week and then
we have thirty or forty workshops about
how to wire up the mix are how to you
are connected phone pouch
how to set up your station governance
how to do your fundraising
and and everything starts out in boxes
on
on Friday morning and then by Sunday
it's got out just work
and the vast majority of people have no
experience im
in radio but by the end everybody has
has helped to build this radio station
cell so that's that but
when I hear talk about that actually
work what I've noticed that
at at hope conferences over the years is
that there are lots of people
there are two people here that know a
lot more about radio than I do actually
sell
the point about the for me to talk about
about on the radio engineer but I'm
kinda about one
um but appeal
satan saying that we probably have a lot
of nerves here who know a lot about a
lot of things
and a lot of them may have X experience
the same troubles that
that we've had over the years trying to
get very non technical people to
to to learn and am and love technology
the same way that we do
and so were we just have a bunch of taps
that we've generated over the air some
other more common sense
um some with some you may be new to you
so that's what we want to
to share with you so I want a quick shot
count
who hears ever tried to share something
really interesting to you
about a technical topic am they people
just look at you like you're from
fucking mars
you okay yeah I'm kinda not surprised
okay have you ever felt like just
totally helpless trying to explain
something like
how to send them email to your
grandmother like just totally
disempowered totally out of control
nothing I say can help this percent
everyone
yeah okay yet so you know funny you
should mention
grandmothers cuz my techno missus is my
mother ever in this country to talk a
lot about like farm workers and
journalist and activist but ok us my mom
I'm so it's a little frustrating but it
kind of comes our relish the challenge
is like explaining to her the difference
between a web browser and and I S key
so I'm so the Sony they do it with her
on this is like immediately applicable
tell a lot of us first to keep the big
picture
really really clearly reestablished what
is that she's trying to do
she describes what she wants to do and
what happens when she tries and like
how it like it just it doesn't
he goes away and so so she she describes
like
okay will so she doesn't need to know
like them new shit like how an MTA works
but she can describe your needs as a
user
I want to send an email to all my
siblings I want to print was no wires
I want to scan a picture and send it to
us to some people so we keep
we keep cytological and thank you
connecting to it through the process
next and let her we'd she's not don't
just smart and other ways
and this is key if you can remember that
people people are smart
you just have to figure out like how
they can connect with what
what they want to learn that'll really
get you through a lot of frustration
so explain and not to break down the
problems she kinda understands
the lines between that the test is
trying to do and ask probing questions
to see what she thinks we should do next
and you'd be surprised how easily people
will pick up on anything kinda like
nudge them okay we're trying to do this
so what do you think comes next
on and nap and that way she owns the
process when she goes to try and do it
again
it's not going to be like this her
memories are gonna be like a whirlwind
of clicks
it's gonna be a logical process as she
can think herself through again
and on her attention for this has been
really really good um
a use and abuse analogies which is
something we're gonna go over a little
bit more
later on but like the wireless print
server described in terms our radio
so the AP is the radio station her
little while scores again for laptop
that's the radio receiver and she went
so far as to get out like the freezer
tape in sharpie and read we have on
for two radio station printer radio host
and it worked for her really well
and last ago very very slowly
so slowly in fact it might even come off
as condescending to someone who knows
what they're doing
but it doesn't come across that way to
her fortunately
and it's not certainly is not meant that
way but is really important to go slowly
enough that you can see that like both
come on
after every every like a logical chancy
don't move on until
you can see that recognition that okay
now I understand I own this part of the
process and then you can move on
what a sweet are message to think
I'll okay so when we
started working with farmworkers I'll
a lot of them talked about this thing
called pop your education and I
I didn't know what it was so I looked it
up it turns out to be this
educational philosophy um and a set of
techniques around education developed by
um a Brazilian educator name up for our
rights
um and I found this quote on the
Internet I really love
um for for a number of reasons
so 30 for education
for RA implies a dialogic exchange
between teachers and students
where both learn both question both
reflect and both participate
in meaning making concretely this
pedagogy begins with the teacher
mingling among the community
asking questions at the people and
gathering a list of words used in their
daily lives
the teacher was to begin to understand
the social reality of the people
and develop a list of quote generative
words
and teams which could lead to discussion
in class is for cultural circles
by making words or literacy relevant to
the lives of people
process a conscientious is a sham could
begin
in which the social construction of
reality might be critically examined
the year 1962 you saw first experiments
and prairies method
when 304 markers we're taught to read
and write
in just 45 days now I think that this
is just so fuckin funny
that hot topic as grassroots as
um you know teaching %ah teaching
farmers to read
has has an incredible jargon of its own
a home that his %uh impenetrable like
words like conscientious is a surname
dialogue exchange um so it's about
that's cool enough itself just about
every field of human endeavor house like
just like him have Malta technical words
but the other thing that I liked about
it was was this idea
um up up the education going two ways
and arm and and the and the need for
relevance
and on so we were thinking about how we
could apply this to
to teach in radio and unfortunately
there were no generative words like
the team decibel yaki or
electromagnetism around him
in the lives of the people working with
but we we definitely liked
to incorporate the idea that everyone
was learning and everyone was teaching a
mess
in this circumstance on okay so
here there's our last up some things
what one thing that we try really hard
to do
is that if I am some key terms early
there is nothing stupid are then
teaching for all
our only to realize that half the people
do not know what a what is after you've
been talking about know a lot to kill a
lot some
group does a lot so whatever arm
and whenever I I come across on these
words that people have
have trouble with I try to go back to
you its
it's really in things that people
usually experience i cum
like frequency is a good one all
a lot of people say also I wanna I wanna
build the low-frequency radio station
he are and about you know one response
is like smack
you know it's a low-power radio station
I'll
but but it's actually helpful when when
you look at
at what is I'll you know where these
words come from and how they relate
so with frequency I take to purchase all
one is like what is frequency
how would you use it im if we weren't
talking about radio how would you use
that
you know the frequency at which I pick
my nose like three times per how are you
know
or or whatever um and radio just happens
to be something that happens much more
frequently
them them pick my nose %ah you know my
life cycles per second
yeah all and top but
okay so that's what frequency years but
what we actually use it for
it something totally different we we
have to use frequency to distinguish
between just for channel so
a frequency is really more like a name
for
for a station that that using cell if
you if you go back to like
where r people might know something from
and also home but then
talk really practically about about what
they're gonna use it for
that's that's really helpful
arm sue next thing we have in our list
is to use and abuse metaphor and
they recover metaphors analogies the
P-three's is that I
I really enjoyed you want the stadiums
get that one
balances start with the essay yeah it's
a large him God
so um so a I can not I could never
remember for the life of me
how to wire pin XLR cable the the ground
like %uh
the heart mccall to the one two and
three on the adapter thingy so I came
over this
just stupid memory aid so you know if
you're if you're solitary for one year
ground is the one goes the ground
and if if there's two you know I two's
company hot
mates is so hot where goes the two
and then you know trees three's a crowd
so once you have a third
Khan called so um that is the only way I
could remember this thing and I
pass it on to you as a friend of mine in
phnom in
enough western Kenya actually and he
took it and like
put this like artistic flourished on and
sorry I was like a wise man once said in
a kinda
like every every iteration up this late
retelling of this
memory a god-like more more artistic and
beautiful until it
was appreciably less stupid than how I
it started with it
and with there's another one when your
soldering you wanna put like the heat
the you save my the heat than the cider
take this on our way and take away the
key
so a technical director any gun in Kenya
came up you know he kind it was doing on
this is a dance so
during the whole trip to Kenya am used
on you he
cider cider he keeps others he and
people
um clung to this so well the body into
the trip our friends there how to rap
about this
in the local oMG local Nairobi so he
called Shane
it was fucking amazing gorgeous so
you know the stupid use enough sweets
yeah yeah it doesn't hurt to like just
make up a stupid story to
like if I'm trying to explain the way
that a transistor act as an amplifier
all just like they something like okay
like let's say that you have a bunch of
like corporate executives that you wanna
smash on the hat and
and happened out that the services of a
75-foot giant but unfortunately the
giant
is blind and deaf and um and so
doesn't know when to use his giant club
to smash these
dudes and and so what you can do is you
can put a little
Elf on his shoulder who can II
who who can here and then you just
send a little signal over to the Al and
elf
like polls on the hereof the giant and
then to
and then Aug you know it just goes you
know and
and so that that is the effect of a
transistor
like letting you know taking very small
signals amplifying
make making the much larger and I you
know you just try
you I could talk about collectors and
I'm matters and
and all that sort of thing but but
frankly I forget that whenever
I tried to talk about itself so this
feels like it's okay to be campy
is um it so wasn't our next point which
is put yourself in peoples mercy
make mistakes teach in a different
language and
tell people how the how you figure
things out for you don't know what the
hell you doing
a minute when you don't know something
make it clear that
you're not smarter than the people that
you're teaching and and do things that
they for use other peoples mercy
so that so that so that they've and it's
this that is reserved for suspect it's a
source of humor
was a good things can happen so um see
what you wanna get across that
you happen to know maybe that's one
thing but the notes and stuff you want
you wanna learn from them as well when
you do that a couple things happen not
only dudu
like actually sincerely edifying that
the person that you teaching
but you also said a breakdown this
teacher-student hierarchy
you kind of breakdown this authority
figure versus observer you eliminate
that sounds like
who you're sitting up there too fancy
soldering annual
to be installed its the door and I'm got
there
a and so see you you add to the sense
that like collaborative learning
on and you know you get a you get to be
that person to the feeling that they're
the experts
and I'm and that if they walk out of a
seminar which other weather
ever feeling like they totally own this
situation
and you're just like some smokers have
pointed a couple things out to them
then that's the epic win when you look
like an idiot
that's the win yeah it's good
II I always insist on like burning like
the numbers and the colors and
and that's our thing and then when I
screw up it's like
it makes it a little bit more even like
because okay they forgot
you know that it's %uh MRF 240 M
I forgot the name for the color blue to
sorry
creates an object to even the score a
little bit
on okay another teaching track
do not over engage a single individual
whenever ideal like a class or something
there's always some to you in the third
row
that knows like way more way way more
than everyone else in the group
and he wants to start talking about like
what happens if you do a colocation up
the HD radio signals with the sell your
panel antennas and blah blah blah blah
and gotta be justly called on did
I'm totally taking out for a beer later
to talk about this but we cannot go they
are in this class because
you know this isn't between you and I
this is you know this is a
a group learning experience and you just
gotta um
not necessarily like it gauge that and
then like out
everybody else to now very very
important to be assertive
cuz when you are trying to communicate
something to a large group
you cap you can't just like take the one
person
similarly to run on that flip side to
that um it's important not to engage
individuals fears others a lot of times
they are people who are coming or shops
you
I'm were coming in like kinda scared to
take the touch technology
there's that person if you are
submissive to me it is required off to
the side
engage that person get that person to to
touch the technology get that person
um to you engaged in the process be
sympathetic to their wariness
understand whether where he's coming
from and respects
especially respect that they can to the
space to to try and get over that
but don't let them while 0 on the ticket
stub just gonna give more from little
knowledge to the next step
don't do it for them don't whatever the
task is don't do it for them but
acknowledge that it looks kinda
complicate on the surface
the keep them focused on the angle so
that by the end of the workshop they can
understand how
how awesome it feels too like figure
this thing out and get it done
the next see I'm so
its this is so difficult some of us have
to learn to shut up
it's okay to like leave some space
I'm we ask each we get really excited
about the things that were interested in
you wanna talk about every aspect of it
we talk really fast we don't stop
talking cuz everything so interesting
but we need
to learn to embrace the awkward silence
so it's okay it's just like put a
question out there just really let it
hang until it feels uncomfortable
because at some point somebody is gonna
venture a guess I find that
even quite people talk under two
conditions when they care enough
and when their space to speak and when
you leave that space you leave space for
unexpected learning and even
leadership stars2 stars to pop up if you
fill in every step we silence
that not everyone is 30 if there's not
everyone is motivated to compete for
space to speak so if you fill in all the
silence as you might miss
a great question are brilliant insight
and so to bring to try not to squashes
opportunities because
your self conscious about silence you
engender the geniuses the people around
you
and down and that way you also
bolsters Jason a participatory learning
so you know
it's okay to be quite some time up
okay and other one very common for nerds
very common for nerds to make up the
fallacy
up being way more accurate than
necessary
this isn't science its technical
education
said don't say 4.57 time to tend to the
23rd
cry six just say a zillion because
you know that's what people need to know
is a big is that small is that
you know that's key all
another one boots or somewhere that is
it doesn't some
it doesn't heart act sometimes I I had
this professor wants
do his time an older guy
and he was he was teaching out
%ah you know some basic electrical
physics and
he would be like okay so we've got a
buncha quantities here we've got power
we've got car and
we've got powers the style some so which
formula do we
do you think we'll will fit this like
well we could use them
p walls I'll by
a square heard I'll fuck
and and so everyone in the class our
minds are all like
people's I squirt are for fucks sake
fuck an old coot I can't believe
you know so like but he was making our
minds jump ahead of what he was saying
and I caught him kinda like acting a
little bit more
%ah %ah tottering many really was
sometimes
so its it have a good track let people
like finish their sentences and
you know it's it's very job often often
the the learning goes deeper when they
do that
um another like participatory learning
going trick is um there's no replacement
for hands-on stuff you know when you can
touch something you can look at and can
pull it apart
there's there's nothing there's nothing
the beach that and it also known as the
sense of ownership of the project
I wear that compressor this this review
session is mine
I you know it this this this is Mike be
resource like me use it
um there's nothing like getting like all
up in your technology to understand it
to me that link between the theoretical
on the tangible
and kinesthetic learning is something
that people talk about
when and when you can touch something
you can start to dispel the fear about
it
um the worst thing ever is like is this
feeling like if you touch the technology
it'll break
we all have days like that but the check
is to pretend that it never happens
you're trying to dispel
the you know that misconception that the
artery are you know board doesn't work
because Mercury's in retrograde at the
transmitter want to
because they're sunspots and the best
way to try and get past that
is to get people like like get their
hands in the transmitter get their hands
in the side in the got serve the
computer have your niece and nephew
rewire sat at
aside a disc inside the inside the
computer um
I do this adds workshops I'm called
injured audio
and the opener for that class has been
particularly successful we start with a
pilot cables and connectors and everyone
in the class picks one up
takes a back to their chair we go around
the room and identify them
we start this special like looking at
unlike how big is it where is it
where is it what's line richard is fit
and as I have stripes how many
and and over the course of that we
discover which you what each one
does where it fits why it doesn't it
what it does
and then we give it a name and when we
start out people kinda struggle with it
but by the end
people learn to speak each other's
answers to help each other out and
I don't have to give any input at all so
it was really really well
on on another one the store at I
I read recently %ah another
another person that does odd development
work
arm with and its it's about how to
finding something often kills it
what what he did was saw I wish I could
remember his name but
he job talk integrated pest management
got to to farmers and are developing
nations
and it was his job to basically like
educate these people all
about about how to um use different
techniques that weren't so dependent on
pesticides
and you know that they were very
accustomed to like people coming and was
like what the charts and like all kinds
of things
on but he tried to take a different
approach I this story
help to I'm Stanley is ideal a lot
now if someone like someone he said if
someone asks you
what's this bug I mean one thing you
could do is you could say
poet stopped at the Crowne pro-press I
insect us
while the local of well and that's the
worst possible
answer because just like giving it a
name
I in Latin is about the most useless
thing that you could do with that
that piece of curiosity from the person
home establishes that you have a great
memory
and that they didn't know it might you
dead move
RA for you um but what do you do and
that is like
and on the phone um let's take a look at
it you know how many legs does it have
where does that seem to be setting is
that one of the bugs that seems to be
um eating your plants is at 12 bucks it
seems to be eating on the bugs that
eating your plants
like what's what watson this bug for us
all and and just sorting through and
yeah eventually
you know after quite a bit about
servation and thought okay what you know
this
let's look in the mirror guide and see
if we can tell which one it is
and then then maybe you get to the name
I'll
but ot you know the real question is
email
are there to show off or are you there
to like actually
encourage that scientific mind set
that inquisitive that X exploration
that that they can actually I mean with
it does little good to like teach a set
of facts the people but if you can
um share our your approach love
inquisitiveness
and ham how to learn that is actually
that much much more valuable
so area I'll were at the uncomfortable
on
oh yeah okay gender and race matter
um now I gotta say some people
talk about these issues and they are
super fuckin annoying
just like self-righteous and like really
bother some and
yet they drive me crazy to however it is
a shame
because if you look at the facts
underneath
Holme you will um
realize like how important and how it
makes a lot of
otherwise incomprehensible social
situations
on much easier to understand and
actually improve
me if you look around at this room um
what you're seeing is %ah people who
have been
who courage in technology calm
its very different from if you just look
out
on the street at New York right outside
you know 18 floors below
on it's a very different set of people
now with people in this room share our
is have education
now however da master teachers who are
in however irritating education laws
you know that you know had some
education opportunities
relatively supportive families even
though everyone's family is crazy
um column and some people spend their ad
hoc
and probably are there was enough money
around to purchase gadgets
and probably had parents that didn't
smack you when you took apart the only
telephone in the house
and then nothing was was there actually
when you took apart the telephone they
like %ah that skew
now I and arm gotta make a great
engineer why these days
arm so what these things together out up
to you is what's called privilege
on a privilege is not necessarily a bad
thing there's
there's I think up there as being too
kind a privilege
what is the kinda privilege that nobody
should have a serve and with the big
and
and stand around fan airpower his years
a closet with two thousand pairs of
shoes
those a privilege it does a mother
fuckers rafter you know but up
I'll there's the other kinda privilege
is things that should be a right for
everybody education
food on the table healthcare equal pay
for equal work
in this is but in this society some
people have these things and some people
do not
and race and gender are statistically
speaking committing to protect
whether people have all of these things
in lilac not individually
but statistically you know it's its its
best it's actually very very meaningful
now your privilege
it's not your fault it has to do with
the social structures
around but it's not your fault but it's
your responsibility
to to deal with it there's no point in
im feeling guilty about having
privileges that everyone should have
but arm what you have to do is you have
to notice when it's there are
and work to share what you have and not
ported when you're bored at then you
become
like really a part of the problem arm
it's also important to realize that
that whether are whether it's this
incredibly
honor and privilege or whether it's
whether it's not calm
it often is experienced by people that
don't have it the same way
um so home and and a very funny thing
about privileges that is very often
totally invisible to the people that
have a arm
and are you know there's nothing more
infuriating
you know like you're walking down the
street with your friend a friend has a
lot more money than you
like want something to eat um they look
in a restaurant like hey let's go there
and you like ship salish cost $25
dollars i was thinkin like
slice a pizza or something all and
you just wanna smack their ass you know
because that
like what the fuck they thinking you
know um
and its it's not that they were like
trying to be mean to you are
are make you feel bad about yourself or
something but its its
but that's how you experience and it's
not just money the same goes for
education and knowledge
it's not really socially common for
people to talk down to others about
money
but is very common for people to treat
each other like they are
their stupid because they don't have
some level of technical skill
on that others do and so it's really
important like
you know to to to to think about these
things and think about those dynamics
when you're
on your when you're trying to walk arm
one other thing that we always do
when when we're putting together our
a-bands we try our very best
to to balance the paddles hollom
if it's a technical topic we tried very
hard top as many women on
on their ass man on which I have an
appropriate mix
I love a I love differ races to that
to the to the town that were and all
and its calm if not always
easy because you know you have to like
look a little further you have to look a
little harder but its
its work that's very worthwhile and
doing um
because it breaks up the math that like
you know you might get on TV that like
you know on like you know technical
people are only like
white guys in like-for-like white coats
or something like that
on we don't always another thing is we
don't necessarily go for the person that
has
absolutely the most knowledge we think
about whether they have the
communication system arm
skills and whether they can connect with
with the audience that they're working
with
and arm it you know sometimes some
people know so much about a subject that
they can't even be effective teachers
and so we really like you know think
through
a lot when one more planning are how
how how the race and gender how the
privilege how all those things are going
to play out
and you know when you do that um things
that
otherwise look like really confusing
are who are calm or puzzling they
actually
it's like avails been taken off and also
on you like actually I'll wait a second
it's it's actually a very simple problem
it's like
its its that's how people communicate
how people are used to seeing things up
so why is the wait do talking about
gender race when
though woman whose foul-up brown other
dates July is to pass it back
we actually talked about that and who's
gonna take take this point we decided am
that that I would not do it for some
very specific reasons that than a point
out and
so it starts out with the fact that
honestly and
I don't know maybe some other ladies in
the room can relate to this but
just by virtue of being the owner and
operator a pair of boobs for my life
much was a woman in the computer field
I've been teaching gender 101 my entire
life and hired so you have to like
explaining clarify things but
am truthfully when men teach each other
%uh how it about how to adjust their own
sexism
the message comes across much more
easily much more effectively similarly
it's not the job for the Pakistani
British person or a Guatemalan immigrant
or an African American citizen to teach
me
how to treat them with fairness and
respect it's up to people with
privileged understand how
how it works and train share as much as
we can with people who deserve it just
as much
but it don't have it for something
nonsense reason and so if we wanna miss
you
stores around own community if we as a
community don't wanna meet shirts
that is up to us to learn the pitfalls
that can sometimes make like poor
asshole the other people who are
otherwise very well-meaning
so message via done
well not dun dun some work done with the
uncomfortable right now we get back to
this
that's the fun part so the next the next
%uh popular education tip that we have
is on
don't let the techies touched tools
because the techies when they get here
early
would like like stuff we like to you
like to play with toys whatever
on but if you if you let the technical
people do all the stuff with tools
then you can at the camp take it and run
with it and you really don't want that
to happen
um so yes so so just kind of like
have them play you know like that game
where someone's like
teaches a man knows how to make peanut
butter jelly so like you have to give
instructions to the person like okay
open up the jar now take up the knife
into so if you can get your technical
people to do that with your shop
attendees
then you cross the boundaries you you
get the technical person to understand
what's difficult about using the tools
and the the first who's participating
that's actually touch it
and men don't take the tools that
happens happens
this happens all the time its astounding
um to united to be watching at a
technical first-ever whatever and I'm
and come out even talk to someone you
who unified you're like yeah thought it
was gone pretty well
whatever and then like the engineer do
came over and just like rather site
owner
my hand and didn't like I guess I was
doing your own
epic fail don't do it old do it
and if you see someone else doing it
just slapped them
it's okay it's okay to spot them number
one complaint
number one complaint are raising like
here at five times like I'm always on to
someone that
was like I was doing this thing and then
all the sudden like this guy just
was like now and grab the screwdriver
like
yeah oh man it was a with and and
they're like
say I just felt like shit like I didn't
now I'm not gonna do this anymore
and sell just up up
I do it all the time and I have to like
stop myself
and so just like doesn't mean you're
evil person but like thank just think
about it
who now about about about how it feels
and
and think about when your arm
when you're trying to learn something
whether you're really gonna be Barnett
if someone else just takes it away does
it for you
so arm okay here's another one
sometimes the greatest learning moments
happened
when you are totally out of control and
things fall apart
um for about 10 years I worked as a
carpenter
them when a in the in the very beginning
when I was a carpenter's helper
when my boss when his plans were totally
tolley working
I was just stand there all day bangin
nails hang another nail bank another
nail
all day long um so that was when he was
happy
I'll but I was learning absolutely
nothing except for bangin
more and more nails but when that I
really hard how to become a carpenter
it was when my when my boss when all his
plans went to shit
you know when all the sudden we
discovered that like
you know that the arm the beam that we
are planning on building this wall of
love actually it had been given away by
termites as I call
of and then we crawl under the building
and we start sawing off parts and it's
like oh my god I gotta get this thing I
get that new
then all his plans and his thought
processes became transparent to me
and I was like oh that's what you do you
if that am
watching him improvise so
um watching him improvise was where r
I actually understood what it would be
not to just be a male bangor but to be a
carpenter
and so on for that reason
on I really I don't over plan
there's one way to like look at that
house Cup having a 150 volunteers build
a radio station over the weekend
and you could think of that like like
you're a symphony orchestra conductor
like om here come the bile them and
that's when
like all about I'll keep you know it's
all the cables get install them
and here come the two bus and that's
when %ah
you know the tower goes up in and you're
just like this great conductor
mom I don't plan these radio station
events like dot
um I more like to think that them like a
dance party
which I actually find more fun all like
you know there's some people over here
dr. mass m
you know some people over there done
that I'll it leaves some room
for other people to be heroes and
heroines you know to come up with the
thing that is going to actually make the
whole thing work
I know going in there that I've got you
know 150 people that really wanna make
it work I got at least
you know twenty or thirty tacky is that
like really know what they're doing
so you know I'll it's a real mistake to
think up like any social
human interaction like a Swiss watch
with like lots of little
here are some things that people are
like it's a little messier
way cooler to think about as a party you
know and
an active people are at their most
productive one when they're like that
it's kinda like provides James provides
music stuff happens
so a great example this honors and in
there in
not never be an Aggie get over early
talking to me and we had this a
with went to the workshop and you you
know we were we're so proud of myself
because we have these locally sourced
irons in the police force
equipment we brought them over and we're
gonna do out our chat
so we had to change the schedule when we
got there because there is no
electricity for the morning
this is the on didn't happen in you put
it all which is fine with it some more
and more conversation bees were shot in
the morning and then we got we got ready
to
to get setup for sighting in and
Chancery building in a in the afternoon
well so electricity was flowing into the
neighborhood except
there we go no outlets no what we do is
go out and just play inside Iran
you know I can heat up on my arm or
something so so what did the people in
the neighborhood do
but they took a light socket and just on
the Flies sounds like
you know sent Oscar down to the
neighbors and he came back with a couple
of things
and all of a sudden they took the took
Aleve the took a practice like
live on light socket and turned into an
outlet
and that's how we sought spread out
other at ceiling
and leaving some forecasts leaves room
for other people to be the geniuses in
to teach you something the
it just never even when it crossed my
mind to do something like that and that
happens
all the time
help um okay so also
we've told you that we have these very
time limited situations
you know we have three days to build a
radio station and sometimes you do you
have to just get things done and we
cheat on
on our rules but if all else
fails at least leave things open to look
and ask questions
all you know you think about the way
people use to learn their trade how did
like an apprentice hard bro
blacksmithing usually a little kid with
guile when
you know they will carry the water and
they would like help like noble fire and
all that's our thing
all they would start at six an over the
years they were just get of the time
to observe how a blacksmith you know
made or shoes or whatever
now you can't do that at a radio station
today
you know their doors are close you can't
do that my science lab today
and so what happens in in those places
is really invisible to the public
am you know it's no wonder that most
people don't really know very much about
it
so I'll so when we
do do these events we just make sure
that remembers that the goal is not
really
just to build a radio station three days
but for everyone to walk away just start
thinking like
you know they look around at all the
chaos they see all these different
people working on different parts and
whatever
and and 8th at the end about someone
who's attended has never been involved
in building rail station before
if they look and they say you know if
these jokers can build a radio station
like this
I can definitely go home and do a much
better job myself
if if we've done that then we feel like
you know
our goals stole a map we're not going to
have to go build their radio station
I'll just call it themselves they told
you are the things they need to learn
so so we have just a couple minutes for
questions and stuff
I'm thank you so much for coming and
hope you can check out the website
committee is radio project at orgy
I and yes so we have a government stay
questions or talk about some the
experiences that we've had
or 632 that you have okay fantastically
someone
commit Mike just
carries the locations at the next bar
reasons
um we don't have one Sat we have a
number for power radio stations that are
are getting ready
I'm we just how to filing window where r
um about 140 new radio stations were
applied for around the country
and I we've got about seven or eight
construction permits out about
so were thinking about scram were
thinking about missus at the
were thinking about organ we haven't
decided yet but we're gonna be
announcing
we sent around up mailing last and died
you know if you sign yourself up on that
will double to keep you in touch in
terms of like
when we're building stations and and all
kinds of things
did it go around ever get that mailing
list around
okay get if you didn't get on it you
know will be around for a little bit
longer it's like the thought the parts
come around
you gotten set down you had a pirate
radio station a
how you said it lasts about a year and a
half
how does that change are they stricter
are they less strict
how dangerous is it to run a pirate
signal water something today
well it depends on your conception of
danger I mean this is the united states
and
and you know people don't get shop for
right for operating right
radio stations the way they are do in
other countries I'll
but they can be a considerable houseful
you know eleven thousand dollar fine
I love you know you can get your house
broken into you and your equipment taken
away
um there are a number of places where
people are still running pirate stations
the changes that we won were
tragic odd you know the we got a lot of
stations in small towns but we got very
few in the larger cities
we have a bill in congress right now
that would change that call the local
community radioactive fallout 2008
sponsored by John McCain and I'll
and saw and da Maria Cantwell
and we've got a good shot a passing at
this year and if we do
than there will be column many hundreds
of more
rock me radio stations in the in the big
cities so
number breaks I doubt that if you get a
chance if you know any congress thugs
you know let him know you wanna see that
the past
Canada duplicative the last question
actually how was the progress on the FCC
Chairman's decision
to open up low power FM
well at the SEC's made a couple of good
decisions in the past job
%ah in the past six months or so um
but they don't have the authority to
like open up thousands of new
frequencies
because congress actually took away
authority I'll
up from from the FCC to get out the
power stations basically because the big
broadcasters didn't want any more
competition
so um right now the next up is
definitely in congress a congress gets
back the authority it's the FCC then
SEC's gonna get out a lot more licenses
one thing we're really excited about
is whoever wins this this election if
it's became
or of its Brock Obama um both have
endorsed low-power radio and
and george bush has been opposed to it
cell I'm even if McCain wins this
election
yes we will be at war for a thousand
years
on but we'll have lots of low-power
radio stations to complain about it all
I on I'm sorry we're but
I know you we can talk later thank you
so much everyone
will start this Steve Stephen lady
keynote
momentarily stick around for this
upcoming keynote
we have the doors open all the way back
low back there and if you can hear me
just now you'll be able to hear me
momentarily
you can see the screen just now you'll
be able to see the screen to the right
there
so sort of see