he's been working on this stuff and it's
awesome his wife was like we had a few
minor technical problems
you so we're going to the second behind
I'm
Paula my mic okay so what my show and
tell Mom animus I produced an urban
milling weird things myself in with
others suffer couple years
on this supposition runs about 30
minutes or so so
of the whole questions will be plenty of
time for questions cuz I have questions
for you as well and I don't wanna miss
on them
and my interest in this got started back
in 1988
I was the ended idiocy and down a macro
that made those polish or bar codes that
you see on now
on oliver and political personal kids
and the idea behind this macro for
Microsoft Word I was that deals praise
on email get there faster
but no one like 50 box I was the poorest
for high school student and
so I'm wrote my own but some
instructions on how to do that so I had
to learn how to get specifications for
the post office and they won't do it
much for Business Insider make up
reasons and
this one social engineering along the
way it got a lot worse in college my
head even more time a huge research
libraries include things like the annals
of improbable research
Iran and the article on weird stuff they
were sending
and then of course I'll are wired for
time to send a contest that they run
every month in the editorial section
had the weirdest thing again the mail
gets a free t-shirt or something on them
now of you wonder why the post office
matters to them
I it's really important to our economy
because its its universal delivery
service is really cheap
oMG nobody here's my take something to
California for forty three some sex at
the post office
and a lot of banking a lot of business
medical supplies books large libraries
its I everybody is the postal system and
so it's it's really important to us
it's also need from a libertarian
standpoint because it's a fiscally
independent government organization
and there's not a lot of these out there
I it is a private corporation although
all the shares in
are owned by the fayed om no good
balanced is to paying for postal
delivery service said they completely
have to raise our money
and then I saw a few other agencies had
to do that too it's also
really useful for explaining hacking
techniques to do managers
because people have been really familiar
the postal system they know how we're
really know how to use it
and as long as you can't use it now
there are similar to
techniques we might use the computer
world but you don't have a computer
person a standard
so let's turn off by looking at
how letter get from point A to point B
and when you drop your
a lot of mail one first things that
happens the disoriented and cancelled
not stay in school and ultraviolet B
this is saddam not black-white
quote-unquote
yet so shorter wavelength higher energy
I'll bring allows the yet to be taken to
see which side to the envelope is the
address I'd
and also which direction determined on
nafta gonna play with this remember that
you he will burn your retinas against
sunburn I and it doesn't really he also
wear eye protection
on you just like cheap two dollar safety
glasses from Home Depot leave a nice
outerwear blocks
pretty much all UV and now my sunglasses
do as well
so bizarre murders of so the first the
next thing that happens is they take a
picture for envelope
and this period orange bar code on the
back fence it's a fluorescent orange and
doesn't show up very well on projectors
but uses different space instead of that
hall in short order
incurred zeros and ones and the reason
to take a picture
at your envelope is that they can run
the address soon as the our system
and try to figure out what the whole
addresses including zip code and if they
can't figure it out like
if you have a doctor's handwriting the
this in the images to Singapore in the
half
your armies people working for on a
problem like 70 cents an hour
typing addresses now you're my
Wonderwall why we need the entire
address not much just as a kid
and the reason is they will take that
not apply forwarding so
ICN here in New York anti-male my friend
San Francisco a letter
but he's actually moved to Miami the
computer ago
we've affording order for this person
there's a reason the truck this to
California
and then back again want to send it
straight to Miami say save a lot of
money
and that's part I'm even the postage
rates keep going up it's actually going
down we look at the inflation rate
sale a lot of these mom on nations and
and
additional efficiencies in the postal
stream axonal help it remain really
competitive
now after we figure out where it's
going. we apply carrier pre sorting
and the post office has this huge
database of all the addresses they
deliver to
and this is what they use to play the
next afforded to them to give
at the bar code they also add two more
did it's called the delivery point code
that's the actual stop number that the
mail truck makes is driving down the
street
so the computer system after efforts
plays at Barker dawn is the drought me
on sort mail
all the way down the point where the
mailman just opens the box grab the next
bundle in Sun City on
an doesn't have to be long and sorting
the does it for killing scene skin if
you look at it carefully
had broken up into different things are
different side to the street that's how
you get on an even number ranges
I this particular street with your
sample other the cul-de-sac but its
intersected by another street
such changes about halfway through the
intersection has that I think the
the mail truck it's a right hand can and
it's also interesting that
whoever's out 815 is at the end of the
cul-de-sac in
now he has his own zip plus 4 code
on 31 your I'm there's a lot about this
is like this particular post office
boxes
are but it gets interesting because you
can just ride zip plus 4
on an envelope and they will be
delivered
good no I suspect that in the future the
post office wall competently Brainiac
idea that they can just hand out numbers
that have nothing to do with the up
and that you register your ROM your
physical address that we move you don't
actually have to change your address my
magazine subscriptions in all your junk
mail
you tell the post office hey I'm number
52 8675 3 2009 and I things addresses
on if mister just so secure in every
business is unhelpful Security numbers
and yeah I don't be that idea
not yet even if you have multiple
numbers as well point the same person
bring this begs the question that won't
happen if I just put the zip code just
for the barking dog
envelope and mail it and the answers it
doesn't quite work that well
but almost on this is going to post
office box
and we sent several other pieces of mail
to the same post office box it had
various address in problems
and we got back at this exact same stamp
with the broken
EM broken are in the slightest much
offender and the
a dog stuck in the ED so we know that
this envelope meet
always the destination post office box
and I think what happened was that the
Act postal clerk is putting in the
cubicles
couldn't figure out which cubicle it
went in and say David the finger and
send it back
alright but these markets is this bar
codes are just the event by computer in
it doesn't think anything in it
answer first first opportunity to mess
up the system
so when I was in Baltimore you see the
post office %ah the yom
postmark in the top and we sent this
letter to atlanta
but we use the toilets were percent code
for high/low Hawaii
and with when we do these the always
under control and look at the same time
that's perfectly
address normally so we can judge how
much delay there is in the process
this and two weeks delivery time
and also my said they oppose market
again I finally figured out and and
blacked out the park adds that the
machine wouldn't keep sending it back to
whitey
so this in addition to this the input
validation issue
arm because so many things rely on the
post office or use the post office is a
benchmark
this allows you to hack other things now
I P O my taxes like fun places in the
IRS agents the office I've never done
this
but since your tax payment must be
postmarked by April 15th
not necessarily received if somebody
sent their payment to
the thought of the office but they
coated it with mmm and no one is fishing
villages in alaska that only gets mail
once a month
your check just got flooded
so there's a lot of fans like that re
you can use the post office to do other
things
so we took the estranged dressing a
couple more steps for their limits
mother and leads to see
how good is this is the our system and
we've taken a number in this church sign
generator here and done a couple others
were we've used the picture and the
address was somewhere in the picture
and in every case these been delivered
we've never had one of these get lost
I and on average we have less than one
day delay
between these in the control envelope so
we thought okay what
how good is the post office let's try
some captures
our new line of three other for these
arrived with no delay whatsoever
I'll the a1 the bottom right hand corner
which is a reading green camouflage
pattern
I it never arrived and in general we
don't get return addresses on
on our experiments because we want to
force them to put it through we don't
wanna given the
the option to just give the finger and
send it back and be lazy
are so the end of the dead letter office
and publish righted
I'll we've sent addresses that are ready
and we've sent addresses that are green
and those both live with no problems
whatsoever
but somehow mixing them up in the same
characters just confuses the heck out of
them
suppose not have been around for on a
twenty five years or so and they're
gonna get replaced with this new thing
called one code
now the post office commander think our
planet which is ace some the serial
number
an all salmon amassed me or us online
and Sears I'm sending out catalogs and
my office in catalyzing rhonda
Tom yet so I i get of junk mail spam and
junk mail company and I and I can
in addition to the down I securing
running information like the serial
number on the bottom
and every time I mail passes through
some sorting equipment the post office
Wilson is they don't say
says hey equipment over here saw this
Barker at this time
and so I can use that to judge how all
my meals propagating
now I can also use this the other
direction so you'll see this on a London
Fog visa and American Express statements
now where your stuff the mail back their
payment
house on those kids so now we can tell
that you drop your payment in the mail
and maybe think it's too late they want
to charge a late fee
or maybe the use it for cash flow
forecasting since they have a pretty
good idea where you pay your balance a
timer or just campaign the minimum if
you pay off completely
I also know if you wanna monkey around
with and you could send another envelope
but reuse the number that was assigned
to you
you can either do this but to slap you
know that another envelope we can make
your own one code you can mail a letter
to your mom your
you know yourself even and now the
computer go on as a payment from someone
so
okay so I'm not the only person who's
doing this and one a
worthy earlier works as follows the book
call the from when can I still have a
screw the post office
and what questions that comes up in this
is not some stuff
and this there's no way to get a legal
opinion from a post office on where you
can do something on
so you have to think of ways that you
can do these experiments that don't hurt
anything
on don't technically violate the law and
it's like you have the really neat idea
I
he says that he went out to utility
company and ask them for all the used
envelopes from payments they want to see
what other people were doing
I think you done for the ability case
one thing she discovered
what was that if you I kinda
arrangements Nelson cut them in half
that there's an app for that ultraviolet
to get there the post office says
although this is going to be a fun yes
once and I'm on
and so we wandered from were also that
work
mister wizard tells us on that the Tom
the glue in the stamp is actually
contains the tag and
so if you have a sheet a cedar Pino
stamps
will add stuff also close so you know
where this is going
we could have answered on the envelope
answer another post marketing class a
troop
now it would really suck to be stuck in
federal prison for stealing forty-three
census stamps
I'm pretty sure that would make the
everybody's bitch arm so what do the
little things we discovered was that
two-cent stamps don't blow so we cover
the back a 2-cent stamps and thoughts
that we pay the postage on this envelope
million other stuff too close to arm any
the I'll
a meter marks glow in those going to UVA
as you can see that under blacklight
are you can also get his prepaid
envelopes for the post office they had
like an extra three or four cents to
cover the
cost the paper and it just has a tiny
little strap is like maybe the size of
my thumb nail that blows
so it doesn't take very much at all that
the trip cancellation equipment thinking
that's an actual envelope but his wish
we could have some other issues too
as it uses the the stamp to orient the
envelope like him
what would happen if we pull in
different places and I'll
the couple meet once the upper right
when you can see the bar code is on the
top
I was actually process the envelope
upside down I them arrive with that 2x
them arrived I think a day later the one
right below it the same problem
it arrived three days later on the other
2i think actually rival control time
but interesting that the several
positions you can put it where it can
reaching can cancel
so you can kinda messed machine type nom
it is illegal to use the state even if
it's not canceled so we have these in
the safe and we can demonstrate the
memory is them
so those little things you can do with
envelopes the packages are fun tale
so it's in a variety of fun packages
beyond the happy face there's probably
the most fun is a 12 inch ball I think
it's a a Walmart promotion
and now so we we rode on the back as an
apparent actually
and I put stamps on it rather address
and taken to the counter to I wasn't
served like what surcharges would simple
word on apply
I think it'll scale a transfer and his
computer typing is that cared and walls
of the scale
and goes well and hits the floor
say picks it up and you have this is a
postal clerk they put on scaly and turns
running into walls lop
so finally be like put some pants on the
scale makes a love triangle and zeros
that in ways and we get stamps to
foreign
now is getting he was heading south
mission was to do it is somewhat taken
aback
as he takes in the back reports on table
and it comes out here why are my
hope got my pick up my parents just fine
Texas I'll stick
five days I think to make it to you live
from Leonard Washington DC and just
covered with dense
Albert a question to the and are now
able to: nothing like a dance com the
your pennies were kinda fun my car
tonight people were got messed up
and he just never talk to people the car
tag office and now so I some how does
get much money and status and MSN and
pennies
on but we didn't want the Flat Rate
Priority Mail Boxes
and some people often ask it will pull
people think about your products and
white wall
you when you walk into the 70-pound
flattery prior to the All Blacks
eye-catching a yearly thing against the
system here when the ass getting it on
its pennies the tag office day love you
for trial some even now playing around
with Parcells recently and one
experience we tried was
what happens if you take the up a
delivery confirmation sticker and reuse
it
now to start with I think delivery
confirmation is really stupid
I mean why should I have to pay a
service fee to find out whether or not
I got what I paid for it's like it would
you feel if they said
would you like oil teens confirmation to
me
so the whole thing's a racket but basic
question if I reuse label
what's going to happen cell work
some thoughts were that may be the first
package but a sharply tracking online
and maybe to track it online only the
second package which show up
and maybe if they were really smart both
packages that show up
but this is the post office were talking
about your package is obliterated it's
gone
now this is really dangerous because
this leads the way into on hacking
pretty much
any e-commerce store that uses the post
office
arm a scammer can order something for
eBay and receive the package
then we could be mailed package
basically to anyone could be a milligram
self recycle center is mom whatever
our way for the package did not show up
on the Post Office website anymore and
then complain that he never received it
and soul doesn't have a lottery force
now it doesn't happen every time so if
you are so you're not deemed
arm we found it happen about 75 percent
of the time and we're not quite sure
why it's why it's not exactly the same
all the time
i it seems to happen mostly with your
print barcodes like from Stan Stockholm
software or keeping of
you bassist amor pay pal system a Post
Office website
on and we've never been able to get this
to work with the green stickers
up in any case track your stuff early
often and and say the personal
so it's in some other interesting
parcels are just trying to test the
limits
love what the postal system fails om the
small things successfully sent a package
playing cards the lightest thing they
were sent to your container
I'll circles and spheres make it very
well I was an honorable bouncy balls and
not yours like 90 on someone's in the
indicated
Walmart on the be serious or earlier
on other phone line is we've written an
address on a sticky note and a stuck the
sticky note to letters and by and boxes
both
in-state stock on the post office is a
as actually trying to make it into
commercial service of some sort because
they think marketers will pay money for
it
another fun one is unprotected CDs we
have about 75 percent
success rate setting a CD totally
unprotected Michael put the address on
the label itself and and stick a stamp
third
on and then when it was evil post am
also that it
it doesn't vibrate in the driver may
call in ways and identify check some
and 75 result I'm the day let me read
perfectly with no envelope unusual case
no nothing
one my favorite is we don't simply
honesty testing we're taking
mom really thin and blitzer glassine
I'll stamp collectors getting fighting
them from the post office
and we put money in them so you can
clearly see that there's money in this
envelope
and with mail that and up it's never
been lost
it's never been stolen but sometimes we
get a white opaque
USPS envelope somebody's me an address
to that our city and and they put in
money inside that and sealed it
so what this tells me is most postal
employees are pretty honest
but they think their coworkers on yep
are we try to the two hundred dollars
say arm can pretty daring and sell what
we've been playing with that with
various packages we saw a lot of small
stuff
armed the post office that's bus was not
small size limits and now length and
girth to basically take all six
dimensions
package and together it's got to be.
less than a hundred and thirty inches
and we try to design the weirdest thing
we could sound and so far the best we've
come up with a pool noodle
South was fun good
somehow traditional tests in progress
were playing around somewhere with color
blindness tells
are trying to see how picks up different
colors in different colors a paper
I we're trying to find out specific
really bright orange the use the bar
codes in the back and try to make and
what about that
arm we're playing a strange centers a
gravity like you know they can achieve a
tp2 box
and I put a block a tungsten in one
corner and then to stay on the rest in
are we've been playing around trying to
send some packages like the dry ice that
get lighter is a go through the vessels
wimp
said I get a refund on delivery up
are also playing around love alone or
Garmin recycled envelopes
most recent one we've done is this
aluminum foil and loads which actually
make their way to the post is very very
well
armed sunnyside out was just as well as
long as I can
so if he's a young I what about the
are getting your own cancellation
pronounce and there's a a couple types
you could do
I it's really archaic there's like some
old stamp collector law that allows you
to apply for permit to cancel your mail
and have you are healthy and that has
like all the stuff you need to go pick
up and get it
on but it would be instantly know that
your post office is a weirdo too great
for to do
are and there's also a couple separate
system call pictorial postmarks the view
public hearing from the holidays work
usually advertisers will get to their
own postmarked upon
outgoing mail and now you can get these
are the mostly for special occasions and
festivals and stuff like that and
there's
an amoeba 120 or so any given time
around the world
I didn't find out about hope in time to
get II hope cancellation for the secured
but if we do another one are you gonna
have work on your area it's a really
hack
so I got a couple challenges for all the
other things I can't quite figure out
your hand
aren't one of them I'm looking for help
decoding electronic and Asia on my East
champs
and Dom now different imprint from
posted services
we decode number them at the accuse
number stream it looks like this
bled even on sequentially printed arm
stamps like the into the same that kid
from the same meter for the same amount
the same date
even the number groupings change around
and it seems like there's some things
that match up
each time like maybe's you like ninety
percent meter numbers are in there
somewhere in this one
on the printer next one to different
places and it doesn't appear there
& Suites we haven't been able to find
out anything on something but he
works for a company that makes these I'd
be really interested in specifications
cuz
right now the post office is just not
given to me
another stricken fun to do is a GPS
tracking and I understand there some
some cheap but one of cell phones that
you can get that sent a signal backs the
same weather out
and I've I dug around all that my just
gonna be able find any sales people who
can
likes only something worse directly so
if you've experimented with the
GPS cell phone talking abundant like
what the Bible service to get
and stuff third answer to buying yarn
delivery confirmation we can actually
tracker packages and see where the heck
they are
and I'm also trying to send a package in
get stuck in the postal system for
entire year
and the best idea I've come up with so
far as to cut a hole in the box and put
like an LCD display in their
and every night at midnight change the
address
anyway I just I just don't know enough
yet about the electrons on how to do
this
I know it's really simple and there's no
makes got the different controllers to
cart
on but I'd I just haven't had time to
learn how to do it yet
the best simple idea from up with this
again the book reader and later 360
3/3 65 page PDF for the different
address on Danny's page
and just use a timer to advance the page
every day but yeah
anybody would like to help out with this
we we have some ideas on how to power a
tea and some ideas on on how to make a
package strong enough to withstand that
kind of abuse
so there's a couple for ethical
considerations i mentioned already don't
steal from post office
on it really would suck at the
government spending a hundred thousand
dollars a year to keep incarcerated for
stealing 43 cents
I this is done doesn't make any sense
are please don't do anything to harm to
the people's mail
and we've had a really careful with this
like we had a group a magician's we're
working with
that Tom we bleed all the box that is
too big to fit down the slot in the
mailbox
and it's like had elastic bands
definitely would reassemble itself when
you like I love it
Tom the only does that the song on a
used one we discovered that it could
clog up with that would fill up a huge
amount of space and the people who bring
a male and female staff in
so we just decided to lay off that idea
for a while on and be nice to the postal
people
on so foreign never even said anything
negative om something kinda confused
and noms look give you ideas on
BRB be nice to him and be very careful
on the milling dangerously items
Tom to suggestions to get all the time
people ask me if I never mailbox said
I ate no I don't have a dog be a one
touch the stuff
if you're at the track Republican SMS
lab sampled houses growth there's no
point
and a little when people see these names
the announcements on a bowling ball
and like in the lightweight sphere that
was like maybe three or four ounces
is a lot different than yell something
that's twenty pounds ago from goes
rolling for a warehouse for nobody can
hear coming this fall the machines then
break somebody's ankle
so we gonna be really careful that stuff
sale that's all I got so today on my
your blog is always use a PO dot com
there's a cock is presentation there I'm
also the link so they're
feel it right down one of them and the
only after the fed funds than one this
is great our bedrock colorado's now like
800 people
and they get so much mail addressed to
fly %uh different ones them
that the post not postmaster had a
special staff needs has returned to
sender
fictitious cartoon character
ok up
okay that's what I've got I really
appreciate hoping the so on this is that
a great event as always and I really
really appreciate the fact the record
all these presentations
and put them on the website for
everybody so if you like to ask
questions we got a microphone set up
over here
if you go if you'd like have been
unthinkable at the house lights
integrates right for partial
I'll we have lots of time for questions
and for your ideas
cell thanks a lot for coming
go for it
up
we're having a the problem is Mike
working might not make the switch
has worked in we have a red light on the
back as I think it's fun although %uh
that is turned up with them
mixed not so difficult to convey a
covered okay that's better
Ron you said a lot of stuff to the same
location with the people
at the post office box called their
views but getting all these meetings
coming to that one box
yes are we have several but we have
several participants on summer because
Evans don't like the
didn't have the address is on a big
screen and I didn't wanna like have 'em
presentation folders blacked out stuff
and make you look at the CIA or
something
are but yeah we have our about 15 people
nationwide the sense that is so we know
if we're getting consistent results from
one post office box the next
are don't you think about sorry two
things arm
the phone you want to look at is the
tracfone there's one model that's like
20 bucks or something P paid and it has
a GPS and you can send the GPS
coordinates
over SMS visit no I continuously sound
at work you can program it to do
whatever kind of sending you and the
service with iPhone owners alike and how
long after his early 30 results into the
fountain
so you have to load whatever the
previous offers on the phone find out on
you all the details
it's a tracfone specifically on the
other 1i wanna just his have you tried
much sending make internationally
I don't know haven't most likely don't I
don't know anybody internationally to
send stuff to me or for me a sense after
them
yeah I'd be interested in SMEs if I can
accurately I don't space in Toronto so
if you wanna send the stuff we don't
have been sent to email my address is on
the I'd love to get some international
stuff
so your turn okay is it not something
I'd recommend people do because it goes
against you are saying about keep about
a VoIP for Eid
but yes is that this is a comment the
old the
the ancient recovered for flipping the
addresses
has worked in the past and probably does
that doesn't mean
it you should be doing it but it merely
yet the radically a good first thing as
a theory exercise it does work
yes it does work on we know people who
have tried it I haven't tried it myself
but people send me stuff that way it was
unsolicited
I I don't recommend it because really
obviously can't and won't if the
postmark
a city doesn't match the return address
city that you have a really hard time
explaining that courtside
wouldn't ride I did you see the
the TSA back and talk or are you a yes
they did
our considered that approach may be
published with the GPS logging
arm yes I that section of the questions
on it out thank you for bringing it up
I would love to deal with I think the
cell phone and also be able to put
unlike in a way sensor something on Sat
tons of fun from the airplane
that we may like it has lost I can tell
what city it's an analyst stan around
the airport waiting for it
arm there's also a group of people have
sent cameras to the post office
and I deposit don't have a link but Dom
a Google probably knows and that was
that was kinda interesting I wasn't even
put a camera on the side of the box a
big sign a box asking postal employees
to please take pictures
and when they got the entire camera
inside his like this post employees in
different places taking pictures around
the place
sell that the defense sense humor your
point
yeah i i thank you for talking and you
ate keep I've been doing I've been
trying to fight the
the junk mail influx it's very bad luck
been waging lately
on things I do a lot of people do with
the get the postage page
postage-paid envelope from from
unsolicited send their business reply
mail
people your with people you know they'll
take me just send the
drawn back in the mail from and I've
taken all rubber mat trying to
I get the mails from these these things
where they send you a huge
what of coupons Nadal won so I've been
set wrong was I have been taken those in
jamming them
into the put the postage-paid yasser
turned thanks
trying to figure how to increase the
weight move the post okay
is dis couple things without I actually
know somebody who got rid of an entire
power to an extra breaks
I and the the bases by any a couple
things to consider
the first in addition to the postage
I'll the down
the company that owns the does reply no
permit also have to pay a surcharge I
think it's like 49 cents an envelope so
it's almost the book right now
just isn't it back empty on you can add
additional way too and i think is a
weight limit
oMG the post office is also not required
to charge them all they are required to
deliver it
also I'm not sure how much economic
damage you can have up another thing
I've heard is that dollar credit card
companies that receive a lot of those
are they open all automated equipment in
order to process it and gave notice
looks like bar codes and stuff
identify your applications that ought to
be typewritten all I can think
on glue the invalid completely shocked
the public jam on this machine some
go for it have you ever tried sending
magnets through the post-sale
magnets yes weaves we start you can some
magnets
if they're above a certain power rating
they have to be labeled as the
or deregulated materials domestic calm
but yes you can as long as it's packaged
properly
so you don't like has a to stick to a
machine as far as you know
arm if the Packers properly it's a non
stick to machine on that this also gets
into it and we've we've sent some like
now
like baseball size nearly magnets and
like you if you pick the southern moved
across the room you need to think before
you walk
%ah because all the things like playing
a hand in a file cabinet break the
bounce and add
I and we have some discussed after the
male body yeah I
properly packaged it is safe to do oMG
but yet the
be careful about the SAT the point you
mentioned mailing out
phone with GPS yes principally gonna is
there i mean you could probably in
trouble for that if it's on
you also mentioned having none of us on
the phone so if you mail the phone that
was on my airmail
are I don't know I don't know any rules
against and if it goes
airmail it's a good question I mean
style you start to have
radio transmitter and what happened with
the FAA regulations as a passenger from
allowed to
on Argo so I don't know I don't know how
cargo would actually
that would actually work with that was a
big ass up at camp thing to bring arrest
me I
you know it's a question I'm just does
all kinds and I can get into the whole
nother supper talk about the cell phones
in airplanes I am a pilot and I'm
the second talk a lot about I'll with
the hazards on hazards on so much that
one so fun to mess things up as we have
a hundred and fifty of them
on actually the the pilot can hear that
Dad GPS Chaturthi in your computer
speakers
and we have a lot on it %ah that's
probably the most the interference that
we would die receive
but now pilots right on the front to
colin White the I'm approach will be
home in time for dinner or whatever
and you hear on the ATC frequencies
all-time cell it's not gonna call to a
plane to crash
yeah i i would like to find some way to
they were able to detect some you might
really in trouble
aren't we I don't really I don't know on
the fun things we have to check out
before we
down for good now thanks for coming on
his No
I've heard that was more due to keeping
people's attention
during the takeoff and landing
procedures the thumb the case you should
be all that talk to russell flight
on cell phone carriers also don't like
the fact you're six mile high antenna
and start connecting multiple powers
that's why they haven't really for have
a hissy fit on
much a point in the truck from maybe
more cost-effective
but have you thought about sending photo
loggers Matt for
photographers use to track the pictures
and basically keep the timestamp
and the current location it doesn't tell
me where my packages what's lost enough
stuff that what we're looking deal
om I have several customers use any part
in this is actually for work I have
customers is handled through the mail
I like you don't know the Hope Diamond
is actually sent registered mail to this
analysis on in post office very proud
that
I N E the registered mail service
actually have a lower loss rate than any
other courier service in the nation
so if you're if you get in commercial
insurance is actually cheaper on but ya
there
there website only updates like once
every 48 hours or something like that
and we would like more real time
tracking them down
so that's kinda Laurentian but down yeah
thanks
24 if you tried deforming have flat
flat rate to mail envelopes a
with various shape since inside
inside the envelope for also with
respect the question
love whether s stress might be imposed
on the
a glued seem depending on what you you
put inside
okay song yes we have we fold one
are bursting at the seams with concrete
rebar of
and the rules are as long as stadia stay
closed under its own blue
a as it was designed the post office is
legal to go
on sigh I think I think we got it
I year well actually
yes that you're not supposed to use
papon although most the time the let
that fly
ask me of the hot glue on actually the
info to have fun glenham
and you can now as you can use them is
that the heat seal as well as already
stripped there yes just Iron Girl
arm that idea for short distances that
works for longer distances the the
chipboard it's made out of can really
handle that much weight
om we've put balloons in them and those
go pretty good
and %uh Kozma structural damage and
we've also put are rare earth materials
like dog stand on the don't perform a
lot but take it up to the
73 pound maximum weight limit for om for
the Postal Union
mom annie has a concussion are no
but you those experiments you did also
with the
not not just stuff flat rate parcels but
flatly
emblems yes the other the cardboard flat
rate envelope yes
yes yes it definitely is for the the
rebar not that the plastic cannot charge
recycle once
it was in you you're talking about
having an update
and address continually update like
daily a huge issues like a piece of like
adding machine
role or like Tom your receipt printer
paper
in had something in there that would
like wind it every
okay so you'd like com shannon is have a
clear window in which as you know the
address
II don't I don't know a lot about like
building stuff mom from
by scrapping likewise we thought about
doing that would like %uh Mindstorms
that'd be pretty simple to tell it now
turn ons that someone step forward
cell that's good idea
I something I've just learned recently
if you live in a small town is big city
near your
local man I'll say your mailing
something yourself get routed to the big
city then sent back to you
the actually say to the person at the
counter keep in office
they will not send it out to the main I
guess they where they're out the mail
yes in their local seeker dare to offer
delivery
yesterday you can there's some there's a
lot of love request like that you can
make
on for example stamp collectors like
their like their male to be stamped a
specific way and it's part of my the
apply yourself cancellations Tom is
interesting
and a lot of just now wanted to be near
just that the minimum amount possible on
you can do that also be happening
fragile you can ask my hand can slide
and here's another problem
less thing I was in office early just
like two people working there and I
asked him about this is that will get
the postmaster for you
and now to the back room came a little
guy in for the local post office he was
called
postmaster yes on some post offices also
have a separate mail drop for in town
male
yessir on which the at the same thing
since gas is your time
before I'd like to thank you for your
for your talking is very interesting
I was wondering if anybody through
perhaps the use of helium has tried
sending something it's later than
air yes we look into that and the yeah
that the problem is there's nothing that
die we found that
is saddam light enough to contain the
helium
the everything is just too fragile
already exceeds the the relatively small
sizes
on it was like a mile are bland or
something like that
on and it one thing to keep in mind if
you know sometimes you get some static
when you take stuff at the counter in
the IRS area today
%eh male dancer I don't have to for that
the boxer
if it's under 13 ounces you can just
drop it off and not talk to anybody
SL are yeah it might be possible with
what are some sort of farm not
strengthened tough long-term I'll art
don't have learned that yeah I just I
haven't found anything that's really
accessible to me I'm
sale thank you to come up with some
ideas on how they are not going out with
me think it's in a negative way
kid covering
I I didn't see it on your list to view
or else but you may
you may know it's a a browser for ZIP
Codes summer for Corp
dot com yes um its it see it seemingly
unique because
you can you can put in address and see
not only
you get the the bar code in the the full
zip plus 4 plus
place to mother will also let you browse
the neighborhood see
other addresses and what the valid
addresses are
for like several like all up and down
the block all yes the street you can do
that Post Office website to just buy
acomplia street address and not die
not specify address and that's how I got
the rain let you that such a screen
capture
yet so it's it's interesting semaphore
Corp that Carmen yes
I guess they're in the business is
selling data but there's also mon-fri
lookup
yes just its interesting yes it's me
reference thanks for mentioning
22 two quick questions are how much
would you say you invest in postage in
the air
on in the year maybe two hundred fifty
dollars
on Mill most that's because we're
sending multiple copies of the same
staff to
to other people so we get a larger
sample space
it is by no means statistically
significant sample space but dance
greater than one and then have you
tested like the structural intensity
for like how much a packages jostled
like a vase
thin strip love Legos and seen if they
break up into all pieces on Wii console
number in a package
on that were down that would measure
that
are who else can we do there is not one
person who made
a ball ink pens pointed out and now
a is an art project to see how much to
get scrambled up inside the box
and I was kinda interesting on
we haven't done much else without
although we have been doing some
experimentation in now
materials packaging now we're currently
sending and cook eggs the mail
up week we we drill small burn holes and
now one hand and then a
punch the other hand I'm use compressed
air to blow the actual extent down so
it's not a spoiler turn rancid or
anything like that
I also makes the egg just the shell so
it's now weaker because there's no
internal structure
job doesn't he found his two I use a
milk crate as an excess skeleton our box
and we we've thrown off a parking tax we
drop kick Tom
I we haven't thrown one of an airplane
yet because coming
I but the others you can get public
package you can
the G forces in the mail are negligible
thanks so
oh I want to follow that are you can
send certain types of live animals for
the mail
sowed
so I heard a rumor a while back that
at MIT's Draper labs when they were
developing missile guidance systems they
in fact
try mailing gyroscopes themselves to see
if the dead reckoning state accurate
and course being gyroscopes they would
process so the postman would have a
sorta balancing this man and when I got
onto the mail handling equipment might
sometimes put itself on a ramp
i think is that because one with the
sound of that service there's a gravity
idea should money more about that but we
have a power to
that because I was gonna suck a lot of
power yeah I mean less so if you've got
social vacuum pack them in a course they
had military equipment but I've always
been dubious as to whether this was true
service or wonder if you've ever heard
about it
arm I think I know where I can get
somewhat when I am pilots I can get
%ah mcintyre is no problem by thinking
is something I can borrow a set of
political violence from to try that with
so I have to give it a shot so absence
right the RSS feed me you'll see a
passing
I'm really quick question is was no do
it happens all those
sends letters people Sam lead to the
gonna trash to get return known he the
down it said a charity thing that postal
employees the other good as the hard
on their routed to whatever city the
the child Assam is that and there's
volunteer groups that try to answer as
many as possible
a lot I'm just now get a written
response back to its conflict for
officers to purge Miller best wishes bed
I yeah for like am poor kids and stuff
they they try to fill wishes
and nice postal employees to do that
data off the clock
for free sale yeah they they get handled
sound good question yeah he said that
one time someone you mail the camera
through the mail yes I think I ever
thought my phone
and seeing if you have a conversation
with someone was processing the mail
yeah other than I think yeah
arm that everyone has an issue and talk
time is an issue except that down you
can get the
places T Mobile has the ally free
unlimited calls to five people
so you could just feel like the job are
you now have a date having
yeah that's a neat idea what look you
doing i'd
are along the lines of shipping phones
if you're worried about causing
interference
on a plane you could possibly use an
accelerometer and
a just a very light power drive circuit
that could turn off everything else if
the speed ever cross the threshold
so soon as you're on the tarmac in
coming up to speed you can turn off for
all the other circuitry
and waits to you see the deceleration
and turn our back on
right I'm that's a very good idea thank
you
sir well remembered as me missus
expensive night I have access to surplus
than
yeah I have accessible citizen parts I
good
this is so much for still hacking this
more as an interest in you want to go
home with the mail
um there's a certain company that sells
a and farms
hunt but when you buy the farm you don't
buy actual and seek an accord
yes Israeli actress in yes amphibians
and these are gonna live animals in
something else
rate so you to call you similar anywhere
but they don't check to see who sent it
to fit
anywhere you want you
I
you well
ok thank you very much you up
okay on that women suck on it was if you
wanna play a prank on somebody down so
the post office on get one though some
to the ant farm cats inside is a
postcard that you write off to the
company and I'll mail you the chance
but they don't necessarily know the the
you're the one who bought it so you can
have them send a chance to whoever you
want
your
to Fort sir on the no dove from averting
a package in the post office for a year
if you've seen back to the future yes my
health
your I'm getting at Cannes way do
something like that I'll
Wow the post office is not only the
business holding males
on I'm not sure how we would how would
something that far
i mean that was done with Western Union
on which the product or service
the closest thing we've done without is
signed as they were evacuating New
Orleans for Katrina
I sense some people letters Annex I want
to see what kinda crazy
I returned every time steve harrigan on
it or how long it delayed
and out what happened was that everybody
go back to their homes and it said
I have no power my sewer is backed up I
got 6 inches of water in my house and
there's no gas
but I have letter from you yeah
group so that they really work hard
now Tom he's a question
I in terms have showing the phone off
when you doing airmail you could you
know as the city have axed
airplane parts can maybe try doing some
serving altimeter
thing now know how that would work is
the ultimate in her hotel room after a
case of
on because you're already at ground
level com we look at BB like the
intensity of noise cats
its net very noisy on there but you're
not number wouldn't work
on specially considered like results to
my airplane is the field altitude Denver
and now and then if you could while
another way to do it is if
you could get GPS will if GPS would be
working in the plane
GPS will give you a rough altitude
reading
I'll yeah it was nice to be back out the
TL you not knowing how 18 Calderon
del yeah you can admire yeah are you
your national/international wouldn't
work on however it might that we use GPS
to censor speed
and if we actually do things and set
aside I would make more sense
airports are who had fun for me to think
that just
for energy just looking at once Sao here
listed
yeah baby more like 20 miles near the
purse pattern but yeah
a GPS might work with something Fontana
sound you thanks
as wasn't um I think I I saw it quite a
while ago with a.m.
you put a zip code somewhere in Canada
and then you write the rest the address
in something like Russian not using them
but India Graham script rather than
English and then when you get to the
Canadian like postal service that have
someone who could
speak Russian translated and then
forwarded on to russia
yes yes popular e-commerce fraud right
what you could do is made for
a.m. Chinese code on its send it to
China
and have the just in China saying would
have your home address is
and then should in theory come back to
you who dis need I haven't thought about
Tom sending it to a
getting such a turn from other countries
so I'll I
not all the five try that might be
something working towards you
stand in the postal system for years
that's a very good idea thanks very much
we've got time for I got time for two
more questions and i got to ask a quick
comment my earlier question very very
quick
I've noticed that would post office box
it because the normal zip code
finder at the post office use and what
accompanies use
does not give you the correct last four
it will give you
the what would be the right it was a
street address but it won't be the
correct last four free PO Box
that there are some there are some
general mom
addresses as well for simple fight
systems right on their
there's specials at four sandifer
Rangers like other like an 01
and I know a couple others it was like
to live with it let's examine T-forty
was 0012 once once house ones ones PO
Box
and their is roughly the same location
but it but one is not right
together is but this is to compare it to
the other if you know if you can email
me a sample might look into them are
I can take my questions from some time
your
governor as the Justice swapping stories
but
people complain about junk mail me there
was a guy
who at from suffer as many lists as
possible got a wood-burning stove
and current the postage yes let's hear
that you all for free
min were awesome okay I gotta go on
those are you still have questions if
you like movin talk with me i'm a day
had also we don't interfere with an ex
people but I don't answer questions