let's talk think I saw you in the back
your own movie for Vendetta mask
use those who have come to trust me was
leaders has been made clear to us
anonymous has therefore decided that
your organization should be destroyed
for the good of your followers for the
good of mankind and for our own
enjoyment
we shall proceed to expel you from the
internet and systematically dismantle
the Church of Scientology in its present
form
you recognize you a serious opponents
and do not expect our campaign to be
completed in a short time frame
however you are not fully of the rebel
against the angry masses of the body
politic
your choices methods your hypocrisy in
the general of mississippi your
organization have sounded Steph now
you have nowhere to hide because we are
everywhere
you will find no recourse in attacks
because for each of us that falls
10 we'll take this place we are
cognizant of the many who decry our
methods is parallel to those at the
church of scientology
those who espouse the mysteries that
your organization will use the actions
of anonymous as an example if the
persecution of which you have for so
long want your followers
this is acceptable to in on a bus in
fact
it is in French the on your espy's
overtime
as we begin to merge opens first met at
your church the suppression of your
followers will become increasingly
difficult to maintain
believers will become aware that
salvation needn't come at the expense of
their livelihood
they will become aware that the stress
and frustration have a fear is not due
to us
but as soon as much closer to them yes
we r espy's but this summer suppression
we could never muster is equipped by
that have your own RTC
knowledge is free we are anonymous we
are legion
we do not forgive we do not forget
expect us
good afternoon new york city
a trust will have enjoyed the conference
thus far we are anonymous
a we are legion
well should shell adult after rather
yeah i'm talking about. alright south as
well
global aids and Lawrence rule we gonna
games
well know about shit and personal my
beaches nearby promise
this is the kid
yes I had some weird
up maybe even bigger and deeper and
honeymoons
but he doesn't think beans I'm just even
I'll located %uh hey
that means have this rumor returns or
their cool
will move its yeahh irate
well then I love rate
are so basically I love in late January
a group of internet users but you better
roads are not a couple
image boards decide they're gonna fuck
around the call
and I
on that call was cut scientology and
that
not group called anonymous I'll
commit to the report a lot for this
is sizzling yeah waiting for a
the asshole who was actually supposed to
start he's running up stairs or
something right now
okay but anyway Tom yet we're not miss a
I'll introduce ourselves first and the
many a I run African on the icon on the
venue Gaza for a bit
African on is the the website that
basically
manages yeah the whole New York Region
and Dom yeah I run that
this year is Atkins he
is he's allowed at almost or protests
on this year's him and he's my guys the
process was you
just decide to be here today I think
anybody even invited you just showed up
yeah he discuss showed up is like a case
on Pantone
me said yes it does plus want to reserve
a russia so no money you actually have
to keep her in that coffin
just burst out screaming those great
year
this kid here in the math is poking on
nom he actually has some he has some
relatives that are kinda involved in
scientology
so he's gonna talk about that today and
the
the hot redhead here with the press his
little sister
on AK New York nurse I'm pretty sure
love you guys seen her and psych been
him
Dramatica to accept Tom
look that up there well she has a later
yes
yeah and the advocates sitting here in
the front row
filming us with a really shitty camera
I'm
that's that's in a nation not that's the
same camera that actually got the
if any of you guys have been on YouTube
and seen John Carmack I smell pussy
yeah video he's on responsible for that
so mom i guess im gonna pass make over a
little sister
shit see
I wanna work thank talk
hello there
I'm little sister I have no US we
talking about here
you see him play near
you well not this hassle here in the
back registering hi
he's not suppose you're talking him
faster
fast learner not fast enough save this
mother fucker
sunglasses he makes sense the decade
know this %uh less itself your
I'm and me I'm certainly did a good job
Billingsley around the stairs she no not
really no
up dying of yeah I was told it would be
cool if I just said fuck indicate shit
for mad long
so it's all I got here just I'm kidding
the first thing I'm with his paper
having fun in these are
them I Pembroke when I was writing it
was currie
I want to strain it if I can snap in
half a man in a subdued
Sep 19 my but how is my only in
a I'm company owner among 23
I could tell you guys that because I
scientology site on my name to a lot of
people and a
I'm not saying is that they had to
happen then he okay
a certain to be any a lot of nuns
will not go into detail about this sorta
stuff a few months ago as a matter fact
I remember I could have gone like yelled
at and take that the raid for
saying half the stuff done but said on
up fault see the thing is if a lot of
people disagree with what you doing
though still pretty much make sure that
you can show up or at least if you do
shopping I have a terrible time
you know on that's why the raised
I we do nice info you know why we do and
how we do
don't feed have healthy no I'm I
israelis in a love it um well
in the beginning on being in January
I could say that a some message boards
nisam
other says you as know about is
committed to anonymous %uh
one of them is be busy moms world some
mara you know fuckin the other chains
guy and share yes you can already see
the other announce for me since I start
talking about the real said you know
on the reagan invaded each other
up some cheesy internet thing and you
know soon be there in like a run in
fuckin message each other's boards go on
so maybe Encyclopedia Dramatica change
in trees but people just the stupid
but the thing is I just so happen to all
be happening at the same time
you know well as these are ones going to
bother another another was gonna go
bother another
this was the really cheesy in Steuben I
really was gonna get involved at all
but it just so happened at around that
same time is one hour tom cruise video
came out
are you familiar with that on those
elite
video with Tom Cruise acne complete a
retard
ahead basically making Scientology will
take months if I can say goes
and so they came out on YouTube and then
it got taken down
because the church likes to have
copyright infringement crap and
Josue people and you know there is the
ball you too but taking it down
it would do stuff like this on the
internet for a while it pissed a lot of
people off and just so happen to have
never really really unfortunate time
because
everybody was gearing up to do some
ridiculous shit to each other
on so what happened was
everybody decides to go in start the bug
the shit as Scientology now
on every chain board every message board
that really had the same kind a jerk
soon all the internet our
you know slaying the internet things
everybody knew about
you know everybody was like okay let's
all go and you know that I have a
message for the
what we gonna do you know so
have segment
so you know a few people who were are
better in scripting stuff like that the
human with
you know some scripts that we could use
the bug this site a little bit
if I can phone's ringing dude was over
here
well someone's fucking phones reexamine
I'm I'm sorry
if I'm shift or into the crowd
if answer I'm fuckin sweet
said Yelp
if
daycare you that's our
your I was i
red so it's going to go the fuck to do a
red
up the scripts come out better certain
that able to kinda like not really
illegally but
really like unknowingly overload their
sites to get past that everybody have
people not to have a fuck to use 'em
those people have no idea how the fuck
to use them usually would you know they
would Frank all scientology
fucking piss them off and all sorts of
stupid shit they got pieces worth much
like real juvenile
but incredibly fucking funny stuff does
a lot for the record and put on YouTube
and made everyone laugh and be happy
sever scientology they continue to frown
for ever for
world the corn again them once for the
if so anyway
um me used on interesting system of
collaborating this
basically if one jerk an idea you can
yell it out on one random message board
and everybody would step on him and kill
him but every once in a while is good
on yes
up talk to you
you
okay forms which chairman
another deck speakers hear you talking
no yeah well if I can make something up
yeah I would love to know who the fucks
phone that is unwise to answer in now on
you know not talking about Scientology
to do that and even
so um for the fuckin meantime
head we are we but then and
I'm just on this time we start
clobbering long RC
suck library or outline a man on the
message boards like I was about the same
for the fuckin phone ring for the 50th
time
that a new we used to use
this method of somebody would have a
good idea you know or
some I would have a bad idea you need to
get praised for it or not because it was
on missus warrior no idea who the fuck
said
and our we would you know kinda run with
it and the
that was a lot how this whole thing
started you know I have the dates guy
named someone's name the father and a
you know that how the times damn it so
meet a friend fuckin time you know
and I was on January 18th where we first
decided I write this is gonna be
this is our wave of you know psychotic
miss
you know we fucking called them all day
you can get through the dynamics hotline
all fuckin eight hundred-number
he could not get there was completely
fucking busy paint
there was black faxes going out to them
like you notice pretty much
all black piece a paper Francis yeah
we hit with just yeah we would send it
I'm over this was one person who would
take the paper
and would circle it right they would
like to know they put the bike
the by piece a construction paper
through and tape it to the end
it's like to the fun and so just keep
fuckin sending the fax over and over and
over again
right for some them %um
ap now is in process
it's the only just deserve I'll but you
know funny in juvenile sometimes go in
and
sewn any case us
they got they have had their kind
bombarded with that for a little while
on I'm really the 18th you can get on
any other sites because they were
overloaded
on yeah and we had people on now I
received the US in there
the web sites which is also free
juvenile knowing what you now see using
dissident script kiddies and whatnot but
Dom
yeah when the main purpose is the the I
seen everything we had going
was stung school money main purpose is
no
a have the IRC network originally was
actually the DDoS other web sites
and down they actually had a few as I
said dynamics website they had their
more recruiting website nails other main
website and I think we had their website
Africa record is almost two weeks
um maybe
yeah well became me there was
there was most I think it was down in a
row was public 3 desert and the thing
with the republican issues with upper
body work on the screen get down
um but I think welcome
whatever was on the 18th everything was
down right lines were completely clogged
the faxes they shut them off for about
two weeks
a if then a
you know everything's kind I'm down a
member right around the
you know 1920 if you know everyone's
kinda petering out you see
participation decreasing stuff like that
and a
with the decision was made I guess a to
have a second wave
I she wrote that copy pasta
for second wave and a you know I I had
sent out and I promise I want to focus
more on a
on some press involvement to so I kinda
threw a lot at in there
and I mean nobody really ever had the
area time any idea
you know who I was with the fuck I was
doing but arm
basically if like I said before if you
write something up you know you put it
on the board
where you put it where everybody's you
see it has a good fucking idea
you know so you get a years ago adopted
into it so
that's kinda what happened um
those another wave after that of course
and another and another and it just kept
going on
and our what something interesting
happened at that time I think on the
NRC's
the people start know each other because
a
you know what stuff that wants us to go
around for
you know for a long enough time in
people using aliases they'll stick to
one alias eventually
so so you know you did have some people
getting favor you know some ideas in
favor from some people
some I did not favor from other people
you know
and I guess that's kinda how I got to be
a part of
would eventually would be a channel want
what channels were all the kind of urs
and people who got were a little bit
more respected got into arm
and I was the major centralization in
the beginning of anonymous
than actually on my birthday on January
27th
um smart bunker put out his his video to
a
2 p.m. is tell us that this is not the
way to beat scientology yes I to calm
the fuck down
she has to stop doing stuff they could
you know potentially be considered
illegal
you know and you guys gonna handle it
that way arm
of people thought that are more but was
just had become a target never was going
to a
you know going maybe bomb his Satan you
know do whatever but
you everybody kind members mark bunker
um
and its he actually was what led to
the ire see Exodus as I they call it arm
the operas on a on the ICE network that
we're using
one of which in a minute which is in
repair I am
they'll actually kicked off everybody
everybody all the nonce for use in the
that server at the time
were gone and those whose couple
thousand people
and now we're thinking well how the fuck
Munich elaborate how important this is
really bad
let alone lasted three hours because
while we were gone
to Nexus we all pretty much decided that
paid we have to relax with the legal
shit because one
we can't do it anymore and to you know
Mark Munger had a lot of points
everybody agree with %um
that was mother was that the Britain's
Got plant the the
for beer tent was when we decide to move
into real life we decided to
yeah stop being fat internet kids and
I was I was a lie was fat but then after
that time they are really skinny
arm and at the stop being fed into
nickens kind
kanina runs a real-life go see the organ
person
a you know tell them what we think
fuckin hand out flyers
say weird shit them and now always
remember the a
the morning attend because I'm wondering
with these are people gonna be like
these people who for so long if I said
even the slightest thing that they
disapproved with
will jump wat the fuck down my throat
and be incredibly incredibly mean
and on you know when I met up with them
for sale that's when I was fucking huge
nobody thought I was going to use in
just in your city owns around for
hundreds of people
you know we had planned February 10th in
every fucking major city worldwide
im so just to be just the New York again
fucking over 300 people understand
really well this is this is fuckin
massive
I had no idea you know and a
so I get there and people are just
fucking pool
they're funny as fuck nobody could get a
single freeze out without some other
asshole saying something completely
ridiculous
like everything was just a complete joke
and I'm like wow
everybody's like everyone was the bad
kid in class you
fake this if this is class everyone's
just a bad kid in class there's no
fucking teacher and we're just going
crazy
%um um there was the code of ethics
everybody knew in a fucking relax don't
fucking step out into the street if the
cops are not to the point anybody in the
fucking face
other than that you know I'm we were
chatting daycare sometimes
for him whatever I started the day care
on
but fuckin both you know
I just thought it was fucking great our
and local era before the 10th
are we already had the idea months
already planned
which was the 15th you know i i axons me
a firm believer in a few gonna go in a
and jump into something maybe like the
first thing should always have the
backup thing there
so that you know if it does become a
success you very much like a are let's
do this again then
you know then you have the same Turner
um
so we did and I guess the whole point of
this was for me to tell you how and why
scientology got my name in such more
during those first two raids
those first two protests they could see
that I was a
you know i think is a liaison with you
must feel you you know I was
kinda run around the front runner you
know help organize stuff from whatever
and they obviously saw that
my very flimsy Groucho Marx the skies
didn't do a fucking thing
if well most in Sevilla
biking and and and that's actually how
they got me
they're probably farming homer some
ridiculous fucking thing like that in
and that's pretty much it so now they
know my name
the semi also it's a fucking letters and
stuff like that in a I'm def not gonna
go into work is the shit is way too
fuckin funny to me
but i wanna be Prince keeping the
pressure on we got a lot of luck in
Press
they look more more fucking ridiculous
all time and we just beat them up by
being
fuckin funny insane weird shit that's it
they keep
summer particularly want to pick it up
for
with your exploration up
pokies on latest government ok you know
what's up
yes yes it's it's appropriate
adjustments NASSCOM
now yen yep
yea yeah they can't find where I live
twice so
I don't give a damn a yes
are not really gonna talk about family
involvement in scientology
I can talk a little bit about that if he
want after the panel but our
like Adam question-answer session talk a
little bit about bad shit they do
how they really trillion lines and in
all that on fun stuff but right now
we're gonna keep along the fun side so
on the start of by saying some things
that I have written down
and reading them with my own eyes so
sour you know I think we've been here
nice today because
a now Fox News said that were bunch of
hackers on steroids
that was 2007 a
they also call this the internet hate
machine that's a nice on
and the they they recommend strongly
that if you buy curtains and a dog you
can really protect itself against
hackers
that's a good one I i think that we
should all do this
are also known for exploding yellow vans
according to them though yeah
well this is a report murdoch network so
you know it's true
I love for the most part a lot that
tech-savvy um
certainly not less crowded I'm sure all
view
holy surpassed me in every way but you
know
I guess I'm just Tomball
on allowing the party the internet hate
machine I only joined up with anonymous
as chin ology started so call me
anonymous comments knowledge is
if you're into that semantics go have a
a fun by yourself
I'm gonna be with these guys on
I really don't know what anonymous
wasn't till the until I saw the first
message scientology video that we played
just before
I heard about them once in passing over
the years but
I'm I wasn't a huge internet user I'll
just sort of the I don't know normal kid
grown-up
and the you know I got my AOL CDs and
then drink coasters over the years and
like the early nineties
but for the most part no I have heard
about an honest once when they
sort have made news not even the Fox
News report when the
up when an honest way back when deciding
you catch them had a file because they
thought it was funny
and as it turns out it was I was also
awesome so
you know we ate them up on
I if
your deck you make a solid
crime-fighting
alright that man come down I L
of I was so very literally Robin the
goggles those for you
was berated edelman your you seventy
your you
occasion up and I'm cool okay
so really were a buncha communist Nazi
cyber terrorist
aliens from the market in Empire being
paid by the psychiatric industry to
protest
in order to force the homosexual agenda
and make sure that alien goes for men
imprisoned your honor
gots
alright are all those things I think
that the Church of Scientology said
about us
I couldn't like this because I don't
think that unless I was wasted several
times over I could come up with
something that dumb
these are things that the members
believe because these people have been
totally stripped of their rationale
now thanks maybe later I am but the
these people I mean truly have no sense
of critical reasoning
it's something that's taken away from
them at some point and its
it's really sad because it pervades into
other areas of life
including medicine which you know has
killed people in the past
because they were few psychiatric care
and
maybe get into that a little bit later
but you know
here in New York City Jennifer McDonald
Cox the nice woman who
the came out from the Scientology church
which the corners
public gonna talk a lot and jargon here
because Scientology's all jargon
that's part of a part much hope of
mentality to begin with
so when you're inside I you know what
you're talking about
you feel like you on the club everybody
has the same words
and as an outsider you don't now sell
apologize for all of us if we start
talking and
in gibberish mom buyer to Jennifer
McDonald pass this woman with a mouth
like a song like pet
comes outta comes out and yells at Mike
here
and she was implement foreign
Buffalo covering up Jeremy Perkins
to on very unfortunately is paranoid
schizophrenic
who his mother al perkins a
Scientologist
and as becoming scientologist
was tonight psychiatric care and because
she was told that the psychiatrists are
evil aliens from the marketing Empire as
we are of course move
was told take the some of the medication
Ange he
ended up stabbing her seventy times
and Jennifer mcdonnell parks was
implement all was a
big part of covering up these people are
criminals
was no other way around um
but back to some fun stuff you know
because I said I was gonna do that and
the you know these people
these people are criminals I get I got a
little pissed off because I think that's
the right thing to do
because you know if nobody gets pissed
off a criminal's the just gonna
keep on keepin on because the stuff
doesn't get coverage
because these people are other exactly
for that purpose to cover this stuff
a runoff about the tracks I'm
really I'd like to talk a little bit
about if you see yesterday
you want to get involved with us because
a as in Tower
pretty much the you know pretty much a
buncha will be jerks
yeah arm I mean I that's a great
description of us because
we were kinda means each other helping
each other injure
right want enough
know you I like them the season
and the you know if you want to join up
with us
just don't take anything seriously
honestly I
you can do it for whatever the reason
you want you can do it because you
pissed
good reason you can do it because
scientology is a criminal organization
with the tax exempt status and
you're paying for them you can do it
because they've covered up murders
you can do it because they abuse
children
consistently whatever you can do it
because it's a lot of fun
some people just like to come out with
us and party were
we do worldwide protest monthly we do
weekly protests
physically think we're doing his
physical store real world
we've we've made some pretty serious
effects
in especially in in terms I love I give
a press coverage of the a Scientology
organism
diseased
there has been a few people in New York
who have previously been scientologists
to
were not too afraid to speak out against
the church of scientology because they
know if the
for Chas blackmailing policies against
the Church of Scientology
the members because when you undergo
counseling in the Church of Scientology
the write down everything
and this is for something quick call PC
file
and this is something that will use
against you if you leave
and because I've our presence there have
been
%uh you members were scientologists to
have found a voice again and are willing
to speak up
this is New York City locally
yeah I personally had somebody blow
which is what the call leaving from
talking to me yes
and we have a we accept a couple people
dead
one of them explode for now he actually
end up leaving not to lie yeah and he
comes down protesters all-time
an easy if you look around one for
protest he makes himself very very
obvious
he runs around with with an iPod
speakers strapped to his bell
%ah which the iPod's learning out the
the call the OT three on which
apparently
if I if you hear it and you're not
actually upset lovely yield I have
among the most anything like that now
according to scientology
basically violence speaking of which I
mean because as some
so if I believe years ago I the evil
galactic Overlord you too
another call about overpopulation on a
small planet decided to round up all the
aliens aliens
prospectuses a little olive me what the
so
you get the so this old yeah we've also
we've we've made sure that our
a lot of people actually what stirs the
pot places down a fucking lot worldwide
in locally
are we've made a lot of people wall more
than a
more than I as usual not join up David
they would try and talk to people all
around just would not fucking happen
there their membership is down their
monies down with premature them in
almost every fucking way
so how much membership cost them
almost everyone who said these
calculations that I've done by
interviewing every single scientologist
that's in the Oregon completely making
up right now
I actually I'll we had very reports
I mean I i've heard that they were down
fucking forty percent I don't believe it
I I'm I think it's way more round 10 to
and their membership is on the slow to a
halt as far as i'm new sign-ups
and terms in whose wide
the in actuality a have was somewhere in
the
100,000 19 they say are fighting over a
hundred thousand I think you know they
say over eight million dollar a rancher
and the other day I'll say a
something else on the other they say
something else but we think it's
anywhere between fifteen hundred
thousand
they say a million because anybody who's
ever taken a stress test go karts
industry
everybody both maybe never walk New York
they can City scientologist
he's like unclean such ridiculous
numbers ever taken stresses on the
street
your scientologist there honestly I'm a
Scientologist
honest truth yes well yes this is Isaiah
there
this is one other little camping spots
they do them stress St Ann's
apparently what they consider you one
when they consider you a
a member even if you're not actually
consider yourself a Scientologist
on the county in numbers if the count
into their numbers if you are
ever pretty much gave a name and address
and all that other stuff some
you know to get a book or a to find out
more about it
i mean for example have gone see our
governor I've
question about the allies their policies
and yeah
actually things not
yeah I've gone in there and i five
questions policies gone information now
about you know why this stuff just to
see exactly know what you doing in there
and now unfortunately I
I go home every man every month and I
and 10 ml
with hey I will you sign up for this
coarser I want it so i buy this book
sound yeah number considering all those
they're considering
all those people that go in there and
you know ass ass mad about her ass about
their
a little cold there they're considering
a member's and that's what the cannons
their numbers at the helm post on the
website
most we have a an apparent question I
guess
monarch famous a
the area for yet so
as well as a you guys are making a big
impact on him I'm from Miami Florida
appearing to upcycle federal check the
comm we have you paid so
you know I've been covering you know
where you guys have been doing adding
stuff to your YouTube age is a favor
and people have been contacting me in
like West Palm Beach
you know in north Florida which is you
know where Scientology's base that I've
and they're talking about family members
being seriously involved in mind control
need a break and it's not just
scientology also in a different other
courts a lot of them are like the
aged Aquarius say folks %uh the New Age
nyanza mean it's my controls in the
robbing them blind side
you know that this is Vance often so I
called this makes money for committed to
I'm and a certain people it's destroying
lives
um but at a question must see or get
this is something when I was researching
cuz view with the way you guys are doing
a
like a they have enable a force called
CEO word
the actually have a naval ship with with
an army
how the fuck is that legal named they
consider the naval ship
its really just for decoration well it's
a cruise ship for the blue asbestos
yeah it was recently shut down because
after
something like twenty years after the
fact they investigated the ship the
structural designer architect some sort
of naval engineer
came onto the boat said you gotta shut
this down as for blue asbestos
twenty years later they actually had to
go in and get a government check and
guess what they found
as follows: Luis pass this so
you know doesn't just go away know
either visitors pass passes there isn't
a single Marcus Mojo
in your lungs is basically guarantee
cancer ten years down the line
they've threaten the lives %uh
hundreds and thousands of their members
and they haven't told anybody about this
100 said that s passes is not bad for
your home
yes also the cigarettes are a great way
to prevent lung cancer
that's why so many signs of a smoke by
the way
if they're not telling you not to do
anything because you're talking about
him
that's something also nice amis this is
a quick tension because
I've really strayed far from when I was
gonna talk about behind to
11 times approximations something that
the
is a new one that I learned about only
maybe about a month
maybe month and a half ago something
that they love to do around
disaster sites including our very own
9/11 disaster site
is they will use their volunteer
ministers
which is a for thats you'll see them in
yellow shirts
I'm and the calm and your ministers
they register the Volunteer Ministers at
the 9/11 disaster site and
New York as the National Mental Health
Assistance
which arm in the heat of the moment
sounded
remarkably close to the National Mental
Health Association which is a real
organization
that's not scientology however they
register the Volunteer Ministers of
national mental health assistance
and they intentionally blocked 9/11
rescue workers and victims from
receiving free psychiatric care
because they believe psychiatry is evil
they would
literally take members up their church
and tell them all this is very important
and
something to keep in mind scientologist
generally exceptionally good people
who are horrendously misguided Tom
to calling up the entire New York area
membership
anybody problems ever come in and saying
come on this is
a national crisis get the hell down here
and he's a good people so they do
and they would literally pain of
psychiatrists
with the members so that no rescue
workers could get
care because they believe it even and
even the psychiatrist in the Holocaust
yeah many in short they believe
psychiatrist responsible for the
holocaust so that's
you know their history is really on 'em
speeches been derailed yes speeches not
been derailed
on and in the meantime they told them to
go to the Scientology knocking on
centers
to get the purification rundown which
involves taking
attacked those are nice and for your
liver that's always something good if
you have
and detox farm loans but it does have
nice and not cause flushing in the skin
tell you that radiation leaving the body
that's a nice why they tell you is your
damaging your liver permanently on
and this is just that they're going to
rescue workers and
you know just breaks my heart and makes
the past and the
I think it shouldn't make you please do
because this is ridiculous
was not something that we want going on
anywhere let alone in our city
I'm I was gonna talk about if the
you want to come out with us sometime
because were out often
and we usually in New York because
because we have so much fun we like each
other so much we go out just about every
week
probably every Saturday sometimes
midweek sometimes a few times a week
the occasional miss a week but there's
always a monthly worldwide protest I
think
event and the upon
you know if you if you just come in
there blindly might be a little bit
surprised
might be a little bit shocked by serving
me know the language certainly hearing
us today
on aiding understands the relationship
you might think that we all hated each
other
arm that's only the case sometimes
especially after we just ship back up
from washington DC
because we were marching on the mall and
I we spent a lot of time with each other
so
you know unlike these guys so much at
the moment well I do in the gym
you weren't there but I don't like you
anyway I still like broken on
your email il-sung
also yes he did he just heard as you
think that we're
relief crass and food and
confusing and and you'll be right
and you would be 100 percent correct yea
we r are the difference is that there's
absolutely no
no hateful intentions behind this the
stuff that's done mostly for shock value
I think this comes how does sorta the
internet
I'll when the itself to anonymity
in in its forms just in that then
sure and then that their web forms and
the
looks like I'm running over but that's
what happens when you jerks started
messing around with me rapid up yeah so
blessed skipping ahead
a yeah from was giving you head to the N
you can try and understand us chances
are you won't because I don't understand
us
arm were a bunch in nice people
or party people you know come out do our
thing
have a good time and process we get the
damage a call
so I don't know what are you doing your
weekend that's better than that
that's it for me its
got its last seven minutes
maybe
some I me that so it's all based on
estimates but we we've
reach I I think weaver an average losing
200 150
yeah York that's your yeah it's just in
New York
world we have I values February
is probably in February Tom I believe
reach between February March
we've had well over 8,000 worldwide back
maybe overnight but i wasnt
could be over 9000 yes in a ball for
someone it's at least on
your I've except
yeah um I'm reviews to help me it was
for the Scientology trivia question i've
had for a while
yeah back in about ninety nine it came
out that Scientology was running that
nannying
Manning software they're recommending
for all the members were there like you
can't look at things just work numbered
right and one of the things I use it was
reasonable things like they don't want
to use easy new which is the name of a
the ostensible deity the others see
clambake cuz thats operation clambake
which has been
looking and her psychology for a while
the one that got me when I look at this
list
was the word poodle am wondering if you
have any ideas
no I didn't want you see the word cool
ball
you will know the poodles revive her
talk to teens teens
said that Zee News face actually a
fool's assholes
yeah yes next
first yeah I question who doesn't
necessarily a
physically %uh fucked around with the
cans that they have when they do the
stress this
the even though he's talking about what
you use it when I stress tests yet cuz
if you can if you
it basically is like a physical edge
detector said you know I regulate your
polls you can we prove how these things
do not work
rent some rest no yes yeah yeah actually
are legally obligated to put an FDA
warning all those are all those heaters
that they they do nothing
and and we had sex with her just
marvelous
I just want to say that as soon as that
awesome where stocks video came out
as on the first people to break it means
MPLA we support you
ever since we've lot their phones and
comes here stuff and I just was it if
you have any targets in the future just
please leave the
the the Jehovah's Witnesses and the lady
sits alone because we're havin
as the fun fun with them as it is said
thank you yeah it's
awesome where I've more next
okay next question I am what's with all
the V for Vendetta masks
home how did this come to pass you want
their goods
enormous influence them sister somebody
I want this one you have to design
needles owns one
okay arm before any this fuckin started
it was kind of a it was it was a joke on
some other message was
it comes from some older internet shit
did it's kind of a long fucking story
yeah more like really I think we got
adopted into
was that whole idea above love the
anonymity of people standing up for
something
you know right and all that bullshit but
really actually use another internet
thing
sold nets its everybody's favorite also
so
can you tell me why what you're doing
is any different an attack and an attack
against Christianity or Islam or judaism
without using the cop out that it is it
is a cult
I because I is all major organize
monotheistic religions have long
histories and doing terrible things in
the name of their gods
how is what you are doing any different
than
attack mines a Muslims or Jews was these
attacks are happening now scientology
isn't going these criminal acts right
now
if I had a time machine to go back two
thousand years would have better things
to do with
yeah me I do shit about the Crusades but
you know what
right now wrote the message because
usually at this is because some things
like a
spot at No Sun
visibly before but your the Crusades
fucking divorce with threats to stand up
against that shape you know I'm
welcome to Expat said well despite
having spoken
expansion this crazy chrome right answer
thank you
owns growth of 20
next take I'm were you talking about us
Sea Org
then me right on I heard from him
someone who I guess have bullshittin
scientologists and got some in pro
abouts York from them he said that I am
when
if you do sign up for sushi or give any
you
your contract is for all your I go it's
not for the entire life its four-year
louisianians yes so what over
extracts so would it be possible to go
up to them and say I decided in the
seventies and up yeah exactly
K we can never works they always they'll
have to do is to auditing and shit
says why would you want to yeah
alteration I don't know
I'm just say would it be possible I'll
yeah more or less I mean they would have
to like
confirm it was auditing in all sorts of
bullshit but if you just walk especially
now after like with them all up in arms
about us they would know that you just
fucking with them
okay I covered by would be they keep
their word
obligations Graham X in point make it
worse
that's it means
ironworks did you guys hear about the
circus findings
no tell us um they weren't hands
I hey
girls
that's it wasn't for me
make this isn't a curious if anyone has
a copy if 33 with them today because I
kinda like to see how many signed
I gonna hate them all thanks it's okay
it's
yeah I think I after have turned the
issue with that is that
I anybody that they would send here
today Wooden's
be affected by that because they know
that we talk about it I
what they have is something real like
I'm gonna say
their told to look up any words they
don't understand they only told that she
knew was something from hubbard's crappy
crappy science fiction
that he wrote before the science section
which made him much more money
and a the issue is that their toll that
it was just something from that a fun
one if you wanted to fuck with them is
ask them to clear the work body dayton's
because that's something that's a inthe
within the OT 3.material: and that's
something that they don't have an answer
for
so I you nobody that his body things
body that is now you have menu
governor to look it up I to people to
yeah I said you wanna radio 23
yes all over the place its it's on my
knee just coolin I think actually even
have my back tax guy but including the
recording l/100 okay dennis is that you
have the perfect site
respond thanks very much for all your
hard work I it's it's great to hear
I just wanna test to see if your if you
consider the possibility that your
in some ways showing for the psychiatric
establishment and the pharmaceutical
industry
and wondering if you are still uneven
refocus a left-wing iran denies any
tension and those guys solo no no no no
those guys are the real criminals
no they're not a Scientologist but
they're in the midst of apologizing the
full range of human experience
and they're targeting all people with
dementia less humid years
well I don't know about that they have a
much greater reach
%uh they have far more lobby our and
that they're killing people right now
well safe I'll true true please use it
as a sign in to YouTube has lots of the
doors
I don't think so by Tom I'd be really
interested in applying some your
techniques and energy to solving
some others really large problems okay
also once I get in a lot of ways we're
also not really an activist group was
just gonna run around reading all wrong
but we estimate but I'm the same like
you know anything's possible we could
always direct it was all the things we
don't like
well considering a measure we are
forcing their message for them
unit pharmaceutical industries work for
them by tagging some Scientology's
message because I have seen the truth
yeah I don't care where
were over so maybe you can get one last
question and then
up minimum ok it was a good one I gave
you a USB key just a few minutes ago I
passed it over and contains one picture
if you show to the people you see the
traffic statistics have seen you that
night and you will see what in fact I've
actually had
I yeah I ever I recall seeing at at
February 10th which is the anniversary
of police macpherson's there
that's a woman that very prominently
they just sort of watch
die I can tell the whole story now bada
they pretty much murdered a woman and
covered it up and the
after february tenth you can search the
traffic statistics there's an enormous
spike for searching
Lisa McPherson I think that a
Scientology's a virus and where
inoculating people
information will inoculate you against a
scam
and that's going on last question quick
all psychosis a comment and there's
actually an article
anonymous and on Maxim Maxim yeah
yeah at lead a pretty decent size
article to
yup that's when yes expect more and more
more in the future denies there yeah I
think this round of layoffs is now right
yeah you of these days okay
splits say yes
yes