I can ever hear me as my name is Travis
Goodspeed
and the student University of Tennessee
and they work for a pitch National
Laboratory
this is a side project of mine that
began
during May took on 2007 project
which was a stack overflow exploit
for an issue for 30 days wireless sensor
nets so
where these nodes are deployed and where
they're running certain types
microprocessors you can inject code into
them just as you would a computer
but unlike your computer you have no
operating system
you have no address space levin was
Asian you have known to the defense
mechanisms
they PCs and servers have built up over
the years
its just
flat memory space single application
perhaps there are some standard
libraries but there's no OS as you know
it
see this talk is going to describe
methods reverse engineering software
that you've taken from such a platform
and rather than
introduce reverse engineering itself I'm
going to assume that you know the basics
from say taking apart a PC program in
IDA Pro
they you understand C functions in C
programming language
that it's turned into assembly language
and all that stuff but you have no
experience with
wireless embedded systems Gordon St 4:30
in particular
so I'm going to focus on those ways in
which
this platform is different from the PC
and
in the ways in which the tools are
different from PC
I did does not support the industry for
30 sOooo
I've been working on a pearl scraps
columnist to 430 static
which is used to reverse engineer suffer
for the platform
CST 4:30 itself is a 16-bit
risk ish microcontroller and
for those are you familiar with the
principles rescue was supposed to have
single addressing mode well not sing
like this and that would sing with
fetching and storing the RAM so if you
want to read anything from miami is a
load if you wanna write anything Iran
use a store
your addition your multiplication
is or other opcodes
cannot access RAM directly they can only
access the registers
on an issue for thirty this isn't true
you've got complicated addressing
schemes
and this is necessary to fit firmware
within the
limited RAM and flash memory at the
device
and you can get an issue for 30 static
at SourceForge
is amnesty for 30 static that s if that
net its
poorly written prospects apologize for
that but
it works and its
design is being cleaned up this is the
device that will be hacking today it's
the teal sp
the design came out at the berkeley
note project as you can see in the top
there is and USB plug
that just gives you a USB to serial port
which ran straight into the
microcontroller
on the left if you see that copper
tracing around the
a chip that Santana and that ship that
wraps around as a chip kahn 24 2010
radio it is the edited at 15 at four
protocol which analyzing be an ISA 100
invariably the low powered schemes
this is much more low power than
Bluetooth
and it doesn't specify modes is
maintaining a connection it doesn't
specify anything except how to get a
packet from one device to another
everything else is built on top of that
by
networking stocks and you can pick and
choose your networking stack when you
compile softer for this platform
you to specify a which stack you'd like
to use and it builds everything and if
you want to switch from seizing be to
raw fifty not for thats one option on
your make
command and
this is because the standards haven't
really solidified yet you can't
say that if you doing a commercial
protocol you have to go exactly are you
have to go as high as a one hundred
and you need to be able to switch on a
when
to the first thing that you do is
attach a che tak connector I'm gonna go
through this rather quickly because
it's just a bunch of photos that is
issue 8 connector
on the circuit board now the
you ate is a condensed connector forward
both J tag and a serial port access it
you just pop it off the battery
you break apart one of these multi pin
connectors
you feed them through after plugging
them onto the
translator board solder them and I'll
stand a nice neat row like this as if
they were still surrounded in the
plastic packaging
which you cut off with
pliers if you don't have the proper
sizing as i denna you then add to an
adapter board
this gives you two plugs in the
background is a serial port
in the foreground as the g8 act work you
run that
into USB fat you can purchase one of
these from Texas Instruments
for $50 to $100 dollars connect the USB
port works perfectly in line X
is plug it into the board
and then you actually run GTB
as you would on a regular PC program
so but instead of attaching a process ID
you attach to the physical device so you
just run a script that says
grab the device over this USB port and
you get your GV command line
with the president's program counter
position and everything that you would
expect
on the UNIX process
you run a dump command 2.9 marine just
as you would in UNIX
this gives you an Intel hex file they
Intel hex file I just should have it
here so
this will be the beginning avram and
every single line if this can be easily
interpreted by
script so beginning with this line
the kolenda says this is a line above
the file 10
is the length in hexadecimal as a single
by
so 10 is 16
their 16 bytes where the data 32 nobles
32 characters following that is the
starting address
200 happens to be the beginning love
the address range that we instructed to
dampen it's also the beginning avram
followed by that is the date itself
followed by that as a check some
so if the check some weren't enforced
you could almost
is this as a plain text
hex editor equivalent
will jump to those you disassemble it
using
can you bring your tools the details
just as you would
normally on a PC program is a BJ dump
specify the architecture specified the
input file dump it out to a script
you then read that and amnesty for 30
static
to call and 4s two saves and syllables
as it reads it in and it populates an
SQL database
with everything that's found within that
image
on a PC program where you have four
gigabytes
the potential space that would be
suicide
it would kill performance and the
application will become unusable the
slow
with even a moderately large program
we're dealing with the 16-bit
microcontroller
until you get into later extensions to
the platform
you can only has 64 kilobytes of total
memory thats code that's data that's I O
RAM everything and it turns out that
this is manageable
in an SQL database even before you do
proper indexing
to you communicate with m4s
by you using a dialect SQL
so you give an SQL queries and it gives
you
results this and changes in syntax to
make things like hexadecimal
address is easier and there is extensive
scripting supports you can add a script
in shell script
or pearl or SQL
the sorts of things this is a
macro if you type in that men map that
Gd dot
PNG the pipe the output into PNG file
you get this image
this is actually a bitmap involve memory
the upper dresses are the top
lower dresses at the bottom of his I'm
not sure if it's visible from the
display but at the very top right is a
green line
that Green Line is the interrupt vector
table
that's the set of pointers that are
jumped to when interrupted struck
beneath that you have flash memory
and you can see by the display that most
to the flash
is black that means that its own use
flashes allocated by GCC beginning at
the bottom a flash working its way
upward and flash itself begins just
above ground
with the minor strip unusable memory in
between
the blue dots are addresses which are
referenced by code
and there's a bit of noise in this
because someone the code is
jump around that was misinterpreted and
disassembled
now within the RAM you've got you see
that bar
blue where addresses are constantly
referred to you
that's actually the serial bootstrap
loader its a program which exists in
mast ROM cannot be changed ships on
every single MST 4 30 except for the
very lowest and models
and it allows you to program the chip
without purchasing the
jagger you can buy an FTDI
usb2 you are converter run some wires
send the initialization code and load
everything up
the very bottom you'll see I O
now I owe it is an actual included in
this image because we didn't dump it
when we get the range we said begin at
two hundred which is RAM
and work your way up to four ass
but they're still references to it the
bloom dots
once again our
pointer targets so their points in code
where things are written to
or read from the i/o ranges and that
forms the blue lines the lowest level
the blue lines in the BSL level come
from
tables which exist every time you have
a switch statement you have a table
have addresses which were added to the
program counter and no show up as blue
a quick preview love functions as they
work on this platform
there's a call state the call statement
is usually followed by an absolute
address
it doesn't have to be by the
microprocessor but it always is by GCC
so unless you're doing custom assembly
were your
say doing self rewriting code
which I have done this but on you just
give it an absolute address in a jumps
to it so that means that we have
the entry address every single function
and then we also have a return address
which follows
and if you look more closely at the
output love any given compiler
and their seven for this platform there
in common use
you'll find that every function is
either the target of a call
and interrupt vector table entry that's
an interrupt handler
words used by a function pointer and
function pointers are exceedingly rare
you'll also note that every function ans
after either return
or return from interrupt instruction
and that is always after the last
relative jump there are no
relative jumps between functions
this is partly caused by the compiler
and it's partly caused by proper C++
coding that this is considered spaghetti
code
to have a GOTO statement in one function
jump to label with another
it works but God will continue for
now we can do the search all the entry
points
seeking to a SELECT statement this being
the simplest type of query
is a select the hexadecimal address have
each function
it gives you listen is the first two
elements the first
page results this is a large program
that its includes radio drivers and
this it's tough now flash from begins at
four thousand hacks
and you can see that there's the
function at four thousand hacks that is
the
target the reset vector it always is
suing the chip
powers on and the firm has been compiled
with gcc
execution always begins at four thousand
this is important because that 4,000 is
also one sixteenth
above the password for the bootstrap
loader
and it by recognizing the behavior in
the
compiling can actually get some the
passwords within the chip
at not well enough to break it quickly
but with other methods you can
now you'll also note these other
addresses which occur before
flash memory that's the BS all-round
that's the program that ships and mask
Ron that you cannot erase
on every single chip for loading
software with serial port
and they got dragged into our analysis
because we included them in our range
the BSL itself as an alternative to Jay
tag and its password protected
at black at the summer I'll be
demonstrating a method by which
on the most recent versions the chip and
very few prior
if any you can
break the password the timing becomes
non-regular
and by observing differences have a
single clock cycle
between you're giving the last by the
password
and it's telling you okay I've got it
you can actually tell how many bytes
love your gas are correct
but details on that will have to wait
till August
now it wing what you read in this
program and you've got these hexadecimal
addresses
you can know some of them by a
experience but four thousand
taxes always the entry point OVA
use a program but that doesn't tell you
enough to begin breeding the code you'd
have to
search through thousands have bites have
code to find what you want
no if you think about how you write C
Cody try to use libraries
you purchase libraries perhaps the
open-source
in the cases this system
although the external chip drivers the
libraries and their LinkedIn
no their knots deal else to statically
LinkedIn
only the functions that you caller used
but because it's free compiled code
even the links are adjusted the code is
almost identical
and your belief function give a function
that does not call any other function
it is perfectly identical so absolute
value for example
in assembly you just check to see if the
number is negative
if so you in britain at one to make a
positive
if not you just return
on a given compiler say GCC
every function that calls ABS the
absolute value function will include
that same string
love bites within its software
and we know the beginning and we know
the end
so a database can be made up these
different functions
now of course you can to share the
function code itself because that would
be copyright infringement
but a one-way hash a copyrighted work is
not itself a covered work
and that's all we need to test for
quality
so St 4:30 static actually ships with
a list love md5 checksums
they're not cryptographically secure but
they work I love
functions that you might find within a
given from our image
so you load it up you copy the firmware
of
it can then run through and recover all
of the simple things
%uh functions that it's already seen see
just typed at Live dot important hashed
this is a macro you can see the code
inside the
source you can change it it's just a
string in a database table
any type in that symbol Duk that's the
most ever cover
and it gives you a not an error message
I I conceded beginning sloppy pearl
but the result is that when you do is
select statement
you can see the names a every standard
library function
that I have in my collection
and if any of you begin working with
this in use send me your hashes
I can add them to the list and if anyone
begins analyzing the same firmware that
you're working with
or any related firmware or any firmware
made with the same compiler
they can find the names that you given
these functions
they can also do call grass this is
a simple picture perfect one love
actually the function that causes a
stack overflow exploit
the you'll note that is the right doctor
table at the beginning
olive the inner us just go to the like a
No of
function that says we should it be
interrupting on is
what the hell happened but yet
goes to the reset vector this is a
different ship sOooo flash memory begins
lower at 1100 hacks but it's still the
very beginning a flash a rule about
three-set
vector remains true it calls main main
causes other functions
this other functions cost rank up
now if I gave you this image as
something to break until you couldn't
get main
you would get i-vt you would get actors
and
you would get unexpected
you get test put ass which you could
tell was writing to add about your
and most importantly you would get
string copy at 11 E
so you can audit programs that you have
no source code to
for things like string copying and then
you know exactly which function look at
and you know exactly which functions
colette
you only have to actually decipher two
or three functions
love machine language to figure out a
large program
unfortunately this turns into a rat's
nest
for to the radio firmware that we've
been working with
you'll note that there is a focal point
in the mid as the picture just above and
to the right
you see all those edges overlapping one
another
resume n thats Nessie atomic
and Nessie atomic start
these aren't threads but the close
enough so you have threads and they
don't wanna step over one another
so they're doing at the commit acts okay
so the one task won't
kill another task and if you do some
database queries to see how many are
calling it you see that have 577
total function calls nearly 200
are two this new text architects at
so we can just drop them
and then we did account to see that word
on this 310 278 functions
and looks much cleaner it's not clear
enough
were me to show the whole thing on the
display that you can then start zooming
into individual functions
because the Atomics have been isolated
they're just sitting off in a corner and
we're going them for the moment
there's another macro which recreates
the calls table
after you've mangled
now when you trying to mess with the
program you you wanna figure out
where certain functions have been called
ok with
which functions are included in this
case we have a
chip kahn 2420 radio the operating
system is tiny OS-two
which was chosen because I like it not
because it's
particularly effective and stuff so
you can just do a search for anything
with CZ 2420 in the name
and if returns every single function
that's part
the radio driver because it's seen a
similar function
in 10 the example programs a tiny alas
that's in my collection
now you can also chase by i/o ports
this is a microcontroller see don't have
an operating system you
don't have slashed dev devices as you
would any UNIX you don't have contacts
which is the right to it you know
any of that stuff you just write to a
special address
at the beginning memory other peripheral
register
these are between 0 and two hundred
hacks on the amnesty for 30
is control i/o pins I all modules which
actually do the work I O four years so
if you want to do say serial port
you can rate it yourself using the Pens
you can say
raise the voltage lower the voltage
measure the voltage in every
thing you need to do or you can let for
Phil model do it for you
and then it does the implementation and
hardware and you can spend far fewer
clock cycles
working out the details they're also
timers you can turn interrupt handling
on and off you go all sorts of things
that these
registers upcoming chips are having
USB device ports to these registers
they're having
hardware a yes so within this little
three-dollar microcontroller you can do
as: encryption
just by writing your key to one place in
memory writing a packet to another
and then reading the packet back out
from that same address
but if you look at the data sheets you
get a list of all these addresses their
own hardware you can't hide them they're
not
remapped for the operating system that
they're not
English names anything like that so you
can just select statement
you can say show me although the CC 2420
functions
and which address in memory the right to
Akins the list
and as you see there those addresses are
within RAM
there's a global variables
which are quite useful when you're
trying to change the behavior the
program
but beneath that other performances
so you know which Kansas
the CC 2420 is connected to
even if you don't have any hardware work
with and further you know exactly
which function look at
to control that I'll you know that
CC 2420 receive p reads and writes
the IR registers
which you can find from the
documentation
it's a bit hard to read from that there
but it
accesses port 1 interrupt enable
and then the airport when interrupt flag
so its controlling interrupts
and then after turning these interrupts
on is an interrupt handler
see look at the port 1 interrupt handler
whose name was likely not found by this
and then you can determine exactly what
it's doing
you can replace that interrupt handler
with another one changed to buy to the
firmware
had something on in the unused black
region
from the memory map have that then jump
to the original one and you just added
an inline
packet sniffer to the firmware
and because the regular firmware doesn't
notice this it's jumping over the back
nine everything
it will Seydou channel hopping for you
and then even if you don't know the
protocol even if you don't know which
frequency to tune the radio to know
you're okay because it'll turn the radio
itself
you can have its but things out the over
serial port
you record it everything's good
now the
I'm just gonna conclude with a few minor
notes and then
as I mean it takes a detailed questions
rather than the usual
quick wins feel free to mention ports
hexadecimal anything
on so first there is the issue finding
similar information
this is actually the lives see file
Ave commercial C compiler for this
platform
you can download it gets ago 30-day
evaluation
were luv you actually code size limits
you can only compiler for kilobyte
program
this is not high giving experience with
IRS format
I would love to speak to you this is
image craft
version 7 and I like image craft
because their format so easy to read
you've got a DOS
you have dust text files CRLF thats
LF so the CRS rendered as the control
them
any Macs and their separated by a UNIX
text files with the dots start dont so
between every not start not an
we have a record other function within
the
library now
if you look at the en ligne that tells
you which source file this came from
netscape ABS data ass despite the dot
asset
ending I know that this is actually
compiled
a don't Scott that says that s file
said came from assembly language might
have been precompiled might not have
beneath that you see an ass entry
at the symbol
symbol is underscore AVS commonly system
libraries preap and
their functions within underscores that
you can do it without the underscore to
override
beneath that you have a key line and
that two-line
says it an offset 0 bytes it's the first
two zeros
you have the code beginning 0e 930 334
3e e0 FF FF cetera
that's the actual machine ca when you
link this
that is copied somewhere in your program
and a call statement is used to jump
there
then it takes R-twelve which is the
first parameter
in image cross compiler
and it makes a positive and then it
returns
you cannot call this from GCC because
GCC sense its parameter in our 15
by watching which parameters are used in
which order
you can often determine which compiler
the
code came from another way that you can
finger from the code
on if you see the ffff
in the middle toward the right that is
an immediate
constant the amnesty for thirty has
unique feature they the realize
immediate Constance would be needed a
lot on a microcontroller because you're
always setting a bit clearing a bit
when you set a clear that you're usually
doing one right
and that one is either 0
one 24 a
or -1 -1 in 16 bits
is the 4s that can actually be encoded
by use the constant generator
and there's two bites can be cut out a
dysfunction
image craft is the only compiler the or
some other rather
that assembles this way all the
competing assemblers
will take that FF no cut it out no-cut
that instruction from four bytes
down to you can identify
this you can also identify the lineage
love the file format this comes from
and I can't recall whether it's open
source a free as in beer
but the says some local s4 30 that uses
this exact same format
so from that we can determine that image
craft likely funded
or purchased s4 30
to all these things can be determined
about the
file format and once we have a love then
we can dump that we can
right out ABS and then the md5 checksums
the restive it and then we can identify
ABS
with the N anything that we see but
unfortunately I only have
working importers for image craft in GCC
if you'd like to help out with IR and
quite appreciated
as I R as the most popular commercial
compiler this but fun
know if you pop open a function and I'm
only going to do this for one because
the sort of thing you should do with
pen and paper and private or come get me
in a locket through it
its bad for an on-screen presentation
we've got the bitwise compare
and then a jump at the jump is not taken
then we enable interrupts
but using m4s you can render that as
a instruction flow graph you can see
that
instead that execution begins at the
compare
follows down then if the jump is taking
it because the return it's not taken it
enables an Ratzinger's
return you can you grass like this with
timing
so if you're trying to analyze the
timing a complicated function did
insure that all branches have the same
costing clock cycles
you can do this just add up the edges
between vertices you've got
dozen issue is switch cases and
it puts a you would think the
that if you have a switch love safe
three cases
all which break that would render 23 a
statements
and machine language would look like
that and see in practice what happens
is that some compilers say that
the program counter should be set to the
Foo
element have an array of pointers GCC
does this
and the problem with this is that they
just stick
that array in the middle love your code
they don't it is nothing marking at as
special
so automated analysis tools will trip
over it thinking that its code
and this cause some %uh the static blue
lines
in the unused portion a flash memory
and it's important to note that so long
as this is being mistakenly interpreted
you can't trust every single bite that
comes out
you'll always get a bit of false
positives when you do
say searches on Pope addresses further
some other compilers I'm not sure the
name a bit but the one that's
CIA is is to make the BSL mask ROM
I believe that is the BSL actually
predates code Composer
and inside TI they often use IRS product
donors that the application that's come
out for IR and then for Coke
sir and if you speak to the eyes and
engineers they've
cook poses catching up but they still
have a marked preference
for I R but whichever compiler these
internally for generating the BSL
and it might even be hand written
assembly language they do
and offset thats bitwise
so instead of having two bikes for
everyone at the table
anything not relocatable they only have
one
and they can shove the code anywhere
they like without having to adjust
references
this makes it smaller than GCC and it
makes it even more painful to interpret
because I can't just do automated
interpreter for GCC style
is I wanna catch the other compilers as
officials like that will be written
but automated handling a cig jump tables
is not yet working also
many of the operating systems who turned
is being used loosely it's really
moreover compiler environment
and standard library
that exist for these platforms they do
automatic inlining
because stack memory is very precious so
if you have
function foo which only calls bar and
bars not called anywhere else
within your code it just appears
in machine language as food doing
whatever bar would have done with no
immediate call
this gets tricky because sometimes you
can have
the same library function called only
once
and then it doesn't show up if entire US
you only do an absolute value call once
absolute value does not show up as a
distinct function
it's just shoved right in the middle if
you're calling function
there's also an issue
when writing patches for PC software
you can often get away with just shoving
your code in
having it change bites within memory and
continuing
and this works wonderfully in simulation
because and simulation you can make
flash ROM rear I double as if it were
ran
you can do a simple make violence C
compiler yes and preprocessor directives
specifying the addresses that are going
to be
hooked and it's easy to port it to a
different version of whatever you're
analyzing these young ass
change this constancy don't have to open
up a hex editor and
Patchett knowledge that stuff but in
hardware
because the code is in Flash and not RAM
well you can turn an individual bit from
1280 you can only change is zero to one
by changing the entire segment
to a segment once and this becomes a
complicated routine of copying
everything to either another segment in
Flash
order RAM if you have room wiping and
then copying it back
and gets very complicated if you're
trying to do this to the inner vector
table
using have to disable all other us
the menu if to
break the you have to circumvent a lot
of the hardware limitations
it's also important important to note
that you cannot white flash memory well
you're executing flash memory
so whatever patching routine you have
has to be executed from RAM
has to cut off in Europe's first as did
shut down most to the chip
make its change and then restart by
jumping back in a flash
suing hardware it's best serve patches
few points as possible
and a hopefully is a script for
to have any questions yes
yet ship
this
you
why he's as the
microprocessor in quantities at three or
fewer
is free you to sample it and if you want
development kit
be careful about that though they check
that so don't
keep them on this if you're getting free
parts do it
to learn the platform as far as
purchased
as far as purchasing development kit for
twenty dollars you can get an answer
could debugger
which does everything that the J tag
unit are displayed does for certain ship
models
over what they cost by by wire as well
as a target word
with a chip on it you can compile
suffers GCC
right on their they make a higher end
model with
which includes to rip to target boards
both which have a more powerful chips
and radios this is only fifty dollars
this minor issues with developing in
latex
I've written articles on getting it
to work in there you you essentially
have to downgrade the firmware
love to have the chips on the board but
you can make it compatible
and you can compile your firmware using
gcc thing is
I R and UNIX it all works perfectly in
under Wine
but the development equipment is very
cheap
and it's a very nice platform this does
things that pic could only dream about
and psychic at UIC
right and you have actual
RAM with stack in round it's fun women
architecture so you can do rear I double
code
as everybody go you can have code just
spits out bytes
and then jumps to them an excuse and you
can't do that on a pic
you have as deeper stack
as you have free memory you can do all
sorts of fancy stuff
the pic cannot do for about the same
price so does that answer your question
I did
I feel of so I presented that
to work on 2007 and TI DC 2008
I'll if you like to hear that presented
tonight or tomorrow
gave asleep first who'd like to see it
tomorrow afternoon at name a time
okay I C
right the so I'll do it it's
save 4 o'clock tomorrow I
any other questions yes
yes
sue this isn't their as: chip
has either been announced since I last
looked for at
or has not yet been announced if you
look carefully through their marketing
literature
they do their block diagrams and all
that stuff before they make the official
announcements
so you can see peripherals in their
marketing
pictures that don't yet exist in the
marketing taxed and don't yet exist
in chips that you can order or a look at
the day she's for well
if it works the way that multiplication
does there's no multiple instruction
on this chip you right you're too
factors in two different registers
you hit an interrupt and then two more
registers have the result
or one depending upon whether you want
there's one clock cycle which the result
is invalid
but on the clock cycle after that you
can read the results than
incredible chip and they did this
without taking over another up
if you're interested in
say multiplication on a chip without it
is an excellent article
on doing soft multiplication and I
recently extended that to do
suffocation with code rewriting to you
can
call my code with whatever
number you wish to multiply by and it
generates fixed-point
machine code in RAM that you can branch
to
to perform the multiplication and
something like that is only possible on
fun I'm an architect is like the 430 if
you try to do this in a 251
you would have to do memory management
tricks
I'm the 8051 shipping working with now
actually cannot modify its own code
because if yes what the code out
then you are no longer executing your
own code to rewrite itself
and there's no other RAM available
butted
this architectures know that clutch any
other questions
yes
no I haven't and I have done work with
them by
it's a bus sniffing and I can stick to
syringe needles
into traces in the board and grad year:
as: keys
as you send them from the CPU to the
radio because and present designs
the radio does the hardware acceleration
today s rather than the CPO
and if you sniff it on the bus instead
over the radio you get
they're taxed as well as keys on
is a standard coming out which actually
specifies that we're going to use a ass
and we're going to have affixed able to
enter six keys
and it should be noted that sending
the keys in the clear over the bus might
be an issue
and this is in a secure environment
we're not talking about a toy here
lots of people are making lots of
mistakes
in designing hardware of this type and
in the near future software for
analyzing microcontroller software
become essential to securing these
devices
to determining whether or not what you
purchased
is secure enough for its yes
no
any other questions
because I will canceling the talk
tomorrow for four
have look at the itinerary to make sure
that it's
pencils and and a few announcements
don't block the hotel
for good rude don't turn the TVs of
they don't like it a and then there's a
solar compass for the human domain talk
in this is %um
I don't know what it is yeah
ok yeah
somewhere