yes
enough
good
you
its
of
service you know
here it's not appropriate I
for you
I Mike credibly so
friend his back
for
huge
ago
me
ever
I support
slow
south
services
I think it was like that yes
here
I his
first
I
yes his
so it's so lawyer you
its you Kors worse on
today for yet
its
yeah
pain thank you us yes
route
you
so why is
there's not believe very much
its yen's you
now Jesus useful
frankness
house over
yes use my you on
results security you see any
he is of size use the
he his STA
over and characteristics
if there is one
the over for hoover's
yes
yes me it yeah less
last this and because
series three
you
graceful this life
you know where you know is you really is
also people's me free
me or he's
were and you
also lawler his re
users is is here
great funny both all really
respected forward use for
STA and in this time police one
points is website now in
free is this fleece is possible rice
walls
to on me the text
its good re
see one safe please was
word plans areas for SC he
and here
please me
so
lead
word your course for me
me in prop
hairs and Arsenal
its a racism
its the /url but you can also
servers wise
wire sir
whose since word traditional sir
would he said
passes he is you combine
have with head
I'll all is
see the yes for
rock over the only
he who St
access is this is the third
are those use points
up those that can produce a
if Alan port not for SPAC funds I should
produc sequins or SBA packet SBA by
contrast transmits authentication
information packet
pillows and adjust the packet headers
and other
the goal here forces to make in Matt
ineffective
at detecting a service that's protected
in this way I think the security
community
probably would agree with me that
protecting a service with a kernel level
filtering mechanisms such as IP tables
in the Linux kernel right the FW in the
BST crawls
rpf it sir I in OpenBSD as probably good
way to protect against
any user space phone abilities that may
exist in
users based application like sht that's
not to say the files themselves are
perfect saw for this certainly not there
had been von abilities from time to time
but at least we can minimize
the on abilities that could potentially
be exploited by an arbitrary sources
just happened happily scanning for
SH that diets is a advertise to the
world via TCP socket
so some people rely on
saw for such as deny hosting fail to ban
to look for
password guessing attempts and the SSH
logs a
be a lot like via syslog that's a good
strategy
and at least for trying to to convince
you that that
having a good pass for is a good idea
but many attacks
don't rely on x bird forcing a password
me the sales key energy overflow
exploits
the order exploits gets open SSH for
example are net
there's no password in sight and yet
you're still able to compromise
sshd the recent Debbie open SSL for
natalie was also
a good example where password again
nowhere in sight you have
reduced entropy in the generation of
keys not affected SSH as well
so and there's also a the second will
appoint there's kind of an interesting
article post post on the register
that talked about a new strategy
down for where a coordinated attack
against brute forcing passwords an SSH
demands would be done via on distributed
systems that have all been compromised
by
and an attack or said attackers only 3 a
tense
would come from individual system in
order to try to brute-force apart
password and 138 since been made
the next attempt to come from a
different IP address its order the same
classic technique for you try to slip in
it beneath an IDS
port scan special by producing number
forty scanner scanning over a longer
period of time
like anything so they now apply this is
well it s SSH password guessing a tense
so that reduces the effectiveness of
trying to threshold
does Phil login attempts so personal and
a lot more concerned about
on much more damaging explaining n sht
and so I don't allow anyone to connect
the SSH
until they've generate a valid SBA
packet
so is a useful
I would see yes
and we'll talk about some trends and
second there are many competing
implementations if you look at for
knocking down or
there's about 30 of them a total as
about 5 implementations that
implement SP a style authentication
there's about any another 25 port
knocking implementations
those five SBA implementations do a
little bit differently from project to
project the tumbler project uses a house
pillared for example whereas
there's a there's a a net filter module
that
that those sp-a specifically with air
particularly within the Linux kernel
itself so there's no use when com-
ponent
are running on the server side and I'm
so list
talk about some trans you know it's
kinda hard to quantify
who is running for knocking or SBA I
can't go download in the App and
scan for your port knocking instances me
is designed specifically to make that
impossible
so what can rely on why hasn't download
statistics from my webserver Seifert and
outward
in phnom 2006 got about nearly 3,000
hours 2007 that
more than doubled and so far this year
its nearly 10,000 in this year's only
about half over so I think the train is
up
and we can also look at for true trends
from search engines
so last month I really sick pay to a
call to do trude
you can of course Thomas download as the
link at the end of the slide
which what does it once per day it's in
the senate search terms
into Google and takes the number
above hits in Google and in trans those
numbers over time
and so generates agnew plot graphs
have a that search the search results
data
so I've I wrote the first version if you
truth about a year ago
I didn't release it because I wanted to
collect some data and so
and if i graph the term single pack an
authentication
now authorization and authentication in
this case
on starting from July of last year going
through July
this year its gone from about 200
I'm search result in Google up to over
single back authorization which is a
term that FW not use is specifically
after being up does a of course both
authentication and authorization
which are not the same thing
and the trend back in July 07
I'm maybe a thousand card even see the
red on aircraft but then
you get this stranger loss elation in
fact coming from Google that's probably
more are a faggot how Google built its
index verses
you know say here in in late June a
spike up sixty thousand web sites
referencing go back and authorization
roth and then on the next within the
next two days
all those you noted 50,000 this website
and a win away in Google's index right
so
kinda interesting how Google builders
index I wish I had had
gertrude I when I first as really
stepped up you not but I didn't tell
year ago
but here's the graph what the S&P not
term looks like a course if you're
involved in any open source projects are
thinking of starting one
I it's good to take to you a unique
strains he can do this kind of analysis
FEA search engines it's very
you after being off is pretty unique so
it's easy to get a sense of what
search engines really see it as
incentive having lotsa
other overlapping data
so I'd see SBA uses probably up
but what long are widespread deployment
probably has a long way to go to
on if in if you have some good
statistics re:
that that you would like to discuss your
share with me every really interested
on support within limits distributions
are other platforms
is I think going to be a driver for this
technology
ISA we now supports IP tables and IPFW
like you mentioned there's also a
Windows client
I and there are our plans integrated
with on things like
the open the BRT Linux distribution by
rewriting after being up and see
much more lightweight is currently in
Pearl
on and there's an I think it really into
the open question which is
you know to what extent are these
technologies used by the black community
at Dubai its use them there's been some
anecdotal evidence that seem to indicate
that for knocking is used for has been
used from time to time but
its tennis kinda sketchy there's a lot
of lot of data there that does make a
great topic for a research paper
okay to switch gears a little bit any
question so far
yes
hey
know is the question was any
plans to integrate with packet for
bringing the PFR along the st.
yes that's on the two specifically that
will be done on
and and also it plans integrated within
the iPhone
the question on I don't know much about
what on
what capabilities the iPhone has for
packet children presumably it has IPFW
in
in the in the car all because is running
on Mac OS 10 but
I I don't have one yet so if you'd like
to
provider development from it love to
have contributed yeah
I'm I was a client on
yeah you it if anyone does anyone know
if pearl rounds on the iPhone
okay well in that case it it probably
would work right now
and that the everything up comes bundled
with all the necessary for pro models to
get it to work there is a dependency on
not
on that I said there's a lot more
depends on the server side they're on
the client side side I would anticipate
that you could probably get that to work
today
I in fact if you if you would like to
try that and see me now love them
you know make a blog post about it
reference your website or whatever that
that's a great
a great question night is have I've
don't have anyone tell me so far that it
definitely does work but
if you the first love to know about it
okay so
listens to a little basic comparisons
here and try to highlight the
the real differences between for talking
as PA
on so let's take this
the most simple possible porn oxy points
that is run to say that if
a TCP SYN packet is received on port one
two three four five demo grant access to
let's just say SSH from the source IP
degenerated that packet
this is a shared sequence between pic
the server-side and client-side and has
a few advantages
the first move the foremost being a dick
this can be implemented in the simplest
possible way
on the server side only 16 bits of
incoming information is really
significant and has to be processed by
the server
pretty hard to put in over for export in
16 bits of information probably
um lift the cap is also of course not
required we can just park so far a log
file that's not
not typically a a dangers operation on
and any web browser even could be your
poor talking climb you don't have to
have a niece
specific special saw from the plant site
generates a sequence
on and also an attack and if
pretty effective attack again sport not
secret is in general is the fact that
since the sequence typically you if an
attacker
can eavesdrop on your traffic they can
spoof a packet at 28
to the last four digits on the sequence
and they can thereby convince the
service I did they
the client doesn't really know the
ballot sequins and therefore deny access
to the real point can do that with only
a single packet is involved
so disadvantages well
in that now becomes Maya as an attacker
my airport not planned for us in that
the target twice
from the first if a person that doesn't
scan every single port by default but
and I can certainly make you do that if
you like scan every port
and then scan the target again and see
what's what server reports now open to
me
i really wanna make in that my aunt
for a client so
this still has some measure of security
of course I mean sir Alistair to running
as a from a diff report
on that kinda thing and if you've got
any sort of made attack out their organs
SSH that doesn't
combines such a port scan on this
you know it's probably not going to pick
up to date has to scan this particular
for before gaining access
so step it up a little bit on the first
version about to begin up
combined port knocking impassive OS
fingerprinting and I did this across IP
tables log messages
but the basic concept is to have
multiple packets they can involve
multiple protocols
and also fingerprint the
packets to the same packets coming in
the same way that POF does
not to only grant access to particular
networking stacks
that have been fingerprints are like for
example the next 2.6
from disadvantages
well I'm sorry advantages breaking the
not you not sequence typically River
requires eavesdropping you're probably
not going to get in now
to generate this particular sequence UHV
are packets that even involve ICMP as
well
and let's say an orphan act packet in
this particular sequence that's a
that's fairly unusual but I am
I should know course and probably
everyone here does that die
it's not a good idea to assume that
you're packets are not being
martyred I always assume that
try to even though I can always get
against everything am
and this is an example here USA plus
POF and if you look at the ideologue
message on here at the bottom of the
screen
the lot he said the options command line
argument I P tables will have it logged
the options portion the PCB header
and combine that with the fact that part
really only need a few things that
include the TTL value in the city when
the size
and the options fields you can now
completely do everything up of does
on but just use IP tables logging
messages to do it its source of data is
the same
so
well disadvantages in this applies all
stood also to encrypt it or not
sequences
on any sequence involves multiple
packets like this different ports
looks like a common malicious activity
known as a port scan to
Nena any intermediate ideas that may be
watching the packets from the client to
the server
and also sequence replay
is trivially possible whenever you saw
pics involved other there there have
been some strategies to try to mitigate
on your make replay attacks across for
knocking the implementation to love it
more difficult for example
ask East Valley iteration hashing
function but
they're not really that scaleable I'd
say and sorta difficult applied a lot to
users
on so I you know there it sits
difficult it's too hard to get for not
seeing it is to not be formal to our
to replay attacks and also this is
strictly a shared secrets across not
talking about
using encryption yet okay so next
iteration you can
however Inc report not sequences and
combine those with off at the same time
this is
probably represents the the the the
height up for knocking you've got
encrypt the data as well as
on stack fingerprinting involved and
again this can be implemented within
firewall logs so you're complexity is
lower
generally than something that must
sniffing at work directly with Liberty
Cap for example
on but block sizes and Ryan Dahl
and things now require you to have a
certain minimal
certain minimal lengthy apart not
sequence and
that makes it really look like a port
scan tonight yes
so I don't particularly like trying to
set off
IDS alarm bells and I'm really only just
die trying to gain access
the others passive mechanism on the
server side I personally know someone
who was on
working at a company I work for I once
upon a time in and
he's liked it to scan his remote systems
from it from work
I because you want to try to verify that
his Farrell was currently working in
that the system wasn't responding to
reports that it
shouldn't be and he was fired because
the local security policy at
at my company unfortunately and
the if you were using for knocking
he wasn't me the the intended what he
was doing would not have even been to
scan is system
but it would look indistinguishable to
the security teen because it would
really look like there's a difference
between
for not sequence and this can it really
does look like a scam he would have had
a hard time I think committing a serious
security team that's what he was really
doing
okay so
single packet authorization
in contrast it's fast
you don't have to bill me in any time
delays between successive packets but
there's only one packet involved
it as a minimal network for footprint on
it doesn't look like a port scan
and you have access to use a lot more
data
I given in to use ice on network so
you can encode a lot more information
including four commands it to be now
supports that
and and at this point you really really
require use dropping
eavesdropping to in order to break ISPA
authentication
right breaking in where you what I
really mean is that you had had the
capability
love crib analyzing II packets that are
greeted with Ryan doll
or with I can you PG which is not an
easy thing to do
course and no
to SBA packets are the same replay
attacks are
elegantly made infeasible
SPAD implementations
however the code complexity to
accomplish that
is higher and therefore I think that
there is some room for port knocking
implementations
still it really depends on where you
draw the line
to you you consider that that that
passive sniffing is the most important
thing to be concerned about
you consider the replay attacks are more
are the most important thing to be
concerned about
or not the and
so even I should note however that that
we're still talking about a passive
mechanism is not as though you can scan
for your SP a server
and indeed with the at one point 9.6
release it's even harder
to even detect the SBA is actually in
use on a particular network even if
you're
even if the Montreal vidalia on traffic
see them in and so
with new PG we can even extend things
further
typically I use a 2048 bit new PG key
from ISP a packet's
on and you can use important a newbie PG
keys
GPG keys and you this is used for mister
signing on the client side
see you don't need to generate a new key
on the client side although you should
generate
a and unimportant server-side key for
this
because it to be not need access to the
password so it can be crypt
on the server side the incoming data
in this one complex is probably the
highest
we have in Pearl implementations are
Ryan Dahl
on in the case that they do not bid
actually requires a functioning
insulation in GBG on the server side if
you want to do
on sp back as a critic with GPG
so I kind of like to think about it like
this
isn't exactly it scientific graph
whatever but
I think if you think it protocol
imitations versus complexity
I would say that that the SBA
with new PG is probably the most complex
but also has the most benefits in terms
of limiting the limitations and the
actual
for parts of I'm and I like to draw the
Aero
serve the lower left there really really
low on
in the sense that I soon that that
packets are being stepped all the time
and after the right hand side for the
limitations of the greatest as we've
seen
detection by IDS is ability just to toss
the
day after we are the the Fort Totten
server on
and replay attacks are are chief one's
probably
so it any questions on that yes
yes I think I think it its is she a
great
and he's pointing out that down that
you've got a lot of information wanna
it's not easy be held at you can play
with and I
and you don't need given it all that
information is large VIP tables
on he's pointing out that you did you
could probably use that as a covert
channel
and not therefore require some more
complex application layer information
correct
okay yet on that the the question
becomes
though on what how many beds do you
really need in order to thwart a replay
attack
I would say and so it the the initial
implementations a better Bihar
on included actually they aren't they
all include 16 bytes for the random
information
do I require 16 bytes to make everything
random no
but as soon as I start things you know
fire crews reduce the number bits that
that are that are necessary there I
start to the I started to make it
little bit more he's a easily to easy to
conduct a replay attack although
you know probably some experimental
verification we need to be made our
theoretical argument will need to be
made it see how practical that really
would be
and I agree with you there's a lot but
lotsa bits information that that these
be hatter's allow
on so on the thing is you're you're also
started to
to say well if I need to actually change
bits in the TCP header
I'm probably not at that point gonna
just be able to use the keys
stock at a local system so if I require
changing
something in it in the options portion
of the header thats local stock doesn't
allow me to change i cant use is a
simple user space
have you know applications such as web
browser to construct that packet
now probably need I probably ross soccer
with access to
the options portion at a craft that
myself on
as you have user access controls that
point to any router
so that um I would say
you can certainly come up with any
implementation that would conduct
a covert channel over just raw TCP
I TCP header information but how
much information you gonna be able to
include in that and stop replay attacks
and introducing preferred if you like
I'm I think
you at that point you start you might
need to have more information about the
TCP header laos
that's my gut feeling
okay so switch gears a little bit
detecting as PA traffic
so
FW not
sins you TP packets buy to fall for SBA
Communications
over reports 6'2 201 en españa packets
to Billy going to be at least 250 bytes
long
in its encrypt it basics for encoded
form so
a store rules as you see the top here
looking for any you TP packed in
a you'd be back at to destination port
at least 250 bytes long and
contains the following PCR readers
looking for trailing equals characters
at the into the packet
those trailing equals characters are
produced
as as an artifact base64 encoding so
base64 encoding works by taking raw data
including it into I plain ASCII
said a plain ASCII characters any effect
if the resulting in coding is not a
multiple of four bytes
then your pad that data with equals
characters to make it multiple four
bytes
you can end up with anywhere from one to
three equal signs or zero
if the included eight is already
multiple for whites so just shows into
look for two Eagles characters at the
end above
the this GDP packet incidently on you
might say well why
why use a PC re for this piece here is
kinda expensive and that's of course
true
I'm but unfortunately by dumb jumpers
not work at the transport layer headers
so I can't make it
take the at Lingfield love you deeply
header and use that as an operator to
get to the in the packet data
so using this because this PCR each
expression with his dollar sign
allows me to do the same thing but it's
a slightly more expensive operations
because I have to appeal to the PCRE
library
somebody knows how to get snort right
starting to look for the
the last bite and test that fight for
a particular value but not require
looking at the header
Eve at the same time you know please let
me know his way to do it
okay so that's the first thing so
basically for encoding is used by
all after being up packets sent by the
client
on but we can deliver better than that
an artifact love the crib CBC module is
that
it tries to maintain parity with the
open as how open SSL
encrypts data so there's this static
string salted
underscore underscore is typically used
am I in the in the in cryptid
data and when as base64 encoded it shows
up with this not as this nice 10
character string you TFS the Sarah
I'm and so as I was looking at a bunch
of st. a packet I so well this is sort
of in very in section right at the
beginning you know what the heck is that
I wasn't expecting that considering the
fact that every single SBA I could
include 16 bytes a friend in beta right
at the beginning
but that was being generated you know by
the encryption algorithm itself
and so are looking for that for any pre
1.9 points 6 personal FW not you can
write a star role that would
have a good chance of detecting SBA
traffic this way
so here's an example have the wrong
scripted and
dealt with the wrong for today to for
SBA packing you can see that salted
string right up there at the beginning
and here's the bay 64 encoded version
that packet with that string
in the Bay City koa basis for uncoated
for form a bit
there's no it really was characters in
this particular case because the
encoded information was exactly a
multiple of for
so did needed
so we can also do a similar technique
for a canoe PG encrypt the data if you
look at the Magic database used by the
defile command you'll see that yet
I infers that he filed a kit that begins
with sex
8502 is corresponds to date it's been
infected with the new PG and the basis
for a good version of that
is nice HQ string and also included the
size
requirement a greater than a 1000 bytes
because once you start used the new PG
he's on the the SBA packets
I'm I typically are are free are a
little bit larger so
they're usually over about 1000 by the
year 2040 keep myself
endured years server really abbreviated
version I've
what that pack it looks like it begins
with HQ and in this case
ins also with the trailing people sign
because the original data
was 1,043 bytes long but we had to make
it one thousand forty four bikes want to
be more people for
okay so turns out it's easy tess or to
stop this
on over movies in various sections
yes question
as the question was arm would there be
any into you size problems with having
such a large
on application where he loade on I've
done a lot of traveling and so far I
have yet to encounter network that
dead dead does not handle that well
I mean you're your typical into you size
an easy network is not gonna be a
problem
on you know there are other network
you're dealing here for a close to that
they could become involved but
I'd yet I have yet to see that become a
problem so
typically no so
the the one point 9.6 percent better be
not takes these Invariant Sections
it strips them out completely before
seeing the packet data on the wire
the server-side DN says okay I've got
this now
totally random looking blob love love
hats error ASCII data
and not yet rabin heads back it as
invariant Sections back and before
attempting to do is basically Ford
at decoding or the crypt in for rind all
packets are or new PG packets am
and on and therefore the store rules now
becoming ineffective against
on this latest release a veteran of also
there are sorta I would say
comprehensive for randomization features
now with enough to be enough and this
applies both to the destination port
I love yes the attack itself as well
as the port you choose to make US each
connection over so if you want after the
you not to
create a randomly designated port its
port forwarded to your SSH server
you can do that as well and that applies
both old to
local connections the local local system
as well as
forwarded connections to internal SSH
servers that are not otherwise
accessible
and if I can get the demo work should
show you an example that
so just a is light on what I mean here
this year the top command line if you do
so for
with after being up I want access to my
lets him I'm on radical network
somewhere
i won access to this internal 192 168 n
da 22
server in particular I want access to
ssh on that server
but I'm going to randomize both the
destination for
for the SBA package as well as report
that I want to connect
to on to ssh over in this case
at the pin-up assigns me 4339 for which
I will use on the S
ssh command line to make the connection
so
not the port randomization really makes
things difficult to analyze issues in
addition all
it's just it raises the bar just a
little bit more I can always assume
that my connections are gonna go over
TCP port 22 for SSH at that we not to
make that
unpredictable okay so let's talk about
an attack
instances SBA this one
I think was particularly elegant came
out two years ago 2006 its featured in a
master's degree written by Sebastian
John free am sorry if i'm mispronouncing
your name
arm and I'm basically
the have to be not demand had no notion
maintaining a
a time stamp on incoming as PA packets
so attacker that possessed an inline
device
to an SBA back packet could intercept
one store it off
on disk some are not saying and after
the the client-side well it said this
has the effect across the course
SBA's never acknowledged so when the at
the following message connection was
attended it wasn't allowed well
the client probably just recognize
realized I will make my packing a la
somewhere or
or whatever so the client sends
a new SP a packet which is not different
the attacker says
and that's okay let the Sun through and
the then the service I would open up
port 22 and the
decline would have no way to know that
the that the original as the packet was
seen
was intercepted the the team inside its
have been out demons I was unable to see
that original SBA I get so there's no
way it could do it
a a shot 256 comparison against a new
SPL back in to detect a replay attack
which means that if at the same time
the client used dash ass on the command
line set to force the FW not demand
not to use to trust the source IP on the
I T in the IP header the attacker could
retransmitted
that as PA packet payload from a
different source IP
and gain the same level access as the
original a tent
elegant attack at the office no longer
far more
I it it died yet encodes the source I
address that you want access to with
Indian cryptid
date itself and it maintains a timestamp
pass for all incoming as PA packets
but if you know of another exploit
against as DSP architecture
on yeah I'd love to have some feedback
from the community about the
architecture
so please let me know
don't seem right for a time here on so
this is the 1.9 per tix release there
are a few additional things
on in the in trying to write both
client-side and server-side
software like this ice I've come to
realize that
are tests we is really really important
and
it there's now test we support for port
knocking note as well as as p.m. out of
course is about
i think is about 180 test in there
something like that but anyway
I'm was your question
um upcoming developments
I mention for it's being rewritten in C
arm
I was over to try to get that done by
this conference but just couldn't quite
finish its
but died it will be ported to open wrt
as well as packet protector another
embedded distributions
arm we might have some additional US for
Java
on this this next last one here is
getting kinda interesting now that we
now supports the interface to
T building port forwarding and now rules
I'm also going to add support for SBA
proxying so you can essentially build up
chains have nap rules through it
to it deeply buried SSH server somewhere
on
and you know what's with yet to be not
ins is at the top
now and will build those rules
automatically is that you can access
now from any radical network in all the
way down in that gets busted
and
yes the question is said
in that new proxy mode support on is it
is the information could relate but led
by Lakers are always the original
packets and all the way through the
internal system
yes so um I this is i'd
I'm so little bit design phase for this
particular feature Tom
but and I the couple things are clear
each hop in the SBA past has to be able
to
to to so if I if I send the original
SBA packing all the way through that's
fine but each are
also has to have unnecessary key
information to verify that its
that it's a valid packet on me I at each
hop I could
generating new SP a packet with the same
original information with the section
what's a
random number that's dense including the
any in a Dana and
and that said it still being worked out
a little bit
and there's there's an details there
that down to be top 10
of fun if you like thanks for the
question okay
from I'm okay demo time or
keep going through some examples well
yes one
demagogue a miss me to be a little bit
to set up here to someone to show some
specific information
its resolution
other question was a lot of stuff won't
work for stateful firewall
on actually depends down and Christabel
for hours is on
is that the most serve nice where using
is because it keeps your connection
live or were pressuring the original
except for all down out but you better
be now supports clan drive timeouts
so if you want on if if you
if you want the final tour to accept
your message connection for five days
you can do that I if you configure the
server to allow that
yes the question was on it will work for
something i guess its core pics are you
getting
packets through on their the visa
requirement is that a UAV hack it
add to it the whatever destination for
the clan designates
is sent through at some point and
monitored by after being off instance
so in you know there's some there's an
details there but it should work
typically yes
this
room
time was the sport in the antennae in
the new
I do not one when I'm sponsors release
woods ended
use a YouTube a hole punch method in
conjunction with
TCP connections are and pritchard be
yeah arm that beyond the access
so so once you be back to send may have
to be top actually considered over TCP
your
ICB too but but if the packet St not
demon monitors that I can be accessed
it's rigged it has requested
whether that is a TCP for access or you
to be more taxes
it doesn't its that encoded in the
packet itself by the client so
I'm gonna try to are demo this
what's that
0 make this bigger okay actually here
senator you see that
okay so just a quick mission other the
architecture here
on there are
there are two systems involved here the
two separate systems down here and the
presser
down here this is a this is a FreeBSD
system running an errand underneath
VMware
as running after being up client I have
an Ubuntu Linux system that's running
thats on these two winners appears from
the have definitely observer
and
keys
it's just saying
I don't think I'm going to be able to
you is this
I'm hasn't for with a
Mouser it is that just in the bottom 10
what I've shown here is is that I'm
the IP tables filtering my incoming
interconnection 10 24 22 okay
so the input chain is not allowing the
connection from the BST system to the
Ubuntu One X system
said to be of is running over here now
wanna do is
I'm going to I'm going to use at the
Minot
in INF in that mode here to create
in I a dean at rule for randomly
assigned port over which essay to be
accepted
from there to be no client system the
FreeBSD system
so as you can see down he is just a sign
me
and a Newport so for 119 for
shall in BR I singen
and so now I can log n postname Isengard
which is my Ubuntu One X system as you
can see over in this window
these this is like message is output by
the FAA observer
that you can see a dean at rule for
this particular from one 194 TCP port
to be matted locally to 422 for forty
seconds
and also interfacing course with the I'm
the ideal state tracking mechanism to
keep my connection open
at forty seconds at the Minot D has
removed
this thing input accept rule so now any
new connection that I attempt to make
from the FreeBSD system will not be
allowed but
as you can see here my my session is
still open
that illustrates
on the advantage to using a stateful
firewall for
for doing this kind of thing Southlake
quit exit now
and I just test without I have access to
for 2004 sat down and
in this one now you already see so
this is this is the SBA back in as you
can see the destination port was
randomized to this value
if I were to dive into this fact that
you receive those in very in sections
are also stripped out on the got time to
show that
and then you can see the following
connection which is actually SSH
but it's going over tease the board for
94 so that's a demo and
any questions yes
is the first I could you repeat the mean
this form
yes that is your TV as as i right
the the for the SP a packet itself
kid I is it's usually UNEP by default
but you can use command on a
command line argument the sand even is
in SB attack ever to stab a TCP
connection if you like
that's required to get work effort or on
but you can also arise sleepy is not
necessarily BDP
say any other questions yes i'm Jack a
have you and you departures but you're
using eyes question is how r did me the
Parsis I'm using
that's a that's a great question as you
probably afraid to
net packet for example and the than the
net P cap extension
in Pearl like I think on I've looked at
them a little bit
at what I say that there's a cure I'd
say probably not I mean I
I'd say that's an area where
rewriting in CF think is important to
make sure that
you know things are really well tested I
think using valgrind against this code
is gonna be really important down
so if not in the context of the open SSL
from
anyway um that's a that's a great
question and that
that is a chink in the armor there's
nothing to say that there is not a
vulnerability
in either at Liberty Cap itself or
in the pressures that this code is using
the the main application is to make it
make a target identification phase are
using in math make
that piece hard as possible as hard as
possible
on there could be an exploit waiting to
happen
India to be not server side by virtue of
the fact that uses Pro models that are
also helps
see code in the back end its center
that's certainly possible yes
you the questions yes
on any solutions to chew on it a I
ever virtual system for single backup
cinema quite is that
question yeah um
a said so there have been horrible isn't
in files from time to time
arm you know them many there are
integration points that you could be
you could use within within kernels that
are running in
in a serving a virtual environment just
because you've got access to I V tables
and I DFW things just like in
in rare any VMware but down IFO-twenty
to take a question of why is my question
I got but anyway i think im running
outta time
but I thank you very much
I