right
with different camera
she
three
you
good evening it's nine o'clock
this isn't the bar when you guys doing
here I
my name's Joe Klein and
name is talk is ipv6 next generation
network playground yes how to connect to
explore the network
can I see well let's see I have to step
aside
hands on people that are running ipv6
today
now now everybody else put their hand up
because there's a good chance
ipv6 is under network by the end is
presentation
weird talk about all the systems that
are potentially vulnerable
I'll let me do the standard disclosure
yes I'm responsible for his presentation
on with the job know my customers
not to go for another laptop number dawg
I don't have a dog that you know
will get over that um been researching
this for about five years this is the
first time I've gone to
conference really talked about someone
might discoveries summer the
the viability towards the N word to
discuss I
has been around for two years we've been
a
friends mine are trying to get to
certain people to fix these problems it
takes a while until the wee
tell them hey guess what wanna talk
about this in a hacker conference
so they are suddenly decide to move our
talk belt
a background um when ipv6 some
how did we get to the mess that we're in
right now and we'll talk about them SS
we'll talk about the features like PB
six are gonna provide
a lot of this specially in the security
field on
a lot of features a will be able to use
in control on and also some privacy
issues which is pretty cool
um how to connect you know what is this
what is the three-step so we need to do
to connect this system a network
whatever up to the internet
and lastly some testing we performed and
if we have the time will show the demo
the vulnerability
okay um
the Internet ipv4
internet really started are with
NCP back in the sixties it was concept
that
duty was tired of paying she prices
shipping scientists back in four so that
one scientist could actually
view the records in programs another
scientist sell it East Coast scientists
would have to see something
and they have to fly the West Coast
actually run the application
so they came up with the concept you
there we go the concept of NCP
unfortunately had limited address space
256 device is kinda small rate
um really was based on
allow the concepts from sixties um
currently i pp 4 is based on a lot
I love computing environment ideas many
computers mainframes from 70's
are operating systems that ipv4 based on
is
early version CBS steal annexing I V
units
applications network's programming
languages and we've gone longer
operational experience and we'll head
its
the especially in security and the
operational side
and a in the 90's and 2000's the results
are
that ipv4 is suffering from a success or
to talk about what those
with that suffering really is um we're
also talk about why ipv6 is ready to go
today
and cake current problem
ipv4 was designed with the capability
up providing and Inc an activity so if I
had an application 512 telnet into a
system FIS
authorize the talents that system I B
love telnet into the system
felt all the crazy nets in all the other
complexity and half devil
lots of code to actually perform that
activity arm
today we had this real inability to make
that connection anymore
arm the reason is that
back in nineteen ninety there was a
perception that we're running out of
address is
I ATF announced publicly 1990 running
out of IP addresses yes this is Ben
on around a long time so
after about four years a determined hey
we need to do something about this
the up and decided to put some stop-gap
measures in place
so that we could exist and
IP be forceful as long as we could but
give time for ipv6 to be generator this
new technology at the time it was
I PNG at the time Star Trek next
generation was hot can you
you know next-generation I P you okay
very free
gates on so we ended up with a lot of
work arounds we establish gateways
again and CPE we had established gateway
city next week rate
me four so we didn't have to stab was
gay ways we start a star running out of
address space now we have to create more
gateways
on these gateways for using NAT and PAT
network address translation nom port
address translation
with an atty establish the 1918 space
because people were trying to
suddenly applied say berkeley um
IP addresses internal to large
corporations anybody working the
early mid nineties ran into this on a
regular basis for some bud second you to
this website or i can get a well your
whole
domain is based on 18 tease and
you can't route internally to AT&T
on we also saw a lot of mapping I love
standard ports port 80
suddenly became 4081 4082 Ford
794 whatever their programmers had to
deal with because we only had
one address for 21 address for small
amount dresses
for small mouse service we also had
multiple address
our ranges we have today most
organizations
on how to address ranges from maybe two
three four maybe a dozen
maybe 100 maybe in certain organizations
thousand
address ranges and mapping all that
through the firewall so that we have
connectivity
it's very error prone so with no
problems there
to the real workarounds have resulted
and nested now
there are cases in India that NAT
is six to seven levels deep
can you imagine programming in at
scenario
Voice over IP mmm real good application
that point
one broken applications are those of us
that had to
run on oh well fileshare cross NAT
I broke the protocols the Microsoft had
me
changes make even more complex we
establish on
in the the around 2,000 the program
community said
heck this net stuff is just a pain to
our application so let's create some
workarounds for this so
the programming community %uh supported
by a well Microsoft
fun people like that they create the
technologies like stunned and turn
ice so today what we have is we have fun
a lot about cations that we have in our
internal networks
all have these additional libraries
these additional
code libraries we also have to have
these in our firewalls morale or so we
basically
are getting to a code bloat scenario in
love our situations
and some my coat really wasn't fully
tested in the past and anyway
we end up with more gateways real
complex infrastructure security
um if you were an organization that has
safe for Internet connections
three or four DMC's a dozen extra nets
to customers
mapping that is a total headache and
ensuring from
auditing standpoint from assessments and
point
from penetration test %uh stay in points
for easy cuz you know they're gonna make
stake in it
is so complex on
it takes a lot of time effort and you
really have the inability to
identified vices on the networks anybody
performed the
assessment and all the sudden realized
he does this whole nother networks
hiding behind a snack box that somebody
decided to put up
any they run in that scenario know I
have many times
the it's a really ipv6 is %uh focused on
removing those gateways again so we can
see in touch those devices
I reduce the application for callin
security complexity so we can start
you know down that path we have simpler
code
more secure code and also reestablish
the end and connectivity so we don't
have to have specialized Voice over IP
gateways to be able to
jumped 45 net environments
the justification who there we go
justification the second justification
we have a lot of devices how many have
you have
more than one phone with you
any computer its three addresses how
many you have
well like I do TV shows and
apples and our own lil networks into
firewalls and all the other things at
home
um companies like the cable companies
Comcast
rice and fires there now realizing that
their customers really need anywhere
from $10 to $20 to $50
addresses within their address space
their home address space
and right now they're all behind NAT so
it it causes a lot of complexity
we also have fun X pots I guess
everybody has an x-box
it has an address also so we have a lot
of fun
IP addresses um we don't even have a
list the sensors we see a lot of fun
ipv6 answers for temperature in cameras
and things like that now being deployed
so this point we have fun
%uh by 2012 were expecting about
$2.16 billion devices
unique devices on the net that's before
times
bigger than the current Internet I mean
that's that as a lie complexity I'm not
sure if you guys wanna map all those
netted firewalls around them
kinda crazy on we also have an address
exhaustion to be at a
reach out and touch those are specific
devices
people have to have those addresses so
if the organization year with
has to suddenly implement a new network
or maybe integrate two additional
networks they have a new idea
getting access to address face is
getting harder and harder
and because it's getting harder and
harder to require more complex fire all
setups
routing set-ups he it's making a it a
real mass
also a lot over countries that were only
allocated just a few addresses
have moved ipv6 today some others
customers summers people were customers
love sunnier companies and organizations
um so what we have is
basically people with ipv6 addresses
trying to communicate with ipv4 which
doesn't work a lot of organizations the
really don't won't even know their
customer base is dropping off until
their help desk
start increasing people are saying look
I'm trying to get to you via v6 and i
cant
but Musser customers wouldn't say that
what they they would say can get your
website drive your help those people
crazy
on so we're were basically at a point
right now
that lot organizations need to put in
outside facing ipv6 infrastructure in
place
unfortunately as we go into the
vulnerabilities we've
the that we've done research on are you
know scissors lot business apathy to now
serves yes
that's a new buzzword I'm trying to
implement across the community
that's where businesses decide not to
take action dislike we had with wireless
access points where security really is
implemented until we start seeing bad
things
we don't wanna see bad things this time
and
yes you are here and yes you might be
here
if you don't know if you notice that's
the ipv4 network diagram
I with the ipv6 network ten years later
yes the ipv6 network does exist out
there
their own lot of notes it is currently
routing matter fact I attempted to get
us on the ipv6 network here
at this summer conference so people
would start playing with it
at this time on it's a pretty big
networks
on as we see depletion are the dresses
were expecting the address
the the ipv6 to look more like the ipv4
within the next five to eight years
get so let's review some other features
a by PV six if you
haven't seen a ipv4 verses ipv6 address
yes it's a lot longer yes you will learn
how to type
lot more accurately but if you notice
the grade on the road
not have katha nation its the clock arm
also the capability doing stateless the
autoconfiguration
a the ability to make one line
configuration your router
and support thousands assistance behind
it
minimal change minimal configuration the
ability to actually see multi cast
implemented single data stream that can
nom have multiple drops
so we can finely you know reduce the van
with going out
extension headers and mobility extension
her so we can add new features without
being forced to say
may be coming up with a ninety seven or
eight or nine
on policemen our lifetime I
ipv6 the mobility it can be done with
ipv4 and that is that
a specific node in have an address that
follows them
so things connections don't get dropped
as a
run across the network right now it's
been attempted with I can be foreigners
just landed
nothing dress spaces to deal with say
all the cell towers in the United States
very difficult problem I another really
neat thing is the jumble grammy keep
believe having pit packets that are
6k but that's that's going to make God
data transfers lot of other things very
very effective
simplify the routing because now all the
packets are on 64-bit
I alignment so we're really reducing the
processing our routers have to go
through by reducing l3
I'll check some QS the QS
is the provides a lot more granularity
we have both a traffic class and flow
class
so the application consists can actually
say hey I need this kind capability and
the routing infrastructure can say this
is all I can provide you are this 1i can
provide
and beer provide some custom routing on
in addition
privacy addressing today
if we can act al were directly connected
to the Internet we have a
global you round ball dress that address
is pretty much a sign to us
doing that connection time so if we
bring up a browser somebody tries to
connect to assist the same
capability privacy dress has the ability
to provide you a temporary
random address and in some cases
you can browse for five minutes and you
get another dress for the next grouse
makes a nice
let's talk about the address is we have
the left side in the right side not to
be confused with the political situation
um the left side I was really
allocate by Aaron currently the 18
spaces what's been allocated with a lot
more space to go
I anna has some
issued block so that 285 regionals
round-the-world
we then have the ISP's which are
assigned us last 32 as you can see from
the rare that's a lot of address space
um insights
can be allocated a slash 48 which is
equivalent to
be your slash
whatever I 16
an ipv4 so we you can
pretty much end up with enough space
small companies in
home users themselves end up with two
hundred fifty four networks at home
would have been need um
again notice everything is the and
64-bit boundary
everything to the right by the way is
locally sign
red talk about the right side on
on this segment itself are the local
host assignment
even for single ipv6 address that's
enough posts I think
I could get away with for a little while
within my house
okay arm we also have if the system
itself a sign if itself assigns an
address
we also I am have the vendor id:
associate in the on address that could
be very handy from a
assessment same point maybe are we have
an effort that he's
on so that we can see that is a self
assigned address now we have a
vendor or alignment or defender Simon by
the way
arm just like an ipv4 we have different
ways we can allocate addresses we can
hard coating that stole a pain in very
difficult to manage
we have a stateless autoconfiguration
where it creates addresses like this
and we have the state full address is
using
dhcpv6 so its its
not much difference except we get one
more option in fast
implemented networks are which is this
tale so to convict here's with blocks
look like
yes not to scale so Stanback
um v4 dress let's be serious ago sry
2060 bytes
it she changes
again everything is a online mint scales
right there
on 64 bit Lima skills argue knows a lot
of the
up components have been dropped out so
it makes it simpler
and again arm if our l2 is doing
RCR C&L for is doing
some kind of check some we really don't
need ipv6 doing checks also
one the other features it has the
ability have extension headers as
wow this gives us ability create linked
lists within the pact has some cells
and create custom configurations %uh so
in this case we have an IP be
6 header the header itself says hey
here's a ti the next packet following is
going to be a TCP header and the day
with a TCP header
call arm for the routing header
where we're doing nom source routing we
would
have it the second one the third one
might be
the a fragmentation I mention something
about fragmentation
unlike NV 4 were fragmentation is done
Dom one path to inflate I
v6 the fragmentation is actually
performed on the host and
on the transmission it makes a decision
based on
ICMP packets that it communicates with
an unfortunate on
time to go through a lot other fun stuff
extension headers
hear somebody extension headers yes you
see I P sec
arm authentication encryption H and He
espy's for the fragmentation rally
and yes others exist and others can be
defined
so if there's a specific need within the
industry to crate a
specific type from header it's available
K so now we know the basics so we know
that
the for is running out we have these
problems is figure out how to get
ourselves configure
well the first thing is let's make sure
devices
whether it's your home or your business
or
as large as you want to go and we have
determined that our posts around our
skin support ipv6 wanna show you some
some systems
will check to see if ipv6 is already
enabled on the system's
very simple process and we discuss how
to connect to the ipv4
excuse me the ipv6 internet through
three different methods
gay so does anybody haven't operating
system its on that list
okay wait a second of a second page okay
um on by default so how many of you are
now running ipv6
a lot more aren't you kinda scary isn't
it
they forgot to tell us that name know
the BlackBerry does not run ipv6 are
capable of doing
networking okay
let's go to the next component so well
we want to find out their devices will
are running ipv6 well here's three tests
real simple a.m. type in any there's
three commands will come back with a
result
which describe the results %uh those
with XP XP has it
pickens you can simply type ipv6
installing on storm system
and by the way that can be used by bad
guys pretty easily to install v6 without
you knowing it
its homicide no over and talk about that
in a minute
opens a by the way slides a I have an
email address the email me and I'll drop
you the slides in PDF format
with all those crazy pictures and yes so
the next compile we've got to deal with
is infrastructure
the currently Internet Service Providers
come in four different flavors
we have the ipv4 only weird sure gonna
have to use a transition or a tunnel
technology we go into the details that
meant
we also have ipv4 were
ISP that they put the transition
mechanism
on your local network bill dole
literally give you a router
that has the transition mechanism
pre-configured you drop in on your
network
your internal network is completely v6
they handle all the back end we then
have
very few vendors that support v4 and v6
and in just two countries we have
b6 only environments by the way this is
a
a no not tearing down any company but
all the major carriers and cable
companies have projects
upgrade their infrastructure and if you
call any oven they'll say
yes we can support ipv6 but we can give
you firm date or
you know it's a future van or its owner
roadmap for not to show you kid what it
looks like
um or customers aren't asking for TSO
please go ass to make know the youth ask
them
for it and a lot of them have chosen
I not actually implement this technology
and
could cause some problems long-term so
now we've determined the ISP's here's
one set of mechanisms
mostly operating systems we
had on those two other tables support
transition mechanisms by default
we have a transition mechanism by the
name 624
that is ipv6 riding over ipv4 packets
using protocol
forty-one we have I sit out and we have
territo
and married oh yes you can put Tere Dil
on your BSD
and it's very easy to do the installing
lot of 1x installs
others at the endpoints the protocols
and and configurations nosers love
endpoints their public K
with the other mechanism where we can
use tunnels here's the real really good
companies that support
North America give you address is
and either provide support for now turn
on mobility the
Riverside Ian src make candles if you go
to each other web sites
I a lot times will give in
configurations if you're running Linux
UNIX Solaris so %uh sects
I you can configure it very very easily
if you're the website say tell you how
to do it if its Microsoft box you can
download a piece a
little piece a binary in support that
one specific address
or whole network
by the way this is the commercial
versions
free home user version and they have a
very nice anonymous
version so sick a look at some the
common for bill is again v6 is a
good environment unfortunately all the
vendors that we do business with comfort
got to tell us they turned it on
thing buddy ever run into wireless
access points turned on by default
because the vendors thought was a great
idea
individualistic in
here since seven issues that I've
identified
and over the last five years and doing
assessments testing talking to people
of first I T and security management is
unaware the risk there things like Tere
Dil
allow us to tunnel through and that
firewall
and it has its own problems
lot sums are not willing to find any
ipv6 so we can ensure tools are there
and network administration security
administrators don't know they're there
on how if you do any auditing
assessments penetration testing
K you guys do you like sarbanes-oxley or
hit their it whatever
what happens if you miss a protocol is
an assessment valid or not
have you guys been testing for ipv6 has
your auditors been testing for ipv6
hoops could be a problem than
um a lot of our walls are capable
are fully supporting ipv6
so we have to look for those
we have to have the ability to shut it
down enable it configured properly
and over the last few years we've seen a
lot of firewalls economy got there
love the vendors are telling us sir v6
compliant compatible losing lots o words
by a lot from him and third-party tested
say need a
do some research on that the IDS is an
IPS is how many versus
depend on those yes I
Lance spitzer um actually announced on
my list in 2002
that is snort didn't detect an ipv6
packet attacking
successfully attack easel a response one
in the people on the next message
said who I went back a year and I
noticed that my ideas I had to go
through packet traces
my ID s didn't detect um
ipv6 yes I too was compromised sets all
the way back to 2001
please make sure your ideas and viral
support ipv6 canción can properly
process some
on security product industry for the
last five years they've been
interviewing all the
product vendors most of them are the
same as the ISP's will get there
nobody's asking for it
demanded today we really don't have the
time we don't want another wireless
scenario
on also unpack systems up the
voter Billy specifically to the protocol
and implementation the protocol has been
increasing this year
it's doubled since last year so over the
next 2-3
years we should start seeing nom a lot
of vulnerabilities
get out there perhaps the system's
so here's the answer to your question so
can I compromises system well
if farm we have a lab system
and we have our target across the
internet and
we attempt to do it on before we have
good firewalls
right with IDS is attacked those things
unfortunately most environments by
default do not in
stole the v6 firewall
that's the number-one Vollmer Billy
we've detected is people
implement fire walls and v6 isn't on on
their hosts
on their systems fact we're just talking
with a group that I came up with a bit
their systems for naval
um so if we if you can see that we did a
pain
and it dropped we do trace rail it
dropped
if take a look at the trace route we
were able to get all the way into the
system then we ran en masse can
put a 113 35
seem unaware of racism that would be mmm
mmm do wanna notice remember earlier I
mentioned the
um hexadecimal decimal issue
take a look at that little table there
the
and take a look at the ipv6 addresses
cf44
f7 120 d and they see a repeat itself
don't you
well if we take that v6 address and map
a TV for which is a decimal address when
we get there we
68 247 1813
hmm there might be a problem if somebody
wanted to use scanning network
range that we are ready now this is the
default
624 again most the operating systems you
guys are running
already have the v6 64
enabled so that's where the problem
really comes and
we're we're singing a lot some tools to
make it a little bit easier
unfortunately i am.
I'm writing a a penetration tester
defense
class right now do win September which
we're gonna go through these tools and
actually test them
for the students and everything this is
just a very short Tulisa you can start
doing something today
and IP lookup web-based at least you can
check to see v4 v6
the best thing here is the capability of
looking at it viv
the six address and determining it does
it say that this machines and Apple
is it pre-configured 2624 it does all
that calculation for you very quickly
and also allows you to test ICMP v6
pings some more tools
another tool is a 6-2 446 gateways
bring up your browser fired up and from
a v4 internet you can see the sixes
our website from v6 internet you can see
v4 address so we can test your
test your servers and things like that
to see if those are open
um the and maps fidora's wonderful tool
I very limited so if you have
expectations you're going to do
something with this
it's not gonna work well remember that
slash 64 dress
if you were to start this tool starting
to scan it would take care belt
five thousand years for the current
technology scan the whole range so
this tool only really provides one
scanning one address it I'm
and only provides lists pains and full
connect scans
so I can be a real problem also you
can't do a v4
and a v6 can at the same time therefore
you're gonna have to think about that
when we're scanning
arm again you don't know with the
Rangers are some additional techniques
of learn to
to find those and over the next few
months you can if I'll be announcing use
the different techniques
across different a conferences
a great soul once you have v6 a new
networking you want to play
I this tool kit helps you exploit
misconfigured network devices that are
currently running the six everything
from Wow redirect your all your network
traffic to me
scanner handy a smurf tolls
I remember we talked about the too big
to fragmentation hey
router I'm all my package should be real
small
kinda problematic %uh so this is another
really good settles
de tema peabody interest in a demo many
real-life examples
here okay so
I have this little thing that maybe have
fits in my hand
I went to this website ipv6 done what is
mine v6 dot com in case they might want
to write that down player on to their
little
tiny devices they may have in their
hands are other things
it came back with an ipv6 address and we
said
haha was connected to our wireless lan:
he said from this interesting this
little portable device has this
I'm wonder what's going on sweet and
took a look
and we found out that this 624 was
enabled and
routing already meeting even know this
came to us from the store by default
like this
we also had the icy tapped the automatic
timing pseudo I don't have the second
sly words is
Tunnel adapter automatic time pseudo
there's another
addresses provided there so we
unplugged it we found this information
so we restore the family said F must be
a mistake turn off the wifi
guess what we end up with another dress
win that the default gateway
on the handset so saddened 2002
is a 624 we also found the
I sit ap having the EFI eighty which
many had to row ball dresses out to the
Internet
had exactly the same gateway Sui Sui try
the browser and
lo and behold we were able to axis a
v6 network so that could be real problem
so then we said mean what we do with the
address is now we can resolve it is the
quality record just like we did before
we took the
before dresses we may have to do the air
v6 addresses we mapped in the four
we ended up with two ranges ipv4 dresses
for a provider that was pretty amazing
and it had the same gateway
on by the way the 19 288 9 9.1 is a
default gateway on within b6 for one the
transition mechanisms
so he said he quit race route to it look
we can trace route to this phone by the
way this was two years ago
I had to do my due diligence make sure
that
people were hurt and inform them that
they had problems in a said thank you
very much
and well what can I say
your questions
in the case a love he and the case is
this particular found you see the FFF p
that's actually a self assigned address
no no that's not a want the end
yes with this transition mechanism the
eyes he was actually provide for 64 to
create a global address my local system
was crazy the other 64
K so we said
whom we can trace route to it what else
can we do it reports canewell
two-and-a-half years ago 1/2 years ago
in three months ago
we could import scanned the four tall
and we had
very handy ports open again we on with
the operating system s
mazing the enough after I provide this
presentation back to the provider
on two weeks ago and things have changed
they um change the default gateway
they disabled the DNS what a record so I
can browse on my
in the device come to drag
and all the sudden I'm getting IP four
showing off field reports
and tried and map and hear some the
problems we found
some this was a device we and week and
mapped it
on a SUN the data transmission failures
on the device itself we were unable to
transmit
and a battery life was amazing how the
battery life we kept on plugging in NN
it ran out power with about two hours
tackle and got really hot we had to
reset it
so the reconfigured itself so it cool
down enough and got date again
this might be a problem NK
insert bad stuff here you guys are very
creative
mmm yeah okay so
which operating system we were running
yes
noble five miles 6 and by the way we've
tested other operating systems we can
form the other operating system vendors
and
I again I'm trying practice do the right
thing and now I'm
not expose but there's others that have
it so well which phones so we know
this is only a smallest have some the
fans we found no we
blackberry curve doesn't do it and the
the
serb psychic although would have been
fun K
which provider anybody know for other
providers to
okay so to end it
it's been a pleasure %uh get hold me if
you have any questions
thanks
K