about
my area code you find out a check
Apple's dot com slash 3 to one for those
who don't know the story
I'm the fellow who want to public
service mission hearing when they split
407 in Central Florida
explain to them Cape Canaveral the
countdown couple world should get three
to 1 and then presented with production
the North American Amanda ministration
showing it was available they love the
idea and I think you're
I ask for a they approved it so must be
my area code right but I share so let's
all go back in fines
a message that that I did
simes my regular signature tag to Gugu
Gugu Gugu
UGG UGG
I actually have that as a sound on my
trio phone us %ah
yes my evil scum file is where I receive
fishing male
which I forward on to their respective
companies
are usually to eBay Pay Pal and my bank
fishing now from other banks to worry
about but from my bank
I want my bank protected so I for them
explaining that should the bar you know
first I cut out the header information
that doesn't always go with
before you catchment a pace that in but
tell you what I am let me find one that
I've sent
mmm
shouldn't take too long
your bank account for forward yes do
so high there Martin yes well
you do but attach is a fitting as I
recently received
are you notice that my signature is
indented the five spaces
then I in than five bass and put the the
closing
parentheses as a Cheshire smile then
you know Richard Cheshire comma hacker
never I'm coming from
but then I give me address the Cheshire
Cat com slash perspective dot HTML
that's why is my introduction which
asked the question
just who is this guy they have a clue
remember no one's clothes you give them
clues
so then I go
equal sign equal sign be begin included
text
and I include the header of the messages
I copied it out
and then another clue for them and if
included text
and this is how I will include something
that
since it's only a textual email I have
to give them clues as to what
is the part I'm cutting out and
something to you and then below that is
the actual for reading via yahoo mail
the message I got verify your account
information blah blah blah
and of course we put the cursor on the
link the verifier online banking access
we can see well if we go to view
status bar and then hover over
we can see the bottom that's going to
angel PAF .jp slash uploads less blah
blah blah slash bankamerica complex
bankamerica
so euro is put in there but as a
directory name and
there are those cool you know just see
almost got back american they're a good
look at the click
and no I'm not going to click it even
now
because you don't Kurdish people
so
back to the topic that will go
even further but other point I'm making
is that people don't understand
a message comes on paper had an
origination
were some one side the message now why
am i harping on
their as I said before a ham radio
operator
when I work ham radios in homestead
florida
after hurricane andrew hasn't got much
better since then I can tell you
working since then we found we said up
into the EEOC
emergency operation center this problem
on
paper and hang them into the pit now the
pit
other Emergency Operations Center is
where all the yourselves are arco
located there are deaths
semi-circle around the podium reamers
manager
usually stance and book
the essa the emergency service functions
um yes
one is transportation reopen those roads
yourself to is communications and hang
out
I'll yourself three there's there's
police there's fire
there's mass feeding mask here some
only got about USF-sixteen for his
yourself 17
offer animal care they found out that
you know all these horses and dogs and
our cats running loose they had with
that too so they have their own
yes EPP your service function we will
send a message
into the EEOC you get handed off into
the pit
and had to say I would patrol Highway
Patrol that have good
down their chain of command verify the
information
get that back up and then they would
dispatch assistance
they didn't understand the concept a
message
had someone who sent it and usually
through the hymns we will verify was
sent by that person
you asking for signature because that's
how our messages are
handle we have the tradition message
traffic gambling love our guys for him
produce some work for what Telegraph
Company
yeah we need the procedures you'll find
after an emergency him a particular
credit for
for doing a lot of things with
communications it's because we know what
we're doing
we train ourselves on it we are a while
by the federal government
to play with radios on our own specific
radio frequencies
and weather is an emergency we're happy
to help out
return for allowing us to play with
those radios
frequencies because radios can cross
national borders
it has been decided that national
governments must
license transmitters now there are some
governments don't what
people as many things across national
borders but
for places like the US where it's a
while this is simply regulated
loosely regulated and in the hand
community self-regulated
um and we do our part we help out a lot
%uh what the radio arch came from ham
radio
people who play stuff I'd lose a the
reason I got my cam license
is difficult packet radio data
communications
over ham radio when somebody for said
about
bacteria what that was that
communication overhead
watch data como that I i cant play with
wears those Morse code tapes after
twenty years of listening to short wave
radio
BBC World Service retook international
organic
I finally broke down learned Morse code
got my ham turkey
and six months later they do we have the
most requirement for the
that's okay limit that more by computed
the game
now I was limited because didn't have go
to 15 acres
above the VHF range that meant I could
only play with things like all space
satellites
yeah right restricted no problem
I for ten years later by the breakdown
and of my general
but a I saw the coverage is a plywood
but I do play HF once you're fine lucky
twice your not the 12 years on him but
you feel they when are you
goes up picked up three do's so sup in a
prepared field
background and for 24-hour period we
tried
stations if I'm not lucky there's a
hurricane or something
have got a red cross shelter and radios
and
you know use HF VHF whatever's available
get the word out
my adventures are on the Internet for
working Andrew
and we can time
but the concept get the message through
and that it does come from somebody who
signed off in that message
is real concept that people needs a the
deal with
I'm other any questions
you yes
well first of with ham radio
if you're going to send a message via
ham radio via ham operator
you are gonna put something on paper he
handed off to him because
in our tradition we simply copy what
you've put down
now all sides shelter say
with the 50 cops and you know will wait
out the message
and we will sign it with the signature
up the shelter manager
up but he gave us instructions and the
message
so we can put down a singer that he said
so
and that message signature means he said
so it was a message into
across headquarters by the EEOC you know
couple hours later on the cot up
interesting thing too is
usually when you put in a request for
supplies some kind the ready room
never hears back but step shows up hours
later
you know ever since the announcement
that they got the message or anything
else
but stop those job eventually just
something that happened to notice you
other yes
huh
yes
from Toronto I don't think would provide
from
the US
well the trick with telegrams the
question being
that you know a joint committees
all telegrams of the webpage a examples
and at the local office they may have
more information about the origination
up because you need to be able to trace
back telegram if need be
but use what goes to the customer isn't
doesn't have all the information just
enough people look up in the book
introspective last realization came from
yes oh that if there's a stroke could
trace it back I'm trying to repeat for
the
ready audience ur a thing there is that
in the bad old days the Telegraph you
didn't have a whole other room
for a long white have message headers in
the Internet age
just another wine with another host
routing that
a message passed through an Evo your
complete
Brokeback but you just have affected
last releases you supposed to keep
records
%uh the previous realization the
conference a good race back that way
very labor intensive process trees back
a message like that and in the Internet
age is just
I'm a sitter in fact on packet radio
messages by the way I should at that
packet radio
we still to this day have computer
bulletin board systems
call packable court systems you can't
send
email from you ever to review our reader
via computers
over the radio you can
done for board %uh
the air raid its a bit rate
a the use arbitrators 1200 baud
and other are ninety border
winks between network nodes
and this may seem slow by today's
standards
but you're fine that we have you think
slow is better than that stop
where at least getting the message
through and I for my mother
never worry about me during a hurricane
I'll be in a safe warm
Red Cross shelter working much traffic
yes
my thoughts on text messaging being
would that be descended from telegrams
a text messaging being direct User to
User Communications
does not need formal trace backs and
there was mention that I use you pock
Upoc dot com
which really stood for universal point
of contact with no just initials lost in
the mists of time
and user 2600 Jimmy
Cheshire 2600 you park anyone wants to
UK with me that way
a good
the text messaging
I found by the way in hurricane
situations I was in Port Charlotte
following Hurricane Charley and I found
that while voice calls could not go out
over the cell towers SMS messages
written as a service messages
text messages we're getting through so
what was banned with
limited to only 160 characters but it's
amazing how much impact that you need
you
a course we had a radio as we can
informal massive traffic
that way as well but for someone who's
traffic disaster area F revenge
prior text messaging %uh there's a time
to chance it may still work
okay you have some extra time
and arm appear a topic for a talk that
I'll
used time for you well
um if you'll recall what's the Cheshire
catalyst dot com
flash Talk
the HTML two years ago I was here
with the topic flash sucks for
advertisers
well I'm afraid you I'm still harping on
it
two years coke rewards
dot com
group I must miss bell my
cope review war
mmm
I'll okay with us recovering the F with
that when they're
so you don't have flash
now I've got a backpack
are these people um I've gotten
nifty stereo headphones move coca-cola
thing you know
windup advance I love these things
got about 150 points and other really
handy
I love them but I have to go to library
in order order anything
you see it I can even after my codes
on the screen of course why they let me
send SMS text messages I have a
very large text misting package on my my
mobile phone I would use the term mobile
phone by the way not cell phone
a sailor is the technology in use
they are mobile phones and another of my
pet peeves is when people say it eight
hundred-number
no toll-free number please get into the
habit people
because there's eight hundred it'd H
877 866 855 and the others are on their
way
so they are toll-free numbers
catcher friends at its you can always
member better in front for somebody else
so this is my
pet peeve arm you know you're spending
so much money
trying to get people people's attention
to your website
arm let me show you my web sites ATT
31 dot com I've been great for the bell
solvability
for all my phone number well you see I
share my area code
but I I said the best phone number for
myself
if you really wanna reach
my cell phone I really shouldn't pull
out like this but I will to reach my
cell phone you dial 3
to one liftoff thank you
now I got that number back in the days
before number portability and I ran down
to the kiosk assumes I for the mighty
ricans gonna be put into just as I said
hi 1543 8633 please
she called Melbourne office and they
said now I'm sorry sir
the boys in Melbourne tell me that that
number is in the middle of a hundred
group
on a corporate rate totally unavailable
no
okay went home
well above that W dot com about company
I'll mark Phelan's president
to bed I don't have his email address on
the ground here some more of the press
room
new or press release that's interesting
%ah
the email address Ave publicity flack
first name underscore last name apt
come close to
mark underscore feet or after mister
fiedler blah blah blah my record blah
blah blah may I please have them as a
whoever first nineteen it on my phone
number will be free to one with of saint
we can i watch 6:30
p.m. on a Friday no way I can possibly
have miss ryan told
monday probably Tuesday Sunday afternoon
you have new mail truly committed one
I've been very good for those other body
ever since
both some ability have NASCAR their
sponsor Joe Nemechek a number 42
arm mass car for both our body our comp
are when they switch is singular
they didn't get singular racing I would
do that here until
after the Daytona 500 and then bought
single raising dot com
not been running a fan website ever
since so here we got some graphics
showing
those going from a possibility to
singular to know the future
and every week oh yeah and dog you got a
free coke 0 because they want to be Coke
Zero
612 the up according to my drivers
and every week ago up and I you know add
to
the statistics the love starting
position the finish position the cup
points if they've
got this week the next race will be the
Allstate 400 at the Brickyard
which Carly page not found you click
there because they haven't posted the
entry list yet
but these are all derived our web
addresses
and it will be at the data underscore
entry was done if you know what they put
up
now i cant always get online
to update are my website when I want you
so
there are some little dots down here and
the docs will go to entry list
qualification worst lineup are
the unofficial results and then the
official results of last week
Sophie go to the unofficial results of
the last one
it'll come up and give the official
results for the last race which is life
like dot com 400
arm now this is the same
as clicking on buy flocked dot com 400
right now
but your most this was still the
unofficial race results
because I haven't updated usually with
all the following race
known to put up the unofficial results I
go back and delete those letters
UN for unofficial becomes the web
address for the official results
so you know I just do this when I can
and furthermore all I have to do
but see view page source
and come on down here always
what you'll find is all future races
remarked out this means
that on my Treo 650 cell phone I can use
the FTP application the File Transfer
Protocol application have downloaded
i cant download my webpage edited
on the phone and put it back up on the
web usually from my local bar where much
in the race
I love getting
the results up on my website before Jay
C dot com
sent me the text message with results
and
its is just an ego thing with neon
amenable to that doesn't really mean
anything
I doubt it was really watching but is a
fun thing to do
abut you'll notice
no flash got some graphics on here
I i've links to their stuff I swipe
their graphics
because people who interested in my
website
would be interested in the special deals
oh and I use to %uh be a Palm Pilot
salesman so %uh
I've got special deals on time how to
connect to the internet and
AT&T as well Jeff Burton is driving for
are AT&T and
one thing I do I don't think anybody
else does is I was the associate
sponsors on the car
because if you're in ask our sponsorship
is everything
are with me ask our and actually I'm not
interested in ask our
my interest is in advertising and boy if
you wanna watch ever has a connection
go to a NASCAR race so
being simply a fan website this is what
I do
now I think I've got the
ATT rate did you want to come slash
I'll 1x doc HTML
something on them I guess not I am
once in a while are 12 11 X
a when the race is in
Loudon New Hampshire which is near where
all 1x are tools are
are the car gets paid up with like
colors
in the car at the top will be changed
out
to the likes callers when pilots sec
races
in Texas a change out a picture of the
probe was a car
I keep up with it three years after I
started as a cover letter from age
from our I love wasn't Cingular
saying I was cybersquatting now
oh and there's infringe your trademark I
wanna buy US BDO to go the US Patent and
Trademark Office
website and I'm turned out that
I put in similar racing no such
trademark
the 18 forms of single they had in their
none of them have racing
as a protected from the word mark
trademark I replied what trademark
never heard a word from them again
I'm let's see
all this when I'm proud of you'll notice
you're a graphic
showing I love the the be post other car
with the various our stickers for
snap-on
for GM card and uses the little fingers
as I click on these
like go safer Fig Newtons click on that
it takes me to
the the nabisco paid with the written
that says get flash forget God
well it's not my fault that's you know
on their head
but I even coca-cola gonna call racing
family
take my cooker or Starcom you know what
guys
I'm trying to help you constantly people
it's your fault are sherwin-williams
but this is all the HTML this is a use
map
which just says take anything in these
coordinates
and when you click it sunglasses web
page we need Flash four
appear I kinda have
this one as a little easter egg Jeff
Burton signature on the car
they also yes Jeff Burton dot com but
even he says
you high speed internet connection and
download flash year guys come on
its unnecessary well let me take you to
another website I'm very proud of
museums of Brevard
dot well I'm gonna put in dot com is
really got bored
but of course I bought dot com as well
and fix it is at work that's just how it
should be done
knows I got way to the top the ticket to
the various museums
all the list below so if I click on the
circle Commission
outcomes Commission your list I've got
the graphics laid out with
text on the left and graphics on the
right
the next one is graphics on the left
text on the right
and intersperses like this well the
trick is
what happens when the museum polls out
love this group
arm what we do then
what I do them since I'm the webmaster
Nazi
museums dot txt this is the file he gets
red
it's got arm have been eight-letter
short name which is used for the hyper
want to go to that museum
the name of the museum for he brought
into the newseum the name
I love the Jay pag the within the height
of the Jay pag
the alt text I should put under the Jay
pag
and then the text that to go into the
record and I does run the program to
regenerate the page
it don't need Flash for the stuff
I also have a I love
topped out HTML for the stuff at the top
it generates the list
and then generates thruster the page and
at the bottom I have links
to bottomed out HTML which August
well together because a the Museum
Association get funding for the river
Cultural Alliance
and from the Space Coast officer tourism
my good friend Bonnie came bunny King
hates my guts
funny King the head to the Brevard
County Tourist Bureau
once my phone number really bad
you
that's okay there's no reason to bother
her but it is on the website
at museums are provided at work sorry I
bid for the social engineering battle
you wilbert you and perhaps
but I had fun coming up with this in the
concept evolved in the graphics and the
text
the people like it the harbor was for
people with punter monday I think about
the party room showed what I can do that
visit
the difficult how's it 00 K was it an
extra field there with them
do columns been to and putting them as
they wanted
so what stop think about it you can
forgive her how to get things done
well thats have gratitude anyone I'm
but the message to the advertisers is
what's the problem with something up in
an alternate non flash site but you're
going for the flash okay
so you get the bill more because its
costs more to create the flash
you get the bill more because you need
have your hardwood created
you even have your harbor just short to
the CEO
yellow replace his whole computer system
you can show on
what do sewing up well without depending
on
you know 12 they're gonna have with all
the high end graphics and you know but
the thing is that they get the
to poles and other buildings you know
what you can bill for a text-based
site as well and for a just plain
Jaipur graphics site we have that little
you know no flash click here and not
piss people off
how many folks are still out there with
web TV they hid download flash
Atwell move summer still out there I and
the
vote
the thing is it's not that hard it can
be done
we're just not doing it and
it's bothersome you
well I I've about through with my
comments and your questions
burger will thank you very much oh you
wanna make some other comments
I have brought some I love the books
with me
I love
Louis book of course their secrets there
in the manual
is available it in all HTML I have it on
CD rom
or i flash drive with moving on back
and other CDs are fifteen dollars the
flash drive for twenty
and you know I really couldn't afford
comes the conference
for the past year I had a job ahead word
neckties
and I don't have a job anymore
but over-the-air been collecting a bunch
neckties on e-bay
follow up with telephones on them years
most interesting one
bill says the Mogo barbell logo is
upside down
all these ties are now on e-bay if you
as a gesture catalyst dot com
slash ties you'll find links
or in the Pacers by just put Cheshire's
tie
posting on tight on e-bay and you'll
find my ties
are I put them up last Saturday night
well I guess that means they will time
out this error no one here the
conference
well doesn't that means that you are the
purchaser overtime
you can pick it up for me on Sunday here
at the conference
what a concept I wish I don't know that
thank you
so please I hope you visit the Web site
you can come up here look at the ties as
well