um thank you guys so much for having me
here I'm really honored I love beer Khan
and I'm so glad that you invited me and
uh accidentally I've turned into the
opening talk yay so thank you
um and welcome
let me just uh go to uh to my slides
here
um first of all I was wondering I'm not
sure if I can see all your your chat or
whatever
um but maybe for just for you if you
could just make an estimate of what you
think a glass of water like this would
approximately weigh so if you know what
what I'm getting at here because you've
already seen the title of the talk uh
please don't spoil it for everyone else
but if you've no idea what I'm talking
about please just in your head or maybe
in the chat
um make an estimate of what you think a
glass of water like this would
approximately weigh and what I'm getting
at is
um it's going to be explained later in
the talk but for now just keep that in
mind
and uh I'm interested to think to see if
you've knew if you know the answer or
not
a little bit about me I'm actually not
um like most people in in this field uh
not really schooled in interest
information security I'm actually a
criminologist I've studied criminology I
have a master's degree uh at the
Amsterdam University
or a uh over a decade ago so you know
certain generation and I'm a seesaw for
the Dutch Authority for consumers and
markets which is a regulatory Authority
in the Netherlands we regulate consumers
and markets so we make sure there's no
illegal cartels we make sure that
consumers rights have are properly
protected and I'm their CSO so I'm more
uh you know focused on the security of
our own organization and of course of uh
civil um you know all the information of
the the government that we have
I love infosec I've been working in this
industry for over 10 years in different
uh different jobs different
organizations and through these years
I've actually learned quite a few things
that I think might be valuable for
others and that you'd like to hear and
maybe there's some lessons there that
you can take from that so that's why
I've sent in the stock
and the first story I'm going to talk to
you about is quite a while ago it was
actually my first job I used to work for
the Dutch Police Department in Amsterdam
I I was working for the serious crime
unit and the financial crime unit as an
internet specialist
and as an internet specialist my job was
mainly Oceans open source intelligence
but also uh looking through log files
all sorts of information that might lead
to an arrest or you know solving crime
and
um one of the first uh cases I was on I
went to this team and I noticed that
they were Googling things a lot which is
you know kind of a good thing but if you
look at
um the the way they were Googling you
could quite tell from the referrer what
they their these referrals were quite
specific and I'll give you an example in
a minute
so I talked to the team and I told them
you know you might not want to search
Google for these specific terms because
the website owners that you end up
visiting can see these things and they
can also see the IP address and those IP
addresses from the computers that they
were using they would just end up when
you looked at a domain or the IP
registration they would just end up
looking at the new traffic Police
Department
which we were Amsterdam but hey Tomatoes
Tomatoes it's pretty clear it's a police
a computer so you might not want to do
that so I talked to him about it so you
know if there's anything you want to
Google in this case I'm your internet
specialist feel free to come by and let
me know and I'll have a look
and they in this case they found they
did a house search and they found a key
that had a label on it and the label had
an address on it
um I don't know it's like a Village
Street six or something and uh of course
you know even though I talked to them I
told them not to Google it they actually
did
and and what they found was a website
from a real estate agent that was
um letting a storage unit next door so
they Googled Village Street six but that
wasn't available what was available was
the storage unit for uh the same street
but number four for example so the one
right next to it
and this website that was owned by this
real estate agent
of course could see the referrer
so when you are a webmaster you can you
look at the statistics of your website
and you want to find out how people
ended up on your website and you can see
that someone looked for Vint Street
number six and you know that you led
this to a very very well-known criminal
because of course that's not something
you tend to forget so you know this is a
criminal that hires this storage unit
and you know it's number six so you when
you look at the statistics of your
website and you see someone is Googling
specifically for the number six that's
interesting to you and you want you
might want to zoom into that and which
is obviously what he did and we were as
a police department we were thinking
there might be weapons in the storage
unit
uh and we had good indications of that
because people were talking about it on
the phone this is again way back it's 10
years ago
um these days I mean scribbles are not
always as intelligent but uh I'm not
sure they still talk over the phone as
clearly about weapons as they did in
those days
but they we had a good indication that
there were going to be weapons in the
storage unit that we found
um but however by the time we got there
the storage unit was completely empty
like they even almost sweeped the floor
for us it was there was nothing there
uh and we later found out that as I
predicted the webmaster had seen that we
had been looking at the Village Street
number six well that was not available
that hadn't been available for over a
year and he knew it was uh uh this led
to a criminal
so he actually he just warned him he
said the police department's gonna go
look for your storage unit I've seen it
on my website they're looking for you
don't uh get everything out as soon as
you can which he did
so what my point is telling you the
story is that behavior is quite a hard
thing to tackle and I think if you've
been working in for information security
for a while you've noticed this uh just
as much as I have that you can tell
people not to do something
think about clicking links and fishing
emails right if you know me excuse me
then you know how I feel about uh
phishing emails and fake fishing emails
but uh you know just telling people not
to do something in in security yeah good
luck with that I mean just assume
they're not going to listen to you
because most likely they won't
um
another another story I'd like to share
with you is uh is this one I I've been
working for a certain Organization for a
while and um we suffered a WhatsApp
phishing attack now to to make things
clear what's up in in the organization I
was working for was not used for uh work
reasons it was just there for social
reasons and I had warned uh that this
kind of thing could have happened before
again this is a behavior thing people
tend to not listen to you when you tell
them not to use it for work purposes uh
and they might just
do that and what happened was a couple
of people from my organization were
targeted
through um email telling them I am the
the board member of your organization
please give me your WhatsApp phone
number and once they did they got either
a link uh uh no they didn't get a link
they got a text message for the
verification code of the WhatsApp they
used so their their account could have
been taken over or they were told to go
get a iTunes gift card from a shop
so this was obviously not an advanced
persistent threat or apt this is just
some petty criminals but hey that's
sometimes that's all it takes and a few
of our our people had fallen for this so
I was called to the the leaders of the
organization and they told me you're our
CSO or your security person uh please
give us advice what should we do and I
said well if we don't use it for any
work purposes and it's just for social
reasons then why do we not just block
and ban WhatsApp all together from our
work phones we don't actually need it
it's it's an unnecessary risk to our
organization people can use the phone if
they want to talk to each other we can
find a more secure app if they want to
talk about work stuff but please please
please if you want to prevent this kind
of issue
um just block and banned WhatsApp from
our phones technically we can do this we
have work phones that are managed so
please do this and what they said was a
weekend I'm sorry Fleur we cannot do
this it's too useful we use it all the
time as as a board of this organization
we needed in order to tell each other
that we're waiting downstairs for lunch
or we need it for all sorts of uh well
reasons other than work
it's too useful I'm sorry we cannot
block it and I said well in that case
why not use signal or something else
yeah well other people don't use it so
it's not useful we need Whatsapp because
that's the most used app
and I struggled with this for a while
when I went home I was like well you
know this is gonna happen again and next
time it's going to be worse because this
weird these were a couple of petty
criminals you know wanting to get us to
get some iTunes gift cards but next time
it's going to be an apt and then we're
pretty much screwed
um
and and I I struggled with it for a
while and then I thought you know what
this is actually not my responsibility
it really isn't I'm just an advisor and
I've told them this is not very a smart
thing to do I've given them all the
information they needed to make a
intelligence decision and they've
decided to go the other way and that's
fine I mean I'm not the leader of this
organization I don't have that kind of
responsibility so why am I why is this
bothering me so much uh if things go
wrong all I have to say is I've told you
this
you didn't want to listen
you're responsible
um and and I think this is something I'm
gonna get back to this in a little bit
that we might want to you know get back
to a little more often in our field
because we care We Care a whole a whole
lot and that's a good thing but it also
messes us up sometimes
um and then there's there's another
story that that I wanted to share with
you and that's we were going to buy uh
when uh some uh I specifically I'm not
telling you which organization I worked
for when this happened because I don't
first of all it doesn't matter and
second of all I don't want to get into
trouble uh but I was working for one of
the organizations I've worked for in the
past
and we were going to get a security
incident and event management system has
seen so yeah there's different ways of
pronouncing that word security incident
and event management system right uh I'm
not going to say the old time like that
I just called to see
so we were gonna We you needed this
system for obvious reasons and we were
we went to a vendor that we had
purchased stuff from in the past and we
said well we need this please build it
for us and we have quite specific uh
requirements so it can be like uh
off-the-shelf solution it had to have
some some specific uh use cases in it
and pretty soon uh it became clear to me
that they could not provide but we need
it I asked for a Splunk instance because
I wanted to be able to look into the
scene myself I wanted
to have certain rights in the in Splunk
so I could make uh you know slight
changes in the use cases changed
thresholds if I felt it was necessary
that kind of thing they could not
provide me with that it seemed that they
were struggling with all sorts of to me
quite simple uh questions and a lot of
it was pushback we can't do this we
don't we don't want to do it or it's
going to cost you more money even though
we had a fixed price so it was we were
struggling and I pretty early on said I
think we should move on I think we
should change vendors or go looks for
for a solution somewhere else because
they can't provide
but the CIO and the IT manager that were
also involved with this project they
told me no we we've already invested so
much money into this
um you just gotta have to have some
faith and give them some a little bit
more time and I said I'm sorry I just
can't see it they don't have the
knowledge that is needed to do this
um
and then after I think it was three
years two or three years that's how long
it took to make this scene and they came
to us they gave us the final demo and I
will for the for the rest of my life
remember the first very first line that
this uh blesses our salesperson or demo
person said at this final demo and he
said and I quote whatever expectations
you had
cut them in half
so I was like okay well this is not good
because my expectations were already
quite low and it turned out I was right
and so was he
um because for we said initially we want
15 use cases I think that's quite you
know uh small for for a scene but we
said we might want to build on that but
we want at least 15 use cases and we
specified them
and we got five
and three worked and worked is a term I
will use Loosely here it was not
actually measuring what I had
anticipated or expected that use case to
measure and it was actually not very
useful either as a use case for a scene
so what I've learned from this is that
sometimes there's just nothing you can
do I mean we as a security people we
tend to break our our brains over things
we we keep on
trying to to get certain things
implemented and there's we can see
what's going wrong and you can scream it
from the top of your lungs and you can
tell everyone and do whatever you want
and sometimes there's just nothing you
can do and it will go wrong because
there are just people that will not
listen or just let it go wrong and how
do you deal with that it's something
that we're gonna talk about because
insecurity as you probably already know
a lot of the things we we run into is
that we cost a lot of money but the
results of what that money has been
spent on are clear are almost invisible
so the the funny thing is if you spend a
lot of money on security actually
nothing happens
but that's the point we want nothing to
happen we want everything to go uh
smoothly and it's going smoothly because
you've spent money on it but if you
don't spend money on it then things
might go wrong but they might not go
wrong for a very long time it might take
a while before it goes wrong but
eventually it will
um and we as security people we know
this but of course the management and
and uh people around us might feel
differently they might say well you know
you want me to spend all this money on a
scene but we don't have a SIM now and
we're fine
yeah that's because you can see what's
happening on your network because you
don't have a team
um
so that's one of the travels that that
I've I've noticed that we we all tend to
run into and like I said earlier we all
care we care a lot we care about your
security so of course I've used this
line because it's kind of like a thing
we hear a lot from sales people your
security is important to us uh so that's
that's why I kind of tell my cheek use
it here but for US security people the
security of the organization we work for
is actually important we really care and
sometimes I think we care too much
um sometimes we should just take a step
back and go
hey it's your company it's your
organization it's your decision
um
um of course you can only do this if you
don't have any contractual uh courses
that say you're responsible for anything
my advice would also be never to sign
such a contract unless you also get a
budget and mandate because there is no
such thing as responsibility without
budget or mandate in my eyes but hey
that's a whole different topic
um but that's my thing my point here is
we care we care a lot and that's good
but it's sometimes we care too much
and another issue that we tend to run
into is that people I already laughing
people tend to find that we are doom
thinkers we are people that always
assume the worst and I'm laughing
because that's what you pay us for
you pay us to assume the worst right it
would be bad in security to always
assume the most positive outcome of
things this is inherent to a a job that
we do that's about risk and risk is is
you know inherently something that's not
assuming the most positive outcome it's
actually assessing the most likely
outcome
um you know I Impact versus probability
and uh you know that means there is no
such thing as a positive risk in
security right so um so we tend to be to
be made out as Doom thinkers in our
organization where we yell fire but no
one sees the smoke uh and and that's
yeah that makes our job harder because
when people do listen to us again
nothing happens and that's the that's
actually the good thing but when they
don't and something does happen they
look at us and go why did you not worry
me
so that's uh something I'm gonna get
back to you in a bit as well
and we are always seen as blocking you
know security says no we can't do this
because security is uh blocking this
project I can go into this for ages but
of course we know this is usually
because we get involved right at the
very end of a project and they go well
look at our perfectly beautiful design
please say it's perfect from security
standpoint that we just look at it and
go my God what a dumpster fire is this
um and then we say well you're not going
to want to do it this way and they go
well we already build it so yeah there's
that stop blocking us please think from
a business standpoint which is quite
hard if you're only involved at the end
of a project
and I've also noticed that we get very
little praise again because if any if we
do our jobs well nothing happens
everything works as designed everything
works as you want it to work because we
do our jobs and and no one when
everything works as it's supposed to
feels the the need to go to your
security or even your I.T people and go
pat on the back you've done a great job
whilst when things go wrong they're
we're the first people they they knock
on the doors off and that makes our jobs
you know I think quite hard where if you
have a job where you make like a product
and the product's done and it looks all
pretty and shiny and and perfect and
everyone will go well look what a great
job you've done well when we do a great
job
nothing happens
um and another another thing and I think
this is the single most important reason
why so many intersect people get
um a burnout or depression or that kind
of thing
it's because it's very hard to
prioritize insecurity right so every
single detail is important if you miss
one little configuration mistake or one
little bug or whatever in code
that's all it takes to get your entire
organization around somewhere and I know
this is kind of cliche because of course
there's you know you put layers in your
security and you have different measures
and Technical and awareness and
everything but still sometimes there's
it's just one little detail that you've
missed that can get your entire
organization uh hacked or ransomware or
broken and we know this and that's why
it's very hard for us when things are
brought to us to make a priority a prior
priority list of what should I do first
what's the worst thing I need to tackle
right now because everything is
important and that thing that you
thought was not important might actually
end up being the downfall of your
organization to be your career dream
thinker
um
and I think that's what I find in my in
my job that's one of the hardest things
because I know when I skip something or
when I park something and go I'll go
I'll get back to that later because I
have something more important right now
and that thing becomes the thing that
that causes a lot of issues I'm gonna
have to explain to others that will go
why did you not do something about it it
was right there yes because I had this
whole entire other list of things that
was also right there
um so yeah that's I think that's one of
the reasons we get so many burnout and
depression in our field
so how do you deal with these things
well I I'm I'm expert in that sense but
I do have some tips that might be useful
to you uh um and and I'm not saying it's
it's the answer to everything and of
course that's 42 you will know this but
um
like I said earlier just when things get
too much you know it's not it's not all
your responsibility there's co-workers
there's your board there's your
management there's your CEOs it's not
all you and sometimes it might feel that
way but it really isn't and please
remind yourself sometimes that it isn't
um and what might help is to because
like I said earlier we don't get a lot
of Praise so maybe it can help to make
your work more measurable to uh document
what you do on a daily basis to write
reports about your security team or the
work you do for your security team or
show them statistics of the the
incidents that you've responded to
um the the evaluations that you've
planned or the policies that you've
changed make it more measurable because
that way people will more easily see all
the things you've done and it might help
you get some praise that you clearly
might deserve
I'm just going to say you're not super
human this is the response to the to the
part I said about prioritizing there's
only so much you can do you are one
person or you are one team
um usually security people tend to cope
with uh capacity issues just remind
yourself you're not superhuman and old
people can can actually
um
say to you when when things go wrong is
that you've done all you've that was in
your power to do
and you cannot be expected to do any
more than that
uh like I said earlier make sure you
document the things you do your whatever
effort you put into things actually
matters more than perfection in my view
at least
um when it comes to to projects uh this
is of course a very open door but um has
to be involved from the beginning
um we all we always obviously do but I
think sometimes infosec people are too
modest and they say well I'll I'll see
I'll get back to your project when
there's a design or something like that
and I think it might be better if you
notice that this is causing you trouble
um to get more involved
and I think a little bit of this is also
acceptance so you're gonna have to
accept that things just are the way they
are in infosec sometimes and there's not
very much you can do about it
uh and I would like to uh semi end my
talk with this quote from uh a person
Discord you've probably already seen a
lot of times it's from a former FBI uh I
think it's a director but I I really
love it security is always too much
until today it's not enough
now in the beginning I talked to you it
says questions but I have five minutes
left so I'm gonna I'm gonna speed
through it and if you have more
questions feel free to ask them on
Twitter or
um
you know approach me on LinkedIn
whatever you want I'm gonna show you my
Twitter handle in a little bit but uh in
the beginning of the presentation I
asked you to kind of make an estimate of
what a glass of water like this would
weigh and if it's a trick question
obviously because who this is not even a
picture I took myself
the if you know this then uh then
they're good for you but uh it's a very
old uh story about a teacher that goes
to a class and he has a glass of water
in his hands and he says how much does
this passive Waterway and obviously you
get students saying all sorts of ways
and then in the end he says well
actually the the the accurate weight of
this glass of water is not important it
doesn't matter all because if I hold
this glass of water in the air for like
five minutes or minutes it's it's you
know it doesn't matter what it waste but
if you're trying to hold on to the glass
of water for longer than five minutes
it's gonna be heavier and heavier and
heavier and if you hold it for over an
hour it's going to be almost impossible
to keep it in the air any longer because
it's going to be so heavy and that's the
same with certain things in info
security if you deal with them mentally
and it's helped me immensely all you
have to do when it gets to be too much
is to put the glass down and the weight
of it will be off your arm and it's the
same with these issues from you might be
struggling with if it gets too much and
you notice there's nothing you can do
people won't listen to you
um you can't get anything to change then
what's the point of keep keep holding on
to the glass right there's no point just
put the glass down and move on and
that's what I would like to give to you
a surviving security
uh again if you I'm sorry you're not
going to be able to answer to ask any
questions I can't really see them I
think anyway because I can't see the
chat I only see the beer Farmers chat
from Zoom so I'm sorry about that
um but if you have any questions feel
free to ask them on Twitter there's my
handle and uh you guys have a great con
have a good time don't drink too much
beer and I'd like to meet you in person
one time thank you very much you
that was awesome and you know a shout
out to you putting up with our uh
Shenanigans as we tried to make this all
work we're going to buy to you