hi everyone and thanks for attending
this talk
i'm benjamin erickson and this is a
joint work with giancarlo pellegrino and
andre
sobelfeld so web applications
are growing in complexity and they have
more interaction
bigger code base and even third-party
code that needs to be considered when
looking for vulnerabilities
and this all makes it harder to find
vulnerabilities
at the same time a few years ago google
awarded over a million dollars in
bounties just for cross-site scripting
bugs
at the same time if we look at the
number of cvs from cross-site scripting
we can see that between the years 2015
and 2019
compared to the previous five years they
have increased with almost 79 percent
this makes cross-site scripting an
important topic to study
so how can we actually find
vulnerabilities in these applications
well we can use a black box approach and
the benefit here is that we don't need
the source code of the applications that
we are analyzing
instead we dynamically interact with the
application
to figure out where the vulnerabilities
might reside
so here's an example and the first thing
we need to think about is how we
navigate a web application
so we can follow a link between two
pages we might submit a form with a
username and password
then perhaps clicking on a button to
generate a dynamic
form where we later can add a user for
example
now we need to also think about how we
traverse the application
because where we inject the user might
be different from where we then can see
where this user is reflected so we might
need to go back to the index page and
continue
crawling the application until we find
the user that we inserted
and then we can infer this interstate
dependency
between the view user page and the admin
page in this case
but of course we want a scanner to be
able to do this autonomously
to follow links to submit forms
to click on javascript events or
javascript buttons
add users and then continue crawling
until it finds these inserted values
and when it does also be able to infer
the interstate dependencies between
different parts of the application
so the main challenges we identify is
navigation
traversing and interstate dependencies
and navigation is about which
interaction methods we need to consider
so for example links form submissions
are those simple http requests or can we
model them as
forms javascript events how do we model
these
and then how do we interact with these
objects traversing
is about how we handle the complex
workflows in applications
which might include chaining different
actions so for example we might first
need to upload a picture
before we can comment on the picture and
it's in this comment section
where the vulnerability might be
and finally where should we look for our
payload once it has been injected
and as we saw in the example injecting
something in the admin page might
actually end up being reflected on some
other page
and previous works have focused on
improving
one of these methods in isolation so for
example pellegrino and i'll improve the
modeling of javascript events
while dupietal in enemy of the state
focused on traversing applications with
respect to the server-side state
and to sheena with the liger scanner was
able to use reverse engineering
to try to identify interstate
dependencies
and our key idea is to combine the
advantages of all of these methods
into one approach so
to handle navigation we treat the nodes
in the graph
as client-side states and the edges
between these nodes
are the action needed to move between
these states
so for example on the index page we
might have a simple link
that we can just follow to the login
page
but on the login page we actually submit
the whole form so we don't treat it as a
simple request which we just replay
instead we re-render the form and we add
the values and then we submit this form
enable to log into the admin page
for javascript events we model all of
the
javascript events and we execute them in
a real browser
so we actually click on these buttons or
type text
to to trigger on change events
so for traversing it's important to
ensure that
the scanner or the application is in a
good state before we add any values
so if we're now on the right here want
to inject a new user
we would first have to go back to what
we consider a save state
and this is get request in this case and
then the scanner would resubmit the
login form
click to generate element and only then
do we
insert this new value and this is to try
to ensure that the
server is in a good state before we try
to inject any values
as we re-execute the workflows if needed
for interstate dependencies it's where
the data is inserted
can differ from where it's reflected and
to detect these sources and syncs we
insert
random tokens so here on the bottom
right we want to add a user
so the username we pick here could be
some random string like
frc vw and so this is injected into the
application
and might be reflected on another page
in the application
so we continue to crawl and for every
page we look for all of these tokens
that we have inserted
and when we find one we can infer this
relationship
between the admin page and the view user
page in this case
and this is very important for when we
start fussing because
imagine that instead of adding a user we
simply update the username
in that case if we don't make sure to
check the sink
for every payload we inject on the
source it might be the case
that we only see the final payload once
we
continue crawling so what we do is for
everything we inject in the source we
also check the sink
so we want to evaluate if black widow
can handle the complexity of real
applications
and here we look at both the code
coverage so the number of lines of code
being executed on the server side
as well as the number of vulnerabilities
we can detect
and we do this for 10 different web
applications
and further we divide these into
reference applications
so these are applications running old
versions with known vulnerabilities
and more importantly that have been used
in previous papers so we can compare
with those
but we also look at six modern
applications running the latest version
so here we have latest version of
wordpress and prestashop and drupal
hotcrap etc
but we're also interested in how black
widow performs compared to other
scanners
so for each of these applications we
compare black widow
with seven other scanners so we have
arachne enemy of the state
jack scapefish we also have wget but
that is just for comparing coverage
since that is not a vulnerability
scanner
so the first result we look at is the
coverage so this is the number of lines
of code being executed on the server
side
and we compare black widow to all the
other scanners as you can see in the
bottom so with enemy of the state with
wget with sap
and we pair these up for every
application
so in the first case we have black widow
versus enemy of the state
on the web application os commerce and
so we look at the lines of code being
executed by both of these scanners
and then we see how many are uniquely
found by one of the scanners so here in
blue you can see black widow
uniquely finds about 90 percent of the
lines of code
in common they find about 10 of the
and in the case of os commerce enemy of
the state only finds a few lines of code
that black widow does not find
and then we do this for all the
applications and all the scanners
and what we can see here or the main
takeaway should be that
the blue area is much larger than the
red area showing that
we find a lot more unique lines of code
compared to the other scanners
and we also compare our coverage with
the union of all the other scanners per
application
and we see that our improvement ranges
from a 63
improvement all the way to 280 for some
applications
but we're also interested in
vulnerabilities and starting with the
reference applications
we see that most scanners are quite good
at finding reflected xss
almost all of them are able to do that
but where we really try to improve
is on the stored xss and as we can see
already in the
reference application we are able to
find way more
vulnerabilities compared to the other
scanners
and we can see that they struggle more
with this stored xss
and moving over to the modern
applications we see that we are actually
the only scanner that is able to find
any vulnerabilities in this modern
application and this is both for
reflected access and stored xss
and if we look at the total column we
see that we are also finding more of
course
but more importantly is that the other
scanners do not find any vulnerability
that we do not
find so we don't have any false
negatives in this
in this empirical study at least
but to better understand why we are
finding vulnerabilities
we do a feature attribution so we look
at
which feature in this case navigation
traversing or interstate dependencies
and really was the main reason for
finding the vulnerability
so we see six vulnerabilities here that
only black widow finds that none of the
other scanners find
were due to being better at one of these
features
and just a single feature so a concrete
example here is vanilla for example
where we just needed interstate
dependency analysis
to be able to find the vulnerability but
we see that the real power comes from
combining multiple features
so for example if we improve both the
navigation and traversing
or navigation and interstate
dependencies then we're able
to find eight vulnerabilities and an
example here is prestashop where
are we required a combination of both
navigation
and traversing and there's also one case
where we needed to combine all three of
them in order to find the vulnerability
so this was in wordpress where we needed
to combine all of them
and we have reported this and it's
already fixed in hot crap as well as
prestashop
another positive feature with black
widow
is that we have no false positives in
this empirical study
and in general a very low false positive
rate and this is because we use dynamic
verification
together with unique payload ids so
other scanners were struggling with this
in our empirical study
for example enemy of the state at some
point injects an
eval statement that tries to print a
string and then it finds this string
in the response and so it deems this to
be a vulnerability because it thinks
that the eval
print was executed so here we see the
kind of the need for dynamically
verifying
that code is actually executed
iraq can used dynamic verification but
they reuse payloads and at one point
they were able to inject
a payload into the page title and this
means that this payload would be
triggered for every page load
so it thought that it found
vulnerabilities in every input after
being able to inject the title
so in our case by combining both the
dynamic verification
and unique payloads we are able to keep
false positives to a minimum
so to conclude our key idea is to
combine navigation traversing and
interstate dependencies
in one into one approach and we see that
this improves coverage by between 63 and
compared to the union of all the other
scanners across all the applications we
tested
and we are also able to find more
vulnerabilities in the reference
applications
as well as finding modern or
vulnerabilities in modern applications
and due to our combination of dynamic
verification and unique payload ids
we also keep false positives to a
minimum
and blackwidow is also open source and
available on github so make sure to
check that out
so yeah i thank you all for attending
this talk and i'm looking forward to the
questions in the qea
thank you