hello everyone i'm eaton
from indiana university bloomington this
is the john work with
institute of information engineering
chinese academy of sciences
today i'm glad to share with you guys
our new work
we provide you a new technique to
automatically
discover the network vulnerabilities
just by
analyzing documentation
first let's look at center network with
new technologies and virgin iv
generation the general network has
profoundly changed our life
especially the 4g with a higher rate
faster speed
and greater capability allowed us to
connect our work and daily life
to just one small mobile that really
broadcast the intelligent life
the central network plays a pivotal role
in the current world
so naturally their security and privacy
become critically important and i expect
it to be there any scrutinized
but unfortunately actually
today the central network are much less
protective and thought
it often involves the rest security and
privacy risks
and most vulnerabilities are discovered
by our whole community analysis
of course recently there are some
systematic solutions
they utilize the traditional software
vulnerability discovery methodologies
such as fuzzing and more checking into
the cellular network
but they still cause a lot of manual
effort infesting
previous work manually identify the
security properties
and use them to guide the mutation of
the inject messages
this requires a human to have an
in-depth understanding about the network
design
the model checking previous research
even rely more manufactured
people need to build the model manually
and further give the security properties
manually too so considering current
situation
we want to explore a both systematic and
automatic way
that can discover the general network
vulnerability
looking to this general network
development ecosystem
we found a specific phenomenon the
central network
connects all over the world it is a
super complex system
including many different kind of devices
such as mobile
lt device space station car network and
so on
so natural there are many device
manufacturers from all over the world
so in order to achieve the central
network
all the manufacturers must follow the
same specification
which is provided by 3gpp an
organization uniting telecommunications
standard
development organizations across the
world and providing
and maintaining central technic
communication technology specifications
because of the complexity of the senior
network
now street pp has more than 3000
specifications for it
we randomly checked several of them all
of them
are pretty long including hundreds even
thousands pages we believe that such
huge specifications must include some
clues
that can guide us analyzing network
security
so in our research we made the first
step to consider one situation
when a specification describes a
sensitive operation
such as transmitting a private
information or releasing a connection
because of the huge number and
complexity of the specification
we're curious about whether the
manufacturer developers could
implement it correctly and securely
if not there may be a risk in necessary
network
in our research we focus on the nas
protocol
generally we could simplify as the
neural network architecture
as a slide shows when the mobile also
called
ue user equipment want to
get a service from the core network it
will connect to a base station and
the base station connects to a core
network the nes
protocol is a layer between the uae and
the mme
which is the surveillance network the
nes
provides several procedures for mobility
and security control when the ue using a
network
for example in order to manage ue's
mobility
there's a touch procedure it is used to
build a connection to a network from the
ui
and is a detached procedure that is used
to release the connection
and when the ue is in the idle state and
the mmb has information to center it
the s provides a paging procedure for
security control
the unless also provides several
procedures for example the
identification procedure
that is used for the mme to request a
uee's identity
considering our previously imagined
situation we defined a sentence related
to a sensitive operation in the is
specification
if the network receives a detached
request message
before the ongoing identification
procedure has been completed
the network shows a water identification
procedure
and shall progress the detached
procedure here
to avoid identification procedure could
be considered
as a risk operation so we won't know
when the victimizer and the
network is performing an identification
procedure
during this period if the network
receiver did have to request a message
from the malicious ue
who spoke the victim uus we're curious
about
whether the mme will successfully
remember to authenticate some
malicious ue or just follow the short
description to perform the risk
population
to abort the identification procedure
with the victim building
so carrying that starts with testing of
4g
simulation environment because
considering the ethics we cannot perform
experiment
in commercial network so we're testing a
simulator
but in our testing environment with the
president fund
that mme not only opportunity
identification procedure
but for the release of connection with
the victim ue
the victim ue finally got a dos attack
so from this observation in the is
we have a new idea to find central
networks
vulnerability systematically and
automatically our high-level idea
is first to detect an indicator from a
documentation
the hazard indicator which describes a
risk corporation
and then we use it to guide the test
case generation
based on indicators information we
decide
what attack messages should be sent at
what target state
finally we execute a test case in our
test environment
and identify the poc so next
i will introduce the key techniques
industry states
first the hazard indicator detection as
an example shows the hazard indicator
is a short description documentary
operation which we consider to be risky
so it also describes the
condition to trick the operation so to
find such
indicator our approach is designed to
search all the conditional sentence that
implies a risk corporation in the whole
specification
the conditional sentence is easy to
identify just by the keywords such as if
when
and extra so the challenge here comes to
how to decide whether the consequential
sentence
implies a risk operation in our work we
leverage
an nlp technique called textual
entailment
it can decide whether a hypothesis
entails a premise systematically
here for the example in the slide
through the test
entailment we can detect the
consequential sentence underlined in the
red
implies the risk operation of our
procedure notably the textual
entitlement
is a model that can understand semantics
so no matter the sentences in text
changes such as change into
a procedure shall be aborted or the
sentence uses anonymity such as using
a terminated procedure the test
transmitter model
always works so given the risk operation
on both procedure
we don't need to find its variations and
we can
easily identify those sentences in
primary risk operation
while using the nlp technique test
current element
of course we believe that except for the
risk population body procedure
there are other risk operations
specification we
also need to extract him here our idea
is based on observation
that the risk operation will always
appear together in that documentation
so we use correlation analysis
point wise mutation prevention a
standard approach in
computational linguistics to identify
them
from the seed abort procedure our
approach extended
several new risk corporation description
such as release resource deactivate
context
and progress procedure here the progress
procedure is interesting
because it is opposite to abort
procedures menus
but it does implicitly
imply them when someone progress the new
procedure
he may stop and hold procedure
next let's move to the second step for a
given general threat module like here
ue issue centered attack message to mme
to interrupt the communication between
the enemy and the victim ue
we could have a test case templating
advance
in our work to generate a test case our
approach
is to automatically extract a targeted
state
and a text message from the hazard
indicator
to the other template here we authorize
an
lp technique called the dependence
passing to analyze the syntactic
structure of the sentence
as shown in the slides in the dependency
passing the verb
takes the central control in the clause
or otherwise
either directly or indirectly modifies
the verb
for example the word network is a verbs
a received subject
the word message colored in res a
accounting green is an object of the
verb
received and the word detach
request paladin blue has a compound
relation to a word message
so from these relationships we can
identify
that the detached request message is a
text message issued by the malicious
theory
by the same way we can decide the enemy
exact attack listed after he sends out
an identity
by request message before he receives
the identified response
finally we execute the test case in our
test environment with three
popular 4g simulators automatically in
order to attribute
we modify the open source simulator to
set hooks and around the listener each
of them
um we activate the host dynamically
according to a test case
so in the test screen when the mme
enters the target state
the hook will notify the munitions ue to
issue the attack message
one challenge here is how to get enemy
to attack the state
after analyzing wave funded most
procedural states can be
entered naturally after just
rebooting the phone and for the others
although they usually happen
undetermined but they are always been
after the
attached procedure finishes such as a
paging procedure tracking error
procedure so
we leverage your hooks again when the
enemy finishes the attach procedure
we use a hook to notify the enemy or the
victim ue to start the
related procedure immediately to enter
the target stage
and finally we check the traffic lock
to monitor whether the victim ui has
been disrupted
if yes we output a test case that then
identify
identified posing
now let's look at our whole approach
in one word we identify the indicator
from a specification
and then use it to guide the test case
generation and
execute the test case to identify plc
our system is
input at a similar network documentation
and a threat model specifically a risk
corporation description
and receipt now used to extend the other
risk corporation descriptions
and a test case template that is used to
generate test case
and output is unidentified posing the
whole workflow is automatically
running our system as protocol which
includes more than
500 pages and 200 and thousands words
we found the stem vulnerabilities in
open 5g
simulator and 10 vulnerabilities in
sslt and open air interface respectively
all of them are new vulnerabilities
one may ask whether these
vulnerabilities can be exploited
in the real world since generally in
central network it is hard to monitor
the aiming state
here our answer is yes we figure out a
practical attack
exporting these vulnerabilities we don't
monitor the enemy's precise state
we estimate attack window that eminent
state may enter into
in central network the page message is a
broadcast message that every mobile can
receive covered by a space station
receiving a page message with different
parameters you
will start a different procedure
immediately so
leveraging it using the downlinks
messages paper
attacker can identify the victim
you use target procedure from the page
message and its parameters
once the attacker snips the pages it can
send a text message according to a
patient's parameter immediately to
perform a dos attack
because we cannot perform attacks on the
commercial network due to
ethics we reported them to a same median
and they did to chinese national
vulnerability databases
both of them have confirmed that the
vulnerabilities indeed exist
in major commercial careers by the way
we record
our tech demo and put him in in our
website
it's very interesting you could watch it
for listening
under our workflow were also tested in
another class
thread model and now when the victoria
connects the fake
network in this given thread model we
also find many vulnerabilities and
receive the confirmation from the mobile
manufacturers
finally let's summarize our contribution
first
we provide a new technique to discover
senior network vulnerabilities we're
extracting the indicators from the
documentation
and use them to guide your vulnerability
discovery
second we implement our approach and
fund 42 vulnerabilities in the real
world
including 10 new ones in our research we
proposed a new direction
to discover the neural network
vulnerability from
analytics documentation but it is
relatively preliminary
just scratching surveys the huge
specification
contains a lot of other clues about the
security risks
automatic discover of this monorail this
security weakness
will contribute to the great evaluation
of the sailor security
we will study them in our future work
and we
also hope more researchers come to study
this era together
that's our report thanks for your
listening