hi everybody my name is rooney fielder
i will convince you that there is more
to signatures than just unforgeability
how you can buff your signature schemes
beyond unforgeability
and what this means for post-quantum
signatures
this is joint work with cascaremas
summer dussley mark fischling and
christian yanson
so you may have heard of signatures
before
signatures have plenty of applications
you can use them to sign messages
to authenticate software updates and as
a building block for bigger protocols
such as the key exchange protocol
all in all they are a fairly important
cryptographic primitive
the security notion that signatures are
usually measured against
is called existential unforgeability
an attacker against existential
unforgibility has to output a forgery
for a fresh message
this security definition has stood the
test of time for several decades
hence the results are used for the nist
competition on post-quantum cryptography
however this definition is only
concerned with honestly generated public
keys
but what about maliciously generated
public keys
in this presentation i will tackle four
questions
can maliciously generated public keys
actually break real world protocols
how can we formalize the notions of
maliciously generated public keys
and once we've formalized the attacker
model how can we achieve security
against maliciously generated public
keys
and lastly do their nist finalists
actually achieve security against
maliciously generated public keys
then let's have a look at a real world
protocol
this is about let's encrypt let's
encrypt is a
certificate authority from which you can
get a certificate
for your website in order to get a
certificate
you need to convince let's encrypt that
you are the rightful owner of the
website
and this is can be done with the
following protocol
it begins with the owner of the website
who has a key pair
and tells let's encrypt that it that he
would like to register his website
that's encrypt will generate a challenge
token
and send it back to the owner the
attacker will then use
his secret key to generate a signature
on the challenge token
and then the owner will update the dns
record
for his website such that if you query
this website
you will get the signature as a return
value
our next let's encrypt will precisely
query this dns record
to get the signature and this
dns record can only be changed
by the rightful owner of the website
that is how let's encrypt
is convinced if the signature actually
verifies
which is what lets encrypt checks in the
next step
and if the signature verifies the
challenge token the last encrypt issued
in the beginning
let's encrypt is convinced and issues a
certificate to the owner
now this is how the an honest execution
of the protocol looks like
we are in the setting that an honest
execution has taken place
and now an attacker enters the stage the
attacker
wants to get a certificate for the very
same website
and starts another execution of the
protocol with let's encrypt
that syncr will then however generate a
new challenge token
and sends it to the attacker the
attacker
somehow finds a new public key let's not
concern ourselves with
how it does this but it finds a new
public key
such that the previous signature
verifies
this new challenge token then it tells
slots to encrypt oh by the way i got a
new public key just so you know
next let's encrypt the once more query
the dns record for this website
and get the same signature as before
which was honestly generated
now let's encrypt will check if this
signature which was honestly
generated in the previous protocol
execution verifies the new challenge
token
under the new public key and since it
does
it accepts and issues a certificate for
the attacker
at this point there are two problems
first
now the attacker has a certificate for a
website which it does not own
and second something strange happened
with the signature scheme
it didn't break existential
unforgeability but something happened
that
intuitively should not have happened how
can we formalize what we have just seen
to get a definition for this type of
maliciously generated public key
let's think about what just happened
there is a
honestly generated public key and a
message
and then there is an honestly generated
signature that verifies this message
under the honestly generated public key
and all three of these values are known
to the attacker
and the attacker then produces a new
public key
such that the old signature the original
signature
verifies a different message under this
new public key
and that is a flavor of exclusive
ownership
more specifically this flavor is called
strong destructive exclusive ownership
you can find out more about the other
flavours of exclusive ownership
in our paper and there's two more
notions
of security against maliciously
generated public keys
the first one is called message bound
signatures
which deals with whether a signature is
bound to message
so an attacker against message bound
signatures
has to output a public key to messages
and a signature
such that the signature verifies either
message
under this public key and the third
notion is called non-resignability
here we once more start with an honestly
generated public key
some message and an honestly generated
signature on this message
the attacker will then get the key
and the signature but not the message
and the attacker is required to output a
new
public key and a signature such that the
signature
verifies the message which the attacker
does not know
under the new public key
all of these security notions in
combination
are what we call the beyond
unforgeability features
so that is the flavors of exclusive
ownership message bound signatures and
on resignability
all of these notions are independent of
each other and the proofs for that you
can find in the paper
so how can we achieve security against
these maliciously generated public keys
of course for any specific signature
scheme
you can try to find a proof specific for
this scheme
for some schemes this may be easy and
has been done already
and for other schemes this is infeasible
and specifically for the second case
we are proud to present the buff
transformation
which achieves security against all
beyond unforgeability features
how does this work we start off with
a signature scheme that does not yet
provide the beyond unforgeability
features
and a hash function the key generation
algorithm stays the same
however we have to apply some
modifications to the signing algorithm
first we compute the hash of the public
key and the message
then we sign this digest with the
signing algorithm of the original scheme
that is we just plug in the digest
instead of the message
then the signing algorithm returns the
digest and the signature
so a signature of the modified scheme
has a modus size increase
of one hash digest
the verification algorithm also needs to
be changed accordingly
first we check that the hash digest that
is included in the signature
matches the hash of the public key and
the message
then we invoke the verification
algorithm of the original scheme
with a hash digest as message if both
conditions hold the signature is
accepted
as you can see the overhead in terms of
computation time
is a hash function evaluation in both
the signing and verification algorithm
which is usually negligible the security
of the buffer transformation reduces to
security properties of the hash function
the crucial point here is the extra step
in the verification algorithm
where we check the digest in the
signature this ensures that a signature
is bound to one public key message pair
a successful attacker against exclusive
ownership or message bound signatures
produces a signature that verifies under
several public keys
or for several messages if a signature
verifies with two public key message
pairs
then both public key message pairs need
to have the same digest
in order for the verification algorithm
to accept
hence an attacker produces a collision
in the hash function
the security argument for
non-resignability is slightly more
involved
so i leave it for you to find in the
paper
so as we've just seen it's quite doable
to achieve these security notions
and let's dive into the nest finalists
do they actually
achieve security against maliciously
generated public keys
we have analyzed the signature schemes
as they were submitted to round three of
the nist competition
as you can see in this table some do
some don't
a tick means that the security property
is achieved
so the lithium and picnic achieve all
the security notions
and an x means that we have found and
given an attack which you can find in
the full paper
so ficon and rainbow are so-so while
james
is has a lot of potential for
improvement
as for sphinx plus we couldn't give
attacks or proofs for exclusive
ownership and non-resignability
so this with this you might say okay how
can i achieve all of these security
notions didn't you just introduce
some cool transformation yes you are
right
you can straight apply our buff
transformation to achieve
all of these security notions
and another advantage the signature size
hardly increases
specifically their relative signature
sizes stay the same
so for falcon you may want to apply the
buff transformation to achieve all the
security notions
however after applying the buff
transformation falcon signatures are
still shorter than the lithium
signatures so what have we seen in the
last couple of minutes
we have seen that maliciously generated
public keys can be a serious problem to
reveal protocols
we have seen that there are several
types of maliciously generated public
keys
and we call the combination of all these
security notions beyond unforgivability
features
then we introduce a generic
transformation to achieve
all of the beyond unforgivability
features which is
quite efficient and has a modest
increase in signature size only
lastly we looked at the signature at the
nist finalists
and saw that not all of them achieved
the security guarantees which are
nowadays already
quite easy to achieve if you're
interested
please have a look at our full paper
which you can find on eprint
and i'll be happy to take any questions