Hi, my name is Sekar Kulandaivel and I’m
a PhD student at Carnegie Mellon. This project
was done in collaboration with Bosch Research
in Pittsburgh. I now present our work on CANnon,
a new vulnerability class for in-vehicle networks.
So, with all the advanced electronics and
fancy features that come with a modern car,
remote adversaries have become a real threat.
In this context, remote adversaries aim to
take control of the software for an in-vehicle
ECU through some wireless access point. With
this remote control, an adversary can then
use this compromised ECU to launch further
attacks against the in-vehicle CAN bus. While
attacks that require physical access can only
target a single car, remote attacks can, in
fact, open the door to large-scale attacks,
thus they are a serious concern for the automotive
industry.
Now, one type of attack that’s been a concern
is the remote shutdown attack, where an attacker
uses the compromised software of one ECU to
shut down another victim ECU. While this attack
alone can severely disrupt a vehicle, a shutdown
attack could be used as a stepping-stone for
more advanced attacks, such as a masquerade
attack.
So, of course, the automotive industry has
responded to these shutdown attacks with several
modern defenses. Here, the goal on the defense
side is to detect a shutdown attempt in progress
before the shutdown occurs. In general, there
are three types of defenses. First, we can
use an intrusion detection system, or IDS,
to monitor the bus for anomalies. Or we can
use secure alternatives to the protocol hardware.
And finally, we could monitor the bus voltage
for anomalies to detect a shutdown attempt.
These defenses appear to be sufficient against
shutdown attacks because current shutdown
techniques cannot simultaneously be remote,
reliable and stealthy.
I’ll now clarify our threat model. We assume
the attacker can compromise just a single
ECU. They can modify and re-flash the ECU’s
software application, but they cannot make
physical changes to any hardware. Now for
the attack goals, we essentially want to achieve
the same capabilities of an attacker with
physical access while operating under the
constraints of a remote attacker. Now, since
physical access attacks are considered impractical,
physical attacks have not been prioritized
for state-of-the-art defenses. Thus, if we
could somehow use software to mimic these
physical access attacks, then we could be
stealthy against modern defenses.
In this talk, we introduce a new class of
shutdown attack that uses only compromised
software to mimic and disrupt physical network
signals while bypassing the protocol-compliance
of the CAN hardware.
I now present CANnon, a reliable and stealthy
remote shutdown attack that leverages the
peripheral clock gating feature of unaltered
automotive microcontrollers. This attack operates
using only an ECU’s compromised software,
and it can remain stealthy against both a
monitoring IDS and proposed secure CAN transceivers.
Okay, let’s get into some necessary background.
When looking at the protocol stack for CAN,
there are generally four different layers.
First, the automotive microcontroller (or
MCU) contains the ECU’s software. When the
software wishes to communicate over CAN, it
sends data to the CAN controller, which is
basically a finite state machine that converts
the data into CAN-specific frames. Then, the
CAN transceiver converts the frames into the
proper bus voltage, and the frame is then
sent bit-by-bit onto the CAN bus. Of course,
multiple ECUs communicate on this network,
so the bus is designed as a logical-AND. If
at least one ECU writes a 0-bit, the value
of the bus is a 0-bit as well.
There are a few extra protocol details that
reveal how CAN is vulnerable to shutdown attacks.
To send a CAN frame onto the network, there
are a few steps an ECU will take. We can break
down the CAN frame into different stages,
but the first two are important here. If I
want to transmit on the bus, I send my arbitration
ID and check that no one overwrites me (again,
0-bits overwrites 1-bits). Then, once I’ve
won arbitration, I become the only transmitter
and transmit my data; I just have to make
sure what I send matches what I see on the
bus. Now, if for some reason I send a 1-bit
and see a 0-bit or vice versa, I’ll get
an error thinking that something must be wrong
with my transmission. So I follow the error-handling
protocol for CAN. As we can see from this
state diagram, with enough errors, I can enter
a shutdown state, where I voluntarily remove
myself from the network and stop touching
the CAN bus. Now, this error-handling feature
is what some other shutdown attacks often
exploit. So if an attacker can trick an ECU
into thinking it’s caused so many errors,
it will shut itself off; the attacker wins.
Looking at prior work on shutdown attacks,
one approach uses the compromised ECU to send
out spoofed messages as if these messages
originated from the victim. By forcing certain
bits to mismatch what the victim sends and
by perfectly timing these messages to overwrite
a victim, the attacker can trick a victim
into shutting itself off. However, this approach
isn’t very reliable in practice. And the
automotive industry has built software-based
IDSes that can detect anomalous behaviors
based on timing, content and other features.
In addition, the industry has also proposed
using CAN hardware solutions to detect these
spoofed messages.
Alright, so clearly the prior work on launching
attacks from compromised software can be detected
by modern defenses. What if we could somehow
compromise the physical vehicle? Let’s tap
into the CAN bus and modify signals directly.
Here, we find that IDSes do not produce an
alert even for a voltage-based IDS. However,
this type of attack isn’t taken seriously
by the automotive industry since physical
access isn’t practical. An attacker might
as well cut the brake lines, and they can
only attack one car at a time.
So I’ll now introduce our insight into a
new class of shutdown attacks. Our main insight
comes from a critical change in the design
of modern ECUs, specifically for their microcontrollers.
For the purpose of lowering an ECU’s total
power consumption, designers have implemented
a feature called peripheral clock gating.
This feature allows us to save energy by controlling
when a peripheral is turned on or turned off.
To turn on a device, a microcontroller simply
provides a peripheral with a clock signal,
which allows the peripheral to run. These
peripherals are finite state machines, thus
they run sequential logic that needs a clock
signal to progress. Now, let’s look at how
the architecture had to change to implement
this feature. Originally, ECUs used to have
an automotive microcontroller with a separate
standalone CAN controller chip. But, to implement
clock gating, the CAN controller chip was
moved to be onboard the same chip as the microcontroller.
The key difference here is that, before, there
was only a data line between the microcontroller
and CAN controller, and now there’s an added
clock signal that the microcontroller produces
and passes onto the controller as needed.
By looking at the driver code for an automotive
microcontroller, we found clock control instructions
that are part of the microcontroller’s API.
Normally, a programmer can use this clock
control API to control whether or not the
on-chip CAN controller gets the clock. Now,
of course, if a programmer can write code
to control this clock signal, so can an adversary.
Ultimately, we find this feature is also a
vulnerability that now grants an adversary
the ability to enable and disable the CAN
controller’s clock at-will.
To exploit this vulnerability, I’ll walk
you through two main steps. First, I’ll
show you how a remote adversary can take control
of the CAN clock and perform a basic disruption
of the CAN bus. Then, I’ll show you what
an attacker can do once they refine this attack.
Now let’s go over an example that should
make the implications of this vulnerability
very clear. So let’s say a compromised ECU
is transmitting this set of bits onto the
bus as part of a normal transmission. We have
some 0-bits and some 1-bits, just like a typical
message. Now let’s say the remote adversary
runs a single line of code that disables the
CAN clock right at this 0-bit. If we look
at what the compromised ECU transmits up until
the clock is disabled, the actual output matches
exactly what we expected. However, when we
disable the clock here, the finite state machine
(that is the CAN controller) is essentially
frozen in place. The controller was transmitting
a 0-bit and then it had its clock signal disabled.
Without a clock signal, the controller logic
cannot progress, and it cannot move onto the
next bit. As a result, the remaining bits
that the compromised ECU transmits are all
zeroes. By holding the bus to a dominant 0-bit
state, our attacker by running a single line
of code can disrupt the entire bus and block
any other CAN traffic. Now, in the paper ***, we
discuss details to refine this clock control
and reliably use software to form physical
signals on the CAN bus.
So let’s see how we can exploit this vulnerability
and all that we’ve covered to create our
CANnon attack. Here we give a single CAN message
loaded into the compromised ECU that runs
our CANnon code. This single message is what
will allow us to target and shut down a victim
ECU. First, we load the attack frame into
the compromised ECU’s transmit buffer. Then,
we wait for the inter-frame spacing, basically
when the bus is idle. Then, once we can transmit
this message, we transmit the arbitration
and control fields and then disable the clock.
Two things here: our ID of 0 gives us the
highest priority so we will always win the
bus. Also, after we transmit the ID, the compromised
ECU now believes it is the bus winner, and
all other ECUs stop transmitting. Now, since
the other ECUs see that a message stopped
for some reason, they produce an error. However,
since the compromised ECU has already disabled
the clock when this error frame appears, it
does not see any kind of error and simply
thinks it’s about to send the data payload.
Now that we’ve tricked the compromised ECU
into thinking that it’s still the bus winner,
we can simply keep its CAN clock disabled
until our victim message appears on the bus.
So when the victim message is transmitting
its data, our attacker can now craft an error
frame using a reliable approach that we detail
in the paper. Now with a 64-bit maximum payload
for the CAN frame, we can use a pattern of
alternating 0’s and 1’s, allowing us to
create a total of 32 errors frames from just
a single CAN frame. So what happens after
we inject our first error frame during a victim’s
message? Well, lucky for the attacker, the
victim’s CAN controller will try to re-transmit
the message so we simply have to create more
error frames and target 31 re-transmissions.
So now that we’ve attacked a total of 32
victim messages (that is, the original victim
message and 31 retransmissions), the victim
now shuts itself off as we see from the bus
idle. So of course, this setup is not the
only way to use the clock gating vulnerability
to launch an attack. Our insight gives us
a great amount of flexibility in how we can
produce an attack, and we also offer alternatives
using other parts of the CAN frame. We can
create an attack simply uses the start-of-frame
bit to create an error frame, we can also
use the acknowledgement bit. Both alternatives
use only a single bit and do not require transmitting
any other data onto the bus, giving a powerful
attack with a very small footprint on the
network. We also address how to tackle practical
challenges in the paper.
For our experiments, we target two vehicles:
a 2009 Toyota Prius and a 2017 Ford Focus.
We target ECUs in these vehicles by using
these two automotive microcontrollers. Think
of them as the “compromised ECU” in our
attack. Also, for our prototyping and initial
experiments, we used an Arduino Due board,
which has a similar design as the Microchip
board.
So our first attack, we target the engine
ECU of the Ford Focus using the Microchip
board. We achieve a shutdown attack using
the loading/firing version of the attack we
discussed before, and we can perform a shut
down of the engine ECU in 2ms. The victim
does recover but we can repeat the attack
as needed. We imagine that there could be
some future work that investigates how to
suppress and then stealthily masquerade as
the engine ECU using our work as a launchpad.
In another attack, we target the power steering
ECU of a Prius using the ST board. We achieve
a shutdown in 700ms using the start-of-frame
bit version of our attack. While this attack
has a smaller footprint, it does require more
time to be successful but it still works.
The power steering ECU does not auto-recover
and remains shut down. You could imagine an
attacker launching this attack while the vehicle
is in motion.
We now pit CANnon against three defenses used
by state-of-the-art techniques that successfully
detect other shutdown attacks. First, we build
an IDS software application that checks for
a significant change in message timing. Another
defense we tested was building our own custom
secure transceiver that checks the ID of any
outgoing messages. Finally, we build a frame-level
voltage IDS that looks for a sudden shift
in voltage in the middle of the frame. Well,
CANnon does well against these. It attacks
very fast within a single period, it doesn’t
use full frames so no outgoing ID to block,
and it only induces a small voltage spike
during a victim frame. Now, we also asked
ourselves: well, what if I have a software
IDS? Could I simply push an update to detect
the CANnon attack? Unfortunately, we think
it would be difficult for a software IDS to
differentiate between this attack and a true
fault on an ECU. In our paper, we go over
a couple ideas on how this attack can deceive
even CANnon-aware defenses, forcing a defense
solution to exist not only as software.
Let’s now discuss the important takeaways
for this talk. How can we implement some countermeasures
against this attack? First, we could build
a bit-wise voltage spike detector. We can
monitor for voltage spikes during a frame
transmission. The CANnon attack footprint
won’t be as obvious as the footprint for
other attacks, but it is possible. Likewise,
if you do on-chip power analysis (say for
a host-based IDS), you can monitor for unexpected
changes in power which occurs when the CAN
clock is disabled and enabled, this would
be a great metric we’ve seen in our own
experiments. In terms of prevention, one idea
is to forcibly clear an ECU’s transmit buffers
when the clock is disabled. If the buffers
are cleared, then the attack cannot work.
As we’ve seen, CANnon is a software-based
attack that mimics a physical attack. We do
this by exploiting the peripheral clock gating
feature of modern microcontrollers. It is
clear that modern defenses need to consider
this type of attack, especially since CANnon’s
flexibility could lead to other advanced attacks.