Good time of day,
my name is Dan Frumin and
I would like to present you our work
on compositional reasoning about non-interference for
fine-grained concurrent programs.
This is joint work with Robbert Krebbers and Lars Birkedal.
Before we go forward, let me briefly explain what kind of problem we are trying to tackle here.
The question that we are trying to answer
is this:
how to reason compositionally about non-interference of
fine-grained concurrent programs in a foundational manner?
There is a lot of jargon in this sentence, so let me unpack it a bit.
By non-interference we mean a specific notion of security, that guarantees that a program does not leak secret information,
as we will detail later.
We are considering non-interference specifically for fine-grained concurrent programs.
that is, concurrent programs that use non-blocking atomic instructions, such as compare-and-set and fetch-and-add, instead of less granular synchronization primitives like locks.
We want to reason about non-interference of such programs in a compositional way. For example, if we have a library and a client using this library,
what do we need to know about both of these components separately in order to conclude that their composition is secure? Can we prove non-interference (possibly under some conditions)
for the library and for the client separately, and then compose the proofs together?
Finally, we want to take a "foundational" approach to our non-interference proofs:
with all the notions formulated against some agreed-upon operational semantics of a programming language, formalized in the Coq proof assistant.
Let us talk a little bit about what we mean by non-interference, since it is a notion that we heavily rely on.
Non-interference formalizes a notion of security for a computer program. We start with some program `e' that operates on sensitive data.
Let us suppose that the data is stored in the variable `secret'. We say that the program `e' satisfies non-interference if
if varying the secret data in the program does not lead to observably different behavior.
So, an attacker who observes the behavior of `e' from the outside, couldn't tell the difference between `e' operating on the secret data being an integer 0 or an integer 1.
Intuitively, this means that the secret data is not leaked to the attacker. For those who are familiar with non-interference,
the specific notion of observational equivalence that we use in this work is strong-low bisimulation of Sabelfeld and Sands.
Here are some examples of programs that do NOT satisfy non-interference.
As we can see, the first program leaks the secret information by directly printing it onto the screen.
This is an example of a direct information leak. The second program, on the other hand, exhibits an indirect information leak:
depending on the value of the secret data the program can output different numbers to the screen.
The third programs leaks information through the termination behavior. On the face value, such termination leaks might
not provide much information to the attacker, but their effect can be aggravated in presence of concurrency.
Determining whether a program satisfies non-interference can be quite complex, especially in the presence of  programming language features
like concurrency. Let me try to illustrate this with the following running example, written in an OCaml-style language.
At the beginning, we create a new record `r'. It contains two mutable fields:
the field `data', which stores an integer, and the field `is_classified' which stores a boolean.
Initially the `data' field contains some secret value. And the idea is that the `is_classified' bit tells us
whether the information stored in the `data' field is actually secret or not. With this record `r' initialized, we run the following two threads in parallel.
The rightmost thread does the following: it first overwrites the secret information in the `data' field of `r' with some junk, and then it sets the `is_classified' bit to false.
The thread on the left acts as follows: it spins in an infinite loop, and in each iteration it checks whether the is_classified bit is set to false.
If that is the case, the thread prints the value of `r.data' onto the screen.
This program is secure, it does satisfy non-interference.
To see, informally, note the following two facts: first, if the `is_classified` bit is set to false,
than the information stored in `r.data` cannot be secret. Secondly, once the secret data
is overwritten, the `r.data` field does not get assigned secret information ever again.
Both of those facts are quite important. Note that, for example, if we switch around the two lines in the rightmost thread,
the program violates the first condition and becomes insecure. This is because the right thread can be interrputed in-between the two assignments,
leaving the record `r' in an "incoherent" state. The left thread then can observe this "incoherent" state,
reading the value of `is_classified', and drawing incorrect conclusions from that.
What I've shown here is but an informal argument. How do we make it precise and establish non-interference formally?
Or, even better, can we establish non-interference of this program compositionally?
That is, can we identify what do we need to know about and establish of the sub-program (the left and the right threads),
to derive non-interference of the program as a whole? This is what we mean by compositional non-interference.
Alright, let us take a set back and talk about how we can enforce non-interference.
One of the most popular ways of establishing compositional non-interference is, at least on the
level of programming languages, is by using a type system. Typically, you would have
a type system in which types are annotated with sensitivity labels. `H' for high sensitivity (for secret data),
and `L` for low sensitivity (for public data). In the typing judgment on the screen, we see a program `e`
that returns a low-sensitivity integer. It operates on the variable `x', also a low-sensitivity integer,
and the variable `y', which contains potentially secret data, as determined by the sensitivity label `H'.
Type systems are popular because they are fundamentally compositional in their nature,
and can be extended with various programming language features -- although not always in the most obvious or straightforward way.
On the other hand type systems are too weak, when it comes to programs where non-interference depends on functional correctness properties
and some protocols on data strucutres, as was in the previous example. This in particular means that a conventional type system
would not be strong enough to verify non-interference of the previous example with the record `r' and two threads.
That is, the typing judgment for this program is not going to be derivable.
In order to account for such programs we use a technique called "semantic typing".
The idea behind it is as follows. The job of the type system is to delineate between programs with "good" behavior and "bad" behavior.
However, a type system is described by a set of inference rules, usually in such a way that type checking is decidable.
So, a priori, type checking cannot be used to check behavioral properties in all the cases.
Now, under semantic typing, instead of using inference rules, we take a typing judgment
and we generate a predicate, which descrbies what kind of behavior the typing is actually supposed to delineate.
Then, instead of checking that the program `e' satisfies some typing judgment, we instead verify that the
generated predicate holds for the program `e'. This allows us to leave the world of typing derivations and use the whole power of mathematical logic.
For this approach to work we need to ensure that all the typeable programs do indeed satisfy the generated predicates.
This approach is great for reasoning about combinations of typed and untyped code. If our program consists of both, then we
can simply typecheck the typed part, and separately verify the untyped part of the program.
In fact, this approach has been previously successfully applied in the context of the type system for the Rust programming language.
(in the RustBelt project). There, the type system guarantees the safety of the program, and the generated contracts were called "safety contracts".
In this work we instead consider "security contracts", which gurantee not only safety, but also non-interference.
In the modern approach (such as the one used in the RustBelt project), the safety contracts are
written in Hoare logic. The typing judgment gets translated into a specific Hoare triple.
This works quite well, as Hoare logic is tailored towards proving safety. In our work we introduce
another program logic, which we call SeLoC, and which is aimed at proving non-interference.
The key idea behind SeLoC is to internalize the notion of a strong-low bisimulation inside the logic.
So, instead of Hoare triples we have propositions of this shape,
which we call "double weakest precondition", or DWP for short.
Intuitively, this proposition says that `e1' and `e2' are in some sort of bisimulation, and
if they terminate with some results, then these results satisfy the predicate Phi.
One way to think about it is that `e1' and `e2' are essentially the same program but with varied secret input.
And the double weakest precondition ensures that they produce the same observable behavior.
As such, we have the following soundness theorem:
Suppose that we have a program `e' with a secret variable named "secret".
We then take this program `e' and produce two other programs by replacing  the secret in `e' variable with values `h1' and `h2', respectively.
(where `h1' and `h2' are arbitrary values).
We then ask that the two resulting programs are related by DWP,
In the postcondition we further that the resulting values `v1' (from the first program) and `v2' (from the second program) are in fact equal.
If that holds, if we can derive this proposition in SeLoC, then we know that the program `e' satisfies non-interference.
Another imporant ingredient in SeLoC  is a mechanism for defining and enforcing protocols on programs and data structures.
As we've mentioned SeLoC is a program logic, specifically, it is a concurrent separation logic.
Concurrent separation logic is an extension of Hoare logic geared towards reasoning about concurrent and stateful programs.
We build SeLoC on top of the concurrent separation logic framework Iris, and as such, we inherit useful features like
invariants and custom ghost state, which are crucial for reasoning about concurrent programs with custom protocols on data structures.
I will not go into the details of this, but I would rather like to illustrate this on our example.
Recall this program from before, with the record `r' and two threads operating on this record.
We are going to formalize the protocol on the record `r' as a transition system containing three states, corresponding to
how the record `r' evolves. In a way, this transition system tells us the life story of the record `r'.
Initiallly, `r' is in the Classified state, meaning that
the `is_classified' bit is set to `true' , and the `data' field contains
sensitive information.
Let us first look at the rightmost thread.
The first thing we do in the right thread is overwrite the `data' field
This moves the transition system into the Intermediate state.
Meaning that the `is_classified' bit is still set to `true', but
the `r.data' field does not contain sensitive information.
Then, the program sets the `is_classified' bit to `false'.
This moves the transition system into the final state -- Declassified.
So, the rightmost thread evolves the reference `r' in accordance with the protocol.
Now, let us see how the leftmost thread can rely on the protocol in order to show non-interference.
First, when we check the `is_classified' bit, and it is set to `false',
that is, we are actually going to take the 'then'-branch,
we know that the system has to be in the Declassified state,
because that is the only state in which the flag can be set to `false'.
Then, when we reach the output command, we know
that the system still has to remain in the Declassified state,
because the state does not have any transitions out from it.
So, that means that the record `r' could not have evolved into
a different state inbetween those two operations.
So, whatever is stored in the `r.data' field is not sensitive
and we can output it to the screen.
Now, I am not going to show you details on how this protocol is actually encoded in the logic,
but I just wanted to show you that it is indeed possible to do so.
And there is a semi-systematic way of encoding protocols and transition systems like this.
Please see the paper for more details.
So, in conclusion, we have presented SeLoC --
a novel relational separation logic for proving non-interference
of fine-grained concurrent programs.
To our knowledge, it is the first program logic to tackle non-interference in the context of fine-grained concurrency.
It is fully formalized in the Coq proof assistant, including all the examples and utilizing the powerful Iris separation logic framework.
We have shown how to construct a model of an Information Flow Control type system, using the methodology of semantic typing.
Please see the paper for more examples and a more thorough explanation.
Thank you very much for your attention.