Hi everyone! I’m Luca Piccolboni from Columbia
University and I’m going to talk about CRYLOGGER,
a dynamic tool to detect cryptographic misuses
in Android applications. Before moving on,
let me thank the other authors of this work,
Giuseppe, Luca and Simha.
Android applications use cryptographic libraries
to perform operations such as encryption,
hashing and authentication. Unfortunately,
using these libraries is very complicated.
We need an understanding of cryptography to
know which algorithms and which parameters
to use in a given situation. Suppose, for
example, that an application has to perform
an encryption with AES. The application has
to call an API by passing as parameters the
plaintext and the encryption key in order
to obtain the corresponding ciphertext.
In addition to these parameters, the application
has to specify many other parameters such
as the operation mode or the padding scheme
used for encryption. These parameters are
not as easy to configure. Choosing the correct
values for these parameters is, however, critical
for security. When these parameters are misconfigured,
we say that the corresponding cryptographic
APIs have been misused.
Cryptographic misuses are very common in Android
applications. According to some recent studies
almost 90% of the Android applications make
at least one mistake in using cryptographic
APIs.
The good news is that cryptographic misuses
can be detected with automatic tools. Most
of these tools are static: they analyze the
code of the applications to detect when wrong
parameters are passed to the APIs. A static
tool takes as input the application and a
list of cryptographic rules. An example of
rule is forbidding the use of the operation
mode ECB (electronic codebook) when multiple
blocks of data are encrypted with AES.
Once the tool has analyzed the application,
it reports a list of violations. These violations
have to be treated as security warnings. A
rule violation doesn’t necessarily lead
to an exploit; it is instead a warning that
needs to be further analyzed to make sure
there are no problems for the the application
or its users.
Let’s see now some examples of rules.
Some rules forbid the use of specific configurations
of the cryptographic algorithms. For example,
rule #2 forbids the use of broken encryption
algorithms such as DES. Another example is
rule #20 that forbids the use of RSA without
padding.
Other rules don't let applications use bad
keys or initialization vectors. For example
rule #7 says that we cannot use a static initialization
vector. For instance, using 0 as initialization
vector with the CBC (Cipher block chaining)
mode makes the data vulnerable to certain
attacks.
Other rules focus on random number generation.
For example, rule #17 says that we cannot
use unsafe random number generators. An example
is java.util.Random that shouldn't be used
for cryptographic purposes.
Other rules focus on passwords that are used
for key derivation or for storing sensitive
data. For example, these rules prohibit the
use of weak passwords and black-listed passwords
or the reuse of the same password multiple
times.
Other rules focus on key derivation and the
related parameters. The typical example is
rule #13 that says that we can't use less
than 1000 iterations to generate a key. Using
a lower number of iterations is considered
unsafe.
Finally, some rules are for HTTPS and certificates.
An example is rule #22 that prohibits the
use of HTTP.
To check these rules, we developed CRYLOGGER
a tool that detects cryptographic misuses
by using a dynamic approach. The execution
of CRYLOGGER consists of two steps.
First, we run the Android application. To
do that we use Monkey. Monkey is a tool that
generates random events that trigger actions
on the graphical interface of the application.
An app developer can, of course, use more
sophisticated tests to improve the coverage.
We used Monkey because it was the easiest
way to execute several apps of the Google
Play Store and we were able to detect many
misuses. To log the information about the
crypto APIs, we run the application with instrumented
Java classes. We instrumented, for example,
the class Cipher, the class MessageDigest
and others. In this way, every time one of
the functions of these classes is called,
we can log the most important parameters that
are passed. For example, on the left you can
see that an application that uses the class
Cipher to perform symmetric encryption. When
the function init() is called we store in
a log file information about the algorithm,
the operation mode, the padding scheme and
other relevant parameters.
The second step is done offline. Once we finished
to execute the application we analyze the
log file and report all the violations.
The first step is the instrumentation of the
relevant Java libraries and methods. We instrumented
12 Java classes that belong to the Java Cryptography
Extension (JCE) and the Java Cryptography
Architecture (JCA). These classes provide
a common interface for cryptographic algorithms
to all applications. This interface is implemented
by ‘providers’, which are crypto libraries,
for example BouncyCastle or OpenSSL. By instrumenting
these classes we can monitor the parameters
used by thousands of applications.
An example of class that we instrumented is
MessageDigest. This class implements crypto
hash functions. These functions take as input
an arbitrary amount of data and produce hash
values, called digests. We instrumented the
method digest() so that we can log which particular
algorithm is used to calculate the hash, for
example, SHA1 or SHA256.
We instrumented the other Java classes in
a similar way by determining the relevant
functions and parameters for each class.
After we collected the log file, we need to
analyze it and see if it violates some rules.
To do that, we defined four checking procedures.
Each of these procedures takes as input the
log file that we collected and reports a list
of violations.
The first checking procedure is used to extract
from the log all the values of a parameter
or a combination of parameters and verify
that they can be used for a certain API. All
the values that are collected from the log
are sent to a rule-specific function that
says ‘yes’ if the values are allowed by
the rule or ‘no’ otherwise.
For example, to ensure that we don’t use
any broken algorithm for symmetric encryption,
we check that those algorithms are never used
by the application. If we see one in the log
we report a violation.
As another example, to check that we don’t
use weak passwords, we collect all the passwords
that we find in the log, we evaluate their
strength with an open-source tool, and we
report the violations.
The second checking procedure is used to verify
if a parameter of an API is constant or not.
For instance, we need to ensure that applications
do not use static initialization vectors that
are hard-coded. To verify the rules in this
category, we examine the logs of two executions
of the same application and check that the
values that are found in one of the execution
log are not present in the other one and vice
versa.
The third checking procedure verifies if a
set of values is random or not.
For rule #06, for example, we need to guarantee
that the application uses encryption keys
that have enough randomness. To verify this
rule, we collect all the values of the relevant
parameter and we check if the values have
been generated with a bad method (like java.util.Random).
If they are, we flag a violation, otherwise
we apply the NIST tests for randomness. If
at least one of the tests fails we flag a
violation.
Finally, the last checking procedure checks
if a value or a combination of values is reused
across the same execution of an application.
For instance, for rule #9, we have to ensure
that the same pair (key, IV) is never reused
to encrypt different messages. The checking
procedure collects all the values from the
log and checks if there are duplicates. If
there are duplicates, it means that the app
has used the same key and IV to encrypt different
messages, which should be reported as violation.
Let’s now discuss some experimental results.
We analyzed roughly 1800 Android applications
by using CRYLOGGER on an emulator running
Android 9. We downloaded about 2000 free Android
applications from the Google Play Store. These
are popular free apps of 33 different categories.
We discarded some applications since we did
not detect usage of crypto APIs and some as
they did not work on the Android emulator
either because they kept crashing or they
required libraries that could not be installed
in our environment.
We used Monkey to interact with the graphical
interface of the applications by using 30k
random events, which we saw it was a good
compromise between running time and violations
reported.
So, here are the results of our analysis.
This graph reports the total number of applications
that violate the 26 cryptographic rules checked
by CRYLOGGER. The x-axis reports the number
of the rule, while the y-axis reports the
total number of applications that violate
that rule.
Let’s discuss the results for a few rules.
A very high number of applications use broken
hash algorithms and unsafe random generators.
These numbers are very high because they account
for secure uses of hash algorithms and random
number generators for non-sensitive data.
Unfortunately, it is not easy to discriminate
the unsafe uses from the safe uses in these
situations.
Several applications use bad keys and initialization
vectors which are either constant or they
don’t have enough randomness. Most likely
some of these problems are coming from popular
libraries that are used by many applications.
Many applications use also bad passwords.
Often these passwords are used to obfuscate
the data stored locally on the smartphone.
As mentioned before, each rule violation should
be treated as a security warning. In fact,
a rule violation doesn’t necessarily mean
that an exploit exists. To understand if these
violations correspond to real exploits, we
manually analyzed 28 applications and we collected
the feedback from the developers of 8 applications
and 2 libraries. We discuss now the main lessons
that we learned through this process.
First, developers are interested in real exploits
that have a direct impact on the security
of the applications. Some rules define, for
example, the minimum size of a key or the
minimum number of iterations to use for key
derivation. While these are important rules
to follow their security impact on the particular
usage can be difficult to determine.
Second, sensitive data are sometimes stored
by using poor encryption practices, for example
by employing constant passwords or broken
algorithms. These are reported as violations,
but they are more difficult to exploit by
an attacker. Of course, it is better to always
adopt safe cryptographic practices even when
certain attacks, like privilege escalation,
are considered out of scope.
Third, some violations are raised for non-sensitive
data. For example, using a random generator
that is not safe for cryptographic use is
OK when the values that are generated are
not used as keys. Discriminating this and
similar situations is very challenging and
some rules more than others can suffer of
this problem.
We compared our approach with Cryptoguard,
a state-of-the-art static tool for automatic
detection of cryptographic misuses.
We observed that static tools and dynamic
tools can complement each other. Static tools
are great for analyzing a large number of
applications. But they can report false positives
because they analyze parts of the code that
might never be executed. In addition, they
can produce false negatives as in some cases
they clip the explorations to reduce the execution
time.
On the other hand, a dynamic tool can focus
on the code that is actually executed, but
it can produce false negatives when the application
is not fully explored. It can also produce
false positives, for example, when it is difficult
to distinguish critical from non-critical
contexts.
For future work, we recommend combining static
and dynamic analysis for more accurate results.
The problem of crypto misuses is interesting
and there are static and dynamic approaches
that can detect misuses, but there is still
work to do to understand the real extent of
this problem.
First, we need to improve the analysis of
the applications. For dynamic tools, this
means improving the coverage by using, for
example, test generators that try to trigger
the execution of specific APIs. In our work,
we used Monkey as it was easy to use, but
smarter test generators can guarantee better
results especially for applications that require
information such as login credentials.
Second, we need to improve the accuracy of
rule checking. The safety of using a particular
parameter for an API depends on the context.
For example, a broken hash algorithm can be
used to generate unique IDs for non sensitive
data. To distinguish these situations, we
can log more information on the usage of certain
APIs or exploit static analysis.
In this presentation, I talked about CRYLOGGER,
a dynamic tool to detect cryptographic misuses.
The tool is available on GitHub if you want
to check it out.
We showed that it is possible to analyze thousands
of applications to look for cryptographic
misuses but accuracy must be further improved
to avoid false positives, false negatives
and more in general to make the analysis more
accurate. We suggest combining static and
dynamic approaches as these have unique advantages
that can improve the overall understanding
of crypto misuses when combined.
Thank you for watching this presentation.