Hello i'm Thomas and i'm going to
be talking about formally verifying
verification electronic verdict this is
joint work with both Rajeev and Bhavesh
so just a brief clarifier before i begin in
this talk what i'm really trying to talk about
is verifiable electronic voting without a paper
trap so we're talking about what is sometimes
referred to as sort of online voting we're
not talking about the myriad of electronic
voting systems which have electronic
components that are kind of in some sense
paper-based so in these online voting systems
you have things called verifiable mixed nets
and the basic idea is they take effective inputs
they mix it and they create a vector of outputs
and so you kind of have um basically ballots
coming in being randomized in the order and then
and then coming out again and this is very similar
to how ballot boxes work into traditional voting
so you underpin almost all voting schemes with
non-trivial tally methods for example um you
know uh single transferable votes um instant
runoff voting all this kind of stuff it's not
not things like uh not things like first past
the post and these are deployed in national
elections in norway is still in switzerland and
numerous other places in lower two elections
so these are prime locations for critical errors
and so what we'd like to do is machine check the
cryptographic properties however several
different encryption schemes are used in
different variations and that makes this hard
so in this work what we did is we machine
checked the design implementation of all the
variants of the most commonly used mixed nuts
so a little bit on mixed notes before
i proceed so mix notes are this
basically collection of authorities that jointly
work together to transform and permute the input
so you have the input vector and you can think of
these as encrypted votes next to people's names
now obviously we don't want to just decrypt these
votes because that would reveal how everybody
wrote it so if we put them in the mix net they get
all muted up and then they come out in some manner
and what's actually happening underneath here
is that we have this sequence of authorities who
are each in their turn permuting and then we're
encrypting the ciphertext and so on and so forth
until eventually our output is well this should
be the product of all of the permutations that
the individual mixes used so this is how we can
make this work okay so the problem here is that
implementing cryptography is actually really hard
and this seems to be particularly the case in
e-voting so one significant example was with
the swiss system which the the actually the
federal chancellor withdrew it from use uh 2019
because despite the fact they had what seemed
like a really good process for developing this it
actually turned out that when this thing was made
public there were lots and lots of errors in fact
every single zero knowledge proof they implemented
was broken in some way so it's very hard to
do and i think the most same way to do this
is to try and machine check the properties
particularly if we can do that in a way
which we can reuse well so voting systems of this
very large collection of software and formally
verifying everything is hardly a practical goal
there's just too much stuff that we'd like to
verify and even and moreover even if we knew the
software was sort of correct we wouldn't actually
know that the election management body was
actually running the software they they said they
were running the sort of techniques for remote
anastasia and stuff don't really work in this
threat model however as we're best observed we
can use a whole bunch of cryptographic techniques
to have something called software independence
this is the idea that the system should produce
public evidence which we can independently check
which should then prove that the result that it
output was actually correct since the so as i
say again this is called software independence
so then we sort of we moved our problem we've
moved our problem for integrity from the software
that's running the election to the software
that's checking the evidence so but that's
that's actually quite nice because the software
checking evidence is a lot smaller it's happening
after the election it's a lot easier to manage
than the software running the election itself
this is precisely the fact that we exploit in this
work we sort of do this verified verify actually
we do a lot more than that but you can read the
paper for that um the main sort of thing that we
want to actually use in practice is the verified
verified that we actually machine check to heaven
so the two most common mix nets for electronic
voting are tyraelus fixturn and biograph
and in fact the most common is actually
the optimized variant of total spectrum
the roth one is really only being
pushed by one significant vendor
so there are many slight variants but essentially
the optimized variant of the 1262 mixnet works by
taking the original mixed net and restricting
it to the case where the ciphertext space has
prime order or sufficiently close to primary so
this style of mixing is primarily implemented
in verification which has been used in several
national elections and in the ch202 system which
was designed for use in swiss national elections
and the various implementations have been used
to make millions of ballots in national and lower
tier elections now it was proved that the original
mixed net worked for y-class encryption schemes
and it was focused that the optimized variant
also worked for a significant class but an exact
uh claim and proof had never been given previously
and the other thing that i want to mention
in background is that proofs of shuffle
as with most sort of xerox proofs can either
be interactive or non-interactive and generally
the proofs that are fine and proven in
the interactive variant and then made
non-interactive using the future we transform
and i'll talk a bit more about that later
so a little bit upon the inductive
theorem over we've used we use interactive
theorem overclock [ __ ] and basically what you do
in this theo improver is you give as lemons to be
proven the properties you want to hold and then
you prove that they impact hold and what happens
is that once you've written out the proof the
interactive theorem improver can run through and
check that yes indeed uh your proof is valid if it
is actually a sequence of valid steps and there's
various tools that the improve also provides so
let me now give you some feel for contribution
um the first page is sort of background stuff and
then we get to the more significant contributions
so there was previous work from from almost the
same set of authors from ccs 2019 where we mainly
focused on single protocols but we did show that
yes actually you can do sort of mixed sets as well
um but we only actually did it in that paper for
two so we only had two voters that was fine but
of course in general uh you want more than that so
in this work we we get rid of that restriction and
we prove it for an unbounded number we formalize
the genetic classroom encryption schemes which
captures most of all the encryption schemes
commonly used in voting so we're actually going to
formally define the encryption schemes
for which the mixednet is going to work
and then we provide a kind of paper proof so the
optimized uh mix net is actually available for
shuffle for any encryption scheme in that class
so this is um basically all things that were
believed to be true but we had to actually just
do them to actually get to our main contributions
okay so then what we did is we encoded the above
class of encryption schemes into [ __ ] and
machine check the security proof that i talked
about previously so we checked that yes you know
if you build a mix on top of anything inside this
class it is actually a valid uh proof of shuffle
and the machine check that there's
an implementation of the mixnet
there's already mixednet to be complete that
is honest parties will will happily terminate
sounds if the verifier accepts the
motherboard probability the statement
is true and zero knowledge it doesn't leak
anything more than just in the statement
so what why why what's the nice thing about
doing this well the nice thing about doing
this is that it then suffices to prove that a
given encryption scheme falls into this class
in order to get a formally verified verifier
without actually directly doing anything with
the mixnet all that's already done for you so you
just prove the encryption scheme is there and then
you're done so this is very nice and it makes it
very easy to use okay so we proved in [ __ ] that
both basic algorithm and something called
parallel argument or multi recipient organelle
fall into this class we also subsequently proved
that some more complicated encryption schemes also
fall into this class we also proved that anything
inside the class is preserved under composition
both of the same encryption screen in parallel
and the different encryption schemes in power
so basically these are kind of the things that you
would hope would be true in fact we've proven that
true and this allows you to do a lot of things
automatically which is very helpful so we've
done this kind of nice work we now know that we've
actually you know this thing is actually secure at
least in theory um we've got nice general ways
of doing it but does it actually correspond to
what's happening in practice are the actual mixed
nets that are running actually the thing we verify
so the way we did this is we took existing
implementations of the tavares mixture mixnet
we got proofs out of those so they generated
some proofs and we verified those using our
verifier so we checked and remember that soundness
is basically a property to verify so the fact that
our verifier accepts on the proofs is produced
means that that proven must actually in some sense
be valid dishonest property implies okay so
the first implementation we verified was the
verification mixnet which has been used in norway
estonia and switzerland and the second one was the
ch vote system which was planned for use in the
state of geneva switzerland is currently on hold
okay so let me now just go over a bit of the sort
of limitations or clarifications i want to make
then i'll give some future work and then i'll
sum up so what did we verify this is always the
question should be you should ask people say oh
you verified this okay you verified it but for
what properties what did you actually verify so we
verified as i've said completeness zero knowledge
and sounds and the first two of these completeness
and zero knowledge actually hold perfectly
so the arguments here there's no probabilities
involved it's just algebraic reasoning
you can actually read in the paper about the
various techniques we use to actually not have to
reason directly about probabilities okay but some
of the other properties specifically soundness
are actually in form of reductions to underlying
heart problems and of course if the parameters
are chosen incorrectly an underlying problem
is not hard then in fact there is no security
the other thing that we the other limitation
here is that we didn't actually consider
sidechart attacks so the primary piece that we're
interested in getting out of this is the verified
the verified software is the verifier and this
is a public algorithm running only on public data
so we don't actually care about side channels
with that and we talk a bit in the paper if
you're interested about side saddles on the proof
itself so the next big caveat here is the virginia
transformer so we proved the interactive variants
of the proof of shuffle however in practice the
non-interactive variant isn't verbally used now
all of the verifiable mixtures that sort of come
out of our functor can be made non-interactive
with a one or two line change to the algorithm
but actually proving that that one or two line
changes secure is left as future work the issue
here essentially is that actually formally
proving what we want to prove here involves we
want rewinding random articles and when you rewind
metamorphicals you've actually got to think about
the state of the internal state of the random
article as you rewind it and also not only mental
miracles but also actually adversaries accessing
random articles you've got to rewind adversaries
think about their internal state there's a lot
of complexity here i won't go into um but we have
some sort of way of trying to actually solve
this and that'll be interesting future work
and the next thing is to do a code extraction
so we defined the specification of the thing
inside [ __ ] we proved that to qs that's a
nice contribution itself but we actually run
is not that specification but a more
efficient extraction of that verification
and alas the the means by which we do this is
not itself formally verified there's ongoing
work in this area but at the moment we don't
know that that wouldn't introduce more errors
okay so let me now briefly give the future
work so one of the limitations in our work
here was that for completeness and zero
knowledge we proved sufficient conditions
but we didn't actually prove that the sufficient
conditions were sufficient and the reason was
while the argument that they're sufficient is
fairly trivial actually formally proving these
properties formally proving formally defining the
properties that we want to prove here is actually
very difficult i'm sorry left this is future work
this is future work that we've actually made a
lot of progress on and hopefully um in future
years i will share with you the results of that
the other thing we'd really like to do here is to
prove the biographic snap to be as secure so the
verification extent is actually fairly simple
there's sort of one underlying signal protocol
and then there's one more round on top of that or
maybe two more rounds depending on how you do it
um so it's actually a very simple thing the
biographics on the other hand is much more
complicated there is i think six different zero
knowledge proofs that are working together to get
the results and because of the complexity involved
there the actual you know there's not a really
nice fully detailed argument of its of its proof
that i believe is actually publicly available i
don't know any in general so this one is actually
much more likely to have bugs and but it's much
harder to do and we need to do a lot of work to do
that we're trying to do that but it's not going to
work okay so let me just briefly summarize
so what we're doing here is we're working
on online voting systems which are using these
things called verifiable mixnets to basically
use as a ballot box but these systems are
actually very complicated pieces of cryptography
and they are very likely contained critical
errors which we would like to find would like
to get rid of um before they're actually run right
so what we've done is we went and machine checked
both the design implementation of these bits of
cryptography to do what we want and we did that in
a way that gets us very good coverage with a lot
of different implementations and then we actually
checked it with implementations to make sure it
actually worked and then we yeah so then we would
actually verify transcripts that were produced by
systems for national elections which is very nice
but there are these kind of limitations and
all governments of work that we need if we're
actually going to get proper coverage of all
the kinds of things that people are doing in
practice in the space so thank you if you have
any questions you can obviously email me or
you know read the paper and then and then also
there's a lot more answers in there and then
also of course you can you know email me after
that and i look forward to seeing you at s&p