hello everyone my name is chong chen
currently a phd student
at peking university in this talk i will
introduce our paper
when lora means emr electromagnetic
power channels
can be super resilient this is a joint
work with telugu
dr rytan and my phd advisor dr jin huang
em current channel is a classic state
exfiltration attack
where the attacker steals classified
data from a computer
by using a model to manipulate the emr
of
memory power management unit usb
and so on conventional cover channels
highlighted
in network traffic thus relying on a
compromised network interface
in contrast em carol channels exploit
the infiltrated computer
as a radio transmitter and thus can
bypass
a variety of network security measures
such as firewalls
traffic monitors and even air gaps where
network interface cards
are disabled or removed to physically
isolate classified state
from the outside world however due to
the low power of emr the threat of the
existing em color channels has been
limited
to only short-range attacking scenarios
for example prior studies show that the
emr of a typical cpu memory system
can be decoded within only 5 meters
which demands the attacker to be
unrealistically close to the target
system in addition to pass loss curved
em signals are subject to the
attenuation
caused by shielding for example the
temperature standard
developed by nato and the national
security agency
requires classified systems to be
shielded by
minimum of 1000 decibels in comparison
the emr of a typical cpu memory systems
is only 15 decibels about the noise flow
in this paper we challenge the common
belief that em curved channels are
vulnerable to attenuations
caused by past loss and shielding in
particular
we asked if yam card channels can
survive deep continuation
thereby achieving long range or
breaching
aggressive shield previously considered
as
secure to descend we will revisit
em color channels with lora a
state-of-the-art
various technology that enables
kilometer level
connectivity for android styled iots
lora features an attenuation resistant
modulation
called chirp spread spectrum in its
chirp
signal frequency linearly increases with
time
leading to a pattern that can be
distinguished from
significant noise in lora different
beats are represented by different
cyclic sieves of chirps for example the
red figure shows four chirps
it's carrying two bits represented by
one of
four possible shifts motivated by the
super resilience of lora networks
we ask the question is it feasible to
exploit em sources as the lora radios
to fundamentally escalate em-called
channel attacks
to explore this feasibility we design
implement
and evaluate yam laura the first em carl
channel that can
exfiltrate dates over long distance and
aggressive shield
we conduct extensive experiments to
study the performance of yam lora
and demonstrate how yam lora enables
attacks in
previously impossible scenarios the key
idea of em lora is to exploit
memory as a lora radio transmitter yam
lora shares the same attack model with
previous em cover channels
but can significantly boost the
attenuation resilience by five orders
to achieve this yam lora faces several
unique changes
from a signal processing angle yam lora
must handle the complex spectrum of
memory emr
from a system angle the malware of yam
laura faces uncontrollable cpu
contentions
which pose a fundamental challenge for
precisely shipping covered signals
in the following we demonstrate how
attackers can circumvent these changes
to make yam lora visible and
reliable em laura's transmitter is a
user space model that
shifts memory mr by manipulating memory
rights
the code of vm lora transmitter consists
of two parts
the first part is a fixed frequency emr
generator which alternately writes to
ecosize the bad blocks into memory
because the two bed blocks produce
different current flow patterns
in memory bus the generated emr
approximates
a square wave where bad block size
determines frequency
to generate em chirps an iu method is to
call
square wave with linearly increasing
frequency
unfortunately the turbo energy generated
in this way is very low
because of cpu contention this makes yam
laura unable to accurately control the
timing of generated waves
thus introducing frequency arrows to
address this problem
em laura performs approximate chirp
generation
specifically it first divides a
continuous chirp into discrete frequency
levels
and then generates multiple square waves
at each frequency level
for a certain wheel time because square
wheels at
each frequency level are independently
affected by timing arrows
the average of their frequencies follows
normal distribution
according to the central limit zero the
variance of
average frequencies decreases as the
number of square waves increases
which means that the longer the wheel
time the stronger the emr energy at
the intended frequency based on
empirical observation
we found that the dual time of 1.5
milliseconds
is sufficiently robust to generate
strong chirps
to decode the covert signal of em laura
it's important to understand
the spectrum characteristics of memory
mr
specifically before chirp modulation
memory yammer is purely produced by
memory clock
which is generated using spirit spectrum
to reduce emr intensity
as modeled in this equation a memory
clock is the sum of a series of
subclocks
for example the bottom figures show the
emr spectra
of ddr3 on the ddr4 agreeing with the
model
the energy of memory mr is distributed
as a series of peaks
where each peak corresponds to one
subclock
we observe that the modulation of em
lora introduce
complex features into the spectrum of
memory clock
specifically sharp energy is dispersed
as
a series of mirror images where each
sub-clock is associated with the
abstract and the dung chirp
in addition each up and down chop
produce a sequence of harmonic images
such energy dispersion significantly
reduces the
intensity of em chirps thus posing a key
challenge
to em laura receiver we have developed
a theoretical model to explain such
modulation
impacts of vm lora on memory clock
signals
details of the model can be found in our
paper
to decode coverage em chirps em laura
augments the standard lora
receiver to handle the complex spectrum
of memory mr
and performs a series of signal
processing to fuel the dispersed
chirp energy to boost the current signal
intensity
this figure shows the high level signal
processing pipeline of em laura receiver
specifically is the first performance
symmetric deterp
where it converts up and down chops into
fixed
frequency signals em laura then sums the
results of
symmetric deterp of fields the energy of
mirror chirps
to further fill the tropical images
associated with sub-clocks
yam laura exploits the periodicity of
subclocks and
performs the folding of faster signal
processing algorithm
originally used to amplify extremely
weak
periodic astronomical signals after
floating
disperse the chirp energy says are
filled into one energy peak
host frequency indicates the base
carried by the chirp
as the user space mower em laura
transmitter has to share the cpu with
other processes
as illustrated in the figure cpu
contentions of other processes
may block the malware transmitter of yam
lora
which interrupts the transmission of
covered signals
and distorts the generated em chirps
to further understand the impacts of cpu
contention
we test the effect of different cpu laws
on the frequency and the power of em
chirps
as shown in the red figure em chirps
begin to suffer
distortion when cpu becomes fully loaded
the frequency error and power loss of
generated chirps
further increase as the cpu becomes
overload
to make yam lora survive cpu contention
we leverage the tradeoff between
throughput and
chirp robustners specifically longer
chirps carrying therapies
improve robustness but decrease
throughput
in comparison shorter chirps carrying
more beats degree robustness but the
increase throughput
based on this observation young laura
first estimates the level of cpu
contention
and adopts chirps to balance bit rate
and robustness
specifically it first measured the
timing error experienced by chirps
and then uses the timing arrow as a
feature to classify the level of cpu
contention
based on classification results em laura
switches between three predefined
spread factors calibrated for underload
followed and overload which defend loss
and indicates the number of bits
carried by each chirp the red figure
shows a runtime example of
chirp in the beginning yam laura
transmits short chirps for higher
throughput
when the cpu is under load when cpu load
increases
yamlora increases turbulence to improve
robustness we have implemented a
prototype of the amorous receiver using
blade rf
inexpensive software radio equipped with
a 2.2 dbi
whip antenna the malware transmitter is
deployed on different systems
equipped with ddr3 and ddr4 of different
speeds we compare yam lora with cs mime
or state of the art memory card channel
for fair comparison both yam laura and
the
are implemented using the same blade if
receiver
and then compared under the same bit
rate we observed that
compared with the s mime m laura
improves attenuation by
up to 53 decibels under extends its
communication range by
up to 21 times when receiving from the
ddr3 desktop
yam laura achieves a range of 2000 to
2050 meters
and then resists up to 78 decibels
attenuation
we note that the resilience of yam lora
can be further improved
using high gain rna and directional
antenna
which typically provide an additional
gain of up to 70
decibels and thus will allow yam laura
to defeat the 1000 decibels bar
of tempest we then evaluated the
performance of
em laura under cpu contention we started
two types of
contending cpu workloads including video
streaming
and the monero's colon mining this
figure shows the good process of yam
lora as a function of
attenuation when rate adoption is on and
off
we observe that rate adoption
effectively maintains attenuation
resistance under cpu contention
specifically
it provides about two and five decibels
gain over the basic
em lora next we demonstrate how yam lora
enables attacks
in two previously impossible scenarios
by achieving long communication range em
laura enables
wide array data exfiltration which
allows an attacker to deploy a receiver
in a public area
to receive classified data export
treaties from a building
to demonstrate this attack we use a ddr3
laptop as em laura transmitter
and deploy it in a building with
concrete walls
we then place five reservoirs out of 30
and
1020 meters away from the building
we observe that all packets can be
correctly decoded
at r1 r4 and r5 due to long
communication distance
receivers at x2 and x3 experienced
a moderate package loss with a loss rate
of 11.2 percent
and 53.4 respectively
we further conducted retracing based
emulations in two scenarios
where we deployed em lora receivers in a
public park on the sports center
to receive covered signals leaked from
two government buildings located in
washington dc
and beijing in its scenario we placed
transmitters in
three selected locations within the
buildings
we found that in the dc scenario the em
laura receiver can decode most
packets and limit package loss rates at
below
20 in the beijing scenario yam laura
suffers a relatively high packet loss
only when receiving from ts2 at act 2
found that this is caused by the block
of a building
that casts off the direct pass between
transmitter and receiver
we next demonstrate through the voltage
at filtration
from an aggressively shielded server in
an indoor area
the target server is deployed in room d
and is sorted by a commodity
faraday cage that provides about 70
decibels attenuation
we observe that without shielding of 30
cage
leak states can be received at all
locations except
a when the target server is enclosed in
the third
cage location b and i turn to dead spots
despite that yam lora can maintain a bit
rate higher than 2 bps
at all other locations in conclusion we
presented
yam lora the first super resilient em
card channel
em laura expressed memory as a covered
lora radio
it shared the same attack model with
prairie m carroll channels
but can significantly boost attenuation
resilience by
up to 53 decibels by achieving this
yam lora can enable attacks in
previously impossible scenarios
including wide area data exfiltration
and third decade
penetration in the future we plan to
further investigate the implication of
vm lora for other em sources
and develop effective detectors and
countermeasures to mitigate yam laura's
right thanks for listening please direct
questions related to this work to the
following emails