hello everyone
today i'll be presenting our work on
protecting formula verified
cryptographic libraries from spectre
style attacks
this is joint work with the many
wonderful co-authors listed here
so it's pretty well known that
cryptography is really difficult to get
right
cryptographic design flaws
implementation bugs
and side channel vulnerabilities are
regularly found even in the most widely
used libraries
and because of their large attack
surface for security
crypto implementations should achieve
what we call the big four guarantees
first they should be memory safe to
prevent leaking seekers held in memory
second they should be functionally
correct with respect to some standard
specification
third they should be provenly secure to
rule out important classes of attacks
and finally they should be constant time
to avoid leaking seizures through timing
side channels
problem is that achieving any one of
these can be difficult let alone
achieving all of them at once
so to help a lot of recent research
looks to using high assurance
cryptography techniques
to develop high performance
implementations with formal machine
checkable guarantees for the big four
although high assurance cryptography has
been hugely successful in producing high
speed
cryptographic software with formally
verified guarantees
the bad news is that these guarantees
can be undermined
by recent microarchitectural side
channel attacks such as spectre
which exploits speculative execution in
modern cpus
in particular spectre style attacks
reveal a gap
between formal guarantees of constant
time which hold for a sequential model
of execution
and practice where processors can
execute instructions speculatively and
out of order
this mismatch combined with spectre
style attacks can cast doubts on the
robustness of high insurance
cryptography
so in this work we set out to study the
impact of speculative execution
on the big four guarantees
our main goal in this work is to extend
the big four guarantees to a setting
with speculative execution
we do this in four parts first we extend
the classical notion of constant time
which holds for a sequential setting
to the notion of speculative constant
time which holds for a speculative
setting
to do this we formalize an adversarial
program semantics for speculative
execution
based on existing work by sanjay one of
our co-authors and others
and use this speculative semantics to
redefine what it means for a program to
be constant time
second we develop a verification method
for checking speculative constant time
to simplify our verification approach we
prove a key property of our semantics
called secure forward consistency
which drastically reduces the number of
execution paths to be considered
and also shows that code proven correct
and secure in a sequential semantics
also enjoys these properties in a
speculative semantics
third we integrate our verification
method into the jasmine verification
framework
prior work has used jasmine to develop
high-speed cryptographic assembly code
that enjoys the big four guarantees in a
sequential setting
but now we've extended jasmine's
capabilities to the speculative setting
as well
finally we use our extensions to the
jasmine framework to develop
spectral protected implementations of
cha cha 20 and poly1305
which are two key primitives used in tls
1.3
we find that the development and
verification effort for adding spectra
protections is not too onerous and that
the performance overhead is relatively
modest
before we dive into things let's first
explain what the classical notion of
constant time is
how it protects against timing side
channels and what changes when
speculative execution comes into the
picture
for crypto code even if it's function
correct it can still leak secrets
through timing side channels
this happens if the code executes for an
observably different time
depending on the value of secret
information
for example in the left code snippet
branching on a secret value can lead to
a measurable timing variation
since the body of the conditional is
only executed if the secret value is
true
the right code snippet is a little more
subtle the first
line loads a byte b from the secret
array and the second line
loads a value from the table array using
b
this secret dependent memory access
leaks secret data
since the lookup to table b will be
brought into cache
an attacker can then infer the value of
b by measuring timing variations when
accessing different indices of the table
array to protect against these timing
side channels
the constant time programming policy
disallows control flow and memory
accesses
that depend on secret values
unfortunately it turns out that applying
constant time coding recipes
to turn secret dependent code into
secret independent code
is pretty unnatural and tricky to do
correctly so there are many existing
tools that let developers annotate
program inputs
as either public or secret and then
automatically check
that the program is constant time
it's worth pointing out though that
essentially all of these tools consider
only a sequential model of execution
in which instructions execute in order
one after another
modern cpus however execute instructions
out of order
and speculatively to increase
performance
for example upon reaching a conditional
branch modern cpus can use a branch
predictor
known as the pattern history table or
pht to speculatively execute one of the
branches before resolving the branch
condition
if the predicted path is correct then
the cpu commits
speculatively computer results to the
architectural state
and this leads to an overall performance
boost
otherwise if the predicted branch is
incorrect the cpu backtracks to the last
correct state
by discarding all speculatively computer
results and this results in performance
similar to idling
so although the results of
misspeculation aren't ever committed to
the architectural state
remnants can still be left in the
microarchitectural state such as the
cache
and this is the root cause of many
recent high profile spectral style
attacks
to make things more concrete this code
snippet which is secure in the
sequential world
is vulnerable to what's called a spectre
phd attack
the first line is a balance check on x
which prevents reading secret memory
outside of array 1.
unfortunately an attacker can supply an
out-of-bounds value for x
such that array 1 of x reads secret
memory outside of array 1
and then mistrain the pht to
speculatively bypass the bounce check
so that a secret value is stored in the
variable i
this happens the third line loads the
secret dependent memory location array
two of i
into the cache leading to a timing
vulnerability
memory fence instructions can in theory
protect against these vulnerabilities
these instructions act as speculation
barriers and prevent further speculative
execution until prior instructions have
completed
for example if we place a fence after
the conditional branch
this prevents the cpu from speculatively
reading from array 1
until the branch condition has resolved
at which point any misspeculation will
have been caught
unfortunately inserting fences after
every conditional to protect against
specter pht and before each load
instruction to protect against a
different variant called spectre stl
really hurts performance on the other
hand
heuristic approaches for inserting
fences leads to shaky security
guarantees
so our solution is to automatically
verify that implementations use fences
correctly
and efficiently to protect against
specter style attacks
specifically the specter pht and spectre
stl variants
in order to form a reason about
speculative execution we first need to
formalize its semantics
i'm only going to choose some of those
high level features of our semantics
but the full details can be found in the
paper
the programs we consider are written in
a core fragment of the jasmine
programming language
which includes commands for assignments
memory loads
memory stores conditionals loops and
importantly
fence instructions the program shown
here is the one from before
program states at a high level include
main memory
which is a mapping from addresses to
values here addresses are pairs
of array names and indices and for the
sake of illustration suppose array 1 at
index 8
which is out of bounds holds a secret
value s
states include a special right buffer
which contains sequences of delayed
write instructions
the right buffer is an essential for
this example which is vulnerable to the
classic spectre pht attack
but in a nutshell we use the right
buffer to model out of order execution
on behalf of the cpu's memory
disambiguator which can be exploited to
perform specter stl vulnerabilities
states also include a register map which
is a mapping from registers to values
and here
the value x is set to zero and finally
states also include
a misspeculation flag which is set to
true if misspeculation has occurred
previously during execution
and false otherwise
our semantics is adversarial in the
sense that program execution
depends on a schedule of directives
issued by the adversary
for example at control flow points the
step directive
shown on the left allows execution to
proceed normally
while the force directive shown on the
right forces execution to follow a
particular branch
and finally our semantics is also
instrumented with observations
to model timing side channel linkage for
example
the adversary can observe the targets of
memory accesses via read and write
observations
and control flow via branch observations
if we run this program on the state
shown using the directive schedule step
the condition with x being 0 evaluates
to true
making a branch true observation the
next line
leaks a read of array one at zero with
value three
and the last line makes a read of array
two
at three with value nine using the
schedule
force true leads to the same
observations
and informally we say that a program is
speculatively constant time
if for every choice of directives leaked
observations do not depend on secret
values
at least in the program executions we've
considered so far no secret values have
been leaked
but suppose the register map has x as 8.
if the adversary chooses the directive
schedule force true
which bypasses the bounds check then the
execution misspeculates
which sets the misspeculation factor
true and
leaks a read of array 1 at 8 with secret
value s
and a read of array 2 at s with value 7.
the secret dependent memory access array
2 of s can lead to a timing
vulnerability
so this program is not speculatively
constant time
we can fix this program by adding a
fence instruction after the conditional
which acts as a speculation barrier and
prevents further speculative execution
until prior instructions have completed
if we run this program on state with
register x as eight
the adversary can issue the force true
directive
which sets the misspeculation flag to
true and leaks a branch true observation
however because there's a fence
instruction in the way the adversary can
only proceed by issuing a backtrack
directive
which checks if misspeculation has
occurred and backtracks if so
since the misspeculation flag is true
execution backtracks and leaks a
backtrack observation
and now the only way for the adversary
to complete the program execution
is by issuing a step directive which
skips the conditional body
leaking a final branch false observation
since the leaked observations don't
depend on secret data this program is
now speculatively constant time
we next developed a verification method
for checking speculative constant time
and we integrated it into the jasmine
verification framework
prior work has verified the big four
guarantees of jasmine programs in a
sequential setting
and i've used jasmine certified compiler
to carry these guarantees all the way
down to assembly
in our work we extend jasmine's support
for verifying the big four
by inserting our speculative analyses
into the compilation process
we also prove a key result called secure
forward consistency
that significantly simplifies our
analysis and it also carries functional
correctness and provable security
guarantees
establishing a sequential setting to the
spectrometer setting quite seamlessly
using our extensions to jasmine we
developed verified scalar
and avx-2 implementations of cha cha 20
and poly1305
which enjoy functional correctness an
extended memory safety property we call
speculative safety
and of course speculative constant time
we compare our verified implementations
with
unverified open ssl implementations
in our performance measurements we
report the cycles per byte
for processing messages of varying
lengths here lower is better
on the left we show the scalar cha cha
20 implementations and on the right we
showed the avx-2
charger implementations the purple lines
in both
are unverified open ssl implementations
the green lines are specter protected
jasmine implementations and the blue
lines are non-spectre protected jasmine
invitations
overall we find that our spectre
protected imputations come with only a
modest performance overhead
in terms of developer and verification
effort we found that
most of the effort was spent in fixing
speculative safety issues
after that there was relatively little
additional work for fixing speculative
time constant time issues
the functional equivalence proofs were
mostly automatic and as part of future
work we plan to
connect our implementations to provable
security guarantees thus completing the
big four
to conclude the key findings of our work
are that one we can lift existing
approaches for the big four to
speculative execution
second the performance overhead of
spectrum protections is relatively
modest
and in the future we hope to adapt our
general approach to other
microarchitectural side channels
if you're interested in learning more i
hope that you'll check out our paper and
i'll be happy to take any questions