hi
my name is lee icho a phd student from
imperial college london
i'm here to talk about high frequency
trading on decentralized enchanting
exchanges
this work is joined with kai fighting
christopher torres
dukley and other durbay
so why do we need a ducks there are
typically two types of actors
in an exchange namely the liquidity
provider
which is alice and the liquidity taker
which is bob
for traditional exchanges if alice and
bob wants to make a trade
they need to both trust a centralized
service provider
and this centralized entity executes the
trade on their behalf
this is how things would work if
everything goes as planned
but there are other possibilities for
example if the exchange is hacked
then these assets are lost
so how do we solve this problem
decentralized exchanges
or taxes allow different actors to
participate in financial markets
while returning full custody of their
funds
it relies on the underlying blockchain
to clear the trades
the price discovery and the trade
matching are encoded in smart contracts
the logic within the smart contract is
completely transparent
and anyone can check that the smart
contract is executed correctly
over the last year we have observed a
dramatic
increase in the trading volume of the
decentralized exchanges
as we can see in this slide the trading
volume increased
from under 1 billion us dollars to more
than 50 billion
within a single year this trading volume
is already significant
even when compared with the most
successful centralized exchanges
for example on april the 22nd the total
debt trading volume is already more than
seven percent of binance
and one point four percent of nasdaq so
given this
incredible high trading volume one major
question is
does high frequency trading work on
decentralized exchanges
and can the market be manipulated to
attack the traders
the answer is yes on blockchain-based
decentralized exchanges
transactions are executed by the miners
the traders however are typically not
directly connected with the miners
therefore in order to let the miners
know about their transactions
traders need to broadcast the
transactions over the public p2p network
the miners have a local transaction
pending queue
also known as the mampoo which stores
the transactions it receives
over the p2p network so once the
trader's transaction is received
it will be added into this manpool
every round a miner will be elected
which orders the transactions
and generate the next block since
permissionless blockchains are open
source
the default transaction ordering
strategy is known
to everyone ethereum miners for example
by default orders transactions based on
transaction fees paid per unit of
computation
the attacker can follow the same rules
and then place its own
transactions right before or right after
the victim's transaction
in more detail in order to manipulate
the transaction order
the attacker needs to connect to as many
nodes as possible
to gain speed advantage on the network
layer
this is because the spy node aims to
broadcast
its own transactions to the miners
before the victim's transaction is
executed
so the earlier the adversary detects the
transaction
the more time it has to react
for instance the attackers can perform
front-running
in the optimal scenario the adversary
detects the victim's transaction
before the miner even receives the
transaction
then the adversary issues a transaction
with a higher transaction fee price
and broadcasts both the victim's
transaction
and its own transaction on the p2p
network
the attacker can also perform background
in transaction and backgrounding attacks
in this scenario the optimal strategy is
to configure the same transaction
fee price then the adversary
sends the background in transaction
immediately after the victim transfer
victim's transaction to the miner
in this paper we focus on one specific
type
of aim of taxes called
automated market maker dex or amm
amm dax relies on smart contracts
um to prove to accumulate liquidities
there is the liquidity provider which is
alex
who provides both sfx and y into the
liquidity pool
and there is the liquidity taker who
sells asset x
plus fees to alice for sfy
so the idea is
to let a smart contract to do the market
making
the simplest amm mechanism is a constant
product market maker
which keeps the product x times y as a
constant
for a given asset pair this pricing
formula has
three properties firstly it offers
instant liquidity no matter how big or
how small the trade size is
secondly the smart contract
automatically adjusts the price
the purchase of asset x for example
will increase the price of x and
decrease the price for y
lastly the ratio of f x and y
is determined up determines the price
here we give a concrete example
in this plot the x-axis represents
the amount of asset x in the proof and
the y-axis
represents the amount of sfy in the pool
so the proof starts with 10 units of slx
and 30 units of asset y
the product is equal to 300
so let's say a taker wants to transact
five units of x
for asset y um
so the x axis will shift from 10 units
of asset
x to 15 and in order to keep the product
as a constant
the amount of asset y while in the
exchange will decrease
from 30 to 20. therefore the taker will
receive
10 units of sfy
as we have shown in the previous slide
when the liquidity taker
makes the trade the amm state of the
price
shifts along the bonding curve
expected price slippage is the expected
increase or decrease in price
based on the trading volume and
available liquidity
at the beginning of the trade
however there are other participants in
the market
due to concurrent transactions the
actual slippage can be
different from the expected slippage
here
for example let's assume transaction d
is executed before transaction c
because transaction d already shifted
the market
state downwards before transaction c is
executed
transaction c will have a worse
execution price
due to unexpected slippage
note that unexpected slippage can also
result in better prices
for example transaction d might be
trading in reverse direction
therefore transaction c will have a
better price than the
than the attack is under expectation
so in order to limit the impact of
unexpected slippage from concurrent
transactions
traders typically configure a slippage
protection threshold
which is slightly above the expected
slippage
therefore if transaction c goes beyond
the slippage protection threshold
as a result of transaction d then
transaction c will be reverted it will
not be executed
this slippage protection mechanism
however makes sandwich attacks possible
so the idea here is to manipulate the
market and
maximize the victims slippage
the adversary can emit two transactions
to exploit
the slippage protection before
transaction v
is confirmed so as an example let's say
the victim
issues a transaction to swap asset x to
y
the adversary then issues two
transactions a1 and a2
for the first transaction a1 the
adversary front runs the victim
and it also swaps asset x y
if everything goes as expected then the
victim's transaction
the slippage of the victim's transaction
will be maximized
but the slippage protection will not be
triggered the adversary
in the second transaction backgrounds
the victim by
transacting asset y to sx
so transaction a1 and a2 then forms a
profitable arbitrage
okay so let's go through the whole
process again
in the first step the victim sends a
transaction tv
on the p2p network through a lightweight
node or full node
recall that the trader needs to
broadcast this transaction on the p2p
network
so each node on the p2p network can
observe the slippage protect the
slippage protection settings
the adversary needs to operate a spy
node which connects to as many nodes as
possible
to detect the victim's transaction
before the miner
executes the transaction the adversary
then
determines if the victim's transaction
is profitable
if it is profitable then it will issue
two transactions a1 and a2 on p2p
network
if everything goes as planned the miner
will
receive transaction a1 and a2 before the
confirmation of transaction b
and then executes them in the exact
order the
third the adversary wants so it will
execute a1 first
engine b and then a2 as a result the
victim suffers
a much worse slippage and then
the adversary gets revenue from the
arbitrage
performed by transaction a1 and a2
on this slide we show the analytical
evaluation of sandwich attacks
on a specific market state we assume the
victim transacts easy to sign
sai is just some cryptocurrency asset on
the access
axis we show that the amount of ether
transacted by the victim
on the y-axis will show the amount of
ether transacted by the adversary
in transaction a1 if the victim
transacts 40e cell psi
at a slippage protection of 0.5 percent
this line here then the optimal strategy
for the adversary is to transact
18.5 years in the first transaction
this attack will realize a profit of
0.08 ec
which is equivalent to 11 usd
at the time of writing so here is the
important takeaway from this figure
we can observe that there is a threshold
here the white area
where if the victim's transaction size
is below this
threshold then the sandwich attack is
not profitable
no matter how much easier the adversary
transacts
intuitively this is because the revenue
of the adversary gains
could not cover the cost of the attack
we call this threshold the minimum
profitable victim input
or mvi this threshold can be numeric
numerically derived for any market
states
so here comes the one of the mitigation
mechanisms
we proposed in the paper for sandwich
attacks we can disable transactions
above the mvi if the liquidity taker
wants to make a big trade
for example 122 is 123 ether
then hey needs to split the transaction
into smaller ones
in this case five smaller trades
this is by the way this is a very nice
website that the other researchers
developed to help traders to divide the
transactions
you can find the link of the website
here
one of the disadvantages of dividing
transactions
is the trader will need to pay higher
transaction fees
for each of the transaction so
there are also other mitigation
mechanisms which we have discussed in
the appendix of the paper
another interesting question is what
will happen when there are multiple
trader multiple sandwich attackers with
simulated outcome
and our results suggest that having
multiple attackers
does divide the total revenue among the
adversaries in
expectation all the attackers also need
to create higher transaction fees
uh overhead uh note that if the
blockchain is congested
then we observe that the break-even is
harder to attain
we also found another sandwich attack
pattern
in the paper which we will not go into
details but the adversary acts as a
provider
instead of acting as a paper in this
case
so in summary the transparency of
blockchain-based exchanges in
combination with the latency for
transactions to be processed
makes marketing manipulation visible
thanks for
listening to our presentation
you