hi everyone on site knowledgefire this
is the presentation for our work is
private learning possible with instance
encoding
i'll do the first half of the talk and
then florian will continue with the
second half
the process of machine learning starts
with a training set that is labeled
according to some concept function c
and the goal of the learning algorithm
is to look at this training set
and find a good approximation of that
concept function
so this process can leak some
information about the training set used
and the
study of privacy preserving machine
learning aims at finding
private algorithms that can minimize
such leakage
instance encoding is one specific idea
that could be used for
uh achieving privacy preserving uh
machine learning
where we have an additional encoding
step added to machine learning pipeline
so before applying the learning
algorithm we first encode the training
set
into this intermediate object that we
expect to be private
by achieving some notion of privacy for
example we might
want the encodings to be non invertible
or we might require the encodings to
have some stronger indistinguishability
guarantees
but in both types of definitions no
matter how we define privacy
the learning algorithm here is expected
to just learn by looking
at the encodings
why would this be nice so such an
encoding could be really useful to
achieve
two types of privacy at once that are
both proven to be very
challenging to achieve so it can achieve
private computation
because these encodings are supposed to
not reveal information about the inputs
and
the computation could still be done on
top of them so this means in the
multi-party learning scenarios that
privacy is
important such as healthcare the
the data set owners can just reveal or
share the encodings of the data without
worrying about
extra privacy leakage
it can also provide private outcome like
what we have in differential privacy
this is again because the algorithm is
done is is being applied on top of the
encoded data
and no matter what the algorithm does
and what the output of the algorithm
is the final output will be at least
as private as the encodings and
everything will boil down to just
analyzing the privacy of the code
so if we have such a private encoding
these two types of privacy will be
obtained immediately
one instantiation of such instance
encoding mechanism
is insta hi that was introduced in last
year icl
so inside propose a way for achieving
privacy
without sacrificing accuracy or
efficiency and they actually win
a beloved's price for their contribution
however they act their privacy of their
skin is not
well understood yet so in this world
one of our goals was to first understand
how private this
instahyde algorithm is and we also
wanted to have a more general treatment
of this
privacy to true instance encoding idea
so for first question you provide an
attack that breaks the challenge data
set that the instahype authors provide
and florian will talk more about this
challenge but here i'm gonna
give you a high-level idea of how our
attack works
but before that let me give you a
summary of the instahyde's
encoding algorithm so this algorithm has
access to two datasets
one private dataset that is a labeled
dataset as a source of learning
and there is also a public dataset that
is not labeled and we don't
care about its privacy and it's only
there to help the encoder
so how is the encoding done so first the
encoding algorithm
samples a bunch of images from the
public and private data set and combines
them linearly together to get this
combination
and after that there is this masking
layer where
each pixel in this image has its sign
flipped with a random randomly with
probability half
so after that we get this image that
doesn't look like anything to human
but if you gather enough of them and
feed that to a learning algorithm
it still is able to learn a good
classifier out of these encodings which
is surprising on its own
now how do we attach these encodings
so we have this challenge dataset that
is a bunch of encodings and we are
supposed to
invert them to the original images that
were used to produce them
so the first step of attack is the
clustering step
where the goal is to match these
encodings together based on which is
which image they are encoding so we
train a neural network to do this
clustering for us
and after that we have this recovery
step where we use the
the cluster information to come up with
the image corresponding to each cluster
after these two steps we can actually
get a very good recovery of the images
i'm not going to elaborate more of about
the deals of these steps but i suggest
you to have a look at the paper for that
but here is a a sample of uh
what our attack they are so the
extracted images that you see here are
very close to the original images that
were used to encode the
uh challenged interest in the instant
challenge so this shows that instahyde
is not as private as first stop
and we basically have a complete break
of their challenge
additional to our attack against
instahart we also have some theoretical
results showing some barriers against
achieving
privacy through instance encoding
as we want to prove theorems here we
have to work with formal definitions of
privacy for instance encoding and
instahype doesn't come with any formal
definition
so we had to define our own so we have
this protocol
with encoding and we also have a fixed
concept function
for example you can think of the dog
versus cat concept function
and we define a security game for this
setting
so in our security game the first step
the adversary selects two
instances that are labeled the same
according to the constant function
so for example it should be either two
dark photos or two platforms
and then the challenger will encode one
of these two images
or instances and sends it to the
adversary and now the adversary has to
decide which one of the
images will use to come up with this
encoding
so the advantage of the adversary here
is the probability
of guessing correctly which image was
encoded
note that here we are forcing the
adversary to submit two images with the
same label because we don't want
the advantage to increase by leveraging
the
label information that exists in the
encodings
now that we have our privacy definition
we can ask this question
can we achieve privacy and accuracy
together using instance and code
it's important that we want to achieve
them together because achieving privacy
alone is not a hard task
but there are two ways that we can
define accuracy here
the first way is by defining accuracy on
top of the encoded data
so in this setting we have our first
barrier that says that if a learning
protocol with encoding can achieve
accuracy half plus
epsilon on two uh for two different
concept functions
then there is a polynomial time
adversary that can break the security
gain
for both of c1 c2 with advantage half
plus omega
epsilon so the key idea here is that
if the algorithm uh is going to achieve
high accuracy on the encoded data
this means that the encodings should
have information about both c1 and c2
uh in there so this means the adversary
can actually
use the information about one of the
concepts to break the security game for
the other one
so this idea only works if we define
accuracy on encoded data
so we have another theorem about the
case that you define accuracy on
original data
so in this setting we have a very
similar theorem
but with the difference that our
advantage here
depends on the sample complexity so the
advantage of adversaries here is
half plus one over n where n is the
number of examples in the training
so this is a slightly worse than the
previous bound but the still sufficient
to prove
impossibility of achieving cryptographic
levels of privacy for instance encoding
together with accuracy
so that was the first part of the talk
i'll leave the rest to florian
for the second part of this talk we'll
look a bit more closely at the insta
hype challenge that was released by the
offers
releasing security challenge is not
uncommon in machine learning security
these days
i will now discuss some of the goals
that we should strive for when designing
security challenges and the role they
should play in
arguing security of the system the main
message i want you to take away here is
that a security channel should never be
used as a substitute for a formal
security claim
in fact when we design a secure system
the very first thing we should do is to
provide a falsifiable claim of the
security goals that the system is meant
to achieve
within a formally defined threat model
this is the single most important step
if we want to treat security as a
scientific discipline
after that it's of course great if we
can prove something about the security
claims
but that isn't always feasible and
that's okay instead of a formal proof or
maybe in addition to one
we can also publish a challenge to
invite the community to try and attack
our system
and such a challenge should be designed
to capture a necessary condition for the
system's security
so that if someone solves a challenge
this implies that the system is insecure
the converse is not always true usually
the failure to solve a challenge is not
enough to convince us of a system
security
let's look at a specific example that
everyone's probably familiar with rsa
encryption
today we have strong formal security
claims for rsa
for example that it is indistinguishable
under chosen ciphertext attacks with
proper padding
but note that this security claim cannot
be directly captured by a static
challenge because it involves multiple
rounds of interaction between an
adversary and victim
but stating challenges are still very
useful to measure and drive research
progress
for example two decades ago rsa
published a suite of factoring
challenges
and these challenges satisfy our earlier
stated goal and that solving them
indeed would falsify rsa's formal
security guarantees
but we don't know if the converse is
true it might be possible to break rsa
in other ways than the factory
while such challenges can be useful it's
also very well accepted within the
crypto community that a static challenge
is in itself not sufficient
as a measure of security even if the
challenge is hard to solve
because by that metric the cipher used
by the zodiac killer could even be
considered secure
since it took over 50 years to crack it
but it definitely isn't considered
secure according to any modern notion of
cryptographic security
so let's now talk about the instant
height challenge which was released to
test the security
of the instahyde protocol this challenge
consists of 100 images that were each
encoded 50 times using some undisclosed
public dataset
and to solve the challenge we have to
reconstruct the close approximation of
these 100 private images
we use the attack that they presented
earlier to solve this challenge and we
cover
all the private images so according to
the goal we stated earlier for a
security challenge
this should mean that our attack
invalidates instahid security claims
right
it turns out that no attack can actually
do that because the insta hype protocol
does not come with any formal and
falsifiable security claims
all we have is this challenge and this
is a major problem because in the
absence of the formal security model
the only thing we're left with is the
threat model that the challenge
implicitly defines
namely that an attacker gets access to
50 encodings and has to recover the
private images
but this threat model is a bit
simplistic and to make things worse
there are actually ways in which the
challenge makes the attacker's job both
easier
and harder than in an actual deployment
of instaheim
for example a real adversary would
probably have some prior knowledge about
the type of data that is being encoded
and what public dataset is being used
the adversary might also be able to
actively participate in the protocol
and aim for a slightly weaker goal than
full reconstruction
the challenge doesn't allow for these
things and so in this sense solving the
challenge is
harder than breaking the instahype
protocol which is fine
the bigger issue is that the challenge
also makes some things too easy for the
attacker
such as giving direct access to many
encoded inputs computed over a small
data set
and our main attack on the challenge
obviously exploits all of these
capabilities
but this also means that whether the
challenge gets solved or not cannot
conclusively tell us anything about
insta height security
in a different threat model for example
we also consider a slightly different
threat model in our paper
where the adversary does have some
auxiliary knowledge on the data that
instahype protects and in particular we
assume the adversary has
access to the public data set and under
these assumptions we give a very
efficient attack that scales linearly
with the size of the encoded data
and can recover a private image given a
single encoding
in many ways this attack might be more
realistic than the one we use to solve
the challenge
but this attack fails to solve the
challenge because it operates in a
different thread model
so this brings us back to our main
takeaway here that a challenge is really
not a substitute for
formal security claims in a well-defined
threat model of course
this doesn't mean things would have been
better if instahyde hadn't come with a
challenge
publishing a well-designed challenge is
always a good thing but we
always first need formal security
definitions and security claims to base
the challenge on
taking a step back i'll conclude the
talk by noting that many of the issues
that are work raised for instance
encoding schemes are not uncommon in the
broader space of machine learning
security today
and that there are many systems that are
being designed and proposed for various
security properties of machine learning
but these properties are often not
defined very formally
but rather expressed as informal
desiderata about the costs of successful
attacks
and in turn the evaluations of these
systems are also often
incomplete and typically limited to
testing that prior attacks fail
i think that these problems are exactly
what people in this audience are
uniquely qualified to tackle
if you like attacks that's good news for
you because there's currently way more
new systems being proposed here that can
be rigorously evaluated
and if you like formal security and
coming up with nice definitions and
threat models
there is also a huge amount of cool work
to be done in this area
towards the goal of a much more rigorous
and formally grounded approach to
machine learning security
thank you