hello everyone welcome to my
presentation
i am jason chad from kaist in this talk
i will present
nt files which enables type aware kernel
fuzzing on windows
by using static binary analysis this
is a joint work with my colleagues kansu
kim and dezin li
and my advisor sankir chang
in modern operating systems a user
application does not directly access
hardware resources
instead it makes a request to kernel by
invoking a system call
or cisco insured then the corner code
runs in a privileged mode
to solve the request and interact with
the hardware
now let's think about what would happen
if there is a security bug
in such a privileged corner code
at the very least a malicious attacker
can incur
denial of service by making the kernel
to crash
in the worst case the attacker can
escalate one's
privilege and take over the whole system
because of their security impacts
microsoft and apple
are respectfully offering bounties up to
thirty thousand
and fifteen thousand dollars for colonel
docks
this highlights the importance of kernel
security
therefore there has been a growing
research interest on finding colonel
bugs
there are various methodologies for
finding bugs but in this talk i will
focus on fuzzing
which is a popular technique due to its
simplicity and effectiveness
as i previously mentioned system call is
the primary interface between the user
and the column
therefore kernel photos naturally target
cisco interface
they generate a massive amount of system
course while randomly mutating their
arguments
recently there has been a series of
remarkable researches on cisco fuzzing
however note that most of these fossils
are for linux
which is an open source operating system
in open source oss
cisco type information is publicly known
therefore photos can utilize such type
information
to provide appropriate arguments to
cisco's
many previous studies show that
diverging type information
in cisco fuzzing is indeed crucial for
efficiency
but the problem is how can you first
system course in a closed source os like
windows
this is the research problem that our
paper addresses
first let's take a look at previous
files for closed source oss
in fact most of them targeted a specific
subset of cisco interfaces
first fossils often target publicly
known ciscos
even for cross-source oss certain cisco
interfaces
like ioctr are publicly documented
therefore fossils like imf and ioctr
fossil
target such known ciscos to find bugs
however this limits the generality of
cisco fuzzy
second fossils can rely on manually
written hardness code
in other words a security expert needs
to reverse engineer os code
to figure out how to provide arguments
to a specific
target cisco then the expert should
manually write a harness code which
repeatedly calls the target cisco
with mutated arguments for example
kafl takes this kind of approach
however considering the fact that
windows has more than a thousand of
system cores
such a manual approach is not scalable
our goal is to enable general and
automated cisco fuzzing in windows
in other words we do not target a
specific cisco
but target general system interfaces
also we want our system to run without
harness code
to enable automated cisco fuzzing
to achieve this goal we bridge the
information gap
between the known interface and unknown
interface
by using static analysis
to further explain this idea let's take
a closer look at how user level code
interacts with kernel
normally user applications do not invoke
system codes directly
instead they call documented api
functions provided in the system
libraries
then the api function passes through a
chain of internal functions
and reaches the final functions whereas
score is actually invoked
our key idea is to analyze this function
called chain
by tracing data flows from the
documented apis
to undocumented ciscos we can figure out
which values are passed as cisco
arguments and what they look like
in other words we can infer the types of
z-score arguments
by statically analyzing system library
files
in this talk we will call these library
files as
system binaries note that we can infer
the type of any cisco
invoked from this system binaries so
our approach can target a broad range of
ciscos
also the static analysis process is
automatic
and does not require manual effort
with this idea we design and implement
anti-fast
that enables type aware cisco fusing on
windows
first nt-first takes in system binaries
as
input it analyzes these binaries
and obtains type information about
ciscos
then the forcing module takes in this
type information
together with a set application in order
to perform
mutational fuzzing on cisco payload as a
final result
anti-force outputs are set of corner
blocks
however analyzing system binaries is
challenging
due to their large scale from now on
we will take a closer look at how our
static analysis operates
and deals with this challenge
let's start by considering a real-world
block found by anti-foss
the code is simplified for ease of
explanation
the vulnerable score takes in a
structural pointer as argument
and processes its two fields length and
buffer
note that a system call must sanitize
the inputs
to make sure not to access invalid
memory space
therefore this function checks whether
the length field
is unexpectedly set to an odd number
and whether the buffer points to an
invalid memory range
the problem is that the log error
function at line 5
does not raise an exception or above so
it will continue the execution to line
10 because
the two checks are combined with errors
if closed
at line seven as a result
we can make the corner to access
arbitrary memory and crash
by providing an odd number as rank field
the first point i want to emphasize
is that it is important to recognize the
cisco argument type
if we blindly generate the argument of
this cisco
without considering its type it is
unlikely that the generated value
points to a structure that we desire
another notable point is that system
calls are often related to api functions
for example actually there was a user
level windows api
that internally invokes this system code
therefore we can infer the cisco type by
analyzing
api implementation in the system
binaries
unfortunately there are several
challenges that make this analysis
difficult
first note that our analysis actually
runs in binary level
and it must be able to trace memory
states in addition to resistor values
therefore tools that focus only on cfg
construction
like ida cannot be used for our purpose
moreover note that the previous code was
significantly simplified
and in real binaries data flows often
involve
a chain of function calls for example
this api can call functions to update
memory
or it can pass its data to another
function that internally invokes the
cisco
this means we have to trace data flows
across the function boundaries
and perform an inter-procedural analysis
of course such inter-procedural analysis
is not theoretically impossible
but the real problem is in the large
scale of windows system binaries
even though we carefully examined and
selected a core set of system binaries
we still have to analyze more than 12
of functions that are interconnected to
each other to the best of our knowledge
there is no existing binary analysis
tool that can perform
inter-procedural analysis at this scale
so how can we design such a scalable
inter-procedural analysis
to achieve the scalability we use
modular analysis
let's consider this simplified chord
graph where top level functions
represent documented api functions and
bottom level functions represent the
stop functions
where cisco is invoked
let me first introduce the traditional
global analysis
in global analysis we start from the
root node of the core graph
and transitively follow the functions
called by this node
naturally we have to visit and analyze
the same function for
multiple times for example in the case
of f5
in contrast modular analysis starts from
the lyft nodes of the core graph
we analyze each function and compute a
parameterized summary of the function
that can be concretized later then
when we analyze the colors of the
already visited functions
we reuse these summaries instead of
analyzing the queries again
therefore modular analysis can avoid
repetitive computation
but this comes at the price of
sacrificing soundness
for example it cannot soundly summarize
functions
when there is a cycle in the core graph
however note that our purpose is not in
verifying programs
but in finding practical type
information to assist
fuzzing therefore our analysis does not
have to be fully sound
in the evaluation we could confirm that
our analysis can collect
meaningful type information even though
it sacrifices
soundness in certain points
modular analysis itself is not a novel
idea
but applying it at a binary level is
challenging
due to the time limitation i will not
discuss all the details in this talk
so please refer to our paper for more
details about
our novel analysis design and how it
enables
modular analysis on binary code
so far i have described the static
analysis module of ndfas
now i will briefly introduce the fuzzing
module
which reverses the cisco type
information obtained from our static
analyzer
we use hooking-based fuzzing to first
windows kernel with the type information
we obtained
we first launched a set application to
spawn a sequence of well-formed ciscos
then we intercept these ciscos and
perform a type of verimutation
by utilizing the provided type
information
for example on pointer type arguments we
have to traverse into their content
and perform mutation recursively
now i will present the evaluation result
of anti-fast
in this talk i will focus on two
research questions
first we evaluate the impact of type
awareness on fuzzy
second we evaluate how effective is
antifas
in finding previously unknown kernel box
and you can find more experiment results
in the paper if you're interested
to evaluate the impact of type awareness
we used windows 10 released in april
which has more number of confirmed bugs
than the latest version
to see if antifas can find previously
unknown box
we used windows 10 released in january
which was the latest version at the time
of our research
we used eight zip applications for
hooking based fuzzing
and run anti-phos for 48 hours
on each application first we compared
the number of found crashes
with and without type information the
graph shows the number of total and
unique crashes
found over time we repeated the
experiment for five times
and plot the average here we could
confirm that ndfas finds
1.7 times more unique crashes when it
utilized
type information obtained from the
static analysis
next we evaluate the effectiveness of
anti-fast
in the latest windows 10 and compile and
device against other tools
we examined many corner fossils
available for windows
but in the end we could compare
anti-fast against md core
and iota fossil only we manually
classified the found crashes
into unique bugs and counted their
number
when we repeated the experiment for five
times nti first found about
eight unique bugs in average and
outperform other tools
when we collected all the bugs found
during this experiment
antifas found 11 bugs from the latest
windows tab
and 4 of the bugs were assigned cves
moreover these cvs were rewarded with 25
000 dollars of bounties in total due to
their critical security impacts
this highlights the practical impact of
ndfas on real world
we believe there are several promising
directions for future work
first we can integrate the cisco type
information
with generational or coverage based
fuzzing as well
also we can extend our static analysis
to support more complex types
like union lastly in this work we only
analyze user level code
but we can further complement the type
information
by analyzing kernel code as well
to support open science we will release
the source code of ntfos
on github in july if you're interested
please click the stars and watch our
repository for the updates
this is the end of my talk and thank you
for listening