Hello everyone.
I’m Gertjan, I’m a PhD student at DistriNet
at the University of Leuven.
And today, I’m gonna present our paper “Reading
Between the Lines: An Extensive Evaluation
of the Security and Privacy Implications of
EPUB Reading Systems”
But before we get too technical, let me first
give you some context.
Nowadays, almost any book is not only published
in a physical format, but also in a digital
format, so-called e-books.
And since their introduction, e-books have
grown into a multi-billion dollar market.
This, in turn, gave rise to a lot of e-book
formats, each one defining their own architecture.
Now, most of these formats are proprietary. For example,
owned by a publishing company.
Luckily, in an attempt to promote consensus,
an open e-book format was introduced, as what
is now known as the EPUB technical standard.
Since then EPUB has become very popular, as
now it is one of the most widely supported
e-book formats across devices.
Now let’s have a look at the specification.
Here, I’d like to focus on two main parts,
being the architecture of EPUB files and the
way applications are supposed to render EPUBs.
These applications are called EPUB reading
systems.
The specification describes an EPUB as a ZIP
archive with an internal predefined structure.
This ZIP archive contains all the necessary
information to represent the e-book.
Most importantly: the actual text and imagery included
by the author.
But how is this content represented?
Well, EPUBs primarily consist of XHTML documents,
CSS stylesheets and possibly even JavaScript
code, making EPUBs bear close resemblance
to actual websites.
As for EPUB reading systems, these will render
EPUBs according to the specification.
And why reinvent the wheel here?
For this, EPUB reading systems rely on web
engines, the same components that are used
by web browsers.
And like browsers grant certain capabilities
to loaded web pages, EPUB reading systems
grant certain capabilities to loaded EPUBs.
This brings us to our research questions.
The first question is: what is the state of
freely available EPUB reading systems, on
one hand in terms of capabilities granted
to loaded EPUBs and on the other hand in the
context of upheld security considerations.
Or, simply put, what is an EPUB allowed to
do on the user’s device?
This ecosystem has never been subjected to
a thorough evaluation,
and according to us, this is paramount for providing
the user with more transparency, also taking
into account the rather lenient security considerations
described in the EPUB specification.
For the second question, we focus on the EPUBs
that are being distributed online; are the
identified capabilities already being abused
in the wild.
Here, we consider two threat models.
Can we find find malicious EPUBs that abuse
capabilities to harm, for example an attacker
who tries to hack a user’s device.
And can we find EPUBs that abuse capabilities
to track, for example a publisher who’d
like to know more about the user’s reading
interests.
To answer the first question, we collected
92 of the most popular free reading systems
across 7 different platforms, and additionally
5 physical e-readers.
As a side-note: Amazon reading systems do
not support EPUBs but here we used a conversion
tool to convert the EPUBs to a compatible
format.
When you are to evaluate such a large collection
of applications, you better automate it, right?
So this is what we did as much as possible,
however, crippled by the large variety of different
user interfaces.
To this end, developed a semi-automated testbed
which performs a blackbox evaluation, as shown
on the diagram.
Our crafted EPUBs are embedded with experiments
that probe for certain attack primitives.
When loaded, these experiments would execute
and instruct the EPUB reading system to display
the result, or if allowed by the reading system,
send the result to our local server.
The outcome is then stored for later analysis.
In total, we performed 8 different experiments.
I’ll give a general overview of those experiments,
but for more details I refer to our paper.
First, we checked whether embedded JavaScript
is executed, a rather straightforward experiment.
Then, we inferred whether the EPUB is allowed
to communicate with remote servers, for which
we used a comprehensive collection of mechanisms.
We also checked whether the reading system
requires user consent, which is recommended
by the specification.
The remainder of experiments require JavaScript,
and were only performed for reading systems
which execute embedded JavaScript.
In the third experiment, we investigated whether
the EPUB is granted reading access to the
local file system.
More specifically, can it infer whether a
certain file is present on the file system,
for example through timing attacks? And can
it actually read the contents of this file?
We also evaluated whether the EPUB can store
data, leveraging inherited web engine functionalities
like cookies or the local storage API, and
whether this data persists between reading sessions.
This could be used for tracking purposes.
As you already might know, nowadays web pages
can request the user for access to features
like the device’s microphone, webcam or
even location.
In this experiment, we checked whether this
functionality was inherited from the embedded web engine.
If the reading system supports URI handles,
this can be abused for example to initiate
a phone call, send an e-mail, or download a file.
Here, we tried to open applications leveraging
various handles.
For each reading system, we identified the
embedded web engine, leveraging a web engine
fingerprinting technique.
This way, we checked whether this web engine
was outdated and vulnerable.
And lastly, for smartphones, we also checked
whether the scripts embedded in the EPUB were
able to keep running, even after the user
switched focus to another app.
This could increase the time window for a
potential attack.
OK, let’s move on to the actual results.
Again, I’ll give a general overview of the
most interesting results.
For more details, I refer to our paper.
As is displayed here in this table, almost
half of the evaluated reading systems execute
embedded JavaScript.
This number is the smallest for browser extensions
and e-readers.
With the former, in 7 cases inline scripts
were blocked by an active Content Security Policy.
With the latter, we suspect the engine is
configured not to execute any embedded JavaScript.
Also about half of the reading systems allowed
remote communication, of which only one required user consent.
This means that almost half of the reading
systems are not compliant with the EPUB specification’s security considerations.
Again, the next experiments were only performed
for the reading systems which allow JavaScript execution.
In 16 of those reading systems, a loaded EPUB could
infer the existence of a certain file on the
local file system, and in 8 of those reading systemts it could
also read and thus leak the contents of this file.
Interesting here is that none of the iOS applications
was susceptible to this vulnerability due
to iOS’s strict permission model.
Here, none of the applications requested access
to the file system as a whole, only permission
was requested for the actual EPUB file to
be opened.
Furthermore, for the browser extensions, the
enforced Same-Origin Policy prevented access to local files.
And also interesting: 21 reading systems provide
the means for persistent storage between reading sessions,
which can be leveraged to enable
tracking.
Although the results of our semi-automated
analysis provide a comprehensive picture of
the state of free EPUB reading systems, we
argue that the exposed issues only pose as
a lower bound.
Our framework considers each reading system
as a black box, and performs the same experiments,
essentially pushing the same buttons on each
try.
Most attackers are much more inventive than
this, they examine the application for weaknesses
in order to exploit them.
To demonstrate that this strategy would expose
more issues, we performed a case study on
the most popular reading systems on three
different platforms by manual analysis.
On desktop, this is Apple Books, which comes
pre-installed on MacOS.
Here, we discovered that a symbolic link could
be abused to leak user information or to launch
a persistant Denial of Service attack against
the application.
The second case study involves the EPUBReader
extension for both Chrome and Firefox.
This extension required the  permission,
which allows the extension to read responses,
from any website.
By circumventing the Content Security Policy,
we were able to execute our embedded scripts,
which led to a universal cross-site scripting
attack.
And lastly, by reverse-engineering the Amazon
Kindle, the most popular e-reader, we exposed
an input validation issue which enabled otherwise
disabled JavaScript execution.
Because the embedded web engine is an outdated
WebKit version with publicly disclosed vulnerabilities,
we could exploit one of those to leak the
entire library of the user.
Now that we have an idea of the general state of
EPUB reading systems, let’s have a look
at EPUBs in the wild, our second research
question.
Users generally obtain e-books in two distinct ways;
either through legal channels such as online book stores,
or through illegal channels such as
file sharing platforms.
To evaluate the latter ecosystem we downloaded
a total of 9.000 EPUBs from The Pirate Bay and 4shared.
To check whether any of them were malicious,
we parsed the contents for suspicious elements
such as scripts or references to local files.
This way, we discovered that less than 1%
actually embedded scripts, of which all were benign.
No abuse was detected whatsoever.
As for the legal channels, we downloaded several
free e-books from 5 popular e-book stores.
Again, after manual analysis, we did not find
any indications for tracking, nor malicious intent.
However, to find out whether it would be feasible
to publish a malicious e-book through official
e-book vendors, we also assessed the self-publishing
ecosystem.
Most vendors nowadays provide a self-publishing service,
which can be used
by smaller writers to publish digital books
without the interposition of a publisher.
Since the manuscript is provided by an untrusted
party, being the writer, it would be good
practice to sanitize before publication.
We evaluated this sanitization process by
submitting our own manuscript to the six most
popular and free self-publishing services.
We checked whether any of our included primitives
were removed from the published version.
This way, we found that out of the 6 self-publishing
services 4 do not sufficiently sanitize submitted
manuscripts before publication, and can be
abused to effectively distribute malicious e-books.
This accounts for 94% of the market share
of sold e-books.
OK, we’ve come to the end of my presentation,
but allow me to recap in a few takeaways.
First, our evaluation demonstrates that almost none
of the JavaScript-supporting reading systems
adhere to the security considerations.
We exposed various flaws, such as for example
file system isolation issues in 16 reading systems.
In total, we contacted the developers of 37 reading systems
as part of our responsible disclosure.
We’re very pleased that, as a result, the
reported issues have been fixed in various
widely-used reading systems such as Apple
Books and the Amazon Kindle.
As a more long-term solution, we propose to
revise the EPUB specification.
Foremost, we urge to make the security considerations
more strict.
For example, the enforcement of the Same-Origin
Policy should be an obligation instead of
a consideration, to safeguard millions of
users.
Furthermore, we argue that the inclusion of
practical developer guidelines for embedding
web engines would greatly benefit the overall
security.
This could prevent the misconfiguration of
important security policies and the unintentional
inheritance of potentially dangerous web engine
functionalities.
Moreover, the specification allows for several
questionable capabilities such as JavaScript
execution and local and remote file access.
Based on our real-world analysis, we argue
that prohibiting these capabilities would
have a minimal usability impact, since adoption
is rare and all EPUBs analyzed in our real-world
study would remain functional.
Fortunately, we did not find any indication
of abuse in the wild, as of yet.
However, we demonstrated that this is very
much possible, even through legal channels.
Then lastly, we have open-sourced the semi-automated
evaluation testbed.
This way, we hope to assist developers in
developing secure reading systems,
but also to provide a level of transparency to end-users.
We intend to maintain this project and welcome
any new contributions.
With this, I conclude my presentation and
I thank you for your interest in our research.