Akim Boy He's back
[Applause]
[Music]
Hello everyone
Thanks for being here
I'm I wanted to see you I wanted to
come back Excuse me you know
I'm excited I have an easy tear
[Applause]
Two and a half years have passed November
2019 We were here  then it came I'm
[ __ ] covid
But actually when we came here
on Thursday to prepare the room for
yesterday's event the television business
that went very well actually after
10 minutes It was as if this time not
this hiding there had not been  and therefore I
am still happy this morning too It
was great to see you again I have yet to
finish hugging a lot of
people But we try to eh
to stay on time In short, to respect
the times
then
as you well know for almost 8 years
This is the Onlus that we support
are  in the Democratic Republic of the Congo
in Kinshasa they have the banquet outside and
all the donations of the event go to
them because they do real concrete things and
therefore it is right  to because as I always say
we are fine We are healthy
we are lucky we are here we have
a little less fun and the updated numbers
I do not remember them but they
should keep up with 320 children
who are not few so if you want to
donate your 5x1000 and this  it is the
tax code however out there are
all the flyers all the information
thanks to our main sponsors as
you
can see there are a lot of new companies there
are a lot of confirmations
thank you very much for the trust and
I also put myself in their shoes eh many
companies did not know me did not
know the event it is not easy to
sponsor an event of this type
that does not allow you to have
the sponsor's banquet to advertise
in a certain way and to have
speakers who are not connected to the
sponsor companies for  at least in a
direct way and also to be back in attendance after
two and a half years
It was certainly not easy so I
thank you
as Obviously ringra  uncle also our
sponsors goals also here you can see there
are a lot of news a lot of a
lot of confirmations and therefore thanks
to
them our Silver sponsors too there
are a lot of news a lot of
companies
that are with us Sorry  I turn off the radio
that I have been with us for a while However, there
are practically all the representatives
of the sponsoring companies are here
today our friends partners
I humbly apologize
to friends events so Ramacca
Novate of Bergamo and many others
it was a terrible time in the
last  5 months from the stress point of view
for so many personal
health things that some of you know
unfortunately I can't do everything I
'm not a robot as much as I can
commit myself to write everything down I
forgot to enter them So
I apologize Guys but  they are
present here so it is nice that the
community that the events In short, one
goes to the other, we help each other In short, it is
nice to continue to be a community for  Because
it is also nice to be in various areas
of Italy during the year because it is always
nice to go to events when I go
to the other 20 I have fun I rest a
little But it's really nice because
in short Uhm we see many friends again
so there are  they too obviously
Then this is some news out
you will find these associations the
Cyber strategy guys do free
entorship sessions if yo
frame the QR Code you can book
mentorship session obvio
sly all free with them who have
he table outside they are 7
so they have
a slightly more reserved area there are the chairs You
can sit down and you can have a
little chat with them There is
an improvement association for those
who can help you activate the spid and
there is another association
very important against bullying there
are also them out they have a lot of
flyers a lot of interesting things
from
da Somma to show you before I
forget  who If you see a little news
we have always had the
big counter with the speaker seated I said
go let's try to do as the
serious conferences do that have only Lectern and
speaker that goes up so in this
edition let's try to see how
this formula goes
obviously  thanks to them that first of
all they are friends and then they were or
sponsor speakers they gave me a hand
with for Paper a lot
of proposals arrived and
they helped me to choose We hope
you like today's talks and Ah
a '  another thing before I forget and
Stefano and Cristoforo had a
little problem they will arrive a little
later so now the speakers
will be two less than the
program.
second
edition of akibo business and on Saturday 3rd
the nineteenth edition of kingmbo Ah
by the way I don't remember which
chat I read it on no anz  i no Maybe it was
Maurizio who told me Cazzarola Mario
But whoever you invoke has come of age 18
editions because today at the eighteenth
edition I roar and then we
applaud Kimbo who has
come of age
[Applause]
the cruise has remained in my heart it has
remained there  in the heart Why do you keep
writing to me all the time I am
honored to stratospheric levels but the
covid
the organization is not exactly simple the
permits that the port requires
anything else do not allow me to do it at
least
a year I do not know but I promise you that we will do
it again  cruise
2023 akinbo is 10 years old
Oh well I just said 18 has become 18
years of age anyway
First event September 2013
and this too I, as usual, I
promise you that I will put all the possible effort into
all the staff who are wonderful
Indeed we applaud the staff  for
today for yesterday
because they are fundamental Thanks to all
guys If they weren't there as
I always say I could  I would have a thousand
beautiful but unattainable ideas
this thing that you will now see this
little spoiler preview of the
announcement that we will do in December
will be a very big thing very
complex
I repeat I will do my best to
make this happen If I do not
succeed we will
surely postpone it  but it will not go into
oblivion and the spoiler is this here
I will not tell you anything else
it is not the tower of Pisa eh If anyone
should have any doubts it is another
type of Tower
[Applause]
obviously interested companies
can write us here the email is always
active
Marina How beautiful you are Marina the
daughter of Mattia epiphany Let's give a
round of applause to Marina and my children who
are also here in the front row.
sandwiches with fresh sliced mortadella and w
ll arrive staggered So anywa
there will be and therefore thanks to Luca
itali  also in
gluten-free version
and of course there is always the beer that has
now become the official beer of the
event since 2016 I have
n't had it yet I haven't drunk a little dry throat
eh
So it's time to activate  the
bracelets and brooches during
registration I asked
you if you were looking for a job now Do not
take, let's say these groups as how to
say they are the ones that, based on
past descriptions, group
a bit of everything that you
have requested in most but not  it means
that if you find a sponsor with
a green pin around you cannot still
chat, exchange information and
more so the bracelets
correspond to these groups the
sponsors have the Green pin
on the chest and a nice way to
interact during the event
a  important thing that I
always forget to say the email cv@kimbo.it is
always active where the sponsor companies
sometimes write to me asking Mario
you have this fig  ura and this other one, however,
you can send us updated curriculums
they only say courtesy in the object
Write me your
specialization directly because we go
so many that it is me then I
can not open 200 at a time and
go to sift through so remember
in the object to put  directly
your specialization so much the emails
that arrive there are only for the job search
ok
So take the phone
scan with telegram
look for the hakimbo bot thanks to
Massimo Massimiliano dal Cerro of
Digital difference that there is
optimized
here too there will be information on the
job search on the program In short,
read the instructions it is quite
simple if I did it, as I am not a computer
scientist, you should succeed
too and it will also help you a little
in managing the day an important thing is
the ticket that you have been
given the entrance ticket  cool as I
remind you it was completely offered by
Kimbo even yesterday  you have to keep it for the
whole stay in the park Because if
they ask you You don't have it you have to
pay the entrance and
the parking is not there so when
you can you want to go out go
directly
done a scanned let's
have fun These are the official hashtags
and I am  always very excited to
introduce Mattia Epifani and the speakers
of the eighteenth edition of akimbo
please guys
[Music]
[Applause]
We are two photos
Andrea six photos of us photos Andrea Federico
So we'll do you later
is coming
Take advantage of it if you want to photograph
just rightly mine  son
asks me there are a few Minors in the room
If you have to take pictures, erase your
face or
take the picture
from your back.  iset that have been
delivered please
guys guys come take a picture
with the audience behind let's see if you re  we go out
to recover all of us then maybe we can do it again
Even after with Cristofaro
you take us a bit
exact
guys a courtesy you would like to raise the
envelopes diset let's take a quick photo
Thanks
raise eh direction we can turn on
all the lights for a moment please Thanks
I finished the  time now I've been
Yes yes you can
[Music]
Thank you guys Thank
you please me and the sponsor ok
I would say we made it We can
start and
they wrote me I heard there are
some problems with transport anyway
a  a lot of other people are coming
Mattia how nice We find ourselves here
finally
the last time was
I was after we can left with
Elena for Las Vegas on vacation to have
a wonderful vacation now we're back with
Marina it's dad Hi
It's very nice to be back again  here
finally Bravo to you for the meantime for
having continued even during the
difficult moments online In my opinion it was
still a moment to stay attached
I had place Not  I know if you remember it
seems to me the 4-5 of March 2020 in which I
canceled all
one because I did not think this thing
would go ahead of the pandemic and
two because to me the totally
online event obviously God forbid I
understand it But it never has me  thrilled
you have literally flooded me with
messages of veiled threats because you
wanted to continue having the event and
then we continued to do it online
it went very well anyway because
we had
all the events thousands of people
connected it still went well but
I wanted to come back in an emergency it is not  the
same thing and I repeat in my opinion as if
we did this and we had to go back to
2019 as if this period had not been there
absolutely no
the faces are the same enthusiasm that is
the beer that is so Who is that here for the
first time ever
Who is that  all the editions have been done
but let's
not waste time let's start as
usual I respect you at stratospheric levels
Thank you for being here me
I am a pleasure and we said that
Bellis Come really was difficult
this year because with the two-year stop
this year an avalanche has arrived says
You did a lot of work and
above all difficult to choose so
I do not want to put pressure on the speakers