dal brazil queen is talking will be in
english
so thank you very much philippe for
being here with us today
discovering discovering common and
controlling malicious pdf with
obfuscation and coding and other
techniques thank you very much and
thank you
okay
hello
hello can you see
let's see
no
okay
so
[Music]
no
why not
i'm sharing
okay
yes yes that's correct it's connected
yes everything connected
another
oh yeah oh that's okay that's okay
awesome yeah that's it's running
once
i know i know why
htcp
you need a scalar
okay
yeah yeah
[Applause]
the most common happen when using mac os
sorry for that
um
okay
[Applause]
[Music]
holy
[Applause]
i think yes
[Music]
we're good what do you think
but i can see here
yes
it's good
yes fingers crossed sorry
thank you thank you thank you thanks so
much sorry for
this problem and um
the idea is to
[Music]
explain first
theory things and after that to do some
demo
in live and because of that cross your
things
because you know how this can happen so
my name is felipe pierce
this is my
contact at twitter and today we're going
to talk about something about the pdf
malicious right so my idea
and this afternoon is to bring you
something about how you can study more
about the malwares ptfs
and and some basis about that okay so
here other information about me i have a
small
web page here you can find other talks
in portuguese and english and spanish if
you want
and some project and research that i'm
i've been doing in my github and the
folder name thread hunting you can find
there if you want
you can
i made some tests using some
security sensors
sofas and crowdstrike
and others and you can find in my github
all those informations of course all
those informations i send this report
from these vendors so it's not a problem
about that okay and i think no no
problem in my linkedin as well so um
now i'm security research of this
company is a startup company
um
i'm responsible for creating the
intelligence for this product i'm
responsible for creating the attack
modules basically this product is
responsible for
looking for attack path management so
understand based on the policies that
you have in the cloud on privacy
environment
it's kind of similar of bloodhound can
you hear about bloodhound right okay and
it's a similar but uh for an enterprise
perspective and i'm responsible for
creating attacks for aws azure id
octa gcp and so on and so on okay
and by the way if you'd like to be a a
better tester we can talk with me after
the talk okay and for aws i create four
attack modules from this specific cloud
and if you want and for the community
view i'm a secure advocate of this
organization since
it's a solution of the plan but the idea
is to talk about the security and spread
the message
and i'm hacking is not a crime advocate
this project is very interesting talk
about the hacking about the future and
what is exactly hacking because
hacking's it's really not a crime okay
if you if the people if the guy is a
lawyer
and
do something bad
continue to be a lawyer but not a lawyer
it's a criminal in this case if this
lawyer
do something bad okay
and the problem is the television and
the newspaper talking about the hacking
has a criminal but it's not a criminal
as we heard during the during the
conference is attacker right as a threat
actor that's the idea behind of this
project okay
and i'm sneak ambassador
uh the open source project of course not
enterprise often for open source so this
idea of this project is to talk about
the how you can develop your product
your environment in a security way using
open source project okay
and i'm lead of the the sg it's a
community in brazil
in sao paulo by the way defcon groups in
sao paulo is a part of the defcon
conference but the groups spread
around the world and i'm structural
writer and have your those three
magazines in europe it's a fantastic
magazine hockey night in a foreign
magazine
okay
take a picture i can send my mother very
interesting for her it's very important
okay anyway so first of all it's very
important to understand about this
simple thing what is a track a thread
probably you know what is a thread it's
not definition from philip this is the
finish from this iso but
exactly what is a threat is a potential
thing that can happen in organization or
company
but it means a software attack or taffy
of the electoral property or maybe
identity death sabotage and information
distortion like a what like a ramson
seber server by the way it's a ransom
kind of ransor it's a it's a server it's
a kind of renzo and
it's a kind of types of
thread so if you see all those things
is focused in specifically software you
have a code
and this code can be
changing a binary or
app right so in the end of the day we
will have a binary behind of the
software we have applications libraries
and stuff like that okay
nice
so when you think about the more
analysis we need to think about this
specifically flow we have an artifact
you need to identify if this simple or
artifact is malicious or not because of
that it's very important right so you
have a
possible malware it's acronym of the
malicious software or you have a maldoc
acronym of the malicious document like a
pdf okay so when you're performing this
you after that you have a simple you
need to change what the best methodology
you can apply i mean you can choose what
the best approach you can use like
statistical analysis and the naming
canals when you do that
my recommendation for for knowledgement
you need always register all those steps
that you are looking for on the pdf
why
because first we will learn about that
right you understand those steps
executed by the attack
not only that but you can create a
report
and after that you can create an article
think think about that
and if you create this report you can
present to you this of your manager your
coordinator
right it's very important to you you
will learn
and you can
sell your work
okay
and not only that but
you can improve your defense's mechanism
why because you will understand what
exactly technique used by the attacker
to bypass
your environment so because of that
import and you can create this kind of
beautiful word called the cyber threat
intelligence it is a very nice word
right but the real life is not too
easy but anyway
but if a small company knows you can
work with that or you can
using
other service and of course we need to
have this kind of strengthening
resilience but philip what is exactly
statistical analysis simple definition
uses usually is the first step using by
the analyst why because this is is a
kind of analysis that describe the
process
that you are analyzing the binary
you doesn't execute itself the binary
you understand those process or
if you can see for example if the binary
have a specifically function that these
functions is imported by specifically
dll
or library for
the unix platform for example so in this
case it's
more safe of course it's more okay
because doesn't run at this time the
binary on the other hand you have a
dynamic analysis just a simple
definition basically is based on the
runtime analysis you execute this binary
or the sample in a controlled
environment or is using specifically
tools and they will give a result and
that's the key here in our conversation
today
you can use many tools
and usually when you talk about the
offensive security offensive perspective
or the penetration tester or whatever
you think about how are you using burp
suite
to analyze the request and i will use
sql sql map
to executing specifically sql injection
attack but we're using tools
but if someone asking you about for
example using burp suite so how is the
handshake of the tls
oh my goodness
some people ask him about that so how
this works the tls handshake
this is the very common question from
the atr team right not atr team but the
technical interview right
and i am seeing many
questions about that not only that but
about other technic stuffs and talk
about the power or defensive perspective
or offensive perspective and my question
not my question but my point here during
our conversations
you need like me understand because i'm
studying i need to learn about that how
this works
and more deeply right
so dynamic analysis i was a good
teaching using tools and i can use it i
can automate the process using using
this
concept calling sandbox
do you know what is exactly sandbox
right
so if you don't know what is a sandbox
sandbox is a specifically controlled
environment that you can put in this
binary like this this pointer is a
binary i will put this binary inside of
this sandbox a control and environment
and then i will run this binary inside
of that
and now you see if this binary is
malicious or not right
so
if sandbox
is a virtual machine that i can execute
my binary inside of that
so i can basically
open my virtualbox
install virtual machine and i have a
sandbox is that correct
no
because the sandbox that we're using for
our analysis for example or using for
executing malicious things inside of
this the controlled environment you need
to have
the engines responsible for detect if
this binary is malicious or not
that's the key
when you execute when you put in your
binary in the antivirus and vero's total
scanning
you know how this works inside of the
virustotal we have many engines
providing from different security
vendors like a set like mcafee like a
trend micro like many others and
specifically engines
for example essentials here
oh my goodness
and
probably they have
some engines inside of that and if
you're looking from the product from the
set
probably you need to enable specifically
checkbox
for increased detection because of that
when you put in the binary inside of the
antivirus the virustotal
you're looking for i have the solution
like a kaspersky or other but my binary
didn't attack has a malicious why
because if you see from the vendor
perspective they haven't specifically
checked or to enable because of that
didn't attack the solution
okay because of that it's very important
understand not only how to use in the
tools but how is the result
when you putting something inside of
these tools okay so nice
so
before to talk about the logic of the
pdf i would like to show something more
about this
specifically
and where is my virto machine
okay cross your fingers now because it's
here for you
and i can see you here
anyway let me try okay
so can you hear me nice okay i will try
i'm looking from this other
here let's put in my
here okay
so i have here some documents okay can
you see
many documents
first of all are you using file comment
can you
can you some people know this comment
right file okay so fio i will looking
for amazon first
this is my friend amazon it's a it's a
microsoft word document right so i have
another friend called bu
very nice guy
it's a pdf nice and i have another
i think i have something like a mower
here
let's see
i think it's
malware
right
it's a ascii text okay
so
let me try see more about the
[Music]
let me read this document mower
it's a simple python script that's okay
i think yes let me looking for another
i'm cruising curious for this another
thor like pdf
it's a pdf document
nice
okay we have a different documents here
but is another point is
how the file
binary or two works
they need to find something in a
specifically binary to identify remember
the first step identification steps
so
do you know what is exact
this part of the code or this part of
the binary that the file you find
to identify this binary
can you try
someone
the magic
wait
so
anyone
the magic
probably they look in my presentations
let's look in from the manual
is a determiner type file
let's see what happened here
and they have something like magic here
i think
take a look here take a look here
what's your name my friend
fredrick
exactly answer
they're looking for the magic number
exactly
magic number that's the information that
fio
find
or search
where
if you see the the text
they find it
no mick okay
a store in particular placing the
beginning of the file so that's the
information that the file you're using
to find this information
okay
nice
let me turn here
if i have here
one specifically python script in this
case in this file
malware
let me try as i could this file let's
see what happened now
what do you think what do you think
it works
nice
but if you see the file don't have
extension
okay
so let me
change something here
hello
okay let me change something here
let's see what happened if i put this
three double quotes here and i will save
and take a look what happened now
file malware
now is not more
only ascii text but if you see now it's
a python script executable
let me do other things let me go to the
the tor
pdf
file
in this case it's a pdf right okay
let me try read this
file
is a pdf okay
let's
good always happen this
okay
double check
i always close your fingers now
oh username thank you
i'm trying looking here but you know
some people are looking they will open
the password
okay where is the other
ah okay i remember okay another here
simple
file simple.txt
no not text it's a it's a python script
okay
let's see what happened now
let me check here
it's difficult to read for the the
monitor you know
but anyway
you see in this case it's another python
script as you can see here right
being
is a simple
python script to you know removing
special characters for
specifically function okay remember that
i changing i put in specifically
think in the beginning of the my other
file called malware remember cat mower
remember that the quotes here
okay
here
so now changing the file so if i try as
i could this
mower despite this file now take a look
what happened
some problem it's happened here
why
but if you see fio identify has a python
right
but if i try to use in python it doesn't
works
something can happen here in this case
the answer of the log is about this
probably some
thing about the syntax okay
so let me change the other thing here so
if i change again this is my file
now and i will cut here
you cut here
okay
and i put percent pdf-1.9
[Music]
and i will save
okay
and i will try see what happen now
malware
now we have a pdf document
nice
so
if you use for example pdf id
see this file
we have the tools works
the tools
it works pdf id basically is a tool from
the dj stevens researcher that create
these
tools is a pdf right
nice
because
these tools analyze
the header of the ptf and the magic
number one of this information of the
header of the pdf
is a percent
pdf has i put in the beginning of the
file
right
if i
let me change other thing this
here to show you
okay
so now i will
take this point
i will put in
[Music]
move mower
i will change the name
mower
doc pd pdf
and i will go to once again
here
okay
doc pdf
and now you cut this
and i will save
you see what happened now i change once
again the magic number
and i will try to using
the
same command
but now
i will put why
i put in the file using the extension of
the pdf
so
it works right
no
why
so you see i'm using two tools
and i'm i'm i'm i'm do something
fun
with the magic number of the file
because of that it's important when
you're executing specifically tools you
not only use it but you receive the logs
from these tools
remember that when you execute your
researchers your analysis
you need to looking more deeply about
how this works
for example
you if you think about
for example about them let's go to my
linux folder
i have here
some hours i think now it's hours i just
using hours in my demonstrations and my
course is always more so something
happen
i'm
okay anyway
in this case
if you see
um let me using um i would try i think
it's agne32
airbus okay
so i'm looking now for the specific
specifically hexadecimal informations in
the beginning of this this elf is a
binary from linux okay
if you see here take a look that this is
the string right
in the beginning of the file you can see
yeah nice this is the first string that
appears for us right
okay
strings dash a it means all
airbus
pipeless because the fire is too big
okay
so i started since the beginning
first string is elf
no
why
or
how
how it's possible
good
so it's a simple question a stupid
question i know
but for if you read these informations
here in the manual
you understand exactly the answer
i don't like read manual by the way
if you like nice but if you don't like
like me
but anyway we in our
career we need in our field security we
need to read this is the answer
string prints the printable character
sequences that are at least four
characters
just because of that
you see
so they need to have the four sequence
simple like this because probably when
you receive and specifically sample the
first step you will executing this
string
it is putting the string dash a
uh
putting copy all those information for
specifically them text and then you read
the text
to see because you cannot you would
want to manipulate the malicious in your
environment right so we will copy these
strings in a specifically text file you
will read more calm relax but
some informations you can read
didn't appear there because
the string didn't appear
or will appears at least four
sequence
this is the key
remember in the beginning of the talk i
mentioned it with you so my idea is to
bring this information to you to
understand those steps and how important
it is for your study your evolutions
because it's important for me i'm
studying and i think it's important for
me so maybe maybe it's important for you
okay nice
let me return in my
presentation
okay so let's talk about the physical
and logical structure about the pdf
pdf in general have four parts right so
the first is header
it's all this is very similar for
different binaries always has a header
okay
a body is a part of the you know
like a font or other things like this
they have a cross reference table is a
part of the
the correlation of the object and the
trailer it more informations i will
share
with you in the next slide
okay so we
oh hello
i'm here in this one okay
and if you see here
here the structure of the pdf okay we
have in the beginning the body has i
mentioned that with page image phones
and stuff like that what funny things in
the pdf you know the shiny things
and cross reference table basically is
the location of the object i mean you
have in the beginning the root
object in the pdf
in this root we have a child like object
two and object three
and those in in these others object like
two and three you can have you can have
other
childs of this object like at three okay
one connect to
an object two and object two maybe can
connect an object to where v13 depends
it depends of the how many objects you
have inside of this pdf okay
because of that the access is random
inside of this is referring or in this
case each object reference each one okay
and the trailer
is a part of this
location
uh is totally linked with a
cross-reference table okay it's a
theoretical part not so good but anyway
so
this is i recording just because it's
it's longer i recorded this demo to show
you
so
let's see what happened let's go
and i will explain all those steps so i
received the pdf malicious so the next
steps is to
investigate all those informations right
so okay so first step
i
verify if this pdf
it was a pdf of course i made others uh
other activities but i just recorded
this
specifically steps right so first of all
is a pdf malicious it's a pdf document
version 1.3
and after that i
using pdf id remember these two
basically performing specifically
is scanning inside of the document
for
looking for any specific informations
what kind of information philip
we can find for example objects so in
this case we have a 15 object inside of
this up this file
and if you see we have a two streaming
and with streaming usually is a part of
the
content inside of the pdf use it by the
attacker
not only that but usually we have
more informations that you can
investigate that okay
and if you see
this specific pdf has a one specifically
page
okay they have one specifically page
streaming
and if you see they have
five reference or two in this case js
and three other reference
we can find many others reference
basically when dj students create these
tools probably they think about
strings probably and what kind of
information the
the tool could collected from this file
and he created these tools basically
this way that happened the tools that
people create
they look in front some information
and they try to automate the process
because of that it's very important to
understand how the tools works how the
command works and how the answer of this
command
appears to you okay
okay let's continue to this
investigation and other point is about
this open action what that means
phillips
open action and aa
is the same meaning okay but in this
case they have one open action open
action is basically
the function when the user received the
the pdf
let's suppose that you're working with
hr team or a financial team probably you
receive a resume every day and probably
receive every invoice every day okay so
the
everyday
these people
open the pdfs right
or resume or invoice okay so after
the user click to open this pdf
we will be executed this function open
action
i mean i will explain
basically one thing
will be happen automatically
okay the user don't need to interact
once again with the file when they open
the file
automatically happens something in the
background
when you find this open action
this means
it basically okay you understand
i think it's clear
okay so let's continue so we have
something interesting we have a
javascript
and we have
an open action
okay flippy it's encrypted
maybe we need to password to using
something here okay
so the next tool that i use here in this
investigation it's another tool from
this package from the dj steven pdf
parser
to using to
to parser some informations or to search
for some information inside of this pdf
basically okay so we have many
informations or many comments that i can
use here but basically
the first
i just will show you about this
information javascript remember we have
a three
in this case in this case this is the
first reference object one
object seven and object twelve 3
reference remember that
and another search is about js
just to confirm using two different
tools if you see the first is pdf id
first and second so if you remember i
use pdf id and i found five informations
related js and javascript
are using another tools to confirm the
same information
so in this case we don't have any false
positive right
nice so the second one i will using now
the other comment using the same tools
just to explain more details okay are
you using
dave w or
my idea here in this case is to collect
the wrong
output data to find
more deeper informations about that okay
so i secured this in this specifically
resume pdf
and
let's see and now you you can understand
how those object works so if you see
here take a look this reference
object one in this case
they
remember the tree
so this is the the first object and they
have six reference here
object two three four five six and seven
seven
seven do you remember how many objects
we have in this file
no
15 yes 15 objects two looking this is a
a small object i i can show you after
17 18 objective can you imagine just
analysis
15 it's easier thank you god for this 15
but
yeah 15. so
but here we can see just seven right so
we need to looking from others
oh my goodness oh sorry for that i
yeah let me go
again more
our objects okay
so we have a 15 objects and take a look
that this open action is totally linked
with the specifically javascript
remember open action
so when the user clicking the file to
open something happened what happened
something about the javascript but we
don't know what exactly in this moment
okay so other reference object four
eight and nine so other new reference
object eight and i appears now for us
and take a look other reference
something about the
not important
for now
any or uh
i can't i cannot see
the value information and here we can
see all the reference object eight
of the reference
you see other object reference another
looking from the javascript
let's see
here the reference object 10 referring
other javascript in this case js and
here we can see the first streaming
i need to stop this
okay
yeah the first stream take a look that
object 11
containing stream so maybe you can look
in from the object 11 because
we have any stream here but if you see
here the left
is very very small
maybe the content inside of this stream
is not too valid
but we can look in from that and they
have another flag here flat decode
basically
we need to decode something
okay so
let's move on
okay nice
and let's see object l 12v referring
another
13.
in this case if you see they have
another string but the left in this case
is
is very different
it's bigger
so maybe you can this is the object that
we need to investigate more okay
so
let's move on
for this specific object okay after that
i use pdf techcom
because we don't have more time to
explain but we have a pdf taker this
these tools we can manipulate pdfs we
can merge pdf we can compress pdf and
you can uncompress pdf that that's my
idea now uncompress
those informations or many informations
that i can see inside of this stream
remember object 13.
so i execute these tools
to uncompress this information exactly
inside of this object 13 because
when i made this investigation this
content for me it was valid because it's
it's bigger okay so i using these tools
uncompress this information inside of
that
and i i copped this in specifically.text
and after that take a look what happened
i found
this is the content
inside of the object
13.
and here
we have the first technique used by the
attacker
the javascript obfuscated
okay so the attacker using basically the
javascript obfuscated
to obfuscate that the code inside of
that the point is remember the flow
user receive the resume
download the machine and open the resume
and after that they click and open this
file
and when they click and they open the
one javascript executing automatically
this is the javascript
so we need to look in what is exactly
what
what is the action of this
javascript if javascript i thought so
javascript web application
i using this
this basically i rewrite i found the
specifically evo parameter here and i
try to rewrite
this of course it's not too easy to do
i made other tasks until now until i
write these results okay and after that
i rewrite here using the document right
to print this information
in the web application and if you see
they haven't specifically standard
behavior not behavior but you know
percent number ladders and other things
like this very interesting
okay so first
what i did here is i rewrite this
information in a specifically html file
to print this information in a browser
right because my idea is to looking what
information i will find in this
javascript
it was obfuscated and now we
skate this code
and take a look what happened now
when i try to open this
file
what information we on this case we i
found
wow
the payload you know what is payload
yes or no
yes you like this
payload is a package if you don't know
what is payloads it's a package or part
of the code
that you download in the victory machine
and this package is responsible for the
callback
from the attacker
okay so that's the key so now we have
here
here the payload
remember the flow
so inside of javascript we have a
payload
download the victim machine so if this
payload is responsible for callback
so we we can try
it more deeply because it's totally
malicious the idea is if
it was
investigators this fire is malicious or
not but it's malicious okay but now we
have a payload next step is to try and
investigate or to find what kind of
information you have here
i'm using a lot unix platform but maybe
you are thinking flip just using linux
okay
i would like to see in the linux in
windows platform anyway no problem are
using the windows to show you other
tools okay
so here we can see
the same investigation not this none of
the end of the investigation actually
here you can see the same code
okay the same file the same information
the same
javascript obfuscated okay so i will
write all those information all those
things
is there
here is the payload okay so basically i
cop
this payload here as you can see
and i passed here and this tools mozilla
why because i need the attacker using
here another technique the encode
technique right and
they're using the only code using to
only code to encode
maybe
you know with the language here but
anyway
the attacker using specifically
because when you using something to
encoding you can use in ascii okay based
on bytes or you can use a new code based
in two bytes in this case the attacker
using unicode based in two bytes and not
only that but the attacker using the
other techniques to encode this
information the using the ucsc2
is old when you compare with utf-16 with
f32 and stuff like that this is the old
part okay
nice so i copy and paste this payload
here and the first i
using here this ec2 to convert to x
decimal information basically i cut the
percent and
only that okay
you can use sad in linux and after that
i generate this
file
binary
why because this attacker is from the
windows environment
okay so i generate this cnc because if i
have the payload i can try to find the
cnc from the attacker and that's the my
idea i generate this binary and after
that i'm using another tools
from the dj steven by by the way
to try if i figure out specifically the
ip address from the attacker
and if you see
we find
okay this is the ip address from the
attacker
so now we have or maybe the
the
the last hope that attack has
i don't know
but this is basically the last ip
address from the attacker in this case
in dystonia okay
and yes
so now i finish the presentation and
this is some recommendation of books if
you want to know more about the mara
analysis talking
we have many other books but just some
reference to you and
30 seconds i finish
the presentation sorry again for the
problems but remember the flow between
the machine received the cv inside of
the cv we have a javascript obfuscated
the attacker using unicode's technique
to encode informations inside of the
sony code we can found the pdf right
mathias thank you so much thanks so much
everyone
thank you philippe