we
would like to continue with the last
talk before the break
um which is about the android
debug bridge from gabriel
kerlik gabriel is a software developer
and the so-called bot hunter at white
ops located in london
uk in the past he worked on
threat intelligence and he obviously
loves to dismantle
break and things all kinds of hardware
he can get his hands on
today's going to talk about the android
debug bridge
and how his self-made honeypots
discovered the worms abusing this
networked debug interface so please
welcome with me
gabriel hello
fellow humans and thank you eric for the
introduction
let me just share my screen
is it all good yes we can hear you and
we can see your screen
all perfect awesome
so first thing first thank you for
having me here
i'm gonna show you today some neat
tricks that
are not being understood well by
the hardware development community but
first thing first i want to know you
uh a bit better hang on a second
i need to find a way to see
the window the
participant window so
raise your hand whoever is an android
developer
could you please just raise your hand
ah all right we've got two people
three okay four
so we've got uh a nice audience uh
for those who don't know what adb is
it's uh basically
android debuggerage um
it's a developer's way of communicating
with the device
and building up a
debugging bridge hence the name between
the app that's being debugged
and the and the developers
computer and today we're gonna
look into ways that this is being abused
by the bad guys
at least a vendor's uh generosity
into allowing easy debugging of their
devices being actively exploited by the
bad guys
and now a bit more about me so
i haven't started my security
research career for long i pulled the
stunt a few years ago
people nicknamed me the public
transportation hacker after i
uh did the simple midfield hack with the
public transit system in romania
and after that i discovered that i
couldn't hack my
way through the town anymore so i
started hacking my car
uh i found out that it knew quite a lot
definitely a lot more than i knew about
myself and about the people that were
roaming around that car but that's a
story for a different time
and recently i started hunting uh
bots at white tops uh hopefully
we're gonna prevent the next uh
robot insurrection but right now we're
just preventing them from doing ad fraud
and this little
tiny bit of research
kinda started from the fact that
we have smart tvs smart fridges
smart toasters smart cars and even
smarter toasters
so what we can do
if we want to make to stay safe is
sprinkle our little honey pots in
between all of those
smart devices and the iot
where s stands for security as we all
know
and looking at all of landscape
uh something caught my eye it looks like
among this rubble of smart devices
some of them were being noticed by the
bad guys
and it was mainly android devices
who had adb on
this was being spotted by kevin bomo at
around two years ago i think i can't
recall exactly
i still remember that it was summer so
it might be two years ago
uh which kind of prompted me
into trying to figure out
what are they sending to those devices
is it what are they exploiting how are
they exploiting it
uh can i exploit it as well so
a lot of questions going around in my
head
basically being a
protocol that you can use to connect to
you can push binaries to it and you can
also
send shell commands through adb to that
phone
because guess what at some point
in history adb got externalized
over tcp so
even though initially the protocol was
designed for usb
only at some point
the powers that we decided to put it up
on the internet and anybody can just
type adb tcp
and the port and bam then adb is exposed
on all of the interfaces
that your phone has or tv or dvr or
whatever
on the internet and that's when you're
owned
so i started working i started tinkering
and hammering away trying to
uh just find a way to do it you know
just pour in the hard work and read rfcs
rtfm and you should be able to do it
and i did read the manual the one that
we have from google
all of the there there is documentation
for everything that's going on but it's
very outdated that stuff was written
once when the protocol was made they
even
described the flow through ascii art
but fortunately the community came to
the rescue and they decided to compile
and add
more resources on top of that
but it was still not enough so i had to
dig a bit more
fortunately i have i found some people
who reverse engineered most of the
headers and the message body and
initially at least according to the rfcs
on an adb packet that's being sent over
tcp
you have the command you have the two
arguments
only two uh
the length of the data being transmitted
to the crc and some magic
simple enough i guess you have
four functions that you can call and
using those four functions
you should just able to assemble really
complex instructions
like in this case trying to execute open
a shell on the device and execute a
simple command
when you execute command you open the
share but in order to open the shell
you need to uh send the open which will
fork
that uh the adb demon into the shell
and then in order to do that you need to
actually
send some proper handshake before it
but it didn't work
and it got that's when the whole rabbit
hole started forming up and it was just
ripe for diving in um the crc
it's not actually the crc uh it's
some kind of implementation that they
did uh the magic had absolutely no
reason
they it wasn't documented what's the
format how it should be there
is it really commands sore and the other
uh
the list of f's uh nobody kinda knew
and nobody kinda knew why that happened
probably you know just um
pms breathing down your neck hey guys
how can we wrap this up faster and
faster
and add pcp-ip over adb or just finish
it yeah
just we're gonna bolt something together
and
uh let it be so
these are my attempts at sending
because in order to write that honeypot
i needed to reverse
those three functions connecting sending
a command
sending a binary so i was trying to send
the binary
using the same devices on the same
connection
three times and i got three different
flows
totally different flows okay let's say
that
the first part kind of
is kind of in line with the other i mean
that's the handshaking part
but until we reach the actual stream of
data
there's a different flow every time and
in the
last example you can actually see that
there's like a big discrepancy over
there
so what i did
i got a the headers
and the body of the message from an open
source repository that i found and i was
telling you about
and i just got to work
i basically implemented
the send function like a rosen function
and tried
every corner case known to humanity
until i could get 99 of the payloads
let's say that there was this odd puppy
that would come in sometimes and
screw everything over but let's say that
in the end it was a great success i
finally had a honeypot
and you can actually go and connect to
it right now
the honeypot has been running for
around one year and a half
and catching attacks all over the
internet
bad guys that keep connecting to adb
and trying to exploit them and to
deploy their malware over there so we
can could go connect over there to my
server and say hi
don't worry nothing will it's gonna
happen it's just like my
private list of my private zoo actually
when it comes to malware and speaking of
zoo
let's get into some of the more
interesting samples that i found
um
the first one got my heart rate a little
bit up
made me seem like a bit wholesome
it looked like there's this guy going
around on the internet stealing my
original idea
thinking that hey i'm gonna make a
botnet that is gonna
fight with other botnets and clean the
internet
hey look this guy already decided to do
that i mean he's removing like
one two three seven other miners
from that device and of course he's
deploying his
own after he's doing that so
yeah that's how my hope in humanity
collapsed again
very simple operation shutting down
his competitors and then trying to push
his no
his own apk using adb push and
after that he starts his apk the apk
starts mining and not only that
in case that who knows maybe the user is
done installs the apk
he always he also has some scripts that
download some binaries that do the
miners
mining but he's not relying only on the
apk
uh at some point came along
a guy who kind of forgot that you can
do adb and push of a command
of a binary so he escaped
the payload behind hex
and then he tried to rebuild it
even though adb shell commands like
go in all directions everywhere and
it's not like always especially over tcp
that you're gonna have the same
commands go in the same
order especially if the connection
becomes this
like close it at some point
uh here short-lived needless to say
and the putin helper yeah this guy's
nose
representing uh that's the actual name
of the malware
putin helper um it's some kind of
dvr mining scam
like most of the bad guys out there it
looks like
mining is still going strong when it
comes to
android botnets mining and banking
making money um
and i actually like felt sorry a bit for
this guy
for this guy he's actually
uh asking for a job over his botnet
for those who don't watch i'm he's
saying i'm sorry but i'm mining on your
device not because i want to but because
i need the cash
and then he attaches his protonmail uh
email and saying that he's gonna send
you a cv
if you contact him over there yeah what
can i say buddy
hoping that you got
a job finally and renounced your ways
and now lapis
um trinity uh trinity is an interesting
uh piece mainly because it's the biggest
malware that's going around the intern
on this on these devices right now
which at their peak were about 50 000
or 60 000 android devices
um it's a
bot it's a bot that's comprised of the
three parts
a native miner an android miner and
a spreading script and all of these
three components are pushed dynamically
so the bot an infected device let's say
will start scanning the internet
but if at some point it will find
a device that has
the 555 port open he's going to connect
to it
and see if the malware the same strain
of malware is already running on that
device
if it is then it won't do anything it
will just leave it alone if it's not
running
it will check each of the individual
pieces that i
told you about native miner java miner
spreading script if they are running if
not
if one is not running it will push it to
the device and try to restart it
in order to achieve this meta
persistency
mechanism there's a lot to delve into it
uh a really cool researcher
nc commander uh made an analysis of it
i don't think he published the research
yet but basically this guy is
actually uh infiltrating in the recovery
partition i think
uh if it found a rooted device so
he achieves this extra resilience over
there
but anyhow the nate the um
java miner is really straightforward
it just embeds low it has a
file embedded it loads it in a webview
uh and inside that file they just open a
coin hive and
make money uh the native miner
is just your run-of-the-mill mining
binary
for monero while the spreading script
this is the more interesting one that i
was telling you about
it contains the routines required for
all of that to extra
uh punch with
uh embedded emitting itself into the
recovery partition and
trying to spread around as much as it
can
now trinity was not
was the most successful but a close
competitor to it was fbot
which got covered by the guys at key who
i think
um
and they discovered that it was using
some kind of blockchain dns system like
going all out blockchain blockchain
money blockchain dns blockchain
everything
uh and at some point
they were specifically targeting trinity
over here ufo minor this is trinity
and catalin chimpanu actually made
i think for zdnet a really cool
article about how these two botnets are
actually fighting with each other
on top of this network of devices that
are adb enabled into
basically the ownership of your smart tv
or
smart home or smart whatever
uh but hey gabby it's not that bad maybe
these guys only had
all devices
my sources told me that
they are pretty new devices android 7 8
9 even android 10 devices you're gonna
find everything in there
which leaves us the question how does
this happen i mean uh
it's not like an active exploit or
anything
it's something that is as designed
probably some somebody in the factory
when they were building the tvs had this
brilliant idea
of enabling adb over tcp
connecting them to a wi-fi and then just
pushing the apk for
like the qa process or that tv or that
dvr
and just automating the process and
somehow
they forgot to remove this debugging
feature uh i'm using this educated guess
because
it it happened in the past that's how i
got to hack my mazda before
they just left all of their debugging
tools
like on my machine like on a production
line
machine and not only for me but for
everybody else
um but
yeah anyway um
just a quick reminder you can always
connect
and try to work around my uh
honeypot in order to
maybe find a bug who knows and together
we can improve it by the way the
honeypot is
available open source it's written in
python
and last year it was upgraded to python
3 as well
um everybody can just pop on
and pop it and see what
these guys are sending but then enough
of the honeypot
i mean i've talked i didn't talk enough
about
what can you find on those devices so
we're gonna have like a demo
ish like a prepared demo i know i'm
cheating
but i couldn't have done it live it's
again from my
sources i can show you
what can be seen on these devices and i
would kindly ask you that
you don't like record this
part or let's say that you don't
specifically target this part because
there are people behind those images and
we're going to start with something
light um some bad guys just injected
uh their uh uh
ad fraud apk onto that device and are
actually trying to test to see if
they can get something done uh more
testing
for ad fraud these are just the default
ads from admob
and bam they got it they got an ad
running
and how this happens they
uh you just say let's say that you have
one of those tvs with adb enabled
you plug it in you connect it to the
internet and then you just get picked up
by some of these bad guys for example
like the ones that push ads and
you're gonna start seeing interstitial
ads on your tv
from now and then fun right um
this guy was just trying to ins to was
was in the process of being hacked
somebody who was just connecting to him
and pushing
the fraudulent one of the fraudulent
apks that from around the internet
uh on his device as
i as all of this screen capture was
going
some random people watching apk watching
youtube
people playing games you know
i mean up until now it's not that
harmful right i
mean what can go bad it's it can be
i mean what are the hackers gonna do
like use your mining
use your cpu for mining time and see
that you're watching vikings
well how about porn
um yes
zero privacy if you one of the one of
those devices
you've got zero privacy somebody can
connect to it
at any time and just use this as fresh
ransom material uh or how about
your messages that you are discussing
with
your loved ones or whatever or just
spying you while you're doing your
i don't know actual human
being stuff trying to
talk with your relatives trying to i
don't know
use what's up and then here comes this
jackass connecting to your phone and
stealing sensitive information and your
chat logs
and i had to do i mean
that's when i knew that i had to do
something so i open sourced
the honeypot as i was telling you
earlier and i got fresh memes
for uh these are these are were not made
by me these were made
by some guys as a reaction to uh
uh to the honeypot being open source
which was like
really really really wholesome i mean
being kind of fresh
in the infosec industry and basically
piggybacking so much
onto the knowledge that was shared with
me
by other people i felt that i needed to
give something back
so a single reaction to that
to this give back was just amazing it
was
really cool thing open source best
10 out of 10 would do again
and yeah it got the honeypot got
integrated by the guys at telecom
uh into teapot which is really cool you
don't have to deploy it by yourself you
can just deploy teapot and you've got
an adb honey instance running on
by itself over there the number
of infected devices after i started
evangelizing this decreased from
more than 50k to 15k
and it even decreased
more this was last year it decreased
more this year to write 7k
or something like that but we'll get to
that later it keeps oscillating
um some interesting statistics
there is something wrong with june and
july like i'm not
really they like knowledgeable data
science
guy but when the graph goes like this it
is bad
right so we've got two spikes one here
and one here and this was from last year
lo and behold the same spikes
over here in june
i don't know what's going on but
it looks like the bad guys want to go on
vacation
maybe who knows and
yeah they they need they want to rake in
some cash something really interesting
is that
they seem to have like a lower activity
during the winter holidays maybe they
just
take time off being a malware guy it can
be hard right
and texting another
interesting aftermath is that the number
of devices keeps shifting up and down
um for example there were only like
10 000 devices that were open on ipv6
a couple of months ago fortunately in
the meantime sometimes somebody decided
to shut that down
so the number
dropped from 20k a couple of months ago
to only 7k right now and all of the ipv6
devices
uh have pretty much gone in the dark so
somebody over there must have done
something really
well and i thank him for that because
the botnet is still going strong uh
even if you i mean if you get infected
and even if you
shut down your internet connection after
that or sorry you put your device behind
the net
you're still gonna get you're still
gonna mine for that guy and
try one and spread the malware basically
but
at least we're seeing like a downwards
trend
um and without further ado
um follow me on github for my latest
project i have
some really cool stuff that i'm gonna be
releasing soon
and follow me on twitter for uh
all the fresh memes thank you guys
and thank you the guys at android
security symposium for uh having me
okay thanks gabriel for this animated
very mean powered presentation uh we're
ready for another round of
q and a there are two uh people
in um in zoom still raising their hands
i don't know whether or not you would
like to ask questions or
maybe this is from your questions
regarding android development before
claudia do you want to ask a question
okay i don't i don't think so so if
there are any questions
please just type them into the program
the one q and a in metamost
um well almost all of the questions are
prepared during the first half of your
speech you actually answered
in the second one um it seems that
most bots you detected have their main
focus on
mining cryptocurrencies is that correct
or
did you find malware which tries to do
anything else in particular
oh it's mainly ad fraud and
cryptocurrency they are still exploring
the ad fraud part
but the cryptocurrency is there to stay
they are mining like crazy
okay um is is mining
on on android hardware
yeah exactly interesting when well
when you i mean when it's not your
device any kind of mining
is financially
useful you just need to find the
reasonable amount of devices i've seen
people trying to mine
on even a lower number of devices like
1k
for example okay and yeah and it still
break some profit for them
well obviously they wouldn't do it
otherwise i guess yeah
there is a another question from renee
uh
who asks what's the plan b
or c or d on recovering or resetting the
honeypot when attackers manage
to compromise the next level oh
there is no next level it's completely
uh
non-interactive i mean it's interactive
as in it responds
to the various uh packets
like lower level packets that are being
sent
because you just can't like make a
handshake and then send a command now
you need to like follow that protocol
so the whole adb i implemented the whole
adb protocol
from the ground up and
the payload is just download it in a
file
and the shell command is outputted to a
text file
that's it i mean unless
they find some kind of exploit in the
honeypot in python where
they can do some shenanigans
there is no second level
okay i guess i guess that answers it um
we have another question from paul
which who tells you you did a good job
on your talk have you seen any
any malware from another source that
attempts to turn
on adb over wi-fi
he also says he assumes that whiteheads
can find these devices
atp connect and disable adb over wi-fi
while connected
so that's some sort of the drop
um from my knowledge the
adb so the connection
is permanent like built
in from the hard so even if you disable
it right now
when you reboot your device it's gonna
be re-enabled
i can't recall for sure it depends on on
from vendor to vendor but i've seen one
that did that
and this is one of the issues that i've
noticed it's
a bit harder to patch it
yeah but and to answer the first
question
i haven't seen any malware trying to
open adb connections
like and we were talking about android
malware like google play malware and
stuff like that or side channel
malware third-party malware they don't
do that they either
go like they
wiggle their their way through adb where
and they do all of their shenanigans
or you download them from a marketplace
whatever
and they just stay in the context of
that device and don't do anything
cross channel okay thanks
um another question from uh weaker she
asks do you know what kind of devices
are these like a list of devices um do
you notify the vendors to fix it
the list is really big uh i tried
yeah it's it's i tried i
at some point i tried doing some recon
but the
configurations that came were very
diverse and colorful and
yeah what can i say just gave up it was
it was basically whack them all because
you would try to
let's say that you found a vendor but
then the next day you had like
this other vendor like the ipv6 guys
that i was telling you about
they are some kind of dvr company from
brazil and they just pop them overnight
they spread everywhere like just like
that uh
fortunately i'm trying like a more
proactive approach so
i'm trying to speak about this and to
raise awareness
hoping that this kind of knowledge will
spread as much
like go right to the guys actually
making this stuff
and getting them informed and
fortunately shutting down
adb okay we'll see if that works
hopefully okay um
i do have a last uh concluding question
uh a more general one so
speaking of of pushing system upgrades
uh
especially devices like tvs have a
notoriously bad track record for for not
being taken care
of after manufacturing them as far as i
know
much worse even than it is the case with
some smartphone manufacturers
so do you have the impression that
companies which are using
android for devices other than
smartphones care significantly less
about the security of their devices
i don't think that care would be the
correct verb
i would say that they just don't know
yeah it's it's like let's say that
you're making tvs
and all of a sudden uh there's this uh
requirement from the management hey guys
you need to make a smart tv
yeah but now we we need to like release
in a couple of months
we don't care it has to be smart so
then you have devs just rushing
and bolting things together and i mean
i know because i've been in that
situation i've written some
bad code and i'm i feel guilty about
it so i think that this is happening
it's a it's a light motif in our
industry
yeah from from what i know i i'm afraid
you're right about that
okay um it seems like there
aren't any questions left to be answered
so uh thank you very much once again
gabriel
thank you very much for your talk