Ali we did it we did it so I Riley
security conference
yeah we are in it right now this is
happening it's really cool and when we
first started talking about this year
ago these yes right around a year ago
yeah we had this idea we have this
theory that defensive security people
defenders needed a place right
a gathering space at home to be right
yeah to productively share information
to step out of the darkness right shine
a light on it right but also not just
not just stepping out of the darkness
but actually center stage in a sort of a
culture environment that's cured towards
them celebrating yeah the work exactly
the it was a little scary right there's
a lot of right security events out there
there's a lot of noise
sure are and now that they would you
think how do you feel
oh wow did we get it right yeah i kinda
I kind of think we did I mean still
their first year right there's things
that we can always do better and
differently and and next year with the
community and the industry needs might
be different than what they needed this
year but I and just so thrilled that we
knew going in that the quality of the
agenda we were able to put together was
amazing and I'd heard lots of feedback
before the event that folks were really
looking forward to hearing from some of
the speakers and trainers that we pulled
in so the and day one has gone really
well yeah
word on the street so what are you
hearing from people word on the street
is sort of thankful not just of the
quality of the agenda because folks kind
of saw that that's why they got to get
this weather here but also of everything
else surrounding the event to make the
whole experience really useful and
productive all of the the sort of help
helping people make connections with
each other and have that context and
kind of keep things professional but
also fun though
strike yes it is but i think that we're
doing a good job and one of the things
that I've sort of kept hearing through
the talks and also as I've talked with
people is this idea that on this
defenders it's a team sport
I mean it's come up in almost every talk
that that it really sort of takes a
whole group of folks working together to
to build that road from otays to know
days and so we knew that we're a culture
of builders but i think the idea that
this space and information security and
in technology is such a team environment
and needs people from all different
spaces has made it really interesting
for the folks participating to see that
we're trying to create a culture where
that is also sort of fostered yeah and
not just IT right there there's been
some really JIT talks I feel like along
those lines and really great i've seen
great feedback on Twitter to from people
right
it's like it's okay to celebrate that
that you're not right that's what let's
try to light on that too its and we
don't feel
yeah about that shoutout for the marine
biology majors the history of computers
that philosophy majors English Lit made
several arts brethren so it takes all
kinds of skills because the tools that
we're going to use are not all
technology and the things that we're
trying to protect our all computers and
so that has been really it's been really
interesting to kind of sort of feel that
in my own work but then also hear that
come back to me from other speakers and
folks in this space and folks who are
just joining us so I think that's what
i've noticed the most then you've been
to a lot more other security purposes
and i have but to me it felt like the
signal-to-noise ratio on what people
focused on defense need with way up here
right like it could you could set all of
that other stuff aside it's still there
you're hurting your browser's on you
could
but but in this space with these people
it was like the quality of that signal
and then the you know the sort of breath
of that it's palpable and like that's
not here for those folks right so yeah
so what do you think we're going to
answer down we are worlds we are going
to Amsterdam we're going to Amsterdam
immediately so it's going to be a
different audience and I think that we
tried to pull in a mix of folks the
absurd am event who would speak also to
the sort of concerns of our friends
around the world right global concern in
Europe they have a just just operating
across borders and trying to deal with
different regulatory environments and
and such is very pressing there so you
know the agenda will be tweet the
emphasis of it will be tweaked a little
bit to make it really relevant locally
but I'm hoping that were able to foster
similar discussions and really inspire
people to connect and think about
protecting their systems and their
companies and you know neways different
ways get ideas from each other
yeah I'm not an and one thing that the
thing that kept coming up the keynotes
and other things is not a not a single
point in time right
this is a vector is it you know it's a
journey and things like that
dan kaminsky hack upon that that has
legs that could continue right that's
fantastic into next year right
yeah they called the call for volunteers
is never going to end really like the
opportunity for folks to pitch in is
never going to end
and we're going to make progress we're
going to make progress together into the
future into the future and Beal and
beyond
yes so yeah I'm really I'm really
interested to see whether we do more
hackathon events exactly what what other
sort of supporting infrastructure we're
going to provide to the community
yeah to be determined rain
work-in-progress like great
fields but i think it's it's so perfect
actually that it is it is a hackathon
start of the supporting activity because
that's a building activity right it's I
think that it would be very interesting
to do a sort of capture the flag type
Blue Team Red Team exercise an
environment like this but it's sort of
like poetic and perfect that what we are
but we're sort of bringing to the table
is building
yeah fixing building and building
something that's going to last beyond
the the event itself right the tools
that are being created they'll be open
source people can use them they can
incorporate them they can add on to them
but we're building together which i
think is really great