/ for the introduction our company is
based in Moscow Russia we have started
over 20 years ago and actually our first
commercial product was about tests for
cracking it was a cracker for zipper
house we have done it for ourselves just
just because we forgot our own password
an end we decided to try to start to
sell it and after about two weeks we got
the first order from the FBI and we
decided that that that could be a good
idea to develop such kind of software
and since then they have developed the
full range of password cracking software
and selling it to law enforcement all
over the world but today I'm going to to
talk about something different about six
or seven years ago we started another
direction now a company related to
mobile and cloud forensics from from our
customers that are working for mostly
for law enforcement we will learn that
they're much more interested in breaking
the encryption and getting data from
mobile devices and from the cloud it's
usually much more much more interesting
data there so we have we have started
our first product about mobile forensics
was for breaking passwords also for
iTunes backup and that was the first on
the market and after that later we
started to explore that different
different clouds started also with Apple
iCloud then we made a product for Google
and was really surprised how many
information is collected there and not
all of them can be downloaded with
Google Checkout so for for today we'll
talk about them
iCloud security and so they were really
interesting tools earlier today and
yesterday about the authentication about
access about two-factor authentication
and what I think
couple of things were missing and a
really important he'll secure your date
is actually in the cloud
what if someone get a physical access to
that data to their servers and what
someone whether it is a hot air or
someone working for law enforcement can
get from your a cloud or any other cloud
account if they have proper credentials
what if they have your password and do
they really need the second factor what
if they have both what information can
be accessed and what not we we we know
that there is quite a lot of data in the
cloud available and we'll check how
secure it is there is a kind of timeline
related to two Apple iOS and Android
Cloud iCloud appears first time about
seven years ago with I was five and the
next year were released the software to
download iCloud the Cubs when I bet and
that was actually my idea I came to the
developer and said why not to try to
download iCloud backups he said for what
you can always restore the backup to the
to the actual device but we still
decided that it might be really
interesting and useful for people and so
for usual regular customers and for law
enforcement as well then we realized a
lot of very interesting things how the
data is stored how it is encrypted I
will learn that three last backups are
stored in the cloud and that they
incremented and how they're splitted by
shanks and every chunk is encrypted and
what actual physical servers they're
store at one next year the iCloud
keychain was introduced by Apple we well
almost immediately we tried to to get
access to it but it was really much
harder than getting access to the iCloud
backup sent to other data was successful
but only at several years later only
into 2014 to 2-step verification has
been
introduced by Apple and at that time it
was protecting collie only Apple
purchases at the Apple Store for the
software and for music and 2sv didn't
protect iCloud backups I didn't know
what happened next you probably remember
that and August 2014 celebrate when the
private pictures pictures of over the
hundred celebrities were leaked and they
were taken from from their iCloud
accounts and two years later we realized
that that several persons used our
software to do that I don't know should
be proud of that or not but anyway that
happened and there's the same the same
year and probably on the same month the
iCloud account of Russian Prime Minister
Dmitry Medvedev was also correct
we never know who do that who did it and
who actually what software has been used
but anyway so it is a huge security risk
but soon after that Apple introduced the
2sv for iCloud account for for iCloud
backups as well and a bit later
iOS 8.1 has been released with iCloud
photo library I have decided to include
that item there because that that that
means that by default all the pictures
made with your iPhone immediately go to
the to the iCloud even if you iCloud
backups are not enabled of course if you
can disable that option to you with iOS
9 to 2 step verification has been
changed to two-factor authentication and
for some time for about 2 years I think
they coexisted and and later Apple
allowed only to enable 2fa but not not
2sv and i should say that to to fa is
much more secure by default the second
factor is is being sent not by SMS which
is not secure but with the push
notification and also if someone trying
to access your icloud account you get
the education on all your trusted
devices immediately this
second including the actual location of
the computer
Ohio's device this account has been
accessed here and there were also other
security measures and I both started to
push aggressively there to FA and it was
a really good idea
always when when installing the setting
up the new iPhone and transferring from
from Bakar installing the new version
you always get a warning that it is
highly recommended to 2fa and also the
same year with us 11 the health data is
started to sing between the devices and
iCloud I don't remember unfortunately is
it is it enabled by the by default and
note I think it is disabled by default
but but my name many people enable
because it is really convenient and
allows you to sync across devices with
Alice 11.4 messages including kind
message and SMS also going to to the
cloud it was actually promised to
release it with us 11 but I don't know
the reason for for the ways it was in
first 3 beta versions of a celeb n' then
this just disappeared and then appeared
again in some later versions in also and
better and it is actually only in us
around point for release and it is still
not working really stable there are
still a lot of bugs syncing the messages
across devices and with us 12 now there
is a nice physical screen time it is
enabled by default and a lot of data is
collected on the iphone and it is can it
can be also synced across devices
through the iCloud did this year Apple
has made it several nice moves improving
that their security also mentioned the
messages and screen time and I should
know that those two features I mean not
the fish the cell is syncing that data
with the cloud is only possible if you
enable 2fa because it Apple probably
decided that it that's
it's much more secure and that's right
move also the some changes have been
made to authentication tokens since some
time ago we realized how to access
iCloud accounts using Java tokens
extracted from the proper authenticated
I was device from Markov windows
computer and so getting the data in if
you don't have a password and even
without that second factor it is now
much harder the tokens on out
tied to the computer and was we are
looking for working around and really
close to that and for the combination of
s 11.2 and later versions and two-factor
authentication so now we cannot download
iCloud backups anymore even if we have
an iCloud password and a second factor
and anything else what it what is needed
so there are some checks that data being
done by the iCloud service that that
that that actually verify that the
downloading process has been initiated
from the actual iOS device but not from
the computer you also find a workaround
also really close to that ok to
understand how secure your data first
have a look what it is actually stored
in the cloud and that's not a very easy
equation as as you might think the first
thing to tries just to go to iCloud
settings on your iPhone quite a lot of
buttons and with a every new evolution
you get a couple of new ones but
actually not all the categories are
listed there for example try to find an
option to disable call log syncing with
the cloud if you found that maybe about
a year and a half ago we have conducted
several several journalists about that
hey see that Apple doesn't say that and
there is no option to disable but once
you enable the iCloud in general you
immediately get your audio incoming and
outgoing calls the metadata coming to
the to the crowd why is that they did
day later I have received the cool and
when my bell phone from Apple and there
were two people from Apple on the way
and one from marketing department I
think the second one from the security
department I have explained in the
toriel's what we have found and also I
even mentioned that this is not about
the continued to feature about accepting
the incoming kill on the other device
this is absolutely not and not related
you can disable continuty and steal all
your co logs will go to the cloud the
next day Apple issued the official
statement explaining that this is only
for user convenience and this is only
about the continued decision so we had
to publish the blog a blog article about
that some options actually require the
iCloud keychain to to be enabled to in
order to work and it is also not obvious
what is really under the iCloud drive
and in fact there is a lot of
third-party application data there is a
nice cloud kit ago from from Apple you
can use the iCloud for storage and also
for syncing your data and many
applications can create their own
backups in own the iCloud right there is
an iCloud like an add-on in in both
Windows and Mac OS and you can see some
files but mostly documents on the iCloud
drive but note the third-party
application data actually you actually
you don't have an idea of what is stored
there checklist number two its it's a
very short and simple one you can give
just to icloud.com and see what
categories are there and you will not
see much contacts calendars the mail
anybody is using iCloud mail I don't
think so nodes and and things like that
not too much that the next thing is much
better there's a privacy doe table
dot-com side it first appeared and has
been seriously improved with the new
European Luigi DPR
and you actually took all the companies
has been forced to to allow users to see
what date is available on them and
allowing kills who to correct the data
to delete the data and so on first it
was introduced only in in Europe then it
was extended to United States and Canada
and about two weeks ago it's it's now
also available in Russia and about 10
other countries including Mexico someone
in Asia and soon I don't have an idea
about China probably not the interesting
thing that is back Copsey this is your
personal data but the cops are not
available through that that side and the
most interesting data is hidden under
the item other data and sexually about
the the iCloud okay
so anyone if you are happy enough to
live in the country where that site is
available you can log on pass two-factor
authentication or without a fail you'll
probably have to answer the security
questions and then she put the check
boxes near the categories you want to
get and then wait exactly one week I
also don't know why is that even if
there is no such much data there Apple
is first I thought that Apple is
preparing the data for about a week but
then I give you the email from Apple
explaining that by taking a week for
checking wealth that I am the legal
owner of the data how how they do that I
have no idea but I still had to wait
let's check list number four it's also
very interesting it is available on the
Apple website it's under the government
and information request and Apple dis
describes but not in a very high detail
what they can do and what what data they
can provide for for for the given iCloud
account are you you here you have to
loot
work for law enforcement of course too
to be able to send such requests and but
it's actually a lot and some of that
date is not available by other means but
probably it's about the same what is
available under the GDP are including
backups and there is also some metadata
about the FaceTime calls so once we pre
we know I stole that for items and we
are still exploring we're also checking
the the data being transferred between
Apple devices and Apple iCloud and to
see the records there it was not really
easy to implement when the middle attack
and because their certificates are
pinned to their device we were able to
fool that for the jailbroken devices
only and even with a jailbreak for as I
was 11 it was really hard but but then
we realized that some extra data is also
being transferred yes iCloud sings a lot
of data that's not only about backups
and not only well the applications that
use them the iCloud and this is probably
like Google did that for many years and
then through it they still don't have
complete device backups in the Google
cloud but they were always singing and I
don't have when I change their Android
device to the to the new one you don't
need to restore it from the backup you
just connect it to your Google account
and and by syncing you get everything
back on on your device Apple Apple
started with with other idea with
complete iCloud backups and only then
started to sink more and more deta with
the clouds especially like several
categories like nodes I start right now
so an iPhone and continue on the on my
Mac and there is a health data yes inked
and photos and videos and passwords and
pay attention to the last item there is
a file Walt to recovery token if you
have selected that option and I think it
is enabled by default then the recovery
talking for you mark
all right we'll also store it in the
cloud that's not the recovery key that
you can enter manually and it it's not
easy to do creep back up with they're
talking you have to use two third party
software but it is still possible and
that is stored in the cloud so anyone
with the proper credential will will be
able to get most of that data I know
that many people disable their cloud
backups but they still have most of the
case I quote related categories enabled
so let's move to protection and
encryption and there is an article on
the Apple website on the knowledge base
and let's say that 128-bit encryption is
being used and some data use so code and
to ant encrypted data such as like
categories these are human either health
iCloud keychain payments information
your credit cards see the information
Siri actually works seems to work only
one way we know that the data is there
but one table to go to get it sofa and
those categories use strong encryption
what does that actually mean if if all
the data is already encrypted why there
is a reason to encrypt it stronger but
let's also realize now the first thing
that protects your iCloud that is
obviously the Apple ID password and then
the two two-factor authentication to a3
is actually not available anymore it is
still being used on some all the devices
but you won't be able to enable it on
there you new ones
the problem is also pay attention to the
last item the encryption key is store it
alongside with the data that's like
leaving the key right right near the
door that's physically the location is
not exactly the same the actual date is
and the cloud is located on different
servers actually all over the world
but the keys for the data store it only
at Apple in Cupertino at the data
centers but once you have the proper
credentials the Apple ID and password
and second factor is needed you get both
for every chunk of data you get you sent
the first records please give me the
data then next file you get the URL
download it and then the second records
like please give me the key for it the
location of the key ends with the next
step you get the key then you'll have to
unwrap it and to apply to to decrypt all
those chunks to compile all those chunks
into into actual files so that's a long
and not very easy process but still the
encryption key is store it alongside
with the data at first time we saw that
they store it all together at the same
servers and so anyone with the physical
access to the server will be able to
decrypt all the data but that's not the
case fortunately the keys are stored and
it's at some other servers we are still
not sure about China we try to trace
where the actual data end where the keys
are stored whenever whenever that the
date is now stored for the Chinese
iCloud accounts only in China data
centers what about the keys that what
actually makes it news about that
someone from Apple said that no the key
so all belongs to us Chinese government
says that we push table and also we now
own the keys so it's not really and we
weren't able to trace up to the last
point where the the keys are actually
store it now about data that is
protected more secure yeah it is really
more secure and let's start with the
iCloud keychain that's that that's
probably that that's a hidden gem there
all your passwords are there just most
of the people but oh okay I'll try to
get faster
the bezels are there and the the keys
for some other data to store store it in
some some cloud key keychain sing
special service and to access the cloud
keychain a login and password and the
second factor are not enough you will
also need to to enroll the device to
make it trust it something like that to
go into the trusted circle and only that
way you'll be able to access the
keychain data and for that you need to
know the passcode of the one of the
trusted devices and there were also some
changes to authentication tokens that
they're now short-lived the some time
ago the least well actually almost
forever then the time was cut to 30 days
then for just 24 hours and now sometimes
they relief from only only one hour ok
where the date is actually stored if you
curious they store it in Microsoft Azure
storage at Google and Amazon 80 AT&T my
data I'm located in Russia and they have
a Russian Apple ID it is also stored at
Google some somewhere in Europe and
belief there is a law in Russia that
force company store that personal data
also in Russia and it it's a low for for
about three years and able seem to agree
but still the data is is still not not
not in Russia yet I will probably skip
that you you should know how hackers get
the password talks as the account that
the first item is phishing of course
it's obvious you can reset password you
can put the key logger on the device and
the last one is also really works it's a
rabbit hole criminalizes okay about
two-factor yes you have you need to
access that cloud data you need one of
the possible second factors you you need
to access the trusted device
[Music]
there is still an option to authenticate
by SMS and it it seems to be always
available when I try to access that they
can boost notification is being saying
to all the devices but now there is it
is also possible to switch to SMS okay
about tokens ow that's actually a huge
huge topic we have found how to extract
the authentication tokens from PC and
Mac computers if the computer is locked
on into the cloud you get the token
that's binary data we can decrypt it and
then use that token to access all that
well most of the cloud data without
password and without the second factor
okay some change let's hear the tokens
historic I'm sorry I didn't expect that
it take so much time about two-factor
authentication as well yeah there are
two to two other special categories like
messages and I protected yes much better
to access messages stored in the cloud
you first you need to access them now
iCloud keychain first and they in the
cloud keychain you can find the key that
that encrypts the other key store it in
CC kks storage and use that key to
decrypt all the messages and also the
mesh attachments so that's that that's
not easy
also you should know that there are
actually three modes of the keychain and
they all working the different way and
actually the most secure one is will the
accounts with no to two second factor
and within no iCloud security code has
been set up in that case the kitchen
data will be synced directly across
their devices but not through the iCloud
itself so we won't be able to get their
iCloud keychain okay here is an example
of the software that that is downloading
the iCloud keychain we only need to
select one of the trusted devices you
see that I have many and some of them
are actually old and not connected
anymore to the account and we know the
password length for for iOS devices and
any one should work we pretend to be the
trusted device and we authenticate and
we get complete access to the cloud that
here is a part of the data downloaded
from the iCloud keychain I will actually
say that the iCloud keychain contains
only passwords and nothing else this is
not true
the last stop is about tokens and you
can see that there are a lot of tokens
for Facebook for Twitter for what's up
for several other sites like LinkedIn so
once you get access to the iCloud
keychain you you basically get access to
to everything to all the other accounts
ok about screen time knew I was twelve
feature it also can synced with the
cloud and it is also protected about the
same way as message we and that data
cannot be obtained from the from backup
but only directed directly from the
cloud and it is not saved when it
changed their device and restore and so
it's a good idea to save it in the cloud
and we're still working on there that's
one of the biggest challenges we have
had because there is no jailbreak for us
12 yet about health I know that my time
is over
oh there is no sound hey you promised
that they will be sound there oh but
that's actually part of the presentation
in September with announce of new Apple
watches and they were talking about the
privacy saying that the health data is
stored is always encrypted on the device
and a cloud and it's a pity that we
cannot hear the sound
anyway you will get a copy of the
presentation and and fear that Apple
says that all the data is is securely
encrypted and it should be peer to peer
encrypt it as we have seen at the other
side but on another article it says that
Apple does store the
of data both is true there are two
containers related to apple health one I
seek you and the second is not really
secure the secure one is like the
messages to retain the cloud and so you
need to access the iCloud keychain first
and the other one is open to anyone who
has the authentication token and don't
don't even need their know that that
passcode from their device and also
there are really important security risk
related to 2fa I should say that the
device with two FA and the passcode it
might be not really as secure as you as
you think
speaking on the iCloud if someone will
get access to a device and know the
passcode he can do everything about your
iCloud account without knowing your
actual iCloud password haven't even
changed the password tent at his own
trusted trusted phone number that's the
links you will get in the presentation
the for the rating explaining everything
about the keychains security and
encryption in the iCloud cool that's it
sorry
Oh 30 minutes exactly
[Applause]
you