[Music]
i would like to welcome to the states
our next presenter
michael holberg
presenting 5g transport network
requirements and architectures
michael is a distinguished systems
engineer at extreme networks
this is his second time presenting at
nanog and we're very happy to have him
speaking to us
michael there it is
all right good afternoon
so
uh
everything is moving to the cloud and
basically your network is is no
expectation no no exception in that
sense
so
one key thing i i kind of believe based
on the previous uh presentation is that
that you know 5g
is the first cloud native
mobile technology generation
and
looking at that 5g is much more than
just radio and core it's things like
like
management orchestration
you know
software defined networking
uh it is things like like policy driven
ai and ml
and transport
so
i'm going to spend the next 30 minutes
kind of talking through the same uh
kind of of
you know topic as the previous
presentation i think for people who
actually are not that
into the 5g part the transport part
i think it was a
quite deep dive the previous
presentation by igor
so i'm going to touch on on quite a lot
of the same things that igor touched on
but i'm going to try to actually you
know
simplify a bit of things and and
pinpoint you know this more from a a
network point of view
and
with that said uh let's move into to
kind of
going through these things so
how i want to start this is
i said
more like like
you know uh building up or or or
building up the picture for you here i
think ego touched on on you know the
previous generations
being the 2g 3g lte
compared to 5g
but i wanna i want to start this with we
truly compare those two because there is
a huge difference
in the transport network requirements as
i get guess that many of you guys kind
of have realized based on the previous
presentation
so
if you look at 4g
you know
4g is one key service
it's one shared transport network
it is best effort and it's basically you
know latency is not that critical
then you go into the things like the
point-to-point backhaul so for 4g you
are actually using lead to point to
point backhaul carrier ethernet is
completely fine for that
and then you have a simple a single run
architecture basically for that one
so
looking at 5g
first of all 5g is
service average service driven
architecture
which basically means that you have
four things predefined
run is one thing 5g core is the second
thing
the hyperscalers is the third thing
and the fourth thing is transport
and obviously as i said i'm going to
touch on the transport part more on the
network
side of it
in addition to that one on the previous
presentation you heard about network
slicing isolation how would you be able
to actually have to say the same network
providing
multiple different isolated slice slices
for different services
so you truly go into different you know
slicing mechanism splicing types you
have a you know
service slice or the service instance
layer you have your resource instance
layer
and then you have your network instance
so as you can see it started to build up
the the picture here of
5g
5g being far more complex than than the
previous generations
so then you go into i said hand in hand
with network slicing you have things
like like multiple different
applications consumer based you know it
could be the enterprise based things
so you start to look at that
traffic classes could be best for
traffic
could be you know
things like like the enhanced mobile
broadband which basically bandwidth is
the key requirement for that one
or it could be low latency applications
where you probably have heard of the the
kind of you know
so many times used
use case for that one which is
autonomous cars
which basically means that it's truly
latency sensitive
and that's kind of referred to as the
url
you know
use case
now
with that you start to look at actually
having
traffic within an area or region being
cu to cu communication
and then as we heard in the previous uh
presentation you start to actually move
the routing boundary more out towards
the edge
which basically means that that instead
of with 4g and the previous generations
where you actually had point-to-point
backhaul
now you start to move into
you know a dynamic
multi-destination
connectivity type for the x-hole part
here
then you actually have multiple run
architectures in the previous uh
presentation
it was not really covered you know the
different trend architectures that you
have there
and then
you start to virtualize things so you
virtualize your core
and then you have your control plane and
user plane is virtualized
in the previous presentation
he was igor was touching on on the ceo
and the du part the cu part being
basically the control plane and the user
plane
while the du part is actually then the
latency sensitive radio functions
and as i said if you start to virtualize
those that means that you actually move
them out from
the the specific purpose-built hardware
so these two to kind of set the stage
here for for what i'm going to to
basically talk about here the next 20
minutes or so
so looking at the different uh
network architectures
so overran was kind of discussed in the
previous presentation as well
overrun is not an architecture per se
it's more like the the
you know the definition of how you would
then uh
use uh multiple vendors equipment
to build a radio network so i'm going to
touch on on the distributed run
this is as as was kind of pinpointed in
the previous presentation as well the d
run is the traditionally integrated base
station with backhoe connection to the
first part of aggregation there
then you go into the centralized tran
which is basically an architecture in
which the base station is split into two
parts
the base band unit
and the radio head
now
continuing on that path then you have
the virtualized ran the vran or cloud
run whatever you want to call it
which is basically an evolution of the
centralized track
which basically consists of a
centralized pool of the baseband units
and virtualizing the the run control
functions and service delivery
so with the virtual run the base plan
modules is actually moved away from the
base station to the data center
which now means that now you start to
actually run those functions
on computes
so you virtualize everything
so is your network report prepared for
5g transport
i'm going to kind of ignore the the
upper part of this slide
where you talk about the the different
bands you know you have the millimeter
wave you have to see bands things like
that
and instead
kind of pinpoint the the transport
requirements and the technologies i
think the technologies became pretty
clear in the previous presentation
but the transport requirements from a
capacity interface and swing point of
view
so so looking at capacity you know the
previous generations actually as you can
see you had a few hundred migs capacity
need for that one
now with 5g you actually go into you
know 20 gig or also capacity need
and this goes back to my previous
statement saying that okay if i'm going
to go from purpose-built hardware
into running those functions on computes
that's obviously going to put a demand
on more capacity
in addition to that which is pretty
clear is that obviously you need to have
you know the the interfaces on your
computes is going to move into like
2 times 10 or even 25 gig on the compute
side
to be able to cope with those functions
running on computes
and then as we heard you go into the you
know background the frontal part
moving from from cpr into c e c p and
things like that
and multiple you know run architectures
as as
previously kind of of you know i alluded
so
this is a pretty busy slide but if if
you now look at the you know upper part
of this slide
it clearly shows that you go from a
radio head and your baseband unit into
virtualizing those in 5g so you have
your virtualized du and ceu
which is
as said the series the control plane the
user plane the du is
the virtualized you know latency
sensitive radio functions
so truly looking at the lower part of of
this you know illustration
you see clearly the 4g part which was
touched on on the pre in the previous
presentation
your back hole and your front hole
front hole being tdm because it's secret
traffic
while now on the 5g model you start to
look into the mid hole and the back hole
part
which truly have the requirements of
dynamic multi-point connectivity
compared to the 4g model where you
actually point to point connectivity
based only to carrier ethernet
and then on the front hall side you
start to move into a packet based based
uh
infrastructure data due to the fact that
you have easy pre-running which we heard
is a packet based technology
as well as the radio or ethernet there
so that on a kind of high level
to set
you know the foundation for for
this talk going further so
the crown part or or the virtualized
trend or the cloud run
now
i've been kind of alluding to the fact
that that you start to virtualize things
so if we think back like a couple of
years
it would have been pretty unlikely for
service providers to actually think
about you know virtualizing their
networks
so 5g came with force
and with 5g came actually new demands
for for more flexible architectures
as well as designs and and deployments
and more scale
as i have kind of been alluding to in my
previous slides here
so so with that in mind and when you now
start to virtualize those functions what
you actually see in this illustration is
a hub and spoke model
where
in the spoke you have your your radios
so be it a light bulb you know a light
sorry a a you know radio sitting on a a
macro site sitting in in any kind of a
site we do understand that with 5g you
get into much higher density from a
radio point of view
so so ignoring for now the frontal part
which is packet based easy as we learned
in the previous presentation
looking at the hub site in the hub site
you now start to see some kind of a data
center fabric
and that data center fabric depending on
if you talk about the deep edge the edge
could be of various sizes it could be a
small you know two node fabric
or it could be as you can see in the
illustration here a
three-stage claw architecture spineleaf
architecture
running things like like you know bgp on
the ip underlay together with evp and vx
and on the overlay
to connect the computes
as we previously kind of learned that
that the computes are now going to to
host your ceo and the du functions
running you know on on
kind of generic compute platforms
and now you start to look at actually
moving the 5g radio functions
into
using computes which is you know cuts
hardware with some kind of aggregators
in addition to that you now run those
kind of 5g
or those run functions
on on
microservices running on on containers
on bare metal servers
you start to utilize you know cloud
native technologies like kubernetes for
that one
and then you know adapt to devops
principles for that one
and now the key thing is that you also
talk about life cycle my end-to-end life
cycle management here which is then
basically going to be not only for for
your radio part but also your transport
part meaning you know things like
management orchestration automation all
those different things
hitting truly the run and the transport
part of that
so so this to kind of build an overall
picture of you know
as i mentioned on my
kind of first slide that that 5g is
going to be a huge
you know
have a huge difference to the previous
generations of
the mobile networks in regards to the
transport part there
we kind of heard in the previous uh
presentation about this one as well the
sales side gateways which actually start
the modulatory boundary more towards the
edge due to the network slicing things
and due to the fact that you start to
isolate different services
based on the service types
so
this is more or less a kind of recap of
the previous presentation as well but
anyway i want to kind of mention this
you have different use cases
applications defined for 5g
hence you had a network slicing and and
you have used cases like like
the enhanced mobile broadband which is
an sd van like use case or application
where you basically need bandwidth right
it's it's not latency sensitive as such
then you have the urlc
use case which you know using the kind
of famous example for that one is the
autonomous driving
and that is obviously latency sensitive
so now you start to to see traffic that
might be within an area or region
mean that you basically have now traffic
you know going within an edge data
center could be cu to cu communication
there
that's why you start to see now you know
the demand for for
multi-destination connectivity for 5g
and then you have things like industry
40 iot
obviously having things like like
security in mind qos so on and so forth
so clearly you can see that you have
different applications use cases having
different demand
based on on what they are
so
kind of picking on the previous use case
for
urlc where you know you talk about
latency
so obviously as we heard in the previous
presentation as well ptp is kind of of
one of the key factors that your network
do need to support going forward for 5g
transport
so just to recap what is ptp
it's a protocol for distributing precise
time and frequency over packet networks
defined in the ieee standards the first
kind of version
was released back in 2002 which targeted
the lan applications the second version
was actually released 2008
which kind of brought the telecom
network into the picture
and there is a third version under
discussion as we kind of heard in the
previous presentation as well
so so in a nutshell with ptp time is
carried in event messages
and these event messages are transmitted
from the the
grand master clock to the slave clocks
we kind of heard about the ptp you know
here in the previous presentation as
well
it runs over even uh ethernet and ip
and
you basically have
two different flavors of this
you have the archipelago 2.1 cm
which is aimed towards i said the
carrier word and then you have d802.1 ba
which is more aimed towards abb and
industry automation
obviously both of these falls under the
tsa umbrella defined in the 82.20 queue
which basically defines
deterministic messaging over ethernet
networks
and
we kind of heard about you know the the
telco part here with things like clock
preemption
which allows you to blend the ethernet
traffic and see pretty easy free traffic
we also heard about the radio ethernet
which is a way of
the secret traffic into ethernet
so
going into the profiles these profiles
were discussed in the previous
presentation as well but i just want to
recap this because they are kind of
important so so
in short back in in 2008
when you basically had the first ptp
version defined for the telecovered you
also had the first ptp profile defined
which was referred to as the
8265.1
which defined the support for frequency
synchronization over the telecom
networks and obviously it was used for
for
the the
cell base station synchronization
now
going forward as we heard you have two
new profiles
you have the g8275 one which is the full
timing support and the 8275.2 which is
the partial timing support
and
as we heard in the previous presentation
there is a main difference between those
ones now
the
8275-1 the full time in support do
require boundary clock at every node
within your network
each node within your network needs to
actually have ptp support supporting
boundary clocks
and obviously the intent with this one
is that you reduce the timer
accumulation accumulation through the
network
uh
we heard about it it's
you know
recommends the use of synchronous
internet for synchronizing the boundary
clock to stable frequency
and
it operates only to ethernet networks
and supports multiple active ground
monsters for redundancy
the second one which was touched on as
well is the for the partial timing
support
and
the intent of this profile is obvious to
be able to support current networks not
everybody have the luxury of greenfield
installs so you need to support current
you know infrastructure you have in
place to be able to actually provide you
know the frequency time and phase
synchronization of those networks
so the key features of the the you know
the apache time support profile is it
operates our existing switches and
routers using
unicast ip
it uses boundary and transpo transparent
clocks where necessary
and then supports multiple active grand
masters
for redundancy as
the previous 8275.1 profile as well
so
to put this into some contexts i don't
think this was kind of
went true as such in the previous
presentation but
to kind of
explain the illustration here it's quite
clear that you need to have
some kind of sync between your base
station and your grand master and then
ptp is kind of a mechanism to be able to
do that
what you can see in this illustration is
basically that you have your grand
master clock
which is a boundary clock
responsible for generating the ptp
packet which is then going to be
obviously transported over your network
or all the way over to each and every
base station or sales site
which means that you basically have a
path for each and every sales
each and every base station here to your
network
in addition to that one the the grand
master clock is going to derive its
referencing from from a gns satellite in
this example as we kind of heard in the
previous presentation as well
so
on a higher level this is actually how
how you kind of start to look at this
one from a ptp point of view
now
as we heard in the previous presentation
as well you have kind of the magic
number of three microseconds
this is the
3 gpp
defined t a e stands for the total uh
for for the the
alignment error the the uh
which is a relative measurement
so
what happens here is so so sorry so the
ta is tae stands for the timing
alignment error
which basically means that
how it's defined is that you
have actually three microseconds
uh tae between any two ru's
so
that basically means that
between any ru and your time in grand
master you basically have the 1.5
microsecond as your tae defined
now
that more complex into this you have
things like the the coordinated
multipoint which obviously goes hand in
hand with the fact that 5g
is is going to have high density of of
you know the the
cell sites installed so you basically
have you know the same network to
provide connectivity for for many many
base stations
so it's fair to say that that you know
accurate timing is no longer nice to
have it is truly required
and
testing timing is a large new you know
challenge for the csps how would you
test things like this as we are talking
about you know the three microseconds
and then 1.5 microsecond here
as the figures
so
there is a
mechanism in place for that one so so
you have a couple of key factors for
accurate synchronization
so
the factors that make the
synchronization poor are actually to you
have the dte and the cte so the dt
stands for the dynamic and the ct stands
for the the
constant
now the ct is the ptp packet latency
asymmetry
while the dt is the ptp packet latency
variation
so the illustration you can see there is
is basically a recap of what we were
where are we making the statement saying
that 1.1 microsecond is
your your total
tae within your network
so how comes 1.1 due to the fact that
you had 400 nanoseconds which add in the
over air so from a network point of view
your ta is 1.1 microseconds
so
how is this then then kind of dealt with
so i was mentioning when we talked about
ptp that you have your your event
message
so think of the event message being your
your the event message is the packet
flow you know or the packet timing
signaling and this is obviously then
derived from the fact that you start to
look at or compare your your you know t1
and t2 so your your timestamps t1 and t2
and then basically synchronize
accordingly based on those timestamps
within your ptp event message
so
this is an example of how you actually
build this up then
so
you have your 1.1 microseconds which is
the network-wide and then you have 1.5
which is you know from an end station's
point of view
so
the
how this builds up is that
you introduce your prtc or your timing
ground master which is then going to add
some kind of a
timing error due to the faith due to the
fact that it's going to place you know
the packet in or placing the time in a
packet
then you go into your network part which
is based on on the dt and the city part
the dynamic comes from you know the
random error due to sync ethernet for
instance and then your city the constant
is based on your network elements based
on your switches
that as we heard in the previous
presentation you have different classes
you have class a b and c
and those are going to introduce
different levels of timing alignment
errors
and then you have your link asymmetry um
delays which is basically your your
link delay link latency here
so this is from a network point of view
how you would measure this then
and then i said you get into your your
end application noise here
to basically have the 1.5 being your
your you know total that you have to
deal with
so
this was kind of a a pretty fast walk
through on on transport network
requirements obviously didn't touch on
on all of those
just more or less wanted to pinpoint a
few things that you need to take into
consideration when you start to build
these transport networks
so on that note this kind of concludes
my presentation
any questions
okay thank you
[Applause]
[Music]