[Music]
joining me on stage
here is edwards mcnair
and joining us remotely is elizabeth
culley we are presenting the nanog 84
committee meeting
edward is the executive director of
nanook elizabeth is the program
committee secretary
and i'm still augie meethiv the program
committee vice chair
we're all very happy to be addressing
you again today
good morning everyone i hope you guys
are all doing well and have survived the
festivities of the night before
um we've got a kind of a tight schedule
so i'll kind of jump right into things
so
first thing i'd like to talk about is
the icann isak nanog
outreach efforts
the first fruits of those laborers are
starting to come about and
they've been pretty magnificent for the
short period of time that we've been
working on them our goal is to
collaborate together bring our resources
together and see how we can better
outreach efforts within north america
and our early accomplishments are that
isec will be sponsoring individuals to
from underserved regions to attend nanog
events very much like the nci program
that we have
nana will also leverage our discourse
community forum as a way to support
outreach efforts within the underserved
regions so that we can get um
volunteers to scan those
discourse lists and to be able to help
people once they leave the events to be
able to get that the help and resource
they need to continue to support their
community communities
um icann has also submitted a talk for
nano 85 coming up in montreal
and nana will also be presenting at
icon
73 so we're trying to find ways that we
can collaborate together to further
outreach initiatives within north
america
development updates
so these are lists of some of the
projects they're going to be working on
for
2022. uh first and foremost is the
meeting appointment tool we know that's
been something that's been a strong
demand for the community and also from
our sponsors and we're addressing that
features functionality and scope of work
have been shared with our community beta
testers for feedback
we've started ui development on it
and once that once the ui is complete
within the next 30 days we'll pass it on
to our beta testers for evaluation and
for comments and feedback um once that
is all cleared out we start working on
the backend functionality with the goal
of having a uh
beta in nanog85 in montreal and then the
final version to be released
at nanog86
in addition at 96 we're going to bring
back our on-demand
on-demand batch printing service so you
will get your badges print this right
away at printers and queues and we'll
also be making some extensive updates to
the program
uh committee tool
uh nano community forum so um the
network community forum is a
as a piece that we're trying to help and
expand how we can outreach to our
community how we can get people involved
in the conversation how can we maintain
community beyond our meetings um right
now we meet three times a year and then
when you leave this place we're trying
to continue that conversation commit con
continue that community one of the
things that we're doing to extend that
is to have affinity groups so affinity
groups are designed to foster community
and self
organization groups
which would have expanded the community
form sorry
screw that
we're expanding the community forum to
include affinity groups they're designed
to allow
like-minded people you know who want to
have common who have common interests to
get together and to form groups and
interests that that they that they care
about um we've created a few groups to
get started and um but we if you
interested in a group that you don't
find in our forum you can just reach out
to us and we'll add it
so to give you kind of a an overview of
how it works and functions here's kind
of the home page of our community group
if you would look on your lower
i guess that would be for you the lower
left hand side you'd see a mailing list
scrolling down from there you'd see a
complete list of different groups that
you can intend to participate in
so for example i'm going to use the
example of the walking affinity group
so here's what it would look like all of
our groups can mirror a mailing list so
in this case if you see there's an email
address walking at community.net.org
you can
function it functions just like mailman
would you can send an email to it and
get an email response you can set up
your preferences to how you want to be
notified and i'll talk about that in a
minute if it's a group that you're
interested in if you look it over on the
which would be the uh right hand side
you'll see a little bell icon next to
topics if that's something you're
interested in being alerted on you can
click on that and then emails would come
to your notifications depending on how
you want to be notified if you look up
in the corner and up your right hand
corner you see a little icon of my face
that little indicator for me says i have
some messages that are there so either i
can see them when i log in i can get
them sent to me once a week i can get
sent to me daily i can get them sent to
me immediately just depending on how it
choose
so dinesh was wonderful to post in here
and dennis said morning walks so i
clicked on that and so here i saw
an insert for joining me on a morning
walk so the bottom you can see i said
sure love to so dennis and i had a about
a seven kilometer walk this morning
about two hours and had a lovely time
too bad for those who missed out
um if you look on the right hand column
underneath that little wrench icon it
says february 15th the date of the entry
and how many
uh
replies were associated with that
likewise in that little lower bottom if
i wanted to only be notified about
what's going on in this post i could
click on the bell icon at the lower
right hand corner and i would only see
receive notifications on that particular
thread and not the whole thread in and
of itself so you have control on how you
can interact with it
in your preferences i can then talk
about notifications and here i've listed
emails so i can determine how often i
get emails related to this thread and
how they work or how the the the forum
in general
there's also drills down many
preferences you can set for yourself so
you can interact with it through a web
browser or you can also interact it
through via email
so is another example to look at here is
our mailing list so
we have a read only feed of the nano
mailing list that you can go into you go
to community.nano.org
you can search through it the complete
mailing list from it's from its
inception i guess there's something like
51 000 posts in here and you're able to
go in and find a post that you're
interested something recent piers
digging in so a recent post on vpn
connections again you can see off to the
right hand side this was posted on
february 10th there's one of
43 threads connected to it
how long ago was the last thread again i
can choose to be notified just on this
particular thread
and you can see there in the block who
all has connected and commented on that
thread so again right now mailman is
read only but just kind of give you an
idea of how the community service server
can work and function for you
so the affinity groups that we have
starting out will be
events in social gathering women of
technology diversity and tech coffee
kids
lbtqt plus
running walking whiskey connoisseurs
yoga automation dns ird rpki and
security again if there's any groups
that you're looking for that you're not
seeing please let us know we're happy to
add them for you
so if you have any suggestions please
send them to feedback at nano.org
so moving into program committee updates
up next we're going to have elizabeth
colley present elizabeth cully is the
program committee secretary um she also
works as a appearing coordinator for
comcast and um liz culley went down this
path of trying to explore how the
pandemic affected nanog events
and god bless her heart she went down
this rabbit hole and she found all this
data about our programs how they work
and how they operate
it's an amazing undertaking and my
little nickname for her is data because
when you see what she's done it's
absolutely amazing so that being said go
ahead and roll the video she couldn't
attend him personally but she's with us
in spirit
thank you for having me here today so
the purpose of this research project was
to see how the pandemic impacted nanog
attendance and it grew to look at how
nanog attendance has evolved over time
so we start with attendance data from 72
nanogs that we have records for
the records actually start in february
1998 in albuquerque and the average
number of attendees across all these
nanox is around 667
individuals per nano
what we see though is that there has
been a little bit of a difference
between 1998 and 2015 average attendance
was 515. between 2015 and the start of
the pandemic march 2020 the average was
over a thousand and for the past four
virtual nanos it's been around 745.
we do see that by season june anags are
14 more well attended than
february nanags which are around 596 on
average and the october november nana
kind of splits the difference and a lot
of people if you've been to nanak
recently you kind of wonder what was it
like all the way back then in 1012 where
nanox were much smaller
you know prior to the pandemic we were
having a thousand up to 1300 people at
namog and back in the day it was five
six hundred people and you can actually
find that out because today's in-person
attendance is close to 500 and so it's
basically like going back in time ten
years just to be at an anarch that is
much smaller and more intimate so what
we know is that eighteen thousand two
hundred and eighty two individuals have
come to nanag at least once the majority
of people so seventy seven percent
really only attend once or twice uh
there have four percent of people though
that's about 733 have come more than 10
times and i think we can kind of
consider these people to be regulars we
know that there were 210 people who
attended between 21 and 40 times 31 who
attended before between 40 and 60 times
and nine people attended between 61 and
70 times
there are
22 individuals who have attended more
than 50 times and this is a list of
people who have attended more than 50.
so we do have records missing for the
first 11 nanogs so these numbers are
relative they reflect only the 72 nanox
that we have attendance records for and
i just wanted to point out though that
the people on this list
are not just people who have attended
nanog very often these are people who
have contributed hugely to nanag as an
organization
we know that steve and patrick are
currently on the board of directors avi
richard and tony are giving talks at
this nanag if you put together all of
the presentations that john bill mark
aaron and dwayne have given it's almost
a hundred that's enough talks to
completely fill
four three-day nanogs with talks ren joe
jared greg and tony have all served on
the program committee and on the board
of directors in the past betty was our
previous executive director
and we have on this list people from
other industry organizations that we're
close to we partner with we do business
with john leslie and mark from aaron and
aaron hughes from caring db
and this list also includes
founders of nano people who are there
from the inception like larry and steve
so we certainly appreciate all of these
individuals for everything that they
have done
so if you're at an anarch though while
75 of people
do really only come once or twice if you
are at an anag and you meet somebody it
is more likely that they will have been
to nanak several times before looking at
data from the past three years nine
nanox an average of 63 percent of
attendees have attended before and 37
are first-timers that first virtual nano
was inverted from the norm with 63
first-timers and 37 of her attorneys and
since then the average number of
first-timers has remained consistent
while the numbers of returnees has
fallen and sometimes you hear the
question asked you know as people
look around and say how many people here
at nanag are here to watch the speakers
and really attend the conference versus
how many are here to
do business and socialize and this chart
i think kind of answers that question
because if we look at
previous to the pandemic when we were
there in person we had an average of
around 750
returnees and after the pandemic when we
were really just virtual it's around 500
attorneys which is a drop off of around
250 individuals
so they dropped off because obviously
during virtual nano it's much more
difficult to socialize and do business
so 250 individuals across we don't know
the total number but it ranges from
around 25 to 40 percent could have been
of the attendees who are attending
previously no longer attending were in
theory there to socialize and do
business
so nanak has been
hosted in 38 different cities in north
america
this is the 35 cities that we actually
have attendance records for
uh the most frequently used city is san
francisco which was which we were at six
times followed by atlanta five times ann
arbor four times washington dc four
times in san jose four times and what
you're looking at here this graph is
showing the y-axis the vertical is
showing the average number of attendees
at this site and the number on top is
the number of times that we are at the
site so you can see that the virtual
nano had the most attendees total with
over a thousand and we had four virtuals
san francisco we had just under a
thousand on average and we've been there
six times chicago we had
750 and we've only been there once so
that is basically how to read this chart
of the 18 000 attendees who attended
they represented 4
781 different companies this data is
really the most surprising that i was
able to pull out of the
attendance records
18 of attendees that's 3 340
individuals
had at least one instance where they
specified no company affiliation
meaning they attended nanag without
saying who they were representing at
that point that's 12 that's 5990
instances of attendance where no company
was specified and i think this is really
interesting and it's something i'd
actually like to dig into a little more
why did this happen did this happen
because people couldn't be bothered to
put their company down or people really
attending nanag without even doing it
for their company or place of work i
think it's an interesting question so
these are the companies that most often
send representatives to nanog every
incremental number here is
not an individual it's an instance of
attendance by an individual and these
are companies that we all know and
you know work with and work for bionet
cisco and tt juniper and we certainly
appreciate all these companies who do
send their people to nanak so there were
247 different colleges and universities
that have been represented at nanog the
university of oregon
had the most instances of attendance
followed by the university of colorado
at boulder and usc
an average
there are at each nanag an average of
about 18 different schools in attendance
at nanog
so
in total across
all nanogs there have been
1711 it's about three percent 3.6 of
attendees who are there from a college
or university and then just looking more
closely at the past five years
both total numbers as well as a
percentage of attendees have fluctuated
so here on the left we're looking at the
total number of attendees for the past
five years averaging around 30 prior to
the pandemic that first virtual really
we got a huge jump to 124 attendees from
a university and then since then it's
that it's down to around an average of
maybe 30. and then on the right we have
percentages and we can see that that
first virtual nano where we had 124
university students that accounted for
almost 6 percent of all attendees at
that nanag you can see that number has
kind of fallen off since then from to
about two percent
so the number of colleges and
universities represented at each nano
fluctuated and so this chart is showing
how many we can see that prior to the
pandemic there was a peak of about 16
schools
represented well let's ignore the 65
different schools that were represented
in the first
virtual nanog
but afterward there have been really
even ignoring the 65 actually peak of 31
different schools per nanog and at the
last nano nano 83 there were nine
different schools and universities
represented
so finally i wanted to talk about nanox
sponsors so there have been 56 host
sponsors of nanook and we absolutely
appreciate the support of every sponsor
that we have
13 sponsors hosted more than once
and i wanted to kind of draw out here i
put red asterisks next to companies that
they either no longer exist they have
been bought they've changed names for
whatever reason
they're not around anymore and i
there was a debate about should we leave
the name of these companies on as is or
should we change them to whatever they
turned into and i think it's actually
more interesting this way as we look
back at the companies that have
sponsored nanog it's a little bit of a
throwback into time
so that's it i hope that you guys have
gotten something out of this
presentation and i look forward to
seeing everybody at future nanox thank
you
this was great uh thanks elizabeth um
we're going to continue next with the uh
updates the program committee updates
and we'll come back to
the q a towards the end
i'm here to share with you um
highlights of our
program committee strategy meeting that
was held in january of 21st of this year
the entire program committee joined and
this was a friday afternoon everybody
was very active kind of
spent time looking at reflecting back on
2021 the progress that we made
last year the potential changes that we
considered making
uh talked about lessons learned
and we also spent time looking ahead uh
kind of what should we focus this year
and
related to the program
structure
again i want to highlight that the
program committee continues to focus on
building the best program possible
we are passionate about that and
we continue to work hard
in the in that area
right perspective of last year we
improved the program flow by
introductions
we introduced scripts for session
moderators
um you probably noticed that
we think this is uh helps with uh most
more consistent experience
we started sharing um introductions with
speakers ahead of time and we found that
to be helpful to
help people prepare to come up on stage
kind of set the tone
also again elizabeth does a tremendous
job
with collecting data
and as edward mentioned we
we look to make
more decisions around data
this is something that we find to be
helpful
speaker surveys we
we evolved that to where we are
sharing allowing for speakers to compare
contrast their results with other
presentations
again the value of coming here we're up
on stage and presenting is that at the
end you get to
receive honest feedback to help improve
and
finally here within the program
committee we have a handbook
and this is where we document
kind of the roles and
the the things that we do behind the
scene to
build the program we added a checklist
for mentor mentee
training
this is just one example
potential changes that we talked about
is
considering we send annual or biannual
surveys
in addition to the service that we
receive during the conference
we also talked about implementing a net
promoter system
another topic was
the proposal to
allocate a budget
for us to enhance the program
uh again we're this i think this is a
good example where we continue to look
at what can we do to make the program
and if we had some funding would that
help
uh so we're working closely with
the board
uh to um
to hopefully get approval for that
in addition
automation
is key
for us to be faster and better what we
do
again behind the scene
the process is where if you submit a
talk
um a
program a member of the proving
committee is assigned and that person
helps you um
through the steps you have to follow
for
reviewing the talks and
there is a step there with voting every
member of the proven committee has to
vote
and
we
we found that if
if we have a way to notify on regular
basis
members of the program committee they'll
be more active in voting for talks so we
can submit talks
early on
and finally we are
as updates are made to talks to actual
presentations
we uh we look into uh
ways to um highlight that talk needs to
be revisited
and
again this is another way for us to
streamline the process of voting
lessons learned
quick observations on hybrid meetings
we continue to strive and do our best to
manage in person
versus pre-recorded obviously we have an
interest to
have people in person when possible
um also i think we found a good way to
balance with remote and in-person q a
and
with all the technologies that we have
available
related to panels we decided we're going
to either we're going to do a panel here
in person or either
fully remote we're not going to try to
do a hybrid
and
we're also looking to
start additional subcommitting
subcommittees within the
program committee so that we can
kind of have more focused uh
groups on certain areas and
empower
more the program committee members
and finally planning ahead um you know
we we talked about uh talked about
specific themes for upcoming analog
meetings
but as a requested popular topics again
an example is for our next nano meeting
in montreal june 6th is the
the 10th anniversary of ipv6
launch so that's going to be a big one
for us
um
starting to look at uh presentations
beyond just
tech talks but more around
helping develop soft skills
we found those to be well received in
the past so we'll continue to work on
that
and um uh one
one uh one small change we plan to make
is where we'll make it easier for you to
see as attendees if somebody's going to
be presenting in person
versus being virtual
now we're going to move into uh pose
thank you
so um we're having just one poll
question going today and if you guys are
interested in doing that poll here's
where you can link to it and get there
you can also go to our event page and in
our event page you'll see at the lower
bottom they'll say live poll and the
question that's being asked is
how are you planning to attend nanog85
are you planning to attend in person are
you planning to attend virtually are you
uncertain
are you going to wait till the videos
come out in
on youtube so just to get a feedback
from there
the poll won't appear on screen here but
if you go to our website you'll be able
to see those live poll results
which opens up because we had a really
compressed time which opened up for a
little bit of time for q a if anyone has
any questions for
aggie or myself
wow
you guys are still asleep
all right well that being said thank you
all for your time
[Music]