[Music]
i would now
like to introduce brian knight
presenting ingress and egress filtering
for service provider edge ports
brian heads the engineering time team at
knighto did i say that right okay
which is a business telecom provider his
team operates a service provider network
along with sd-wan and firewall services
this is brian's second time presenting
at nanak and we are certainly happy to
have him speaking with us today welcome
brian
sounds good
all right thank you all for coming and
for staying for
the final talk of the day
i know that
excuse me
i'm going to be giving a talk about
ingress and egress filtering at the
internet edge for service provider
networks today
i've only got 30 minutes so
let's get right to it
uh who am i my name's brian knight i'm
engineering director over at nytel
as53828 based out of chicago i've been
slinging packets for 25 years
we do
at 53808 we do business eyeballs uh
internet dia mpls vpns
layer 2 ethernet and sd-wan
there's my email and my linkedin so
so you can check out my profile
so in this talk i want to discuss
what was our motivation for doing this
project uh what were the key decisions
that we made i'll dig into a few select
uh packet forwarding scenarios
i'll talk about how we implemented uh
the filtering
i'll talk about what we saw when we
implemented the filtering uh and and
tested the filtering
and then finally a short list of
recommendations
um i'm sorry casey i might butcher your
name i'm sorry um casey decchio's dsav
team
from brigham young university in october
of 2020 notified us of dns spoofing
vulnerabilities for
the dns servers that we operate for our
customers
and their team was measuring
vulnerability to dns amplification
attacks
so when we got this email we found that
in fact uh dns spoofing was possible
mainly because we had no anti-spoofing
enabled on our network edge ports
we did a quick google search of course
and we could not find an easy how-to for
how to configure that anti-spoofing uh
on a service provider not work um so i
uh i did what uh what i often do is i
post it to nana again and pose the
question to
uh to the community and we found that
many eyeball networks uh in the nano
community did in fact do ingress
filtering
uh they would also do uh
they performed egress filtering
um they would also block invalid ips so
they would do ball gun filtering
uh they would block invalid ports as
well so uh ports such as netbios
microsoft file sharing sun rpc
uh and there would also block traffic uh
to critical infrastructure such as
router loopback ips and uh internal
point-to-point subnets
but even with this guidance we still
struggle to find a clear how-to uh and
template uh on on how to implement this
and and that's what this presentation
strives to be strives to be a template
for this
so one of the first resources that the
community recommended was bcp84
uh the title of that bcp is ingress
filtering for multi-home networks
perfect for what we were looking for
uh it outlines five techniques for
anti-spoofing measures
those those five techniques really boil
down to a static
access control list placed on edge
interfaces
versus unicast reverse path forwarding
checks
bcp84 has the same overarching goal as
bcp38 bcp38 has been widely
socialized within the community
but 38 mainly deals with filtering um
traffic from single home sites into the
service provider network so these are
service provider customers
sending traffic back in
bcp 84's audience however uh includes
any multi-home network um so it's
perfect for a service provider network
because it is
they're typically widely multi-homed
um
bcp84 deals mainly with security at the
data plane so please don't throw out
your your route maps and your prefix
list you still need those at the control
plane not that anybody here would but
please don't throw those
out so going into some of the decisions
that we made um as we looked at bcp 84
instead of these acls really seemed to
be the only way
we looked at i mentioned a moment ago
that it has five anti-spoofing
techniques so i'll run through those uh
real quick
[Music]
it it talks about uh loose reverse path
forwarding
loose rpf
uh says that if a route exists within
the routing table except the packet
uh regardless of what interface it comes
on
that we felt had too little granularity
we wanted to make sure that
if a packet is accepted we wanted to
make sure that there was a valid route
going back to it not just at an existing
route
so we rejected that
um
there's a degenerate case where loose
rpf will ignore the default route
so
again that isn't going to work for our
case
strict rpf on the other hand takes us in
the other direction
and says if the route exists in the rib
and the packet came from the best
destination interface then except the
packet
um
that would be fine except for
uh when that when the route or when the
packet arrives on an interface and it
happens not to be the best path at that
moment
there's a risk then that the packet
would be dropped so that was too strict
feasible rpf is the uh the fifth
uh
technique that's discussed
if the route exists in the rib
and the packet comes in on any valid
destination interface
then accept the packet so in other words
if my bgp route for prefix
is received on multiple interfaces
even though my router is only going to
install one path
in the forwarding information base the
fib
inbound traffic would still be permitted
on both paths
that seems perfect for our application
except for it didn't seem to be an
option on ios xr
so
we decided on static acls
in terms of what to drop we decided that
we were going to
follow as many of the nanak
recommendations as we could uh we wanted
to block
invalid traffic on egress as well as
ingress
we wanted to block bug on traffic in and
out
we wanted to block multicast traffic as
well
any invalid services or ports should
also be blocked and initially we focused
on udp and tcp
port 0 and port 445
and then finally infrastructure uh we
said that except for icmp and traceroute
nothing
should be permitted to hit our router
loopbacks or internal point-to-point
links from outside
our network
so
for us uh being a smaller isp ease of
ease of administration was key
we said that the implementation should
be the same on every device so
what that meant for us was we wanted to
implement the same set of acls
configured the exact same way on all of
our edge routers
and we wanted to not only that we wanted
to use the same object groups even and
have the object groups have exactly the
same prefixes on every router that way
we could deploy a change and have it
consistently deployed across the entire
fleet
so i don't have time to go through every
packet forwarding scenario and i'm not
going to
um i i certainly don't have the time for
it but i do want to call out a couple of
uh of key ones so uh in this scenario
um we have a packet coming in from uh
from one of our upstreams uh sen uh sent
from someone out on the internet uh and
the source ip
is uh
is
one of the networks that we ourselves
originate
in this example so um the the service
provider network uh originates
192.0.2.0.24
packet has 192.0.2.1.
we want to make sure that that would be
that that would be blocked on ingress
however
for customers where we
would disaggregate some of our own space
and assign it to them uh to announce to
another provider
and you'll see in the corner uh where i
have uh as6449
originated networks um
assuming for the moment that you could
announce a slash 29 to the larger
internet and not uh not be blocked by
uh by a prefix list
what i have here is a packet originating
from 203.0.1
which falls within the originated
networks
coming uh
that we're assigned to six four four
nine nine
and
that packet is traversing their other
provider coming through
uh
the uh one of the service provider
networks up streams
coming back into
the sp network and we we want to permit
this because
if that link
uh to the uh to the service provider
network we still want to be able to
offer services uh to that customer even
though their connection to us may be
down
so we made a choice to permit that
traffic
just one other scenario
on egress
we have the uh with the the customer
again running bgp
they're originating some traffic uh that
isn't um
um
isn't part of their network set
so they would send a packet uh with some
bogus address
normally
our prefix lists to that customer should
catch that traffic and block it but in
case it doesn't in case of
misconfiguration we now have another
layer of protection
against that
that customer being able to send that
traffic outside of our
own uh as
so in terms of implementation
um
this is exactly what we did
we we implemented what we decided which
was uh we wanted the static acl approach
uh we configured the the four acls
inbound and outbound for v4 and v6 uh
made sure to configure the object groups
and
we achieved the goal of
making the content the same across all
of the routers
so i wanted to walk through some of the
object groups that we set up
uh the
uh the first three groups um uh the x
group purewan and tran win those all
contain the directly connected subnets
so
uh for the x for example uh it would be
the slice 24 or slash 23
um
put into that
put into that object group and then
referencing the acl
um
for pure and uh and tran when uh
as you can see it's the the slash
thirties slash 126 is
the uh
the ipv4 cust
those were our customer uh provider
independent and provider uh uh provider
assigned prefixes so anything that a bgp
customer
might uh might use and might uh send out
on our uh
on the uh
across their backup wan connection we
want to make sure that that traffic is
then permitted inbound
uh ipv4 and ipv6 bogon those are the
list of invalid prefixes uh ipv4 infra
that's all of our router the backs and
point to points that we wanted to
specifically uh protect
against outside attacks
and then uh bgp ag those are the uh the
prefixes that we would have configured
in our um
in our
network statements
in bgp on all of our routers
and then uh the last group is uh is an
interesting one
backdoor backdoor
was created for possibly valid traffic
uh that was uh observed during
implementation i'll get into that in in
just a little bit uh with the uh
in the observation section
there are four static acls uh
uh pv4i net n nine and out and then v6
and v6 out
in broad strokes this is what the acl
looks like this is the intent of the acl
the the very first uh part of it is
we're going to block the invalid um
prefixes the uh
the address base that's
that should never be used on the
internet
the
next we're going to block the invalid
ports then we're going to permit all of
the traffic to and from those transit x
and peering directly connected networks
then we deny multicast
next we permit where the source is bgp
customer ipspace so this is where that
uh
that path from the customer's uh backup
connection or primary connection um
can come back into the into our network
to be able to use services
uh next we deny where source equals
aggregate ipspace so this is our that's
our anti-spoofing rule
uh and then next we permit any traffic
where the destination
is our aggregate or our customers ip
space and then deny any at the end
on the egress side looks very similar we
start out same way denying bog on ips
denying invalid ports
we permit all traffic on the directly
connected networks deny multicast
we then permit where destination equals
customer ip space
it may seem a little bit odd but uh and
it is um what this does is it covers a
strange behavior that we uncovered
during testing and i'll get into that uh
when we get into the observation section
uh next we permit where the source is
the nitrile aggregate and customer ip
space that lets valid traffic out and
then deny any any at the end
so our plan was to create the initial
acls and apply them to to our ports
we enabled blocking for bagon ports
immediate or bargain prefixes
immediately
but
where rules were intended to be denied
we made them permit and log entries
for the testing period so that we didn't
accidentally block anything that was
bona fide traffic
and then our plan was to analyze the
logs for the matching traffic
and we would go then go through a cycle
of refining that acl until finally
unwanted traffic uh only on when excuse
me
only unwanted traffic was being logged
and then we would switch that uh that
permit to deny
so during our traffic review um
we uh we took the took the logs we
processed them into a big csv file
dumped it into excel uh created a pivot
table to summarize and view the data
cross-reference that with our systems
uh and what we saw uh was
that uh uh for bogon prefixes uh there
were no surprises there uh everything
that we saw that was logged appeared to
be
traffic that was unwanted
on the invalid port side we saw that
port zero uh initially we saw a lot of
random traffic
and
we um
as we dug into it we found that ios xr
actually logs fragments with port zero
because the router doesn't have
necessarily the full um
layer 4 information so it defaults to
port zero so we saw we saw this long
list of uh of ports and
we're like what what in the world was
this
um and we came to find out that it was
actually um icmp fragments so uh we
added a specific rule to block those uh
icmp fragments silently uh and that
noise uh uh went way down
uh once once that noise went down we saw
plenty of scanning and abuse uh no real
traffic was observed i
in in many network tools just don't even
permit the use of port zero um but but
we did see that traffic
um
for port 445
we did observe traffic that uh appeared
to be bona fide we found a customer
using it between several of their sites
um and they had been sending that
traffic out uh out of our own uh network
to internet destinations
um it did appear to be bona fide um we
decided to abandon it uh in case that
traffic truly was
um truly was legitimate
so we
um in the current state the uh invalid
port acl only blocks port zero
the infrastructure side
a lot of abuse hit our infrastructure
it was all different ports none of it
was valid traffic
except for that ipsec tunnel terminating
to an old concentrator
fortunately we found that the hard way
but fortunately we were able to find
that and
rectify that problem very quickly
so as we analyze the traffic we've found
many um
uh what i call mpls of vpn ips coming in
coming back in via our transits um these
are ips that we assign to our mpls
customers
so they're
they're globally unique
but they should never be routed across a
public internet yet we were seeing that
traffic come back into our as
so
our theory was that these customers
likely didn't have firewalls uh or
likely had firewalls i hope they have
firewalls
that uh they didn't nap for the globally
unique ips
um
so all of that traffic uh never they
there were um there were tcp sessions
that were trying to be set up they were
obviously weren't completing so uh we
didn't do anything uh special for those
we we chose to block those
uh on the inbound uh anti-spoofing side
uh i mentioned earlier the uh the back
door uh routing or the the backdoor
object group and
this is this is where it comes into play
we did find a few internet lan ips
with
with that backdoor routing where they
were coming back into our aes
from outside
and those interestingly enough seemed to
be working
um so in the interest of not breaking
things um those were explicitly
permitted uh they have their their
the object group that i talked about
earlier
and they have an entry in the acl
um
the on the catch-all deny rule we didn't
see any significant traffic
on the outbound side
we saw where um
we were trying to send a lot of traffic
uh from other carriers mpls vrfs where
the wan ip wasn't assigned to us so uh
one thing that uh
that
used to be very common on our network
was we would buy a handful of
uh of vrfs or a handful of circuits from
another provider uh and then we would
take their mpls network and then connect
it to our uh global internet vrf well a
lot of these other carriers would
assign their own lan ips
so
in some cases we had routers that were
trying to connect outbound uh to the
internet
using that lan ip that that that the
other carrier had assigned of course it
could couldn't communicate
um
we also saw lots of other back door
connections where
the customer router uh would receive
traffic on on another uh provider's want
ip and then the reply would be sent
through us
uh and
both of these types of traffic
or both of these types of uh situations
we didn't see any uh any valid traffic
so those were blocked
so this is
a really uh
this was the most interesting case uh to
me uh as i was digging into this
we had a situation where bgp customers
would send traffic
from
their ass they would use the other
provider to send the traffic up to a
content provider
but that reply to the from the content
provider would come back to us
through through some routing policy i i
hadn't worked out exactly how this could
have happened
but
the
traffic the reply traffic would be
routed across the x to us
and then we would route that traffic
right back out
to one of our transit providers to go
back to the customer
so
as you're implementing this
if you implement this on your network
you can't assume that bgb customer
traffic will be routed to them uh
directly through you um it might touch
your network before it
it's routed uh it's routed back out of
your network and then comes to them
through that alternate path
on the administrative side
the new acl of course carried process
and procedure implications
any new bgp customer
must have their prefixes added to the
to the relevant object groups on on all
routers any new aggregate blocks
that
that you purchase they need to be added
to the to the aggregate groups
and
one one thing that was there was a a
difficult shift for us was if a customer
calls in with an issue where traffic is
not getting through
um we mentioned we might need to look at
those filters uh it could be that that
traffic is being dropped at your edge
um but fortunately in practice this has
not cost us that much in terms of of an
admin time
um we had uh two issues with this since
implementation uh and and both of them
were resolved very quickly
um
and uh lastly after implementation uh we
checked back with the dsav team and they
showed we were no longer vulnerable to
that spoof dns traffic
so a quick set of recommendations
agree internally what you plan to block
get all the stakeholders involved early
and communicate often
and test test test and test some more
um start with the rules uh that permit
uh start with the the
changing the deny rules over to permit
and and log those and run down make sure
you just run down everything in your
logs before you switch those rules to
deny uh shouldn't be any surprises here
um a little bit of future work
we're looking at doing some automation
of the
object group management
we're looking at doing further security
analysis and lockdown of the
point-to-point subnets uh right now uh
these are open wide from any subnet to
the slash 30 or slash 126.
um
a better practice might be to block all
unnecessary protocols um
so that might be an area of uh a future
work uh and further characterization of
the infrastructure subnets
um deciding what we want to uh
what specifically um we want to block is
is this blocking enough
should we be doing more
and uh
that is uh that's all i have um i do
want to stress in the the appendix of
this
slideshow i do have an example of some
of the object groups that we set up so
this is
um this is a sample of what we've
actually configured on the routers
and
a sample of the access list these are
actually the access lists that that
we've deployed
and then at the very end uh there's a
short list of references
and with that
i'll take your
questions right we do have a few
questions um on the virtual platform
abby friedman asks was there any concern
about volume of acl deny locking on cpu
and was there any impact seen
um there was a concern
with the way that the acl is structured
certainly um
we did have a concern we did look at uh
the uh the capability of our hardware we
run um
asr 9900 routers um and those seem to
have more than enough capacity so it was
something that we looked at and
uh fortunately hasn't been a problem
okay still the one in person i've got
another question for you here from
matthew p tech who says good talk brian
if you blocked all port equal zero
traffic does that imply you block
inbound fragments that could
legitimately be destined for your
customers did that generate many
customer complaints
um it did block fragments uh and that
has not generated any customer
complaints to date awesome
and one more from virtual tony tobor
asks i'm not positive that i followed it
all correctly but if the same
broad inbound acl forcing source within
your address space does that mean a
customer could spoof another address
within that same space eg assigned to
another customer
yes there is that risk
yes absolutely um we we regarded that
risk as
um
low to medium uh our real goal was to
was to block the the majority of the
noise uh and and uh
you're you're absolutely correct uh and
that could be an area for future work
yep
anybody else have any questions here
thank you for your time brian thank you
so much
[Applause]
[Music]
you