[Music]
wasn't that a fantastic keynote
radio came to the university of north
carolina school of computer science
several years ago and i was so excited
to hear her speak i definitely fangirled
a little bit
in that speech she said that her version
of the osi reference model has a few
changes not to worry the physical data
link network and transport layers are
all intact but anything above layer 5
has been relabeled as boring
let's hope i venture no higher than
layer 4 today unless i do the wrong
thing
you got it
my name is adair thackson and i am a
network engineer's worst enemy a
security engineer who used to have a
ccna
this talk is pre-recorded but i've asked
one of my co-workers to hang out and
chat and tag team questions and answers
with me during the anage itself
now
i wanted to give you guys a bit of a
fair warning
in this presentation i'm going to be
using the f word
if you have small children or sensitive
years i just want you to be aware of
that of course this is nanox so the f
word in question is
firewall
i just didn't want to scare anybody when
i said that
this will not be the last sesame street
preacher you see
you're welcome
i work for internet2 which is probably
one of the fastest networks that some of
you have never heard of
when i explain internet2 to
non-networked people i use the illusion
of a toll highway for municipalities
researchers and students across the
country
we connect 46 regional and state
education networks
59 government agencies and more than 300
universities
through our state and regional education
networks more than 65 000 k-12 schools
are connected to internet too
additionally we are working with the
minority serving cyber infrastructure
consortium on a three million dollar nsf
grant to address the cyber
infrastructure needs of more than 700
historically black colleges and
universities and tribal colleges and
universities
this is our network backbone map
i did take this snapshot at 11 45 am on
a school day because i wanted to try to
make it look good
we appear in all the usual places within
the united states and 2020 really made
us take a look at our pairings with home
isps
science and scientists don't stop
researching and applying for grants just
because they're working from home
we need to make some adjustments to
allow better connectivity with home isps
for those people while they're working
at home
we also interconnect with more than 65
networks globally reaching 100 countries
additionally we increasingly provide the
software and tools that enable users and
operators to interact with commercial
cloud
big science projects and other at-scale
or large-scale collaborations
i said new network so let's get into
that
we began collecting user requirements
for our next generation infrastructure
network in 2016.
after multiple information gathering
sessions with our community the rfp was
issued later that year and a vendor was
chosen in fall of 2020. our next
generation network includes new features
primarily driven by software automation
and systems virtualization to allow the
infrastructure to be more readily
integrated into the broader enterprise
campus regional and cloud environment
around us
planning for the secure management
network on the other hand
began in 2017 but was paused because
well i wasn't there at the time
but
when that mean old kid blew up our
beautiful death star it kind of set us
back
we picked it up back up in earnest in
2018 with some new engineers and have
been working on it in conjunction with
the next generation infrastructure
network
anyway this is an analog of course so i
i said i have to talk about the network
maps and the big numbers before i get
into the really interesting stuff which
is of course the security stuff
as part of our fiber network upgrade we
replace the underlying fiber releases in
about 80 percent of our footprint which
means we are now capable of 800 gig plus
wavelengths and 32 terabits per second
capacity per link
the packet network upgrade means we now
have at least 24 400 gig ports and 12
100 gig ports in every node and our
intra node capacity is now a minimum of
2 by 400 gig
almost all of our 3-way sites have an
exit capacity of 2.4 terabits per second
minimum
and some have an exit capacity of 3.2
terabits per second we're going to take
a look back at 2010 which was when we
installed our previous network
in 2010 our backbone link capacity was
250 gigabits per second total
and our upgraded next generation network
now
is capable of 127
700 gigabits per second
in 2010 our total device capacity was
453 gigabits per second
and our new upgraded total device
capacity is 810 000 gigabits per second
over the same time period our total
annual traffic has increased from 104
petabytes in 2010 to 2800
petabytes in 2021.
it's a nice network we built here it
sure would be a shame if something were
to happen to it
previous network was running on the
juniper mx platform and we consists we
subsisted on a diet of access control
lists and control plane policing via
firewall filters
we use the counters to track hits via
snmp
we had a few thresholds that we had
chosen
mainly with a dartboard
and some of them had been removed over
the years when they proved prohibitive
in addition to stateful filtering we
also wanted to filter outbound traffic
which was something that we were not
already doing
in the new next generation network
control plan policing is done with
cisco's lpts local packet transport
services functionality
which is supposed to act like an
intrusion prevention system within your
router
secure management network is a separate
layer of protection on top of that
our existing management network was
really nothing groundbreaking older
cisco devices configured for reverse
telnet with some terminal servers
patched in
the sort of thing that you would really
hope you could find documentation for
when they woke you up at 2am basically
given the chance to fix something you'd
want to make it more friendly in a
network emergency given the opportunity
to rethink this we took it
the first thing we had to look at was
what should go through the secure
management network and what shouldn't
obviously secure shell should go through
the secure path
we have performance monitoring servers
at each location we can manage them via
their out-of-band idrac ports that
should go via the secure path too
and anything else read write like we use
a lot of net conf that should go via the
secure path as well
low impact stuff like snmp is probably
fine
if you step back though in the case of
an emergency the goal is to restore
network access so anything that's
required to achieve that goal should go
out of band over the secure management
network
things that should go in-band instead
are bandwidth intensive things like
software upgrades and netflow
additionally we've identified a bug that
we have fought with our vendor
on because rpki route origin validation
can only happen via an m-band loopback
we hope to have that result soon
lest you thought any bit of this would
be easy our homegrown tools assumed only
one primary management ip address and
they had to be redesigned to account for
the primary out-of-band path as well as
the back-up inband path in case the
secure management goes down we have to
have contingencies for our contingencies
the secure management network has three
essential parts the dedicated router
firewall and terminal server and we have
those across three different site types
the biggest change for us is the
hardware firewall
you may have noticed that we're proud of
the speed of our new network in
firewalls
well
nano is held at austin this year right
you don't bring a toyota corolla to the
formula one race at circuit of the
americas do you
wait
i'm getting
someone is telling me in chat right now
that they in fact have brought their
toyota corolla to attracting at circuit
of the americas
congratulations very good job
now we don't have a lot of experience
having firewalls in our production
network and it's been a bit of a sea
change i'll touch on that later given
the chance to greenfield a new secure
management network we mapped out three
different site types
we have an entry exit site a standard
site and a remote site they're all
slightly different so i'll explain how
and why you'll notice that each
different site type has a dedicated
router for the secure management network
the router has three different vers
one for optical management
one for a performance monitoring server
management and one that serves as the
primary path for managing the network
and any other devices required for the
network to function
such as our pdus traffic between the
verbs has to go through the big firewall
which in this case is a juniper srx1500
and that is where the firewall rules
live
now
this is an entry exit site for us which
is why we have the big firewall here and
a slightly more complex network topology
first up we have the 100 megabits per
second wayside channel optical service
channel over the optical network
of course 100 megabits per second isn't
a whole whole lot
and you know what security people tend
to be a little bit of an anxious bunch
so we couldn't rely solely on that
in comes the layer 3 backbone over the
new next generation network and the
layer 2 overlay over that which goes
between the secure management network
routers
the big firewall has ipsec tunnels to
the we firewalls at some of the other
sites
and finally as displayed in purple at
most of our secure management network
sites we have some 10 gig optical
circuits for good measure
again this is an entry exit site
we have three active entry exit sites up
with two more plans
they were chosen for their geographic
diversity and physical proximity to our
partners at indiana gigapaw and lumen
the standard sites are very sad and
disappointed in lonely sites because
unfortunately they don't have firewalls
they have all of the other links the 100
megabits per second wayside channel
optical service channel
the layer 3 backbone the layer 2 overlay
and the 10 gig connection but no
firewall
this is a remote site which means it has
a router but it does not have an optical
node
it also has a wii firewall which is a
juniper srx345
i'll pop the links up but i think you
get the picture by now
our secure management network is good
enough smart enough and dog on it people
like it so we monitor it just like we do
its older sibling
two walks a day
homemade food who's a good network the
whole nine yards
we've had a homegrown configuration
management tool that we've used over a
number of platforms over a number of
years where our next generation
infrastructure network is using cisco's
network services orchestrator for
automation standardization and policy
management
we are working on migrating the secure
management network configurations over
to nso and hope to have that completed
soon
now
i don't know if any of you have been in
the position of creating a whole new
firewall rule set where none existed
before
if so
my condolences
we had a couple of access lists that
were created back in the dark ages
i should specify that i mean like 2010
thereabouts not the last two years
our optical management platform was
changing our partner networks were
changing
so which roles did we need and which
rules could be discarded
what did the manufacturers say their
required ports were and what were they
really
did anyone really know
when you thumb things but not everything
so we bit the bullet and did the only
reasonable thing we ran away and cried
no
then we looked at the old acls and used
those as a basis for creating a bunch of
rules we did add a permit and log at the
end as a catch-all because we didn't
want to block required traffic
since the juniper firewall logs include
the name of the firewall rule that's hit
this allows us to look at what's being
permitted by each rule to ensure that
the rules were working as intended
it also allowed us to look at what was
being caught by the permit and log at
the end so that we could go back and see
what was being permitted that we didn't
know about
we established slack channels with the
stakeholders for each zone type and used
those to help us create new rules with
the goal of removing the permit and log
entirely
it also helped us identify a few
misconfigurations
when the performance monitoring servers
for example were using a legitimate but
not previously accepted by us ntp server
that it helped us to work with the
management team for the performance
monitoring servers to resolve the
problem in a way that was easiest for
them
in this case it was for them to push out
the correct ntp settings to those
servers themselves so we didn't even
have to make a firewall change
if it had been easier to make a firewall
change that's something that we would
have run through our normal change
management process
that's not to say it's all been sunshine
roses
there
may be a rule whose name contains
which is meant to just
silence the one host who refuses to
change its syslog settings so it stops
filling up my logs
eventually we got rid of the permit and
log rules and no engineers were harmed
in the process
that's what they told me i had to say
we finally did the boring grown-up
security thing and created some policies
governing creation modification and
removal of rules
we have a specific workflow where new
rules must be requested and documented
so they can be reviewed on a regular
basis
and of course all changes have to go
through change management so i have a
couple of templates created for my team
to make common things like address book
changes easier
i have a little bit of extra time it
looks like so i'd like to go a little
more in depth into the firewall rules
that we've created and what we've
learned from them
more work work work
work work work work i'm kidding
i told you there'd be more sesame street
fun fact
before this presentation i have not
noticed that the swedish chef has human
hands
true story you're saying it now i know
you're welcome
of course we have a few next steps
we have an ongoing review process to
determine if any rules can be removed or
combined and we have monitoring in place
to check on unexpected changes in
permitted or denied traffic
we've created workflows around verifying
firewall address books based on our
internal source of truth
and we'll be creating workflows out of
the configuration once we move to nso
i need to clean up some broader ssh
rules and remove some redundant rules so
those two things are on my to-do list
for instance we have a global rule
that's permitting radius which is
processed after all the zone specific
rules so we don't really need a radius
rule for each zone do we
my co-worker has been working with an
open source firewall documentation tool
which will make it easier to parse the
configuration so that i don't need to go
back and make those changes manually in
our documentation after the fact
shoot
i totally forgot that i meant to do that
could one of you guys remind me thanks
additionally we want to enhance our
firewall reporting by finding rules that
aren't being used and can be removed
which kind of begs the question
can you splunk that which doesn't exist
we had quite a bit of fun each trying
our hands at various vulnerability
assessment tools against our new devices
from points inside and outside the
secure management network
we have a commercial product as our
primary means of assessment but we
wanted to see if we could find any
interesting tools for our purposes
my coworker tried some things that he
found on github
and i ran through some kali linux tools
we documented our findings so they can
be repeated in the future as needed say
after we do a software upgrade need to
reassess
we also really want to simulate a full
site outage to verify that failover
works as it should for the secure
management network and for our internal
pools at some of those sites
and of course training our other
engineers on basic firewall tasks
after all you can lead a network
engineer on water but we also need to
make her secure it
the easiest solution can be nice when
you're running a network but it's
probably not ideal for a firewall
configuration
thank you for coming to my ted talk i
mean my nano presentation
i'll be happy to take any questions and
hopefully my co-worker has been
answering some in chat as well
thank you
hi adair
hello
all right we do have some questions in
the chat for you so we will start with
blake willis he says great talk thanks
are you using juniper srx's new vrf
groups to run l3 vpn vrs on your
firewalls in flow mode
no we are pretty much just doing things
as simply as possible
basic firewall zones
thank you
matthew ptek asks adair your
architecture seems to rely entirely upon
the optical network being present and
available in order to work for both your
in-band and out-of-band 100-megabit osc
channel if the optical platform
completely dies do you have dial-up or
other oh access path into your
sights
and your language
gosh i didn't write it
i just we are working
all right we're working on external
commodity connections at our entry exit
sites
okay
and then george emodio asked what open
source tool
uh it's called srx audit tool
uh it's from github
any of you guys have questions here
i think that's all we may have for you
then
well thank you so much adair that was a
lovely talk thank you for your time and
for joining us live for question and
answer let's give a dare another hand
[Applause]
[Music]