[Music]
uh hey everyone my name is uh phil
bedard i'm a principal engineer here at
uh cisco systems um i'm here today at
the nanaga 84 here i've done a couple
other nanak presentations in the past
but today talking about sdn or software
defined networking for sp networks and
this is kind of a
2022 edition of this
sdn has been around for quite some time
this is a bit of an update on kind of
what's going on in the industry
and the overall landscape with sdn today
we'll go ahead and
get started
uh brief agenda uh it's not a
complicated agenda today it's really you
know what is sdn i think most people
understand what sdn is or at least have
heard the term
uh over the last you know 18 years or so
since it originated
and then we'll talk a bit about you know
what is an sdn controller like what is
the the element that's actually enabling
sps to you know do sdn in their network
today what are the standards and
industry initiatives behind those
um and like i said we'll take a look at
these you know the implementations that
are that are out there today um all the
groups and all the standards that are
going into you know how sps might use
sdn
as it's currently you know looked at in
the industry
we'll touch upon a couple of network use
cases
these aren't new use cases they're
problems that sps have had to solve for
quite some time in their networks
but we'll take a look at how we can use
sort of what we call an sdn controller
to really enact those changes in the
network and sort of the standards and
data that goes into that
obviously sdn is kind of a loaded term
uh people overuse the term sdn and they
have for many years to meet different
things
um so we'll kind of go ahead and look
and you know give a little bit of
background to ssdn and this is really
kind of maybe what it means to me
and how i've learned you know to to grow
or love or hate at the term sdn uh and
first of all a little bit of background
is you know what do we consider a
non-sdn network or a non-software
defined network
uh and really for sps that's you know 99
of networks that are deployed today and
have been deployed for for many decades
you know this is a network where most of
the intelligence and the control plane
is embedded in the device and the device
level software
these are our traditional igps so things
like routing protocols distribute routes
end to end
and then in turn the device has software
that installs you know forwarding
information
i think most people are are really
familiar with how these networks work
today
and it's not to say that these networks
aren't intelligent
we've added through standards and
extensions uh over the years many
different uh things to enhance the
intelligence of the protocols and really
the embedded networks themselves and the
control planes when you look at things
like rcvt
uh and what we're doing with that
segment routing uh things like bgp flow
spec
they're really adding intelligence to
the network and more capabilities
and if you look even at an application
like auto bandwidth which is
deployed at a lot of rsvt type networks
that's really you can consider that an
sdn application it's really an
intelligent application that's taking in
information from
across the network to make more
intelligent path routing decisions
um but it's still limited in what can it
could do uh being embedded into a device
uh and the capabilities that
mainly based off of the data that it's
able to consume
and make decisions on
when we take a look at sdn or software
defined networking i i've got a couple
different views of it that i'll present
really the purest view and this was the
original
intent of sdn
was to have an external control plane
that's very intelligent it's managing a
set of relatively simple forwarding
elements in the network
i think everyone who knows the history
of sdn is familiar with openflow
openflow is really a a construct to
implement a strict forwarding on a
device level basis and the idea was i
would have this
brain or control element that was
forwarding the end to end paths for
applications
or just routing across the network
that didn't really you know come to
fruition uh i think that you know what
people wanted to do with sdn was a noble
goal
but there were a lot of gaps you know in
sp networks just things like local
protection and rerouting traffic when
failures occur being able to handle
those in a quick manner is difficult
with a centralized control plane
so we still needed a distributed control
plane to really handle you know some of
those use cases what it did help with
though is to define what we call like
you know standard interfaces for how we
talk to devices
uh standard languages for how we
describe you know forwarding constructs
you know openflow is kind of the initial
one p4 is has emerged uh
more recently as a way to do that and
it's widely adopted for a variety of use
cases so sdn has brought some benefits
in getting people to look at how we can
be more programmatic on how we manage
these networks
um you know my take on sdn is something
that i really kind of call hybrid sdn
and i'm not the originator of that term
and it's really a more pragmatic view of
where we're not you know discarding the
the intelligence that's in the
distributed control plane today
it's really enhancing that with
additional capabilities that are
difficult to put into a device level
software
um so it's really about augmenting
different layers of the network whether
it's the service layer uh the traffic
forwarding layer uh or you know the
routing layer that drives that
um so like i said it's really about
enhancing the network and enhancing
what's done today and i think when we
look at what most sps want to do today
that that really fits in that that story
um a very simple example of something
that
you know some people do today those that
are familiar with path computation
elements that help to manage uh traffic
engineering paths and to end across the
network
a pce is is you could consider that a
form of sdn control in this hybrid
network because i'm using some type of
external data or constraints to add
intelligence to a distributed network
that's running uh traditional protocols
um something that often goes hand in
hand and is also kind of a buzz word in
itself is this idea of intent based
networks
or intent driven networks like i said
you often hear this sort of hand in hand
when someone talks about sdn and a lot
of times it is just sort of a buzzwordy
term
really the whole goal though is to move
to what we call more declarative simple
configurations
to drive more complex network functions
and this comes more into play when you
talk about you know multiple sdn
controller elements talking to each
other
the idea is to abstract a lot of the
complexity of the underlying network
from the upstream controller
and really allow the the controllers
that are managing you know more complex
parts of the network to decompose those
instructions into something that's uh
can be configured on the network
directly like i said it's all about
abstracting sort of complexity as you go
up layers in the network
and being able to have like a simple
call like i need service between a and z
at a say an oss layer of the network and
then have something intelligent
underneath decompose that into the more
explicit configuration
versus that upper layer having to you
know know how to do that
across the multi-vendor networks
end-to-end
i mentioned the term controller a few
times uh a controller when we looked at
the kind of purist view of sdn that is
the the external element that's helping
to control the network
um the definition of controller it's
simply something that directs or the
actions or functions of something in
this case it's the network it's network
devices or it's potentially you know
other controllers
because we can have controllers as
you'll see it in a hierarchy
and that really lets us build a more
kind of scalable solution and how we
enact sdn on the network uh there's some
key components to that obviously on the
southbound side you know i have to talk
to the network elements and that's
through a variety of you know protocols
today both open and proprietary
and then i have to aggregate that data
um if i really want to deploy this in a
multi-vendor network we have to
normalize that data from different
vendors into you know what we call
standard models and i'll present a
little bit about that later
but this is really key to how we have
good interaction between uh different
controllers and you know be able to make
this sort of a more multi-vendor open uh
way of managing the networks
the other part is rendering northbound
interfaces i talked a bit about
abstraction and the idea of sort of a
low-level controller is to you know
abstract the network from a higher level
controller it has to
be able to put that in a format that it
can consume
um and there are standards and there's
initiatives today where where a lot of
that's being worked on
uh to make this a more you know
multi-vendor multi-vendor interoperable
type of architecture
and really sdn is about intelligent
applications um you know it's something
that either has to make the network
easier to operate
um or enhance some type of functionality
uh so really that's the key growth key
goal of that otherwise you know why why
implement something like software
defined networking in the in the
beginning like i said most this as i
talk about it you know really is around
the hybrid sdn view where i'm not
throwing out the existing network uh
it's really about adding functionality
and covering specific use cases to help
sort of enhance services or the
infrastructure itself
uh so why use sdn um and this is sort of
the the agile question of you know what
is it buying me is it helping me you
know save money or make money hit some
way sometimes it comes down to that
there's a variety of use cases today uh
really kind of the the definition view
of it really it's enhancing the network
uh these sda controllers and sdn in
general uh the idea is to take in data
generally it's not available in a
distributed control plane um and add
intelligence to to what's going on in
the network
we've done a lot of enhancements like i
said to add intelligence to you know
device level software and standard
routing protocols
at some point that becomes difficult
obviously all sps know it's difficult to
upgrade you know
software on devices over time we've made
that easier by having some application
you know independent
upgrade processes but still it's very
difficult to do that heads and across
the network
uh it's very painful
so really sdn allows us to have i'll say
a more modern sort of application
delivery outside of the device uh and
the interfaces do the device stay
standard they don't change very often
so really i can rebuild that application
as needed without touching the device
itself
i'll talk a bit about multi-layer
networks and when i call talk about
multi-layer typically i'm speaking about
ip and optical networks and if you've
seen sdn presentations in the past uh
many of them cover how we better manage
ip and optical layers together
uh there was a lot of work put into like
gm plus and gm pls was a device level
protocol
uh set of standards that were meant to
really marry together ipn optical and be
able to exchange data between the two
make intelligent decisions
after many many years it really never
took off
just due to a lot of interrupt type of
issues
even though these are standard protocols
uh
i once called sdn it's sort of the
savior of that
because really you're just kind of you
know punting the intelligence upstream
and i'm able to handle these multi-layer
networks
you know at the sda controller level
and not necessarily between two devices
themselves you know obviously optimizing
network resources that's sort of a
boilerplate you know reason to run
things like sdn
there's a lot of ancillary benefits and
things like network visibility and
that's mostly due to the amount of data
that i'm getting from the network
uh in the applications that you know the
sda controller runs
really allows me to analyze and inspect
that data and get more out of the
network uh i said if nothing else it's
going to enhance visibility by doing a
lot of data collection for the network
itself uh who's using sdn today uh i'll
say even today very very few people are
using you know software-defined
networking especially in sp networks
uh you'll hear you've seen papers and
maybe some nano presentations from
content providers and those are doing a
lot of you know egress traffic steering
of bgp controllers or routing
controllers that they're using and to
end across their network
those are a bit advanced
obviously there's people doing it the
amount is pretty low
most sps are looking at you know more
what we call this hybrid sdn model
and on the bottom this is if people
haven't seen it this is kind of the
the gartner hype curve
i mean definitely sdn went through its
uh you know eras or multiple eras of
this sort of peak of uh
uh inflated expectations
uh and sort of disillusionment means
that you know nothing's really happening
with it i think we're at a point now
where we're starting to see more
initiatives around uh sdn and sp
networks where we're kind of on the
upstream uh or the upswing uh of the
sort of enlightenment phase we're not
quite to a productivity phase yet but i
think we're we're somewhere on this uh
on this uh this line or trajectory up
now
uh mainly driven by a lot of industry
initiatives around sdm that have come to
life in the last few years so i'll talk
i'll spend a bit of time about talking
about kind of standards and initiatives
that are going on right now
key to this i talked a bit about
multi-vendor
and to drive multi-vendor we really need
interop between between these different
controllers between the different
elements
there's been a lot of push towards
standardizing a lot of that
in the last few years
you know we need a standard kind of
architectural definition kind of roles
and responsibilities of what different
controllers do in the network when it
comes to sdn
and the thing that's really helped you
know drive a lot of the standard data
models uh yang
i think most people are familiar with
gang at this point
it's the de facto standard of how we
model data at the device level the
service level
even you know how we describe network
topologies and i'll show that in a bit
and it's really necessary to normalize
you know what's often proprietary
network data into vendor agnostic data
so that we could share you know not only
to applications uh within an sda
controller but also to other controllers
themselves
and also protocols standard interface
protocols and how things interact uh and
you know the models drive the apis
really so the standard models drive
standard apis having standard
communication protocols is also key
at the device level we have net complete
things like gmi that have seen a lot of
traction in the last you know five to
ten years now netcomp is obviously
widely implemented on these vendor
devices today
from controller to controller rest comp
is really the de facto standard i think
everyone is kind of collect on using
that
it does have some drawbacks but it is
sort of the standard and it's the way
that uh controllers communicate between
each other uh so i mentioned having an
architectural framework uh to to really
build this you know uh
sda controller architecture
um and some of that's being driven by
the ietf it's specifically the actn
working group the abstraction control of
traffic engineered networks and they've
defined rc 8453
and really it's a loose framework of
controllers in how sdn works that
what it really allows you to do is move
away from
sort of a big monolithic
type of piece of software that's
controlling
you know many different network types
different domains and breaks that into
you know
more easily consumable you know the
smaller controllers that are responsible
for just their own specific tasks
uh so you'll often see these terms in
the in the actin framework of like an
mdsc you'll see that called a
hierarchical controller in other text
and this notion of a pnc is really
similar to a domain controller it's what
controls a specific domain of the
network uh that it has some sort of you
know technical knowledge of
so it's the lowest layer controller
that's actually talking to the network
devices
so we talked a bit about roles and the
roles of these different different
controllers the cnc or customer network
controller that's an oss bss system it's
often an orchestration system or a
workflow manager
so that's where you want to extract you
know most of the intent to so like i
said if you have a service that says i
just need a vpn from a to z um you know
that's the type of you know function
call it would make to a multi-domain
service controller
which then is broken down into you know
more consumable bytes and then sent to
specific provisioning controllers
absolutely so the hco or the mdsc it
aggregates information from all the
domains so it can make intelligent
decisions and like if it does get a
request for a service from a
cnc
it's able to decompose that into its
constituent parts and send it to where
it needs to go
for example an ip plus optical
provisioning uh operation would be
handled by an mdsc
the provisioning network controller like
i said that's really it uses its sbi to
connect to the devices themselves
it could be other controllers as well
there's no strict hierarchy with this it
doesn't have to be three layers of
controllers
you could have many different layers of
controllers that interact and
communicate with each other
and ectn doesn't specifically
define the protocols used between the
controllers and the interfaces like i
said it's more of this sort of loose
architecture of how they should
communicate with each other but not the
underlying low-level uh protocols and
things like that
uh what else is the ietf doing specific
to sdn uh we talked about yearly leading
standardization at every level
um so the l2nm l3 and m those are
standard network models for vpn
configuration
so it really gives a vendor agnostic way
to describe vpn services and then it's
up to the the controllers themselves to
translate that into you know device
level and configuration
um so we've seen a good adoption of you
know these models like they still have
some gaps they need work and i
you know it would be good for more
operators to be involved in those
efforts
uh there's also been a lot of work done
in the last five or six years around
network models and how we describe
networks uh and this really comes into
play when you talk about controller
to controller interaction
and i'll talk a bit about that in the
coming up
and then really continued work on all
the protocols that sort of enable sdn
these are the standard interfaces to the
devices into the controllers
the ones i list here are more device
level uh standards but you know
enhancements to psep you know continued
you know isis and igp
extensions
bgpls is an important one because bgpls
is a
common kind of de facto way that i
learned topology information from a
network um and then things like network
telemetry framework to
you know create more standards-based
ways to get uh you know performance
measurement data off the network
another group that's really driving
these sdn standards and i would say
doing
a lot of work currently
is the onf tip project so it's the
telecom infra project
so onf is open networking foundation and
they have a number of different projects
and then under those have a bunch of
different groups
and specifically this is the opt group
and then even another consortium under
that is one that we call mustin
for short you just kind of call it tip
must and it stands for better mandatory
use case requirements for transport sdn
uh what they're really focused on is
defining like that the sbi the nbi
uh protocols and things so this is where
you know operators are trying to define
some of the low-level constructs that
are used for sdn
and it really gives guidance to you know
those in the open source community as
well as vendors on you know what they
should be building
as a controller within a controller
they're also defining use cases so a use
case might be you know provision a vpn
from a to z or
you know provision an optical circuit
from a to z
so they're defining those use cases and
those workflows
so if you know those that are building
the controllers you know want some
guidance on what they should be building
what operators are looking for that's
what this group is trying to define
this group is driven by operators
there's no vendor participation in the
must group and as of today i think
there's 10 different operators that are
involved but definitely
if others want to get involved simply
reach out to that team uh always looking
for for more involvement um and they've
just they've you know when i talk about
sdn architectures you know they've
defined their own uh architecture but as
you can see it looks almost like
dynacall to the actin architecture uh
some of the names are a little bit
different uh but that's for a reason you
know we want to coalesce really on one
type of uh sdn architecture
for networks
specifically sp networks
um so i said a lot of similarities to
what you see with actin and how they
define the the controller interactions
so we talk about
and most of that you know covers both ip
and optical we talk about the
architectures that are involved and how
we define that and the tip must they're
working on use cases for both ip and
optical
one thing that i want to mention uh
specific in onf as well in the otcc
project
is the transport api or tapi
and it's a little bit different tapi is
a set of yang models
that really describe all the functions i
need to manage an optical transport
network
optical transport networks are
traditionally very proprietary uh
there's no real device level interop at
with optical networks like we have with
ip and routers and switches
um they haven't you know gm plus exists
but it's not really interoperable
between vendors there's a lot of secret
sauce that happens so tapia is a way to
standardize a set of models
that really is rendered on the
northbound side of a controller
and it abstracts all the functions to
manage those networks
and really tapi has seen very widespread
adoption over the last three or so years
it's really come to a point where almost
all of the optical vendors have a tapi
based controller they can be used to
manage their networks there's still
differences in those they have to be
worked out but there's still some gaps
in tapi but it's it's been a really good
initiative to sort of cost the industry
on a single sort of standard set of
models for how we manage optical
networks
um and there's also been you know
interop events and you can find
information that say that oif has done
specifically with tappy interop events
and it's referenced by these groups like
tip must who's you know defining some of
the low-level interactions uh you know
they're using tappy to do that so
definitely would look into tapping and
the things that are being done in with
transport api today it's a very simple
example of a tapi connectivity service
and this is an example of like a
wavelength service across a dwdm network
everything in tapi is hierarchical like
most networks
optical networks are built in layers
so tapi has a way to describe you know
each layer as well as the
interconnections between between those
layers
as a quick example of a tapi uh to
create that last service like this is
what a tappy rest comp call looks like
it's more for looking out later tapi is
quite complicated at times uh it's
definitely not meant to be human driven
you a human would not write one of these
types of requests it's really meant to
be consumed by controllers and driven by
controllers
so one of the key parts to these sdn
controllers is really data ingestion
data ingestion is what's needed uh in
order to enact changes to the network
it's sort of you know table stakes for
what sdn needs to do it needs data from
the network to make uh its applications
more intelligent and to make decisions
and i kind of separate this between
packet and optical like i said this is
ip and optical that's really kind of the
the drivers for what a lot of folks are
doing in sdn today at least within sp
networks
uh so really i need you know topology
data to make uh routing decisions i need
topology data as well as you know say
performance metric data off the network
um and
i'd say the industry is within the last
few years and probably even longer now
five or six years has really driven to a
set of standards and they're more de
facto standards
than really hard advanced standards but
you know bgpls is is used those that
aren't familiar with bgp ls is bgp link
state
and it's a way to translate igp data
into bgp nlri
uh which just makes it easier to package
and for an external system to consume it
rather than trying to participate into
the the igp itself
and then piece up this is a path
computation element protocol
it's really the de facto standard for
how we get traffic engineering
information off the network
so psep on a device has the ability to
report lsps that are
going through that device or it's the
head end for
so if you look at sort of ip controllers
or packet layer controllers that vendors
have built or even open source
they always include you know bgp lls and
psep components to it
there's still a lot of direct device
interrogation for getting data off you
know either cli screen scraping snmp not
everything is available in your
standardized protocols
that you might need so when you talk
about a domain controller
it might have different ways but the key
is that it needs to expose that
northbound in a standard interface
so when we look at controller to
controller interaction that's a really
sort of key
and we look at topology information
which is like i said sort of table
stakes for doing this sda control
the ietf has defined a lot of rfcs
around a standardized network model and
there's a base model in rc 8345 and
there's a number of rcs and drafts that
build upon that so they add data to the
base network model which may just
include say node information so if i
want to add t information l2 information
even segment routing information
there's other drafts that now add
information to that
we also have test models that describe
in great detail traffic engineering
networks and there's also hooks between
the teas models and the the standardized
network models that we could combine a
really rich
uh combined network model and i think
what you'll find is you know most like i
said most ip controllers i've kind of
coalesced on these now these models in
order to describe and uh consume uh
network data uh just for references is
what the rc 8345 your topology model
looks like with a couple of nodes as
well as a couple of links uh with and
this uses both l2 and l3 extensions as
well as the sr draft extensions
for the network model in order to
describe a
ip topology and typically this is being
consumed by like a hierarchical
controller or even an ossps system it
just depends on the uh
the use cases involved
in many cases you also need metric data
this is what i call metric data which is
really interface stats
flow data through like netflow or ipfix
if you want to make you know even really
application level traffic decisions
across the network that you're trying to
control
and like i said that metric data is
overly overlaid on top of the topology
data or te data even uh it really gives
you a very powerful you know way to
build an intelligent application for
traffic steering and other types of
applications
so we look at network data on the
optical side
so the controller to the network
that's still very often proprietary it
might be tl1 some cases snfp
some vendors have moved to even using
things like netcount
but typically all the coding the models
that are used on the ip side we have a
lot of standardized models for you know
device level interaction either through
ietf or openconfig
the optical the device level is you know
very proprietary
um and that's the reason why the
controller to controller
you know is so important uh because it's
really rendering that proprietary data
into something that's normalized
it's standard across different vendors
so something like the inventory from an
optical device
looks the same and tappy
you know from one vendor to another
vendor uh that's i said that's really
the key in making this interoperable and
being able to build sort of a
multi-vendor open uh sdn architecture
uh like a tapi is a de facto standard
there's a number of models that are used
to describe both the hardware as well as
the topology that's created
as well as the services that are created
over that like i said it's quite uh it's
quite rich today and what they've built
uh and i said there's a number of
implementations of it already
yeah so we've talked a bit about network
data and how network data is consumed by
this hierarchy of controllers uh in this
case you can see this is just kind of a
graphical view of what i just talked
about so you know the optical domain
controllers and you know this is where
i'm using typically proprietary methods
to get that data
uh and then ipcontroller you know like i
said we're more standardized on the ips
or router switch side of how you get
data off the device
not always but in many cases we have
more options than on optical uh but the
key is you know what gets rendered
northbound of those controllers is all
standardized data uh that way the the
hierarchical controller or hco you know
it could be from different vendors that
are consuming that data
and the applications on those
controllers that are able to use the
data in a normalized manner no matter
where it came from
so where do we have standards gaps with
this i would say most of the gaps are on
the ip side the good thing about tapi is
tapi really kind of covers
just about everything on the optical
side
from topology equipment inventory fault
data
we have good topology data on the ip
side
but that's about it you know when you
talk about physical inventory and this
is really controller to controller we
spent a lot of time and effort in the ip
world on standardizing device models or
device level models uh we haven't done a
lot when we talk about you know
controller
ipcontroller to say hco models
um so there's still things like fault
data uh physical inventory did and
recently a draft was introduced and it
says optical but i think it'll be
expanded to cover you know packet layer
devices as well and it's really just a
way to aggregate data from multiple
devices into a single model that could
be exposed northbound to different
controllers
so i said in the ip world we've got a
few gaps that i figure need to be solved
in order to make that you know more more
applicable
um just a couple you know statements on
you know open source controllers uh you
know we see more and more vendor
controllers and i think if you look at
sort of the leading
three or four you know equipment vendors
uh you know they may have hcos they
probably have you know domain
controllers specific to optical and ip
if those are you know equipment that
they supply
uh there's a lot of open source
controllers as well the two really kind
of popular ones and i think people have
probably heard about open daylight as an
sdn controller
it's been around for quite quite some
time
it's a java based system it's it's very
plug-and-play and you know it's got
different use cases and different
applications that it solved over time
it still remained the base uh for
different open source as well as you
know commercial vendor controllers so
really it is a framework for building
applications and sharing data between
those applications that enables these
sdn apps to run on the open daylight
architecture
uh onos uh open network operating system
you know network also started you know
10 plus years ago now uh is now part of
the onf uh very similar architecture to
daylight they have progressed there's a
micro services based version of onos
today uh and they're tackling a wide
range of use cases uh i'll say the
development you know onos is probably uh
as
there's more people working on odos
today as well as you know modern use
cases around 5g bng or openbag
so there's been actually a lot of work
and even you know some
actual production implementations of
things that are done with onos so it
definitely would
take a look at that and the initiatives
that they have and see if others want to
get involved in those
so we'll talk a little bit about network
use cases
and these are sdn use cases
they're not new use cases but they're
things that can be solved in a better
way typically with some type of external
controller or sdn control
outside of what you're doing just in the
the network itself um at first though
i'll talk about sort of real world view
of where people are with sda controllers
today and this plays a part in sort of
use cases in how you solve problems uh
with sdn today
you really consider the controller as
part of the network
i think that's a good way of looking at
it and it's really part of the network
control plane um so the applications
that are built are are meant to be
real-time sort of closed-loop automated
uh you know control applications when it
comes to things like traffic steering or
resource steering in the network
i think when you look at so some
applications you know they're not
necessarily closed loop applications
uh a lot of them are visibility based uh
things just making it easier to manage
the network through data collection and
kind of this is the first entry point we
see for
uh for sdn controllers or what you would
want to call it a modern sda controller
especially in sp networks it's starting
with visibility it's really bringing
data into the network
and i think as i mentioned earlier
there's a lot of benefits of just the
visibility aspect of bringing the data
into a single sort of repository and
then if if you're feeding that into an
hco or a hierarchical controller
then you get you know a good view of
that data across multiple domains so you
get things like fault correlation that
maybe you didn't have before because you
didn't have all that data in a single
repository
or a set of applications that could look
at data from multiple domains and be
able to you know make some sort of
intelligent
decision or correlate some type of fault
between those domains in an intelligent
way
uh like i said fully close-up automation
that's still pretty rare although that
happens in our distributed control
planes today uh not a lot of people
trust the uh the centralized box to make
those types of decisions so often what
we see today is is more of like a
recommendation engine
as i say
speaking of our deployments and what we
do
the real sdn control type applications
usually
they start with a recommendation and
then there's a button for someone to
push or something you know for them to
enact a change on the network uh fully
closed loop we're not not quite there
yet
uh for for the majority of service
providers uh so one use case it's sort
of near dear to me is this notion of
shared risk lead groups
and like i said a lot of all a lot of
the
sdn applications that we look at today
are
talk about multi-layer networks with ip
and optical and this is definitely an ip
and optical type of use case
so typically at dwdm networks today you
know we have multiple wavelengths there
could be multiple ip interfaces
that use the same path of the network
and we don't want to
you know
we don't want to step on those uh you
know two interfaces that are using the
same ddm link so you don't want say one
interface protecting another interface
that share the same fiber
uh you know fiber cuts are the most
common by far the most common type of
failure networks today
so for certain services and interfaces
you you know you don't want to protect
one using another over the same fiber or
conduit or node
and we seed information on the ip
networks traditionally with srlg data
from the optical network but it's it's
quite cumbersome
in many cases to get data off the
optical network and correlate it with
the ip network
because we just you don't have a good
way to share that information between
the two different systems
gmpls has solved some of this
but it's a very vendor closed solution
you can't you know hook up a gmpls
router from one vendor and a gmpls
optical mode from another vendor
and have this type of sharing takes
place they've been vendor proprietary
solutions and even those solutions are
are not widely deployed at all because
they're they're quite complicated yeah
so we look at
risk link groups or srlgs the use case
is really where the ip layer it needs
the optical layer information for things
like protection diversity uh and to be
honest it's just an easier problem to
solve by sending all of this data
upstream to a more intelligent you know
called sdn application
so they can dynamically learn what's on
the optical network and then it can see
the ip network with that information
so if it dynamically changes
things like optical restoration so
optical restoration changes the optical
path dynamically and if the ip layer is
unaware of that and normally it is
unaware of that
then the data that it has about shared
risk is already out of date
so one very simple application is being
able to take all this data together
correlate it
and then seed the router with updated
information almost in real time as it
happens
and this is an application that's been
looked at for for many years when it
comes to using sdn and sda controllers
and getting data off the network
but like i said this is
one very simple common use case that
could be solved with an sdi controller
another common use case is just you know
traffic balancing this is really more of
a bgp ebgp external edge traffic
balancing use case and when you look at
the sdm like controllers that are built
by by content providers
and others probably more on the advanced
stage of automation
they've definitely you know
have
solved this use case
over time another use case is edge
traffic balancing and this is a use case
it's been solved over time by different
content providers they're systems that
they've published white papers on even
that describe how they do this in a
really an sdn controlled manner and a
lot of that
in a true sdn sense it's really about
using network data to make those uh
those decisions and not just you know
you know standard network data like i
said the the real benefit to an sda
application is being able to consume uh
you know more granular data or things
that maybe you just don't even get off
the network uh maybe there's things like
cost maps that come from another source
uh geographic maps as far as you know
routing people to a specific location
like so those are very uh
you know common content provider or you
know sort of request routing type of
decisions
but you know enacting those into network
routing and network forwarding that's
where you know these sda controllers
come into play uh so this case is a
simple where i have traffic that you
know and i really have my intent and you
know if it's really an sdn based
application
i want to give it my intent is to
balance traffic across you know all
these peering connections uh and in
normal bgp and this is outbound traffic
which is a bit easier to control uh but
in normal say bgp that you know that
doesn't happen there's there's other
things that are built in bgp that steer
traffic a specific way
but i want to take you know all this
data and then i want to make an
intelligent traffic routing decision um
and like this then really it's the job
of the the controller
is really to decompose that ask or that
intent into the specific actions on the
network
and that's really where the the real
intelligence of sdn comes into play like
i said this is a use case that's it's
been solved in other ways over time
but we do see more and more controllers
that are able to take care of this type
of use case like i said these are just a
couple of use cases
you know the sdn can be used for there's
a lot of more advanced you know traffic
routing
traffic optimization use cases
so the key is being able to take data
you know not just from the network but
from other places as well
and collate that as well as you know
multi-domain or multi-layer information
to make a more sort of intelligent
decision that can't be made by just the
on-box control plan
and that is it for me
this has been my session on sdn and sda
controllers that i realize it's a bit on
the high level side of things
but really the industry initiatives and
the industry push for this
i encourage folks to get involved in
that uh take a look at that uh and join
groups like the the ietf uh the tip
working groups uh if you have sdn use
cases that you would like to see you
know have broader coverage of
um i definitely like that i encourage
you to join those those industry groups
but uh from that uh thank everybody for
your time i hope you enjoyed the session
and enjoy the rest of nanowrimo
hi phil hello i'm here hey everybody
you're here uh we have somebody walking
up to the microphone now please state
your name and organization
is this mike there we go hi chris
woodfield with twitter um
you were you mentioned openflow very
early in the talk and
i got the impression that you were
referring to it in the past tense um is
that still a relevant protocol or has it
largely been supplanted by the newer
newer protocols you've mentioned at this
point
yeah i think it's been largely
supplanted i'm not going to say open
flow's completely dead and has no no use
cases i would say in the sp context it
probably has you know even less use
cases than what we see in data centers
uh but i think do you think modern more
flexible you know ways of doing
programming p4 is very low level but i
you know like i said open flow
had a lot of good ideas and full flow
version two kind of you know uh
improved on that but yeah as an industry
has just not seen widespread adoption
now
okay thank you
okay thank you chris
uh we have one coming in from the
outside
from randy bush
high level could you relate these 42
complex mechanical protocol ietfish
approaches to the forever work in
progress on the network as a program
magic of mcallen rexford adelia
it seems a bit of software implemented
network and missing some abstraction to
be software
defined
as opposed to hacked aren't we still
using tweezers
yeah i think that's a lot a lot to
unpack i need you to repeat that one a
bit but i think it's just the complexity
of what's still there
and still the i mean if randy if i'm
completely misconstruing this let me
know but uh the idea it's uh it's still
complex and it's still a lot of you know
stringing glue that
is kind of binding these things together
um i think the one thing that we have a
bit more of today is less ietf heads
yeah i want to say that in a bad way per
se but people driving this and that's
where i think the operators that are
driving it and trying to drive the
abstractions
i think that's really key um otherwise
yeah we're just kind of back in the the
day of where we call automation
uh where we just they use this blanket
term of automation in sdn and it's still
super super complicated
but uh sorry if i'm miss identifying
that but uh contact me offline if you
want me to uh to
address it in a different way
okay thank you phil
randy hope that solved it for you and
hope to see you in the person again
sometime
um so
thank you for your presentation uh we're
out of time on that um thanks everyone
[Music]