okay so thanks for coming here also
and Senate night really awesome
anybody showed home me
season I'm so
I'm talking about
free and open source software which is a
pretty while
insolvent try to discuss but
mostly I just might seem yessir slightly
technical
not very techincal overview how you can
get your foot in the door
to contributing to what I consider to be
soon flagship
free open-source I S the latest kernel
and Firefox browser
so reason I want you to stop also is
that
when I was first trying to involved in
open source
and you know it but the idea its
immediate past your mailing list
a or are trying to work on a big project
that was
just some persons I on Sprint
really intimidating you know coach cell
hopefully is toppled
may be easier for supplying online see
involved
these projects about me
using my game i right clicking on the
links
no which is my slightly embarrassing
microplane name I work at Mozilla
non-police issue so download Firefox
that's my team that get all build it
they will come here's
all that nice to house electro state
military is happening in national right
its GMC should check out
me and I don't mean increased my text
which you're gonna see over him
you yeah as Lady Gaga
and she is making a funny face and the
law for talking about myself so I
figured it was
Apple so
we'll be talking about for you to the
source software that using I'll say all
impacted
announced now all they say boss
signed at great cost yet is for free
Richard Stallman twice is a free for you
not freezing here that he indeed 3 as in
here he said she's the idea is that
if users don't have control over this
offer is going on their computer
then the software has controlled which
is
I guess today is the right thing to say
Los he reminded people here
sure I'm sure you can you can live with
that
waiting OS
opens doors so there's a subtle
difference between free and open source
I think a lot of people don't see
which song is very these things that
bother
resource yesterday reno stores open
source means that
the source code is out there remain look
at but here's the trick
did Microsoft made when does it mean
internal
published so that
is you get really wet and cold you make
some changes
less babe giving you the freedom to
share those changes
is offering a if you think some older
building but
is against the law you publish it was I
think that's the
practical aspect and three 30 schoolers
and so another thing about open source
software development is that is very
different
from behind
top-down development that companies
would have done in the past
well still knew someone is little bit RK
these days I think I think most big
companies are
taking this order open source type
methodology to heart with with
developing the software projects that
there is already closed doors model that
s
very top down and there's this bizarre
on a lot of people are going off
and forming little groups are going off
in a corner and building features and
presenting them to each other and trying
to
former world and patches homies nathan
is our motto
i'm looking and
children
no Hao Wei
this is my computer
yeah no
okay so
you should read this book interested in
history reno somewhere and it be known
that was our
services and will lovely now
good it's still interesting here's a
video
explain the differences between free
open-source
straight from that people who
really started
themselves but I'm not gonna show that
as
I'm not sure I'm actually gonna have
time to waste
minutes but you can look at it later
between the sides so a lot of people
like to say that
open sources eating the world software
is
not as it's true most big companies
these days have realized that
they should open source their projects
and has become very commonplace
see that I would argue is on injured my
hand right
you that you can't today being a
marginal business community is a
political statement and I find healing
as partners mind game ball with
computers in the first place is because
I thought mister
radical and is the idea doing being
and the collected and doing things
andrew is a
share your knowledge as hosting our
individuals
and making one cash although
you can make lives in cash to Greg
I'm I can stay
his lasting Greg kroah-hartman he is
coming to be here nice you actually as
the maintainer
staging range experts these the big deal
and he was giving talking he says by
this time
a person has contributed by patches the
Linux kernel they're doing it
just for fun don't have a job where
nice no by that guarantees it
and I think that rings true
in my home I Anna I think about six
months ago
I open source server website server
convoluted mess building for fun I put a
on on pipelines package manager
and in companies engineering managers at
companies
so my project because they want to use
it and I was skip to the end and
budgeting
process that usually very and so
that was pretty interesting to see that
country because I was the stuff in the
past like
what group page that area
think yeah I if you went to Princeton or
steamers
thing but no is to bring I went to West
End years
they don't care if you work on
open-source will do well
and so in hand why doesn't every single
hers go and trying to use you open
source projects
we all know that a No and I
thing that's the point disheartening is
that
I think a lot of people do you want to
do you like the idea of it
but they just don't know how to get
started where they try to get started
somebody's injured or are they try to
patch
it's rejected they don't understand why
and actually there's thirty
I don't know if you can CVS you seems
like
somebody collected
%uh bunch studies actually where they
were looking at what's blocking people
from getting integrated in open source
projects
hands they clustered by a group that I'm
really interested in
three things I'm really interested in
fact that a lot of people found it
difficult or impossible to find or they
found it difficult or impossible to set
up
their work environment so they can even
know how to go about
creating and did and sending selling it
to somebody
for %um and people have a lot of
problems
finding bugs to work which I mean think
about it
your kid in university in thing
did a so we'll talk about that event but
it is
you work on software projects its own
text write
so you have a source file and make some
changes to it
at something or change the name is
something online
did is just another text file that his
only to change
made so you can't stand that that text
last month feels like a model
program called hatcher they can use
version control program
make like that and it will make
their home base like years making added
really well
so that they can here and I sorta
that's the unit and that's offered all
is measured
is instead he
that's something I was gonna get to see
a nice line
think it's a real problem for people
trying to work on older projects
like fish
you on the bus as though and the last
thing is
I think that it's really hard for people
to find out
was the one to get involved in western
all okay great go fine as a bug in the
kernel
that she won X that and I know where to
look
cool so touching her mother just
discussing at schools in dade
getting involved in open source
as a few here is a prerequisite
knowledge that down
directly have bearing software
development and without those you're not
getting
are with them everything's gonna be so
much easier
you need to know about version control
systems so do this
no especially like it mercurial yunis
know about using IRC which he recalled
all time
education you gonna have to know and
I'll setting up email clients
to use plain text only which actually
requires a few hoops these days
everybody these days there is using
Gmail percent
play nice with textile mill in this so
gonna mercurial
I will talk about those little bit I
recommend
reading up on you spirit I'm I actually
will attach
my sources a really great 15 minute
tutorial
has argentines still learn about Yale
and then you're seeing what is it
in the context a text file and not for
by Sonya
I recommend actually generated
and then using tool called patch
using UNIX system and apply it with
patch and not with just thinking
get a feel for for what's happening I S
T cell
every open source project as an IRC
channel Merz channels
I spin every day all day
in IRC channels and sure enough
engineers wander in and not ask
questions
means my teammates will instant recall
really happy there
so yet if if you got to work on open
source project first thing you should do
you find out what
IRC channels its contributors I wouldn't
angle
compartment also you want to use I
received actively
you gotta use announcer or you something
like tires the
I'll and that's going to make it so that
you're never off line
and you can't have nice things like
histories that people talk to you on
your way
you'll be able to see the messages basic
features another job programs but
higher Seans is permitted on purpose
so using something like IRC cloud really
help
I see it this is very important
a lot of people especially
overzealous kids will guitars piano
start
running into rooms and opinions standing
in
with nonsense and people will be mean to
them
and they'll had a bad opinion a buyer's
the
from then on out and it will prevent
them from being involved in open source
projects I've seen this before
has time to okay had a linen shirt on
like all this so bowling shirt like how
can I get involved
in open source projects and I told him I
said well here
doing this I siege there's a grouping
developers in nashville here all the
time
no learn things he says people on IRC
hassles well there are no
now
him nerds candy at home standards to be
assholes
but I fine a lot of times this is just a
misunderstanding or
I'm so do a little research don't just
running errands testing
unexpected people's to be your Google
also
don't ask to ask just asking questions
behaviors waiting on line act like
you're verbalizing
and impatient people people are busy
people or
are using it you know that bouncer the
IRC about it might
you might like are they're never gonna
see my messages unless they keep
standing
because you won't realize that there's a
history but
just be patient people get back to you
ace in communication so
you want your client to be set up for
playing text
that's very important you can deal with
singing hatch's now
so here's a link them saying that gmail
I recommend if you're going to be
sending in patches
mailing lists usually feature get again
playing on gets in
now its main just for this I mean course
get was made by
absurd for where the next though they
had this the gym for themselves
you can just have you just have to get
directly San with you did and people as
much simpler but you can also use my
I think much so the defacto standard me
in my email client it's all plain text
force if you have a gmail account I have
here to stay
that we're all taking your Gmail
credentials and said that meant for you
game learn about using my just by the
in your veins so now we get to you
I guess the fun part when we look at
actually
getting involved in these projects in
some small
hang first by Justin meeting about what
is that like
so none of these projects numbers
as Salaam worse zillions
it but also the Linux kernel tracks
thereabouts a
just sign up for an account is really
easy to use
when using web applications ranges to
sign up for an account
and then click new money you have about
maybe
I don't know maybe Firefox is crashing
%um think it's because it's not playing
well with your YouTube video driver
file it's really easy to do you thinking
about going to show you
all the different all the different
subsystems
or projects that there are issues from
choose one
menu select component you don't know
what component there's another category
and that will attach all the people who
are interested in a
to the email list and then you just
write a nice description
what your body needs to do that there
are a few
police here to you to documents that
will help you write the description but
too long don't read include screenshot
it became
mess always helpful even if you don't
think it would be just go ahead and do
it
home describe the steps to reproduce it
if you are noticing that your browser is
crashing
force it to crash anything
and document what she did to force it to
crashing super important
also search for duplicate bucks
somebody else is already filed only that
but don't do that
morning if you just right there no
description when you go to stand it will
find you can get loans and is blamed for
him
and also this is a great numbers like
that
if you see you next time system I don't
know about Windows spokesman using a
subsystem
maybe but at a pace a
uses Linux back means
use
fuck in nine starts in the emails to all
developers CC was K what about member
they work
don't do that just be patient and when
they do get back to you
try respondent today
but he's never sign up forget for a
proposal i cant
you click new and you
13 users to find the right team to bug
and then you
writers option that's be that's a huge
help
for open source huge well
now what if you're a developer
and don't lie just admit but FIGS now
let's talk about
hypothetical Hodgson's caveat being
this isn't in that at all this is just
minutes is already showing
with the workflow looks like demystify
step 0 when prime steaks
the first cash I stand thanks the
maintainer
subsystem
for a is for a webcam driver started his
email
ok ugh
your you're lumping a whole lot changes
together so what I've done minus
I made for the first mistake she came
with patch
good is I and takes a whole buncha
use them for years all I wanted
don't do that especially people who are
using
have a lot been really willingly I
filling
bill for large changes in the ointment
and forget about it that won't fly
in these projects one change
want and that is the one line text by
the way
just means like mornin want some peace.
concept
like
and changing the sleep time Muslim
nationalism step 1:
meet the guidelines that's why i
shouldn't
honestly they're not really typical
mostly they just say
writing message be an split all
changes and news it's very hard to be
good
it's too small better Spirit Airlines
flight actually
right maze
ID is also yes funny style guidelines
claims the user a space with
a space with cabs for one thing
basically the fall am is
is the way that that they prefer
everything
four-minute and which is really ugly an
archaic
especially weird think that they prefer
the line the with a limit to be a
characters
using it's the stabs items
but read the coding style document
and be sure to be there so
the first thing you know when to use a
gun I was going to take a long time
instantly positive 3 I mention that Greg
KH
is the maintainer staging range so that
you can find you
gonna do development honor home you know
and you to fill me in on the staging
dash
next bridge that's gonna live here you
can
look at room think Oklahoma
first thing I'd recommend you do in your
phone is it you never build the kernel
obviously
he wants me to pass you need to start
building colonels right away
so building kernel is actually really
trivial to do you
especially village near if you run into
you are you run
mint man
you're gonna want to actually building
that %um
and get him package and use
and then install the package
because there's some there's special
stuff that has to go into
to the kernel insofar as models then
we'll worry about that
if you just wanna remind doin' system
p.m. don't mean anything to you modules
just
come source 3 copy over your old
kernel configuration and make
make installment update really easy
there
does here okay
so now you got your kernel know that's
working back into the source tree
check out the staging dash experienced
rain
well against begins ads and check out
dash be that create your own new branch
times that you can make some changes
do similar one place to
to start ensure that you will be using
money wayne's
with just looking at source file Center
Rd imagery
in china fine style years there's a
winter that ships
scripts directory unmixed I'm first
means
just pointed out the source files him
I'll there's a and you mine Union file
when there's a space
should be removed CD that make
hatch months and the or do anything
rebuild there was a really great
wasn't right usually or
there was a
horrible tirade against them 18-19 year
old kid
from Europe who exhibited about a dozen
patches terminals that must pledge bro
the current China building he been
making patches
let not feeling the contested
baby in you on the mailing list and
wonderful maintainers likely
was the villages because he wasn't
joking said that he Jesus
yeah
we all okay he said his kidney diseases
his kidneys he had some series emotional
problems
all yeah I didn't link to that but
you just can't point
that so it the current deals
nobody's gonna sleep Jesus government
committee
she could have done this before I just
want the extra States
doing million can happen billion mayor
hedge and be sure to add a nice
title here
a very descriptive body and in the
bottom it's very important that this
sign up by actually get up
him lol
yeah
me more
Graham or said the way
I'll
the Pacers our testers it's because
its is because the Linux kernel is
colonel my own code is
directly speaking to hardware and so
how can you test that except by mmm
not
the in you but then you're still just
making sure that it builds
at that point
that's true for
over
them pot of gold
PE developing
they girl more and a half dozen other
yet bed actually me
mile yeah id
word you and
Hills their
belittled there
they deduce that noses you want
Friday that well yeah
UK yeah
you can you can certainly do that no
its okay that's a good point I was very
shocked when I heard that as well
I think yet that's that's the way it
goes though I think
these guys are plugging in USB devices
on their desk im
works and that's what I did with that
video driver I had a wet
him then I'm here yes that driver good
or up
baby work using them
here
you know or yeah
he alright map
yeah are no need to Travis file yeah
yeah
all yeah by
more yeah
and there may be some stock I dunno I
I'm nothing an ingrained damaged
their lease a you know unit test as
but yes that that's a weird thing
per share help get is
special made for checking on development
with get
you have the dash yes
that's dash yes and Ashley E options
you turn those on when you commit and
you'll get always nice stuff like signed
off by
that the kernel sports successfully
and the last thing you do that you
committed your patch
is you just run another script that's in
the source tree
it's a prospect Kong and maintainer you
can
be clever and Heidi outfit get show head
or you can just play at the source file
you worked on it will just
for now and listen all the email
addresses
%uh maintainers who would be concerned
about that
I'll you get that list and how saying
surely so that's it
gets and mouse his way to do it hands
you that their email address and she
gets in the mail
in of value hatch injures watch
you were even home for a message that
starts with the
sorry with your question but I would
recommend she do that
don't just don't rise patch
exam style your hair like in instead
I recommend you tried in this challenge
this
is maintained by people from Linux
Foundation likely
it actually works line in this challenge
you will be getting min towards word in
getting patches in the kernel source
tree you work through these challenges
and you will get patches into the links
you will see track teams placing
get long
ok
so that's it I went to the searchers
about that because my point was
and hopefully this point is look at it
passes that Carnival is not a the
mysterious thing
is just weird because it all happens
their mailing list
and the one she said yes and no it's
pretty painless
issues that giving dinners prospect
define the
gases okay snow Mozilla development I
feel is much much easier
and this happens all think that silver
you don't just synagogues here code
review
happens to hear as well so the first
thing you want to do
is checkouts brazil's central
if you working on Firefox there are a
buncha source trees
buttons all leg muscles problem
care about work said wish
were on sale you heard
so mazzola
maintain the get her that is secret nice
to their terrible stories they also pain
internal you're in your 30 as Italy's
just three games so I'm just
his own yeah story because thats always
the first supported that you can if you
want to use it
going final muzzles get used
so check it out usually how it from me
she does a lot word
the you commented I'm villages
owns you was a simple direct remarks
bills
I wrote ever since valves dependencies
that might not be sounds
funneled after it feels like its
building
is just an easy you'll find it's a lot
less painful compound her good reason
and then make some changes
before you make changes
sir 30 mercurial anything I saw a really
good
infographic luxury lines home
get one Swiss Army Knife in Mercurial
course through us all a kitchen knife
pointing you don't said
reelect probably you'll find yourself
having take a lot more serbs
life-changing so honestly can set up
curious release and was commonplace and
use bookmarks materialism in her in his
left lung
it's really simple almost say she looked
like master
A's bookmark my awesome how much and
that's just like
with its get checked out Ashley it's not
just like you
that then instead
worrying about getting your patch
injected
ago find them toward there's
a long long list thousands and loves I
think
that have been two hours that will work
with you to make sure that your past
officially accepted which is very
important
when you're working on projects don't
happen to work
you can send cold who have rejected
because
is doing things in a way that the team
in the hills of leaving or doesn't agree
with the team's No
you had no way I'm supply-demand story
%uh
yeah and work go and see who won
the CIRC homes when I see that was a
little weird
induction developers his ass and I
hey what can it work on the last what
are you interested in
and then you tell the highest okay so
once use I have your pencil account
already ago
you found it love it you want to work on
you don't have rights to take the IRC
you happy gilmore see hands
or leave home
iraq steven has to be held malted
when she added to the bone exchanges
all along AG yet your messages
well number Walsh et cetera et cetera
and
R stands for your Eagles mention his
name
some comment about Changi and then
you say she explained to me that text
file which is good
stay awesome and
had it as an attachment to the just like
an attachment to an email and
you click had or
yeltsin was it if they get back to you
loans %um got some problem yes
strip of the last your changes next
changes committing retention
released or was
here is what I expected housing all
mental and
he said use all the big guy
yes home all reading
base all so
s I don't know if I'm over good
but under
2010 and 20 minutes left yeah
I mean we ask a lot of questions
you
world
me
a
horny
cool
were here
sure
that world
are
I
mine
I think I haven't recently in the AM you
know
yeah
yet
I going to something along those lines I
said yes
people Google people things I like way
yes the cultures in single jersey thing
Hodgins huge Apache projects that use
your
much different
projects i think im project is happened
in fact this team
it is much easier which encourages a lot
practices that added wheels which i
think is a No
people lending if you working on getting
up a lot
try it seems hatched I was a little one
is home
it's important to remember that one
should patch does
no work permits a lot of people make a
follow request to get her
and they're like all I forgot that
hearing
home just how he in the mail they'll
play in the next minute
you know the shit humans it just
magically appear
or less and that's fine with me if you
try to do that
with caramel yes or Bugzilla
you're going into with alarms people are
going
lovingly cultural
problems home
getting near you
get it makes Sony
yeah are all the
well I think
easy I like easy I like the SUN
him more here's a
on past I go on
if I miss rawls
kernel source tree you you know it's in
really is
don't see me work less all
development happens to be heard
us and look and see that there's like 50
portable est
anyone's coming home
you have it has lowered the bar like
incident said live
home
yes it if everybody started do
development with
with
with text-based pastures
maybe a winter she that ass is a little
more but
at the same time let's all just be
thankful but he's emerged
trolls mainstream as I can remember a
time when people want to see me
said files this
worse yeah
release me wall that like
yes
you don't like were on
hurdle know what we're going to hurt or
the Empire
this it how you go about
hiney projects nasa
in Tysons are rising on order holds you
very much
you'll find there with you I'm yinz
channels
use all mind
if there's not a formal way I'm sewer on
yours the channel
make sure that you're familiar with yet
again the
get yourself unofficial that's the only
way
all homes a lot of times
I over your kids
the old days with certain he handed
work you well
shalom was this time there is an ongoing
process
money you know tires the very important
I don't think that's a problem
everything I think most people he hires
the iowans
website resigned
external homie word have any
guy here for you
yes very good and they have have a
mailing list
enhances the United taxes
through their at well for you
Andy eerie
they went well for you anything thank
you
that mean home told by Jesus he was also
banned
home I'll yeah
at all those here
said
yes
and but still has no for
for working on was a little jealous you
know so
this whole issue is take what you're
interested in and then
what skills you have a real images and
it will I'm
share you know it's like that and this
course while
down
are good yeah
yeah you know for
a
hey how are you I'm only working well
love them yeah
okay okay well that
the problem is it has already what thats
lined
or well yeah
around yeah
called there
that's something i've seen floating
around Ashley
I yeah
over solid Himalayan
if we could sell humid
okay
yeah yeah
power yeah
a.m.
yeah hey
argyll thank you finals
Download Manager partially downloaded
file this
system star its own claims
it was filed in 2008
yeah hey
a so right yeah
if you know what I said yeah I don't fix
this on Windows host yes you can install
c'mon yeah
but yeah any write a review
a their
I yeah
lapd
little on us
so ion and houses
I if you did arsenals and yes I think
they'd be happy to take
it I think just from what I seen
my is now a lotta a lot of problems
arising was
already I'll special yes here way
are
you
I don't think so gruesome
yeah I'm here is our passes
analysts are right passes if you can do
better there than here
whose right he I'm
you believed I believe missus and we was
just saying that she not only one
year asses home
want you know muscle is that is a
non-profit sorry
for all well summer
was no corporation is know exactly
hahaha lol
I'll all is exists
as away and radiation Alliance
see nonprofit but basically
like classify myself that way a lot of
changes
and %ah as allows us to compete with
you will snipers still all he knows me
and him
is there's no executives
better their China's raise funds for
shareholders
you
thanks