- It's August, 2018,
a Syst Admin logs into the
control panel of a wind turbine
in Southern France to update its firmware.
More than 600 kilometers away,
their PHP session token
appears on my screen.
Eight months later,
and Egyptian oil tanker pulls
into the port of Sfax, Tunisia
with a malfunctioning alternator onboard.
From my vantage point, more
than 1500 kilometers away,
I learn that the ship
will be out of commission
for at least a month
and I learn the name and passport number
of the engineer who's
flying away to fix it.
Just this summer, 13,000 meters
above the Atlantic ocean,
the accountant of a
Polish real estate group
put the finishing touches on
their annual financial report.
The word document she
prepared reached my computer
at the same time it arrived at
the inboxes of her colleagues
at their parent company,
one of Europe's largest private commercial
real estate trusts.
How does this sort of thing happen?
How do I get this information
and how do we protect it in the future?
I'm James Pavur,
I'm a PhD student at Oxford University
where I researched
satellite cyber security.
And today I wanna talk about the results
of more than two years of experiments
looking at real world use
of satellite broadband.
I do this work with a
bunch of talented people
from both the UK and Switzerland,
and I'm honored to get
to share what we found.
This actually started as a
fairly small summer project.
What we wanted to do is
take a look at some research
from the mid to late 2000s
and see if we could
replicate these findings.
And what was cool about this research
is that these people found
that there were these
satellite television feeds
that were encapsulating
internet traffic as well
and that if you had the right equipment
and the right knowhow,
you could actually find
sensitive un-encrypted internet
traffic inside those feeds.
Now, a lot has changed both
about the way we use satellites
and the way we use the
internet since 2005.
We have smart phones and stuff now
and so we wanted to update this research
and also to make it a little bit broader
and more systematic, look at
large scale usage patterns.
So what we ended up doing
is conducting a series of
domain-focused experiments,
looking at real world
users at land, at sea
and in the sky, for these
satellite internet connections.
In total, we analyzed
signals from 18 satellites
in geostationary orbit
with a combined coverage area of
about a 100,000,000 square kilometers.
To put that into perspective,
that means we were able to receive signals
from as far away as parts
of the United States
and the Caribbean, China and India,
a massive coverage area for an attacker.
And in all 18 of these feeds,
we identified deeply
sensitive internet traffic,
whether it was being transmitted
using those protocols
that had issues we've
known about since 2005
or using newer protocols
that have replaced it.
And it wasn't just any data,
it was some pretty interesting traffic.
We saw sensitive information
from nine members
of the Fortune Global 500
that we were able to identify,
traffic belonging to passengers
on six of the 10 largest
airlines in the world
by passenger count,
traffic belonging to maritime companies
who together make up 40%
of the world's cargo
shipping capacity by volume,
and traffic belonging
to government agencies
ranging from the postal service
of a Eastern European Nation
to an actual air force jet
belonging to a North African country.
We even saw traffic from
regular people like you,
people who might browse
wifi in a coffee shop
or update their Instagram
while they're on a cruise.
Now, before I delve into
the meed of this traffic,
how we got at it and what it has inside,
I wanna be sure we're all
starting at the same point
and give you a bit of a crash course
in satellite communications.
So I'm gonna run through a
very simple scenario here
to explain what satellite communications
look like in practice.
So here's our satellite.
It's in geostationary orbit,
which means it's 30,000 kilometers
above the earth surface.
We have a customer in the Atlantic Ocean
who wants to talk to this satellite.
And to do this, they wanna visit a website
over the satellite feed that's
hosted over here in Ireland.
We'll say it's google.com
and they have a device on their boat
that's called the visa terminal
or a very small aperture terminal,
which is what they'll
use for this connection.
And that device was sold to them
by an internet service provider
who runs a ground station here in Madrid.
We'll also imagine an attacker
who's quite far away
from this conversation,
down here in Accra
but still wants to intercept
the communications.
So how does this play out?
Well, because our satellite's
in geostationary orbit,
it doesn't move around.
So our customer just needs
to point their satellite dish at the sky
and say, "Get me google.com"
using whatever weird
satellite protocol is used
in this network.
The satellite is more or
less a dumb bent pipe.
It doesn't really do any
processing or networking,
it just sends that signal right back down
on a focused beam towards
the ground station in Madrid.
You notice this beam is very narrow,
so it passes over our
attacker and across head,
they can't intercept this communication.
Once we get to Madrid,
the satellite internet service provider
will convert this weird satellite protocol
into normal IP traffic
and route it to Google,
just like if you were visiting
a webpage at home, terrestrially.
It'll get the response over
the terrestrial internet
and then beam it back up into space.
It's worth noting that when
I say beam up into space,
this isn't a fast process.
The roundtrip time
for a conversation like this can
be as long as 700 milliseconds,
because the speed of light is only so fast
and geostationary orbit,
which is the satellite we're
looking at is very far away.
Once we finally make it out there though,
there's one last step,
which is to beam the
signal back down to earth.
Only this time, we'll do it
with a critical difference,
which is because satellites are expensive
and we wanna serve a lot of customers,
we'll send it on a really
broad forward link signal.
You'll notice that the
footprint of this signal
reaches both our attacker in Ghana
and our customer in the Atlantic Ocean.
So those radio waves carrying
that response from Google
will hit our attacker satellite dish
at the same time as it hit the customers.
This is the crux of
satellite eavesdropping.
An attacker can reliably
expect to intercept the signal
from very far away on these forward links,
but they can't always be guaranteed
to see both sides of the conversation,
which is somewhat unusual
for an eavesdropper.
Additionally, we can think
about the security properties
in this context.
Because if we're imagining
say, a vulnerability in wifi
or GSM where the attacker
has to be in your city
or in your neighborhood to
intercept your communications,
here, an attacker can be
in a different country
or on a different continent
from their victim.
So what does an attacker actually need
to pull off this attack?
Let's talk a little bit
about our threat model.
So in this case, if the
attacker is a nation state,
it's very simple.
They simply need a little bit of money.
There are companies out there
that sells specialized modems
for intelligence collection
purposes like this one,
and you hook them up
to a multimillion dollar
ground station like this one,
and you're off to the races,
just listening to whatever
satellite signals you want.
And it's a pretty reasonable assumption
to say that national intelligence
services are doing this.
However, they don't
really give this equipment
to PhD students.
So I had to find a different
way to get us information
and that prior research
that talked about using television signals
is what led our next step.
So we tried to see how far we could get
using simple home television equipment
that's widely available.
We picked up this nifty
flat panel satellite dish,
which costs around 90 bucks.
Although honestly, you
could get something free
off of Craigslist or
Gumtree most of the time,
you may even have a satellite
dish resting on your roof
that you could use.
And then we got a card
to interpret these
signals in our computer.
Now we use the professional end card,
which tends to run about 200 to $300.
You could use a much cheaper
card in the $80 price range
at the cost of maybe not being able
to comprehend the more
complex internet signals,
but you'd still definitely find something.
Once we have this equipment,
the next test is to actually use it
to connect to a satellite signal.
And figuring out where
the satellite is is easy,
it's public information.
And since in geostationary orbit,
they're not moving anywhere,
but actually connecting
is a little bit trickier.
So let me show you what that looks like
in our lab environment.
So what we're gonna go ahead and do,
is use a tool called EBSpro,
which is designed
to help people find
satellite television feeds
to listen to if they wanna
watch TV on their computer,
and we're gonna scan to hunt
for internet signals instead.
Now, what we're gonna do is
point our dish at a satellite
that we think has internet service,
say, because of a press release.
And we're gonna scan the KU
band of the radio spectrum
because that's what our
equipment is set up for.
And what we're looking for is signal
against all of this background noise
that's indicative of channels
that might have information.
In this case, the signal's pretty noisy,
but we do see a few distinct
humps in the spectrum graph
that might contain actual
traffic inside them.
We'll go ahead and tell our
card to connect to this one
and interpret it as a
digital video broadcasting
for satellite feed.
After a few seconds,
we get a lock meaning
that we found a satellite
and we're listening to
the signals from it.
Now, for the demo,
I'm gonna connect to
this weaker signal here
because I know it has
interesting information.
You'll see the signal to
noise ratio is pretty abysmal.
So we're not likely to
get all of the packets
in this network, but hopefully
we'll find something.
I'll go ahead and real quick,
just jot down some information
about the frequency,
the orientation, and the symbol rate,
because we're going to
have to switch tools.
This tool doesn't get us all the way,
it's designed for television feeds
and what we really want is raw data
from that digital video
broadcasting signal.
So to do that,
I'll use a tool that's
provided with our device,
that PCIe card in the drivers.
We'll lock to that signal we discovered,
and then we'll kick off a quick recording.
The amount of traffic you
get in a recording like this
is hugely variable.
You can get a terabyte in a week,
you could get a megabyte in a week,
it depends on your equipment
and the signal you're listening to.
In this case,
I'm just gonna record a
couple of hundred kilobytes,
and then we'll take a look at the file
and see if we have any indicators
that it has internet traffic
instead of television traffic.
There's no trick here to differentiating
between the two types.
All I'm gonna do is just
grep through that binary file
for the string HTTP,
which we would expect to see
in an internet recording,
but we wouldn't expect to
see in a television feed.
And sure enough,
we see here what looks like
the output of a SOAP API.
At this point, this is a
security vulnerability.
We're seeing clear text information
from someone else's internet signal
using freely available tools
and commercial off the shelf equipment.
And that's pretty bad.
They could have sensitive information
just in this API string.
But as an attacker, what we really want
is to see if we can pull
off something even worse.
We wanna understand the
semantics of this connection,
the nature of the communications.
And to do that we have to
delve a bit into the protocols
that are being used.
So in our research, we've
looked at two protocols,
although there are others out there.
The first is called MPEG-TS.
Now you might be saying,
"MPEG? Isn't that a
video streaming format?"
And you'd be correct.
MPEG is widely used across the internet
for sending videos.
It's used for satellite television
video feeds, for example.
And over the years,
people have added all
kinds of weird additions.
They've added the ability
to pause a live satellite television
or update your set top boxes
firmware over these feeds.
And these functionalities
have been hacked together,
offer interactivity and internet services.
And so inside all of these
layers of weird protocols,
you have a fairly
standard container format
that there's a lot of great
tools for working with.
And so, in fact, if you're really lucky
and you get a high quality
signal to noise ratio,
you may just be able
to open that file we saved in the desktop
directly in Wireshark and
start seeing real packets.
This is where prior research focused,
because it was a pretty
straightforward process
to line up all the tools correctly.
And then you could spend most of your time
looking at the contents of the traffic,
which is the interesting bit.
However, MPEG-TS is still a used standard
for satellite internet,
but it's getting replaced
by newer protocols like GSC
or Generic Stream Encapsulation.
GSE makes a lot more sense.
It essentially has an IP layer,
which is embedded inside
of this generic stream,
which is broken up into fragments
and then put directly
into that digital video broadcasting feed.
So you have none of the
weird MPEG characteristics
that are intended for video streaming
around relevant internet.
We found that it was particularly popular
among enterprise customers.
So people who had an entire
satellite transponder
for their network, think
like maritime customers
or aviation customers.
But these customers also
had much better equipment
than we do.
They would spend tens to
hundreds of thousands of dollars
on signal processing hardware.
Whereas we're using like
200 bucks of a PCIe card.
And so when we were trying
to receive these signals,
we were often missing
fragments of IP packets
and had super corrupted feeds,
which meant that existing tools
weren't able to parse
these signals for us.
We didn't get much help in that regard.
So what we did instead
is build our own tool called GSExtract.
And the goal of GSExtract
is to forensically reconstruct, PCAP files
from corrupted recordings of GSE feeds.
And it does this by taking some shortcuts.
If we were designing a satellite modem,
we would have to consider
all of the edge cases
and how a network operates
or how a packet gets sent.
But for GSExtract, we can say,
generally, we would expect
the start of an IP packet
to appear here,
or we would expect this fragment
to belong to this payload.
And by making some of those assumptions,
GSExtract is able to help
us figure out what to do
with between 50 and 70% of the frames
that are hitting our dish.
This is significantly
better than existing tool,
which are just throwing error message
because the feed is so corrupted.
Hopefully, by the time that
you're watching this recording,
GSExtract will be available
on my research group's GitHub.
It may take a little bit longer,
because we're still doing
some responsible disclosure
review process stuff,
but we should eventually end up there.
In the interim,
if you wanna delve into how
it works a little bit deeper,
it's described in pretty high detail
in a related academic paper
that we published a few months ago
in the appendix of that paper.
So this is what you get
at the end of the day
by using GSExtract.
This is a JPEG file that we intercepted
from an engineer aboard a maritime vessel
who is dealing with a maintenance issue
and sending pictures to his colleagues.
You'll see that we're able to
get the start of the packet.
We're able to figure
out, this is a JPEG file,
we knew what port it was going to.
We knew the nature of the communications,
but at some point we
start losing fragments
and then in the case of a
compressed file like this,
we aren't able to get everything.
That said, the first chunk of an IP paleo
often has the most interesting bits.
It may be the entire packet,
or it maybe the parts that you care about
from a session log in or something.
And so we think this is
still useful to an attacker,
even if it's not 100% recovery
and allows someone to get away with $200
or $300 of home television equipment
and do harm
that they would otherwise need
tens of thousands of dollars
to play with in these networks.
All right. So at this
point, we're in a good spot.
We have a satellite dish that
we can use to talk to signals.
We know that if those signals
are in the digital video
broadcasting for satellite format,
which is very common
from geostationary orbit,
we can parse that using that
PCIe card on our computer.
Depending on the contents
of those streams,
we can use existing tools
like dvbsnoop or Wireshark
or tools we've written
ourselves like GSExtract
to get meaningful pcap data out of it
and understand the
internet traffic inside.
The next step is really
to understand the impact
of what we found.
How does this affect modern users
of terrestrial satellite
communications, maritime,
and aviation communication links.
So across all three of these domains,
there are a couple of
general things we found
that are worth highlighting.
The first is that none
of the ISPs we looked at
appeared to employ encryption by default.
That is to say that individual customers
might choose to encrypt their traffic,
but the satellite ISP were
sending over the satellite feed
traffic in essentially the same format
that was coming into the modem.
What this means is that as an attacker,
we had an ISP level vantage
point on the traffic
that was coming to a customer.
We saw every website they visited,
every bit torrent they downloaded,
every connection they made,
would pass over that satellite
link and we would get it.
But when we looked at
the enterprise customers,
this got even more interesting.
Because a lot of these enterprise networks
operate basically as a land environment
across the satellite feed.
A good example is a cruise
line we were looking at
that had Windows machines
on all of their ships
and the internal Windows LDAP
traffic from that network,
that windows local area environment,
was being broadcast
across the satellite feed.
Getting to see Windows to Windows,
corporate land communications
as a wireless eavesdropper
is really unusual.
And we thought it was a
particularly interesting angle
'cause it got us behind the firewall
of a lot of these big
corporations networks.
So the first environment
I wanna talk about,
the first domain is terrestrial customers.
And these were really interesting to us
because they're real people.
They're your home internet users
and they care about privacy.
Now, I know what you might be saying.
You might say, "Wait a second,
my browser has this lock icon on it,
which says that my traffic is encrypted.
What could an eavesdropper
do to cause harm to me?"
And I would say to you,
convenient made up straw man,
that there's actually a
lot that an attacker can do
to mess with your
communications in this context.
So even though we can't see exactly
the content of your communications,
we get to see your DNS
queries for example,
which is essentially every
website you're visiting.
And we can use that to piece
together your browsing history.
Additionally, those TLS certificates
that you think are protecting your traffic
are protecting the
contents of that traffic,
but they're fingerprinting
the websites you're visiting,
which allowed us
to determine which
networks devices belong to
or generally where users were going.
Now, this is a mild privacy concern,
you don't want an entire continent
to hear your browsing history,
but it gets worse when you slip up.
One of the most illustrative
examples of this
comes from a lawyer
whose emails we intercepted
across this feed.
So this lawyer in Spain was communicating
with one of his clients
about an upcoming court case.
He happened to be a defense attorney.
And we intercepted the emails
that were going to his inbox
'cause he was using POP3 to download them
over the satellite link.
And so this is obviously bad
news for that attorney's client
and for attorney/client privilege
and customer privacy in
general and all of that.
But it gets a little bit
worse if we think about it
in the context of everything
else we know about this lawyer.
Because we also know what
other websites he was visiting.
And so we can say, "Hey, this
lawyer goes to paypal.com."
We see that from his DNS queries,
we have his email address
and we can read everything
that goes through his inbox.
We can go and hit the "Reset
my password" link on PayPal
and essentially hijack his accounts.
This demonstrates how a
man in the middle attacker
who's listening to your entire connection,
who's essentially an
internet service provider,
can engage in attacks that
are way more sophisticated
than someone who's just
eavesdropping in a single connection
to an insecure service.
So the other thing we were
curious about were IOT systems
'cause these didn't really exist
when people were looking
at these feeds last time,
especially in the electricity
and critical infrastructure domain.
We found that a lot of operators
seem to be using these
networks under the assumption
that they were secure
against eavesdropping.
A great example of this
is a major electricity provider in Europe
who had this HTTP basic
authentication login
that you see on the left
to access the Cisco router
inside their networks configuration page.
And I blacked out all of
the sensitive information,
but clearly this is a clear text,
admin username and credential
that could probably change
some settings on that router.
And if you have a keen eye,
you'll see that the host IP address
for this router is publicly routable,
meaning that anyone with
an internet connection
could use these credentials
to log into the device.
Very similarly, I touched
on this at the beginning,
there are a lot of wind turbines
that use satellite connections
because they're in remote locations
and they all have
terrestrial internet access.
And what we found is that a lot of them
have these control panels
that were used to configure the devices
that were being sent
over the satellite feed.
And these control panels
are publicly routable
over the open internet.
So we could get these credentials
that were being leaked in clear text
over the satellite feed,
whether that'd be a login
cookie or username and password,
and combine it with
any internet connection
to potentially start messing around
with these power generation facilities.
Now, obviously we didn't
engage in any attacks
on electrical grid system
so there could be another
protection when you log in
as some sort of second factor control,
but I think it's intuitively concerning
that this stuff is getting
sent in clear text.
So heading out to sea for a moment,
I think one of the most
interesting things for us
about the maritime case
was how unique every
boat in the network is.
So we had these terabytes
and terabytes of traffic
from all kinds of different companies
and all kinds of different ships.
And what we really wanted
to do was figure out a way
to tie an IP address in
this massive pcap file
to a specific boat in the ocean
to figure out what it was doing.
So we picked 100 random IP addresses
from the thousands that we had,
and we set ourselves a little challenge.
We designed a fingerprint
based off of DNS queries
and TLS certificates
and a couple of strings
for the first few
kilobytes of their traffic
and we used that to see
if we could de-anonymize IP
addresses and identify ships.
This very basic manual
process was sufficient
to de-anonymize 10% of the
vessels in that case study.
So we de-anonymized 12 vessels,
I've hidden their names here
because I wanna maintain
the privacy of their owners,
but you get a real sense for the breadth
of the type of ships
impacted by this research.
So the smallest fleet that we listened to
was this fishing fleet here,
which had a single fishing vessel
and was using some software
over the satellite feed
to help it find fish.
I'm not really sure how it works.
On the flip side, we had
this enormous container ship,
one of the larger container
ships in the world,
belonging to one of the
largest shipping companies
in the world.
And it's operating within
the same IP address space
as that random fishing crew.
Beyond being able to
identify which companies
and organizations are affected,
another cool thing we could do
is fingerprint operational
technology aboard the vessel.
Good example is this subsea
repair ship down here,
which was owned by a
major petroleum company.
And we were able to identify
from the traffic inside those pcap files,
that there was a device on board the ship
running a vulnerable version
of Windows Server 2003,
that had all kinds of CVEs
that could be deployed against it.
At this point, if we
wanted to attack that ship,
we could potentially deploy CVEs,
not just against that one,
but against any ship in this
petroleum company's fleet
and potentially cause some serious harm.
So another piece of operational technology
we were curious about
was something called
Electronic Chart Display
and Information Systems or ECDIS.
And ECDIS are essentially
GPS map terminals for boats.
They tell boats where they
can go safely or legally,
they have various hazard
updates for mariners
and there's been a lot of great
research on securing them.
There're actually formats out there
to stop people from
tampering with these charts
using various cryptographic
authenticity guarantees.
Unfortunately, we saw that
a lot of maritime operators
were using older or proprietary
versions of these formats
that did not have protections
against tampering attacks
that we could see.
Now, you might be saying,
"Why does this matter?"
You can get free nautical charts
and maybe save a couple hundred bucks
if you wanna go on a sailing expedition,
but can you really mess with this data
as somebody who's just passively listening
to a satellite connection?
It turns out that you can.
Because a lot of these
are updated insecurely.
A great example is this ship,
which had a publicly
routable FTP server on board.
And the way that we
get their chart updates
is someone on land in the back office
would copy the latest chart files
into a folder called Chart
Delivery on the FTP server.
And then it would get deployed
to the ECDIS terminal.
Now, because it's FTP servers
accessible over the internet,
anyone with an internet
connection can connect to it.
And the password is getting sent
in clear text over the satellite feed,
cause they didn't use SFTP.
And so it would be pretty
trivial to send a false chart
to this folder or even
deploy targeted malware.
Another common way that charts
get update is via emails.
And generally there's an email address
like
chartupdates_shipname@shipcompany.org,
which will get updates
every so often as
attachments to the inbox,
the captain will copy those
files onto a flash drive,
walk over to the ECDIS
terminal, plug it in
and update the information.
That's not inherently insecure,
but if you're like this captain
and you use an insecure email protocol,
then we get a pretty good template
for a targeted social
engineering operation
that might persuade you to copy
malicious charts or malware
onto your own vessel's critical
operational technology.
Beyond this operational technology,
I think it's important to remember
that there are real
people aboard these ships
who have real privacy concerns.
Like billionaires sailing
around on their super yachts.
Now I know getting up
at DEFCON and saying,
"Think of the billionaires"
is not a great starting point,
but this was a really fun case study
that I wanna delve into a little bit.
So we were listening to this traffic
from this Greek billionaire's mega yacht
and there were all kinds
of interesting anecdotes
that came up in the traffic
that really painted a
picture of what was going on.
For example, one day the
captain of this yacht
forgot the login to his Microsoft account.
And so the credentials
for that captain's account
came across a satellite feed in clear text
in the format of an account reset link.
Now, at this point, we
could hijack the account
of someone who has a reason to communicate
with a very high net worth individual
and potentially engage
in some super targeted
social engineering attacks.
Because the captain's email address
included the name of the yacht,
we could also very easily identify
which billionaire was
affected by this traffic.
Additionally, once we've had de-anonymized
the owner of this yacht,
there were other things
we could piece together.
For example, the yacht used software
to manage lunch orders and
stuff for the crew members
and for guests.
And so we could see who this
billionaire was inviting
on their yacht or where they were going,
or even what they were eating
for lunch on a particular day,
which is not inherently sensitive,
but if you're hiding who you're meeting
and you don't want an entire continent
to know about your social life,
it could be a little bit
concerning for these individuals.
Beyond the billionaires though,
there are also regular people
on vessels across the sea
who have privacy concerns.
Another privacy thing that we encountered
was what looked like point
of sale terminal traffic
coming off of cruise ships
from a major European cruise operator.
And I don't know if there were
credit card numbers in here
so I've censored the data very heavily.
A lot of the numbers
did pass the loon check,
but it could have been coincidental.
At the very least,
anything that tells you how
much someone paid for a soda,
what their name was
and when they did it is
pretty deeply concerning
that it's being broadcast
across an entire continent in clear text.
Another example of sensitive information
from real people on cruise ships
or on vessels would be
when ports have cargo vessels come in,
they often require the crew to
share some visa information.
And this particular port authority thought
that a great way to do that
would be an insecure HTTP web service.
And so as a result,
we could see from the cargo
vessels pulling into this port,
all of the names and passport numbers
and date of birth of the crew
members of what these ships.
Obviously this is deeply
sensitive information
that should have been encrypted.
All right, let's head out to the skies.
So the aviation use space
is really interesting to me
because it's the newest one.
We were gonna do this
as our 2020 experiment.
We're gonna get all kinds of great data
from airplanes this year
and really get a feeling
for how aviation intersects
with satellite communication security.
And we started out great.
We had some great traffic
from these inflight entertainment
systems in February,
we're super excited for the year
and then everyone stopped flying.
The number of people in
airplanes sank dramatically
because of the pandemic.
And so the amount of traffic
we were getting also tanked.
I was originally pretty salty about this,
but then I realized
that there's actually
a silver lining here.
You see, back in February,
the traffic we were seeing was a lot,
but it was mostly garbage.
It was people checking
their Facebook on a flight,
which isn't that interesting
from a security researcher perspective.
But in April when the
airplanes were flying empty,
almost all of the
traffic in these networks
was somehow essential to either
the operation of the airline
or the operation of the airplane.
There were no passengers
to generate noise.
And even as passenger counts increase,
the passengers we saw
tended to be high value
business executives,
as opposed to just random tourists,
which made the traffic a
little bit more interesting
from a privacy perspective.
Now, because we had
this unique opportunity,
there was something I wanted to test,
which was a claim that
was made by a researcher
whose work I really admire.
So Ruben Santamarta does
research in satellite modems.
He's definitely presented at Black-Hat
and DEFCON and stuff,
doing a lot of hardware
reverse engineering.
And he has this blog post
where he looks at inflight
entertainment systems,
including some of the systems
that we received traffic from.
And he posited that he
suspects the satellite terminal
could be a bridge between
the part of the airplane
that keeps people entertained and happy
and the part of the airplane
that keeps it in the sky
and going in the right direction.
And we wanted to see if there was anything
in these traffic captures
that cross that red line
and cross those two separate
information security domains,
which shouldn't be happening.
We would have missed this
if we had all of that Facebook traffic.
We actually had traffic from
this device for several months
and we didn't realize it
until coronavirus hit.
But we found what I'm going
to call the loneliest EFB.
So EFB is an Electronic Flight Bag.
It's essentially a information terminal
like an ECDIS terminal but for airplanes.
And it includes navigational information
and weather updates and all kinds of stuff
that the pilot needs to manage the flight.
And this specific Chinese airline
had made a mistake in
configuring their EFB
such that it wasn't logging in correctly,
someone had fat-fingered
a password or something.
And so all of the
requests they were sending
were getting bounced off
of this redirect page
from the satellite modem and reaching us.
And we could use that
to not only fingerprint how this API works
and what data is being
sent from the airplane
and where the airplane was at any time,
but we could also identify other vessels
that were using this same device.
And even though it seems
to be encrypted over
the air in most cases,
we're able to confirm that the network
that's carrying this
operational technology traffic
is the same one as the
person a few rows back
who's browsing Instagram.
Another case that we were
interested in for airplanes
is something called a femtocell.
There've been a couple of talks at DEFCON,
about it, I think.
And it's essentially a
miniature cell tower,
that they put an airplanes
that allows customers
to use their cell phones as
if they were on the ground.
And we saw that the front end
of these is fairly secure,
uses GSM or LTE or whatever,
which has some security
guarantees over the air,
but the backend was
being routed un-encrypted
in these SCTP wrappers
over the satellite signal.
And so we're able to see
the contents of people's
cellular communications.
What's particularly scary about this
is that we don't know
if these customers were aware
of what they were doing.
If you forgot to put your
phone into airplane mode,
it's very possible a text message
that you received during your flight
will show up in our packet captures.
You're not even aware you're connected
to a satellite network.
And to bring home the severity,
here's a good example.
There's this person who was on a flight
and in the middle of their flight,
they got their negative
coronavirus test result.
Now that's a huge relief
for anyone who's sitting
next to him on the airplane.
But for the rest of us who
care about health data privacy,
it's a huge information breach
that this is being sent in
clear text, across a continent.
We saw all kinds of wild text messages.
I remember listening to some guy
who spoke Croatian in his text messages,
talking about a wild dream he had
where it's friend's mom showed up
in a burning house or something,
just real people's personal communications
are being sent in clear text.
And it's not just personal communications,
if you've ever used like
SMS as a second factor
for account login,
it's clear how this could be deployed
in an account hijacking attack.
So fundamentally, everything
we've done is passive.
We haven't gotten any equipment
to send signals in these networks,
we don't have a license to do that,
but is it possible,
there are other semi-active
or fully active attacks
we could deploy against these networks?
One scenario I saw, which
is based off of some malware
that actually has been used in practice
by a Russian ABT group called Turley Group
would be to use satellites
for untraceable data exfiltration.
And there are only two
requirements for this to play out.
First, you have to compromise the device
that you wanna steal data from,
and it needs to be connected to a network
that has a route to a
satellite IP address.
Generally, the internet is sufficient
because there are a lot
of satellite devices
that have internet routable IP addresses,
but it could also be a device
inside someone's land LAN environment.
Additionally, as an attacker,
you need to be able to be
inside that satellite signal's
forward link footprint.
You need to be able to
eavesdrop on the traffic
and that's it.
Let's see how this plays out.
So an attacker who's compromised
the device has a problem.
They wanna send the
sensitive data they've stolen
to their server somewhere on the internet.
The problem is that if they decide
to just route this along the internet,
just send a post request
with whatever file they have
to a web server they run,
then law enforcement can very
easily trace that post request
and identify where the attackers
commanding control server
or data exfiltration database is.
But if the attacker uses a
satellite hop as an intermediary,
they can really cause some
trouble for law enforcement.
Because you see, the compromised
computer with the malware
can send the signal to
the satellite customer
that will be routed
over the satellite feed.
And this customer doesn't
need to be involved at all,
it can just be a random ship in the ocean
that happens to have an IP address.
It doesn't even need a
service running at that port,
it could be a closed court
or broken connection.
And what will happen as the satellite
will beam that signal down
across its footprint area
and if a law enforcement officer
tries to investigate this,
they'll see it reach this broken
surface on a maritime ship
and have no idea where it's gone.
Meanwhile, behind the scenes,
the attacker can be using a satellite dish
to eavesdrop on that connection
and leak information in clear text.
Even if the satellite network
had some degree of encryption,
which there are some
networks out there that do,
the attacker might still be able to use
even just like the size of packets
or the contents of packets
or the existence of packets
as a signal that's virtually untraceable
because there are somewhere
in this massive continent-sized footprint
and that's all law enforcement
could possibly know.
Another attack that we tried to pull off
is something called TCP Session Hijacking,
which is a very classic networking attack.
Essentially TCP has
this three way handshake
to set up connections
where you have to know
these randomly selected
sequence numbers to prove
you are who you say you are.
And what we found is that in
certain satellite environments,
you could actually impersonate
one of these end points,
very reliably due to the
physical characteristics of orbit
and hijack orbitary TCP session numbers.
We did this against our own
connection to one device
in one specific satellite network,
but we didn't test it
at a very broad scale
cause we didn't wanna mess
with anything important.
Let me give you a show of how this works
from a physical perspective.
So let's take a look.
So just like before, we
have someone in Ireland,
only this time they're
in a maritime office
that wants to visit a website
that's hosted in the cargo
vessel with status information.
So what they'll do is
they'll send a TCP SYN number
as a start to the TCP through a handshake.
And this has a sequence
number that you have to know
to prove that you received
the start of the handshake
and that you're a party
to this conversation.
This is like a very fundamental protection
against spoofing attacks.
However, our attacker can
easily get the sequence number
over the un-encrypted satellite link
and that the next step, our attacker,
remember, how I said they
were in Accra in Ghana?
So Accra happens
to have some of the fastest
terrestrial internet in Africa
and a direct backbone link to the UK,
although that doesn't necessarily matter.
But because the speed of
light is only so fast,
the attacker 100% of the time
can beat the legitimate
acknowledgement message
from that handshake to our
maritime office in Ireland.
And at this point,
the maritime office will
start a conversation
thinking they're talking to the vessel
when they're actually sending
information to our attacker.
Our attacker can continue
to eavesdrop over the satellite link
and that message with their
spoofed acknowledgement
will reach the ship at sea,
who will simply ignore it,
because it has incorrect sequence numbers.
But our attacker at
this point has free rein
to send whatever information they want
to the maritime office
and impersonate the ship
in a way that is virtually undetectable,
if you're not employing some
certificate signing scheme.
So this is a very simple example
that shows that even though
we can't transmit directly
in a satellite network,
we're fundamentally a
part of a broader network,
which is the internet.
And in that environment,
active attacks are definitely possible.
So obviously this research
has some ethical implications,
it's a real world
networks and real people.
So we're very careful
to adhere to the laws
and go above and beyond that.
You might be a little disappointed today
that I haven't made and
shamed any companies,
that's a conscious choice
because I don't want this
to be about X airline
is leaking your data.
I want the focus to be on the fact
that this is a systemic issue
that affects a lot,
thousands, tens of thousands,
of satellite customers around the world.
We've of course engaged
in responsible disclosure.
Many of the satellite
companies have known about this
as early as 2019, as well
as some of their customers
who have leaked particularly
interesting data
or are particularly large.
Most people were receptive to this.
We talked to a lot of CISOs
who have started changing
around their networks.
We don't know exactly what they're doing,
but at least they're aware of the risks.
And we only had one
company threaten to sue us,
which is really good
for this systemic cybersecurity research.
We got a huge boost to
responsible disclosure,
courtesy of the Federal
Bureau of Investigation
who releases threat
intelligence notification
to the maritime industry.
And what's really interesting
about this notification
is that it showed up online from the FBI
almost a month before our academic paper
was publicly available.
So the only people who had
access to this PDF file
were people who were
responsibly disclosed to
with the request that they keep it private
and our academic peer reviewers.
Yet somehow the FBI was able
to cite specific information
from a chart inside that paper.
Now as a researcher, this
is a little bit unsettling,
how to did the FBI get my paper
before I gave it to anyone?
But if you're ever wondering
if you should join one of these
threat intelligence schemes,
it's clear that the FBI does a good job
at getting a scoop ahead of the industry
or even the researchers themselves
thinking it's out there.
So how do we protect against
these attacks going forward?
How do we defend these networks?
Well, I think we need to understand
why these kinds of attacks can happen.
And it's easy to say it's
'cause satellite operators are ignorant,
but the reality is more complicated.
Remember when I said the speed
of light is only so fast,
that means that sending a
signal to space is slow,
which makes all of those
TCP connections you get
when you visit a website,
add up to make your
internet seem really slow.
So what ISPs have done
is they started splitting these handshakes
as a man in the middle
attacker, basically,
who benevolently
accelerates your connection,
via what we call it,
performance enhancing proxy.
The problem is that
if a customer uses end to
end encryption over VPN,
these performance enhancing proxies
can't find those TCP
through the handshakes
and so they can't
accelerate the connection.
So in the short term,
you might have to accept that as reality.
And just say, you know what,
passport numbers are sensitive enough
that we should send them
encrypted or not send them at all.
And in many cases,
if you're using a TTP
layer encryption protocol
or a UDP encryption protocol,
it doesn't affect performance at all.
You should never be using
pop for your emails,
although we found thousands of
thousands of people still do,
you should be using an
encrypted email client.
And since ISPs are already screwing around
with TCP sequence
numbers and TCP sessions,
if they just change the
sequence numbers over the air,
from what they are in the ground,
they can prevent TCP hijacking attacks.
A lot of ISPs seem to do this already,
although I think it's largely accidental.
In the longer term, though,
we're trying to work on a solution
that makes it easier
for individual customers
to be sure their data is always encrypted,
regardless of what protocol
mistakes they might make.
We're building a tool called QPEP
which uses the quick protocol,
which is a TCP replacement
that is encrypted by default.
And it's a combination
between a tunneling VPN
and a performance enhancing proxy.
If you wanna take a look at QPEP,
there is a public GitHub
repository for it.
This isn't like a commercial product,
the goal is to build a tool
for people to start playing around
with securing these networks.
It's designed to be much more accessible
than existing PEPs,
which tend to be written
in these really obtuse C
libraries for networking.
It's written in Python as a test bed
so you can simulate it without
a satellite equipment at all.
And then most of the
networking layer is written
and go for performance reasons.
And the end goal
is to help individuals
protect their traffic
instead of trying to berate
ISPs into encrypting data,
which we know doesn't work
because we've been doing it since 2005.
So this shows the difference
between those two options
versus using a encrypted
proxy like the one
that we're building and using
a very good open source VPN
but one that doesn't take into
account the unique aspects
of satellite communications.
And you can see the difference
in the amount of time it takes
to load just a very typical webpage
as an indicator
of why customers aren't
encrypting their data.
It's not that they don't
know privacy is at risk.
Many of the people the
response we're to disclosed to
were like, "This isn't a
security vulnerability,
because everyone knows about it,"
which has its own problems.
But I think fundamentally
when you give someone a choice
between performance and privacy,
it's very likely that they
will choose performance,
especially in an
environment like satellite,
where you already have
sluggish connections.
And so finding technological solutions
that enable people to have
as good of a performance
as they've come to expect
while adding in privacy,
basically invisible in the background,
is I think the best way
that we can bolster privacy
and security in these networks
for real satellite customers.
So to sum things up,
today, I've presented the
case that satellite broadband,
as it's used in the status quo,
is vulnerable to long range
eavesdropping attacks.
Someone in a different country
or on a different continent from you
can be listening to your
internet communications.
And yet many people act
like this isn't the case.
Whether it's a massive fortune 500 company
or a random person in a
coffee shop somewhere,
people are leaking
deeply sensitive traffic
over satellite feeds as if they don't know
that an eavesdropper could be listening.
We think this can be changed.
We think the underlying reason
that this is still a problem
is that performance encryption
is something that ISPs have to build
into their satellite networks
instead of something
that individuals can
just run for themselves
when they connect to a satellite terminal.
And we think that we can
balance out that trade off
and bring security to customers
regardless of how they interface
with their satellite connection.
So if I wanted to give a broader lesson,
a major takeaway from this talk
that has almost nothing
to do with satellites,
it would be very simple.
And that is that the Next Hop is unknown.
When you connect to the internet,
there's a whole web of
different nodes and connections
that's constantly changing,
that's routing your traffic.
And any one of those nodes
could be a satellite link
or a wireless tower or a
wire tapped ethernet cable.
And so if we wanna be sure
that no one is listening to our traffic,
wherever it might go next,
'cause we could connect to a wifi hotspot
and it could have the best
encryption in the world,
but if the Next Hop is a satellite link,
that does us no good.
So having the ability to
encrypt your own traffic,
having the right to
encrypt your own traffic
and having the knowledge
to make that encryption
as secure and robust as possible,
is I think critical to preventing
this whole class of attack
regardless of the domain
we consider it in.
Thank you so much for
listening to my presentation.
I'm happy to answer
any questions via email
or in a breakout session after this.
And I hope you enjoyed the talk.