- Hello everyone. Thank you
for attending this talk.
I am Slava, I am a security
researcher at Checkpoint.
Security research is my daily work.
Today, I am going to show
how an Android application
can affect the digital signal
processor of a mobile device,
and thereby gain privileges
and denial of service capabilities.
Let's begin with a question.
Do you know how many processors
are on your mobile phone?
The answer is many.
As a single Snapdragon system on a chip,
embedded in Pixel, Samsung,
Xiaomi, G, OnePlus,
Sony and other devices.
May include multiple CPU codes.
An Adreno graphic processor unit,
a Snapdragon viral model,
a Hexagon digital signal processor,
and Spectra image signal processor.
Snapdragon product tiers are
differentiated by scalable
computing resources for
this CPU, GPU and DSP.
The lowest tiers might contain
only a single Hexagon DSP
whereas the premium tier,
contains up to four
Hexagon DSP processors,
dedicated for specific use cases.
These are, modern DSP, known as baseband,
audio DSP, compute DSP and sensor DSP.
In this research,
I turned my attention to
aDSP and cDSP subsystems.
aDSP and cDSP processors are
intended for such group tasks
as processing of audio and voice data,
computer vision, machine
learning calculations,
camera streaming, artificial
intelligence, et cetera.
On some devices such as a Sony Xperia XZ,
only this aDSP processor
is responsible for all these tasks.
But on other devices such as the Pixel 4,
these tasks are shared
between aDSP and cDSP.
Let's take a look at the communications,
in between an Android application
and a DSP running library.
FastRPC is the Qualcomm
proprietary RPC mechanism
used to enable remote function calls,
between application processor,
where Android is run and DSP.
On Android side,
user mode process initiates
the remote in our case.
In our case and Android application,
calls one of the stub
functions in its name before.
Stub is autogenerated code,
that convert the function
all to an RPC message.
Generally, the stub code is compiled
as separate native library.
The stub code, loads
libadsprpc.so and lipcdsprpc.so
built-in libraries, and
to invoke Android drivers.
DSPRPC drivers sent the QuRT message
to the DSP side, through the
surety memory trial channel,
and then wait for the response.
On DSP side, a framework presented by,
the FastRPC shell binary,
dig uses as the messages
and dispatches them for
processing by a skeleton code.
And again, skeleton is
an autogenerated library
that unmarshals parameters,
and causes a target method
in the object library.
The object library is some
logic provided by Qualcomm OEMs
and design to run on aDSP.
Who can run their own code on DSP?
And if your party developer can implement
it's own DSP library.
Because the Hexagon SDK,
which is responsible for
compiling C C Plus Plus code
in the Hexagon byte book
is publicly available.
But it's impossible to run at
a third party library on DSP.
For security reasons,
DSP is licensed for programming by OEMs
and code running on the
DSP is signed by Qualcomm.
Who manages the DSP? It's QuRT.
A Qualcomm Proprietary Multi-Threaders,
Real Time Operating System.
Integrity of the QuRT is
trusted by the TrustZone,
QuRT executable binary and
different for aDSP and cDSP,
is signed and split into several files,
in the same way as any
other trusted application
on Qualcomm devices.
For each Android process,
initiating the remote in my case,
QuRT create a separate FastRPC
shell process on the DSP.
The DSP architecture,
provides different protection domains, PD.
Kernel PD has access to
all memory of all domains
and Quest OS PD has access
to the memory of its own PD,
the memory of the user PD
and some system registers.
User PD has access only to its own memory.
Skeleton and object libraries,
as well as the FastRPC shell
are running in the user protection domain.
The stub code provided by Qualcomm OEMs,
can be skipped from the FastRPC chain.
As was mentioned, libadsprpc
and libcdsprpc libraries
are responsible for
communication this DSPRPC driver.
Each library exports two major functions.
Remote handle open function
opens remote session
between the client on
application processor
and Nu FastRPC shell process on the DSP.
The skeleton library name is
provided as the (murmurs).
Remote handle invoke function
is able to invoke methods
exported by the skeleton library.
You then these two functions,
and Android application
can request to execute
any skeleton method
without using a stub code.
Now, we have enough information
to state the downgrade vulnerabilty.
DSP libraries are signed
and cannot be patched.
However, any Android application
can bring as signed by
Qualcomm skeleton library,
in its assets and then
open a remote session.
The library will be
successfully loaded onto the DSP
because it's signature is correct.
The fact that there is no version check
of loading skeleton libraries,
opens the possibility to
run a very old skeleton lib,
with known 1-day
vulnerabilities on the DSP.
Even if the patched skeleton
library already exists
on the device,
it's possible to go the old
version of this library.
Any DSP code fix can simply
be bypassed by an attacker.
Due to the lack of list
of skeleton libraries
permitted to the device,
it's possible to run a library
intended for one device,
for example, China's
Xiaomi on any other device,
for example, Samsung.
This means that a
vulnerability discover it,
in one of OEMs libraries,
compromises all Snapdragon-based
Android devices.
Okay, the major goal of the research
was to find the way to execute
custom code on the DSP.
Bypassing Qualcomm signature.
To do this,
we had to discover and
explore the vulnerability
in a DSP running library.
DSP libraries are
proprietary Hexagon ELFs.
The easiest way to instrument
the Hexagon executable
is to use the open-source
quick emulate for QEMU.
Hexagon instruction set
support was editing the QEMU
only at the end of 2019,
and to hit a lot of box
to be able to run a real DSP libraries
in the user mode of xen emulator.
To fuzz libs on you're Boon to PC,
we used American Fuzzy Lop AFL,
in combination with QEMU.
A skeleton library is primarily a library,
and we had to prepare a simple program,
skel loader that loads and wagziwa,
more or were, most skeleton libraries,
why they use these B frame
mod and system calls.
Our simple program could
not handle such requests.
Therefore, we had to load the QuRT OS,
on the MOA to before its
execution of the rest codes.
The easiest way to do so is
not to use the real QuRT OS,
but it's light version, around EOS PBN.
Adopted by Qualcomm for its
execution on a Hexagon simulator
and included in the Hexagon SDK.
That's it, the AFL promoter
is the content of the data,
the data file, and through
those execution of runelf.pbn
on the emulator.
QEMU returns a code
coverage metrics to the AFL,
after execution of the test case.
On this line, you can see the data format
that we used to fuzz skeleton libraries.
The fuzzed word is the second argument,
of the remote handle invoke function.
The index of the invoked
method, number of input,
and number of output
arguments are encoded here.
Next several words would take
as the size of arguments,
and then we expect to see
a value of input arguments.
We were surprised by the fuzzing results.
Crashes were found in all DSP libraries,
that we choose to fuzz.
Besides, most issues
were discovered exactly
in skeleton libraries.
This means that Hexagon SDK
produces the vulnerable code.
Hexagon SDK automatically
generate stub and skel code,
for marshaling and unmarshaling
of function arguments.
Let's take a look at an
example of such code.
Stub and skel code based on,
Interface Definition Model, IDL models
prepared by the developer.
Here you can see an example
of the IDL declaration
of two functions in the
neural network library,
Hexagon NN, a vulnerable code
will be generated for both.
Hexagon NN, SNPPrint function,
passes and input-output
buffer argument to the DSP.
In the stub code,
there's this buffer will be
split into two separate buffers,
the input and the output,
the value of the input buffer links,
will also be duplicated and
therefore ratio one to one.
The skel function
copies the input buffer
to the output buffer
before calling an object and a function,
the size of data to be copied,
is one of the transmitted buffer lengths.
An attacker controls this value int.
All verification checks
can simply be bypassed
by using a negative input buffer length.
Typecasting to the signed int
type on chicken a buffer boundaries,
is a bach leading to heap overflow.
To summarize, the
automatically generated code,
inject vulnerabilities into
the libraries of Qualcomm OEMs
and all assets of party developers
who use the Hexagon SDK.
Dozens of SDK skeleton
libraries pre-installed
on Android smartphones are vulnerable
due to serious bach in the SDK.
So, we discovered many vulnerabilities.
Let's explore one of them.
Libfastcdvadsp skel.so library,
can be found on most Android devices.
In this example, I use the lib extracted
from the Sony Xperia XZ Premium device,
and malicious Android
application can cause,
this lib to crash by
providing crafted arguments
to the remote handle invoke function.
The 3F method allows us to
read and write everything
that we want within the other
space of the DSP processor.
It's enough, to implement
and export and execute
an unsigned payload in the
user protection domain.
Okay, we go to code execution.
What can we do with it?
We can crush the DSP. We
can hide malicious code.
We can try to access
cameras, sensors and more.
Besides, now we can
communicate these QuRT drivers.
The next step of the research is to attack
the QuRT privileged domains
from the user protection domain.
And QuRT drivers are the
entry points for this.
QuRT OS implements it's
open device driver model,
named QuRT driver invocation, QDI.
Linux Power6,
and QDI device drivers,
operate these high
privileges as any user code.
Dozens of QDI drivers can
be found in QuRT vinyl.
Lipqurt.a library which
is part of Hexagon SDK,
contains the QuRT infrastructure.
FastRPC shell is linked
statically this slimer.
QDI provides a simple
driver invocation API,
where the ability to
access a device driver,
based only on the driver name.
Actually, only QuRT QDI
handle and walk macro,
is the necessary user visible API.
Is responsible for all
generic driver operations.
The QuRT QDI open is just a
special case of this month.
To fuzz QuRT drivers on you're boon to PC,
we use the same combination
of Hexagon QEMU and AFL,
as for fuzzing both
user mode DSP libraries.
QDI drivers were not included by Qualcomm
in their runelf.pbn version of QuRT,
therefore we had to patch,
the, around ELF file.
What did we do?
We appended programs segments
of QuRT ELF from a real device
and a directed malloc and
memcpy kernel functions,
used by QDI drivers to their
user mode implementation.
Our simple QDI exec program
is responsible for calling
a driver invocation
function by its address.
First of all, any failure QDI drivers,
can be used to reboot the mobile device.
For example, each of
the lines of this code,
fuzz code DSP panic,
and, can be used for a denial
of service attack on a device.
For research purposes,
we exploited one of
discovered vulnerabilities,
in drilling the QDI
driver, along is the user,
PG export, it allows us
to run a custom code,
in the context of the
guest OS protection domain.
Okay, now we'll show you a simple demo,
to prove the full stake, attack chain.
The payload between a DSP and kernel data,
in accessible form application processor.
The device is the Pixel.
I'm using the ADB shell, to run
to the performance the tech.
An Android application
can run this tool as well.
The first stage of the attack
is to to execute a code
in the context of user PD,
then the user payload triggers
the guest OS code execution,
vulnerability, and then
I dump sensitive data
such as the QuRT data segment
and then controls the phone.
For example, I reboot it.
Okay.
Instead of a conclusion,
I just want to know that Hexagon
aDSP and cDSP subsystems,
are very promising areas
for security research.
The DSP is accessible
for Android applications,
has access to interesting
data for an attacker.
And has many security issues.
Thank you for your attention.