- All right, welcome everyone.
My name is Jack Baker and
I'm gonna be talking about
bugs in game engine.
So, as a little bit of background
over the last few months
I found more than 10
remotely exploitable bugs
while looking at two
different game engines.
And I'm gonna be talking about
four of those bugs today.
So just to level set things.
When I use the term, Game Engine,
I'm referring to the base software
that most games are built on top of.
So if you're building a video game,
you're probably not doing it from scratch,
you're using a pre made
set of tools and software
that are built to make
that process easier.
And that software is
called your Game Engine.
And so the popularity of many game engines
means that a lot of games
share the exact same bugs.
This is made worse by the fact that
updating your game
engine can be a huge pain
as anyone who's done a lot of game dev
can probably tell you.
And games don't usually get
security patches after release.
Maybe like a bigger game,
will have some support,
but like an independent release
is not gonna get patches a
year or two years after release
just to fix some security bug.
So there aren't a whole
lot of good statistics
on what game engines are the most popular,
but there's a general understanding
that two of them are
more common than others,
and those are Unreal Engine 4 and Unity.
So as sort of a rule of thumb,
if you're a solo
developer or a small team,
there's a pretty good
chance you're using Unity,
whereas if you're a larger
team, but not so large
that you've built your
own engine from scratch,
you're probably using Unreal Engine 4.
So, Unreal Engine 4 is
created by Epic Games.
It's named for its roots
in the Unreal series.
It is opensource, there are
some licensing restrictions
on how you can use that source,
but for our perspective
of just looking for bugs,
all the code is out
there for us to look at.
And there are really
two big notable games,
I think right now, that are
built using Unreal Engine 4,
and those are Fortnite and PUBG.
Unity is built by Unity Technologies.
There are some open
source components of it,
but the core components of
Unity are closed source.
The core networking library
we're gonna be looking at
is called UNET, and while I couldn't find
a whole lot of like big
games that are using UNET,
there are countless
amount of indie releases
on Steam and everywhere else,
that are built using UNET.
Now I should say that UNET is deprecated,
but there are a few reasons
that I thought it would
be a good target anyway.
The first is that UNET
has not got an official replacement yet,
Unity hasn't put out an alternative yet.
So if you're using Unity and
you're doing multiplayer,
you're either using UNET still,
or you're using third party solution.
Also, UNET still does receive patches
and occasionally new features,
even though it's deprecated.
So the encryption API was added
to UNET after deprecation.
And so a ton of new, and
more importantly I think,
existing games use UNET.
So I think bugs in UNET
still have some value.
So, let's talk about
multiplayer protocols.
As game engines have evolved,
and as multiplayer protocols have evolved,
there's really been a focus on two things.
The first is obvious,
it's increasing performance,
increasing speed.
The other is moving trust
away from the client
in order to prevent hacking.
But as we're gonna see,
these can sometimes be conflicting goals.
But to really understand
multiplayer protocols,
I think it's worth understanding
the types of attacks that
they're aiming to prevent.
And I think the best example of this
is to talk about the evolution
of what we'll call Movement Hacking.
So, Movement Hacking is the process
of manipulating the player's location
in some way that the game
normally wouldn't allow.
In the old days, this was really easy
because player location was
just trusted to the client.
So if you manipulate your
location client-side,
you can teleport server-side.
And this got more difficult
as game engines got more complicated,
and trust was taken from the client
and put on the server for player location.
So the client can no
longer say, I'm at XYZ,
the client, all I can do
is make a request saying,
I would like to move,
I'm moving in this
direction at this speed,
and the server will update
their position accordingly.
This led to a new type of
attack called, Speed Hacking.
So it's sort of the next
evolution of Movement Hacking.
Speed Hacking, the goal is
not to teleport, necessarily,
but just to move extremely fast.
And typically the way this works
is you send that movement
request excessively fast,
faster than a normal client ever would,
and more requests then means more speed.
This was prevented by
basically giving more authority
and more context to the server.
So the server should be able to understand
what is a realistic distance
that a character can move
in a given timeframe.
And if a client is attempting
to move beyond that timeframe,
it can stop that from happening.
And so by giving this
context to the server,
we're able to prevent this type of attack.
And this is really how
game engines have evolved.
It's been a constant process
of moving trust away from the client
and giving more authority,
more responsibility,
and more context to the server
to understand what is normal.
So with all of this said,
let's talk about some of
the technical specifics
of multiplayer protocols.
Now there's no real
like published standard
of what a multiplayer protocol looks like,
but there are a few things
that are pretty consistent
between different protocols.
And the first of those, is
that most multiplayer protocols
use some form of Distributed Architecture.
And essentially what this means is,
each system, whether that
be a client or a server,
each system has a copy of
every networked object,
every object that's
connected to the network
in the game world, and
actions between objects
and between systems
are performed through what are called,
Remote Procedure Calls.
So, Remote Procedure Calls,
as the name sort of suggests,
are a way of calling
functions on a remote system
as if you were calling them locally.
So this is really easy for the programmer
because it's just like you're calling
a regular function of your code.
The difference is that, that function
is executing on someone else's system,
not your local system.
This is really convenient, but
there's a lot of complexity
that goes into this
process on the backend.
And so, with this concept of
the Distributed Architecture,
usually comes some sort
of concept of ownership
where owning an object usually means
having the authority to
issue RPCs on that object.
And so the way this usually works
is each player has
ownership of their character
and maybe some associated sub
objects like your inventory,
but player A can only
issue RPCs on character A,
it can't issue RPCs on
character B, and vice versa.
Another interesting technical detail
of multiplayer player protocols
is that they're usually
implemented over UDP.
The one major exception
to this are browser games,
where you can't access
operating system socket
so you have to use
something like WebSockets.
But when we're talking
about desktop games,
we're usually talking about protocols
that are implemented over UDP.
And this puts actual requirements
on the protocol itself
because UDP won't do things
like validate that a
packet is part of a session
that you've already authenticated,
or identify when a packet
is either a duplicate or out of order.
So, the protocol gets more complex
because it has to deal with
these types of problems itself.
So now that we've talked a little bit
about how these protocols work,
let's look at our first bug.
And this is an Unreal Engine 4 bug,
and it's actually a file pathing bug.
So Unreal Engine uses its own type of URL,
and it uses this to communicate details
between the server and the client.
So this can be stuff like
the server can send a URL
that says, we're playing on this map,
you need to load these packages.
Or the client could send something saying,
I'm joining the game,
my player name is Jack,
and I'm joining with two other players
who are playing split
screen on the same computer.
And so, one of these URLs
might look something like this.
You start with the IP
address of the server,
then you've got a file path
that corresponds to a particular asset.
And then just like an HTTP URL,
you've got key value pairs
that are separated by an equal sign.
So the bug here is pretty simple.
If you use a malicious URL,
you can cause a server or a client
to access any local file path.
It's not gonna try to write to that file
or even read from that file,
it's just gonna try to
determine if that file exists.
This is pretty boring on its own,
but it gets more interesting
when we start talking about
Universal Naming Convention, or UNC paths.
So UNC paths are special Windows paths
that are used to access
networked resources
as if they were regular files,
so, regular local files.
Typically, a UNC path will
look something like this.
You've got two slashes, then
the host name or IP address,
another slash, then the share name,
then another slash, and
then either the file name
or the full file path.
So using this crafted URL,
or one that looks like it,
we can cause a server or client
to connect to a remote SMB share.
This is pretty simple.
The one trick here is
we do need to include
the part that says .umap,
where umap is a file extension
used by Unreal Engine.
And by having this somewhere
in the domain name,
here we use it as a sub domain,
we can bypass some of the filtration.
And if we provide this URL to a system,
it will cause it to make
an outgoing SMB connection
and try to determine the existence
of this high .TXT file.
And so what this does,
is it opens up the affected system
to the world of SMB-related attacks.
Typically, when a Windows
system connects to an SMB share,
it'll try to authenticate with it.
So this can be used for
Credential Harvesting
or Authentication Relaying.
There's a whole world of
different attacks using this.
This can also be used pretty trivially
as a server Denial of Service
because the whole server will lock up
as it's making this request.
So if you cause that SMB connection
to deliberately take a long time,
you can lock up the server for a while.
So this was fixed in Unreal Engine 4.25.2.
With this commit, it's
really easy to backport this.
So if you're on an older version,
this isn't too hard to apply.
So this is a pretty fun bug,
but let's talk about something
a little bit flashier,
and let's start talking
about our first UNET bug.
So, UNET packets are
packed in such a format
that you can put multiple
RPCs into a single packet.
And that looks a little bit like this.
So the first thing you've
got is the packet header,
which, for our purposes,
we don't really care about,
but then you have each
message within that packet,
and each message consists
of a 16-bit message length,
a 16-bit value, that I
call the message type,
and then the message body,
the actual contents of that message.
And then at the end of that body,
you see you have the next
message just concatenated on.
The bug here, again, is pretty simple.
If we supply a message size
that's larger than the actual
payload of our message,
the actual body of our message,
we can convince the server
to act on extra data
that's already in memory.
So that looks a little
something like this.
If we imagine this is just a regular RPC,
we start with the length,
and then we've got the body,
which is 4-bytes.
But if we were to manipulate that length
without actually increasing
the length of our body,
we will see that all of this other data
that was already in memory,
that's not part of our message,
is now within scope of our RPC.
So, what's interesting about this
is that this old memory actually
comes from previous RPCs.
Not just from ours,
but from other connections,
from other players.
So what we wanna do here
is we wanna create an RPC
that will leak this old memory to us,
kind of like Heartbleed would.
And so to do this,
it's not enough to just
cause the servers to act
on that old memory,
we need to convince the server
to actually send that memory back to us.
And so the type of RPC
that is really good for
this, is Chat messages.
So let's look at what an example
chat RPC might look like.
In this case, again we've got the length,
and then we've got the body of the RPC,
which is just made up of a string length
and then a string body.
But if we just supply that string length
and we don't supply a body,
then all the rest of that memory,
is gonna be treated as
part of that string.
And if that RBC is accepted,
the server is gonna send
back a message that says,
there's a new chat message,
and here's its content.
And those contents will contain
data from previous RPCs.
But even in the absence of chat messages,
there are some other RPCs we can use.
Movement, or spawning a new
object, are both good ones
because they typically involve
giving some form of vector,
some location as an argument.
And we can use this to
leak either 8 or 12-bytes,
depending on whether or not
this vector is 2D or 3D.
If it's a 3D game or a 2D game.
And then there's always
games specific RPCs
that we could potentially use for this.
We just have to get creative.
So, let's talk about what
we can leak with this.
Now, there can be a lot of things,
if you're doing authentication over UNET,
this could be passwords, it
could also be private messages.
It could be game specific stuff
like player locations or player actions,
really anything that gets
sent over UNET by the client
could be leaked this way.
And this was fixed pretty recently
at the end of May, with
UNET version 1.0.6.
So I went kind of quickly
through those first two,
but I really wanted to save
time for these last two bugs,
which I think warrant going into
a little bit more technical depth.
This first one is another
Unreal Engine bug.
And I really liked this bug
because it is a Universal
Speed Hack for Unreal Engine.
So, we talked just briefly about this,
but movement in Unreal Engine
is what we call, server-authoritative.
That means that the client
cannot just say, I'm at XYZ,
instead, the client has
to issue a movement RPC
and ask the server to update
the player's location.
And so this movement RPC has
two important parts to it.
I am oversimplifying this quite a bit,
but I only want to talk about the parts
that are actually relevant to our bug.
So the first argument
is the movement vector,
and this is a vector that says,
the direction that we're moving
and the speed we're moving at.
And the second argument is
a timestamp that just says,
we sent this RPC at this
time, relevant to client time.
And so the actual math here
is that the server will calculate
what's called a Movement Delta
by taking our provided timestamp
and subtracting from it
the last valid timestamp
that we provided to the server.
And then it's going to
take our Movement Vector
and multiply it by our Movement Delta,
to calculate the actual
movement that should be applied.
And so if the server can properly validate
that both the Movement Delta
and the Movement Vector are saying,
there's not a whole lot we can do
to manipulate our movement.
Now we need to make a slight digression
and talk about floating point.
So when I say floating point,
I'm specifically referring to IEEE 754,
and this is how most computer systems
represent rational numbers,
numbers that can be non whole,
such as one, two, three, four, or 12.34,
anything with a period in it.
And so what's interesting
about floating point
is it has some special values.
Floating point can be used
to represent infinity,
either positive or negative.
It also has a special
value called Not-a-Number,
which I choose to verbalize as NaN.
And for completion sake,
I should say that NaN can
be positive or negative,
but it doesn't typically matter.
These special values, usually,
are the result of some undefined
mathematical operation.
So if you do one,
or if you do any non-zero
number divided by zero
in floating point, you get infinite,
either positive or negative.
If you do zero divided by
zero in floating point,
you get NaN.
Similarly, if you do
square root of negative one, you get NaN.
Now, NaN is really the more interesting
of these two special values,
and it has a couple properties
that are really unique.
The first is that any affirmative
comparison against NaN
will evaluate to false.
So we can compare NaN to
zero in any way we want,
it will always be false.
We can do NaN equals equals zero, false.
Is NaN greater than zero, false.
Is NaN less than zero, false.
We can even compare NaN to itself
and it will still be false.
The other thing is that NaN
has a tendency to propagate.
And by that, I mean,
any mathematical operation
where NaN is an operand
will evaluate to NaN.
So, NaN plus one, minus one, times two,
divided by two, these are all NaN.
And no matter how complex
you make this mathematical operation,
if one operand is NaN, the
entire thing will become NaN.
So this brings up the term NaN Poisoning,
which is a condition where
the unique properties of NaN
cause some sort of intended effect.
So let's look at the following code
as a really simple example of this.
So in this case, the
programmer is trying to ensure
that the floating point number
NaN, is between zero and 100.
The problem here is that if num is NaN,
both of these conditions
will evaluate to false
because any affirmative
comparison with NaN
will evaluate to false.
So NaN will pass these validations
and we will end up acting
on NaN in some way,
assuming that it is a legitimate,
regular floating point number
within the range zero and 100.
So, NaN poisoning attacks are pretty rare
because it's typically difficult
to actually introduce
NaN in the first place.
You don't usually have an
opportunity to divide by zero,
or do square root of a negative number,
or anything like that.
These aren't common bugs.
But, when we're doing
remote procedure calls,
we can use any argument
of the correct type.
So if the RPC calls for
a floating point number,
we can give it any floating point number,
including NaN or Infinite.
So going back to our movement RPC.
There's only one argument that
is a floating point number,
and that's the timestamp.
So what happens if our timestamp is NaN?
Well, to figure this out,
we have to look at this
mouthful of a function.
UCharacterMovementComponent::IsClientTimeStampValid.
So this is a lot to look at,
so we're gonna go through it together.
But let's assume that
our timestamp is NaN,
because that is the value
we've provided to our RPC.
So we get to this first check,
which is intended to ensure
that the timestamp is greater than zero.
And because this is an
affirmative comparison,
this will evaluate to false
and we just skip right
past to the next line.
Then we're going to calculate
our Delta Timestamp,
and this is done by subtracting
our provided timestamp
with the last valid timestamp
that was received from our connection.
But in this case, it does not matter
what that last valid timestamp was,
because our provided timestamp is NaN,
and NaN minus anything will always be NaN.
So Delta Timestamp evaluates to NaN.
Then we get to these next two checks.
And the first case, again,
we're gonna pass right by
because timestamp is NaN,
and this is an affirmative comparison.
And for the next check,
Delta Timestamp is also NaN,
this is another affirmative
comparison we pass right by,
and our timestamp is
considered to be "valid."
So, this is all written in such a way
that just by pure luck, NaN
will just pass right through
and be considered valid.
And so the next thing we do
is we generate our Delta Time using NaN.
So our Delta Time is calculated, again,
by subtracting our last valid timestamp
from our provided timestamp.
And because our provided timestamp is NaN,
Delta Time will evaluate to NaN,
regardless of what our
last valid timestamp was.
Now, the server will use our Delta Time
to attempt to apply our movement,
but this is where we've
run into our first issue.
There's one last sanity check here
to ensure that the Delta
Time is greater than zero.
And we will never pass this check
when Delta Time is NaN,
because it's another
affirmative comparison.
So our movement is not applied,
and even though our timestamp
was considered valid,
we don't go anywhere, we don't move.
But we're not quite done yet
because we've caused another
value to be poisoned.
We've caused
ServerData->CurrentClientTimeStamp
to become NaN.
And this is the saved version
of the last valid timestamp.
Because our timestamp
was considered valid,
even though we didn't apply our movement,
NaN was shifted into that current
client timestamp variable.
Now we need to look at that
isClientTimeStampValid function again.
So, we're looking at
the same function again,
but this time we're gonna assume
that our given timestamp is not NaN,
it's not any special number,
it's just a regular floating
point number greater than zero.
So we bypass this first check.
We get to the Delta Timestamp calculation.
And again, we're gonna
do our given timestamp
minus our last valid timestamp,
but this time, our last
valid timestamp is NaN,
so Delta Time is still
going to calculate as NaN.
Then we get to these two comparisons,
which just as before, we're gonna bypass
because server data,
current client timestamp,
and Delta Time are both NaN.
So we pass these checks, and again,
our timestamp is considered valid.
So on this second RPC call,
any time stamp greater than zero
will pass the validity check.
We could say it's 30 years in the future,
it doesn't matter, as long
as it is greater than zero,
and our first RPC call
used NaN as a timestamp,
our second call will always
pass the validation check.
Unfortunately, our Delta Time
is still going to calculate as NaN
because our old client timestamp was NaN.
So still nothing happens,
we haven't moved an inch.
But fortunately, we've
poisoned one more value now.
So while all this is going on,
the server is trying to determine
if our time has drifted from server time.
Essentially, the server wants to make sure
that we're not doing anything tricky,
or that our clock isn't drifting.
And it does this
by independently calculating
its own Delta Time,
and calculating an error rate,
a difference between our Delta Time
and the server's Delta time.
But because our Delta Time is NaN,
our client error is also going to be NaN.
And then this client error
is used to build up our cumulative value,
new time discrepancy.
And this value is used to detect
when we have drifted too
far from server time.
This is used to detect
speed hacking attempts.
It's also used to detect
when a client might just
be lagging too much.
But because our client error is NaN,
when our client error is added,
our NewTimeDiscrepancy
value also becomes NaN.
And because NewTimeDiscrepancy
is what's used to determine
a difference between client
time and server time,
once we've poisoned this value,
we can essentially disable
the server's ability
to detect the time discrepancy
for our connection.
And so when we actually get to the point
when the server would attempt
to detect a time discrepancy
between our time and server time,
this check will never pass
because NewTimeDiscrepancy is NaN.
And more importantly,
no mathematical operation
will ever cause NewTimeDiscrepancy
to become a regular
floating point number again,
it is stuck as NaN.
So, at this point,
because we've neutered
the server's ability
to detect a time discrepancy,
we can now pull off like
an old-school speed hack,
where we just speed up time
in order to move faster than we should.
And what this allows us to do,
is it allows us to move
significantly faster
than our built-in
limitations would ever allow.
So, I've oversimplified
this process a bit.
I know it's still pretty complicated,
but what I've come up with
as not the most efficient,
but the most straightforward
way of exploiting this,
is to just send RPCs in groups of three,
where the first RPC,
the timestamp, is NaN.
The second, the timestamp
is just slightly greater than zero.
And the third, the timestamp is some value
well in the future.
And every time you send this grouping,
it will move you forward some amount.
And because the server cannot
detect a discrepancy anymore,
you can do this as often as you want,
and the only real limitation
is how quickly you can send those RPCs
and have them be processed.
So, saying all that,
let's actually look at this in action.
And I think you can probably imagine
what this is gonna look like,
but I worked hard on it, so humor me.
This is our first demo.
This is built on a stock
Unreal Engine 4 game template.
All I've done with it
is I've enabled all these
speed hacking protections.
I've opened up the game rule just a bit,
so we can run around some more,
and I've modified the client
to actually pull off our attack.
And this is filmed from
the server perspective,
just so that you can see
that this is actually
happening server-side.
It doesn't just look like
we're moving fast client-side.
So in the background,
we've got our hacker,
as you can see, he's vibrating,
he's very excited to be here.
And what we're gonna do
is we're just gonna get out of the way
so we can get a good view of him running.
And in just a second,
we are gonna see him blast off.
And he's gone.
Oka, so that is a little bit
faster movement than intended,
even with the speed
hacking protections on.
I really liked this bug, I
love floating point bugs.
And the great thing about this one
is that it actually does something
other than just being
like a denial of service.
I also think that this type of attack
can apply in other ways.
I've looked at other games
that use floating point in its RPCs,
and you can usually get some
sort of unintended behavior
by using these special
floating point numbers.
It's not always useful,
it doesn't always do anything
for us for an attacker,
but it usually does something.
I should also say that this
does still apply to Unity,
but with UNET, it doesn't
doesn't limit your movement
in the first place,
so you don't have to go through
this complicated process
to speed hack.
So, with that out of the way,
let's talk about our final bug.
We're gonna go back to UNET,
and this is a session hijacking bug.
So, UNET uses a protocol-level process
to authenticate incoming packets,
because UNET is implemented over UDP,
so you don't get the benefits of TCP
where a stream is already authenticated
and you can assume that a packet
is part of a stream that
you've already seen before.
So, packets are not validated
by their source IP address,
or their source port,
or anything like that,
they're only validated by
values within the packet itself.
So knowing this, it is at
least theoretically possible
that someone could hijack
another player session totally remotely,
totally over the internet.
We don't need a man in the middle,
we don't need to be over
LAN or anything like that.
And that's the plan here.
So when UNET validates an incoming packet,
there are three important
values it looks at.
The first is the Host ID,
then the Session ID, and the Packet ID.
And these names don't mean
anything on their own,
so let's look at each one in detail.
So the first of these
values is the Host ID,
and this is a 16-bit integer
that's used to associate a
packet with a given client.
Host IDs are assigned
sequentially starting at one.
So the first client to
connect, gets Host ID one,
the second client gets
Host ID two, et cetera.
Now, Host IDs aren't really
intended to be a secret,
so in a way, we can sort
of just ignore them.
It's also really easy to enumerate
the Host ID of another player.
If we're the second player in a game
and we get Host ID two,
the other player's probably Host ID one.
If we're in a Battle Royale
and we're Host ID 47,
the other Host IDs are
probably one through 46,
and 48 through a hundred.
Things get a little more complicated
when we talk about the next value,
which is the Session ID.
The Session ID is the
primary authenticating secret
of a connection.
And the Session ID is randomly generated
by the client when they connect.
And every packet received for that client
has to have the correct Session ID
or the packet will be discarded.
There are a couple problems
with the Session ID though.
The first is that the Session ID
is also a 16-bit integer,
it also can't be zero.
This means that there's only
65,535 possible Session IDs.
There's also no penalty
for incorrectly guessing a Session ID
other than the fact that our packet
will just be discarded by the server.
So we can easily brute force
the whole range of Session IDs,
even over the open
internet, it doesn't matter,
it doesn't take long at all.
Now, we don't really need to do this part,
but there is one more thing we can do
to narrow down that search even more.
So, Session IDs are generated
with a function named
UNET::GetRandNotZero.
And what this function does
is exactly what the name says.
It gets a random number and ensures
that that random number is not zero.
And this is used for Session IDs
because session IDs cannot be zero.
So, the way this function actually works
is it takes the end
result, that random number,
and it OR's it with one.
It essentially ensures
that the least significant
bit of that output
will always be one.
This has the effect of ensuring
that a legitimate UNET client
will only ever generate an
odd-numbered Session ID.
Technically, a Session ID
can be any 16-bit value other than zero,
but a legitimate client is programmed
to never actually generate
one, unless it's odd.
So this reduces the possible Session IDs
down to 32,768, so 50%.
So if we know the Host ID,
and we can guess the Session
ID, that's all we need
for our spoofed packet to be accepted
within the context of
another player's session.
But there is one more hiccup,
and that's the Packet ID.
The Packet ID is an integer
that's incremented with each
packet sent by the client,
basically a sequence number.
And again, it's 16-bits long.
So what the Packet ID is for
is it's used to detect duplicate
or out of order packets,
because again, UDP
isn't doing this for us.
It's also used to determine
the rate of packet loss.
So if the last Packet ID
received by the server is one,
and the next Packet ID it gets is 1,000,
the server is going to assume
that it's lost 9,998
packets, in the meantime.
So, if we can determine the Host ID
and guess the Session ID,
what can we do with the Packet ID?
I guess a better question might be
what happens if we just
send a random Packet ID?
Well, let's read Unity's
documentation on exactly this.
So according to the documentation,
there are a few conditions.
If the new Packet ID is greater
than the last packet ID plus 512,
we're gonna disconnect the session
because we've lost too many packets.
If the Packet ID is more than 512
behind the current Packet ID,
we're gonna discard it
because it's too old,
we don't want it anymore.
If the Packet ID
is in a list of packets
we've seen recently,
it's a duplicate, let's discard it.
Otherwise, if none of
these conditions are met,
we're gonna accept and
process that packet.
So there are a couple
interesting things about this.
The first is that, if our guest Packet ID
is greater than our last
packet ID, plus 512,
the connection will be disconnected.
And I want to emphasize
that this is not our
connection we're talking about,
this is the other player's connection.
So this is useful because it means
we can pretty trivially kick
other players off the server.
However, it would be
a lot more interesting
if we could bypass this check
and inject a packet that
would be actually executed
within another player's session.
But reading the documentation,
it seems like the odds of
this happening are pretty low.
Yes, Packet ID must be the last Packet ID
plus or minus 512,
which, doing the math,
gives us less than a 7% chance of success.
That's pretty bad.
But when we look at the
actual implementation,
it tells a slightly different story.
So, Packet ID validation
is done by the function
UNET::ReplayProtector::IsPacketReplayed
In practice, this function
actually does not discard packets
that are more than 512 packets old,
like the documentation said.
I spent a lot of time thinking
that I was just misunderstanding,
or that it was more complicated
than I thought, but no,
the logic for discarding old
packets just isn't there.
Instead, old packets are accepted
as if they weren't more
than 512 packets old.
So unfortunately, it's a
little more complicated
than it sounds, we can't just
use Packet ID zero every time,
even though that would
be the lowest Packet ID.
And the reason for that
is that the server has
to account for cases
where the packet ID overflows,
goes from FFFF to zero.
And this happens pretty often
over the course of a game.
So instead of just directly
comparing the numeric value,
the server has to keep like a
rolling window of Packet IDs
to determine if a packet is old or new.
And so doing the math here,
we have what's very close to a 50/50 shot
that our Packet ID will be accepted.
Most of the rest of the time,
our packet is gonna cause the other player
to get kicked out of the game,
which is still pretty useful.
And I say, most of the rest of the time,
because occasionally
we'll guess a Packet ID
that was actually seen recently,
and it'll be seen as a
duplicate and just be discarded.
Okay, so let's look at our second demo.
And for this, I had to use an actual game,
not just something I came up with myself.
And this game is called, Streets of Rogue.
It's very cool, you should buy it.
And I do want to emphasize
that this is not a bug in the game itself,
there's nothing wrong with
how this game is programmed,
this is a bug in UNET.
But even still, what we're
gonna do with this bug
is we're going to inject packets
to cause two other players
to do actions that we tell them to.
So, this little guy in
the red shirt is me,
and these two identical looking people
are our target players.
And what we're gonna do
is we're gonna inject packets,
we're gonna see them do a few things.
First, they're gonna say hi to everyone.
Then we're gonna kill them both.
Then I started to feel a little bit bad,
so we're gonna resurrect them both,
and then we're gonna kill them again.
Okay, so this is a pretty simple demo,
kind of stupid, but it
demonstrates a few things.
The first is that we're
able to inject packets
that are actually accepted
within the context of
another player's session.
The second is that we're able
to do it consistently enough
that we're able to do it for two players
at the exact same time,
even though those two players
have different Host IDs,
different Session IDs, different
Packet IDs, everything.
And finally, we're able to
do it consistently enough
that we're able to inject multiple packets
into each player's session.
We were able to inject a
packet to say something,
pause, inject another packet
to cause them to explode,
pause, and then do this four times,
injecting four different packets.
So this bug is pretty reliable.
And as I said, even if
you lose the coin toss,
all that happens is you kick
another player out of the game,
which has its utilities on its own.
So let's talk about
remediation's for this bug.
This is considered
to be an architectural weakness with UNET.
The actual fixes that would be required
to prevent this entirely,
are not going to happen.
The only mitigation, aside
from moving away from UNET,
is to actually encrypt UNET.
Unity does provide a
reference implementation
that does a decent job of this,
but it's not complete, it
doesn't do key exchange for you.
So to an extent, you are
still on your own with this.
And I have looked a lot, but
I've not found a single game
implementing encryption over UNET.
And I should emphasize
that this is a mitigation,
it is not a fix.
So if your encryption is not complete,
if an attacker can bypass this encryption,
these bugs still exist exactly
the same as they exist now.
Okay, so that was my final bug.
So let's talk about some future work.
I don't think I've found all the bugs,
even in the components
that I have looked at,
but there are a few components
that I haven't looked at at all,
that I think are worth looking at.
So, both of these protocols
have other transport modes.
I think the most interesting
of these are our websockets
because that's what browser
games are gonna be using.
There's also third
party networking plugins
for some of these engines.
Photon and Mirror are two
relatively common ones for Unity,
and there's just other engines.
GameMaker Studio, Godot, stuff like that.
Finally, I want to thank a few people.
Both Epic Games and Unity Technologies,
their security teams were
absolutely fantastic,
super communicative, kept me
up to date the entire time,
put up with a lot of me,
which can be very annoying.
I have nothing but good things
to say about both of them.
I also want to thank the artist
who made the background
art for my presentation.
Grigoreen, he's awesome.
And finally, all the scripts,
everything I've put
together for this work,
I've got up on GitHub.
I've got POCs for most of these issues.
I've got libraries for interfacing
with UNET, and Unreal's protocol.
And I hope that if I
can ask anything of you,
is that you go, you use something
that you've learned here
to go get banned from some video game.