- Good afternoon everyone
and thank you all for coming.
This is abusing peer-to-peer
to hack 3 million cameras.
This talk is the culmination
of about two years of research
so I'm very excited to finally be able
to share this with you all.
And with that, let's get started.
I'm going to be talking about
an obscure feature lurking
in IoT devices around the world.
Peer-to-peer is intended to
make life easier for people,
but it's had the nasty side
effect of exposing millions
of devices to the internet,
even those behind
firewalls are not immune.
Hundreds of different
brands that are affected
by this including security
cameras, alarm systems
and even baby monitors.
But exposure is just
the tip of the iceberg.
When hoards of insecure things
get put on the internet,
you can bet the end result
is not going to be pretty.
So I'm here to show you
just how bad this can get.
By the end of this talk
you'll see how peer-to-peer devices work,
the numerous ways that can be exploited
and finally, how a $40 purchase
from Amazon is all you need
to start hacking into other devices.
So who am I?
My name is Paul Marrapese, I
am a security researcher based
out of San Jose California,
and I probably spend too
much time getting angry at computers.
I largely focus on offensive security
and I work on the Red team
at a certain enterprise cloud company.
When I'm not breaking
things, I make music,
I dabble in photography
and I have two cats who
funny enough are the catalyst
for this entire story.
In 2018, I adopted a
pair of rescue kittens
and I wanted to keep an eye on them
as they slowly took over my apartment.
I had an old IP camera from around 2002,
but this was now 2018
so I figured I could get
something a little better.
Amazon has a wide selection of IP cameras
and some are marked as Amazon's choice
and there's quite a few
with decent enough reviews.
This SV3C model for example is $40
and it has four stars
with nearly 2000 reviews
so it sounds like a pretty good deal.
I figured this would be like
any other network device where
if I wanted to view it externally,
I would need to forward a port.
But once I hooked it up,
I realized I could immediately view it
from my phone, no setup required.
This shook me a little bit
because it implies it's
either doing something
to get around my router
or it's sending my video through
some third party servers.
Either way I'm freaked out
so I load up Wireshark.
And as we can see, this
camera is very chatty,
it's pinging three different
servers every 40 seconds two
of which are in China.
And as I continue
watching, I start noticing
that sometimes my video is being funneled
through mysterious servers
all over the world.
At one point, I even
see this camera talking
to a Comcast IP in a different state.
It turns out a lot of people have noticed
this sketchy behavior.
There are a lot of
concerned reviews talking
about this suspicious
traffic on UDP port 32100.
Not just on my brand of camera
but on many, many different models.
So now I'm extremely intrigued,
what is this exactly?
Well this is peer-to-peer
and I'm sure the name
is conjuring memories
of file sharing networks
like Napster and Kazaa
but the context here is
a little bit different.
In the context of IoT
peer-to-peer is a feature
that lets people connect to their device
from anywhere in the world
without any special setup.
You have to remember some
folks don't even know how
to log into their routers,
nevermind how to forward a port.
So vendors started coming up with ways
to make connecting easier.
To achieve this devices
with peer-to-peer will
automatically work around both NAT
and firewalls so anyone from
the outside can connect in.
But thankfully your device doesn't have
any gaping security holes, right?
So where does this feature come from?
Peer-to-Peer is not typically something
that's developed in-house
by device manufacturers.
There are actually
several different players
in the industry who developed
peer-to-peer solutions
and device makers will get it from them.
So this originates from higher up
in the supply chain, meaning
any faults in it are going
to propagate downward very quickly.
The largest is probably ThroughTek
whose Kalay platform is in use
by over 66 million devices.
If you've got a wise camera
at home, chances are it's
using ThroughTek platform.
This talk will focus on
two products in particular,
CS2 network P2P and
Shenzhen Yunni iLnkP2P.
According to CS2 their product is in use
by over 50 million devices
and iLnkP2P is actually a functionally
identical clone of CS2.
Its market share is relatively smaller,
but it's still present in
over 3.6 million devices.
So with peer-to-peer existing
in over a hundred million devices,
it's obviously a popular feature,
but what are the risks here?
Well primarily peer-to-peer
by its very nature is meant
to expose devices.
And this should be pretty scary given IoT
has a pretty notorious history
when it comes to security,
but convenience always wins
so devices are now punching
through your firewall by design.
In many cases, there's no
way to turn this feature off
and anyone that has your
devices, unique identifier
or UID can easily connect to it.
I'll be demonstrating how
these UIDs aren't exactly all
that hard to come by.
These devices are typically
running Linux under the hood
with everything as route of course.
So when you pair that
with how they're also essentially
online without a firewall,
the insanity of this whole
concept really starts to set in.
Well, there are obvious risks like spying
on someone's camera or
disabling their alarm system,
those pale in comparison
to remote code execution.
Malware leveraging the ability to punch
through firewalls could
really spread like wildfire.
So now we know what peer-to-peer does,
and we've come up with a few ways
that we can potentially have fun with it.
Let's get a bit deeper here
and see what one of these P2P
networks actually looks like.
A peer-to-peer network is
governed by peer-to-peer servers
and these are our gateways
to millions of devices.
These servers are imperative
to this whole system working properly
and the reason for this is
these servers actually
orchestrate everything.
They manage devices,
and they also are what handle
connections between users
and their devices.
You can basically think
of these as command
and control servers.
There are hundreds of
these on the internet
because manufacturers will
have dedicated servers
for their own devices.
It's very common to see these hosted
on a cloud providers like Alibaba and AWS
and they typically
listen on UDP port 32100.
Then of course you have devices
and these could be anything
but the common theme here is
these will be 100% internet accessible.
A very important concept here is
that all of these devices will have a UID
or a unique identifier.
And if someone knows your UID,
they can connect to your device.
So this isn't something
that you really want falling
into the wrong hands.
These UIDs are generated by
the peer-to-peer providers
and burned into the device
during manufacturing
so if someone learns your
UID, this isn't something
you can change.
Let's have a closer look at these.
A UID has three separate parts, a prefix,
a serial number and a check code.
The prefix is basically
used for product grouping
and a single vendor may
have several of these
and their server will only respond
to their own specific prefixes.
The serial is simply the device identifier
and these are effectively
just sequential numbers.
And finally, the check
code is a security feature.
It's used to protect UIDs
and also try to prevent device spoofing.
A peer-to-peer server
will reject any requests
where the check code is not correct.
And finally, there are clients,
a client could be any desktop
or mobile app for connecting
to a device.
It could be for viewing
video, retrieving files
or even configuring an alarm system.
But before a client can do any
of that the user needs to put in their UID
so the client can make the connection.
And under the hood this whole thing runs
on a fairly basic UDP protocol.
There are control messages
for setting up connections
and DRW or device read/write messages
that actually wrap the application data.
Messages are really just C structures
with a 4-byte header
and a signature of this
protocol is its magic number.
The first byte of any
peer-to-peer message we'll begin
with hexadecimal F1.
And thanks to debug information being left
in it was fairly easy
to reverse this protocol
and I was actually able
to create a Wireshark dissector for it.
This was done using a plugin
called Wireshark Generic Dissector,
which lets you quickly write dissector
using a declarative language.
I'll actually be releasing this today
so if you have any devices that use P2P,
you can use this to get
a little more insight
into what's going on.
So with all that, we're
falling at the crux of this,
how does this connection actually happen?
Or more importantly,
how does peer-to-peer punch
a hole through your firewall?
As I mentioned I was able
to access this camera
without forwarding any ports.
The magic trick here
really isn't magic at all.
Peer-to-peer is simply takes advantage
of a particular behavior
present in that in firewalls.
UDP hole punching is a way to
establish direct connections
in the presence of NAT.
For those unfamiliar
with the terminology NAT is just
network address translation,
which is used by routers
to forward traffic
from the internet to the
proper host on the land.
The router does this by
watching outbound packets
and automatically creating inbound rules
to correctly bring the response back in.
The router needs to do
this because if it didn't,
we wouldn't be able to get
responses back from our requests.
But consider if two networks
that are using NAT want
to talk to each other,
any packet sent to the
other is going to be dropped
because no forwarding rules exist.
So how can we get around this?
Well, this is actually
one of the main functions
of the peer-to-peer servers.
Both sides can use a peer-to-peer
server to swap addresses
with each other.
And at that point they can go ahead
and send packets at each other.
This will punch holes
in their respective NATs
and let traffic from the
other side come through.
In summary, just by sending
UDP packets to each other
both sides can create a direct
channel of communication.
So this demonstrates how this works.
When a connection request happens,
the peer-to-peer servers will tell
both sides the other's information.
The device will send a packet
to the client and vice versa.
And even though these may
not actually be delivered,
that doesn't matter the point
here is just to open ports.
After both sides have done this,
then they should be able
to talk to each other.
But the problem with UDP
hole punching is it doesn't
always work, it usually works
with most home networks,
but it might not work in
more complicated enterprise
or mobile networks.
For this situation a client
and device can use what's
called a relay server,
which exists on the network
specifically to help clients
and devices make connections.
As long as both sides can
connect to the same relay,
then it can proxy data between them.
What's really fascinating is
that some networks will
actually use people's devices
as extra relays for the network.
And that means someone else's camera may
very well be proxying your own video feed.
These are called super devices
and this behavior is
kept secret from users.
They are never asked if they are okay
with having their bandwidth donated
and if they have quotas
this could certainly cause a problem.
And as sketchy as this sounds,
this concept isn't actually unheard
of the more standard terminology
for these is supernodes.
And there were relatively
common occurrence
in peer-to-peer software.
Skype actually used to do this too,
but at least people had
the ability to opt out
of that, spoiler alert we're
gonna have fun with these.
Okay so with the background out
of the way now we can start
getting to the really goodstuff.
Since these networks
are supporting millions
of devices, is there anything
we can do to hunt them down?
And specifically, is
there any way we can guess
or generate UIDs.
If we want to do this, the
first step is going to be
to find some peer-to-peer servers.
Again these are essentially gateways
to devices so finding
them has a lot of value.
I started doing this by looking
at desktop and phone apps,
as these are obviously going
to be using a vendor's servers.
However, this is a bit tedious
and there is a much more
efficient way to do it.
We can use an nmaps host
detection to do this.
The protocol has a simple hello message
and any valid peer-to-peer
server will come back
with an ACT message.
So we can configure this probe
and then run it against
the entire IP space
of a cloud provider like AWS or Alibaba.
AWS in particular is very kind
and provides an up-to-date listing
of their current IP ranges.
I've come across 618
peer-to-peer servers since 2018
and some basic fingerprinting has shown
that 86% of these are
CS2 and 14 are iLnkP2P.
So next, if we want to use
these servers to find devices,
we're gonna need to find out
what prefixes they support.
Like before I started
looking for these in apps
and even Amazon reviews,
because sometimes people
will include their UIDs
in their photos without
realizing what they're doing.
These two reviews have 11 different UIDs
and they're using three
different prefixes,
but sifting through these
is also kind of tedious
and quickly provides diminishing returns
so what is a better way?
Well, when we try to connect
to a device the server will respond
with an area code if the UID is invalid,
but that area code will change depending
on if the prefix you asked for is valid.
So I wrote a script to
brute force prefixes,
it continuously sends requests
and saves any prefixes
that appear to be valid.
There's no rate limiting
or checks to prevent this sort of thing.
And depending on the latency between you
and the server, you can find
all three letter prefixes
in about an hour and
all four letter prefixes
in about 36 hours,
in total I have found about
488 distinct prefixes.
And while the average server
hosts about four prefixes,
there are a couple that have 130.
So we're at a point where
we've got servers and we know
which prefixes they support.
We can also predict serial numbers
because they're just sequential numbers.
If we wanna find UIDs the
problem is now the check code,
which exists precisely to
stop this sort of thing.
If the check code is off
by even one letter, the
UID will be rejected.
These are five letters long,
and while that's not
an impossible key space
to brute force, it's still
enough to thwart any efforts
to find a large number of devices quickly.
So how can we get around this?
Well with iLnkP2P luck
would be in our favor.
I found a variant of the iLnkP2P library
that contained the algorithm they use
to generate check codes.
It basically hashes a few
components using our modified MD5
and then puts together the letters
from the hash to create the check code.
This was apparently
included in the library
to do client-side UID validation,
which is odd given the peer-to-peer
server does this anyway,
but someone thought it was
a good idea to ship this.
This is a big deal
because we can now generate
any valid iLnk UID meaning
we can now connect to on
any online iLnk device.
And with this ability,
we can start to do some very
interesting things for one,
we can now find out how
many devices are online,
but what would be even more
interesting is finding out
where these devices are.
We can use a UID to get the IP
address of a device and using
that we can approximate its
location using IP geolocation.
So what you're seeing here is
an enumeration script I wrote,
it generates a UID, grabs
its IP from the servers,
and then it looks it up using
Maxmind GeoLite database,
this is going at 10,000
requests per minute.
Taking this another step further,
I was able to visualize this data
with leaflet marker cluster
and open street map,
of the 3.6 million devices
I've seen Europe makes up
about 21% of this with
France, Italy, Germany,
and the United Kingdom all having
over a hundred thousand devices.
North America makes up
about 8% of this total
with the US seeing over 205,000 devices
and Canada and Mexico both
having over 40,000 each.
Finally Asia is the most heavily impacted
with over 1.8 million devices,
China and Thailand alone
make up more than half
of the entire dataset.
Horrifyingly lots of these
devices use default passwords,
meaning the UID is enough to
gain full access to the camera.
I discloses to Shenzhen
Yunni in early 2019,
but despite multiple attempts,
I never received a
response back from them.
And despite this vulnerability,
I've continued to see an
increase in the use of iLnkP2P.
In fact thousands
of new UIDs come online
every single month.
CS2 doesn't appear to be
affected by this vulnerability,
but that's not the end of the story.
So now I have a way to directly connect
to millions of cameras,
but I'm not really interested
in spying on people
or talking through their cameras.
That's creepy and frankly,
we're not in middle school here.
What we really want is shells.
So let's find some camera vulnerabilities.
When planning for this,
I really wanted to focus on a
big vendor for maximum impact,
Shenzhen Hichip vision technology
is a major manufacturer
in the IP camera industry.
They caught my attention
because as I was looking
into different brands,
I started to realize that a huge number
of them were ultimately
manufactured by Hichip.
In fact, close to 3 million
of the iLnk devices I have
found are using Hichip prefixes.
This sort of practice is very common
where manufacturers will
sell weight labeled equipment
to vendors who then resell
it with their own branding.
This is a list of 50 different brands
that are actually using
Hichip under the hood.
So given their ubiquity
any vulnerabilities
in Hichips firmware
would be both widespread
and very accessible.
So to get started, I began
analyzing their firmware.
One function of interest was
this read request method,
which is used to handle
any commands coming
in over a peer-to-peer,
it even handles login,
and we've got a 1024 byte buffer
to read data off the wire.
The message header has a field
that says how big the payload is
so of course that's validated.
To allow 10 times the size of the buffer.
Okay so we've clearly got
a buffer overflow here,
but how easy is it to exploit this?
Because after all there have been defenses
to stop exploits like this for years
and the library doesn't
seem to use any of them.
So one very reliable Rob gadget letter,
and we've got ourselves a system call
and then a reverse shell
with root privileges.
Obviously any vulnerability is bad,
but the most devastating
really tend to be those
that are pre-auth
because any anonymous
person can explain them.
In this case as long as you
have a UID, you can get a shell,
and we now have all the UIDs.
Once you get a shell, you can run binaries
you can browse the file system
and you can even access
the camera's password.
You can even directly invoke
the cameras wifi utilities
and here's why this is a really bad thing.
You can do a lot of really crazy things
with base station Mac addresses.
Google has an entire API
that uses Mac addresses
to perform disturbingly
accurate geolocation.
And the more information you give it,
the more accurate the
results are going to be.
So once you get a shell,
you can use it to scan
for nearby wifi networks
and potentially pinpoint the
exact location of a camera.
If you want to try this yourself,
check out Google's geolocation API,
feed it some Mac addresses
of nearby wireless networks
and see just how accurate it can get.
It costs literally pennies to do this.
It's hard to say exactly how
many devices are affected
by this vulnerability
but given I found this bug
in almost two years worth of firmware,
I think it's a pretty safe bet to say
that this could be weaponized,
but thankfully Hichip did release a patch
for this in June, 2020.
I did find another
vulnerability worth mentioning.
It's not exploitable over P2P,
but it's still pretty amusing.
Up until recently you could
anonymously reset the password
of any Hichip camera just
by being on the same lan.
The reason for this is apparently
some devices don't have
physical reset switches
so instead you can just send
a magic packet to the camera
and it'll reset the password to admin.
I'll be releasing a script for this,
but I actually found out
Hichip provided a tool
to do this already
so I'm not sure if this
qualifies as an exploit per se,
but have fun with this.
Okay still got a few
more tricks up my sleeve,
let's talk about
man-in-the-middle attacks.
When people hear man-in-the-middle attack,
they might associate it with
something that's restricted
to the local network, sniffing packets
at a coffee shop for example.
Peer-to-peer should be
pretty scary by now,
but we haven't even
talked about how it lets
you intercept traffic over the internet.
This comes from the fact that
as we now know, the peer-to-peer
servers are responsible
for coordinating all connections,
clients and devices obey the orders
of the peer-to-peer servers.
So if we can influence
that process in any way,
we may be able to insert
ourselves into a session.
This is particularly scary
because despite being a transport layer
for the application, peer-to-peer
doesn't actually perform
any encryption or identity checks.
These measures are left
entirely up to the application
and as you can guess, most don't
do a very good job of this.
In fact some even outright lie about it.
This is a screenshot from VistarCam's app,
which assures you that it is
building an encrypted channel,
but as you can see from the
packet capture on the right,
there is absolutely no
encryption happening here.
So how do we get in the middle?
Well, once per minute a device is going
to log into it's peer-to-peer servers.
This action tells the servers
where the client needs to go
when they request a connection.
The problem is this login message
just contains the device UID,
absolutely no device
specific secret is used,
which means if we have
a UID it's very easy
for us to forge this login message
and confuse the servers.
And if our timing is right,
when the client requests a session,
the peer-to-peer server will tell them
that where the device.
And at that point, the
client will happily try
to authenticate to us.
And yes, that is base
64, it's always base 64.
So we have the password
and now we can turn around
and connect back to the real device.
This works with both
CS2 and iLnkP2P devices.
CS2 did try to patch this problem,
but it's pretty easy to circumvent.
The login message is encrypted
with what's called a CRC key,
but a vendor's devices
all use the same CRC key
so you can just grab it
right from the firmware.
And with some servers,
you actually don't even
need to go this far
because it will still let you log
in with the old login message
so there's not much of a point.
All this attack is certainly doable,
there are a couple of drawbacks.
You need to have a specific UID to target,
you need to know
knowledge of the protocol,
and you actually need
to wait for the person
to try to connect.
However, there is another
attack that has none
of these requirements.
In fact, there is a way that someone
with practically zero hacking experience
can start owning handfuls of devices.
Let's talk about super devices again,
these are devices in people's homes
that are proxying
sessions for other users.
A lot of vendors use these
so the chances of you buying a camera
that will act as a super
device is pretty high.
And as I said, P2P doesn't
actually perform any encryption.
So what happens when a
vendor's crypto sucks too?
That means that anyone can buy a device
and access other people's traffic with it.
It means literally anyone
on the planet can sniff
your entire session and
capture your password
or your video without you ever knowing.
There is no need to expend a ton
of effort setting up a
man-in-the-middle attack
when this exists in the product by design.
There are plenty of devices
that don't even use encryption
for sessions, a little
PCAP parsing can give
you a raw video stream
that you can immediately watch
with something like ffplay.
And all the while users will
have no way of knowing whether
their connection is being
intercepted like this.
In fact, it's a risk that
they're taking every single time
that they connect to their device.
As an added bonus, this
has the side effect
of leaking UIDs during the
peer-to-peer handshake.
So alternatively, you can
just take the credentials,
which you also probably captured
and connect back to the device yourself.
I actually developed a proof
of concept of this just
to collect UIDs by
posing as a super device.
And by doing this, I was able to collect
over 236,000 unique CS2 UIDs
over the course of 10 months.
So even though check code
algorithm has yet to be cracked,
this is a very reliable way
for anyone to collect UIDs.
The funny thing is CS2 actually
mention this exact concern
in a marketing deck,
they said a super device can
not spy on any data it relays
because there is no API for this,
but of course that's insane,
you don't need an API to pull this off.
It's absolutely trivial to set up a camera
and then leave Wireshark running
to capture every single packet
flowing through that device.
So that's exactly what we're going to do.
This bullet cam is running iLnkP2P
so against my better judgment,
I'm gonna put this on the internet
and we'll run Wireshark for a while
and see what we come back to.
Okay so I left Wireshark
running for a few hours
and we can see that this
camera has stayed pretty busy.
I have the P2P dissector
active so we can clearly see
what it's been doing.
Each of these hello messages
is the peer-to-peer servers
telling the camera to reach out
and try to help someone with a session.
So this will generate some
handshaking with both the client
and the device.
Of particular interest is
these relay packet messages,
which will actually
contain a UID of the device
that we're trying to relay for.
But we wanna see some
actual session traffic
and we can locate this by filtering
for message DRW messages
so I'll go up here and apply that filter.
And sure enough looks like
we've got some traffic here.
So if we actually pull up the
resulting conversation here,
well thats sure it looks like base 64.
So if we copy that,
(typing)
yup nice secure password there.
So there's some other information
in plain texts over here
we can see some information
about the camera,
the firmware version,
and it looks like some other sort
of name or identity information.
But what about video?
One of the ways that
this DRW concept works is
there are a message indexes
and message channels,
and each channel is gonna be used
for a particular purpose.
So in this case here, it looks
like there's a lot of sort
of authentication or negotiation going on
on this channel zero.
But on this channel two, we
start to see binary data.
So what I did here is I
actually wrote a quick script
that is going to take the
data from this packet capture
and just concatenate it
together so we can pipe it
into a video player.
So what we're gonna do is just go
and export packet dissections
as Json, call this export.Json
and make sure we hit
packet bytes, save this.
And then we will go here and
do node Json2vid export.Json,
pipe that right into ffplay
and we have some chickens.
How about that?
So final thoughts.
I had a feeling things
weren't going to be pretty
when I started down this rabbit hole,
but I never could have
imagined some of these things.
I've reported all of these
problems to the vendors,
Shenzhen Yunni never did get back to me
and the number of devices
using iLnkP2P has steadily
increased since I first
reached out to them.
I've tried to contact a lot of vendors
in China over the past few years,
and it's honestly pretty rare
that I get a response at all.
So I'd also really like to
give credit where it's due here
because both CS2 network and
Hichip kept in close contact
with me earlier this year,
even as the COVID situation
was first emerging in China.
It was refreshing to see
my concerns taken seriously
and especially during
such a difficult time.
the issue is with CS2 were stated
to be fixed in the next release
and Hichip just released patches
for their problems in late June.
With the warm and fuzzies
over boy things are not looking good,
even with patches on the way,
I think it's safe to say
that everything you just saw is going
to be a problem for a long.
And this is because a lot
of these peer-to-peer problems are
outright architectural flaws
and they can't really
be fixed retroactively.
I think even if they could
be fixed, it doesn't matter
because most people don't
update firmware anyway,
I've seen some devices
with firmware versions
going back half a decade.
In June of this year,
I worked with the UK
consumer watchdog group,
which to try to get some
of the effective devices
pulled off of shelves.
Amazon who sells more
than 20 vulnerable brands
didn't respond at all
and eBay said
to use IP cameras without
an internet connection,
which isn't even possible
with a good number of these
so you know thanks for that advice.
I do hope that this was
inspiring to some of you
because I think there's
a lot of opportunity here
for further research.
I think it's pretty clear
that peer-to-peer is a pretty nasty vector
and I'm sure there is a
lot more vulnerabilities
in devices beyond what
I've discovered on my own.
I also haven't really had a chance
to dig into other peer-to-peer platforms
for example Kalay
which is used by over 66 million devices
including wise cameras.
And I know they use a similar paradigm
where a UID will get you device access
so I think there's
certainly opportunity there.
And while I focus my efforts on Hichip,
there are definitely other massive
device manufacturers out there.
In general I encourage folks to climb up
to supply chain a bit if you're
looking for vulnerabilities,
that could be both widespread
and potentially high-impact.
I'd like to leave you with a
few reverse engineering tips
that have led me to
some major discoveries.
First, if you're doing reversing be sure
to collect as many different samples
and variants as you possibly can.
Run diff against them,
look for abnormal changes
in file sizes.
Some may leave in debug
symbols, extra logging
and alternate functionality
so those are all new
avenues of exploration.
Also APKs are a great
way to check out things
with minimal effort.
Java can decompile into
beautiful readable code
that can very quickly
reveal interesting things.
And finally and most importantly,
throw every single interesting file name
or magic string you find into GitHub.
Seriously it is incredible
how many people push sensitive source code
to public repositories
and this has helped me find everything
from SDKs to documentation,
to full on source repos for firmware.
Finally, I'd like to give a shout out
to the folks who published
some of the initial research
on peer-to-peer.
Their work was really inspiring
and key to the success of my own research
so cheers to you guys.
And that's a wrap my friends.
Thank you all so much
for coming happy, hacking
and be safe out there.