- Hello, DEF CON.
Welcome to our talk, DNS section.
Today will be an
interesting talk about DNS
and the workings of the
internet and cryptography.
So what this talk is about,
is about an email privacy breach
in the largest French cloud provider,
which is all sort of first
practical attack on NSEC,
DNSSEC zone walking.
And finally, some cautionary tale
about the use of hash functions.
Why this matters?
Is because DNS is everywhere,
it's part of the internet,
it's heavily used,
it's very important,
and there are tons of
potentially very valuable,
interesting data all over the place.
The other reason why it
matters is that zone walking
has not been demonstrated in
the wild to this extent before,
and this is the first time
that we actually recover very valuable,
interesting data from it.
Who we are?
Well, this is Hadrien.
- Hello.
- And I'm Remi,
We are from Ecole Normale
Superieure PSL university
in Paris, France in the
beautiful place itself.
And this is not the first
time that we talk at DEF CON,
this has been done in collaboration
with Amaury Barral and David Naccache.
So without further ado,
let's start with the
first part of our talk.
So to understand DNS is very important
to understand our talk.
We're gonna start with that.
The basic question that
you ask with DNS is,
who's behind our website?
Such as skytalks-vidz.com for instance.
So DNS, the Domain Name System,
is a system to name remote resources,
to give you access to them,
and it does that by holding
a distributed database,
a system that contains Record
Resources and domain names
and that allows resolvers to
figure out the translation
between a domain name and an IP address.
The DNS tree itself is
subdivided into sub trees
that are called zones
and that are administrated
by different people,
different entities, whose role
it is to keep it up to date.
So when you want to say, build a website,
create a new website.
Well, you actually need to
go through several steps.
Once you have a device
and you have a server
and you have a website running on it,
you need to add your device,
your IP address to a DNS server.
And to do that,
you call registrar and
you run a DNS server
that advertises your IP in connection
to the domain name that
you are interested into,
and you have to maintain
all of this of course.
Most people do not want
to go to such trouble
to get their website running and therefore
they just pay someone
to do the job for them,
including getting all
this working together.
This is the spirit behind cloud hosting,
which does provide the device,
the hosting, the maintenance,
and also the DNS registration
and DNS publication.
And this is the main thing
we are going to talk about.
- Our target today is the OVHcloud,
they are the largest French cloud provider
by far and second in Europe,
and they sell all kind of
cloud related services.
Particularly, to sell domain names,
and a basic plan for domain
names include: email redirects.
Namely, it means you don't
get the full email account,
but you kind of redirect like
contact@yourOVHcloud domain
to your usual Gmail account.
And as a side note, they do
host WikiLeaks since 2010.
So let's create a email redirect
on the example domain here,
dnssection.ovh which we have
just bought for the occasion.
So in the admin panel,
we just add the redirect called
test@dnssection.ovh to target@yopmail.com
and click confirm.
And if we go look at the DNS zone,
which we can also find in the admin panel,
then we realize there is a new DNS
(indistinct) called Intel.
If we zoom of this, then we can see
that for test@dnssection.ovh,
and you have a TXT record
with your target email,
so target@yopmail.com.
So this means that anyone
into wall can just query
test@dnssection.ovh
and get to target of your email redirect.
Obviously it's not easy
to get to a whole database
because you cannot ask the DNS server
solve a whole list of sub
domains of@dnssection.ovh.
- So why does it matter?
Why do we care?
Well, assume for a
moment that we do manage
to find a way to access
this redirection database,
it does contain a lot of
interesting information,
it's actually essentially
client information
for the users of this
cloud hosting service.
It includes emails of
course, but also names
and potentially more information,
billing information for instance,
with which we can be creative,
we can actually start wondering, okay,
what can we do with this information?
Well, we can perhaps spam,
we can try password dumps,
we can perform social
engineering on the basis
of this information,
we can perhaps find
interesting information
on the businesses that
they hold and so forth.
So there's really a lot of ideas
about what we can do with this information
and we will show you that in
the latest part of this talk.
So well, let's try the
naive way, Sudo bruteforce,
to recover all the information using
just a DNS query directly
on the hosts that we're interested in.
So the way we would do that,
is we get lists of OVH-handled domains,
we select those that we
are most interested in,
get the sublist and lists and
we DNS query these domains.
Works rather well for the domains
that are hosted by OVH.
And in doing so,
We have two ways essentially to get
an interesting redirect email,
either we look for the
public email addresses,
the ones that are
displayed on the website,
and we try to see whether
they redirect to something interesting.
This is one way.
The other way is we don't really know
what the real address is
or whether they are
redirects to begin with,
so well, we try addresses,
we think are likely to exist
such as abuse@the domain,
admin@, contact@ the domain.
And in doing so,
if we get a response,
we get not only the existence
of this particular email
address that we just guessed,
but also the corresponding
targets, email redirect,
which does not appear
either on the website
or in that case as well.
Of course, if you just try to do this,
you're gonna run to trouble
because it's very likely
that it is not stealthy
to just query massively random DNS servers
with random email addresses.
So in practice,
if you want to do this,
you better be clever
and avoid rate limiting
by using several clients.
But just for the sake
of demonstrations here,
we cannot do this from a single host.
We using very simple, low tech devices,
including bash and dig
and just the file system.
So really we just run a faster script
that queries the DNS server
to get a lot of interesting
information about the domains,
and then we dig.txt records,
the one that contains
the redirect in our case.
So well, there's demo for that.
Okay, so let's look at this in action.
You have here, the bash
script we just showed you,
and we are going to run
this very script right now.
It will show addresses
we just blurred them
for privacy reasons.
So on the left,
you have the addresses that we query
and we recovered a TXT
records on the right
with the redirection email.
This video is real time,
so it shows you that this is quite fast,
in fact, quite efficient.
And we do this from a single host here,
but of course you can
parallelize these efforts
by calling several
addresses at the same time.
So what do we get?
It does work.
We do get information.
So if we, if we consider a subset
of about 14,000 potentially
vulnerable domains
into a frTLD,
what we get is about
15,000 email redirects
of which about 10,000
unique email addresses,
something we didn't have before.
So this is extremely interesting,
but you might say, well,
we used public emails or
easily guessable emails
and we found private redirection emails.
So well, I mean, it's interesting,
but what are we not seeing?
What are we missing from the picture?
And that's where DNS section
comes into play, really.
So what we are gonna do,
is we are going to use DNSSEC,
DNSSEC is in itself a
very interesting topic
and a very large one.
If we want to go into details,
we might as well do a
talk entirely on the topic
and perhaps even several talks.
So very short summary
What you should know about it is that,
DNS itself is insecure
if you use it like it
just like this, so you need extensions,
which are provided for
most of them by DNSSEC.
Every modern good
implementation of a DNS server
does have support for
DNSSEC and so do Resolvers.
Essentially what DNS does,
is it provides a root of trust
and a tree derivation scheme
that use public-key cryptography,
digital signatures to ensure authenticity.
So you know you you're really talking
to the servers you think
you are talking to,
and that the information provided there
is at least the one that
it commits to sending.
So it requires cryptography elements
and it requires sometimes
some lockpicking skills
as perhaps the recent enough
incident depicted here shows
if you know what I'm talking about.
If not, look into what happens
in a key rollover of a session of DNSSEC.
So we can look at this,
we can look at the information sent to us
by a DNSSEC compatible server.
- One tool that we can
use to recover information
about DNSSEC, is DNSVIZ.
It is available in your
favorite browser @dnsviz.net.
So here, we're apply it to dnssection.ovh,
which is the website we use
for demonstration
proposals during this talk.
It has been slowed down
so I can comment on it.
It is actually much faster than this.
It queries all the interesting information
about the DNS records here,
and we can see the full chain
of trust for the domain.
So in particular,
we can see all the crypto
graphic information,
algorithm in use, and we can also see
some of the common, super code
that appear in the DNS zone.
SOA,
TXT,
MX,
NS
and A records.
You can also see which
algorithm have been used.
In this particular case, dnssection.ovh
users DNSSEC with algorithm 8(RSA/SHA-256)
with NSEC3.
And you can go up to
the OVH and above zones
and see how things are abbreviated
for the (indistinct) trust.
Here, you can see that OVH switching
from algorithm eight to algorithm 13.
one of the 2020 goals for ethnic.
DNSVIZ also checks for
errors Hyatt ondevcon.org.
You will be surprised unless of course,
we're going to have,
watch our talk in advance
and have already fixed it.
Let us dive in a fundamental
obstacle of DNSSEC.
So issue with negative responses.
For positive responses is quite easy,
if you want to authenticate,
is actually record
"example.com is at IP 1.2.3.4",
is exist, sending it's quite easy,
you just affix your signature to it,
but if you want to authenticate,
that's always no record
for bad.example.com.
This is much trickier,
you obviously cannot put every
negative possibility
(indistinct) in the zone.
This is where NSEC comes to the rescue.
NSEC is much more secure and complicated
that what I'm going to explain here,
but all you need to understand
is the principle depicted in this slide.
So basically NSEC signs intervals
where there is no domain.
For example, it could
sign there is no domain
between apple.example.com
and carrot.example.com
in lexicographical order and therefore,
it means that bad.example.com cannot exist
because B is between A and C.
It does create a big issue,
so that you can enumerate
all records in the DNS zone.
How to do that is quite easy,
just pick a random name,
for example, fgfrd.example.com
and query the DNS server for it.
And obviously fgfrd does not exist
it's a random name,
so it will enter as the
interval associated with it
and so here it tells you
that there is nothing
between carrot.example.com
and good.example.com.
So we good.
We have just found two sub
domains of example.com.
We just repeat with the successor of good,
here, good A, get another
name another interval and loop
until we found every
positive record interval.
So it means that it is a trivially doable
for an attacker to get
to the whole DNS zone
of an NSEC enabled domain.
- So now you might be thinking, okay,
that's what we're gonna do,
we're just gonna use NSEC zone walking,
Nope, that's not what we're gonna do
because NSEC'S zone walking doesn't work.
It doesn't work anymore in the real world
for the simple reason that no
one uses NSEC at all anymore.
Yes, you can be sad about this,
is not what we gonna do.
We're gonna do something more clever,
although not very different,
so that's why we talked about it.
What we gonna do is
zone walking with NSEC3.
NSEC3, has been designed and implemented
and deployed for the very reason
of providing resistance
against zone enumeration,
the way we just described for NSEC,
so it's a patch on NSEC.
In a nutshell, what it does,
is instead of having the
records in plain text,
they hash them using several repetition
of the SHA1 algorithm, usually
with salt or without salt.
So the idea is it should hide the contents
of the DNS records
and assuming you cannot do anything
with hash values well,
you don't get access to
them, you cannot enumerate.
Truth is you can still
dump the hash itself,
so you can still do zone walking,
you can still extract the hashes,
it still kind of works,
and NSEC3 is really what is deployed today
in the real world.
So that's what we are going to attack.
- Let me just explain the
assumption behind NSEC3.
Is that, reversing even
partially the hash is difficult
well, practice turns
out, is not (indistinct),
you've probably heard
about many people trying
to break hashes,
especially for passwords
and picking hashes
is even like basically
how you mine Bitcoin.
So I think I hearing a loss
in the Bitcoin mining farm
when to hear that SHA1
cannot be a reformed.
So in practice for DNSSEC,
you can find off the shelf
repeatedly available tools
to crack NSEC3 hashes.
However, to the best of our knowledge,
it has never been used
to dig valuable data.
They only use that for the same demo,
which is finding the list of
some domains of.com or.org,
but most of the time,
the list of valuable domains
is a bit of fun using Google,
or your favorite search engine.
- Okay, so let's show you
the NSEC (indistinct) tool,
which is used to get hashes
from the domain zone.
This is actually a correction of script.
Here we call the script,
collect of (indistinct)
on our dnssection.ovh domain.
It starts by getting the NSEC3 parameters,
which are the salt and the
number of SHA1 iteration.
Then it is going to call
Hyatt and (indistinct) domains
to find the intervals
as we have explained
in the previous slides.
This video has been slowed down a lot,
in practice we have a good network,
this is actually really fast,
you even get a progress bar on the tool.
Here the zone is quite small,
so we get all the hashes very quickly.
If you want to dump a TLD zone, I mean,
top level domain zone.
So charles.org, then it
takes much, much more time.
Another tool, NSEC pre map also exists
and has advanced features
such as parallel queries
and automatic confession for hashcat
and Johnson HIPAA.
Unfortunately it has been
written in Python two,
which is in the process of going extinct,
so use whichever tool you
feel more comfortable with.
- Well, so we have just done
all the versions of dnssection.ovh
What do we do now?
Well, we bring out for GPU rig,
unfortunately we don't
have a holiday center.
We only have a nice day sloppy,
100 if you don't know thing about GPUs,
let's just say, this is not a potato GPU.
So most of you have heard
about a hashcat before this is.
So let us just feed the
output of NSEC3 to hashcat
and try different kind of attacks
such as dictionary attacks
and we toss attacks.
- Here we show you a
little demo of hashcat,
in this case, this is a simple bruteforce
of all lower case alphanumeric emails
of exactly five characters,
as we can see under common line.
First, hashcat displays some information
about the GPU and compiles the open GL
NSEC3 canal tailored for your GPU,
then it start the hash cracking process.
In this case,
we only hung it on a small
subset of our findings.
So video has been speed up
to avoid audience boredom.
You can see a few hashes
being reversed on the screen.
Again, we blurred the
result for privacy reasons.
As a side note, we have
found a bug in hashcat.
Dots were not handled correctly.
Many emails contain dots in the left path
so this proved to be a
serious concern for us.
We made a dirty fix for
ourselves and the hashcat team
has since fixed it properly.
Thanks a lot.
- Let us consider about
16,000 interesting DNSSEC
hashed record.
While using our GPU we
were able to enhance
as much as 88% of them,
so that's quite a good result.
Let's see a little
breakdown of our results.
So in 3/4 of the cases we
were able to reverse the hush
and we did find an
interesting email redirection.
In 14% we did reverse the hash
but it was something else
such as an FBF record,
and in the remaining 12% well,
we were not able to the hush thing.
The remaining one mostly
domain key records,
which are not distinguishable
for email redirection.
A little disclaimer, we are
not here to doxx people,
so obviously, all people
names and domain names
in the following example
have been modified.
Let's look at few statistics.
So first we can just classify
the target for redirection
by the email providers they use.
I think you can guess which email provider
is used by most webmasters and
this is obviously gmail.com.
And then, if you look at
the left part of the email,
it does leak the name
for people quite often,
because well, most emails
are your name@something.your (indistinct).
So it happens that in practice,
the name of a person is, found
is the email in about half time.
However, it doesn't mean that we found
some private information on some website,
where people have been saying
that they do own the website.
So we tried to find out how often,
we could not find the name
in the target redirection
on the website while this
isn't about 2/3 of the time.
So in 2/3 of the time when we have a name
the target of redirect,
then this was not something
we could have easily found on website.
So we have leaked some
private information.
A little more complicated is how often
this email would not
appear in a Google search
and important this is
about half of the time.
So this means that a lot of emails
that are not publicly available
and we did again,
find a lot of private info using zone
Last thing was a little
more difficult to identify,
and this is about business connection,
conflict of interest or fake competitors,
and then, using a redirection we found
while we were able to find such things
in about 1/4 of the cases.
A little homework for you
that we have not tried
is hand by phone emails for
the haveibeenpwned database
and find how many of them
do have an entry in it?
What if we tried to doxx,
scam an adult website?
Well, first please don't
tell my wife about it.
Well, we did try to find some names,
some business connection,
but they are very clever
and it's actually a fail,
say email never disclose user name,
but we still have an email,
so who's the scammer
and who's the scammee?
And you think is most serious,
well, we did find some
famous people emails,
like politicians, and showbiz people,
which are there on Wikipedia page.
We also found a few in email of activists
and on a much lighter note,
we did find a lawyer
website with a redirect
to guess what, my
littlepony.hisbirthdate@gmail.com
And also we found 50 people
who had added redirects
for the noreply@, at our domain.
Why would they do that?
Caveat, this is actually
some manual analysis.
We went for hundreds of website,
fishing for the names and emails,
typically this means going through
the contact page, googling the names,
googling the emails and
dealing with apps and stuff
such as Adobe flash website,
which are like really
difficult to navigate for.
So this is all best effort,
and we might have missed some big data.
- So, okay, we find a lot
of interesting information,
some of it apparently does not
appear either on the website
or in Google and very
likely wise information
that was not meant to be made public.
So we thought it was an interesting issue,
we tried to bring it up to OVHcloud.
So we called the hotline,
and we're gonna tell you
about the disclosure process.
So we called the hotline
and we said, okay,
we think we have a problem
with your handling of private data.
They say, send an email to abuse@.
Okay, so we write the email
and we included technical details
some of which we just
shared with you right now,
and we never got a reply.
So we were a bit puzzled,
perhaps we did not
understand what they meant
by send an email so we called them again
and calling them, again they say, yes,
do send an email to abuse@,
you did the right thing,
just do it again, perhaps they missed it.
So, okay, well,
we write a second to mail
and we never got a reply.
So at that point, what we tried
is to contact people working there,
tried to bring the right person
and to try it and get them to
forward our email internally,
to the right people.
Well to this day, we are
still waiting for response.
So (indistinct) if you are
looking at us, we tried.
Okay, so if you want to fix it,
what should you do?
If you do not want to be targeted
by the kind of enumeration
and privacy disclosure
that we just described?
Turns out that this
has been a goal of NSEC
for many years now,
this was the reason why NSEC3 was proposed
and obviously NSEC3 failed.
But the real, the correct answer to this
is use public-key cryptography.
It's been described in two RFCs,
how to do this with DNSSEC in a way
that's compatible with the NSEC,
and there are two leading
implementations of this idea.
One is NSEC5, which is
already six years old now,
and the other is to use NSEC3
but replace the hash by
a public-key signature,
the digital signature.
The problem is NSEC5
was met with skepticism
in the first draft and the
draft has not been finalized
and it has not been standardized
and it brings latency into the game
but most importantly, NSEC
has a bad track record.
That is already the fifth iteration of it,
and you have not heard of
NSEC2 or NSEC4 in the store
and you might wonder why.
Well, perhaps they never
got to see the light
for good reasons.
The alternative is NSEC3,
NSEC3 with digital signatures.
And today that means ECDSA algorithm 13,
indeed DNSSEC documentation,
mainly because, it is the only one
that can be used in this list
because it signs fast and the signatures
are small enough that it is
actually practical to use,
but it's on the fixed curve
with a fixed hash function,
and it's a bit of an old
logarithm, to be honest,
which makes amongst other issues,
resolvers carry the burden.
The fact that resolvers now have
to perform signature verification,
which is actually quite slow.
It also requires very
careful implementation
and handling of algorithms and keys
because you see ECDSAs famously brittle
and experience in the
matter shows dot DNS servers
are well, historically bad at it.
We gave you a reference on the slides
that you can look into about the handling
of RSA keys in the past.
- Remi has just explained
you how to fix DNSSEC,
but most people do not want
to handle their DNS zone
by themselves and thus use cloud hosting.
So assume for a second that you're
an OVHcloud customer and you are using
the redirection videos.
How can you protect yourself right now?
Well, we have two different
things to protect.
First, the target of
the email redirection,
an easy way to hide
(indistinct) target email
is to use double redirects.
Let me explain, first
redirect test@dnssection.ovh
to test.dnssection@gmail.com
in the OVHcloud admin panel.
Then, in your Gmail interface,
redirect test.dnssection@gmail.com
to your personal email address.
An attacker will only be able to see
the first redirect and thus
will not learn anything useful.
Second, you want to protect
your domain email list,
this is actually quite trickier.
What about disabling DNSSEC entirely
while that is the reason DNSSEC exists,
and the hoping for security properties
of DNSSEC might not be worth it,
or you may also have services
for which DNSSEC use is a must.
Another possibility to protect the list
would be to use long
and unpredictable emails
so the hash is almost
impossible to reverse.
For online website this works quite well
so web server does not care much.
However, a long and
nonhuman friendly email
is not going to make a
good first impression
on your business card.
If your domain email list
is especially sensitive,
the best way out is probably
to stop using vulnerable
OVHcloud redirection for now.
Apply to an OVHcloud plan
with real email addresses.
- So, well, that brings us to
a conclusion for this talk,
which will be rather fast
because you heard most of
what we had to say already.
The lessons remember,
do not store private
information in your DNS zone
if you do not have to,
this is likely to leak unless well,
countermeasures are widely deployed.
DNSSEC, NSEC3 attacks exist,
they are practical and
they can reveal information
that was not obtained in any
other way that we know of.
So try to push you local
representative for a DNS server
to adopt modern counter measures
against zone enumeration,
NSEC5 is not yet final,
try to push for it,
and adoption of ECDSA as a signature
for zone enumeration is also on the way,
but you know, it's taking time.
So try and get that.
That's all we had to say,
and I do have a look as the
proof of concept website
that we put up for you to play with.
Thank you again, have a great
day and try this at home,
very carefully of course.
Bye bye.