- Hello everyone and
welcome to the Talk Spectra,
which is about new wireless
escalation targets.
This is a joint work by
me, Jiska and Francesco,
who has been working a lot with WiFi
while I have been working
with Bluetooth in the past.
And in this work we join our abilities
to build a new attack scheme.
So, the motivation of
this is as simple as this,
I found a partial
Bluetooth RCE a while ago
and then a bit later a
student of mine, Yang build
a Puzzle Frankenstein which
emulates the Bluetooth chips
and he also found a couple of
more Remote Code Executions.
And with this, I said like,
yeah, that's a great chance,
now we can tour the world, tell everyone,
like we have Bluetooth
Remote Code Execution,
take my unicorn, travel with
it and just show everyone.
But, the thing is that
people said they are not too
surprised about Bluetooth
Remote Code Execution because
Bluetooth after 22 years
is really indistinguishable
from magic and they kind of
expected that it is broken.
And then people also told me, you know,
there is Bluetooth RCE, there's WiFi RCE
and WiFi RCE is much cooler because,
first of all, Bluetooth
it's connected via UART
and WiFi is connected with PCI express
that is just nicer for exploitation.
Then also, if you can pop
calc, it's a nice attack but
if you cannot pop calc
then what kind of attack
is a Bluetooth on chip
Remote Code Execution?
So, I was thinking because now
the idea is of course like,
I could try to take the
Bluetooth RCE and then break into
the operating system all the way up.
But, another funny attack
would be to instead attack
the WiFi chip or maybe even the LTE chip.
So, to break the inter
chip separation instead
of doing the same thing
again of breaking into
the operating system.
And then I called Francesco
and said like, hey,
let's build speculative transmission.
And the idea of the attack
was that in a smartphone
you have the same frequency
used by WiFi and Bluetooth
and LTE has harmonics
in the same spectrum.
And they cause interference
in such a small device.
So they need to arbitrate
the channel access
which means they need to actually tell,
I'm sending a packet can
you please not send a packet
right now and so on and
also need to take priorities
and so on.
And this is called a coexistence mechanism
and it's a performance optimization.
And of course, you could now
also instead speculatively
transmit a packet and use
this to infer what the other
cores are doing.
So, this was the initial attack idea.
In the end, it turned out to be a bit more
of a spectrum transmission
but this is the attack scheme.
Of course it requires a lot
of exploitation before so,
it requires the Bluetooth
Remote Code Execution
or WiFi Remote Code Execution
to then escalate into the other chip.
But the interesting part here
is, as this is a connection
directly between the chips,
you cannot block it with
the operating system so, there
is a very nice attack vector
that is hard to prevent.
And if you look into a modern iPhone
this is what it roughly looks like.
So, you have the Bluetooth
and the WiFi chip
which are within the combo
chip but they still run
on different ARM cores,
and they are connected
via Serial Enhanced Coexistence Interface,
this is what we are going to attack.
The combo chip is also
interconnected with an LTE chip
and this is using Mobile
Wireless Standards.
And then you can also see
that the Bluetooth daemon
has fewer rights than the WiFi daemon
and the Bluetooth chip is
usually connected with UART,
the newer iPhones use PCI express here.
And now if you could
escalate between the chips
you have newer attacks
path that become possible.
So for example,
I could now start from
Bluetooth over the air
and then escalate into WiFi
and then go all the way up.
Or I could also try to infer timings
in between those chips and so on.
The Spectra Impact can be
very different depending
on how this coexistence
interface is implemented.
So, first of all, the most
obvious one is the denial
of service, if one core denies
transmission to another core
but it could also be
information disclosure
via timings or pecker types and so on.
And, the first case
would be code execution
and for this one you
really need to screw up
your implementation.
And this attack has been
first on the internet
because of the Black Hat abstract.
Someone start tweeting
and giving it other names.
And I have to say I also
liked the Queer Ghost Attack
but Spectra is like the
original name, of course,
it's harder to find this on
the internet because Spectra
is just a very generic route.
And now let's go for the
Broadcom Coexistence Interface
which we are now going to exploit.
This is also present in
a couple of Cypress chips
because Cypress acquired
parts of Broadcom in 2016.
So, it's synonymous to be used
here so, don't be confused
if I mix up Broadcom and
Cypress, it's all the same.
Actually, Broadcom is a very nice target
because they don't do any firmware checks.
And no firmware checks
means that if we are able
to reverse engineer certain
parts of the firmware then
we can also patch it within
WiFi and within Bluetooth,
and there are no further
checks which means that there
is no secure boot, no
signature checking, et cetera.
So, you still need to
understand what is going on
to patch such a chip but
then there are no further
security measures to prevent this.
And those chips are in
many, many, many devices,
so for example, all iPhones,
all MacBooks, iMacs,
and also the older Apple Watch system,
since the new ones have a different one,
the Samsung Galaxy S series,
the older Google Nexus phones,
all Raspberry Pis, a couple
of IoT devices and so on.
So, this is a very nice
prototyping platform
for all kinds of attacks.
If you look into the older data sheets
you can also find a couple of
details, still not everything,
but the new data sheets just don't exist
so, we need to live with what
is there, what is documented
and what you can see here,
there's this Bluetooth chip,
there is the WiFi chip,
they share an antenna
so, they need to arbitrate
access onto this one.
And then there is a lot
of stuff going on between
those chips which we are going
to attack in the following.
Nonetheless, they have different
ARM cores so, this one has
an ARM Core CM3, there's
ARM Core CR4 and so on.
So, this is still separated in some ways.
For understanding the attacks
now we need to understand
the Serial Enhanced Coexistence Interface
which is used between WiFi and Bluetooth.
It's also called ECI, so
without the serial, and GCI
which might be Global or
Generic Coexistence Interface
but it's all used in the
same way in the data sheets.
To understand it, the best way
is to actually separate
Bluetooth and WiFi.
And in this setup you can
see that there is a Bluetooth
and WiFI board by Cypress.
They don't have a shared antenna
so, everything is separate.
There are no side effects
and the only connection
that they have is the Serial
Enhanced Coexistence Interface,
which we can now also intercept.
So, that means that we are
actually able to observe
each and every signal that is
sent between those two boards.
And there is nothing else that is going on
that could block a transmission.
If you look into this
in detail, first of all,
we did the experiments of streaming
just some music over Bluetooth.
And then on the WiFi chip, we
did a scan for other WiFis.
You can see a peak when you start to scan,
actually it's two peaks.
And then there are a couple of other peaks
when you get the scan results
at the end of the scan.
And what is very interesting
about this protocol
already at this level is
that the Bluetooth and WiFi
are sending with 3MB over
the serial interface.
And 3MB is also the same
amount of data that is sent
from the Bluetooth chip to the host
to send the actual music of the stream.
So you can imagine how
much data there is within
the coexistence interface.
And now you can see that
Bluetooth is within each peak
actually sending some data
that is annotated in X here.
And also WiFi is sending some data.
So, each tiny peak there
really has some information
about the task that is
running and other stuff
that has priorities of packets.
And in the last example, you can also see
a Bluetooth keyboard
which has regular peaks
that is then being sent when WiFi is idle.
So, this is roughly what it looks like
just to give you some
idea about this protocol.
In the first attack, we
didn't even need to understand
all the details of this.
It's just a simple
reconfiguration of this interface.
So, there are a lot, a
lot, a lot of registers
that are mapped into
the Bluetooth ARM core
that you can write into or read from.
And actually, I tried to
understand all of them
in the very beginning and
you can also do fancy stuff
with this but I didn't
understand all of them
and then Francesco just told me, well,
if you don't understand
it, just try breaking it,
just write something
in all those registers
and see what breaks.
And I found out when I write just Fs into
the gci_chipcontrol, this crashes WiFi.
And more interestingly in
this evaluation board setup
I could even see some voltage
drop on the logic analyzer,
this was very weird.
And on some devices this
even causes a kernel panic
because upon writing
to the gci_chipcontrol
within Bluetooth, WiFi might
stop or even spam stuff
over PCI Express and so on
and then there are very
weird effects from this.
I tested it on a couple of devices, so,
starting from the Nexus 5 but
then also going all the way up
to the newest MacBooks
and iPhones and so on,
and the Samsung Galaxy S10, S20.
And what you can see here
is that, first of all,
depending on the date of
the chip you have a slightly
different scheme but on a newest
ones you just write Fs into
one address and already
this is sufficient to have
a kernel panic on lot of those devices.
On some of them it's all
just WiFi that restarts
and that's it.
Now, this already looks very promising
for such a simple attack.
And because of this we try
to build more fancy attacks
with this primitive.
And this is what Francesco is
now going to tell you about.
- [Francesco] Thanks Jiska for introducing
this part of the talk.
Let's start describing
the Broadcom WiFi chipset.
The last two decades it
evolved from a Soft MAC
to a Full MAC implementation.
And functions that were originally running
on the Linux host at that
top are today offloaded
by an intermediate ARM core.
Interestingly, low-level
operations are always managed
by the same piece of hardware,
that did not change much in 17 years.
No matter which WiFi chipset we are using,
time critical operations are managed
by the same D11 microcontroller
that coordinates PHY,
radio frequency and DMA operations.
Let's have a closer look to the low level.
The D11 microcontroller
runs the microcode,
a short piece of software
that keeps checking
hardware conditions and
triggers a specific operations.
We see here some code from the main loop
that checks if the PHY started
receiving a PLCP preamble
or if the current reception is terminated.
In such cases, it will execute
the corresponding handlers
that will decide what to
do with the current frame.
This other piece of code
is extracted from the part
that schedules the transmission
of an acknowledgement.
We see the preparation of
the reply frame that starts
with D4 as usual.
The D11 tool chain was created
by Michael Busch in 2007.
We incorporated it
inside our Nexmon project
and we've periodically updated
it by adding new instructions
when a new chipset is introduced.
As a spot in the ucode in
the ARM binary blob is easy,
we can modify it adding customized parts
as we will see later.
The D11 CPU coordinates many blocks.
First of all, it controls the transmission
and reception engines, it
manages channels access
by scheduling transmissions
and the sites which receive
its frames should be
pushed to the ARM core.
It can configure with
the PHY and the radio,
and it does so by running
the ucode that is loaded into
the ucode memory by the ARM
firmware during initialization.
D11 has access to an 8kB
shared memory where it keeps
its configuration and state variables.
And it also accesses
indirectly the ARM memory
where packets ready for
transmissions are cued
for deciding which packets can
be transmitted or aggregated.
D11 is equipped with
general power post timers
and with many different
interfaces for talking
to other parts of the chipset
like the SECI interface.
During the years, it turned
out to be a pretty flexible
architecture and we use
it as a research platform
for showcasing operations like
jamming, piggyback in schemes
and time of flight measurements.
Let's now talk about D11
Coexistence Interface.
It includes quite a number of
registers and a 64-bit buffer
for receiving messages from the Bluetooth.
Such messages are transmitted
by Bluetooth every 1.25ms.
It is the minimum Bluetooth
connection interval.
They report to WiFi the timing
and type of all Bluetooth operations.
WiFi copies this information
inside dedicated SECI
count down timer that
differ WiFi operations
and prevent collisions.
On the opposite direction
WiFi uses the Bluetooth
transmission control register, in red,
for granting Bluetooth
access to the chart.
The flow of messages in
the two directions builds
a grant reject scheme.
As we will see in our
attacks, we use the knowledge
we collected on such registers
for breaking such scheme.
According to our analysis,
more than 10% of the ucode
is dedicated to coexistence.
As in general, many other
operations take much less code,
we understand how much complex
is the Coexistence Interface.
Finally, by programming
two boards for transmitting
SECI messages when receiving
the same WiFi beacon,
we measure it with the
help of an external FPGA,
the jitter of the SECI line.
It turned out to be caution
with a 200ns deviation
which is perfect for this application.
So, let's see how we broke
the Grant/Reject Scheme.
We did that to see the
effects when watching a movie
that requires to download
content over the WiFi
and send audio to a Bluetooth headset.
At the bottom, in green,
we see SECI grant messages
transmitted by the WiFi.
Bluetooth uses them for
understanding when it can transmit
audio to the headset.
We introduce into the ucode
a few lines for configuring
the WiFi chipset remotely
from the air interface.
We can hence prevent the
WiFi from sending SECI
grant messages to Bluetooth.
You see this happens
between 2.6s and 3.5s.
During this interval, no more
SECI messages are transmitted.
And in fact, we cannot hear
any sound from the headset.
We tested this both on Nexus
5 and on on-development boards
from Cypress.
This experiment clearly demonstrates that
a denial-of-service
attack from the WiFi side
against Bluetooth is possible.
Let's take a closer look now
at the messages that Bluetooth
sends to WiFi and if we
can use such information
for an attack.
These are the SECI time
diagrams when we have a keyboard
connected over Bluetooth.
Depending on the keyboard,
we can observe SECI messages
transmitted every 15ms or 30ms.
Bluetooth sends these SECI
messages to inform WiFi
that it is going to poll
the keyboard so that
the WiFi defers channel access meanwhile.
In this diagram, WiFi is idle
so, WiFi always grants
access to Bluetooth.
This is what happens when
somebody is actually typing
on a keyboard.
At the bottom, we have
the periodic sequence
of SECI messages, on top we
have the key presses sniffed
by Wireshark when capturing
from the Bluetooth interface.
As we are typing with
moderate speed each key press
is separate from the
others and we can also see
the Bluetooth message with key release
following each key press.
In between, we can see the
HID data captured by Wireshark
with a specific event ID
that represents a key press.
Below we see SECI
messages that we filtered
on the WiFi chipset by
selecting the same message type.
This demonstrates that at
the WiFi side we can easily
distinguish SECI messages
relating to key presses.
This clearly demonstrates
that having access
to the WiFi chipset that is
enough for measuring key press
timings with very accurate resolution.
And we know that in some
cases with the help of some
artificial intelligence or
classification technique,
this is enough for guessing
what the user is typing.
We hence believe that without
any part further protection,
the SECI interface can be used
for mounting side channel attacks.
And we request the CVE
for reporting the
associated vulnerability.
Jiska, the ground is yours again.
- Thank you Francesco for the
very detailed explanations
about the Serial Enhanced
Coexistence Interface
and attacks on it.
There is still one thing
mentioned in the data sheet
which was clearly missing
which is the WLAN RAM sharing.
And in following, we are
also going to attack this.
I would call this effect
when you spend too much time
looking for very fancy side
channels and dig deeper
into all of this and try to explore them
while there is the one
obvious thing in a data sheet
that you just couldn't find within
the Serial Enhanced Coexistence Interface.
And for us this was the
WLAN RAM sharing so,
it must be some variance
in the data sheet arrows
just go into one direction
here from Bluetooth to WiFi.
And we just didn't understand where it is
and couldn't find it
for quite a long time.
And the reason for this
is that the Cypress boards
come with some development
kit and within this there are
some symbol leaks but the
problem here is there's nothing
mentioned with WLAN.
And so, there probably is no
WLAN RAM sharing I thought,
maybe it's just another route
for the enhanced coexistence
mappings but then there was
also another part of symbols
and I was able to obtain a RAM image.
And it's not from a development
board but actually from
a MacBook and within those
symbols there suddenly were
a few called WLAN buff something.
So, it looked a bit like
probably the shared RAM.
But it routes just functions
and then I analyze those
functions and there was one
function that was polling
somewhere in the 0x680000 region.
And actually, when I saw
this then I tried to read it,
it sometimes crashes if you
don't do it in the right order
and so on but in the
beginning of the section,
I actually saw, wow, there is
a string 0x80211-something,
on the device where I did this.
And then I was like, probably
I'm already in there.
Still to confirm it, I
instead tried writing to it.
And when I write to this, what
happens is that quite often
the WiFi crashes.
So within Bluetooth, I
write into those registers
and suddenly WiFi crashes.
And the nice part about a
WiFi crash is that on a couple
of devices, this is causing a
crash dump and this crash dump
actually contains parts of the RAM image.
So, I could write data that I
know and try to find the same
data again to make the
mapping and find how WiFi
and Bluetooth are mapped into each other.
And also it revealed a
couple of function pointers.
So, within the function pointer
table I was just overwriting
a couple of pointers
and it turned out that
if you're in this position
there is a pointer table
and when I write to this I
can get the program counter
under control so, I can write
to RAM, I can set the program
RAM too so, I can have code execution
and that was really amazing.
I have a demo video for this on a MacBook.
The mapping is slightly different
so, on the left hand side
I use internal blue to
write assembly instructions
because I'm just writing within a function
and not within a function pointer.
And then on the right hand side,
you see the WiFi crash logs
on macOS and you can see that
I can get a program counter
under control.
And this is how fast this attack works so,
just within Bluetooth I can
get code execution in WiFi.
The interesting part here is
that I couldn't find this area
on a Nexus 5 so, either
it's not mapped at all
or it's mapped to a different region.
Even though this was the
one that I initially had
as the idea like, from this
data sheet there must be this
WiFi RAM sharing but so
this one, I didn't find it.
Then there are a couple
of devices where within
the RAM dump you can even
find a 0x680000 and so on.
So, you know that in the
firmware this is used
and on those also the attack works.
The fun part here is that the MacBook,
I don't have it with me,
I just have the this dump
so, I couldn't try it on
my own on this MacBook but
at least I know it should work
because the symbol is there.
And in the newest devices,
this register is never ever
mentioned in the firmware
but still the attack works.
So, it's probably a feature
that has been abandoned
and it's not longer used
but still we can use it
for this type of attack
on all those devices.
The even more fun part is
that sometimes I got, again,
issues with PCI express, so why is that?
On all those chips I had
no idea of what exactly
I was doing so, I mean,
yes, there is the mapping
but I first of all need
to get the chip to crash,
to get this RAM image and then
I need to load it into IDA
and analyze it and somehow
find a place to get
code execution for each chip.
And so I was just writing
certain things and then again,
like sometimes finding a pattern again
and when I find the pattern
like in the program counter
then I probably have code execution.
So, this was roughly my approach.
And then on a couple of devices
this turned out to be a very
efficient puzzle so, just
flipping a couple of bytes
somewhere in the shared memory
between WiFi and Bluetooth
was sufficient to get kernel
panics on a couple of devices.
So, sometimes just perfect crashes
but sometimes even kernel panics.
And this is interesting
because there are, of course,
also some memory areas that
are used for the PCI Express
queue between the WiFi
chip and the host and so on
or it might just simply
block something within
the communication, between
the WiFi chip and the host.
And depending on this, it
can already cause a reboot.
So, with the super sympathizer
of just flipping some bytes
or sending some bytes,
you can reboot devices.
And this is a capture of this.
I just use an iPhone 6 because
on this one, it's very fast.
It also works on a
couple of other devices.
And you can see first of
all, WiFi is switched off.
So, that's on the left hand side and then
the device is already rebooting.
Now you might wonder what
the patch looks like.
And I mean a lot of
this is in hardware so,
you cannot really patch it.
But what I have seen in a
couple of devices is that
they are now blocking the communication.
So, after the Bluetooth
chip is initialized
by the Bluetooth daemon,
the Bluetooth chip is then
blocking any read RAM commands
or at least writing, the
reading is only blocked
on a few devices but writing
is blocked on all newer
chips as far as I've seen.
And now the thing is that
this prevents at least attacks
where the Bluetooth daemon
would try to get code execution
within WiFi so, that's like
this path but what is not
prevented by this is if you
have remote code execution
over the air and then escalate into WiFi
or if you just know that
the timing between the WiFi
and Bluetooth is a fixed
one by now and use the known
timing which is not random
because of some things
sent over the air but
actually like predictable
because of coexistence schemes.
This might also be a thing
that's exploitable here.
But at least they added
this to the attack model
that suddenly Bluetooth
might be able to attack WiFi.
And because of this,
this part is now blocked
because you can block this quite easily.
And now, I mentioned in the
beginning that this might
also apply to other chips.
And now the question here
is like, what are the chips?
If you look into the
Bluetooth specification
and read it backwards because, I mean,
I'm a Reverse Engineer so I
also read the specifications
backwards obviously, what
you can see on the last page
is the Bluetooth logo and
on the second last page
it already starts with the
mobile wireless standards.
I guess it's another serial protocol
which is used between
WiFi and Bluetooth chips
or Bluetooth chips and LTE.
And they are also sending
activity information
and so on over UART.
And then there is another
thing that goes via
the operating system to
initially configure it.
And this one is also used on iPhones.
So, I saw it on an iPhone
so probably is also tech
that belong to them.
And because everyone has some
proprietary coexistence features,
we asked Broadcom if we can
also include other manufacturers
in the responsible disclosure process.
And they said, yes we can.
And so we informed a couple of
those who at least mentioned
that they have coexistence in
their data sheets and so on.
And some of their responses
were like, that this doesn't
really apply to them because
there are some chips that have
just one core that handles
multiple wireless protocols.
So by definition, that
wouldn't be a attackable
in the sense of, you already
have code execution either way.
So, a Bluetooth Remote Code
Execution is automatically
a WiFi a Remote Code Execution
but of course there might
be other sections like,
I can now from the timing
of WiFi frames that I send
on an upload
maybe predict how the typing
on a keyboard or something was
for example or how the
activity was on the other
via this core.
And this might be something
that could still be possible
even though the code
execution is kind of by design
that cannot be prevented,
there might be further attacks.
And as a summary, so, what we reached is,
if you have a Bluetooth
remote code execution
on a Broadcom chip, you can
now cause driver kernel panics
get information disclosure about WiFi
and even code execution within WiFi.
And the other way round if you have
a WiFi Remote Code
Execution you can now do
denial-of-service against
Bluetooth and also get information
disclosure within Bluetooth.
If you have further questions
there will be a Q&A session.
And you can of course,
also reach me on Twitter
or you can write an email
to Francesco and me.
Thanks for listening.