- Hello, everyone and welcome
to Domain Fronting is Dead,
Long Live Domain Fronting,
using TLS 1.3 to evade sensors,
bypass network defenses,
and blend in with the noise.
My name is Erik Hunstad
and I'm the CTO and adversary
emulation lead at SixGen,
a full spectrum cyber security company
based in Annapolis, Maryland.
Today, I'm gonna go over
what domain fronting is,
including HTTP and HTTPS basics.
I'll talk about TLS 1.3 and
encrypted server name indication
and how this can be
used for domain hiding.
I'll show some demos of this
in action from basic bypasses
to bypassing the enterprise
TLS decrypting firewall.
And finally, I'll talk about
some ideas for defenders
who may want to detect
this in their environment.
Domain Fronting 101.
If we're gonna discuss a new
method for domain fronting,
let's all get up to speed
on what domain fronting is,
why it works, and what happened to it.
Like many things in security,
to understand the cool stuff,
you have to dig into the basics.
To understand domain fronting,
we really need to
understand HTTP and HTTPS.
Specifically, we'll be focused
on the server name indication,
which is a special extension
added to TLS that allows multiple sites
to be hosted on the same server.
For TLS 1.3, this
extension can be encrypted
and combined with encrypted secure DNS.
We can do domain fronting
2.0 or domain hiding.
Okay, let's start with HTTP.
I'll skip over the super low level stuff
as it's not relevant here.
The first external request
involved in an HTTP connection
is a DNS request.
This DNS request gets sent
out un-encrypted via UDP
to port 53.
The DNS server responds
also unencrypted via UDP,
with an answer that
contains the IP address
of the domain from the request.
Now that the user's computer knows
where the domain is hosted,
it can issue an HTTP
request to that IP address
with the host header indicating
the domain the user wishes to browse.
This request uses TCP,
but it's un-encrypted.
The web server responds with content.
In this case, some simple HTML.
This was fine for the
early days of the internet
when it was just a few
research institutions.
But as soon as people wanted
to conduct business online,
the obvious issues with
completely un-encrypted traffic
had to be fixed.
Plus, without encryption,
all your data is free game
for any number of actors
that are positioned
between you and the web server.
HTTPS was the answer to this problem,
and it starts off the same
way with the DNS request.
The DNS request and response
are still un-encrypted
when using HTTPS, unless
you use a different system,
which we'll talk about later on.
Here's why HTTPS is different.
The connection to the server
starts with a TLS connection,
specifically, a ClientHello.
In this packet, the server
name extension is used to tell
the web server which website
the user's requesting.
This allows the web server to
return the proper certificate
for that site.
The server returns the certificate
and a ServerHello packet.
And then the client and server
can agree on which
encryption algorithms to use
and exchange session keys.
All traffic after this is encrypted,
but both the ClientHello and
ServerHello are un-encrypted,
which leaks to the domain and certificate
to anyone between the
client and the web server.
And we know there are
plenty of organizations
interested in that data.
With the basics covered, let's
talk about domain fronting.
Domain fronting as a technique
to get around network defenses or sensors
by connecting to an approved server
while hiding the true
destination of the HTTPS request.
One of the biggest
restrictions of domain fronting
is that the fronted domain and
the true destination domain
must be hosted by the
same service provider.
Typically, this is a
content delivery network.
So how does domain
fronting work in practice?
Well, it starts with the
same DNS lookup as before.
And the TLS handshake is the same as well.
However, in the handshake,
the client connects
to the front domain, not
the true destination domain.
Once the TLS handshake is
complete with the front domain,
the fronting begins.
The client sends an HTTP
request to the front domain
wrapped in TLS, but with a Host header
of the true destination domain.
When the content delivery
provider receives this request
and inspects the Host header,
determines that it's
for a different domain
hosted on the same provider
and dutifully forwards the request
to the true destination domain.
You can think of domain
fronting like a postcard
inside an envelope.
On the outside of the envelope,
the client writes the address
of the CDN, but on the inside,
the true destination
domain is on the postcard.
The network filters or
sensors are like mailman
who can see the outside of the envelope
and they deliver it since the
CDN is an approved address.
However, when the CDN opens the letter,
they deliver the postcard
to the true destination internally.
This was working well on all
major CDNs until April of 2018
when the Russian government
put pressure on cloud providers
to stop it, since the popular
messaging app, Telegram,
was using both Google and
AWS for domain fronting.
Both Google and Amazon
stated that the reasons were technical
and domain fronting was
either never supported
or a violation of terms of service,
and other providers follow
suit to include Cloudflare.
Microsoft's Azure platform
still allows domain fronting
for now as do a few other smaller CDNs.
Domain fronting is a great censorship
or network bypass technique,
but it has some major problems.
For any network censorship
bypass to be effective,
it has to be really painful to block.
And since the largest
provider shut it down,
it lacks the punch that it once had.
Also, the true destination domain
has to be hosted on the same
service as the front domain,
which limits the potential front sites
and imposes costs on anyone
wishing to set up fronting.
With the background out of the way,
we can talk about TLS 1.3,
encrypted server name indication,
and what can we call domain hiding.
First, let's talk about TLS 1.3.
It's seeing steady growth
on the internet today.
This is data from Qualys SSL labs,
which test the most popular 150,000 sites.
As you can see, TLS 1.3 is on the rise
and it's supported by 31.7% of those sites
tested last month.
Cloudflare is seeing 59% of
all traffic using TLS 1.3,
again, showing a steady increase.
Before we dig into the
mechanics of a TLS 1.3 handshake
with ESNI, we first have
to secure the DNS process.
If a network defender or sensor
can see our DNS requests,
they can easily be blocked.
Also, secure DNS is a cornerstone of ESNI,
which we'll see in a moment.
The first solution is
to simply wrap DNS query
in a TLS connection.
To make things even more
difficult for network defenders
or sensors, DNS via
HTTPS is a newer standard
that is seeing more widespread adoption.
Once we have an encrypted
way to perform DNS queries,
we can use this to retrieve
a public key for domain,
which we can use to
encrypt the server name
in the ClientHello packet.
In this screenshot from Wireshark,
you can see the
encrypted_server_name, TLS extension,
and the encrypted SNI value,
this is just an encrypted hex string,
no longer can defenders
use the server name value
to block traffic based
on a plain text value.
A TLS. 1.3 connection with ESNI
relies on having the server's public key
in order to encrypt the server
name in the ClientHello.
And the current standard
for how to get this key
is to use DNS and query
the _esni text record
for that domain.
This request returns a
base64 encoded public key.
The client can use to derive a session key
that encrypts the server name.
Providers that support
this should rotate this key
to provide some forward secrecy.
Cloudflare, for example,
rotates this key every hour,
but allows a few hours of buffer
in case a client has a slightly stale key
from a previous request or from caching.
Armed with the server's ESNI public key,
the client drives a
session key and uses that
to encrypt the server name
and sends the ClientHello.
The server has the
corresponding private key
and can drive the same session key,
which it uses to decrypt the server name
and performs the same
steps as standard TLS.
The session key generation
ensures that the key
is tied to the session that generated it
and prevents replay attacks.
Another difference between
TLS 1.3 and previous versions
is that the certificate returned
by the server is encrypted.
This is possible because in TLS 1.3,
the ClientHello includes a
list of supported ciphers.
And the client also makes a guess
as to which key agreement algorithm
the server's gonna choose.
And it preemptively sends a
key share for that algorithm.
So all the plaintext portions
of HTTPS we saw before
have been mitigated.
However, there's still weak spots
where sensors or network defenders
could stop the connection.
Even if the DNS request
itself is encrypted inside
either TLS or HTTPS,
the data returned by a
resolver may be poisoned.
Imagine a scenario where
a country or enterprise
returns their own key
for all _esni requests,
no matter the domain, to
enable man-in-the-middle.
DNSSEC solves this problem
by signing the record set
and allowing the chain
of trust to be checked.
The details of DNSSEC are
outside the scope of this talk,
but I encourage you to check it out.
But what if encrypted DNS
is completely blocked?
The solution here is to
bootstrap the connection
by pre-loading the current
ESNI keys by some other means.
Maybe encrypted DNS is blocked,
but what if I have a script
that updates a GitHub gist
with the current keys every hour?
Or you could just bake the
keys directly into your binary
if you know what's gonna be executed
in the next hour or two.
Okay, let's say we get a valid ESNI key,
but the IP address
of the server we wanna
connect to is blocked.
The IP may be shared with other sites,
but it doesn't have to be.
Is there a way to route from
arbitrary domains and IPs
to our true destination domain and IP?
The answer is no, but let's
see how close we can get.
So far, I haven't introduced anything new,
but we have covered a lot of ground
and identified potential
issues and solutions
around domain hiding
with TLS 1.3 and ESNI.
Let's tackle that last
point and get around IP
or domain blocks.
We'll do this by leveraging
the world's largest CDN.
Cloudflare was founded in 2009
and has had explosive growth.
It's now the world's largest CDN,
with the most internet exchange points
as well as being an
authoritative DNS server
hosting over 26 million domains.
Cloudflare is on the forefront
of internet technology
and supports TLS 1.3, ESNI,
Websockets, QUIC and DNSSEC.
This new technique, which
I'm calling domain hiding,
accomplishes the same
goals as domain fronting,
but uses different technologies.
A TLS 1.3 connection with an
ESNI of the true destination
is made to any Cloudflare IP
and the underlying HTTP request
also has a host header
of the true destination.
This enables any Cloudflare
owned IP to act as a front
for any domain hosted by Cloudflare DNS.
This technique was first shown
to be possible by Robin Wood.
So props to him for the discovery.
Today, I'm releasing noctilucent,
a project that enables ESNI
and goes crypto/tls library,
as well as exposes two
additional configuration options,
ESNIServerName and PreserveSNI.
It can be used by any project currently
using the standard crypto/tls library,
as it's backwards compatible.
It comes with a demo client
application that allows you
to control just about every
part of the TLS connection,
as well as the HTTP GET request.
So you can play with what's
possible using this technique.
It also supports Websockets
and through the magic of Go,
it compiles cross-platform
to a single binary
with no dependencies.
Here's what a standard TLS 1.3 connection
looks like with noctilucent.
We've specified the TLS host in red,
the server name indication in yellow,
and the HTTP Host header in green.
The output shows what we expect.
There's no ESNI, the SNI
is set to cloudflare.com.
We're connecting to
cloudflare.com on port 443.
And our GET request to cloudflare.com
returns the expected 301
response, nothing fancy yet.
Let's enable ESNI and
set the ESNI server name,
everything is the same as the
normal TLS. 1.3 connection
we looked at on the last slide,
except this time the ESNI
value is set to cloudflare.com
and there is no standard SNI.
Progress, but no fronting
or domain hiding quite yet.
Now I'll change this, the ESNI server name
and HTTP host header
to a domain we control.
In this case, defcon28.hackthis.computer
But leave the TLS host as cloudflare.com.
Notice that this connection
is still going to cloudflare.com,
but the HTTP request
successfully goes to
defcon28.hackthis.computer,
which returns Hello DEF CON!
To anyone between this
host and Cloudflare,
it appears to be a TLS
connection to cloudflare.com.
We've successfully achieved domain hiding.
Now the fun begins.
Here we send an ESNI and standard SNI
where the standard SNI is cloudflare.com.
Because Cloudflare
ignores the standard SNI
when an encrypted SNI is used,
we can set it to anything.
The HTTP connection works as before.
And this time, anyone between
this host and Cloudflare
looking at SNI data thinks
that this connection
is going to cloudflare.com.
In addition to the
underlying TLS connection
actually connecting to
a cloudflare.com IP.
What I've demonstrated is the ability
to arbitrarily front or hide any IP
behind a domain that is using
DNS provided by Cloudflare.
The true destination IP doesn't have
to be a Cloudflare worker
or other Cloudflare service.
In fact, all the examples today are IPs
hosted by DigitalOcean.
Best of all, the requirements
to sign up for Cloudflare DNS
are minimal and it's free.
What domains can we use for this hiding?
It turns out a lot, over
21% of the top 100,000 sites
are behind Cloudflare
and allow this to work.
Some notable examples are shown below,
including three of 11 domains,
which are both on the Palo
Alto decryption white list
and behind Cloudflare.
I'll demonstrate why this
is important in a minute.
There's a little bit of
everything on this list
from security related
sites, banks, sports,
higher education, streaming services,
and even government sites
and porn, so much porn.
Here's a good example of how the variety
of available domains to
hide behind can be useful.
This is a request to www.okta.com.
A single sign on and identity provider
used by many enterprises,
but the actual request is
going to a server I control.
To a sensor or network defender,
this looks standard Okta traffic
with the exception of the
ESNI extension being used.
The logical next step is
to try out noctilucent
with some web filtering
and see how it fares.
It turns out most web filtering
is done by inspecting the SNI,
and making a filtering
decision based on that.
Here, I set up the untangled firewall
with Federal Government settings
and explicitly blocked
defcon28.hackthis.computer.
On a host behind the Untangle Firewall,
I made this request, which succeeded.
I set the un-encrypted
SNI to bypass-untangle.com
to see if it appears in the logs anywhere.
After repeating the
requests 30 times or so,
back on the firewall, we
can see that the top domains
include the decoy domain that
we sent with the request.
Simple SNI filters were easy to defeat.
What about HTTPS decrypting firewalls?
These are often seen in
enterprise environments
and work by breaking and
then re-encrypting HTTPS
using a root certificate
placed on endpoints
behind the firewall.
You can think of it as a
corporate man-in-the-middle
that allows the network defenders
to inspect full encrypted packet data.
Kazakhstan actually attempted
to implement this nationwide
for a few weeks back in July of 2019,
before a major international
backlash forced them to abandon
what they called a "test".
I headed to AWS and spun
up the latest and greatest
in enterprise firewalls, a
Palo Alto PA-VM version 10.0.0.
Released in June, this
version touts the ability
to decrypt TLS 1.3 with
a two times speed boost.
Imagine my surprise when it was all set up
and the default decryption
profile didn't include TLS 1.3.
Instead, it let it pass through
while logging an error
about a version mismatch.
Once set up with a decryption profile
that enabled decryption of TLS. 1.3,
I pulled the list of default domains
that are allowed to bypass decryption
for variety of reasons,
such as having a pin certificate.
Here, the firewall interfaces on the left
and a Windows VM behind the
firewall is on the right.
We can see that decryption is enabled
and we have no other decryption rules
that would allow traffic
to bypass decryption.
Normally, in an enterprise environment,
categories like banking or healthcare
bypass decryption due to privacy laws.
But this setup is as strict as possible.
No explicit exemptions.
On the Windows VM, I'll
run a PowerShell script
that checks the certificate
hashes of major sites
against hard-coded known fingerprints.
We see that it fails indicating
that all tested sites
are being man-in-the-middled.
Additionally, opening a
browser and going to google.com
shows a lock icon, but
inspecting the certificate
shows that it's the firewall certificate.
Switching to the command line
and using the noctilucent test client,
I'll set the TLS host to mozilla.org,
the host header to
defcon28.hackthis.computer
and the un-encrypted SNI to mozilla.org,
which is on the decryption exemption list.
The SNI is preserved
and set to mozilla.org.
A connection is made to
mozilla.org on port 443.
And we see the Hello DEF
CON 28 response we expect
from the test server.
We'll run nslookup of mozilla.org
so we can look for the
connection in the logs.
Looking at the firewall traffic
logs serves a connection
to one of the IP
addresses for mozilla.org.
Moving to the decryption
logs, we see DNS over HTTPS,
which is the ESNI key
lookup that is performed
before each TLS connection,
but no traffic to mozilla.org's IP.
To make sure we didn't
miss it, I'll add a filter
for the two possible IPs.
No results because mozilla.org
is exempted from decryption by default.
We have successfully defeated
an HTTPS decrypting firewall
by using built-in default
exemption in domain hiding.
This bypass is great, but
every time we wanna send data,
we'll add an entry to the traffic log,
which could stand out.
What if there was a better way to hide?
This technique works at the TLS level.
So any protocol that
Cloudflare supports underneath
would also work.
We saw that regular HTTP requests work,
but create a new connection
for each request.
Websockets are a technology
used by many streaming services
that enable full duplex
communication channels
over a single TCP connection.
And we can take this a step further
by using one or more of
these websites connections
to tunnel arbitrary TCP
or UDP packets to a proxy
beyond the firewall.
Here's the noctilucent test
client sending and receiving
via Websockets to a test server
while hiding behind www.okta.com.
Websockets are the perfect
candidate to use as a wrapper
for a proxy protocol that
allows us to send arbitrary TCP
or UDP traffic using a helper program
while only making a single TCP connection.
The noctilucent project includes
a fork of the amazing
Cloak project by Andy Wang.
That enables two new options
in the client configuration,
ESNIServerName and Preserve SNI,
which operate just like
they did on the test client.
Cloak is a universal plugable transport
that cryptographically
obfuscates proxy traffic
as legitimate HTTPS traffic,
disguises the proxy server
as a normal web server
and multiplexes traffic
through a fixed amount
of TCP connection while providing
multi-user usage control.
With the additions from noctilucent,
it can now do domain hiding as well.
Here's the same Palo Alto
and Windows VMs from before
with a public IP of 3.14.44.10.
This time, the Windows VM is running
a noctilucent Cloak client and
a local shadowsocks client.
The Cloak client is connecting to a VPS
running the standard cloak
server and a shadowsocks server.
Firefox is configured to
use the local SOCKS proxy
provided by the shadowsocks
client running locally.
And I can browse the
internet as I would normally.
The certificates of websites
in this proxy browser
are legitimate, as they're
not being intercepted
by the Palo Alto firewall.
And all traffic is appearing
to come from the DigitalOcean VPS.
The speed is surprisingly good.
During testing, I was getting speeds
up to a hundred megabits per second,
using four TCP connections with Cloak.
If we look at the firewall logs,
we only see the four
connections to mozilla.org,
which are not decrypted
while the client has been browsing freely
with all traffic remaining
encrypted and uncensored.
Switching to the decryption logs,
we see the DNS over HTTPS requests,
but no request to mozilla.org.
I'll filter for the mozilla.org IPs,
but we'll get no results.
What we see here is arbitrary
traffic at highs speeds
using only four TCP connections
to what Palo Alto thinks is mozilla.org.
Can we use this technique for
our preexisting RedTeam tools
if they support proxying?
You bet.
Here's a Cobalt Strike listener
with a SOCKS proxy setting
for localhost port 9999.
For fun, we'll set Cloak
to use bitdefender.com
as the front domain, which
has the IP address shown here.
After starting the
noctilucent Cloak client
and local shadowsocks
server and SOCKS 4 mode,
we'll double click on
an innocent looking EXE.
We get the call back immediately
and it works as expected.
And, of course, the first thing
you do when you get access
is pop a calc.
Switching the firewall and
looking at the decryption logs,
we only see entries
for cloudflare-dns.com.
I'll paste in a filter
for the two possible IPs
for bitdefender.com and we get no results.
Looking at the traffic logs,
you see four connections
to the IP of bitdefender.com
as well as lots of DNS over HTTPS.
Our Cobalt Strike beacon is
still functioning as normal
and any network defender
is none the wiser.
Packaging up Cobalt Strike
Cloak and shadowsocks
into a clean package,
possibly communicating over
named pipes instead of sockets
is an exercise left up to the viewer.
RedTeamers are no doubt wondering
how much work it would be
to integrate this with
their existing tooling.
And I can say if you're for using Go,
it's almost no work at all.
Here's a new C2 framework called DeimosC2.
It was a released just five days ago
and is built using Go, Vue.js.
I've set up an instance
here with an HTTPS listener,
with a public IP on port 443.
Going into the listener settings,
we can view the source
code for an HTTPS agent.
It has the C2 host import in the code,
and the agent will connect
directly to this host.
Switching to an editor, I've
made a few modifications
to get this to work with noctilucent.
First, I set the host to bitdefender.com
and I've added two new variables,
front domain and actual domain,
which are set to bitdefender.com
and deimos.hackthis.computer.
The actual code changes needed
to get everything working
is just 30 lines.
First, we have to query for
the ESNI keys and parse them.
If we wanted to, we could
bake in the current keys here
to avoid the network traffic
related to querying for them.
Then I define a TLS config
and set the minimum value to TLS 1.3.
I'll define the two new
options from noctilucent.
ESNIServerName is set to the actual domain
and PreserveSNI is set to true.
I define an HttpClient by hand,
so I can tell it to use this tlsConfig
when dialing the host.
Besides that, the only change the agent
is having the HttpClient
use the actual host
when it makes its POST requests.
On a Windows VM, I'll
set a filter in Wireshark
for the IP of BitDefender
so we can inspect the ClientHello.
I'll double click this new innocent EXE
and switch back to Wireshark.
In the ClientHello, we see
the un-encrypted server name
is bitdefender.com and
the encrypted server name,
it's just a bunch of hacks.
Back on the C2 server, we
have an agent calling back.
Notice the external IP.
When using this technique,
the reported external IP
will be from one of Cloudflare's ranges.
Just like with Cobalt Strike,
everything works as normal.
You can run whoami, pop a
calc, and check the public IP.
Besides the external IP
appearing to be from a Cloudflare range,
the agent functions as expected.
Back on the Windows VM,
I'll search for traffic
to the C2's server IP.
No packets, there's no trickery here.
With just a small modification,
this Go-based agent
is using domain hiding.
So what is the blue team to do
given that we've just seemingly bypassed
the most sophisticated network defenses?
The easiest thing to do
would be to block TLS 1.3,
but that's likely anywhere from
25 to 50% of the TLS traffic
leaving your network, it might
make a few users unhappy.
You could block Cloudflare,
but dropping 21%
of the most popular a
hundred thousand domains
probably is not a good idea either.
What about just targeting
ClientHellos with ESNIs?
It's possible, and one vendor
has had the ability to do that
for six months now.
However, since you can't
determine the destination site,
it's all or none blocking.
There's no way to only
block selective domains
if you block TLS connections
that have an ESNI.
I was surprised by the
lack of support for this
across major vendors,
but perhaps it's just not an issue yet.
The most sensible way to
detect this specific technique
is to alert on packets that
contain both a server name
and an encrypted server
name TLS extension.
There are no default
helpers for TLS in snort
besides ssl_state, which can help you get
the ClientHello packet and TLS. version,
which can get you TLS 1.3.
So you'll have to get creative
with the content parser
and look for the extension types.
Securicata has a bit more
horsepower than snort,
but only has a selector for
tls.sni and not tls.esni
so custom rules will be
required here as well.
It's gonna come down to tried
and true techniques that work,
regardless of traffic content.
Things like beaconing
detection and anomaly detection
can help show clients that all of a sudden
start sending regular
traffic to destinations
that perhaps don't make sense.
There are even some open
source tools that do just this.
A network defenders should be
asking if a traffic pattern
to a given end point
makes sense in context,
perhaps that Windows machine in accounting
shouldn't be sending gigs of data
to your single sign on provider.
TLS fingerprinting with JA3 and JA3S
is another technique
that could be effective.
JA3 looks at the specific
options used in a ClientHello,
that can sometimes
uniquely identify a client.
And JA3S does the same for servers.
This will work until
attackers tune their tools
to be identical to browsers
and common web servers
and work is already underway to do this
in projects like Cloak and utls.
As always, a layered approach
that uses strong instrumented
and managed endpoint
detection and response,
and other techniques is the
best way to prevent compromise.
Or as Microsoft so hopefully says
just don't let untrusted
code ever run on your server.
To wrap up today,
I've discussed the basics of HTTP, HTTPS,
domain fronting, and a new form
of censorship resisting
communication, domain hiding.
This technique is usable
today with noctilucent
either as a drop-in replacement
for the Go-TLS library
or as a proxy.
The ESNI standard is
still very much a draft
and this technique will continue to evolve
as the changes in adoption grows.
In fact, it's not even
called ESNI anymore.
Just as with standard domain fronting,
this relies on the CDN permitting it.
However, in this case,
besides preserving the
standard SNI header,
we aren't really doing
anything terribly out of spec.
I look forward to seeing the
snort and securicata rules
to detect and block this technique.
And like every good RedTeamer,
I'll push my customers
with the latest techniques,
hopefully before the real adversary can.
I wanna give special thanks to Robin Wood
who first showed this
technique was possible
with a rough POC using a fork of OpenSSL.
Andy Wang, the creator of Cloak,
and Nick Sullivan from Cloudflare
who helped to get me
data on TLS 1.3 adoption.
Noctilucent is available now on GitHub.
If you have any questions or comments,
feel free to hit me up on Twitter,
on my personal handle is @badsectorlabs.
Thanks for watching.