hello everyone welcome to epic battle
devils vs security I'm frozen I AKA
player 1 so I'm a ex sysadmin x devops
engineer now a cloud security operations
engineer capital one you can properly
dealt not graphic designer yeah i'm
representing delp's well you got one
here let's here i go on hello everyone
I'm Nick I am player too I am exercise
min IMX security operations before it
was called security operations explain
toaster x pci q SI x security architect
i am also not a graphic graphic designer
I will be representing security okay Wow
a quick show of hands who's a developer
okay whose operations whose security oh
wow six security maintaining their
operational security in staying very
quiet I like it alright so their vaults
versus security um something I should
have grabbed I have been paying
attention today I've like genuinely GC
for my security background interest in
this I'm enjoyed the talks however
they're all wrong basically so those of
you who've stayed looks like about half
of you well done you didn't bother
coming really I mean Chris dare said
earlier actually said it was good that
everybody's agreeing you keep getting
the same talks it's not the way it
should have been I mean I'm as shown I'm
an ex decide when I've been doing
security since Fraser was a teenager and
some of the terms of good things like
full spank ninja sounds fantastic but
DevOps is just a bad idea the thing it
reminds me of is the internet of things
it's just you get all that technology
together and you have to get it to
market and you just get some code
together and you just publish it and you
end up with just the stuff like the
stuff that happened to
you Brian Krebs the Myra botnet you just
compromised globally the internet of
things really easily take down his
service so problem is you're going to
end up with DevOps you can end up with
an Internet of crap thousand points to
security okay all right all right just
to be clear then so DevOps you know it's
not a management fat or anything like
that yeah as you've heard the intro
sorry all right thank you again is worth
waking to iPhone off still another
important Quixote right yeah so DevOps
is it's it's not of management fabre
like that everyone here knows what
DevOps is all I get broken down into
culture automation lean measurement and
sharing and then sort of dev psych ops
is obviously just that with security and
I know if is argued today much but
people suggest that the security should
automatically part of DevOps then you
shouldn't need the term dev psych ops
but I quite like dev psych ops or sec
dev ops or whatever or rugged DevOps
because it reminds you to remember about
the security element so if you just call
it DevOps it can be a little bit ignored
so yeah I mean that's that's DevOps it's
it's it's not it's not it's a grassroots
movement to get stuff done faster and
better with more quality yeah but it's
still just those separate teams can't
you just have meetings we can all talk
to each other card you have those remote
meetings were all connected all the time
you can just talk to each other and the
great thing as we said previously is
separation of duties also just the
security here you've got different
groups of people and as we said it was
Colleen said earlier I think in one of
his slides was like developers are from
our securities from Venus operations is
from Neptune shift leaders on technical
support from Pluto you get these are
different types of people with different
functions if you separate them all you
get the benefit of DevOps because you
still talk to each other but you don't
lose that security can't we just talk so
another thousand points exactly that you
pretty much nailed it DevOps isn't about
a unicorn engineer doing all the things
it is about breaking down those
traditional silos there's different ways
of doing it as you say you know
different functional you have a
functional team with members from
security operations QA developers etc on
the same team with the same sort of
goals or different teams working
together that's its it's about getting
the right people involved earlier on
it's not about unicorns then still
meetings but now with just all these
different teams all have to talk to each
other because you've got all this
communication going on it's the same
meetings but with more gimmicks and more
overhead and from this slide the guy at
the top left in the black with his
earphones are not talking to anyone
definitely from security it's the same
meetings but for some reason you will
decide to add post it notes and take
away chairs or it's just meetings but
weirder say well problems it's another
thousand points I'm doing quite well
stated yeah okay yeah it doesn't have to
be like that though I I agree with the
idea of the separation and having the
different teams but and this is where
automation comes into play you know do
things as code have think of teams as
microservices you know we're going to
jump on the SLA van wagon think of them
as micro services and have well-defined
api's and interfaces that way you get
the benefits as the separation of duty
but you can use automation to speed up
and remove that human element you know
you've got developers here there see I
see the environments talking to the ops
which talks a second devs talk directly
to apps and app sec although that could
be automated all your pipeline stuff
could be you know push through to
production or whatever within 20 minutes
with all the people involved without
pointless meetings and you know 20
people on a conference call yeah
automation has been mentioned a lot
today and automation is a good I
but automation just means you can screw
everything up at once you if anything is
compromised you can compromise
everything at once you need that smart
human intervention to stop all the
dominoes falling over you need that's
what you need security people for
automation just fails too fast it's
another thousand points yeah I'm not
doing real well in my um oh yeah okay
I'll take your point and their opinions
interesting cases where automation I
think Google have had some interesting
outages due to deploying stuff a little
bit too fast but you can break things at
scale but it also means you can react at
scale as well you can detect and
automatically respond and even rollback
changes automatically again through
automation so and and don't forget I
mean classic it XKCD you can still
really really break things manually you
know you're only after if you've five
o'clock in the morning you've been doing
a release for two hours that's been
waiting for six months copying and
pasting from a word document into you
know bash terminal or whatever you copy
the wrong thing for you know you've got
a good drop table or something like that
or you've screwed something up and that
could take down an entire service as
well I think game with automation at
least you can remediate that problem
quickly enough you maybe get a few
arrows maybe the users see a bit of
downtime but you have to accept kind of
some level of risk you have to accept
some level of risk this is security
failure is not an option that's a
central tenet of security is hopefully
the security people in here no security
you can't fail you get fired your
organization goes down you get
completely hacked it's 2,000 points
that's so obvious razor I heart but I'm
appalled yes failure is inevitable you
you can't avoid it to some extent you
you your options are you either pretend
it's not going to happen to you and sort
of finger in your ears lalalalala or you
embrace it and try to use that failure
to your advantage find a way to you know
do things that velocity and accept those
risk of failure accept failure all these
companies accepted failure some of them
now exists some of them don't you can
just you just can't exasperated earlier
yahoo has been mentioned frightened over
sick of time today you can't fail people
get fired people lose their livelihood
people lose their data as i said we
can't fail 2000 points if you all right
so those organizations you know what are
you suggesting they didn't they you just
for security you just need to add more
resources more people more technology
more information more threat
intelligence just more stuff and cyber
security will finally work throwing more
like a more less than throwing more
people resources and things like that at
ineffective processes you know isn't
gonna work that's like trying to find a
needle in a haystack by adding more hey
it's fundamentally going to be it's not
going to work it's not going to scale
it's going to be a bad time basically
the security again the central tenet is
the strength of any security process is
as strong as its weakest link so you
just we can't fail I kept saying it
until you listen that's another 2,000
points is a tricked you don't I mean and
you just don't understand the cyber
environment we're in the cyber risk or
exposed to the cyber intelligence we
need to understand the cyber threat
intelligence from the cyber threat in
their hoodies which have seen far too
much I've around today I have noticed
I'm the only properly dressed person in
this entire benefit the cybercrime and
of course the hoodie way in binary globe
faced cyber threats that we're all up
again there's just lots of cyber you
have to deal with Fraser another 2,000
points and also I mean as was mentioned
in the keynote you've got things like
well you've got auditors you've got the
insider threat and the
along with auditors is of course that
they're using lots of different
intersecting sort of the same but sort
of conflicting compliance regimes as
well as that you've got an every
increase in attack surface which needs
to be reduced all the time and as well
as everything I mentioned before as a
cybersecurity person I have to deal with
all of this so I don't have time for
this management fad of can't we all talk
to each other and let's be friends we
need to get on throw more resources at
cybersecurity there's just no time you
call that a thousand points you may
notice I've got clicker as well as
they've binary faced hoodie wearing
cyber threats as well developers do a
really good job your opponents are
mainly yourselves though their mistakes
in code or their issues with just the
way code is written or code is designed
there are issues with the way
infrastructure operates your main
opponent is complexity the cybersecurity
your main opponent is a sentient
opponent who's actively looking at what
you do and thinking intelligently how to
attack it it's a completely different
kind of adversarial situation a thousand
points for that one also I'm glad you
didn't even try to interrupt as a cyber
security person I mean I've got to
manage internet firewalls internal
facing firewalls the ingress and egress
rules for all of these because
unfortunately I have to let users talk
to each other I've got to have hardened
proxies in place as well I've also got
encrypt data on the endpoints I've also
got to have antivirus and the new name
for antivirus endpoint threat protection
there's all of this is feeding into my
security incident and event management
system so that people can look at it
look at all that data and try and find
patterns so this is what I've got to
manage with all my special security
staff and also then I've got sock
analyst looking at this and then I'm
given a hunt team a hunt team wants to
look at the raw information so they want
a data Lake Fraser I don't even know
what later lake is but I need to have
one there's nothing special specialist
need double point 28,000 points I'm
saying I'm saying no reason for you to
have any points at all so far thanks um
stop is maybe what you should just yeah
yeah exactly that's great everything but
well I think what you're suggesting is
security needs to be absolutely
everywhere in every part of the
organization and involved in every
single way you could that again as I
said and as we've heard throughout the
day doesn't scale you know you security
will be a blocker at that point you you
can't expect security to to to have to
give approval to every single decision
made throughout the entire set one more
resource just getting money start and
I'll will will finally get sober
security sobbed it's only been it's only
been 25 years will get hang of it food
rolling it realistically if you've got
like a hundred developers you probably
only get have like three security
engineers for those you know you can't
have three engineers blocking a hundred
developers because yeah the
organization's going to be at me a
hundred security engineers like a bad
that's not realistic it anyway yeah I
mean that that's just doesn't work you
can't block everything and what you need
is a security team capital s the
security team just coming in give me
give me those hundred cyber security
engineers to look at all that code look
at all that information look at their
stuff that's going live and just be be
those people who can say no who can
block things you can stop
vulnerabilities appearing on the network
yeah we've heard this I think at least
three times three times today I don't
know if you can actually see it but that
does say the Department of know it's
been disbanded got close but with no is
gone if the Department of no has been
disbanded then the hackers will get in
and everything will be on fire and when
everything is on fire Fraser what you
use to put the fire out but that it's
hackers or things are going to happen
right hackers are going to get in in
some form at some point in some way
it is inevitable you know you're
focusing a lot on the prevention side of
things and if you really want to prevent
security again you heard that today
switch the device off bury it in six
feet of concrete that's the only way you
can secure your thing ultimately
otherwise you have to accept that people
are going to get in Europe at the moment
you're completely ignoring things like
the detection and containment and the
remediation process where you're
accepting a level of risk of people
coming in you can't you know overdo the
security in one aspect you know what
he'll do I priority police response on
garbage it's good there are native
monitors monolith yeah yeah so yeah you
hackers are going to get in you have to
you have to be a little bit more dynamic
and how you approach your risk ok if I'm
going to drag myself out of a 90s
security stereotype it is all about
react but react needs to just understand
the amount of information a security
team will receive you need long and deep
contemplation of security logs security
information vulnerability feeds from
experience and thankfully expensive
consultants like myself really the way
to go dev ops I mean the thing just what
I've heard most today I mean DevOps it's
all about speed velocity like I said
about referring to the Internet of
Things it's all about the rep the push
to make things live just uh basically
slow down is what DevOps needs to do the
way we've been doing it so far it's
worked ok so far we just need like I
keep saying lots more resources somehow
it's just too quick I'll give myself
3337 points for that I think out very
generous of you all right let's take a
step back actually surprised I haven't
heard this mention today so Google have
the concept of an error budget and the
idea of an error budget is to align the
deployment deals with the operations
teams so you define your your arrow
budget is 1 minus the SLA for a given
surface you know if it's particularly
important you
ethically large SLA but that's that's
your kind of wiggle room for getting
stuff done you take your arrow budget
and you take how much down time you've
had so your availability that's a per
quarter subtract the two and that's how
much spend you've got left in your in
your sort of error budget so if a
development team has had a particularly
bad quarter let's say and they've had a
lot of downtime in their product in
their service they would have spent
their error budget and you know they
have to slow down that deployment
process probably by writing more tests
or maybe better tests but conversely if
they haven't spent that budget then
thats budgets gone to waste so maybe
they should have written fewer tests for
ironically or you know just tried to
innovate more potato more risks because
you know Google's opinion is that you
don't need a hundred percent
availability because it's unrealistic
you know users would notice that so
let's find that balance that incentivize
both operations and development teams to
the same figure that some reason off it
sounds reasonable but the thing with
availabilities it's really easy to
measure stuffs either up or down it's
either on or off I mean like I say I
have actually been paying attention
today like Mike Milner made really good
points earlier but the up from the
operational side it's just it's up or
down brilliant yeah use that SLA is
great maybe deploy a bit faster if it
supports that but security is much more
intricate and complex and difficult to
understand as people have mentioned
today you can't analyze this with a tool
people have made some suggestions but
there's no obvious tool out there where
just the security posture and
organization will make sense all right
so bearing in mind the risk budget
absite the risk budget the error budget
what if you could to find something like
risk budget so the idea would be you add
a line for security with the DevOps
velocity just done any reasonable k soon
as I've got such a elite score which a
few people in the audience should
understand I'll let you go ahead what's
a risk but
again lots of stuff covered this today
already your organization probably has
different ways of measuring risk already
and if you've got pipelines and you've
got things as code you're really doing
most of this out of the documentation
coverage if you've if you've got
documentation embedded into your code or
you've got external documentation how
much and how well your stuff is
documented is you know is something you
can measure unit test coverage unit test
results integration test coverage
integration test results all of these
basically help define the quality of the
the product or service and the
assumption here is that if you've got a
high quality from a software engineering
point of view product or service you'll
so probably have quite a high security
quality product or service but we've
also do other stuff as well again heard
lots of this today continuous security
testing if you're running BDD security
measure the output add that to some sort
of risk equation maybe you can do Co
driven threat modeling levels of ink
scruton Gator that's quite an
interesting idea if you can measure how
early and how much you get security
involved in the development process if
you can measure that you can sort of
count that towards a risk calculation
pen test results and again the idea if
you've got gated passes to production
you could maybe look at the percentage
of successful deployments to the
production as another risk metric why
would you do all this well let's take an
example let's say you've got a
particular service that you want to get
to production and you look at how
important what sort of data it has in it
and you arbitrarily give it an X number
of risk budget points per quarter let's
say so before they're sort of state
might may have looked like this they
didn't bother getting security involved
earlier on in the process so that cost
them like 50 points for a production
deployment nicer right more or
whatsoever that costs 100 points the
pretty good documentation maybe that
only costs in 10 points good test
results no security tests that's going
to cost them another hundred points good
gate rate and again no pen test
another hundred points so if we sort of
total these up you end up with 400
points per production deployment which
if you've got a risk budget of a
thousand points let's say that's only
two deployments per quarter it's not
particularly agile as if it's it's
pretty pretty bad but what you've done
is you've it basically incentivize them
to improve their security posture so
maybe they sort of sit down scratch
their heads think you know we want to
get things out the door a little bit
faster how can we do that you've
basically aligned them to your
requirement this time around they get
security involved a lot earlier and took
the larger extent maybe security attends
the stand ups and stuff so they've gone
down from 50 points for deployment down
to 10 basic set model maybe it's not
dynamic maybe it's not generated but
maybe it's just a like a security
markdown file in the root repository at
least it's shaped off a few points
documentation blah blah blah screw
t-tests they've managed to shave off and
other 80 points on the deployment by
writing security tests it's something
that can be measured something we
tracked something could be calculated
and they've got a pen test result let's
say pretty good maybe not perfect but at
least it reduced the points so if you
total those up it's now 155 points for a
deployment that lets them deploy every
two weeks and again automation is key
here this isn't a manual process this
isn't a spreadsheet or something like
that you would implement this as a
gating process to deployment so
developers you know they build a test in
a staging environment it's you know they
can have a big red button that says
you're not going to get this through to
production because you haven't got
enough points so yeah I mean an
interesting approach and a different
approach yeah I mean it's from this
you've obviously thought about it from
and to not be the cliche from my
original thoughts on this I was like 50
50 on DevOps but talking to Fraser
putting together the talk that they were
putting remor to the left so this you're
actually thinking about securities you
go along if it's not secure you stop if
it is secure you keep going if it's not
secure used
really secure you keep going almost
that's the slightly absolutist think
more of less security person being a
traitor more secure and less secure
again it's about the risk side and if
you think about it you know developers
like we've heard the word today as well
development teams and DevOps and stuff
works with value and you know they are
going to write a feature because there's
a high likelihood that pic feature is
going to have a positive impact on that
say you know the number of sales or the
number of users you know whatever the
key metrics are that sounds a lot like
risk to some extent doesn't it yeah
certainly I mean in this partly because
we run out of time looking at the clock
for today partly because we're running
out of time because cyber security
people have been trying the same thing
for the twenty odd years I've been doing
it and all we can say is just give us
more into the process and will finally
make it work I can see the two sides
risk is a negative beginning negative
beginning point of view that's negative
impact times likelihood of negative
things but from a developer site in the
DevOps point of view it's just impact
times likelihood of the positive effect
of releasing code and effectively it's
it's looking at the same problem from
from two different sides but looking at
it in the same way yeah exactly it is
all very sort of yin-yang two opposing
sides coexisting two sides of the same
coin you know positive value and
negative risk are essentially two of the
same things if you sort of look at it
slightly more philosophically develop
that looks horrific battle no it's
better on my laptop screen and so DevOps
has to take into account the negative
side of human nature it cannot ignore
security it has to take responsibility
for security and accept that it is there
a job to to accept that there are bad
people out there and they sometimes are
out to get you but at the same time and
we again we've heard this today security
has to you
july's the human at the positive human
side of human nature you know not
everyone is out there to get you shift
it left distribute that responsibility
let the developments and operation seems
do their job building out the security
but have that trust but verify model
have the controls in place just to
ensure that they are doing what they
need to do but then just let them get on
with it yeah absolutely i mean this is i
mean just what i've heard today and what
i've heard everybody saying today just
the whole push it to the left social
security gets involved earlier we were
discussing earlier today like the
difference in cost between remediating
issues early and remediating them at
that that last possible moment when you
realize you just have to talk to the
security team you can't avoid it any
longer and then if they find a
fundamental issue you have to change
everything so push it all the way to the
left them in something Marcus Pinto
mentioned earlier I really like the
phrase embedded security expertise so
that everybody's involved with security
and everybody understands security which
we've understood again again and sort of
looks right I really like Chris des idea
of Marvins just that army almost of
automatic thoughts inspecting code
raising things doing that first pass
which I mean to use the cliche I forced
into the presentation if there if dev
ops and security work together we all
get the high score we get really get one
cheer for over yes so do the dev ops ii
people in the room be patient with
security they are having to go through a
pretty radical philosophical like
paradigm shift so give them the space
they need to the security people in the
room if you're here to be honest i would
think you understand the value of DevOps
but to to the people you don't just tell
them to be patient and get them talking
to devops people if you get past the
cliches if you think it's all plank
meetings and just smashing developers
and operations together so you pay half
the staff half as much or rather have to
staff twice as much but they have to
work four times as hard I've seen
companies try that before
explain to your security people about
this and get the DevOps people in front
of them as I've learned from talking to
Fraser lucky I was 5050 to Fraser
explained a lot of the concepts to me
there was people have the best
intentions and similarly these ideas are
pretty cool security doesn't have any
really any fresh ideas anymore it's
about you doing the existing ideas but
better from listening to so many of the
talk presentations and people here today
DevOps is a genuinely new way of
approaching this and is the most likely
that i see that will actually work and
don't worry I'm not going to read this
out together to everyone remember
empathy goes both ways we have to find
ways to work together and accept
differences and yeah I mean it's you've
you've said to me the basis of the
culture of DevOps is empathy and
listening to people although it is a
stereotype the basis of security was not
listening to people and telling them
telling users or operations how wrong
they were so gain that empathy and
actually we can improve cybersecurity
and retaining can improve development
yeah thank you thank you very much
probably I'm sequestering whiskey yeah
yup 5-10 minutes i think maybe some
questions no one's no I'm not seeing any
look you know time just sneak out Thanks
okay we're good thank you