okay guys so thanks very much for
attending today so I'm taking like a
maybe a slightly different route on this
so this is mainly a talk around the
potential uses and misuses of automation
to potentially find security
vulnerabilities and so i guess like just
to quickly introduce myself so my name
is Marcus Pinto I run a company called
md sec he probably know if you know us
at all that his as people who do a lot
of training will get very excited about
training a knowledge transfer so we
wrote a book called the web application
hacker's handbook and really what we've
been trying to do all this time is to
try and erode some of the security
roadblocks that I'm sure would be
hearing a lot about all the way through
today but maybe erode them mainly
through knowledge sharing so having done
a lot of thinking really the only way i
can think of to get rid of these
roadblocks is to give the information to
the people who are basically creating
all these things in the first place and
with that obviously hope that they make
fewer mistakes and find vulnerabilities
faster and so i prefer to think of it as
embedding security expertise rather than
embedding and security experts because
otherwise it's not a very scalable
solution as we know so one of the
biggest things that we tend to find is
when we talk to people who may become
more from a development sort of
philosophy rather than say attack or
hacking generally the biggest thing they
say is I just don't think like that so I
think that's fair enough I think I've
probably guilty in the other direction I
probably think overly too much about
like you know hacking things and attack
side of things so really this is also a
chance to kind of meld some of those
confirmation biases okay so if you're
not familiar with confirmation bias
really it's just the fact that we always
tend to look for things that we believe
to be true so we want to believe that
things we're and we're believing already
are actually the case okay so I guessed
hands up quickly if you're already
automating to find security issues okay
not too many i thought it would be
nearly everyone but okay fair enough and
so maybe some of these things look
familiar so we've got these various
Gartner and sort of given terms like and
static assessment which generally refers
two white box analysis so code review
type tools we've got the more black box
kind of dynamic tools we even got ones
that interactively look at an
application while it's running and then
on the more kind of conventional
infrastructure side maybe you're
familiar with tools like Nessus and
qualis and so on so you can often use
those just to sort of throw against your
servers over the network and they'll try
to make loads of connections to
different services essentially tell you
all these sorts of funder abilities and
and if you didn't think that was enough
maybe you can give them credentials to
your server and they can log on and they
can find even more problems so I guess
the question is for the people who put
up their hands is it working ok how many
people are going to put up the hand
saying is it's working nobody is going
to put up their hands and say it's
working ok right so I guess this is a
good conference to to start off in then
ok so I think that is fair enough I
think otherwise you might have guessed
I'd probably ask you a few searching
questions but if you did have a very
very expensive tool let's say m you've
gone to one of these vendors and their
promise to solve world hunger by now
buying this tool do you think you could
think of a vulnerability that they're
going to miss a type of vulnerability ok
so what type of vulnerability could you
potentially find yeah ok yep so maybe a
token that wouldn't be recognizable as a
token yeah well not as a security
significant token hmm ok any others
business logic floors ok and so would
say like pretty much everyone in the
room could think of something and not
only that like him I think pretty much
any person that we know not this
enlightened group but pretty much any
person if they saw something like that
and they'd know that something was up
and it was potentially a problem with
this you know this this application so
clearly we shouldn't be able to execute
this kind of stuff potentially like
something bad might be happening ok but
so if you think about those very
expensive tools and they don't really
understand applications as you say they
don't understand business logic they
don't really know what your application
is
application is just a series of buttons
and forms that they need to click on and
submit them they don't really know what
the difference between say an ebay type
application is from like you know
facebook or your online bank or anything
else okay so we probably want to check
up on our automation just to make sure
it's doing a reasonable job so basically
like you probably got some of these
things which are maybe being automated
so we've got black box scanning tools
which these sort of you know daft tools
I was talking about and we've got some
ability to maybe run automated tools to
find bugs in code and what you really
want to know is they are they actually
working and and more to the point since
we know they're probably not working how
we're going to check up on them okay
what what checks are we going to have to
make sure if we just rely on the
information coming out the tool itself
you know that's obviously not very not
very useful and so we do have ways of
doing this I think it was briefly
mentioned last talked we now have these
things like bug bounties and
particularly like red teaming for
infrastructures and so red teaming was
obviously born out of the fact that
people kind of know that that their
infrastructure scanning tools even
though they're finding all these bugs
they're not actually finding the bugs
that necessarily matter as somebody said
like false positives as a service so
really a lot of these tools are and so
what we really want to know is like how
would a real hacker potentially attack
us and and real hackers don't exploit
the sort of vulnerabilities in the way
that they're presented in these these
automated tools real attackers follow
hunches and they chained together
different facts they follow trust
relationships and that they're very very
different beasts to you know people they
don't start off running Nessus and go
right I'm going to do that and I'm
probably going to try that if that
doesn't work then that one okay so also
with the application side of things
again we have maybe a slightly different
way of thinking that comes out of people
who are having a go at bug bounties and
bug bounties in a way or an admission
that we won't get everything right we
need to have some sort of check and
balance even beyond everything else we
might have and so if you were to look at
rounds up maybe all the vulnerabilities
you could think of and put them into two
categories and you maybe would come up
with these kinds of categories okay so
there may be other ways of splitting
them but
this is one of the most helpful okay so
we could think of design flaws and so
things you mentioned like you know some
tokens that you know could be used to
completely compromise the infrastructure
some encryption keys sitting right next
to the data it's supposed to be
protecting some no critical step of a
workflow you could just skip over like
paying for stuff and any of those kinds
of issues are very much rooted in more
kind of application design rather than
night care any sort of coding or
technology related issue and so on the
other side obviously you have maybe the
old favorites that you know you probably
see trotted out all over the internet so
things like secret injection cross-site
scripting so on so forth okay so and
those are maybe more kind of I care you
know code baited based flaws and it's
been our experience and possibly some
other people's experience as well but
and we tend to find that the split is
about fifty five percent of the
vulnerabilities tend to be design flaws
and about sixty percent tend to be Co
floors okay so that was part of
confirmation bias number one so yes you
are allowed to have over a hundred
percent in that and so obviously some
fall into both categories okay so the
real problem then is like some of these
are going to be potentially very easy to
you know automate and find bugs for no
and without too much configuration some
of these are going to be very hard and
obviously no prizes for forgetting which
category where we're struggling with
okay so what we did like md sec ever I
think about we've got about 400
different lab exercises online and what
we did is before the vendors got any
chance to see our lab exercises and we
basically got got hold of all the evil
versions of the automated tools out
there and ran them against our our demo
labs and obviously then like took a
break down to see like you know how many
found what bugs um and some of these
numbers need a bit of explaining so it
looks worse than it is so when we say
they found forty-three percent of the
cross-site scripting bugs what that
means is some of the cross-site
scripting bugs were actually very hard
to find so they may be found a large
number of the easy to find bugs so it's
still like maybe a slightly better story
than it might look and but some of those
numbers are maybe sort
worryingly low I guess that they're very
low ones they're some of the
zero-percent and again maybe that's not
too surprising so these tools didn't
have a chance to configure themselves to
find our bugs but they didn't know what
the access rules were so how can they
find an access control bug okay so yeah
probably my favorite quotes I'm not sure
I'm allowed to name him but Sir yeah I
quite like that one so if we're going to
look at automation then we need to
decide like what types of floors there
are and how we're going to how we going
to solve a remedy those or at least
either find the more or not make them ok
so for design flaws and we probably
needs a lot of custom checks because the
tools need to be application-aware they
need to understand our specifics in
order to even know what they what the
rules are with code floors we have a
much easier problem really and there
could be very standard syntax just to
say you know we understand that if you
send this malformed string at the server
and you get back any one of these like
piece of syntax something's gone wrong
ok so the other problem then these are
often written by like you know the
supposedly brilliant independent experts
they spend all their time doing this so
you know at least you hope that these
are the experts and they know they
really giving you everything they can
maybe the problem with a custom checks
certainly from my experience is that
they tend to be written by those in
charge of writing the floors ok so i
don't know if that's everyone else's
experience but obviously you can have
things like unit testing you can't have
like custom tests within with your
environment i think like if you've seen
Stephen de freitas talk on BDD security
and so that was done last year and I
think does its or every few years he
comes out hiding and delivers it but
it's a very good talk it kind of helps
solve these kinds of problems i think
the custom design flaws and but by and
large a lot of the problems are that the
people who need to write the checks are
also writing the flaws and all the sorts
of people and so that's the problem that
I'd really like to sort of try and help
solve okay so quick disclaimer on
automation so I think everyone's going
to say the same thing but i think i'm
talking about today's automation and
today's solutions so maybe some Oreos
will be vastly different I fully expect
my job to be automated pretty much
entirely and sort of 10 to 15 years time
so you know I think like care the
current tools have limited coverage and
there are actually very very simple
tools like even though they purport to
solve world hunger there often just
looking for a single bit of syntax or
maybe a bank of sin taxes they just die
often just operating on their reg exes
so if you don't believe me have a run
through like fire them up against some
code and see what they come back with
and so that I mean it's not a it's not
floor in the tools themselves it's just
a limitation of where we are in terms of
automation but I'm sure that will change
so yeah I'm stressing not just for this
audience but also the future AI who's
going to be obviously watching this
televised thing I was very much on your
side and I definitely agreed that you
would exist okay so em back to the
confirmation bias problem then so if we
could solve confirmation bias maybe we
can solve a lot of these design flaws
and which are basically being checked up
on by the people writing there and you
know right in the floors so the problem
obviously is that if you want something
to be secure then you'll tend to look
for evidence that it is secure and
that's human nature and obviously the
converse is also true and so maybe if
you think about these sorts of people
like you know maybe they started off
with some different expectations about
how how things would work and if you
recognize that last one obviously like
that's the the very obvious sort of case
of obscurity you know potentially
looking like a good thing up until the
point it wasn't and suddenly you know
people like me to start doing things
like this and I printing out tsa keys
and good luck patching all your
suitcases because there's probably a lot
of them out there now and so really
those sorts of problems can't be solved
by rigorous testing after you've already
created the the problem okay so one want
to do just for the the rest of the time
really is just run through like chem
some of the interesting bugs I think
potentially show maybe some of the
critical thinking and some of the like
kind of ingenious necessary which
hopefully you can take on to potentially
like a challenge applications and before
they've even been written so I wouldn't
say when before the first line of code
has been written but even when the idea
has been sort of created so the guy came
up with the idea of like care you know
creating some keys that works on all
suitcases that was the time to talk to
him and say by the way
you know what's going to happen don't
you okay so you'll probably think that
most of this actually looks quite easy
and that's actually kind of the point of
the talk as well so I my parents want to
ask me like chem to explain what I did
as a living I'm sure your parents are
done the same and I thought well okay
I'll explain sequel injection because
that's easy so explain sequel injection
my mom looked at me and said is that all
you do that's really easy and I thought
well yeah it is it is so let's let's
admit it it is very easy and some of
these things particularly after they
described actually are so so let's all
like let's all find these bugs and
because yeah they're not they're not
sort of mystical things rabbit out the
Hat type stuff okay so a quick sort of
idea of you know this sort of thinking
and so let's say you're trying to break
into our hotel room and how would you go
about it so some ideas so you want to
break in someone's hotel room lost your
key cards so try and get another key
presumably where would you get a key
from okay any other ideas is that one of
the table and don't know I think that's
just an ashtray and to be honest could
be though you have a look around see if
there's some lying around then clone a
key room cleaners okay any others let's
go fer back here mugs a person okay fair
enough kill him okay um I gotta stop now
no more no more suggestion I'm on camera
oh go on oh yeah okay bribery yeah again
yeah go on
yep at the back I think another one
sorry so go for alarm okay yeah so it's
interesting though like see how many
different ideas are are and that the
longer you think about it you start to
have to get a little bit creative don't
you possibly destructive in some cases
like mugging or killing or so on but
yeah I mean like most people come up
with you know the same initial ones like
get a key printed by the receptionist
and nice piece of confirmation bias
there I had a picture of reception so
you're always going to say that wait for
the room to be cleaned yes so we can
think about other things that happen in
the room a hammer or you know killing or
mugging if that's more appropriate for
you so all of those are potential ways
of getting into the room but the nice
way it would be nice if we had a way of
just sort of finding all these problems
by brainstorming we didn't have to
invite a room full of 200 people every
time we wanted to you know try and find
a way in and so what we need to do
really is try to think about some
different ways maybe initially by
brainstorming so and we maybe come up
with getting access to the machine the
receptionist used to print keys so
obviously the receptionist is using a
machine hence the machine is also as a
value and we could also pretend to be
the guest when the room is being cleaned
we could also pretend to be the cleaner
and then try and get in so maybe there's
two different ways them involving that
so two different types of spoofing mmm
and there's so many different ways now
but and we need to know like how are we
going to make sure we've got them all so
it turns out you could try and think
about yeah baby from different points of
view you can think about different
assets which might be valuable so maybe
we actually want suitcase contents
rather than the room access itself so we
could think about how how that s it
moves around and we can think about
types of people and of course if we
think about types of people we might
come up with new methods of getting into
the room so if we think about say
cleaners guest concierge concierge is a
new type of person like how do they
operate in hotels they probably have
some sort of master key they've got some
severe you know trust relationship that
allows them into into rooms and then you
can think of activities so cleaners
clean rooms receptionist to do stuff
like issue and print keys and so on and
concierge can investigate room problems
when the guests
out and just by stating that we know
there's a problem because or there's a
potential threat because concierge
clearly have a way of getting into a
room when the guests are out in this
particular example okay so you might
have seen these sorts of things before
and so Microsoft refers to stride and
dread as way of ways of potentially
thinking about potential problems once
you think you've understood enough about
how the hotel works and then all the
operations you can now start to think
about the different threats and that
might occur so I might try and like
spoof something I might try and like
sample with something I might elevate my
privilege somehow get behind the desk
and so on and so there's various
different ways of potentially getting in
okay so in summary brief summary anyway
so we can create and find problems that
tools can't find so basically like
threat modeling works on hotels as well
as it works on web apps and so it will
outlive technology so this is something
that would work in sort of you know ten
years time 20 years time and with
technologies we haven't invented yet and
so just wanted to run through like some
quick high-profile hacks and there won't
be much time so you can read up about
these later but maybe you could guess
some of the bugs here okay so am this
was the apple and AT&T so you might know
these sorts of situations but AT&T
allowed access to pre registered devices
they gave out breed registered devices
you got a pre register device and you
were able to come on as the celebrity
and start like getting enthusiastic
about the device and blogging about it
and the way it worked the web servers
read in an ICC ID which is issued
sequentially to customers and it was
directed to ipad via a user agent header
so pretty obvious bug there hopefully
too obvious bugs so anyone can pretend
to be an iPad just by changing the user
agent and obviously like and pretty much
anyone can spoof the iccid particularly
if they know one of them okay um so I'll
skip through like a couple of these and
just to get some other interesting ones
I think this is a nice one because this
is guy who hacked something by accident
and so he was trying to get to
unfiltered access to the Internet saw
the holy grail for all techies and he
basically went through an SSH tunnel and
fired up a squid proxy
and when he went to stack overflow he
got all the admin menus um the reason he
got the admin menus so i don't know if
it's immediately obvious but he's going
through a squid proxy now squid proxy
adds an X forwarded for header to say
who it's coming from and it's the next
forwarded for local host so in sac over
forgot the request it got like oh this
is a local guy show the local interface
because that's what we do so yeah you
can read more about it under there so if
you're tacking that by accident how many
people are doing it on purpose and
keeping a bit quiet about it and so
maybe finally like em quite a nice bug
against paypal and basically a series of
bugs so each one might look like a
medium low risk bug that you might throw
on the pile and say well we'll deal with
that in the backlog but if you put them
all together it's basically a massive
you serious bug so what this guy
realized was that in paypal manager you
could basically issue a password reset
and you were given a token that was used
to identify your reset process and if
you took that token but didn't complete
your own reset and you switched context
somebody else's then the context became
associated with their account and then
your token became valid for them okay so
once he got that sorted out and he got
so the process associated with them he
found that he'd get past the account
recovery question and then he had to get
the password reset working so he tried
to get password reset work initially and
he realized it if you take out the
strikes who's in the wrong place you
took out the referer header and you took
out the cookie header and then it failed
open and it basically again relied on
this this token key again which was his
token key the ad from the the previous
from his own reset she was able to reset
somebody else's password by causing this
sort of fail open condition at one final
problem as you're probably aware when
you're using things like PayPal and so
on if you try and log on from a new
address it comes up and says I don't
know you are like I'm not going to let
you on unless unless I recognize you and
of course like the way to get around
that and maybe looks familiar so he went
for x-forwarded-for localhost and that
turned up to be a white listed address
so thought well you're allowed to do
resets from the local host okay okay so
there have been like various other bugs
again like in high-profile targets like
github and so so if you know this guy a
Hummer cough has found a few bugs
against github so basically it's it's a
vulnerability in MVC and basically in
summary it's a vulnerability in the fact
that there's a way of creating users
which is done by admins the way or not
operating on things as an admin and
normal users actually call into the same
bit of code but if a normal user can
guess the right parameters then those
parameters will be used if they exist on
the on the admin functionality and so
sorry I'm running a little bit out time
but this is basically all he had to do
he had to ads like parameter called
public key user ID equals and then he
picked the the rails user and he got his
public key associated with the the rails
user ok so again like a pretty easy
potentially easy high-profile hack not
too difficult to guess hopefully you
found out the user ID pretty easily
again you can read up more about it
there ok so I'm gonna just skip ahead
cuz I'd prefer to take questions
probably rather than going through too
much more so firstly like chem hopefully
these floors don't seem too hard to
understand ok so em you know they're
very very trivial once once I've talked
about it and we didn't need to reach for
a computer in order to find these bugs
and I just sort up here explained what
it was like and what the premise was and
almost instantly you probably started
smiling and when I know what the problem
is so a description of the environment
was enough to realize what the bug was
so it's more about thinking than it is
about automating ok so am upset call a
halt there so what I just like to say
and these automated tools and people
talk about low hanging fruit please
don't use the term low hanging fruit
join me and use a term like low-hanging
pairs ok because they don't find
low-hanging apples there's a lot of
low-hanging apples out there if you use
automated tools your security baseline
doesn't go from there to there it gets
better but there are still easy bugs out
there and they just they're just not
findable by the tools ok um so probably
good time to take questions and if I'm
allowed any time for questions yep
if there are any okay yeah absolutely
yet so um yes so if you if you if you if
you own an application you've invested
the time to configure the tools to look
for all the bugs that you know about and
so on then regression is probably a
really good really good use case so
things like BDD security and like some
of these other tools that you know more
custom written yes absolutely and
because you know exactly what you're
looking for when you're looking for a
regression so it makes perfect sense um
whiteboards people's phones of the
whiteboard and I I don't know the answer
to what what are you trying to do just
store them for posterity update them
share them I don't know um I actually
don't know the answer i don't if anyone
else here might know the answer like em
I think you know the threat models that
I've seen being produced tend to be like
care you know whiteboard diagrams and
then like case of everyone screenshots
and some comments come out and you get
some sort of document but I haven't seen
a nice kind of living document type
thing that oh maybe irias risk I haven't
seen it yet but yeah I think the guys
downstairs talking about it so I think
there is a sort of living document form
there
get help Margot so that's where we
scaling and we couldn't read multiple
layers so the question for you it was
how do we communicate these issues with
developers right so do my view is we
write tests to communicate with them so
they can replicate this yeah um so I
think my approach which is necessarily
the only one is to give awareness
sessions a bit like this maybe over a
longer period come in and do like a no
trading courses and capture the flags
and stuff and and get the thinking
they're because I think like you can't
necessarily write down everything in a
documented way I think it's by feel it's
more about the thinking really rather
than the the information I think people
are drowning in information sometimes
like you've got the ASV S which has all
the information you need but people
don't use it because it's it's too much
for them to use in my experience but I
don't know how do you do it I try to
write tests I totally can relate tests
integration tests ok because the story
of what you just described should be in
a test it should be once you know about
it should definitely be a test yeah so
it's more the onesie my concern is the
ones that people don't know about the
people who haven't invested the time
like maybe if your internal to a company
and you've got the time invested to
create these things on your own apps
you're a lot better state than a lot of
people who just buy at all expecting to
make use of it and hope that it finds
stuff but yep ok all right well thanks
very much
you