so hi everybody
and I'll try to keep you entertained in
this sort of coveted before lunch spot
in the talk so I'm a guy I put John
you're a guy pol and I'm here today to
give you a talk that I sometimes called
secure node code and sometimes call
stranger danger which deals with some
node specific advice around securing
things in this echo system as well as a
general theme or concept about
vulnerabilities in open source packages
so a little bit about me I started with
security you know a daunting number of
years ago now I'm showing my age a
little bit about 20 years through the
Israeli sort of cyber security army and
that have been in apps like for a good
sort of 17 years now I guess or 16 years
working on apps shield naps can the
first well firewall were up security
scanners then I left security which is
an initial move and started a
performance startup called blaze which
got acquired by Akamai you know CTO
attack might for a few years and then
have recently left that to found another
startup called sneek which is where I am
right now so open source is awesome
right I think that's pretty well
accepted let's share work when we
created it lets us reuse the word from
others and therefore focus on our core
and makes us very productive and as a
result open source has exploded the use
of open source has gone from something
that's more rebellious more sort of you
know a few small entities except for
maybe the major exceptions for Linux and
the likes to things that is really
prevalent across any organization
including banks and the other is just
about how much of it to use not whether
you use it and unfortunately we get this
constant reminders that the fact
something is open-source there's not
meaning secure that may or may not have
been true earlier on that because it's
open there's eyeballs on it and people
scrutinize it but it definitely is
insured today with the volume of
activity that's going there it doesn't
mean open source is insecure there's
also the pros and cons but it definitely
does not implicitly secure and again we
get all these like brand name
vulnerabilities designer vulnerabilities
that help us reminder of it right like
like
heartbleed and shell shock and log jam I
love this sort of CloudFlare animation
there since the log and a jack that's
kind of the best they can do and the the
other thing
that happens whether open source is that
attackers are targeting open source it's
a very lucrative target it's one
vulnerability it has many victims it is
everywhere so it's a very appealing one
and therefore there's all sorts of stats
but the majority of successful exploits
are attributed to some form of unpatched
servers or on updated open source
components and there's a lot of
conversations like the one we had
earlier today from that on on how to
handle this both on servers as well as
on more modern environments like
containers and also some studies show
that it's a very real problem and that
it's just continuing into this new world
with binaries of containers where 30%
this is one analysis again different
views but definitely many of the
containers out there and repositories
contain these types of vulnerable
binaries and alongside it although as
we've just heard it's not easy there are
at least some solutions there's a lot of
conversations around how do you tackle
that in terms of updates in terms of
container security tools there's kind of
growing chatter there but all of that is
about open source binaries what about
open source packages open source
packages that get pulled into our code
they're just as hacker friendly you know
a lot of sort of usability taking into
account there the vulnerabilities are
already found for you you don't need to
work it's just sort of there by the
community you just need to write an
exploit and it's kind of easy because
you can download it to your system their
every word millions and millions of
downloads a month that's true for
packages and binaries and they're hard
to update in part because of dependency
chain and this thing depends on the
other and what's in memory so encode is
you know what is the dependency
component things are out of your reach
and in part because of fear right we
think that you might trigger some
breakage some functional limit and then
lastly it's sort of pulled in across the
system in the case of binaries it
servers everywhere in the case of code
this is all these applications where any
developer has the legitimate mandate to
pull in another piece of package that
sort of work efficiently so for the
remainder of the talk we're gonna pick a
node because it's fun and because I sort
of have some tools to show on it but
really this problem is is prevalent it's
not just sort of a node problem so we
didn't know the package repository for
for open source packages is called NPM
and it is awesome and it is growing at
an amazing pace that forces me to update
this slide every time I give a talk like
this with some other staggering numbers
like 6 billion downloads a month I mean
that's a fairly impressive number and
this is more than double what it was I
guess about 9 or 10 months ago when when
they just sort of started quoting these
stats
it also has over 65,000 publishers I
think it's actually more like 70 or 80
thousand right now which shows the
strength of the community that's sort of
pushing in this content and what that
leads is to the situation where this is
your app and this is your code and at
first glance you must think you might
think that this is a negative slide but
actually think of it as a positive slide
you can create all that orangish value
with only that purplish level of effort
that you need to do that they need to
actually build in so it's a good thing
it lets us run faster lets us be
competitive be innovative but it's also
a scary one right while on the
functional side it says that javascript
is one you know as many of the GS people
like to say that again does through
other environments from a security
perspective each one of these
dependencies is a security risk and when
you stop to think about it there's a lot
of daunting questions I mean do you even
know which open source packages are you
using do you know for every single one
of them did it undergo the developers
writing it have any sort of security
expertise they did undergo any sort of
security testing you know keep in mind
that security tools are generally
oriented at enterprises and many of
these packages are written by one two
three person teams written on a weekend
and sometimes you know well-maintained
for a period of time and then kind of
neglected not sort of the same model as
security assessments have been done and
often times these people have no
security expertise and maybe more
practically do you know if they have
known security bugs you know packages
have bugs it's been known to happen and
some of those are security flaws just
like the binaries so it's sort of the
the code part of what you're pulling and
then the second concern there is the
people part there's a lot of greatness
again in the open source world that open
source is written by people it's
community people all the solutions and
all the opportunities are about people
and it's easy to forget that these peep
or strangers you know we don't know who
they are and yet we pull hundreds and
thousands of packages written by tens of
thousands of strangers from the internet
and we run them in a financially
sensitive environment based on at best
minimal minimal scrutiny so it's scary
and while we like to think that these
are all like benevolent ponies
definitely in the NPI microsystem we in
this room know that they're not you know
some of them may be the vast vast vast
majority of them are but there are bad
actors out there right there are people
that are trying to do something bad and
once again you know we don't really know
those users we don't know if their
malicious we don't know if they've been
compromised know how well do they treat
their development environments we've
seen some examples on this on mobile
development with Xcode ghost and recent
former ability in the Play Store where
developers were distribution vehicles
for viruses these were pieces of malware
that attacked developers of Xcode or
Google Play of iOS or Google Play apps
and injected malware when those apps
were submitted into the App Store and
the true victims are the true target for
the attacker were the users but the
developers were used that is a
distribution vehicle it's a very
efficient distribution vehicle and
unfortunately a fairly hackable
distribution vehicle today so this is a
bit of a doom and gloom and it's a big
problem and I think it has no single
sort of silver bullet and it needs to be
a bit of a community solution and
there's a lot of conversations going on
it for the rest of the talk I'd like to
focus on what I think is the most
concrete aspect of it that we can start
doing in the open source packages world
and that is no informer abilities right
in the world of NPM about 14% of the NPM
packages that are out there right now
the latest versions carry unknown
vulnerability
either they have one in their own code
or they pull in another package that has
that vulnerability in it we it's Nick we
deal with this and we see that about
four and five node development shops
when they go in and they starts to test
their applications on first lines they
find a vulnerable package at least one
that they're using and in the majority
of cases these are or in many of these
cases these are very high severity
issues this is this is like I'm not the
only one talking about this
opponent this has been mentioned by sona
thai by various others you know can have
a mandatory Josh Corman mentioned here
he's not here is he's in spirits talking
about calling this software supply chain
you can kind of call it whatever you
want but you know it needs to be
addressed so I will ask two things first
is how do we protect ourselves from
these issues
what processes should we adopt how are
they different than open source binaries
and then second from a code perspective
I find that these vulnerable packages
because they're so contained because
these are real-world vulnerabilities
they're actually a really great
educational tool for developers in our
systems to learn from these mistakes and
understand how do they avoid making them
and how do they address them when they
happen in their own code so the
remainder of my session is not going to
be here but what I'm going to do is I'm
going to try to kind of demonstrate a
little bit why this is a real problem
you should care about using a vulnerable
application that we have called goof
it's you know it's in JavaScript so it
needs to be able to do MVC that's so it
is and it allows you to do some
important note-taking like call mom or
you can highlight a few things like by
year just sort of parentheses and and
use that components you know it's a
simple app and within a deduces a bunch
of packages popular packages that are
used in the recommended way so there's
nothing I didn't sort of intentionally
you know obscure this or messed up with
this just to sort of make them
vulnerable is more highlighted it's used
in the naive in the standard way and
we're gonna use kind of excuse here the
plug we're just gonna use it for info
we're gonna use sneak for it so this
stick would allow us to sort of test the
different repositories that we have in
it all the different NPM packages and we
will find this one here goof which we
can see has a bunch of vulnerable
components some high severity medium low
severity and we'll we'll just sort of
pick a handful of these going into the
test report that you know again kind of
try to show the the magnitude of why
should you care about this so there's a
bunch of vulnerabilities here and I'm
going to pick on a very arbitrary set
I'll start with SD SD is a package that
was created by the author but by Isaac
from and
the guy runs NPM super capable developer
and it has a directory listing
vulnerability in it so let's just get
warmed up a little bit we use st to
serve static resources in our
application so easily serve our CSS
files our JavaScript files as well as
our about page which is sort of
highlight how awesome this application
is so we can't really do any hacking in
the browser because it normalizes paths
for us so we're going to switch at this
point - big enough start this and we'll
sort of switch to curl and we'll fetch
our little about page again just kind of
getting warmed up and we know there's a
directory traversal vulnerability here
so what are we going to do suggestions
no dot dot dot dot dot a bunch of these
and maybe we'll kind of ask for the HC
passwd file and the app is kind of
running on a Roku and this will do
nothing because actually you know this
is a good package written with security
in mind except you know like many pieces
of code it has a bug so the dot dot is
actually sanitized however if I did a
different way to do dot for instance %
to e
your own encoded version of it things
would not fare as well so again just
kind of getting warmed up just to see am
i doing this ok here and ah yeah there
was a missing flash over here some live
coding here like hacking uh wallah ok so
just getting started a little bit
there's actually a handful of vulnerable
sort of static resource packages in in
NPM right now that have these components
and this is one of the top
vulnerabilities that we see happen there
which is sensitivity to encoding is just
sort of not thinking through again not a
lot of security consciousness seems like
101 from a security perspective but many
of this is not had a security
perspective ok got start a little bit
you know got our Heroku if you see
passwd file which is not that useful
these days anyway and let's sort of go
on to a next one the next one is and the
winner is
marked anybody here happened to hear of
marked alright is actually much more
popular package so marked is a markdown
parser and we use it to be able to
highlight beer in our in our to do
application which is important you must
admit and it gets downloaded about two
million times a month it's the top I
believe in markdown parsing library in
node and it has as we know now across
the scripting vulnerability so what are
we gonna do we're gonna do script script
alert one script and nothing just like
st marked has a very comprehensive
sanitize function that's built into it
now interestingly sanitize is off by
default we turn it on in this
application to sort of add the security
feature but it's off by default
similarly st allows directory listing by
default so this is another sort of facet
of security concerns you should think
about with open source packages which is
their insecurity faults ongoing
conversations through binaries as well
around whether that's a vulnerability
per se or not but it definitely is a
security consideration you should have
and it's not well documented so we're
still still struggling around whether we
want to present these vulnerabilities
but for now you know both marked and st
don't have good security faults but
anyways in this case we turned it on but
it doesn't have you know this
vulnerability any other suggestions for
variants for cross-site scripting no
some encoding so encoding how I'll start
out I'll kind of do a little bit of a
I'll get you started so you know marked
caches HTML very well but this is a
markdown format that would actually give
me an alert or sort of a JavaScript link
just part of that page so if I do this
what will happened no that's it before
lunch you're just too tired nothing
because sanitize is actually very
comprehensive and it catches those
constants as well but once again this
one has an encoding problem in it so how
can i encode in HTML
no I need more red team's here so I'm
presented yeah exactly HTML entities so
we can do something like this and
something like this
41 : and these are HTML entities so
there are way to sort of represent to
the browser to say this is actually a
Colin if I do this then now I get
nothing and this is maybe a point to say
that crosses everything is hard to block
and mark this actually has the sanitize
function is actually really good
according to the spec however browsers
do not follow the spec as they should
they're actually very very tolerant so
if I go in here and I add this over here
just some word the browser is gonna look
at this string and say wow like I know
it's not the spec but I kind of get what
you were meaning you give me enough
hints you know I will follow along and I
will think of this as a Colin and if I
do this
voila we've got our coveted alerts which
we just love so much in the world of
security so you know these are the the
reason I kind of go through this process
and all these encoding is to say you
know just put yourself a little bit in
the mind of a newbie developer an
experienced developer but not
necessarily security conscious one just
for thinking about all these scenarios
is hard right it's not an obvious thing
and we're consuming a ton of code from
these environments I'll show a couple
more examples and then I'll kind of
switch a little bit more to solution
mode because these these are all you
know like if you're a red team you're
not that thrilled by finding across that
scripting and a directory traversal
you're sort of looking for something
more hardcore there's a couple of like
remote command executions that are on
the way to be published but I can show
them quite yet so I'll show a couple of
others that are more memory related so
we talked about heartbleed before the
next one durability I want to show you
is on Mongoose has anybody here heard of
Mongoose Mongoose is really quite
popular so Mongoose is the way to access
MongoDB which is the database or most
popular database in the world of nodes
and it has a moaner ability due to an
object called buffer buffer is a very
tricky objects in the world of node
JavaScript developers typically don't
think about memory but buffer allows
them to actually create an object that
holds just a bunch of allocated memory
and it has two constructors it can take
a string like this in which case it
would just allocate that amount of
memory into a buffer or it can take an
integer and when it takes the integer it
allocates that amount of memory except
it doesn't zero it so at this point if
I've received a piece of input if I've
received kind of piece of integer and
now I have this object and I somehow
managed to get it back to me the
attacker then I can now read heartbleed
style server-side memory this is not
from open SSL so the secrets will be
different it'll be source code and code
secrets versus necessarily the SSH keys
but you know it'd still be too bad and
actually depending on how you have your
note it might even be the SSH keys the
TLS keys I'm sorry so let's talk a
little bit about how we how this happens
here in buffer but this vulnerability
buffer related vulnerabilities are now
in some pretty major packages so whether
in Mongoose they're in requests they're
in WS just to give you a sense for what
gets downloaded 17 million times a month
and we did a quick can I get hub query
cuz get a vessel some of its data in
bigquery and very quickly found 10,000
projects that use a vulnerable version
of request directly so it's several
people just don't think about it so in
gouf we use buffer as the as the entity
or the element that holds our notes here
so we're gonna again switch to the
command line a little bit here and I've
got some aliases here to help me do it
so you know just to kind of flow through
I'm gonna do this echo content by beer
and I'm gonna use HTTP pie just for
syntax highlighting this is like curl
but prettier so just sort of posts posts
the the content and all we've done here
really is switch to a curl a command
that will just add the by beer over here
but because this is node typically you
can take input in another format any
suggestions
JSON everybody loves JSON in JavaScript
you know it's so native it's so easy to
work and super trivial to to to add so
we can do the same thing and again just
sort of sparing myself some typing here
you can do the same thing using JSON
just a little bit here and it's the same
thing right I'm just gonna say fix the
bike run this going here fix the bike
right nothing all that spectacular but
because this is Jason I can do another
type of manipulation here it is so Jason
I can do this which is just another
string right if I just do this then I'll
just get an 800 here
but in Jason it actually typically gets
translated to a JavaScript object so if
I remove the quotes the inferring of the
type would happen as part of the the
processor and the parsing of the object
so if I do this
suddenly what I've passed is an integer
or not a string and if I call this and
this is just for convenience where I go
back the the the note and if I go in
here I'll see a bunch of binary data and
if I do this enough times and you know
there's no telling what happens in a in
any specific set but and it was in
fairness enough time I will get again
the source code the different secrets
from the code so this is this is very
much a severe vulnerability and it
happens in very popular components and
you'd be amazed at how often they are
not updated because from from a
developer perspective there's not a lot
of conversation there's not any
conversation really about vulnerable
packages and therefore people oftentimes
some people are very upgrade biased like
they wants to use the latest and
greatest but there's a lot of also fear
of upgrade because you don't want to go
to break you want it to be deterministic
you want to know that you can deploy
this and it's the same version again
so people are oftentimes very averse to
upgrades so I'll show one more
vulnerability because that is maybe a
little bit more relevant to node and
again I switch off I think I still have
10 ish or seven minutes which is in MS
and this is maybe one of maybe the most
popular this
the most kind of recurring type of
vulnerability then we see in our system
we mark it as low severity a little bit
dubious and what it is is a regular
expression D now service anybody here
heard of redose some aware of it
awareness of it like clearly already
knows of dose of dental service and what
happens is regular expressions are we
don't think of them that way but they
are algorithms and they take a nonlinear
amount of time to process an input
string depending on the regular
expression that lack of linearity you
might be you know a very steep curve or
it might be a lighter one but it
definitely is nonlinear so it means that
every time you are running a regular
expression if you're not containing the
length of the strings that come in and
sometimes even if you are you might
actually make that thread very very busy
for a long time this is this is a
problem in every language because you
can pretty easily occupy a thread and
you can kind of get a server out of
commission but it's especially bad in
node because nodes claim to fame is that
it's event based it doesn't scale on
threads it scales on events a single
thread can process a huge number of
clients so even a massive production
application in node typically doesn't
have that many threads running and so in
this case we use MS and redose happens
just everywhere but we use a mess to say
something like you know Cole mom in two
hours and it would I understand ms is
just a little package that takes strings
like two hours and the likes and this is
a very simple regular expression to
convert those into the number of
milliseconds but that would take so you
know we we support this type of input
but what can we do is an attackers if we
anticipate or in fact we don't even need
to guess because we might have seen the
package online that it has a redox
vulnerability what we're gonna try to do
put in a lot of numbers put a very long
string so I'm just gonna sort of skip
the foreplay here and go straight to it
which is I am going to just echo a long
string here and what I've done is I've
just printed 60,000 fives because if I
did another zero then my Heroku build
would skyrocket and I also made the
string almost match the pattern because
you know the
just so much more fun to make the Rex
run longer and if I do this what happens
now is you know it takes a long time to
run and more interestingly if I go here
and a click
alright type the application is not
responsive and it didn't take much and
if this was a massive application then I
might run many of them and if this was a
service application then this would just
hike up a bill and you know clearly not
a good model so those are just four of
you know as you might imagine many many
vulnerabilities but really the point I
was saying here is these are real
vulnerabilities these are not some you
know make-believe sides you know this is
the theoretical problem that happened we
see this on real applications massive
applications of large organizations so
let's go back here a little bit so so
with that in mind I'd like to talk a
little bit oh actually you know what
that's gonna stay here still talk a
little bit about solutions so there are
several steps that you want to do when
you talk about addressing the solution
first is is kind of acknowledging you
have a problem so you want to find these
problems you can use sneak for a node
you can use that ole wasp dependency
checker you can use victims to be in
Python it's still a very new problem
there's a shortage of tooling but you
know you can kind of find the tool
that's right for your environment then
you want to fix them fixes generally
happen through upgrades like they do for
binaries and rarely you also have a
patching mechanism like you do for
automated updates like in the case of
snake we build some of these patches for
node in the case of Ruby the rails
community sometimes offers some of these
patches for rails itself so you can look
those up and a lot of this needs to
happen like I will posit that while you
need to know about this problem and you
need to understand it you don't want to
tackle it yourself you don't want the
security people to do this but as we've
sort of talking about you want the
developers to embrace this so when you
think about whatever tool might have
done we're here when you think about
whatever tool that you've chosen to
integrate you want to think about how do
you want to pull those types of fixes
those types of tests in and make them
happen continuously so again I'll kind
of show you how we do it here instinct
which as we found the issues we
fix them by submitting a fix PR so we
find that that approach in general for
whether its dependencies or other
approach is useful you submit a pull
request there's an actual change I think
Matt mentioned that as well it's now
being tracked people like closing pull
requests they don't like accumulating a
backlog of them and these have the
necessary changes to to make the changes
go away and then once you've sort of
found the issues and you have fixed the
issues and your vulnerability free you
want to talk about two continuous things
that you want to do the first is prevent
you can add tests into the the pull
request processor into your build
process to catch whenever somebody adds
a vulnerable package so you know github
allows you to do things like this like a
test in the in the pull request that
just sort of says hey you've just added
a vulnerable package or the equivalent
of that is put in the build put some
form of test action in the build so
you're catching them when they happen
and then the last step we talked about
is respond and that's be able to track
which dependencies you're using and then
track vulnerabilities against them we
have a little bit of an advantage here
because unlike the world of binaries
which is already very messy and we get a
lot of these unnecessary items here we
can try to build and focus our tools
directly to the environments and the
tools that we use again kind of in our
world we do this via these proactive fix
pr's fixed pull requests or when there's
a new vulnerability we sort of submit
one of those fix PRS and notifications
you you can build these are again
because of the loaner abilities are very
tailored to a specific environment if
you were to build automation around it
you can be proactive but only the
vulnerabilities that affect your
applications just sort of test if they
exist there so to recap
kind of stepping out of that two types
of takeaways first is maybe a little bit
more specific maybe pass on sort of the
core dev teams if they're not here which
is there are some specific things in
JavaScript that you might be able to
learn from these and from the other
vulnerabilities around how to do secure
coding I've seen various shops actually
start to use those as internal training
as a way to sort of educate their
developers around how would they what
types of mistakes might happen not be
offended by them because they happened
to really good developers on really
popular packages and see how they were
addressed in the real world
and then maybe my bigger takeaway is
that we should think about open source
packages sort of there that black is the
new pink or whatever you know OSS
package vulnerabilities in my mind are
kind of the new on patch servers as the
world especially with server lists and
platform as-a-service moves into a world
where we're trying to manage servers as
you know as little as possible unless
we're at Yelp then then the this concern
like there's a lot of acknowledgement of
the open source binary vulnerabilities
and therefore a lot of these solutions
and like ecosystem wide around how do we
tackle them but there's really no
conversation around open source packages
and I think that just would make them
the next easiest way for attackers in
it's already a pretty easy one there
there was a bit of a plug I've got a
blog post I posted just a day about
serverless security vulnerabilities
welcome to join it so I would say for
those ones similar workflow to maybe
what you're hopefully doing for binaries
you know define the issues you want to
fix the issues via updates or patches
when available you want to prevent
vulnerable package don't don't
accumulate this as a technical debt it's
an opportunity to take on a new problem
in a modern way and you want to respond
quickly to new vulnerabilities before
attackers get a chance to exploit them
and I do want to stress that while I
picked on node and at p.m. here this
happens in Ruby gems it happens in
mavens the stats and examples for every
one of the environments so that's it
open source is awesome but please enjoy
it responsibly
thank you
I have time for questions I think it was
supposed to be to 1250 so I have four
minutes it's the mic floating around
yeah I think the lack of maturity for
vulnerabilities also happens in the sort
of tracking of the vulnerability a
little bit so for us we build we have an
open source vulnerability database it's
on stereo slash Volm and it's on github
where where we kind of sniff github for
security related activities two-thirds
of the issues we inventory have no CVE
people don't understand the need to
report those so we have multiple sources
some of it is around research but a lot
of it is just tracking github activities
and recently increasingly we're starting
to get some reports from people that
have identified something unfortunately
too often after they've logged an issue
they come to tell us and get them
themselves they're also conscious of the
fact that there's no way to privately
report a security issue and they're
considering what they could do around
the platform to do those so we're sort
of talking to them about helping provide
some guidance yes yeah you can say and I
can echo it back as well so how can we
then tell if you know once you have a
particular package it has
vulnerabilities how can we tell if our
code is actually using those particular
methods do you get specific you know
information about it's this particular
usage or this particular API thing yeah
no it's just so vulnerable components
does not equal a vulnerable system and
you need to check it
I guess my thesis is that if you make
fixing easier than assessing you might
as well just get it out of the way and
to an extent that's what happens with
the binaries you don't like most of the
time you don't spend the time even
understanding what it is exactly that
came in you're just trying to stay up to
date and to an extent I think that's a
more sane approach because you can't
expect developers to have you can give
kind of that guidelines around saying
hey you want to address these
vulnerabilities when you cannot address
it sometimes using a that uses B that is
C C has a vulnerability but you have no
path like there is no
in a way that would get you to a fixed
version of C sometimes you can patch it
but if you cannot patch it you cannot
upgrade you have to have the
conversation around assessment and
clearly you should should log that you
should track that over time but in most
cases at least what we try to do is make
it so easy to fix that it's easier to
fix than it is to to to have that much
more complicated conversation about
whether your system is actually more
neural that doesn't work very well when
you have the the features themselves are
the vulnerabilities right or dangerous
functionality absolutely this is a slice
of security that deals specifically with
having vulnerable components once you
have a vulnerable component to it you
know that there are many paths to using
that that specific component and those
paths may change over time so I just
think you know with the principles of
defense-in-depth you basically would
rather just avoid having the vulnerable
component it's not going to address
design vulnerabilities right now it
doesn't yet capture insecurity faults so
there's more to do there for sure I
think it's great I think you know it
already is a massive sign of maturity in
a workflow when you can even use this
most most dev workflows cannot even
start to do great and I think that's a
big thesis as well which is like we
built and I think there's some nascent
here but I think the way to approach is
to think about how would you build the
developer tooling set that would that
would help address this problem is
opposed to how do you build an audit
tool someone who wrote a security like I
static analysis tool that ran in the IDE
and was called applicant developer
edition and it was not it was an
auditing solution that was very sort of
InfoSec Orient's it was a great tool but
it was not the developer tool in terms
of workflow so you know personally like
that snake we were trying to sort of
build it from that mentality and I think
anything you build homebrew you should
start from the developer methodology and
and figure out how do you fit into that
versus you know like Elizabeth was also
mention about earlier on other questions
oh so I'll be here I'll let you go for
much thank you