media
maxine while I had
no look better we thought the problem
some I'm sensational you see you in New
Zealand
resort yeah is good some bad
a liz has action so
very much my pleasure issues
from us
hey welcome everybody you talking about
I will talk about
day a.m. which is the year design
me the wrong the making from talking
more accessible
is on bottom anything over
yet I think that number did and the
I'm also going to be quite often all
coat
across the province computing
environment which is life more
interesting
that focusing on job for
so and remain for me know
they know is because our company it is
the offering enchanting from 212 orange
and to as special and I'll
for within your web browser there's a
number from
to of rent an effort to talk orange up
none of them actually a involves ever
course they're called human more
integration
native up just purely probably after
and you currently have a user
stories about had about think about that
and over changes
rod so
NJ interaction and pretty much sensual
if you want to have terms of heart
basically I you know
for both stories a.m. the user provide
of dokie and No %um
or plain text ever exciting anywhere
outside
communication and point and ignition
point is always
you were necessary condition Michael
through but to is assumed to be true and
the the fact that surviving person is
not an awesome
illustrated by any issued of
a in 2011 where after software update
and their of Education checking
Road and or of our gridlock
any problem how anymore and
to involve a horrible reached or
director region all
for to a crawl which would not have
happened
had use and incursion and another
topic that is becoming an issue the fact
that
government are getting very interested
in the
sport daughter from card provider
and it's very easy for government just
for
retrieved and mom all while or
bro so that's another reason why in
Jennifer's
is pretty much essential these days so
the difference between end-to-end
encryption and a
surviving fraction is a fourth that
encryption
both in a I'm no
bridge all daughter when the incall
reach the unit
1 p.m. law any carmen hart
by into the persian ones anything useful
and surviving fraction there's something
to
you can always just going to anyone Hall
if you want compromise and a car all
an entertaining for up to 12 hours
provider what happens then
well as old to be fine which is
in to you always detectable whether it
is happening in fact
other matter but the you you could not
do so without
user be able UK the quite
more a as we all know in person but
use or up use a horse
example GP was up twenty your has still
not really gone mainstream
outside take Muni and airports
special to lower barrier to entry and
10 you or pretty much only way to do so
and home for par bro just open the
the URL because I heard and uses
without and install or any have all
abroad
result problem majority users
not using it a
nevertheless for some reason the the
choice all using javascript proto has
stirred up by the
motion adjuster causing
read thing and a delegation
JavaScript is a terrible idea
someone said then on the for
well republicans of that's bad use ours
for those better than I thought things
are or or
that on earth public you tried
all hyper other or there's no security
implications
or on are or this particular on
or on more said
on occasion Davi as don't are or and
the chocolate generating random numbers
job somewhere propecia problem
reno or for the 312 illustrated
what are you emotionally-charged talking
proponent of
is and at the reason why I would like to
know
preservation today and with a number of
alternative
a confers Java aretha
security issues after the more takeover
I would not advise anyone to run Java
the versions and there are over flash
a.m. having more whole
and by a factor of about 10 or 20 lower
at today's of saw so like that
and ActiveX thing don't want to use a
cross-platform
apartment either so Jonathan on her
rollers and or officially completely
and now features compression strong
right number generator a auto cold that
a that is up to in part by
you have provided any a report
is able to reblogged of ed right profile
but if required are home problem as haha
but and of and with the upcoming Hoffman
like from 20 and yes he will be looking
at
says phones but today you can usually
improve thing about yes
and job your development of
performance a all the various platforms
by investing
last on market faster job tonight yen
just start last in 2011
however today is actually quite of Raja
lineup today and Safari the whole
a prop when the offer makes of course
are or pretty good and problem pro
the year development in that regard v8
engines
read the basic you dream job performance
level American action today yeah he's
actually
I 10 and 11 are actual of problems
are also from
and you expect upon crypto on
make ish so question
it's far you can do it up is your
is the desired problems of and the
when you look at the you apparently no
major 0
actually quite interested if you have
Road home you will probably haunt of
than they did because poco in a
proffered ten-member the winning
think the main at the security office
occasion
well-made only don't wanna that of and
when your entire
farm system you Perth later
if you have fucking home then there's
both
again very lonely front of both
the old potentially high good have a
horrible thing
poison to love you and again
your tire machine put your your car
jeopardized however a compromise 0
job termination old are believe
completely compromised both or a.m.
10 interfere with the operation of Java
when she was breached
and an interview with the operation or
nations reach
and it makes no difference whether you
inflict compromise
intentionally your cell or you
installed 3.0 from the mall source
are pro run high environment not only
have evolved Nov fermentation of
unfortunately many of these about of
breakout
X hold on machine fell
which means the Java
sandboxing did not mean for and we have
a lot of
same origin policy regions as well 15
interview with another site
to a.m. and very
ish and interesting and rather topic is
prospecting where the users/suppliers
content and the confidence intervals
pose
fortune you proper manners interviews
call hochberg policy as you have
your application problems separated old
and
on them and you have to be probably
about
policy hold of run grave
of suffering caused
and the jobs but also provides a better
separation between unrelated up
on the crosstalk then they'd only you
don't run it in virtual machines or
differences are a.m.
crosstalk tight-knit hair on paramount
from her is more you read issue so
I have not seen any working further a
and more tomorrow
ATI's that I'm for permission from jobs
that it is a bond for example
if you're concerned about your you
ending up on her pagey
pile then you might on his job because
there's no API
block three-month in memory but again if
you
for hibernate use head
to death and even those law eighties
course made you are that no big
difference
the biggest issue with Java is actually
about only JavaScript
in for delivery pay you actually trial
the whole that's what about Bob with
major phone
we have on Windows and Mac OS other mark
for
a build and protect check it's called
cosigning and you can obtain birth
certificates from
better also offer SSL Certificates that
baby
because are better are potentially
subject to national
leonard and in my heart as applying
fourth
make people look like it's your unreeled
its law
on all the platforms you usually involve
your fav or chrome
independently for fun or which
I don't know how resilient from home
redhead
you to a request from the US government
some stuff
into their repository or
better apart or oh and 21 on hark.com
with that have a passion hopefully
published independent channel
that hopefully verified and
also nato's and belong and
than Ron well Java unfortunately
is a not take checked and it
know it and refreshed on every time you
know the website
there many more opportunities although
the initial install much suffers from
some other
trust issues there's many more
opportunities more website operated
power from Joe on times
that overly provider
made old inflation on
partly install separate verified
hash we have progress on
updated in a made hold-ups becoming more
popular
both benefit because Yuki 15
love you original programmer but long
arrest because both those program
special open-ended
stay might use up to to
election so in conclusion
if you want to to the permissions hose
sp1 delivered
for are you're better off with jobs
you we have a significant this involves
you end up and a.m. there's some
indication
mechanism and the install robbed
still don't have Paul F
machine but they are the that holding
job locally don't have loan from her
every time
side and you can progress sign me up
for this brings us back to for sign
auto updates aerial aidid that or
we are awesome option if you want to
inject malicious old their very better
or source you can do so
by poor religions or the original
programming 5
row or or low then that you
point for you always dead total you can
just packed or compromise web server
is holding the Java or combining
you can use the network management a
already
yes everybody's you today you again
forms izetbegovic you government
and on hover marie's your connection
summer
user her and or name server:
which awesome possum government if you
want to
many things up easy a horse as no
mechanisms of problems that would
has jobs rejected as for long
mutated is changes
an issue want to meet a difficult as a
reformers fine the native over par
support
difficult and present place the improved
source and the you have you
separate published and many verified her
than your for
the September a compromise a
course the to them look at the half
compared
that it's not happening so
the problem of home-and-home
trustworthiness in general
help you growth biochemical and
fortunately if you want to move on for
example when does
just a single run updated bed
a lot of leftovers and therefore
practical
and the is one behind backdoor
then you here your about
jobs although you are program problem
hi back for jobs as well just think
about every overrun
and think that on community
semen hair to the untrained eye and of
course you the fact that most
home run today never objected all
and auto we have to rely upon
rock crock
and the such as a music fan of
via across hardcore things for example
on me we trust aren't enough people
on more to play again we line
of people that we don't know if you want
an operating system
we talk Largo around Marvel for
among the homeless more than a thong
over on Windows
there's more than two I'll work on of it
would be more
makeup I development old
a.m. so is it better to have a lot of
people that many
change other open mic problem proper of
to to independently verify and take it
from there
43 but you know that and
or trust to make of questionable
a
0 another issue with fast that
even the most prosperous service
provider of software vendor
might be subject to government action
that fourth
and relinquished
the hundred-page the head and for
built back doors and old Hollywood
on my import and
again effect infected autos & Co is a
pretty much necessary part and
undermine trust are with minors
every month re naw Hall so
and every Windows RT is a collector for
the are
350 don't know any case where commercial
for a better
youth the on up there to actually Trojan
a user a upon request are
or or agency but this from
and he does because Mike run flesh or
here and there's free from the original
with fourth you here
but still complex if you want to
audiences or
hold of me a nontrivial of approaching
was bed significant I'm a.m.
may have of is open for up in a
five-hole
you want to have a look at it so and
might have about our running so
incentivize people
to long and on fine back to earth at
some or Mahal ho
other nobody was home or month there
and I just everybody over
program and fully on it 100 and from
there on all updates all
by number independent reviewer your
chest area
fining yet rose session that I talked
about only
except the update or you made only
accept an update
and their third threshold met all
your signature and the abortion
I don't know any your world occasion
desire
and of home by a hermit our involved
of often told just or
own on home that basis redid
as a vision I would say that
said of and has a two-fold is actually
better job
better indeed a accessibility for
so if you run your mind in a separate
sample
and to you don't need a special
privileges and you have you look at the
half and
masthead and only really attack record
that one go undetected 2011 already
in action regional programmer
implementing something that
or fourth something the very very
the preferred unfortunately does not
bend
so to in the village if you have to
first are concerned of
on a life-changing has of
that tomorrow should or
JavaScript is better than of
of God because it provides parent that
bomb
through the browser therefore have
missed own I'll
your machine just him so rigid
playing to provide for them the next
ever made
of run old machine on the run very old
bro
from E on institution problem your day
does and tomorrow jonathan Aitken
called a home similar products so
whether you have for
hold off buying more you have a
or Java you still want after Austin
to you for running so there's no real
difference
on other than the fact that jobs problem
years all but heart so and
of complex a draws a heart attack chain
there is
a shortcoming about them a
roth offering such believe made other
with a typical or
at least some have then published on
severed Weather Channel or even better
from abroad awesome that is not me tight
the internet for example printed
newspapers
and then just compared he had today he
vision are other much for that
up overall pictures makes
a.m. we see in the JavaScript is not as
bad as some think it'd
for but I heard
and still a lot of harm to entrust
bar through partying
program made okay that
the situation any question yes we store
has all
follow opponent ho encryption and heard
a few friends
generally only filed have
several independent from for conversions
are
files up by in bed every his
but anything longer at very much in love
or is it possible that the same file
same you
Hector uphold or to hold a
coincidentally file different of
anchor different and other Paul but
those are by
art more for life file well
defective the shortfall are usually
mock very mission-critical and longer
part of someone like
to combine that uses
sufficient have I hope Ruth so
a one like fun power a horrifying to
the collision president number that up
we a at half past your iPhone running
only hope that a lot of people want
have onerous course pro room
old each other old but don't have a
formal
in and external from a commercial lender
a we might actually that
your challenge the community and the
phone by the number of
the gonna miss you issues
at work very quickly at there was no
sign of any
party back door and as far as I know
or program head
so and a hollow you don't have all a
the mall parth
from service providers we strongly
believe that doesn't lock
or or K and it doesn't knock
for made a hole in the government to
or coupon that part to
form X objected and of ago
for in order to prevent
prediction from here or you
we have a any 50 million from
third-party home
up quietly %um and yes that
if there was any 3G Shindo that we've
already have
for but a.m. as in the initial airing
for comprehensive ok you have to
and who all Park on FB
as a field trip like orgy you your all
these other
on you also the that
or that Iran the Jonah on
in theory of up to be subtitulado star
the BIOS the computer those on the
operating system
browser or any other for others running
on them me
and for the Wii paranoid a
you and digital machine should be from
because there have been some spared
Intel a bag of chips which i think is
low-level my hope up from no
invent number generator of cultures my
we
art you don't know no
we'd only third-party on RRT you
whole apartment or finder
company invested for anyway but remember
comment
homes and those are some like
%um I'll you home there's nothing to bed
if you have
up in the morning there there's an
update home
and then the is your
service paranoid compared you have was
independent channel does interviews
those
you there bed
that's exactly the problem
if you have a user looked for example
did
between and all the new version play it
by change the on of
make said as old what happened
independent on doesn't look at it every
time you have
and that basic some channels yeah
I don't over your head you don't guide
you have from he struck me or from
but have fine saw and yet
for their where browser extension you
an update once there's a minimum number
of final
by independent auditors that one amended
I from there %um and
know about what happened for their
afternoon
good
head no
the government up
that government not use of
a you have use have particular on their
call
some think about everything video and
they will send it off
say look this file author on hobbled by
the website
do you have any user I'll same I'll
we couldn't tell other or and whole
corruption
I'm follow corruption and would have to
know
you know crypto bed user
at went up on that popped the hood
forever the only the encroachment father
more don't ever or at
line 53 I'll up
cranny order of greg has there's no
a way for us to check whether the hash
get
event but if I'm is actually you love
her so we don't do it
yes on take has for on our own server
for unification for and you factors that
the government fine makeup with he
attacked that's a different story that
weekend
fourth tell government very or
with you up but they're different wrong
his wife moving base on about and very
low
at want to buy it to the power info
100 I'm outside haha
one problem what happened within for
by time forever
unification other you have and you take
young there's all a
at someone more to follow there all and
there's no physical
up having on the server for membership
so there is
unification up
'em 3 yet so
you have you know the power so if you
have a very large file
a declared 5 and yes Mahal
however I don't know the eventually fell
of by then file what a
X or or been jobs issue
or no longer I'm
it's a very long %uh about while very
or my up
0 you are commenting bat actually hat
a
up
greater up
yes up don't or part
if you do so for Pepe
should mo
we don't want that a.m. don't know
follow
structure whether with yeah adversely
affected by at
mode I'll are
moments values but the don't want to end
up
at this point about unit of blood
reviews are hard saying
the top
in
yep
free follow actual originally at about
Brenda data and then
incur all day and would no
of all up for at all
your
hi yet
we have no
party of course you have
inhofe from prop another
you mentor ahora you there
quite a bit of people humour are you up
just community more yard by and
offer their own implementation by
tomorrow
okay and we have of course any move
find any mention of those on the website
use them at your own risk like
run cold you probably never
to be a backup as yours
ducks brand as well
from I hope you guys enjoyed everything
was important here
miss you guys see you later math
their back to deal with jobs
like this alright
comics come away