hi everyone and welcome to creating
network effects
intelligence sharing for supply chain
security my name is andrea little
lombago
i'm the vice president of research and
analysis at enteros and i'm thrilled to
be here at the threat intelligence
practitioner summit at virus bolton
today what we'll be talking about
is the essential role that intelligence
sharing can play for supply chain
security across your entire ecosystem
now before getting into this role of
intelligence sharing it's really
important to first understand
just how complex supply chains have
become and how fragile
and insecure they become to then
highlight just the how foundational
intelligence sharing is for supply chain
security
and so i'd first like to focus on is
that within global brands
it's not just a few suppliers that they
may have it's tens of thousands
or even hundreds of thousands of
suppliers
and so when you think about gaining
visibility and threat intelligence
sharing
if you have hundreds of thousands of
suppliers it becomes very very hard to
understand
who all those partners are within your
network and what their levels of
security are
so it really does broaden the attack
surface in ways
really an unprecedent from previous eras
so how did we get to this point and so
let's quickly walk through how we got to
the
area where supply chains can have
hundreds of thousands of partners
because that
really does just seem overwhelming in
numbers and so it all goes back you
in post-world war ii era look at the 50s
and 60s the advent of computers and
containerization
warehouse management that really helped
to expand
supply and and trade practices across
the globe
and so that continued at a decent pace
but really took off in the 80s and 90s
when the end of the cold war started to
spark a shift towards manufacturing in
asia
and really importantly the japanese
model of lean production took off
and why that's so important because it
really highlighted and focused on this
role of
optimization and so what that means is
really doing just in time production so
that
the production within the warehouses was
only stuck
stocked enough to have whatever was
needed in the very near future
and as we've seen over the last few
months that's part of the reason why
we've had such extensive
disruptions across supply chains not the
only reason but it helps contribute to
it
so during all those technological and
geopolitical shifts that were going on
the beginning of 2000 as the internet
took off and as china became a member of
the wto
we saw again this enormous
transformation in the
shifting of the world system at the same
time as the drivers of technology
leading to a doubling of global trade
during this time period
and so it's really the height of global
interdependence and trade going on
during this time
and then really over the last decade yet
again technology plays a very big role
in the expansion of globalization and
global trade
with internet of things big data
analytics production automation and so
forth
and this automation continued and so
while technology took off
we also saw china's role as the world
supplier
and really the a huge concentration
component
of trade going in and out of china
really to a point that it was such a
focal node
that hadn't been in existence before
across the supply chains
and so we got to this point where really
interconnected
very complex with hundreds of thousands
of suppliers
and then at the same time this
concentration within china
and this just-in-time automation led to
an environment
where when kobe came along earlier this
year the global pandemic
just really shook the foundations of
that system
so you look at the graphs of the trade a
global trade fell
at a record level and so there are many
records that have been broken on the
trade and economic front over this past
year in addition to the
horrific human toll that is the pandemic
has caused
on the in the area of supply chain
that's global supply disruption of trade
really just disrupted all the supply
chains as well we see trade falling for
u.s
uh in china as well you can see a little
bit on the
on the graph where the trade war already
started to see a decline in trade
between the two countries
but it still continues to uh decline
since the beginning of covet and so
there are all these trends that were
already
accelerate that were already existing
prior to the pandemic that are now
accelerated including the geopolitical
tensions going on
and a distrust of trade between two of
the major powers across the global
system
and so we're at a point with just
enormous supply chain fragility
they were extraordinarily complex that
again gets to the
thousands tens of thousands hundreds of
thousands of pliers all across and
if you look at that i think that graph
is actually a nice uh
visualization because that really is
what it looks like when you start to map
out all the different suppliers
super super complex super integr uh
related integrated
um just leading to basically just uh
very complex supply chain systems that
then become
very opaque because it's really hard to
gain visibility across
all of your partners across that entire
supply chain and so there might be
vulnerabilities in there but they're
masked because you can't see them
so in addition to that we also have the
concentration risk so these bottlenecks
in china
that we highlighted in the previous
slide just increases concentration risk
and it's not just a geographical
concentration risk
it's also a risk that can occur from
uh focus on a specific vendor if there's
a concentration risk there
but also on the geography and in certain
products and so any kind of
over reliance and over concentration
within a supply chain does in turn make
it fragile
and in addition to geopolitical tensions
we see the floods in china also cause
major disruption across supply chains
and finally in india perhaps most
related all of these together combine to
create just enormous insecurity
across supply chain ecosystems
and that's really what we'll be focusing
on is just this complexity
this limited visibility also helping
highlight the ip theft and cyber
vulnerabilities and
even the legal risks that can emerge and
so as globalization has taken off
as we've seen the supply chains become
extraordinarily interdependent
and opaque you see the concentrations
risk going and you see this
globalization getting really disrupted
during
uh prior to covet and then it's really
uh accelerated
after it and along with all that came
along these these security risks
both by having an over concentration in
certain countries that may mandate
access that's where the legal risk comes
in they there are certain governments
that mandate access to data if your data
is stored in those countries so that's
some data localization laws
so just a whole range of risks are
starting to emerge into super insecurity
across the entire
supply chain ecosystem
and so it's no surprise given everything
that has walked through the
the complexity the opacity the
concentration resistance and security
should be no surprise that supply chain
attacks continue to be on the rise
and so just for a little a few data
points to help highlight that
uh according to one study your supply
chain attacks increased 78
in 2019 and so clearly that's just an
enormous jump from from previous years
at the same time we're seeing 60 of data
breaches that are linked to third-party
vendors
uh also increasing so again when we
think about
the role of third party risk management
very often you see
focus on your immediate partners but not
necessarily your partner's partners and
so forth but
with this integration and their
dependencies go across the supply chain
that's where you start seeing additional
so it's not surprised to see some of
these big jumps given that foundation
that we laid out as far as the
how supply chains actually work together
and how just interrelated and complex
they are
so we're also seeing a thousand percent
increase in financial crimes linked to
third parties and that's just
a staggering increase and then next-gen
supply chain tax
just more advanced supply chains
especially going in through apps and
different kinds of
updates which we'll talk about you know
surging 430
so these are all different studies but
at the end of the day they all highlight
very very similar trends
that supply chain attacks are on the
rise
and it's to the point that earlier this
year the fbi issued a notification
focused on cyber supply chain campaigns
that are targeting certain industries in
this case it's targeting the health care
sector
and so this is something that we'll see
again again throughout this talk is that
very often these supply chain attacks
are targeting certain industries
and so that can help highlight just how
much there needs to be that information
sharing intelligence sharing
both across industries and then within
your supply chain as well
now let's first focus on physical supply
chains because
for the most part when you think about
supply chains i think people get in
their mind
uh just you know they've got views of
ports and warehouses
and various kinds of logistics and
certainly that's the foundation to it
all
but we don't really think about how
those different ports of entry can also
become
point points of entry uh for supply
chain attacks
and so suppliers and partners are very
increasingly the point of entry into
your network and so uh in the past we've
talked about unfortunately target seems
to be the name that always pops up for
these kind of
uh third-party uh risk and access
when one of their hvac contractors uh
access to that network then became an
access to the network of target but they
are by no means alone and that that's
something to really
uh you know highlight or illuminate
because if you look at the
stats i showed on the previous screen
you know it's increasingly common
the f-35 similarly you know it wasn't
the
the main um supplier it was it was a
supplier
and a contractor you know of a major
corporation that was the one that ended
up
uh becoming the access into it and so as
organizations especially as these big
you know fortune 500 global brands as
they become better and better defending
themselves
what you see is that attackers work to
look to the weakest link and that
weakest link may be your initial partner
but due to the supply chains and just
how broad and
expansive they are it might be your
supplier suppliers or their suppliers it
really can go on
and while all that's going on for the
most part suppliers are really viewed
though as trusted networks and so
they're not
always brought in when thinking about
third party risk management because if
it's a trusted partner why do you need
to defend against it
and so that perception needs to change
they still can be trusted as far as
having a partnership
we need to think about what they're
doing for their security uh and how that
may impact you as well
and how it may impact the broader
ecosystem
now there also are really the focus on
digital supply trainers and digital
supply chains
attacks can manifest themselves in
numerous ways it could be along the
lines of installing a
malicious hardware software for back
door access and control
and so if you think about the cleaner
attack from a few years ago
is a really good case in point so what
happened during that point
during that attack uh was that a
legitimate software
update the ccleaner legitimate software
the update within it
was injected with malware and so at the
at the peak of that 2.25
million downloads of the software of the
update
the corrupted update uh was downloaded
so that's extensive that's
millions of uh of computers are impacted
by it
but only one well over one and a half
million of those phoned home
and of those it turned out that 40
organizations were targeted
and so i think it's a really good
example of how even for very targeted
attacks
others may get caught within the they
get caught within it and download some
of the corrupt
files because they're part of that that
ecosystem and they're able to get in and
that's that's sort of the backdoor
attack the installation of malicious
hardware and so
even for very targeted attacks others
can become
collateral damage within that and so
that's one way you also can think about
the installation of
counterfeit hardware or software again
that impacts trust
you could be relying on a malicious or
unqualified service provider
it's another way for digital supply
chain attack to happen and sometimes it
can be unintentional uh with
unintentional hardware software
vulnerabilities
and this is something that we see
increasingly with misconfigured clouds
where
it could be one of your partners exposes
your data because they misconfigure
their own cloud and so it may not be
uh something that is in your control it
may not be
uh something that's intentional and that
may not be a malicious intent but it
does
happen it can impact the security of
your of your data
and so one more example of the malicious
hardware software providing that
backdoor is dragonfly 2.0
again very you know recent attack where
trojan software was in the updates very
similar with you know to see cleaner as
far as the focus on the updates
uh leveraging phishing emails again
major uh
you know it remains a major point of
entry uh this one focused on targeting
the energy sector
so again again we see the the sector
component becomes very very important
which is
again why within supply chains why that
communication across
your industry but really within across
your suppliers becomes really really
important
now i like this because it's a good
example of how intelligence is really
just growing importance
as the globe is going through so many
shifts and so as i i've
alluded to you know with the supply
chain disruptions of the last six months
that's going on at the same time as all
these geopolitical shifts that are going
on
and so more and more organizations are
rethinking what does it mean to
to have security uh within you know
going forward within a trusted network
you know what does that look like within
a re-globalized world and so this was a
really uh interesting op-ed that focused
on the imports of maritime
so kind of going back and focusing on
what we really you traditionally think
about when we think about supply chains
and and within those areas this is a
necessity for information sharing
uh across the community is really
becoming highlighted as foundational for
security
and for situational awareness across the
entire operations
and so even within these broad logistics
chains and so forth
the role of information sharing just
remains foundational
uh to that it's for situational
awareness and to
bring together all those diverse data
sets together so that everyone within
the ecosystem everyone who's partnering
working together
from then it's across the carriers and
the equipment and so forth
uh provide and to yield greater insights
and to be able to proactively identify
vulnerabilities before
they get exploited
and this is i think just gets back to
the overarching theme of supply chain
attacks this is a recent
wall street journal op-ed that i highly
recommend that focuses on
the role of sharing information across
supply chains and it's a substantial
investment
in securing customer data at one company
can easily be undermined
by a supplier with weak financial
incentives for safeguards
now what that really highlights is you
know it gets back to that weakest link
and so you know i think very often we
hear the human is the weakest link in
cyber security and that's you know
perhaps one of my pet feeds i i hate
focusing on that because human elements
are
are part of it take that notion
of the weakness link and look at you
know the weakest link tends to be that
that we can slink within the chain of
your of your
of your supply chain and which company
has the weakest security
could then come back and and haunt you
as well and lead to your own insecurity
and so
there needs to be incentives to help
encourage across your supply chain
greater collaboration for information
sharing and we'll talk about that in a
bit
and so when thinking about information
sharing you clearly need to know
who is in your network and so that's one
of the first steps is really identifying
what is in your network
and fortunately standardized information
sharing can help
and so currently with such complexity
and opacity within supply chains
really what we're seeing is that there
isn't that visibility you know for the
most part it doesn't exist
and for even places where there is
pretty good visibility uh as we've seen
your supply chains are really changing
quite a bit right now and so
even if you think you have a good idea
of what your supply chain looks like now
you know a month from now two months
from now it may not do to either you
know bankruptcies shifting suppliers and
so forth the disruptions are having a
ripple effect throughout
and so you need to continuously have
that visibility across your supply chain
and that's exactly where information
sharing can help to you know to enable
that continuous monitoring
to figure out how some of the companies
are shifting across your supply chain
and you have a good gaze on who and who
the partners are so then from there you
can start focusing on security but
you can't really think about getting the
security unless you know who's in your
network
and to figure out who's your network
that's worth a lot of standardized
information sharing
and sharing of some of the threat
intelligence even can help figure out
and help build out
that situational awareness of what your
ecosystem even looks like
and so the first thing you obviously
when you've got that visibility
next you need to ensure that there's the
fundamentals flow across your entire
supply chain ecosystem
and so don't just have a visibility
visibility for visibility's sake
start then from there start sharing
information
sharing intelligence to figure out uh
where some of those weakest links are
and then to help work as a community
to help build them build the incentives
and that's where also as you're starting
to think about different partners
across your supply chain you know those
with greater security you know
leverage that up as a higher priority
for who can make it within your own
ecosystem and so it becomes very very
important to have that kind of
visibility and ensure that their
security and the standards are up
across the system
and so once you've got that you've got
your visibility you're starting to talk
about the security levels and sharing
intelligence
all that together combines to help build
this trusted system of systems and so
you know as we saw with the example of
the ports you know as far as gaining
situational awareness and gaining
better visibility of the vulnerabilities
and the threats and various processes
that are going on
a company that's only focused on their
own data doesn't have that complete
situational awareness and i think this
is probably a theme that we're going to
hear throughout
the threat intelligence practitioner
summit diverse data sets coming together
mean better threat intelligence
for everyone involved and so the
essential component of this though
has to be bidirectional and we've seen
over and over again that
information sharing intelligence theory
and sharing when only goes in one
direction
it doesn't build up the trust and then
in fact it can be detrimental because
it can lead to distress because if one
company is sharing all their information
and gets nothing in return they no
longer are incentivized and so the
incentives need to be
in such a way that both companies are
both entities uh feel like they're
benefiting from sharing that data so
that's where that trust comes in
by having bi-directional uh information
sharing where both entities feel like
they're benefiting from it
it creates that trust and that trust
then can permeate throughout your system
so you get a system of systems across
the entire network
of your supply chain
so when we've got to that point it takes
a trusted network you know what does
that really mean and
this is starting to take on even a
higher higher priority
as we start hearing this you know even
in headlines about uh countries across
the globe are starting to figure out
which technologies to allow within their
within their uh both
the government systems but then also
mandating what
any kind of contractors suppliers can
use based on this notion of trust
and so why is that so i highlighted
earlier
this notion of the the re-globalization
of the world and
the shifting geopolitics is shifting
supply chains
all of that again is just accelerating
right now and we're seeing you know
that the fracturing of the internet uh
that you know our radio was going on a
little bit as we started seeing some of
those data localization laws that i that
i've talked about
but what we're seeing is not just in the
policies and laws it's also in the
technologies
and so it's really that splintering of
the internet is also a splintering uh
across hardware as well and creating
these techno spheres of influence
where the home country of some of these
companies becomes
really really important uh because of
some of these digital supply chain risks
that
i talked about earlier and linking them
back to government actions
and so basically whether those
technologies can be used as a trojan
horse for access to certain data
and so because of that because there's
all this lack of trust going on across
the countries because of
you know in sync with the what we've
been seeing on the geopolitical tensions
and as well as the supply chain
disruptions and digital digital supply
chain attacks that are going on
in turn democratic governments across
the globe
are really stepping up and creating some
legislation
that both regulates what tech is allowed
within the system
but also the security controls across
the supply chains and that's why this
matters so often
when we think about the trust issue what
we're hearing more so is a focus
on just within one company that's
expanding into the supply chain networks
because
because of this uh growing trend of
digital supply chain and physical supply
chain attacks really those two can't be
uh disconnected anymore there's so much
intertwined between the physical and the
digital
and so in the us what we see is uh this
year and trusted communication networks
act
we're seeing that the federal
acquisition supply chain security act
and that one
specifically has an information sharing
component it highlights who has the
responsibility for information sharing
and ensuring
there's threat intelligence sharing
really across the entire supply chain
ecosystem
and so this notion of trust is so
foundational and so reliant on intel
sharing across companies and across our
supply chain ecosystem
we're seeing it in the new strategy from
uh dhs on 5g
with a focus on expanding situational
awareness of supply chain risks
and a major way of doing that is through
information sharing intelligence sharing
so hopefully
by now you're seeing this trend where
intelligence sharing information sharing
helps provide that situational awareness
across the supply chains which is one of
the biggest areas where we're seeing
heightened risk and heightened
vulnerabilities
to further address this uh we're seeing
the task force uh have evolved
and started to emerge to address uh
again these exact same kind of risks and
to then further figure out different
ways that the private sector and public
sector can work together better
again to get some of that bi-directional
information sharing
so it becomes very very important a
whole component of it does focus on
information sharing
and then there's the standards the cyber
security maturity model
certification the cmnmc has now gone to
effect
and so along with that what you're
seeing is that those standards the
hygiene that i showed earlier
companies are increasingly to work with
the government need to have that cmmc
compliance to work within and so i
imagine you're going forward
organizations may be looking more and
more at the cmmc and sort of that proof
of the seal of approval for certain
security standards
within their ecosystem so these are just
a few of them there's a section 889 of
the national defensive authorization act
that prohibits her and um private
certain companies from being within the
supply chain for the federal government
both those you know strongly linked to
china five chinese companies and their
affiliates and so we're just seeing more
and more of this legislation coming to
play
mandating both who can be in your supply
chain
how to share information across your
supply chain and what are the security
standards that also are there
to help improve the security again
across your entire supply chain
and your supply ecosystem
and while right now vivid is focused on
some of those standards
and the technologies it impacts really
every aspect of
hardware and software we're already
seeing different laws and
uh regulations coming out that are
mandating what app stores are allowed
which apps are even allowed uh you know
in india
recently banned over 100 different
chinese-based apps so
this is something that we're going to
keep seeing more and more
uh mandating cloud-based services which
ones are allowed and which ones are not
the same for carriers and you know at
some point make it to the point of
understanding cables which ones might be
uh allowed to be used or which one's not
so all this gets into
what you know the focus on having
trusted networks
and ensuring that there are trusted
networks within your supply chain
it's really going to permeate throughout
uh and
legislation and regulations are just
going to continue coming i mean i think
it's one of the most
uh dynamic regulatory and compliance
landscapes that we have seen in really
quite some time
and a lot of it is because of this
growing trend that we've been seeing on
the digital supply chain tax
uh you know laws has been us focused but
i really really want to highlight
it's more than the us many democracies
are very concerned
uh about technology and software coming
from china
but also just ensuring that uh they they
have their own
uh national champions as well in certain
areas and so it's really an interesting
distinction that's starting to emerge in
australia there's a really great report
on supply chains and cyber security so
i'd recommend reading that from aspi
and the focus again is on greater data
security across that supply chain
um what are the what are some standards
for sharing what are some for securing
that data and they
walk through a lot of that that
hopefully can help influence
other democracies as they start thinking
about progressing and prioritizing this
kind of security
in the uk i really like this quote from
the ncsc
do as much as you possibly can to work
with your suppliers supply chain and
partners to help them improve their
security
and foundational to that is ensuring
that everyone has situational awareness
through that information sharing through
that intelligence sharing that becomes
very very important
then finally you know uh from constant
tab when we have three information it's
worse to have it
and not use it than it is to have it not
have it so really
if you have information and intelligence
and you're not sharing it that's even
worse
and we know that's happening and this
this one quote really highlights very
strongly
just that role of bi-directional you
know in the in the role of trust
if entities aren't trusting one another
to be sharing that information they're
not going to share it
and so it's an acknowledged challenge
and problem um
definitely building out that trust is
requires
all sorts it's not a technology problem
you can fix a lot of that certainly
there are aspects of the technology that
helps fix it and ensuring that those
foundation that that cyber hygiene is in
place to secure that data
but overcoming that the trust issue is
really something that uh
you know the task force and other forms
of legislation are really trying to
shift the incentives
to ensure that there is a bidirectional
data sharing aspect of it
to help increase the situational
awareness both for companies
as independent companies but also
acknowledging just the interdependencies
and the integration across the entire
supply chain
and so i think we're moving a direction
where the problem has been identified
still plenty of emphasis on the tech
solutions which is great but i think
we're getting to the point where
really focusing on some of the
organizational issues as well to help
address it
and so to wrap up really the forces
are aligning that are prioritizing
greater security across your supply
chain
so in the beginning we talked about the
increasing attacks and how those attacks
are starting to emerge
because of this expansion of the
complexity the lack of visibility that
massing these vulnerabilities the you
know the
thousand-fold increase in some of these
attacks all that's going on across the
entire supply chain ecosystem
at the same time as geopolitics and just
a shifting global environment
are leading to greater focus on new
regulations and compliance
to ensure there's trusted software and
trusted security
uh standards going on within your
company and across your entire supply
chain
and so whether it's focusing on the
attacks whether it's focusing on the
supply chain compliance and regulations
that are coming
both are coming together to really
highlight the heightened role for
intelligence sharing and supply chain
risk management
so i'm i'm hopeful that this focus will
continue
but what we really need to see is that
there's more focusing within our
community to highlight how can we
increase information sharing
and intelligence across the entire
supply chain and
look at different ways not just across
new industries but also think about
these ecosystems to have
and benefit from those network effects
and so just you know a quick way to look
at how you do it you can gain the
visibility
ensure those access controls are going
on securely share that intelligence and
it becomes a virtuous cycle
you know very often right now there's no
visibility which means you can't verify
any security
and there's in some cases very minimal
uh
intelligence sharing across supply
chains so if we can change all that you
benefit from the network effects and
everyone can you know raise up everyone
and make them more secure
and have more timely and insightful
early warning of vulnerabilities and
attacks
in order to defend against them and so i
want to leave off with a
a quote from uh winning ather when
talking about threat intelligence
sharing
so it used to be that that defender had
to be right all the time an attacker
only had to be right once we hear this
all the time
but if you have information sharing
especially across the supply chain
now the attacker has to be silent all
the time the defender only has to spot
it once
if someone with any ecosystem spots it
they can share that information
and they can all as a community help
stop it and so
the benefit can go to the defender so i
think it's a great quote i think it's a
point of optimism to end on uh and if we
can all you know work together across
the community
across your supply chain to gain this
visibility share intelligence
uh we can help move those stats in the
other direction and really
lead and help strengthen defenses
thank you