hello
i'm des beck i'm a cyber security
engineer at
mitre and i'll be talking about the
malware behavior catalog
otherwise known as mbc which provides a
standardized vocabulary to support
malware analysis use cases
i'll be focusing on using mbc for
standardized reporting
which improves interpretation of malware
analysis results
as well as how those results can be used
for detection and mitigation
so i'll start with an overview of mbc to
include other use cases
its relationship to mitre attack and
nbc's components and then from there
we'll focus on how
mbc is used in standardized reporting
so mbc is a catalog of objectives and
behaviors created to support
malware analysis use cases so to get
started here's an example
of some of the objectives which are in
the boulder font
and behaviors which are in the regular
font that might be associated with the
malware sample
so it could be if you look under the
anti-behavioral analysis you know
malware may make
analysis difficult by delaying execution
or having obfuscated code
it may disable security tools under
impact you'll see you know
it may hijack system resources and this
is just a sampling of the behaviors that
are defined in the pc
that can be associated with the malware
sample so
as far as other use cases you know today
we're going to
focus on standardized reporting but
there are other use cases as well
so for example mbc can be used to
correlate
malware analysis results so say you have
you know
different tools a couple of different
tools you can
if they're both mapped into nbc you can
compare to see
if they the results agree if they do
agree you could be more confident in the
results
and if they don't agree then you'll know
where to focus for further analysis
um nbc also supports malware labeling to
generate data sets for research
so you know given a data set which has
its behaviors labeled with nbc
would enable you know researchers to
extract whatever subset that
meets some chosen criteria and then also
it
supports you know the malware analysis
process and that's because
you know having a set of behaviors
identified and organized
helps an analyst know what to look for
so i'm sure many viewers are familiar
with mitre attack
it's a curated knowledge base and model
for cyber adversary
behavior and it's widely used to capture
various aspects of the adversary life
cycle
so i should i want to point out that nbc
is not part of attack you know the nbc
team is not part of the attack team
you know their independent efforts but
nbc is related to attack so it's
important to know the basics
and understand that relationship between
them um
attack for enterprise defense defines
adversary ttp
seen during the analysis of an intrusion
and the associated tactics you know the
adversary's technical goals
range from initial access to impact and
are listed there underneath the attack
for enterprise
label and they aren't shown but
associated with each tactic
are what attack calls techniques which
are how an adversary achieves a tactical
objective
and then you've got pre-attack you know
it covers the earlier
phases of a cyber attack but as tactics
aren't shown because they don't relate
to nbc
um and a few years ago we talked to the
attack team
our mdc team talked to them about
expanding attack
to cover malware analysis more
thoroughly or
those use cases more thoroughly um but
you know we weren't the only ones
wanting attack to expand
and you know attack can't expand to
cover every use case and everybody who
wants it to
so instead we decided to develop nbc you
know not just to support malware
analysis
but also you know as a model and a test
case for how attack could be modified by
second parties
so um as far as you know adversaries
behaviors
adversary behaviors and malware
behaviors you know they they overlap
adversaries sometimes use malware um
nbc aside you know attack is used in
reporting to capture malware behaviors
so for example joe sandbox falcon
sandbox any run
cuckoo sandbox you know they currently
map behaviors
to attack techniques but attack is
oriented toward adversaries not malware
it generally focuses on behaviors
identified during an intrusion
rather than those discovered during
analyses like are done for malware
and that's not to say some malware
behaviors don't map nicely into attack
many do for example you'll see that
example there
starts command.exe for commands
execution
that maps to attack version 7
it's sub-technique command and scripting
interpreter windows
command shell but there are some malware
behaviors that can't be mapped
the best examples are anti-analysis
behaviors like those that are listed you
know
for example queries kernel debugger
information
so those missing behaviors in attack
motivated the development for mdc
so nbc expands upon attack by defining
new behaviors
like anti-analysis behaviors and what we
call micro behaviors which i'll define
in a minute nbc moves away from attack's
focus on the adversary perspective
and instead focuses on malware code and
as the diagram there
the table shows nbc version 2
it's been updated to work or to be
compatible with attack version 7 it
defines 41 new behaviors
23 micro behaviors and it enhances with
malware analysis details
30 attack techniques or sub techniques
and if you're familiar with the
philosophy of the attack methodology
you'll recognize the bullets in blue as
malware code-oriented analogs
so mbc maintains a malware code-oriented
perspective
it focuses on real-world malware
behaviors and it maintains an
appropriate level of abstraction
so these are the components of mbc we've
got the objectives which
are you know those are why malware does
something
a behavior or micro behavior captures
what the malware does to accomplish
the objective and a method refines the
behavior
so the standard way of capturing the
components is as a list separated with
double colons where the objective is in
all caps and that's our convention for
using nbc um and then these three
components have equivalence
in attack you know objectives are like
tactics behaviors are like techniques
nbc defined methods before attack define
sub-techniques
so they're a bit different but they they
serve a similar purpose
and in mbc we're also building a
collection of malware that exhibit the
different behaviors and methods
and we haven't done it yet but we're
planning to build a library of code
snippets
that exemplify each behavior
so mbc adopts attacks higher level
structure
and many mbc objectives correspond to
attack tactics
the objectives are shown on this slide
and if you're familiar with attack
you'll recognize you know persistence
execution impact and so forth
then the objectives outlined in yellow
are not defined in attack
but they're key to malware analysis such
as you know the anti-analysis
objectives up in the upper upper right
um and we also found when we looked at
behaviors identified by analysis tools
some that were really low level they
supported many
objectives and other behaviors they
weren't malicious in and of themselves
but
you know they're often identified during
analysis so they're captured
so we capture them in mbc and those are
what we call
micro behaviors and then the associated
micro objectives that are kind of like
the
categories of the micro behaviors and
they're related to things like you know
http ftp dns communication cryptography
and so forth
so um as far as uh
nbc relative to attack they are meant to
be used in combination or nbc is meant
to be used
in combination with attack we don't want
to duplicate attack content
in nbc version one if you'd seen it
before
you know at that point we were
referencing all attack techniques
relevant to malware analysis
there was a stub for you know each
individual technique that applied to
malware
but in version two we've moved away from
that and
version two of nbc only contains
behaviors that are new
or have added content so but the idea
that attack techniques will still be
referenced and used as needed
so in some cases though we've enhanced
an attack technique and that's the
malware behavior you know it extends a
tax description
to cover some specific aspect of malware
in other cases we found that an attack
technique was too broad
so we refined it and defined multiple
behaviors and there's an example there
if you know software packing
an attack uh relates to both what
we think of packing from a malware
perspective as well as
you know of obfuscation of executable
code we've separated those and there are
two different behaviors
in nbc and then when there is no attack
technique
for behavior that's needed to support a
malware analysis use case
we define a new nbc only behavior and
it's been interesting because
attack has grown over the years to
include techniques that
nbc had already defined
um and so this example shows kind of how
we handle those cases
so the attack technique um
virtualization
sandbox evasion which is associated with
the defense
evasion tactic was defined after we
define related behaviors in nbc
nbc has these kind of lower level
descriptions or definitions of behaviors
nbc separates detect from evade and we
separate sandboxes
from virtual machines but as the errors
show
um some of the nbc methods relate to
attack subtechniques i mean they're
the same you know after when you look at
their definitions
so to make things less confusing we
reference the attack content
as i'll show in the next slide so
here's an example mbc is available as
markdown files on github i'll give the
link and more information at the end of
the talk
and this is an example of one of the
behavior pages
this is the dynamic analysis evasion
behavior
that i showed in the previous slide
and so you can see that
at the top of the table that we show
that the virtualization sandbox evasion
attack technique is shown to be related
we list it there and then if you see
down in the description
for one of the methods the delayed
execution method
it too includes a reference to the
time-based evasion subtechnique that
attack defines
so we do link it up um
so as to you know show what's equivalent
or similarities between the
two um between attack and nbc
so there wasn't room to show the entire
page associated with this behavior
but um each page also includes a table
of example malware that exhibit the
behavior
and then references and so forth
so with the basics of nbc covered i'll
now talk about how nbc is used in
standardized reporting
assuming sticks is used as the reporting
format
there are three components uh one
component involves mapping tool
signatures that will generate analysis
content
content to mbc and then the second
component is that nbc must be expressed
in sticks and a third component is that
the tool report you know the output that
tool
provides that too must be translated in
the stick so those are the three
pieces um
and i'll be using cuckoo sandbox for the
signature
mapping example so it has cuckoo sandbox
has a community repository of 565
signatures and of those 313
are behaviors that are appropriate for
mapping to nbc or attack
the others are av related or not
behavior related
and then 165 signatures
were already mapped to attack version
six those were in the community
repository and
included those mappings but then we used
nbc's
malware focus content and we were able
to update
83 with a more accurate mapping that's
actually means we changed the mapping
um to something that was more related in
looking at the signatures
and then we extended 21 of them
extension meaning that we defined an
additional behavior
there are some signatures that have more
than one behavior map to it
and then working with the you know the
nbc only behaviors that we define
we were able to look at
some of the other signatures and in the
end we defined 148 new mappings so we
got a lot more coverage by having the
malware focus of nbc
so this table shows a few example
mappings
some signatures map to nbc behaviors
which have identifiers starting with
a b that's in the first line there of
the table
and then some map to micro behaviors
their identifiers start with a c
and actually it was by working through
the cuckoo signatures
that we decided to define micro
behaviors in the first place because
there were a lot of things that
weren't mapping low level things and
that's where the idea came up
came from and then some signatures map
to attack techniques
that have malware focused enhanced
content
and those identifiers start with an e
for enhanced and they keep the same
number as an attack and that's the
third line there you know the process
injection process halloween example
and then there are some uh signatures
that
map to standard attack techniques those
identifiers start with a t
and then given the mapping so we you
know mapped all the signatures that were
in the repository um given that
we then added the proper identifier to
the cuckoo signature and so i've shown
you know an example of the signature
this is the signature that
goes along with the anti-sandbox sleep
signature defined in cuckoo and you can
see in the ttp
field we've added that which corresponds
to
the dynamic analysis of asian delayed
execution
that's the b00
so and then the latest mapping
which includes so it uses nbc version 2
and attack version 7. that's available
um on github on the mbc project
pages and so you can find it there
so we have the tool in this case cuckoo
mapped to
nbc and attack as we just looked at so
now we need to express
mbc and the cuckoo output in sticks
so stixx is a language for exchanging
cyber threat information
i don't have time to go into the details
but i've given the reference to the
latest
committee specification there at the
bottom of the slide um
for those who are familiar with sticks
the relevant
sdos are the attack pattern malware
analysis
and malware objects and then we use the
relationship objects to associate the
actual nbc behaviors
with analyses and our samples so i'll
show a couple of examples
next um so
expressing nbc in sticks that's
what enables you to then use mbc through
tooling and apis
and we've used the same six objects as
attack uses to express is
its content so if you're already using
attack using nbc
it shouldn't be any different because
we're using for example each of our
behaviors
is captured as an attack pattern object
as you can see in this example
um the name of the property is the name
of the behavior
the phase name of a kill chain also hide
it up there
corresponds to the objective or tactic
as attack would say
and then the identifier is defined as a
property of an external reference
um and the content is available there's
a
nbc nbc-62 repository on github and i
put the link there
where you can get that content
and then these next two slides show how
cuckoo analysis
results nnbc can be captured in sticks
2.1
so this analysis malware analysis object
captures the
cuckoo output you see that that cuckoo's
listed as the product
and then the various analysis details
are captured in different object
properties
and i haven't really gone into them here
but um you know it may be found a domain
name or ip addresses you can see that
those are there
whatever is in that cuckoo report would
be captured
in in the malware analysis object and
then kind of the
nbc related part to that is that there's
um the six relationship object is used
and so
in this example you can see that the
object type is derived from or the
relationship type
is derived from with the source the
attack pattern which corresponds to the
behavior
and the target is the malware analysis
object which corresponds to
the cuckoo analysis so so this kind of
reads you know
the behavior was derived from the
analysis
uh and then a similar relationship could
be used to associate
the nbc behavior or the malware behavior
really
with the actual malware sample so that's
again you you kind of have to have some
knowledge of sticks to
thoroughly understand this but it kind
of gives an idea of how
you know the standardized reporting
comes out from
using nbc so as far as next steps
we'd like to define mappings between nbc
and other analysis tools
like we've done for cuckoo we're
currently mapping the fireeye
flair team's open source capitol to nbc
and hope to have that done relatively
soon
we also plan to expand the malware
example content
and to create a repository of code
snippets to provide examples of how each
behavior is implemented
and then for now all the content is in
markdown files
on github the github site has separate
pages for each behavior
there is a fairly long list of faqs
and a set of malware examples or example
malware
a few organizations are using nbc but
it'd be great of course to have more
people using it and helping to refine it
so please have a look at github and if
you'd like to join the discussion list
please send a request to mbc mitre.org
so thank you very much