[Music]
welcome back to black hat
our program will commence shortly with
some opening remarks from jeff moss
followed by our keynote speaker daniel
gruss black hat would not be possible
without the support of so many people
especially this year as we've been all
been impacted by the global pandemic
and have had to rethink our entire event
in a virtual format
i would like to thank our sustaining
sponsors our global sponsors and of
course all of our black hat asia
sponsors for their ongoing support
i encourage you to connect with them in
the business hall and to explore the
many free resources they have provided
i encourage you to attend their sessions
which are open to all attendees
to our black hat review boards for
trainings
briefings our executive program and
arsenal
we thank you for your tireless efforts
in building the program for this week
thank you to all of our speakers for
their eagerness to embrace
the online format some housekeeping
before we begin
be sure to download your copy of cyber
threats in turbulent times a report
just published from the annual black hat
attendee survey
the survey and report were developed by
our colleagues at dark reading
and is available to download in the dark
reading booth which is within the
business hall
if you would like more market research i
invite you to visit omdia
our newly rebranded research and
consulting business who are also
available
in the business hall as we kick off
today's program
i would like to thank you for attending
blackcat this year and remind you that
the same content will be available to
you
for 30 days after the event we encourage
you to come back
and revisit the content at your own pace
and now it is my pleasure to welcome
back to the stage the dark tangent
jeff moss welcome back to day two of
black cat asia singapore first virtual
event
and it's my privilege to introduce the
day two keynote speaker
mr daniel grouse an assistant professor
at graz university
of technology who finished his phd in
only three years
he's been involved in teaching operating
system security to undergraduate courses
since 2010. most recently
daniel's work has gained international
attention
through his research focus on side
channels and transient execution attacks
he was involved in the team that
implemented the first remote fault
attack
running on a website now famously known
as rowhammer.js and his research
team was one that found the meltdown
inspector bugs published in
2018. these kinds of deep technical
faults
in the way that hardware operates as
fundamentally changing
the way that we view cpus remote hosting
and bare metal architectures and so i'm
really looking forward to
seeing what he has on the horizon and
thoughts he has on
hardware security
hello and welcome to today's keynote i
will talk about
uh how complexity killed security uh my
name is daniel grouse i'm an assistant
professor
at class university of technology so
let's start with a simple
comic from xkcd so in this comic uh
you probably know this is your situation
are you coming to bed
i can't this is important what someone
is wrong on the internet
and i thought maybe we start with some
case like that
so this is a comic from xkcd as well the
meltdown inspector exploits use
speculative execution
what's that you know the trolley problem
well for
why now cpus have basically been sending
trolleys down
both passes quantum style while awaiting
your choice then the unneeded phantom
trolley disappears
if we take a look at how spectre
actually works you will see that the
processor just makes a prediction
as you can see here and then walks down
that path it doesn't walk
down both paths and then if the
speculation was incorrect of course
it will first walk the one way and then
walk the other way
um if it had to re-adapt this
speculation
okay so this is not actually fully
correct but let's take a
look at the second part uh the phantom
trolley isn't supposed to touch anyone
but it turns out you can still use it to
do stuff
and it can drive through walls also
there this is the reference to meltdown
meltdown and spectra are separated texts
but i will get to that also
later as well that sounds bad honestly
i've been assuming we were doomed since
we learned about row hammer so what's
that
well in row hammer you access rows
and if you access them often enough then
you will
find bit flips in the middle row so you
modify memory without actually
accessing these memory cells and you
don't have permission to access them
which allows you to implement very
interesting attacks
it sounds interesting to me
do we just suck at computers yeah
especially shared ones
so uh here's also my conclusion that i
want to start with
uh computers were a mistake uh
we are all doomed and we don't even know
what we are doing
so let's take a look at how we got there
and what the situation
actually is in this picture we see an
illustration of
the modern internet how it is connected
as a fully
connected graph of servers
the complexity of this is so enormous
that we are getting into a scale that is
almost of biological measures um
if we take a look at this
comic again if we software
developers but also hardware developers
were
architects probably we would try to
build
buildings like this
the thing is we are putting layers on
top of layers on top of layers that
depend on each other
and that make assumptions about each
other but it's not really clear whether
these assumptions always hold
you probably will also know and you will
probably have experienced
this how complexity exceeds our
uh thought capacity very quickly and
very easily
my code doesn't work i have no idea why
and vice versa my code works i have no
idea why
and it takes us quite some time until we
understand
why the code works so it's very easy to
build complex things
that at first are very difficult for us
to understand ourselves
let's take a look at one example so this
is a dram module
and these dram modules they have these
chips banks
rows they have channels
ranks and if you uh take a look at
how this mapping works from physical
addresses
to the actual hardware cells
that's not documented right it's not
public
but we reverse engineered that and that
was
uh four years ago and we resolved these
functions for
several different machines how did we do
that we used
side channels in a side channel
for instance in this example uh you
probably have seen that in the movies
you have this safe and when the ledge
snaps and you hear this
snapping noise and you can hear that
with a stethoscope and then you know
that you have to turn the wheel the
other direction
and you know how to open
the safe so what is a site channel i
would say the site channel is
obtaining metadata and deriving
secrets from it and maybe some people
don't agree with that but this is the
definition that i can work with
and in this case in the case of drama we
also used
a side channel the timing side channel
so we use
row hits and row misses because if you
access dram cells
some of them will be cached in the row
buffer and others are not and you can
see that
this timing difference here rohit romis
and uh that's basically we apply uh
methods from natural sciences right we
measure
uh whether it's faster or slower and
infer something from that
and many people say well that's not
really science because if you take a
look at how computer science should work
or
where computer science is you can see
here the branches of science and you can
see
basic and applied you can see natural
sciences social sciences
formal sciences and here we have
computer science
wait a second computer science is a
formal applied science
also this guy here computer science is
just applied mathematics
well i'm not entirely sure about that
but applied
mathematics so maybe let's take a look
at a actual computer
and let's do some applied computations
so oh we can type a number here
yes maybe this number oh
if we turn this around this is from the
other side this is hello
this reminds me of something hello
[Music]
i don't even need network right
your cash noise pattern it clearly
doesn't save your vm anymore
[Music]
wait a second wait a second they talked
about noise
we are talking here about computers
applied formal science
this should be a fully deterministic
system right
so why do we have noise this is from our
hello from the other side paper and you
can clearly see
that we observe noise how can that be in
a
fully deterministic system the thing is
there
is no noise noise is just variables
unaccounted for so this means
we are we are not in a noisy system at
all but if we go back to these uh
questions like is computer science just
mathematics uh
i would say i would go a step further
math is just applied velocity
well if computer science is just
mathematics then probably this is also
right but this leads us to a very
interesting question
uh that i've been wondering about with
endless computation
power and knowledge of the entire state
of the universe
i think one could predict the future
maybe it's not possible that's right but
the thing is we have to
uh we have to accept that we build
systems that are so complex
that we are analyzing them with natural
science methods
because computer science building things
exceeds what we can analyze with
just formal methods in this case
we also we probe the dram bus
and inferred what the actual mappings
are in another case
we looked at address translation so in
this
case we look at x86 64
and we wanted to know whether the dress
translation which has multiple layers
will take a different amount of time
depending on
where the translation stops for instance
if you have a two megabyte page it would
already stop on this level
and directly map a page or for a four
kilobyte page it would stop on this
level
and directly provide a four kilobyte
page
and if you look at the timing
differences you can see
where for instance if you run this on
the kernel addresses
where the kernel addresses are mapped
because the other parts
they stop at a higher timing for
instance because the pages are not valid
there
and this is again uh science right we
reverse engineered
how this mapping works and you might
wonder
well why don't you this is stupid humans
build it so this must be documented
somewhere
so why don't you just read the
documentation right
and the next step is well of course this
is not documented because it's not open
source
so the question is would open solve the
problem
is risk five going to save the day and
the question that i want to ask you here
is
did open source software save the day it
didn't
we see the same number of
vulnerabilities in closed
software and in open source software
the thing is there are some advantages
to open source software for instance
that
it's usually a shorter amount of time
until a bug is patched
um you also have
probably a larger community that looks
at the software but you also have other
disadvantages for instance as we have
seen around meltdown inspector
that it's very difficult to patch very
uh
critical bugs out in the open so there
are advantages
and disadvantages and i think
i don't have a clear answer to that in
terms of security
there's no clear benefit other than
the reduced time to patch
let's take another look uh at one
example
uh because if you would say well open
source isn't going to help
why don't we just make everything closed
source
and just hide all the ugly security
hacks that we had
for instance let's go for up security by
obscurity
and i have one example here this is the
msr
0x 150 and you can use this to
select the voltage as we did in the
plundervolt attack
and here you can see that you can select
via this msr you can select the plane
index and the offset
and change the voltage of the cpu by
that
this is um yeah is this security
critical
is this security biosecurity let's take
a look at this simple code here
on an endless loop uh this should never
terminate because it computes the same
number over and over again
and it should never go into this line
but if we take a look at this
um when we run this code
here you can see we are undervolting
this now and as we go down with the
voltage
we see that a fault occurs and this
fault
then can be exploited again similar as
in the rohamer attack
so the question is of course if we are a
formal science if we
are part of mathematics can we just be
provably secure systems and a question
that i want to ask you there is
what properties before the internet came
up
the properties that we wanted to have in
a secure system
were different than the properties that
we want in them today
today we have these channels where um
criminals can send money over the
internet
we have things like ransomware coming up
that without the internet wouldn't
flourish as much as they do
the internet radically changed what
security
properties we want in a system but this
also exists
on a much smaller scale with all the
single new discoveries that we make
for instance when we discover a draw
hammer
we saw this patch in the linux kernel do
not disclose
physical addresses because of row hammer
the problem here is that no one would
have foreseen that suddenly
physical addresses would be considered a
secret
so why would your formal system try to
keep this a secret if we don't even
understand that this must be kept secret
for another attack that was not even
known at that point
so the required security properties
change over time
if we take a look at the complexity of
systems the complexity of systems
is composed of the complexity of the
subsystems that we have in there so if
we have this larger system
which is composed of three systems then
the complexity
is at least as much as the complexity of
the smaller
subsystems but we have not taken into
account that we also have a system
interaction here
that adds additional complexity so even
if each of these systems by itself
has a complexity where we can say we can
make a formal proof we can
reason about this system and argue why
it is secure
as soon as we put multiple systems
together new effects occur
that maybe are not covered by our
security proofs so if we take a look at
uh
for example this case here we have a
user we have an execution unit in a
processor and the user says
i request or load data and the execution
unit will then in the second step
check the privileges and then kill the
user process or kill the threat
if no privileges or if the user doesn't
have enough
privileges this is one system one
interaction between
two components this is one system
another system is this system here to
obtain data
so we have the user on the one side that
sends the request
and the execution unit because it
doesn't have the data itself
will just send the request on to the
cache and says
send the data to the requesting load so
send the data to the user
and the cache will send this data to the
user so
both uh circuits both um
both cases both systems by itself are
secure the right thing happens
but if you combine them you will see
that you have a race condition
in the third step because the kill might
occur just after the data was already
received
by the spy so the question then is of
course if we are building so complex
systems that they have bugs like
meltdown is the solution maybe that we
go back to more
simple systems less complex systems
and in general i would say yes to some
extent we can
we have been doing that for instance the
pentium 4
was arguably a more complex design than
the later
core processors that went back to the
pentium 3 design as a basis
so now what we are doing there is we are
combining more and more of these less
complex
designs into larger and larger
processors larger and larger systems
and we at the same time make them
smaller and smaller
which allows us to run these older less
complex systems
at a higher frequency at a higher speed
so moore's law promises us that we can
actually do that that we can
take simple cores and put them together
into a system with multiple cores
and each of these simple cores will run
faster and faster and faster because we
can
put more transistors into small amount
of space
we can run them at a lower energy
level and we can run them at a higher
frequency
the problem now with moore's law is it's
any
it's basically we are very close to the
end um
and the problem is that if we take a
look at
our computation demands i didn't find a
plot for the computation demands of our
entire
uh population but i found an energy
forecast of
our computer systems and here you can
see that
the s current estimate is that by 2030
around 21 of electricity that we produce
will be consumed by our computer systems
and this of course is a problem this
directly is correlated
to the computation needs that we have
but if moore's law is ending and at the
same time we have a strong
increase in the computation demands
of our society then the question is
how can we how does that fit together
how can we
then still meet our computation demands
and the solution that i want to bring up
here
is that well in 1999 we said
oh i developed one piece of software in
only 120 lines of code and it's not so
much
about the lines of code that you write
but the lines of code
that are involved in solving the problem
if you would take a look at the early 3d
games or
maybe also consoles they were heavily
optimized
for size and performance so that they
can run on the constrained devices that
they had
at the time by now the systems uh due to
moore's law
scaled so much up that it doesn't matter
this much so we now can write many
things
in a much more wasteful manner
but what i would predict in 2029 we
might head back the other direction
and start optimizing again for low level
performance for assembly for c
because higher level languages might be
too slow
or too energy consuming so what we will
have here because of course writing low
level code will have
more complex problems synchronization
problems interaction with the low level
parts the operating system the hardware
so yes we will have more software
complexity
of one kind also if you take a look at
the hardware complexity if moore's law
is ending
then i would expect that we have also a
slowdown
in the performance
of modern processors but if you take a
look at for instance
the cpu benchmarks you see that the
benchmark scores are actually
increasing a bit above linear
the question is how is that possible if
moore's law is ending because
this shouldn't happen right it should
slow down
the thing is we are adding more and more
optimizations on the microarchitectural
level
and adding more optimizations on the
micro architectural level
means more hardware complexity more
clever hardware
more instruction set extensions and that
means again
more potential for problems we are
combining more and more
systems into single systems that
are more difficult to understand so if
we take a look at the complexity of
modern software or hardware
you can see that the software complexity
is almost reaching the level of
pretty complex biological organisms
the dna sequence the genome
of a mouse for instance so our systems
that we
as humans build are getting so complex
getting as complex as nature itself
and there um i want to bring up this
book
by herbert simon the sciences of the
artificial because
it is not a natural science to study
how a computer works because a computer
is something artificial it's something
that we humans build
but we have to study it like nature
because it exceeded the complexity
that we can reason about in another way
so we have to study it
like nature and that means we have to go
through the regular natural science
methodology
with question hypothesis prediction
then testing whether our prediction
holds
and then the analysis of the
results and then of course we also need
to compare it
with previous work with related work to
see whether
our hypothesis makes sense and whether
our hypothesis might be correct this is
how our science work
and our artificial science where we
study computers
works in the same way now
what is the conclusion here our systems
are getting more and more complex
and that means that we will have to
invest more and more time into studying
them
like nature in 30 years i would expect
that we have a significantly larger
number of people
studying the security and analyzing the
security
of our systems than we have today and if
you
take a look back on 20 years ago
30 years ago the job of pentester didn't
really exist
so we have more and more security
analysts and we will
see more and more variety in the jobs
that need to be
performed there so the takeaways are the
complexity of hardware and software
systems
continues to increase this does not stop
and it cannot stop
because we have our computational
demands and at the same time
moore's law that is ending
we need natural science methods and
significant efforts
to understand systems and their
complexity and their security
and the last aspect that i want to give
you
is the perspective on security might
change over time we have seen that in
the beginning
the internet changed the perspective on
security but also
for very very concrete attacks for
instance for the meltdown attack
we thought the meltdown attack that's it
it's solved
but only recently we figured out that we
can also
turn this around in a way and do
something else
and with that i will show you one last
example is there a way we can do
something like that
by injection inside or
or and it turns out that the idea to do
something with injection
is not so bad so here's our trailer
if you haven't seen it yet for load
value injection
there's one thing you should know about
me i specialize in a
very specific type of security micro
architectural security
you're talking about meltdown
mr van burk has an idea he would like to
discuss with you
spreading meltdown
not exactly we turn meltdown around
you bring the subject into a fault and
then they fill it with their secrets
then you break it and leak it well it's
not
strictly speaking leaky
it's called load value injection
i think you overlooked one square and
this last square
that's lvi
we mustn't be afraid where the female
fans is darling
thank you for your attention uh now i
will be available for the q
a and i'm looking forward to any
discussions on this topic
so see you in the q a in a second
[Applause]