[Music]
hello and welcome to blackout asia 2020
a virtual event 2020 has been an
unprecedented year with so many new
challenges
the critical work you all do to secure
our digital world
is more important now than ever before
and bringing all of you the black cat
community together
to discuss the latest research trends
and best practices
is vital while our event is entirely
online this year the blackout team
and the review board have made every
effort to provide you with the same high
standard of black hat content
to help you this includes more than 15
technical trainings
and it includes 40 plus black hat
briefings over 18 tracks
covering the latest security research
from the global community
outside of our trainings and our
briefings programs we have a
wide variety of content that is
available to all attendees
we have over 30 open source tools being
demonstrated in the blackhead arsenal
and many sponsored sessions on current
trends and best practices being
presented by
many of our partners our keynotes and
review board lock notes are also open
to all attendees we have a packed agenda
with the best content and we hope you
enjoy your time with us
it's now my pleasure to welcome jeff
moss to provide his opening remarks
but first a little bit about jeff in
addition to founding both black hat and
defcon
jeff has served as vice president and
chief security officer at icann
he is an advisor with the u.s homeland
security advisory council
and a commissioner with the global
council on the stability of cyberspace
please join me in welcoming the dark
tangent jeff moss
welcome to black hat asia singapore
2020.
this is the first year we've done this
virtually since the year 2000 when we
started coming to singapore
and so i'd like to welcome you and i'd
like to
congratulate you for taking a risk and
going online
so who am i i'm jeff moss i'm the
founder of black hat
and i'd like to welcome you and give you
a little bit of our history
for those of you who are new in the
audience we do a couple of things before
we kick off
and i introduce the keynote i want to
talk a little bit about
who's in the audience and then i want to
talk a little bit about what we do
to try to grow the audience and the
diversity and then give you a couple
thoughts
about where i think things are going to
sort of frame the talks and the
conversations that we'll be
having over the next two days so let's
kick this off
who's in the audience we have
representatives from 112
different countries and out of those 112
countries we have representatives from
28 countries with only a single person
and so i normally read through the list
call out
give kudos to those who are there
shouldering the burden of being the sole
person representing their culture
and virtually now you can maybe raise
your hand virtually during a break
and say hey i'm from palau anybody else
from a nearby country
and try to network try to meet some of
your peers from around the region
and grow your connections so here we go
albania algeria angola
armenia azerbaijan the bahamas
bhutan bulgaria costa rica
estonia finland liechtenstein
macau madagascar mali
malta mongolia mozambique
palau romania chaselles
slovakia tanzania u.s virgin islands
uruguay
venezuela last but not least zimbabwe
so thank you for making the trek
digitally all this way
and getting involved second part is
we really do try to get more people
involved every year and starting about
five years ago black hat
started a program of offering free
admission
to those who qualified students teachers
military veterans and we've extended
that program this year and continued it
for singapore
so we have scholarships that we've given
away to 75 students
to attend that wouldn't normally have
the financial means to get into a black
hat until maybe further along in their
career
but we really want to try to grow that
next generation
also we have 35 women in security
scholarships
trying to increase gender diversity 10
educator scholarships
and 25 passes donated to the singapore
cyber security agency for their career
mentoring program
so why is diversity so important well
global perspectives are going to become
key
in the direction of technology in the
next decade and why is this well
people are saying that the 2020s to the
2030s is the decade of tech now we've
heard that since the dot-com bubble but
what's different here is we're on
a threshold of several breakthroughs of
technology
you know the explosive growth and
computing power has led to ml and ai
breakthroughs and this will continue
with moore's law in the next decade
so expect more consequence more impact
from ai and ml
we're going to have more in bio
breakthroughs
don't forget robot breakthroughs and
then there's going to be
something going on in quantum computing
and uh for 5g 6g
what's happening here is as the
technology spreads around the globe and
becomes more
important in everybody's lives
governments are going to be looking to
us
to try to interpret the risks and
provide advice
on the security around these
technologies
and something i'm fond of saying is that
internet problems are global problems
and this is really a reflection that if
there's
an attack in one country it might impact
routing
for other countries if one country does
a bgp hijack
it might suck in traffic from a third
uninvolved party
and to resolve these conflicts and these
tensions you're gonna have to have
conversations with people
in countries other than your own you're
gonna have to understand other cultures
other languages and so therefore i think
a more diverse cyber security population
will only benefit us going forward
only benefit companies and help us
understand how the technology is being
used
but there's a corollary to this which is
global problems are now
internet problems the tensions between
states have bled over to the internet
and this became really obvious in the
2016 election in the united states
russia really took it to america online
instead of sort of behind the scenes or
diplomatically or through economic
sanctions
it became really an online internet
problem
and as other countries learn from that
you see the techniques used by russia
disinformation information operations
multiplying
this is just going to be a constant
background to the world we live in
add on top of that supply chain issues
and the immediacy of any time there's a
global issue
pandemic fires in california there's
phishing campaigns
ready to roll botnets globally deployed
so i think in the past maybe the
technology and security problems are
very
stovepipe very limited going forward
they're going to become much more global
and because of that policymakers or
companies are really going to turn to us
to provide sort of a third party or more
of an independent perspective
what does this all mean how do we design
our product
to comply with the gdpr what are the
security risks of
housing all of our pii inside china if
we want to do business there
so i think that's key
and at the same time we're just
discovering a new form
of diplomacy which i'm calling app
diplomacy
and this is a reflection of recent
conflict on the indian
china border between china and india
where some indian military were killed
in a conflict
and india could have decided to respond
by escalating
but instead they de-escalated and went
to an
economic response by banning bite
dance's tick-tock
application on the indian app store
so this becomes an economic response
nuanced in that it's
through to an app and had a six billion
dollar market cap
consequence so real economic pain
lateral thinking sort of asymmetric and
response
great didn't involve blowing things up
but on the other hand
it's now a new way for companies and
countries to respond
don't like your economic competitor
maybe you pull their app
want country a doesn't like country b
ban some of their apps from your store
and this has the impact of fragmenting
the internet
so i can predict confidently
unfortunately
that the future will hold a more
fragmented internet
and a more fragmented internet while it
doesn't serve anybody's best interest
it's really convenient and attractive
for a number of reasons
one is you sort of know who your friends
are in a fragmented internet
you could say we're the rule of law
countries and those are the
authoritarian countries
and it's really convenient for sorting
who your friends and
enemies may be right well
while that's convenient that's maybe not
the best for
world peace and efficiency and an open
free and interactive internet but that's
the world we're going in and that's the
world we're going to be operating in
and so i want you to just take a minute
and think about that
um you're going to intentionally or
unintentionally over the next four or
five years
end up picking sides you're going to
find yourself naturally gravitating more
toward platforms that are maybe more
open or maybe more controlling
you're going to be working for a company
that's building technology maybe to
surveil and potentially repress people
with facial recognition
or create profiles or maybe you're
working for companies
like a microsoft that says we're not
doing facial recognition anymore
right so you're going to end up working
for companies or governments that
reflect
your moral values or maybe not
maybe you just don't care right maybe
you want to be like switzerland and not
pick a side
not picking is also picking by the way
that's not an escape valve for you
so when you're doing this just don't
forget
that the companies and the governments
and the way you've made your decisions
will greatly influence the internet of
the future the internet our children
inherit
and if you fragment the internet too
much in the next few years
our children will grow up in a world
that is not like our world
right you fight too much online on the
internet and the isps
and the carriers will we'll redesign the
internet to be more safe
but in doing so it'll be fundamentally
different than the internet we have
today
so keep that in mind
i would like to uh to also talk a little
bit about why i'm so excited about
singapore as a location for black hat
and i was excited this way 20 years ago
but a little bit more now
for a number of reasons one singapore
really has a commitment to the rule of
law and that's led to a couple
of outcomes i believe one is they're a
big routing
superpower in southeast asia if you look
at a map
of where all the fiber terminates and a
ton of it transits through
singapore because of that there's more
and more data centers here
it's becoming sort of a data haven that
rule of law
provides a certain amount of
transparency and predictability that
allows companies
to invest and because of that singapore
also has one of the highest
educated populations is very quick to
adapt
they're a big exporter of high
technology so i think
they're suited very well to become an
influencer in the area
they're not like in america or china or
germany
where their market power is so great it
can swing things
but what they can do is provide sort of
a moral guidance on where this all leads
and so that's why i'm really excited to
introduce
our keynote speaker so for day one
our keynote speaker is brigadier general
gurov kirthi
he's also known as yoda he was a former
air force pilot
and in the military he has also held
roles in
capability development innovation
and in his final tour of duty he's
responsible for the cyber defense of the
air force
as deputy chief executive development
in the cyber security agency or the csa
gurov oversees the cybersecurity
capability and ecosystem development
to keep singapore's cyberspace safe and
secure
he also has on his personal side he's
graduated from stanford and harvard and
has a passion and has founded
numerous non-profit digital startups
and is also the national lead for tech
for good the volunteer run
organization and i first met gurav
several years ago at the paris peace
forum
and we hit it off and i was really
impressed with his depth of experience
and his perspective
and i knew he was going to be someone
who could really
vocalize and help explain provide
guidance
for this next generation going forward
you know where singapore sees it's going
so anyway it's my honor and privilege to
introduce
daewon kino general gurov thank you
thank you so much for having me here
it's an honor and it's a pleasure
i'm excited and surprised
and a little bit disappointed to be here
i'm excited because
this is black hat and holy cow i'm
speaking at it
this is incredibly exciting at least to
me i've watched black hat online for
many years i've learned so much
and to be given this opportunity is a
real honor
i'm also surprised and once you google
me you'll also be surprised
what on earth is an ex-air force pilot
doing at black hat
is he at the wrong event it should be at
a different conference black flight
helmet to something else
how did i end up being responsible for
driving
cyber security capability development in
singapore
finally i'm also a bit disappointed
because frankly
when i got the invitation to speak at
black hat i was really excited to meet
the people chat with you guys have a
beer
and feel this amazing community spirit
well
hopefully next year so at this point
you're probably wondering
what am i doing here who am i and
i am a relative newcomer to the cyber
security industry but i'm looking
forward to being part of it
over the years i studied computer
science many years back before cyber
security was even a subject
i don't think was even a real word in
the 90s
but despite my promising start
i signed up to become an air force pilot
and 20 years of being in the military
was an interesting experience quite
different from cyber security
i must say that last year at the keynote
speech when mikko hippenin
spoke about how many fighters our air
force had i definitely sat up a little
bit straighter
my pilot call sign is yoda long story
but because of my tech background and my
interest in technology
all the tools i built i was appointed as
the chief innovation officer of the air
force
and the commander for the air defense
and operations command in my final tour
that command is responsible for all of
the operations that we run
obviously and if you think it sucks to
get your social media account hacked
well i was responsible for the cyber
defense of all of our networked missiles
radars control systems and aircraft so
that
really would suck and so i took cyber
security extremely seriously in that
tour
one thing led to another and here i am
at the cyber security agency of
singapore
i'm now responsible for redesigning how
we defend singapore from blue teaming to
red teaming
to all of the capabilities in between
and i wanted to use this keynote to
share with you a few
thoughts more like questions actually
that i've been reflecting on as i take
on this journey
and because i come from a
non-traditional background i thought it
might be useful to draw inspiration from
unlikely sources so here we go now the
first thing i realized
is that defending a country is not the
same as defending
a network
i know that this audience is full of
people who know how to defend and attack
corporate networks but unfortunately i
cannot just extrapolate the techniques
for defending a network to defend
singapore
a country has bounded geography
but there are many related and unrelated
network topologies that kind of
crisscross inside the borders
they have dependencies on network
topologies outside our borders
they interact in intricate ways to
provide an essential service to people
and defending this open interconnected
network this digital space within a
geographical area
is infinitely more complex than
defending a corporate network one of the
first lessons i learned in cyber
security was
know your assets well try doing that on
the scale of a
country i think i could retire before i
figured out what our assets were
now complicating this even further is
that singapore isn't content to just be
on the internet no we want to be a
smart nation a leading light that
showcases how we can use digital
technologies to make our citizens lives
better
digitizing everything from lampposts to
traffic lights
and when you digitize everything at that
scale cybersecurity professionals step
back and think
attack vectors i see attack vectors
everywhere
and it's true so the cyber security
agency of singapore
has a pretty expansive mission
we keep our cyberspace safe and secure
to underpin our national security
power a digital economy and protect our
digital way of life
i'll cover four broad questions in this
speech
should cyber security be a public good
or a private good
should users or vendors be responsible
for cyber security
should cyber security be a policy
problem or an engineering problem
and should cyber security be a cost or a
benefit to manufacturers
and i'll wrap all this up and kind of
answer that big question how do we
defend singapore
so let's start with the first question
should cyber security be
a public good or a private good and
it starts with econs 101 you know what
is a public good
a public good in economics is one that
is non-excludable and non-rivalrous
lamp posts for example are public good
they're non-excludable
i cannot exclude you from enjoying the
light of this lamppost
just by standing underneath it it's
non-rivalrous
i cannot my benefit from enjoying this
light
doesn't prevent you from benefiting and
enjoying this light
public goods are therefore a bit of a
complicated problem provision and
governments generally step in to provide
public goods
because it's difficult for the private
market to price these things
so things like clean water national
defense these are public goods
the opposite of a public good is a
private bad
i'm just kidding it's a private good and
a private good is
built by companies many of you work for
them and sold to consumers i am one of
them so asking whether cyber security
should be a public good or a private
good is actually a really important
question
because if we decide that it is a
private good purely a private good
then i can end the speech very quickly
because it's not my problem
it's your problem please defend
singapore thank you very much
but if we decide that it is a public
good then
you can all zone out because it's not
your problem it's my problem i will
defend the internet for you
clearly this is a false dichotomy and
the answer is somewhere in between
but i want to push this conversation
further because it's an important
question
now the lessons that we can learn about
public goods and how we deal with it in
singapore
from singapore's experience with
policing when you walk through the
streets in singapore
even at night 93 of people feel safe
the economist intelligence unit ranked
us as the second safest city in the
world
and how do we do this and what lessons
can cyber security learn from it
well we have police who patrol the
streets they're part of the
neighborhoods
and the singapore police force provides
a public good called security
to reduce the risk that gangs of armed
robbers are roaming my neighborhood
they do public good called security but
that said
i still invest in private security i
invest in locks on my door i have
cameras at home and i have an alarm
system
but i know what type of threats i'm
responsible for defending myself against
and what type of threats i can rely on
the police to protect me from
i've come to a good balance in that
sense of how much security the
government provides and how much users
provide
but in the digital world do we have the
right balance
should we continue to expect users to
protect themselves against
all threats big and small let me give
another example to make this even
clearer
this time from public sanitation
basically
water and sewage literally up until the
1800s
nations treated drinking water the way
we currently treat
cyber security governments would warn
their people
don't drink dirty water do not mix your
poop water
with your drinking water it is your
responsibility to boil the water and
make sure you are not drinking dirty
water
governments truly believed that the
users were the weakest link
and they kept drinking dirty water and
dying of all sorts of disgusting
diseases
now it became a public health problem
because these diseases were contagious
rather than just affecting a private
user
one person's lack of water hygiene
spread to became
many people's health problems so
governments decide to change their
mental model
and they built these vast networks of
plumbing and sewage
to provide people with clean water
straight from the tap
they realize that clean drinking water
is a public good
to some extent because the problem
affected the whole national health state
today with modern filtration you can
turn on the tap
and drink the water we've curbed the
problems of people contracting strange
diseases
through contaminated water by making it
easier to drink
clean water now not everybody drinks
water from the tap
industries obviously need highly pure
water and they buy that
people drink bottled water and some
hipsters put fruit and little copper
tubes to ionize their water
people have their own balance of what
type of water they want to drink
from the private market and the public
market there's a balance
so where are we for cyber security i
think you can recognize from my not so
subtle analogy that we're still
around the 1800s some parts have moved
forward
but generally our view is we're warning
people don't drink dirty water
and if you're drinking it and dying it's
probably your fault
that may still be necessary but i don't
think it's sufficient
cyber hygiene is becoming a public
health crisis
just like water sanitation it's no
longer a private problem
now as more users connect to the
internet whether it's through their
laptops their phones their smart watches
their baby cameras their wi-fi routers
we need to be worried about our
essential services being ddosed
by botnets just like the mirai attacks
in 2016.
one user's lack of cyber hygiene
actually now translates to a contagion
which can affect
other users just like how all of the
wi-fi routers and printers were hijacked
to disrupt my online streaming access
so we need to start thinking of how we
can provide clean drinking water from
the tap
and make sure that any poo in the water
is taken out upstream
at the filtration plants now the analogy
isn't perfect
it's not a pure public good but it gives
you a sense of where a
drawn and what kind of answers we could
have for the cybersecurity digital world
how much should governments be
responsible for i don't quite know the
answer
but i do know we should be responsible
for much more and in singapore we're
rolling out the safer cyberspace master
plan
which is our master plan to build a
safer cyberspace
is to protect all users small and big
and it's ambitious
it seeks to rebalance this equation and
to provide that that
clean drinking water from the tap
we want to make singapore one of the
most cyber secure nations in the world
i don't want to reveal too much about it
because next week at the singapore
international cyber week
we'll be announcing all of the details
so stay tuned for that and i urge you to
attend if possible
so the second question
now that we've explored the role of what
government should be in the provision of
public goods
let's dive a little bit deeper into the
private goods market
there are two parties involved in the
transaction the consumers
the customers the users and the
producers the vendors the oems
the developers today we largely hold
users
responsible for cyber security i built
the cloud
but you as the customer are responsible
for configuring it and if you configured
it wrongly it's
your fault you need to have a stronger
password because you registered on my
website
now i've interfaced with many industries
over my career but the cyber security
industry is always a little bit of a
strange one to me
in most sectors the customer is always
right
it's but in cyber security it's actually
acceptable
to tell the user to their face that the
user is the weakest link the customer is
wrong
it's unusual and i argue it's unhealthy
it creates a self-fulfilling prophecy
where our wider industry doesn't take
full accountability and responsibility
and ownership for this problem
and i know that we pride ourselves on
being separate from the developer the
software developer sectors
but we need to be careful in how we
apply this distinction in front of the
public
allow me to now draw some unusual
lessons from the automotive industry to
explain this
you've probably heard this analogy a few
times but cyber security is like the
brakes on a car
while technically brakes are the things
that slow you down
actually brakes are the thing that
without which you dare not go fast good
brakes actually help you have the
confidence to go faster
it's a useful analogy and even though
you've heard it many times i argue we
don't
push it far enough when you buy a car
a car salesman comes up to you and says
this is a good car
it's got a good engine it's got good
wheels it's got good brakes and it costs
this much
you do not go to a car showroom to hear
the car designer
the engine designer and the brakes
designer have an argument about whose
responsibility is to prevent you from
crashing
they sort that argument out behind the
scenes they have their robust debates
and they come to a conclusion before
they launch the car
customers expect good brakes to be part
of a good car
they don't want to hear your arguments
in front of them and it confuses
customers and it reduces car sales
another lesson from the car industry
actually cars became a lot more popular
when they became safer and easier to
drive safely
today you don't need to know what a
carburetor is and all the other parts of
a car in order to drive it
the automotive industry got to where it
is today
because they realized that drivers are
an essential part
of the industry's ecosystem they didn't
blame
bad drivers as external actors they
didn't blame them for the accidents
no they learned from the accidents that
bad drivers had and they recognized bad
drivers will continue to exist
but they learned the lessons and they
built crumple zones
they built airbags they built better
seat belts
they built forward sensors reverse
sensors cameras
blind spot alerts they learned lessons
from accidents and made
safer cars so you don't need to be a car
engineer
i'm an air force pilot so this trend is
even starker in aviation
modern civil airliners can fly
themselves pretty much all the way
safely and some aircraft are so advanced
that
pilots barely need to touch the controls
we need to take these lessons and
engineer more secure products
that basically protect the users instead
of designing more and more complex
auditing procedures
or post-hoc measures to slap on security
at the end of it
because that's not an effective approach
cybersecurity has evolved to become a
complex
monster that even the initiated
professionals
find it challenging to understand but
that's not useful
cybersecurity needs to be usable in
order to be effective
it needs to be inclusive every person is
part of our ecosystem small and big not
just the technically savvy ones
even at the government level we're
taking this message on board by taking
devsecops
and making it our way of launching
products we're trying to simplify
security as part at the national level
to make it easier for developers to
adopt best practices
some examples we've pushed out sync pass
as the national digital biometric
authentication system
and we're enabling important apps like
those from the banking sector
to access it for authentication we
simplify the back end
so that the users the developers don't
have to think about it so much
and it makes it invisible or nearly
invisible to the user
part of a seamless and convenient
experience
we want to make the secure process the
easier process
just like it's really hard to dig up a
well in your backyard
boil the water and drink it it's easier
to drink water straight from the tap
and now the cleaner experience the safer
experience is the better experience
people adopt better habits when it is
convenient to do so
and revert back to bad habits when it is
inconvenient
so we want the secure way to be the
easier way we see the industry doing
this
and we encourage it we move on now to
the third question
but the summary of my first two
questions is basically
users vendors and governments have a
part to play
no surprises there but it's interesting
to note that for this question
should cyber security be a policy
problem or an engineering problem
we find that different parts have
different answers governments have
generally taken a very policy-centric
approach to the problem thus far
there's a problem with internet security
we'll put in laws regulations and
policies to make sure that our message
is loud and clear
singapore has a cyber security act
industry on the other hand
has taken a very engineering-centric
approach to the problem
partly because they can't set policies
so there's a specific problem with
internet security
by my new product it has artificial
intelligence machine learning
blockchain and robots but i think
as usual the answer is somewhere in
between governments need to take a more
engineering approach to the problem to
complement policies
again using cars as an example it's easy
to put speed limits all over the road
but that's a policy solution not fully
an engineering solution
an engineering solution is thinking
about speed humps
thinking about speed cameras and now
they have such sophisticated speed
cameras
that it detects your average speed over
a long road rather than just your speed
at a point in time
now that's a clever engineering approach
to slowing down cars
i think you can see the pattern to my
answers it's not
extremes but somewhere in the middle
blending
engineering policy economics legislation
social and organizational behavior and
that singapore's approach
we sometimes place engineers to write
policies and
non-technical people to write capability
development
but our end goal is to make sure that we
have taken this problem and approached
it from all directions
we move now to the fourth question now
i'm talking so much about cars
because quite recently i exchanged my
gas guzzling car for a smaller hybrid
car
i did a lot of research otherwise known
as car shopping
and one thing i realized that because
i'm now the father of a little boy
i'm no longer looking for the coolest
car that is befitting of the
image of an air force pilot no i spent a
tremendous and inordinate amount of time
looking for the safest car comparing
safety features
and in the end i actually ended up
paying more for a car
with better safety features what i
noticed was that cars were competing and
branding themselves
on safety this brings me to that last
question
can cyber security be seen as a benefit
rather than a cost to manufacturers now
in the past few years we've done well to
elevate and escalate cyber security to
become a management concern at the board
level
but they're still taking the discussions
as a delicate trade-off between
cost and balance but cost and benefits
sorry
between security and usability and
sometimes there's a race to the bottom
where they try and spend the minimum
amount on cyber security just to meet
compliance requirements
the discussions are driven by the mental
model that cyber security is a cost
and it's a cost they have to bear to do
business
customers do not reward good cyber
security habits
but they heavily punish bad cyber
can we flip this around and make
cybersecurity a selling point to
customers
as they become more conscious of their
safety and security
again we learnt lessons from unusual
sources food labels
and air conditioners first food labels
we realized that cyber security benefits
are actually quite invisible to the user
but similar to how we highlight the
nutritional value
and ingredients of food products on the
side of most of them
if you care about your diet you can take
a look at the label and avoid the sugary
drinks
if you are on a specific keto diet you
can again check the label
and buy the food that suits your
requirements but today
i have no way to look at a router and
decide
this router is more secure than that
router
it's invisible to me and customers
cannot pay
for what they cannot see so we started
thinking
what if we could put a nutrition label
on iot
devices on digital products
that's exactly what we're doing we will
be introducing the cyber security
labeling scheme
on network connected devices and we've
got a range from one start to four star
for being the best
again i don't want to give away too much
we'll be announcing all of the details
next week
but think of it like nutrition labels
for food except now on products
we also learn from air conditioners many
years ago
air conditioners were terribly energy
inefficient
and so singapore introduced what we call
the five tick system
over time it became very popular and
today
you can't buy an air conditioner that
doesn't have ticks or has one tick
every air conditioner advertises itself
on four ticks or five ticks
some are even making up a sixth tick
this is a fantastic race to the top and
we want this to happen
in cyber security we want to educate
consumers
and we want to encourage and incentivize
manufacturers to build
better safer more secure products so
that the whole ecosystem moves up
it's a race to the top rather than a
race to the bottom for the lowest cost
we've taken quite a long journey now
across four big questions and from
highly unusual sources
these four questions bring me to the
biggest question on my mind
how do i defend a nation how do i defend
singapore
and the answer in my mind requires us to
change our mental models
on what cyber security is and how we do
it
first cyber security is both a public
good
and a private good so the government
will be taking a more proactive approach
in securing the cyberspace for our users
together with our industry partners
second we want to design digital tools
that are more
secure by design so that the more
convenient
option for users is the safer and more
secure option
third we want to complement our strong
policies with clever engineering
solutions
and fourth we want cybersecurity to be
seen as a benefit
not just a cost and we want the whole
ecosystem to move
upwards to build better safer products
for users
i don't know what the right answers are
i don't know what the perfect solution
is going to look like
but i hope that we're asking at least
some of the right questions i still have
much to learn
so i hope to be back here regularly and
get to know more of you
get to learn from more of you and be
part of the audience in future
thank you so much for your attention and
i look forward to hearing your views
on this speech i'm sure there are enough
hackers in this audience so you can all
find my email
thank you very much