hi everyone thank you for joining today
we'll be escaping virtualized containers
hey i'm involved i'm a security
researcher at palo alto networks and
me and my team's main focus is cloud
security and container security
and today i'm going to walk you through
a research i conducted on a cata
containers which is a
sandboxing solution for containers that
runs
virtualized containers it runs each
container
inside the virtual machine and today
we're trying to escape that sandbox and
hopefully
through that learn a bit about the
container security so
a bit about the agenda for today we will
start off by talking about the
container and container security in
general and then we'll talk about cutter
containers a sandboxing solution like
i've said
and why is that needed and how is it
implemented and
then we'll try to escape the sandbox so
we first need to
break out of the container and then
escape the virtual machine
so we have quite a bit of challenges
ahead and then we'll wrap it up with
some
takeaways from the research so let's
start with containers
there's a misconception that containers
are just lightweight vms that's not the
case
truth on steroids is actually a better
description if you're
familiar with linux but when i wanted to
really sum up containers
in one sentence what i came up with is
restricted processes
running in a separate file system and
the keyword here is
processes at the end containers are just
linux processors running with a couple
of isolation primitives
applied to them and you probably heard
about some of those
isolation as isolation primitives
so for example namespaces define what
the process or what the container
can see so the pid namespace will define
what other processes
a make container say and then you have
primitives which are more related to
what a container can do
like capabilities in a second so for
example capabilities
are based are basically privileges in
linux so you wouldn't like the container
to have the
assist reboot capability as that would
allow him to shut down the machine and
of course that's something you don't
want the
container to be able to do finally the
final piece that really ties it all
together are a control group so c groups
which are all about resource isolation
and limiting the containers access to
host resources
for example you wouldn't like the
container to be able to
exhaust the entire host memory
and launch a denial of service attack
against the host right
and all of those together give allow us
to
separate a process enough from the
system for it to be considered
a container but you still can't really
compare the type of isolation
provided by those primitives and the
isolation of containers
to the level of isolation provided by
virtual machines and and the main
difference is is that virtual machines
run with a
on a separate kernel from the from the
host and containers
share the host kernel and that's really
a fancy way of saying that containers
at the end are just processes and like
any process they interact with the
kernel quite frequently frequently
either a
when they invoke system call or if a
page fault happen
it happens in their context
and that means that like other processes
on the
on the machine and the kernel is quite a
large of an attack surface for
containers to try and exploit
to gain a foothold and a control over
the entire host
right and the the issue here is that
those vulnerabilities don't really have
to be
related to namespaces or to c groups or
to any of the primitives
that really make up containers just any
privileges creation vulnerability in the
kernel in the in a code path in the
kernel that
the container can somehow invoke it
could allow a container to
break out and that's quite concerning in
a lot of scenarios
and to tackle that that issue
a few a solution around a few tools
arrives that allow you to sandbox
container
and cutter containers is one of the
first solution
to actually try to do that and it takes
a pretty straightforward approach at the
sandbox in the containers
it just runs each container inside the
dedicated
lightweight virtual machine and by doing
that you get two layers of isolation
right you get
first the container and then the virtual
machine and you also mitigated the
breakouts which are based on kernel
vulnerabilities because even if the
container exploits the vulnerability in
the guest kernel
he's only compromising the guest right
he still doesn't have access to the host
and really the idea of qatar is to
provide a simple way
to sandbox containers where you can just
plug qatar
into existing solutions like docker and
kubernetes
and have a certain containers run with
an additional
layer of isolation so what's what's the
use case
for this type of solution so first as
i've said kata is great for
untrusted or targeted containers where
you you're afraid the container might
want to
break out and affect the host and it's
also really useful in multi-tenant
environments where you want to
segregate a container from a
several tenants and there are a lot of
scenarios where you
those use cases are useful but cloud
service provider is
is one of the prominent ones because
that's
those two use cases are really the
problem that cloud service providers
have right they run a containers from
multiple customers on the same platforms
those containers might be malicious they
they really don't they really don't know
they need a and they need a solution to
create a strong isolation boundary
between containers of different
customers
right and qatar really fits that
scenario
great and several cloud service
providers are already using qatar in
production
to support customer multi-tenancy so how
do you really
use kata and so
in a normal container setup you have the
container engines of something like
docker
and you also have the container runtime
and that's because container engines
don't really know how to run containers
and when they actually need to they
defer to their defined runtime
and that runtime actually knows how to
set up the container
so normally you would use the run c
which is the default
in industry standard runtime but you can
decide that you if you have an untrusted
container
where you want to sandbox that container
you can just define
kata as the underlying runtime of your
container engine
say docker and now when you run that
container with kata it will be
deployed inside the virtual machine with
an additional layer of isolation
so we at the end of the day they want to
break out of this
of this sandbox so let's see a bit more
in depth how does that work so that's
how you
that's the command to start a container
under docker with qatar
and the way this works is docker will
tell the cata runtime on the host
please set up a container for me and the
canter runtime now needs to set up a
virtual machine
so it will defer to one of the
predefined
virtual machine monitors virtual machine
modules are basically software that
knows
how to set up virtual machines and those
are either a qmu
a cloud hypervisor by intel or
filecracker by amazon
and it will use one of those to set up
the virtual machine next it will also
set up a shared directory
between the host and the guest virtual
machine to deliver some files for the
fro to the guest for example in order to
deploy the
container the guest must have the a
container image
right and and now once that done a
process called the cutter agent it will
start running
in the guest and he is responsible for
actually deploying
the container inside the guest so it
will take the container configuration
from the cataran time and also the image
from the shell directory and use those
two to actually deploy the container
and there you have it at the end you
have a container running inside
a lightweight virtual machine what you
expected and you get
two layers of isolation so now that we
know how things work
let's try to escape the sandbox and why
would you like to do that
well first it's fun and it's challenging
right you have two isolation layers
to break out of and second i think it's
a great opportunity
to learn about container security so
what's our attack scenario
so enterprises use qatar to contain
untrusted and targeted containers
we're that untrusted container trying to
break out and affect the host
cloud service providers use qatar to
support customer multi-tenancy
so we're that evil customer uploading
our malicious containers
and trying to break out and affect the
entire platform and affect other
customers
so as that as a malicious container
what's the plan
it's pretty straightforward we first
need to escape the container
and then break out of the virtual
machine so we'll get to that in a second
but i want to
discuss scope for a bit a cutter is very
configurable
the vulnerabilities i'll show here won't
work in every configuration but we'll be
targeting the standard default
configuration that cut our ships with
it also we'll be focusing on a simple
container guest
on a single container guest under docker
and with kubernetes you could have a
multiple containers
in one guest which some exploitation
gets complex because of that and
in one of the attacks i'm going to show
them still i still need to
win a race condition for that to work
under kubernetes so
we'll keep it simple we will focus on a
single container guest under docker
and finally i want to say this is not an
indictment against kata you know every
software will have
its share of vulnerabilities i really
want to show it just to so you could
learn about container security so our
first job of the day as i've said is to
escape the container right
so we could rely on the vulnerability in
the guest kernel
right and in a privileged escalation
vulnerability in the guest cornell
but that really misses the point right
we want to learn about container
security we want to find an issue
that is related to containers so we want
to find
a native issue with how kata sets up the
container inside the guest virtual
machine
so in order to do that we need to talk
about how do those
issues even look like you know how do
you approach the task of
looking at the container runtime and
trying to break it
so let's look again at the setup of a
containerized environment
so you have the engine which as i've
said like docker which as i've said
doesn't really know how to set up
containers and you have the runtime
which really knows how to
take configuration and set up a
container so the engine responsibility
here is to
generate a secure configuration it will
tell the runtime what restrictions to
set up so
which namespaces and which capabilities
and so on
and the runtime will take that
configuration and apply it
to create a container now when you're
talking about how do you
escape containers you're really talking
about what issues
uh could be indeed in this process so
the first type of issue that could uh
that could arise in this process is in
the initialization of a
of the containerized process you have a
host process the runtime
trying to use untrusted variables like
like the container image and the command
and to set up a containerized process
that process is really
uh that a procedure is really a
complicated
and crucial and a lot of the
issues was found in that process for
example
there was an issue with the runtime
exposing a briefly exposing host file
descriptors
to the container which the container
could have used to break out and that
issue really is a runtime issue
because the runtime is the one in charge
of setting up the container
right and the second type of issue
is really an engine issue where you at
the end you you finish the initial
initialization of the container
and now you have a running container
with a couple of restrictions
applied to it but there could be a
scenario where that container is simply
not restricted enough
right and that really points to a
a problem with the container
configuration
and the restrictions supplied by the
engine and because that that's a
issue with the engine and it really it's
it points to permissive engine defaults
or perhaps to a new breakout techniques
that wasn't discovered before
and normally those are the two areas
where you will hunt for
issues and vulnerabilities in but
when i came to look at qatar i noticed
that it's quite a unique case
because kata is a runtime that actually
modifies the configuration
uh received from the engine and the
reason it does it
is because it turns out that a
configuration generated on the host
need to be adjusted in order to be a
valid
a valid for use to deploy a container
inside
a different machine inside the virtual
machine which has a different kernel a
different
set of emulated hardware and so on but
that's really dangerous to do because
container engines
over the years of vulnerabilities have
learned how to create a
restricted enough configuration that
isn't breakable so for us
if we want to escape we can take a look
at what qatar does and perhaps find
issue with how it modifies the
configuration
and kata does a couple of things but the
main things i want to focus
on is that it discards a several c
groups several control groups
c groups and c groups are tied as i've
said
to hardware resources and because the
host and the guest have a different set
of hardware resources right the guests
have an emulated set
a virtualized set of hardware resources
some c groups just don't make sense
in the guest if you generate them on the
host so
for example a device group the host and
the guests have different devices
and you might think it's a bit extreme
to just discard several
several c groups but if you if i wanted
to understand the reasoning behind it i
think i think the reasoning is that
ac groups are known to be mainly about a
denying denial of service attacks
preventing denial of service attack
from the container to the underlying
machine but because here the container
runs inside the guest virtual machine
it's no problem really if the container
launches a denial of service attack
against the guest right is is not it's
only a health in itself only attacking
his own sandbox he's not only closer to
a gaining code execution on the host
but the thing is c groups are mainly
about preventing the knife service
but some people forget that they're not
only about that
and one device one c group that is
actually quite interesting
which kata doesn't enforce is the
devices group
and let's have a look at what the device
group does so the devices group
restricts the container access to system
devices
quite simply and qatar doesn't enforce
that c groups as i've said
meaning that we inside the container
have more access than usual
to the devices of the underlying system
and when you look and
that system is the guest virtual machine
and when you look at those devices and
think what device could be
interesting to us from the container
well the guest how this is quite
interesting right
we in the container have a view of only
a specific file system the container
file system
but if we gain access to the entire
guest health disk we can now
possibly manipulate it in order to gain
code execution on the host
right so how do you even access a hard
disk
in linux what and those type of devices
are called block devices
well you first need a way to refer to
that
a hard disk to the device and in linux
everything is a file so of course
you create a device file that refers to
that block device or to that hard disk
in linux every device is identified by
two numbers you can see in the examples
in the example here those are eight and
one so you first use make node
to create the device file uh referring
to that device
and then you mount the device file over
some directory
in your system and now when you interact
with the files under the
directory you are actually interacting
with the hard disk right everything you
do in the directory
is propagated back to the hard disk and
that's really the
the easy way to interact with the file
system
but we that's actually not very useful
for us in the container
because the container in the container
we have the make node capability which
is required
to to create the device file but we
don't have the sys admin capability
which from the name you you you may
realize that it's good the containers
don't have the sysadmin capability
but because we don't have that
capability we can't mount
and below you can see a a a cutter
container running under docker
which tries to which can create the
device file for the guesthouse but
it can mount it so it seems like we're
in a bit of a problem even though we
should
have more access to the devices other
restrictions are still
stopping us but there is actually
another way
to access devices in linux and that's by
directly reading and writing to the
device file so you don't even need to
mount them
and why why is that useful for example
if the hard disk has a corrupted file
system and you are not able to mount it
correctly
you might need some direct access to the
device to try to fix things
so there are actually a build
tools like debug fs which you we can use
inside the container
to directly interact with the hard disk
without needing to mount it
and you can see in the example there
that we can see the files on the hard
disk and we have a great indication that
that's really the guest style disc
because when when we inspect the
binaries in it we can see the cutter
agent which we
expect to run to be present on the guest
and it's not only reading access to the
how this is only also
writing access so because we don't have
devices group
we can actually modify the guest hard
disk from within the container
so does that mean we broke out can we
now just
easily execute code on the guest well it
turns out that it's not so easy
and there are two mechanisms in a way
the page question that the entry cache
and because of those changes that we
make at the device level
may not really be apparent to a
processor running on the guest
so why is that in linux when you
when a process interacts with a file
linux will read it
by reading it executing it or whatever
linux will read that file from the hard
disk right
but that's an expensive operation so it
will also keep
a cache of that file content in the page
cache
so the next time a process access that
file then linux doesn't have to go all
the way to the hard disk
and can simply access the page cache
that's great for performance but it's
pretty bad for us
because we're in the container and we
are directly writing to the hard disk
so if we're in the container for example
and we modify
a sh on the hard disk and then some
process on the guest tries to
access a sh if a sage is already in the
page
cache and that process will see the
original version
of the sh from the page cache and not
our malicious version
on the hard disk and that's not good for
us if we want to gain code execution on
the guest
to make things work the guest is pretty
static
and besides the cutter agent and systemd
nothing really else really runs on it
and it doesn't really invoke and
interacts with files
so it's even harder for us to gain code
execution
so how do you deal with that problem so
as i've said the guest is static
so and we can't expect it to just run in
a new
executable so we need to replace an
already running executable
so that's either the cutter agent or
systemd but those as i've said are
already loaded to the page
cache so in order for us
to you know in order for the uh
for modification that we make to the
hard disk to actually be apparent
to guest processes we need to some way
to force the guest kernel
to free the page cache and how can we do
it
well the page cache uses memory that is
currently unused
but if a process wants that memory the
kernel will give the process that memory
because it will say okay
later on i can just read it again from
the hard disk
and and right now that that memory is
used
is necessary by process so when the
container can allocate
small chunks of memory to a slowly chip
away at the
the page cache and the files in it until
we can actually
successfully clear cutter agent from the
page page cache
and now when something access the the
cut agent binary
it will must go to the hard disk so if
it's still
and not completely clear i'll try to
explain it by showing the how the attack
will work
so the attack the scenario is that we
are in a malicious container right
and we want to gain code execution on
the guest
so what we do we first override the
cutter agent binary on the hard disk
but nothing really really happens
because the cut agent process the memory
is mapped to the
version in the page cache which isn't
malicious so in order for us
version to be propagated to the guest to
the process
we need we mel we allocate small chunks
of memory
in order to clear the cutter agent from
the page cache and now
when the execution passes back to the
cataloging process the kernel realizes
okay wait i need to get the version i
need to get cutter agent from the hard
disk again
and now when it does it it fetches the
malicious version that we've put in
we've put in the hard disk so and now
the cutter agent process maps to our
malicious version
and it runs the code that we wrote to
the guest hard disk
so it seems like we can get a guest code
execution
but the truth is it's it's not really
that easy
because replacing a process that re
replacing the binary
that the process is running while it is
running
it's quite tricky because you can
imagine that uh the pro
the cutter agent process is now running
a specific op code
in a specific function and now when we
replace the executable that it is
running we don't know
when that switch will happen so we don't
know where in the new binary
where it will end which op code it will
now execute in the new binary
so it's really hard to get the stable
code execution using that
and the most likely thing that will
happen is that the cut agent process
will just crash
so that's not good for us we want stable
code execution
so instead of the of the cat agent
process crushing being a bug over
exploit we actually make it a feature of
over exploit and we intentionally crash
the cart agent binary so how do we do it
we intentionally override the catagen
binary on hardisk with garbage data
but we also override another binary
system the shutdown with the actual
malicious code that we want to run on
the guest
and then we follow the same procedure as
before we allocate small chunks of
memory
to clear the cut agent from the page
cache and now when execution passes
back to the cart asian process on the
guest it the kernel must read
the garbage cut agent version from the
disk
from the hard disk and the cataloging
process now maps to the version its
memory now maps to the version
and it of course crashes right because
it now maps to garbage data
but now once the cutter agent process
crashes a
system this shutdown sequence is in is
started
which eventually as you might have
guessed calls the shutdown binary
now the shadow binary was never executed
before it is only
accessed when you want to shut down the
machine and therefore it is not in the
page cache and will need to be
directly read from the disk so
now the malicious version of the
shutdown binary that we've put in the
hard disk
will start executing on the guest and it
starts executing from the
like a normal process and not a switch
in the middle of execution so
that we can actually get stable code
execution by doing that
so let's see of them of how does that
work in the demo the malicious
the malicious shutdown binary will
simply create a file in the shared
directory
which is supposed to be only accessible
from the guest and not from inside the
container
and just and we it just creates that
file so we can
see that the the exploit works so
let's see the export in action
so i'm going to show you the code of the
shutdown binary that i'm going to write
run on the guest and the code is quite
simple as i said it just creates
a a binary in the shared a file in the
shared directory called guess is now
malicious so it's quite simple
and then it slips so we can see inspect
the shared directory
so we are now running the exploit with
docker under kata and the thing
first thing the exploit does is tell us
this is my container id
so that's where the share directory on
the host side should be
and we can see that the shared directory
has the normal contents everything is
okay
but now when the container continues it
gets create a device file for the guest
hard disk and it replaces the shutdown
binary with the
code that i've showed you and also swaps
the kata agent binary on the guest hard
disk
and with garbage data nothing really
happens now right
because the qatar agent is still in the
page cache but when we allocate
enough memory we will actually crash the
cutter agent causing our shutdown
process to start running and we can now
see that
it indeed it ran on the guest and it
created the file that we expected
so that's great
and we got a way to break out of the
container and execute code on the guest
a breakout technique that exploits a
direct device access that exploits the
lack of c groups
and it really shows you if you mess
around and modify containers
configuration
you better be only adding restrictions
you you you
you don't really know what other effects
removing
that might happen if you remove a
certain restriction
researchers might find a way to exploit
that to break out
now the container does need the make
note capability in order to
exploit this issue but that's default in
most places and of course
this issue received the cv so the next
thing that we want to do is to
escape the virtual machine and that will
actually be a bit easier
so let's talk about the attack surface
of the virtual machine
so first of all the cutter runtime is a
process running on the host
and it passes messages from the qatar
agent so if there's a vulnerability in
the qatar run time
a malicious cutter agent might be able
to exploit that and gain code execution
but qatar runtime is written in golang
which is memory safe and
none of those messages really are that
interesting so
that's really not relevant another thing
that could happen is the issue with the
vulnerability in the virtual machine
monitor right which is actually the
boundary between the
a guest virtual machine and the host but
we'll uh
not talk about that for for for now
what i really want to talk about is the
shared directory between the
host and the guest because it's quite an
interesting of an attack surface
and the cutter runtime on the whole side
operates on the files in the shared
directory
but the guest can control those files
just as much as the host right it's a
shared directory
meaning that we're in the get in the get
in in a malicious guest
we can manipulate the file in the shared
directory in order to
maybe affect the catalog time running on
the hostess loot
to do some things that he doesn't expect
and one of the most interesting things
that's done with the shared directory
is that it is used to deliver the image
to the guest
so let's see how does that work so
when you're when the guest virtual
machine is started cataran time bind
mounts
the container image to the shell
directory then the container starts
running inside the guest at some point
it terminates inside the guest and then
the cutter runtime unmounts the
container image
from the shared directory so that seems
quite reasonable right
but the problem here is that both mount
and unmount operations
follow symlinks so in the guest meaning
that a malicious guest could
place sim links inside the shared
directory and cause the
qatar run time to target other things on
the host
that are not in the show directory so
it's really easier to see it
in action so let's start actually with
the unmount redirection because that's
easier to understand
so that's how the attack looks we are in
the malicious container and we somehow
broken up to the guest
maybe using the technique that i've
showed earlier and now from inside the
guest we can create
a sim link when we where we know in the
shared
way where we know the qatar run time
will unmount we'll try to unmount
and then we we can actually kill the
container
in order to trigger the cataract and to
unmount
that path in the shell directory and now
when it does that operation
it actually is redirected
to a target of the guest choosing and
that's true a really easy way to create
a denial of service on the host because
of the because of the how the qatar run
time does the unmount operations
uh if we tell it if we create a siblings
that points to
the root directory it will actually
unmount all mount points underneath the
directory making the host
very unusable and not able to run any
container
so let's see a demo for this attack
so first we will inspect the mount
points on the hose see that everything
is fine and then we will run a container
that
exploits both the container to gas
breakout and then the unmount
redirection vulnerability
and it will target the root directory in
its attack in its attack
and once the container is taken down we
can see that
those mount points don't contain
anything anymore on the host
and if we try to do other things like
run a container you can see that the
host is really unusable and you can't
really
use it uh to do anything so that's in
host denial of service
and that's actually a a very nice moment
for us
because we got the first effect from the
container all the way up to the host
and the first sort of a sandbox breakout
and a denial of services is nice right
but we want to gain code execution
so let's look at the mount redirection
you can also redirect
not only the unmount operation of the
image but also the mount operation of
the image
and that's more interesting because the
image as we as i've said kata is used to
run untrusted images so the image
possibly is malicious so let's see how
that attack will look like
so we are assuming that the kata agent
now on the gas is malicious
so the catalan time will tell it we're
about to create the sandbox that's the
sandbox id
and now using that message the qatar
engine can know
where in the shell directory the cataran
time is about to bind mount
a the container image and it can create
a sim link at that path
that will actually be followed by the
catalog time
when it tries to bind the container
image and now that untrusted
possibly malicious container image can
be will be mounted
over a path on the host that the k that
the guest decides on
so and there's those are the several
very interesting paths that the guests
could they choose like slash bin or
slash lib which will allow a pretty easy
code execution
on the host but the problem with this
attack
that is that we assumed that the kata
agent is compromising that the guest is
malicious
even before the container starts running
on the guest right because
if if it's before the container image is
bind mounted
to the shell directory then of course
the container isn't
running on the guest so we actually need
we actually need a way to compromise the
guest before the container runs
and we don't have a way to do that right
now right we only have a way to
get gain code execution on the guest
from the container
and that task so in order to do that we
look at cloud hypervisor
and an issue and vulnerability that i
found in how qatar uses it
so cloud hypervisor to remind you is one
of the free virtual machines
monitor virtual machine monitor options
of qatar and when i tried the container
to guest
a breakout on a cutter with cloud
hypervisor
i noticed that kata stopped broken after
that i couldn't run
any container and when i inspected the
virtual machine image i saw that the
kata agent
a binary on that on the virtual machine
image actually contained garbage data
and that's really concerning because
that was the garbage data that i wrote
to hard disk on the
a from the container meaning that
from one con from in one guest any
changes that we make to the guest hard
disk
under cloud hypervisor are propagated to
the virtual machine image on the host
meaning that one guest can control the
hard disk of all
future guests and because all virtual
machine monitors use the same virtual
machine image to set up the
guest this means that one guest can
control
every future guest regardless of what
virtual machine monitor
it uses and that's really bad for
multi-tenancy right
and beside from being a pretty severe
issue by itself that one guest can
control
of all future guests it's also a way for
us
uh to gain code execution on the host
because we now can exploit the monthly
direction right
we needed a way to for the guests to be
compromised even before the container
runs
but if we have a way to compromise the a
the virtual machine image that means
that the guest can be malicious from the
moment
it boots right so we can it can actually
create the malicious
symlink before the container is started
so
if it's still not that clear let's see
how that full attack will look like so
we are now seeing a full container to
host
code execution it will require the
victim to run our container
twice on their system but that's a
pretty
acceptable expect that's pretty uh
a pretty normal uh requirement because
most people an automated system if the
first container crashes it will just try
to run it again
so let's see how it works the first the
first time the malicious container
is executed is executed under cloud
hypervisor
and it uses the direct device access
vulnerability that we found
to change override the cart agent binary
on the hard disk with a malicious
version
now because we are running undercloud
hypervisor that malicious version is
going to be
propagated and committed to the virtual
machine image meaning that the next time
a guest will be run it will run with our
malicious qatar agent right from the
moment it boots
so now that malicious cutter agent on
the second container run
can exploit the mount redirection issue
create the sim link
and redirect our malicious image to
whenever on the host we want
to gain code execution on the host so
let's see a
demo for that attack
so we will be trying to mount the
container image over slash bin on the
host and we can see that slash bin
is completely normal right now
so we'll run the container under kata
with cloud hypervisor and the first
container
will replace the qatar agent uh the kite
agent binary on the
virtual machine image exploiting a the
vulnerabilities that we discussed
and now the next time our malicious a
container image
is executed it will be running under a
with
under a malicious guest right and that
malicious guest could
exploit the redirection vulnerability
that we found to redirect the image
over bin and now if we want to if we
check out what hap what's happening
on bin in the content in the host we can
see that it has
a completely different files and that's
actually the files of
our malicious container file system and
if we now try to execute something
from a inside the fro a binary that
is inside min we can now see that the
malicious version of that binary is
running on the host
and we actually got code execution from
the container
all the way up to the host so that's
great
right we we set up what we wanted to
accomplish in the start we got code
execution
on the host from inside the container
and really the underlying issues here uh
show how the
the share directory is really a big
attack surface for virtual machines
right we saw two issues
with host app with a host applications
that interact
with the shared directory right the
mountain and mount redirection issue
that we found that we found that could
be exploited
and that could be used to trick the
qatar run time
so there could be issues with the host
application accessing their share
directory
but there could also be issue with the
mechanism itself of the shared directory
normally there is some
process on the host that manages the
share directory and you can actually
find the issues
with that and i found one of those
issues that could allow in qatar to
launch a denial of service attack but we
won't get into that i just wanted to to
let you know that
the mechanism itself could also be
abused so
what attacks that we saw today we saw a
container to guest
a breakout using direct device access
and exploiting the lack
of a device group using a breakout new
breakout technique
and we also saw a guest to host unmount
operation right which we could have used
to launch a denial of service attack on
the
on the host we also saw a way for one
guest
to compromise future guests under cloud
hypervisor
and we also found a way for one guest to
gain code execution
on the host by redirecting the malicious
image mount
and i also briefly discussed a a denial
of service issue that could be found in
the shared directory mechanism
itself now all of those attacks could be
chained together
all of those vulnerabilities can be
chained together to perform a number of
attacks
on the host and i showed some of them
today
all of those issues i've disclosed them
to cutter containers maintainers they of
course they
were fixed and you can read more at this
directory
and aside from seeing like a cool
exploit chain and sandbox sandbox
breakout what can we really learn from
this research so first of all i want
i hope you now understand it uh more
about container security and understand
that containers are only as secure
as their configuration right uh and a
simple way to improve the their
configuration and security
is to drop unused privileges um
the breakout that we saw today uh uh
relied on cup make note right and it's a
great example for that because a
cup make note most containers have that
capability
but almost none of them actually need it
right an ngx container doesn't need
to create device files and interact with
them in any way
so today we the point is that today we
saw a breakout in qatar container
that relies on the magnet capability but
tomorrow it's another breakout right in
a different container runtime that
relies
on another capability that your
containers have
but they don't use so the point is you
really should
remove capabilities and privileges from
the container which it doesn't use
the second thing you you need to do is
to
beside further dropping capabilities is
further restrict the container using
some best practices
and history shows that all of those
vulnerabilities that i've talked all of
the types of issues
that i've talked about in the container
escopology part
most of them or a lot of them could have
been mitigated by simply applying best
practices like username spaces or
running the container
as an as the no not user and that
those type of things should really be
the number one thing you do
if you're trying to improve the security
of your containers
but we also saw a we also talked about
sandboxes today
and sandboxes do limit the attack
surface right
but i want to clarify there aren't
magical solutions that
an attackers would find way to break out
so the point here is
don't bet all of your chips on a on one
bag right
don't only rely on the sandbox
you should really be prepared for that
sandbox to be broken up
broken out of it should be an
enhancement and not a replacement
of your coin security features and the
final thing that if you do decide to use
a sandbox
you should get you should really get the
full potential out of it and enable
its security features cutter for example
has some security features that aren't
enabled by default
that could have been useful uh to
mitigate one of the attacks that we saw
here today
so that's really uh all i have for you
today i hope that you enjoyed it that
you learn about the container security a
bit and i'll be happy to take any
questions