okay hi guys
welcome to our presentation on finding
back doors in applications by max and i
from garth tech singapore
so this is the brief outline of what
we'll be covering today
first a little about us max who will be
covering the ios portion of this
presentation
is our residence ios specialist he likes
digging into mobile applications and
poking into kernel level stuff as for me
i used to be a developer until i found
that breaking programs is more fun than
making them
oh by the way i just published my first
cve so check it out it is 2020
so next i would like to introduce our
organization
we are the cyber security group or csg
of gov tech so gartek is in charge of
driving the singapore government's i.t
systems and technology while csg is in
charge of the cyber security posture for
these systems
so as an organization we believe in
giving back to the community
so we will try to publicly disclose any
vulnerabilities that we find
after working with the developers on it
so we will try to open source any
in-house tools or plug-ins
that we develop so a recent example
is a plugin that we built for google
tsunami that detects the cve 2023-452
so this cve is a directory traversal
attack on web interfaces about cisco
appliances
so this was recently submitted and has
been merged into tsunami's master branch
so our guys also recently presented at
blackhead usa
where they showcased that open source
intelligence honeypots called manuka
that will help bolster the blue team's
arsenal so if you are interested
do check out the qr code on the right of
the slide
so max and i we belong to a division
named
advanced cyber capabilities or acc
within csg this diagram
is a summary of the activities we do on
a day-to-day basis
so our bread and butter is will
generally do
pen testing for mobile applications iot
and web applications
we also do adversary simulations where
we will do phishing operations and we
may deploy
in malicious insiders into organizations
to probe for their weaknesses
so in addition to all of that max and i
also conduct product security
assessments
so product security assessments are when
we test the product for an extended
period of time to make sure that it does
what it says on the tin
and also the probate for any bugs
so as the applications that we test can
vary widely
from thin clients to web applications to
web gateways to
black box appliances we do not have a
fixed methodology
so this is an example from a previous
application that we
tested so we were supposed to test a web
gateway
that promised to cleanse all javascript
from the input source
so we wrote the fuzzer that generated
all permutations of html tags and their
attributes
and we threw it at the gateway so if it
worked the gateway should take out all
the javascript so it would look like the
image on the right
so before you ask yes we did manage to
find a bug where there was a html tag
and a valid
attribute that could result in
executable javascript
so we have since informed the developer
and this has been patched
so now we come to the meat and potatoes
of this presentation
which illustrates an incident when we
found a back door in an application
so we tested this application which was
being used by an agency as part of our
routine technical audit
so this application is a critical part
of the organization's operations
and it is a mix of native and c-sharp
code and it interacted with a back-end
database
so users would log in and they would
adjust the database and manipulate
manipulated
by the program's gui okay
so as we were thrown into this program
without any background
we started with looking for interesting
strings via ida
so we found a string that said answer
password for blank
so this password was not encountered in
normal operations and seemed to suggest
an elevation of permissions
so therefore it's extremely interesting
so we traced
function calls where the string was used
and we found that it was being
called when the program was starting up
so you know as when program starts up
they will generally do things like load
dlls
read and write to registry values
initialize data
so this program did all that but it also
did something extra
it will check the keyboard to see if
certain keys were being pressed
so this was highly unusual as most
programs don't do that
so we propped a bit further and we
figured out what the keys were
and we pressed it when the program was
being started up and viola
the dialog box appeared using the string
that we were looking at
this was awesome so
now we have a next question what is this
password
so for starters we could force the
function to always return true using a
debugger
by passing the password check however
this wouldn't be cool so we decided just
figure out what the password was
so this was what we knew at that point
the password was not hard coded
because we did not see it in either we
did not see it checking any static
strings within either
so we also didn't think it was stored in
the database as this prompt would appear
before the user signs in and this would
be before the application made the
database connection
okay so after more digging we found
these two functions
generate super secret password and call
check password
so generate super secret password will
take in a constant seed
as you can see from the first assembly
line over there
then it will generate this password and
it will pass it to
call check password which will prompt
the user for input
and compare the user's input against the
generated password
so this is the decompile code for
the super secret password function so as
from the previous slide we knew that it
had a constant seed value
then it will take that get to this date
and time
and it will do a bunch of operations
that involve division
modulus by shifting source and ends and
it will return the six character string
that will change
every week so now
since we knew that the password didn't
change that often we decided to just use
the debugger
and break after the function ended so we
could get out the register generated
password from rcx
so this is the password in its full
plain text glory
so after we put the password into the
prompt so we were greeted with a console
when we started the program
so this does not usually happen when the
program starts up so it's like yes
so from the console we discovered that
we could run stored database procedures
that were previously defined by the
developers so these procedures they did
not have any access control so our low
privileged user
could just run any of them so this one
is an example where we could pull up the
user logins with the sensitive
information like login ids
property phone numbers and their login
sessions
so what was the impact of this so a user
by having such a password can run stored
database
procedures like what i mentioned and
also raw sql
so this would let the user run do things
such as changing passwords for other
users
and using raw sql to modify the database
potentially bypassing any application
constraints or logging
so why in the world did the developers
put that in
so they put it in because they wanted to
ease their remote debugging maintenance
and deployment operations however they
did recognize that this could be an
issue
so they generated this function that
will create a password that will change
every week however since the seat was
always the same
somebody with this program could
generate this password which could be
used in
any installation of this program across
any organization
okay so before i enter my session i
would like to touch a bit on the
challenges that we face when auditing
this software
so we were very low privileged users in
a very restrictive environment so we
could not patch the binary nor could we
change the underlying os
so we also had an issue in communicating
with the developers
the developers being developers they
felt that
this wasn't a big of an issue because
they preferred to go with the ease of
development and maintenance so they did
not find having such a backdoor such an
issue
so with that our council were close and
let me hand over to max
who will talk about his presence his
experience in encountering a backdoor in
ios applications
over to you max hi i'm max
so today i'll be talking about some of
the applications that i found on the app
store
so during my free time i like to look at
applications on the app store and
in this instance i'll be talking about
local authentication bypass
which i found on the app store so
we actually look at password managers in
this instance because
password managers hold a lot of safe
passwords
and some of them actually are easy to
bypass
because their verification checks are as
simple as string
check like true false value so let me
give you an example
this is an example of one of the
password manager which i analyzed on the
app store
where the verification of the master
password is just by comparing if the
string is equal with the input password
so whatever you input is not actually
used to decrypt the vol
this allows an attacker to actually use
debugger to easily bypass
the save the master password they have
set and access the same password they
have set
so we are actually here to see if you
can actually entrust
your password to password managers that
you'll find on the app store
so as a learning experience we selected
this password manager called
log password manager to conduct a test
so it can be downloaded from the apple
app store and it's an average of four or
five star with
500 over ratings so when we first
launched this application
it asked us to set the master password
for the password manager
well i set one and then after they asked
me to set a password key
and i didn't set one because i don't
believe in password teens
next the password manager asks you to
back up the master password
and the complaints that if you do not
backup this master password
there will be no way of accessing the
app if you ever forget this master
password
additionally you can see from the screen
they will double confirm and tell you
that
there's no recovery passcode so if you
forget your master password
you should not be able to access this
application anymore
to analyze this application our team
uses
a booking framework tools to observe the
application flow for this password
manager
so i've listed up the syntax over here
so what we want to do is we want to
observe
the application flow when you enter the
right and wrong password
so as you can see here when you enter
the right password
the application will call each success
login passing one as the argument
and then when you enter the wrong
password it cause each success login
passing 0 as the argument
looking closer into this function we see
that it's just doing a simple string
comparison
where it is comparing the input password
versus the master password
if both strings are equal it returns
true if not
it returns false
and then when we look into the assembly
code for this section
we see that when you enter the right
password it calls set date flag
and then cause is success login passing
one as the argument
so we now know that when you keen the
right master password
each success logging will be called with
the parameter true and then you display
all the save passwords
however when you key in the wrong
password the application should just
only prompt an error saying that
you have key in the wrong password but
when we look closer to the code
we realize something strange and that
was
this application was actually checking
for fixed string and this fixed string
was
what you see in the screen star hex u6
hex star
well this was very unusual because if
you are actually keen
in the wrong password why would you
actually need to check for
an additional fixed string so that led
me
to actually try out what is actually
this
fixed string and we actually found out
that
there's a secret back door in this
password manager so just by keeping a
user input of star hex06 hackstar you'll
write false to the key pair
k password on and it totally removes the
need for master password to unlock this
password manager additionally as you can
see in the screenshot in the right
all your saved password entries are
available for the
attacker or anyone who has physical
access to your device
so they can see all the existing entries
that you have on your
password manager set next
we dive in further to look at this
important key value pair
um k password on so we see that this k
password on determines if master
password is needed to access the app
and k login password stores the original
set master password
and both of these are stored in this
group key list file
where we actually tried to extract it
and extracting it
we found another thing from this
application
as you can see in the screenshot in the
bottom left
for the k login password it stores my
orgini set master password
soho this app not only has a door where
you can actually access it through
the the fixturing star hex06 hackstar
if someone actually managed to get hold
of your device
he can also retrieve your master
password to unlock
your your password manager so so much so
for 10 users to backup their master
password and that there's no recovery
password
when you see that's totally not true
looking further ahead we're thinking
well this is only one password manager
there are like
tons and tons of password manager that
you can find in the app store
so we wanted to look specifically at all
the apps that were developed by this
developer
so we search it up and we found four
applications
three of them were actually password
managers so
we tried to look at the free password
managers which were
password manager fingerprint lock and
log password manager
so we tracked the other password manager
which is called password manager
fingerprint
and yet the same interface as the
original application we tested
so immediately i tried the same backdoor
star hex in the six hexta
and it worked so this shows that the
developer actually
sort of reused the code base and without
testing the paid version of
the password manager we highly infer we
infer that there's a high chance that
this password manager
would also have the same backdoor
so what would be the impact of this
finding is that someone with physical
access to your phone could access
all your saved password on this password
manager
assuming and why would the developer
even do this
maybe because he wanted to have a backup
recovery code in case
some of their users forget their past
master password
so as a mitigation we actually reported
to the
developer multiple times since january
and as
of now actually the app is still on the
app store
so other than testing ios applications
our team also looked at a variety of
different
technologies such as smart locks
and iot devices so our team
will actually publish this variety of
security articles on our
medium page as you can see so you can
feel free to scan the
qr code to access a page
okay so this year
gov tech will also be organizing a ctf
event
and we'll be releasing more details on
stack 2020.
so stack 2020 is a developer
concentrate our developer where the
government and the
developers come together where we will
share how we can
better secure our applications as well
as uh
we will share what the government is
doing and
for this ctf there will be a variety of
prizes to be won
including cash prizes so more details
will be released
soon so thank you for your time
you can reach out to us on angelister
and mexican linkin
or anjali said twitter thank you