so welcome everyone to our presentation
today
we are going to present star to league
forwarding there and back again
um my name is claudio canella i'm a phd
student at guards university of
technology
you can also find me on twitter or send
me an email if you have any questions
my name is lucas gina i'm also a ph.d
student in graz
don't be thrown off by the shirt some
below this later you're exactly where
you're meant to be
and my name is michael schwarz i'm a
faculty at
sisbe helmholtz center for information
security
and you can reach all of us on twitter
via email if you have any more questions
more than you could ask after this talk
so what is this talk about
so we want to figure out in this talk
how stores and loads are handled on
modern micro architectures
what happens if we load a value from a
location where we previously
stored some value we also want to look
at the meltdown mitigations
and see what they changed in this store
and load
path in the micro architecture and see
whether we can figure out some new
mechanisms from that
that allows for some new
and of course we also want to mitigate
those attacks that we find
so we'll also talk about some clever
mitigations here
okay so first we need a bit of
background
so the manual model you can have as a
programmer from the cpu
is fairly simple so instructions are
executed in program order just as you
expect just as you write them down
the pipeline stalls when the stage is
not ready
and if data isn't available we also have
to wait
so this can look something like this
where we first fetch into the l1
instruction cache
we decode the instructions then we
execute them
if necessary we access that we perform
accesses to memory
and finally we write back into the
architectural register file
i always thought that microarchitectures
are much more complex
than that well that is a very simple
micro architecture
and in general in modern architectures
you want more performance
and more performance means super scalar
and superscalar means that we do loads
of things in parallel
so the question here is if we don't have
a dependency between
different instructions and we have many
execution ports available
why don't we do loads of things in
parallel
so we execute them in whatever order is
is convenient and supports are available
and importantly we retire them in the
order that they're in the program
so from the outside from programmer's
view everything still stays the same
so now an interesting situation is when
a fault happens
and there are already newer instructions
in flight that are already calculating
on data what do we do with them
so for this the processor tracks
the architectural changes that
instructions would make
and if there is a fault it undoes the
out-of-order effects
and we then call those instructions
transient
that's pretty smart yeah it is
and those transient instructions don't
leave any architectural trace
they're basically gone so at this point
you might wonder
if they don't if they're undone if they
don't leave any trace
what are they even for what's the point
of them or what can we do with them
more as an attacker and so i said
remember i said
the processor tracks the architectural
changes and reverts those
it does not track microarchitectural
changes so we can encode data
that we calculate during uh transient
execution
into a microarchitectural state
do you have an example for
microarchitectural state yes i don't
know what you're talking about
yes i do one of those stateful
microarchitectural elements
is the cache that's a simple way
and so ah the state in the cache is
if a cache line is present or not and so
let's have a look at an example
we access a variable and try to load it
into a register
and so the first time we try this the
cpu will have a miss and it will have to
load from ram
we'll get a response and it will be
cached at that point
and the next time we try this slow yeah
and the next time we try this we get a
cache hit
and that'll be much faster
so the dramax is very slow the non-drm
the cached access
no surprise here it's much faster and
this difference is
very very clear and we can determine
this with high reliability
so in the future of this talk when we
talk about transient
transient instructions and their effects
this is how we generally see them
architecturally how we
make use of them we encode them in the
cache
so when we look when we look at the how
core is made up we've talked a bit about
the execution engine the front end
so what's left is the memory subsystem
and so here first we have a load buffer
and the store buffer
connected to the load ports and the
store ports in the execution engine
as a next level we have the l1 data
cache with a
tlb and light field buffer with a second
level with the l2 cache
and another tlb and then off core we
have the l3 cache
and the ram finally and so these three
caches are what we can use as just that
to encode our transient uh our transient
data
so wow that that looks complicated
yeah so why don't you tell us a bit more
about the store buffer
okay so let's see what actually happens
if we have some data stores and data
loads
that we are executing that has to go
through all this machinery you just
explained before
so if we move some data to the memory
so if we store some data then what
happens is that in the execution
unit we have the store operation it has
to store some data and for that it uses
the store buffer
the store buffer helps that it does not
have to wait for the store to actually
complete
it just throws it in there and then the
store buffer handles
the rest of it and the store buffer
then can go to the l1 store the data in
the l1 if there's space in l1
and in the meantime the execution unit
can already
continue with some other instruction
you've said that before with this out of
order execution
so now we do something maybe stupid
we write some data to memory and then
immediately afterwards
we read from this memory address the
data back that we just wrote
we of course know what this data is but
what does the cpu do
so the cpu for loading a data it uses
this low data part in the execution unit
and it uses a load buffer where it also
has a kind of a queue
which stores what values to load and it
knows this address
it has to load that and usually it would
go
to the l1 memory check that l1 memory is
this data
there if there's a hit then retrieve it
otherwise go to the l2 l3
or dram but the thing is
cpus are quite smart nowadays
so what this additionally does it checks
whether somebody some address was
already
stored before some data stored to the
same address so if there's a match
between the store address and the
address that we load
we can do a shortcut we don't have to
wait for the memory
so we directly take it from the store
buffer
and do the store to load forwarding to
this load
so this is a lot faster so we have this
this data that goes there into the
execution unit memory substance
subsystem and then back again before it
even
reaches the memory subsystem that the l1
or l2 so this makes it a lot faster
and is a nice optimization that we have
in modern cpus
of course we can optimize that further
so we don't have to check for a full
match we can optimize that even
more so we can do something like a
normal comparison
and if it's true we do the forwarding
and this can be
okay so it's true positive everything
happens as it should we only forward the
things that actually match
maybe we also have some errors in the
comparison there because things go
really fast
and we might have other stores and loads
in between
so maybe we also have some true
negatives
where we don't have some uh
something there and we're also not we're
not matching anything
we're not forwarding anything this is
also fine that's true negatives
and this is basically all true positives
and true negatives that we
exploit in this talk here wait a second
that sounds familiar isn't there a
second attack that does
exactly the same isn't there fallout
yes because these are not the only two
cases in the store buffer
we can also have some let's say kind of
errors or optimizations in there
like false positives so we have
addresses that are actually not the same
but the data is forwarded
so this one is exploited in fallout
but already fixed in modern cpus
and then also the other direction like
false negatives
the address is actually the same it
should forward the data
but it doesn't do so and this effect is
exploited
inspector stl
so all these store buffer magic in there
are optimizations for the transient
execution
so for the parts we don't see if this
optimization is wrong
architecturally we don't care because
everything is undone as luke has
explained before
so we will never see that and our attack
here
just relies on the store buffer to do
everything
correctly so correct matching correct
forwarding
on the same addresses
interesting part here that we are going
to exploit
is that stores can only be forwarded
if we store something to a valid address
of course that sounds kind of intuitive
we can't store somewhere
that's not a valid location so this is
also described
in the intel manual so it says like the
store execution phase
it fills the store buffer with linear
and physical address and data
and one store address and data are known
the store data
can be forwarded to the following load
operations that need it
so if everything is known then we can
forward
this data to them to the load
and what does it mean with valid and
invalid
a virtual address that has an actual
physical backing to it
so we have some data page where we can
really write to it
then this is a valid address and then we
can
use that the interesting thing that we
already know from meltdown
is that permission checks on intel cpus
are a bit lazy and they're not done
up front but at some point in between
when we already do that
so that's what that was exploited in a
meltdown attack
and we want to exploit the same thing
what happens with distort load
forwarding when we store some data to an
address
and then read it back but this address
is inaccessible so it's still valid
there's a physical page behind it
but maybe it belongs to the kernel so we
couldn't access it
does this mechanism still trigger
so let's try it's not that difficult we
write some value
onto our kernel address that of course
gives us a fault segmentation fault
but out of order execution instructions
are still executed
so in this out of order execution we
read
the same address back and code it in the
cache as lucas explained before
and see if we get the same value back
if so we know that the store to load
forwarding that's actually working
although there was a fault so that's
nice no but
what does that get us what can we do
with this
that's a good question i bet you've
heard about
address-based layout randomization
especially in the kernel
we have that so we randomize all the
parts in the kernel the modules
and the kernel image and every time we
put
it's at a different location so the
modules that are different locations the
kernel image this is a different
location
so we don't know where the kernel is and
so we can't
mount reliable attacks on the kernel
because we don't
know where this the image and the data
is located
okay but with this like this explanation
i can
i think i know what your attack is that
you want to do
so i think it's called data bound we can
see here we have again a memory
subsystem with the store buffer and the
load buffer we have a little bit of code
and the blue
square here indicates the location of
the kernel
within memory and mem here is just an
array where we store
data and if we time this right now
using the primitive that lucas told us
then
we just see the timing is always the
same because we need to fetch it from
dram right so now what we do with this
stored load forwarding logic is we
simply write to a kernel address
some value in our case the value x and
later on dereference it
use the value that we get back from the
kernel address
as an index to our memory and then we
should observe
this x if distorted load forging logic
works so let us try this so in the
beginning there is nothing met
so as michel said we cannot write this
there's no store buffer entry for this
so we don't find anything we can repeat
this
and we never get a value back but now
we find the location where the kernel is
actually met and
suddenly we can write to this address we
get a stop of
entry when we load then from this
address we get distorted load forwarding
effect
we get it into the load buffer and the
data is forwarded
and used in subsequent instructions for
the access to mem
and if we then use our primitive again
we can suddenly see that the
axis time for x is much slower and
slower
and we know that there is something met
our kernel is there
so the question then is what if an
address is valid
but unknown so we know it has a physical
backing
but it's maybe not in we don't know the
physical address yet because it has not
been used recently
so what if we simply repeat data bounds
we can see here if we have unmapped
regions we have
mapped regions as well if we get our
data
and in the first try of data bounds so
it's forwarded on the first try
we know that this in the dlb so it has
been recently used
because we know the physical address if
we get it on the second try we know it's
valid but it's not in the dlb
and in the final case we don't get any
forwarding no matter how often we try it
then we can infer that this address is
unmapped it's not valid
that's a nice observation claudio but i
don't think it has any security
implications i mean
what are you going to do that we already
broke kslr
what are going with that additional
information no i think we can do
something i think
there's an attack primitive here and all
good attack primitives need a name
so i think we're going to call it fetch
and bounce so now we aren't agnostic of
a tlb anymore
we know it's there and we use it so in
this case
we see four kernel pages that are all
mapped
and now what we're gonna do is we're
gonna do it again but
with fetch and bounce we only access
once each we don't repeat
and so when we do this for the first
address we can see that we got a lookup
in a tlb
there's nothing there and so when we try
to store
we can't get a valid store buffer entry
and so we also can't get forwarding
and so now there's a tlb entry but it's
already too late
we've moved on to the next address and
the same thing here
tlb is entry empty there's no entry
again we don't get a store-bought entry
so now but for his
third and uh third address there is
already a tlb
entry and so when we try it now we get a
sob of
entry we get forwarding and in our next
address
we get the x back and so now what we've
learned
is that there that recently this page
was actually used by the kernel
and so that's a new attack primitive
here for the last page again it's not
mapped and so we get nothing back
okay so what can we do with this we can
observe kernel activity
and more specifically for example
something like the modules
we can check which module is used and
which code page in it is used so as an
example
we use a bluetooth module and maybe we
connect our phone to it
and play some music and then we can
detect
when there is some activity here
okay so does that really work it does
really work or is that just
theory it seems a little bit far-fetched
so can you show us that this works
because i don't
okay okay okay all right
let's let's go into detail a bit more so
the first step
first thing you have to solve is we
don't actually know where the modules
are
because they're also hidden by kslr and
so
unlike the kernel we might be able to
find them but we need to
do some more to identify them and so
what we do is here
in this demo we scan the entire
module address space as you can see
that's very quick we
identify contiguous pages of memory and
we can
infer that those are modules
and we can read the size of the module
with that and so now we can match
unique sizes to modules with unique
sizes
so here we've identified three we're
going to check in proc modules
if the addresses are correct so we're
going to check for bluetooth
that looks correct we're going to check
for the
wi-fi module that we tried to identify
that looks good as well
and lastly the thunderbolt module we
also correctly identified
and you can also see that the font sizes
match
because of sizes again are how we
identify the modules
so this doesn't work for modules of the
same size
so that's the first step we know where
our target module is
in this case the bluetooth module so
what you've basically shown us now is
that
this is data bound this is data bounce
right this is later bounce you still
haven't shown us
that fetching bounce works correct let's
use faction bonds with this
now we know where the module is we know
an address let's say
some page in a bluetooth module we want
to attack and so now what we're going to
do is we're going to sample
uh we're going to sample with fetch and
bounce this page in a bluetooth module
then we're gonna clear the tlb for this
core because they're
the tlbs are per core and not shared
then we're gonna jump to the next core
and do the same thing
and so with this we move through the
cores in order and give the bluetooth
module time to work and then we sample
again
and so this is what it looks like in
action
we get hit rate
and you can see as soon as we hit play
on the right in the phone
we get correctly identified once
and so for the bluetooth module
something we've noticed is that there is
some after activity
so now we get zeros again we're gonna
start
and we get a very sharp identification
here again
so you can see right now we have about
one percent of detection
which is because of that's how often we
sample
so again you can see that there's the
temporary resolution for first detection
is fairly good in this case we just
don't
do this very often and
you can see it is all very stable and
in general from the from the music you
get
this is a very important plc this is
very dramatic
right so
it works okay yeah i believe all right
we can do something with that that's a
great demo
thanks so thanks we have something else
as well though
another variant but for this we're going
to have to go a bit back in time
and mikhail is going to tell you a bit
more about that
exactly i was just thinking so you
talked about out of order transient
executions and stuff
what if we actually combine that with
another transient execution attack that
we know spectre
so if you test short recap for spectre
it's about
um the variant one is about bounce and
and
predicting uh bounds of accesses and if
the cpu
predicts that something is in bounds if
you do an imbalance check
then everything is faster because it was
predicted correctly
um if the miss if there was a
misprediction it might be a bit slower
but it's still okay
if it predicts it's not in bounce and is
actually not in bounce it's also fine
the prediction was correct but yes one
corner case
that is actually exploitable the
spectral attack so if the cpu predicts
that something is in bounds but it's not
inbounds
so that means we can transiently access
data out of bounds
of an array and if you look at the
simple if condition here that checks
whether an index a given index
is smaller than four and then x is an
array that has
four elements and after this array
there's some secret data in memory
that we shouldn't be able to access
architecturally
because we have this bounce check here
in the if condition
and uses this data here as an index for
some
[Music]
memory for example a font file here to
do pretty printing
of this letter that we get from the
array
so if we look at that the first time the
cpu has no idea if this condition will
be true or not
it speculates something maybe it
speculates for it's wrong
okay nothing happens then if we actually
execute that on the cpu
the cpu sees oh this condition was
actually true
because 0 is smaller than 4 and it loads
the first value
from memory it uses that to index this
font file that we have here
and all of that is put transparently
into the cache
and the next execution we have the next
index
one is smaller than four the cpu is like
oh it was smaller before
it was true before so let's speculate
that it's also
true now it speculates that it has to
get the
data from memory it does that looks it
up in this font file
everything is put in the cache and when
it actually
executes then architecturally it sees oh
my prediction was correct
everything is fine nothing has to be
undone perfect
super fast and it continues like that
for the next index and for the next
index
and then we get to index four and four
is not smaller than four
but the cpu is like yeah it was always
through this condition
will be true as well this time so it
starts
fetching memory that's actually out of
bounds of the array
so it shouldn't be accessible and takes
that
looks it up in the font file puts it
into the cache
and there we have our problem we have
something in the cache
that correlates to the secret data in
memory that we are not supposed
to access and as lucas said before
we have this attacks that can measure
the timings
and also audio exploited that and we can
see that from the cache
and infer the secrets from that
and now we could also combine that with
our fetch and bounce method so if we
have this
bounce check here this condition and
then we could access something based on
this index here
then it's not only put into the cache
but also into the tlb
so then we can use fetch and pounds
to iterate over the memory instead of
doing a cache attack
we're doing a tlb attack with fetch and
bounce
and we can infer that secret from the
tlb
when it was a tlp hit or not so whether
fetch and bounce
succeeded at the first try or not
that's very interesting but i remember
there was specter and wasn't there
another vulnerability as well
that's i don't know it sounded really
scary something like nuclear stuff
something like that ah you mean meltdown
yes
meltdown was also at the same time but
it's a different attack
so this exploits the the permission
check that we also exploit here
uh with data bounds so that permissions
are checked later on
and with that it was possible to
basically read the entire memory
because even inaccessible memory could
be accessed transiently
encoded somewhere and then restored with
a side channel attack
and as the kernel maps all physical
memory basically
we can read arbitrary memory with
meltdown so
yes you're right super scary yeah but i
mean
we know it's scary but how do you fix
this i remember that
it was like this huge performance impact
so
isn't there a smarter way to fix this
right so
we know intel did fix it but we don't
really know how
right so let's reverse engineer this
let's see
we make a few assumptions here so
starting the cpu we think
might be a bit costly and it might also
require some re-engineering of the
pipeline
and we know that these mitigations were
rolled out fairly quickly
so let's make a guess here let's say
data is just zeroed out on a load if
that load falls
but the load still happens so we can
test this hypothesis
so first we just do meltdown and
meltdown unsurprisingly on mitigated
cpus now returns
zero and not the data anymore so that's
that's good
mission accomplished right so
we confirm our hypothesis of how this
works with some performance counters
so first we look at memory stalls and we
compare
intel cpus that are vulnerable that are
mitigated and an amd cpu
and so what we can see is that on a
vulnerable cpu and on a mitigated cpu
for user and kernel accesses there is
the same
percentage of stalls that is not a
hundred percent like it is for
non-present
and on an unaffected cpu such as an amd
cpu
we see that non-present pages and
current pages both stall 100 of the time
so we can look at a second counter the
issued micro-ops on the load ports
and again here we can see that with and
without
mitigations user and kernel
address accesses have the same number of
microbes issued
and that again points towards our
conclusion
that loads still happen in the
background they just zeroed out
and so just to be sure we tried a third
measure
that is when we have an access that
misses the l1
we measure this uh we look at this
mispending cycles counter
and again we see that between
unmitigated and mitigated cpus
the ratio of user and kernel accesses is
exactly the same so again
this leads us to the conclusion it's
just zeroed out the
load happens in the background anyways
so
that's very nice but when i see this i
immediately think that
can we use the hardware based
mitigations for an attack because it
sounds like we can do that
why don't you build one well we've seen
already ksl outbreaks we've seen data
bounce which was such an
attack and when we've looked at these
mitigations we
thought okay we find another one let's
call it echelod which is a very fast and
reliable case law break
and it again simply encodes the return
value
when we access it simply like a meltdown
attack in the cache
and actually load for instance it can't
be summarized with
this very short sample of code it's more
or less a memory access
encoding data that we load from the
kernel edge that looks almost the same
as before so
yeah but different now but it's a little
bit different because what you hear
exploit now is that
we exploit this stalling behavior when
the cpu
uh when the cpu tries to access the
memory that is not
backed by physical memory so we can
change this kernel address and we never
find
we always stall but at one point we get
to this location
where the kernel is actually placed and
now we see
the effect that these mitigations have
because now we have a faulting load
and we get a zero back so we know now
where the kernel is placed nice right
that's pretty cool
but the question then is always what's
the performance of issue
right because that's what we care about
in the end we want numbers we want speed
yes
and we evaluate it on several cpus with
mitigations without mitigation because
it also works on those without
mitigations because
then it's simply meltdown and
we also tried it because we have 14
loads so we need to somehow
prevent our program from dying we place
the
faulting load within speculation within
tsx which is an intel feature
or simply by using a segfault handling
and as we can see
it is very fast on the i9 i9
with dsx we have like 29 microseconds
and a perfect accuracy with an f score
of
one so we are very reliable and very
fast even faster than previous state of
the art
and for the other cpus with speculation
we sometimes see that it's not
completely perfect but this is more or
less because
inducing speculation doesn't work always
reliable
so this might be the explanation for
that
what we were also able to do is we were
able to show that these
that this attack works in sgx and we can
also use it in javascript
so now in the beginning we talked about
that
we not only want to attack something but
we also want to defend against these
attacks
and we need softwork around for that and
we don't just want to mitigate
data bounce or actual load we also want
to mitigate
other attacks that have been designed
previously and so
in order to do so we need to come up
with what
are these attacks exploiting so we
looked at the
at all of them and we discovered that
they all exploit timing differences
between mapped and unmapped pages like
we saw
just now with echoload and data bonds
for instance as well
there have been has been another attack
that simply differentiates the kernel
based on the different page size it uses
and
there's another one that can
differentiate the timing difference
between executable and non-executable
pages
so if you want to prevent all of these
attacks what we need to do
is we need to mitigate all of these
attack vectors
so our mitigation is called flare it
stands for fake load address response
and we can see here the current linux
design without flare in place
and we have the beginning of the kernel
is somewhere
somewhere randomly placed with kslr and
the code section n
is directly followed by the data section
so
code is obviously mapped
using executable pages and the data
section without
so we need to prevent this in the first
step let's take the
look at the mapped and unmet pages we
simply fill out
all positions where the kernel can be
met quick and easy solution right of
course
and we're done now right and more or
less so we
we fixed the data bounce and actually
load for instance but others are still
problematic so in this step what we also
need to do is we need to ensure
that all of them use the same page size
so
all of them use four kilobyte pages for
instance in the next step we mitigate
the difference between executable
non-executable pages
so we simply split the range for the
kernel place
executable code in the first half and
non-executable in the second half
so the switch now is always at the
predefined location that the attacker
already knows
so with this simple fix we've fixed
all of them so how does this now look we
should for instance perform flare
we've seen this before but now
everything is mapped
and we always get zero back so that's
echo load right
that's actually no right
so when we take another look at all the
other attacks
we have seen actual already before uh
prefetch this is the one that was able
to differentiate the
different page sizes we can see here
unmapped one gigabyte four kilobyte and
two megabyte pages
with flare there's nothing in there
anymore
databands we've already seen that one
also not differentiable
the double page fault simply tries to
access something twice
and measure the timing difference
because if it's mapped the second axis
will be fast
also not possible anymore dr k improved
the double page fault by using tsx
so we also don't see it there anymore
and fallout
is also hidden and we had already
discussed the difference between fallout
so we also implemented this as a proof
of concept
which you can find on our github page
check it out we don't take any
guarantees that it works
flawlessly but in my practice system
i never have probably won't never
happened to me so
yes all right so what
do we take from that so we see again
optimizations whatever they are in a
micro architecture
they introduce security problems
and sometimes these mitigations
can fix the main problem but this can
still be some edge cases that are
overlooked and are still exploitable
and we've seen that once again just like
with meltdown
we require software mitigations to
prevent these edge cases
with that we are more or less finished
with our presentation and
we hope you enjoyed it and we are
looking forward to any questions that
you have
thanks for your attention