hello everyone
thank you for attending our talk it's a
pleasure to share our research on wifi
security with you
today we'll be talking about wifi attack
service and how to
find high risk when repeated in wifi
driver
first of all i'll allow me to introduce
my partner
and myself my name is shayhakko i'm a
security researcher from
our singularity security lab and my main
research field is software vulnerability
while you and johnny are security
researchers or
vital security lab they are criticized
funding and hiking lte devices
next warning and i will show you this
topic
let's start our topic this is an
overview of today's presentation
we'll start with introducing some
mainstream wi-fi chip manufacturer
in the world and the wi-fi one
repetitive in recent years
so that you can have a general idea of
the wi-fi devices
we use and their current security status
then we'll move on to some key attack
services or wi-fi
in the end i will explain our
vulnerability discovery
measures and share two vulnerability
cases
without further ado let's begin with the
background
wi-fi technology has been around for
more than 20 years
most of the wi-fi chip used by smart
devices today
are produced by broadcam pro cam realtek
meteor tech malware intel famous
products
that use broadcast a ipo computer iphone
and samsung mobile phone qualcomm
snapdragon mobile
platform is widely used instead android
phones
intel wi-fi chip are mainly using laptop
computer
in which lenovo and dell laptop are used
intel wireless network adapter meteor
tech
wifi chips are used in neutral network
adapter
and android phones real-time wi-fi
chips are mainly used in bluetooth and
usb network adapter
the most popular usb wear wireless
network adapter
in china use real-time web achieves
malware
microsoft surface pro you use malware
wifi chip
now technology is bone perfect history
shows that
wi-fi also has many vulnerabilities you
after more than 20 years of development
its security remains to be a big person
in 2017 the remote remotely exposable
vulnerability of broadcast chip exposed
by
google project their multi
android and ls as long as the table
and the target device are in the same
wi-fi network
they can launch the user insensitive
attack
in 2018 denis introduced a remote
vulnerability exploitation of malware
weaponship
accelerates converse which is also an
attack that
can be launched without authentication
in 2019 us search released a number of
security alerts
for broadcast wi-fi chip drivers which
affected
android linux retails and other devices
i also already attacked can launch
attacks
so managers wi-fi packages these attacks
can be launched without authentication
no user interaction is required and no
physical contact is repaired
ordinary users this candle attack is
very difficult to province
as the reality really supports all
at least just individual cases to get to
the bottom of this
we took a closer look on wi-fi security
and from
that this is actually a big attack
service
next we will will focus on key
attack service on wifi wi-fi chip
is used using intelligent devices it's
it not only
sends and receives communication package
from datalink layer but also interacts
with system and software the
communication interface
and the operating logic of data a link
layer
high on remote attack surface the finger
on the left
release several remote attack surfaces
with great influence
the finger on the right shows a local
attack surface
of wi-fi a software can communicate with
wi-fi driver through our control
interface or wifi driver
and because the code is in the kernel
driver
the code running authority is very high
if there is a vulnerability
it can cause local employability
escalation
well we mainly focus on the remote
attack service
first let's talk about the association
stage
the three interaction of station
associating
access point this is the most surprising
and widely
used function of wi-fi access point
refer to wireless router and other
devices that generate wi-fi hospital
a station refer to mobile phones or
computers and other devices connect to
wi-fi
how does the mobile device access the
wireless network
the connection of weld network is very
simple as long as the network
cable of the device is inserted into the
network port network system is connected
to the wireless network
need to complete this part of work
through
the management frame the mobile device
search the network system the network
system verify the mobile device
finally the mobile device is associated
with the
network sector the the where learners
network
system is connected
the bio function is mainly implemented
by measurement frames
such as bitcoin frame prop 3
authentication frame
association frame etc this page takes
the structure of association requests
frame as an example to introduce a
structure
of measurement free the management frame
is composed of frame handle and free
body
the frame handler contains the mac
address of target device and
source device the frame board is many
composed of information elements
the structure of information elements is
a typical tlv structure
tag loss value but it usually contains a
batch element id field or
as long field underwear or long
value field some information elements
also have an
extended element id field more
complication
in the more dangerous however in the
process of station oxidizing access
points
only sweet message interchange and water
is a
complexity of such a simple process the
complexity lies in the information
element
first a variable loan structure
generally there is a central
range for the loss or information
element
such as ssid information element which
is usually
0 to 32 bets but the actual value of
this structure
can reach 255 bets
if the launch is not very fast in the
power it's easy to
cause buffer overflow this scandal
vulnerability is easy to find
but even if it were found more than 10
years ago
that doesn't mean then you won't make
the same mistake
second there are more than 200 kinds of
information elements
information element carries a candle
information
it must be a lot of effort for coder to
implement these functions it's because
of the
abundant information elements that
refine post such rich feature and
functions which
also expand its attack surface third
the extensible interface for the future
is reserved in the information element
and the operation of the extended
information
also increases the complexity of the
program which also increases the
security risk in the vulnerability this
is later we will give an example to
illustrate the risk brought by this
operation
first progress customer mass information
element
vendor specific information elements can
not only contain the
content of defined by each manufacturer
but
also include wi-fi protection
sense and other functions it carries
so many functions in an information
element which requires a higher level
of information element passing fifth
structural content structure taking as
an information
element as an example as a represents
robust security network the information
element enable station and the access
point to exchange security information
it contains encryption suite
supported by devices the encryption
series has a count field
and the corresponding suits at least it
may cause
conflicts between the loans or
information elements
and the counterfeit which can easily
cause problems
all these can all these are
challenging for coders not to machine
some
undefended parts in the 802.11
specification they even create infinity
possibilities
wi-fi authentication stage this doesn't
refer
to the part of the interaction or
authentication free
but the actual verification of the
password information
of station us other
authentication methods such as wp wp2 is
a four-way handshake or
eapoll package the more complex one
is with handshake certification or wps
and the more complex is the
authentication of
enterprise wpa this stage
involves more computation of
cryptography
aggressor and attacks based on
every ceramic vulnerability usually
occur at this stage
for example krbc vulnerability
of course there is also the possibility
of memory corruption
and vulnerability
wifi also has many other functions and
features such as spectrum management
tdls radio measurement fast bss
transition
so on which can be well researched
next i'm going to introduce our owner
ability discovery method a blackbox
protocol
value is based on a hundred 800 2.1
specifications so we can use it to find
wi-fi
model of different manufacturers on
different operating
system this is our first
process in fast mode patch with our
frozen target
such as excel port station p2p then the
fuzzer will
permutate frames with specific special
mutation strategy and send frames to
targeted devices
if tax is a crash we will
try to generate richer plc and analyze
vulnerability
we designed three and five moves
including
access point mode station mode and p2p
mode
in exactly point mode our father is a
thick access point
which interacts with real station device
in station mode our father is a thick
station which interacts with real access
port
in p2p mode our photo is a fake p2p
device which interacts
with real device all these three
modes power pre-machined remote attack
surface
in our opinion the efficiency of fat
is significantly affected by the
quantity of mutation strategy
strategy our mutation strategy is the
primary reason that we can find out
some vulnerabilities to start we tested
a target device just through a laptop
and a wireless network adapter many
vulnerabilities were found
within 10 minutes and the remaining
paths were found within
several hours the
dynamic mutation degree in the left
graph acts three types of mutation
strategies
in the red graph which make our mutation
strategy
more flexible and can be tested both
widely and deeply the same mental
frame mutation we mean measurement
frames absent
in an output or an ordered manner
by saying information element mutation
we mean we will
combine various information elements in
an orderly or
disorderly way to create a malformed
management frame
by saying mutation of information
elemental content
we mean some views or information
elements
are muted and malformed information
element
is generated
now i would like to show you how to
mutate a mutated
management frames during the interaction
with an example
the first method is to send the
measurement frames
according to the normal logic of wifi as
shown in the finger
we can mutate the problem passed on
mutated
probably pass and association factor
in this way following the staging
machine within
the deeper logic can be tested
the second method is to send the
measurement frame
control frame and the data frame
randomly different
combination of management frame and
control
frame may trigger new code pass
next we will talk about information
element mutation
take association requests as an example
as we know frame body is mainly composed
our information elements so we can
mutate the frame
by adding information elements changing
information elements or deleting
information elements
lastly we'll talk about mutation or
information element
content take the as an information
element as an
example we can see that information
element is
composed of our various fields recent
researcher a group cipher or ui
with a random value and don't give
paralyzed
cipher suit tab or random value so this
information element
becomes abnormal now
i will hand it over to my beautiful
partner when
she will go on to introduce and
introduce a following slides
after the free mutation we need to send
them to a target
the ao2.11 particle is at the data link
ledger
we can use the monitor mode of the
awareness network adapter to send the
communication package
at the data link layer the command
on the right graph is to set the network
card to be
monitor mode and the cellular channel we
have tried these three schemes
to send frames each with its own
advantages and disadvantages
the rail link has the advantages of the
no
crisis and the stable performance the
disadvantage
is that the stem stem field can't be set
but it doesn't seem to affect cindy
frames
the ar9271 network
card can ensure the content of the
package is completely
controllable but the monitor mode is not
stable and
it often be stuck the advantage
of sdr is that the sending frame is
fast and the content is controllable and
disadvantage
is that the cost is too high
regardless of the varieties of wi-fi
devices
from different manufacturers and
platform
we can send frames through network
adapter and
files however things goes easier in
linux
we can communicate with wi-fi module
without an
awareness network card by modifying
source code
as shown in the figure firstly we create
a queue
in the kernel then a program in the user
name your keeps
input the mod frames into the queue
whenever the kernel nature receives an
external frames
and will take out a multi-mouth
mouthful frames from the queue
to replace the external frame so the
wi-fi module in kernel will person
multitask
frames like the picture on the right the
advantage of this way
is that it can improve the efficiency of
fasting
and ignore the influence of the
awareness network adapter
if we find a crash and then poc
streaming is completed
it is necessary to analyze the cost of
the vulnerability
through reversing binary file in most
cases
we don't have the driver source code and
can only analyze vulnerability by
reversing binary file
generally speaking the latest drive does
not have
simple information we can only search
for the symbol information of the old
version on internet
which is also very helpful to us also we
can use our idea script to restore the
function names in the branches
because some streams contain function
names or related information finally we
are able to
analyze vulnerabilities by binary symbol
information
and the function stock after system
crash
in half a year we discovered 18 wi-fi
zero-day vulnerabilities like the
pictures
now let's move on to the next session
vulnerabilities
since most of the vulnerabilities we
have discovered are still being fixed
by the manufacturers we can't disclose
details of those
so what i'm going to introduce are the
public known ones
now i will introduce two vulnerabilities
we found
this one is the stock buffer overflow in
the wi-fi driver of usb
awareness network adapter on windows
platform
this vulnerability can be triggered in
ap
and station mode when the windows
platform
opens the mobile hotspots through this
network adapter
or connecting with a fake hotspot
will trigger this vulnerability
these two is are the main causes of the
vulnerability
they present the data rate and the
extended data rate
which is supported by the device the
workshop screenshot
is normal i.e as you can see
it is usually 8 bytes in length and
vulnerability exists in the association
part
regardless of whether it is a request or
response as long as the two malicious
construct ias are carried
the vulnerability can be triggered
pseudo code is used here to show the
logic
of this vulnerability this function is
two pers supported resign in an extended
supported rates ie
and then copy all supported risk to the
global variable
we can see the lens chair can be
bypassed
the first if statement is to determine
whether the length of the supported
rings ie exists 36
if we set it to be 36 it come
bypass the first one and the second one
if conversion
and then we can set extended supported
rings beyond the normal range which
would trigger buffer overflow later
this is the poc demo
the vulnerability exists in the intel
windows wi-fi driver
it is a memory out of band's writer
vulnerability
when the windows system shared a mobile
hotspot through this network adapter
the attacker can trigger the
vulnerability as long as
contacting with it causing the system to
be blue screen
we first discovered this vulnerability
in the thinkpad
x240 loadbook this
notebook uses a wi-fi like 260
awareness network adapter currently
the wi-fi network adapter has been
discontinued
and the thinkpad x240 is also a very old
notebook
so this vulnerability exists at least in
2014.
after testing it was found that this
problem
exists in the corresponding windows
drivers of the above national awareness
network adapter of intel
floating the latest ax
200 chip
the core of this vulnerability as a
supported operational classes
ia this is to declare the
operation class is supported by station
the structure is not complicated
one byte in the information re
represent a clause use code to identify
this vulnerability logic
from the name of the function we can
know that the function is to process the
challenged supported
by the association frames in this
function
the function of uto regulate
clause 2 channel list is called the
circle the function writes 500
bytes to the blocks of memory
each time and accumulated the memory
address
when the number of a course is too many
it would
cause the memory to write out bands
the number of times of this loop is
determined by the lens field of the
supported
operation classes information element
that is
they can be up to 255 times
this is obviously low check on the lens
field
pass in front user this is the poc
demo
now to conclude our presentation
user above mentioned vulnerability will
attack
pretend to be a mobile phone or a
computer
and initiates a con connection request
to a hotspot the panels sent will cause
the security
damage to the kernel resulting the
delight of survive of the pc operating
system
nowadays personal computer mobile phone
and
more and more iot devices supported
awareness
network communication and the security
of their underlying communication
practical is
extremely important and the security
research on this practical has
important venue most of vulnerability we
found
were in the network assess stage in fact
there is still a lot of research
filled in the authorization stage
and other functions okay thanks again
for
participating i hope our sharing today
is helpful to you guys