hello everyone my name is Katie also
known as Insider PhD welcome to level up
this is a talk on eight ways to never
get a dupe again and really it's eight
ways to almost never get a dupe again
dupes are gonna happen when we do bug
bounty hunting like they're just kind of
a fact of life like sometimes we're just
not quick enough but sometimes you're
actually hunting in a way which like
encourages duplicates and that's really
what I'm going to be talking about today
how to change your bug hunting
methodology to kind of get out of like
that finding duplicates or not really
finding anything and moving to you know
actually finding bugs getting paid for
them
so first of all is dupe suck
like they just are a sucky experience
that that it kind of doesn't feel good
but actually quite a lot of hackers
especially the top hackers very rarely
get duplicates and there are people who
genuinely you know can go to
um life hacking events and not find a
duplicate and find complete unique bugs
and this is really what inspired this
talk it's from my experience in Vegas
this year of going to live hacking
events and being one of those people who
didn't get a dupe who did just find
unique bugs
now sometimes people are just really
fast like sometimes people are just on
it they get an invite they start hacking
they submit things you know five minutes
after they've gotten an invite but often
there's actually a difference in the
methodology and the type of bugs they
look for which is actually causing this
and is why they don't get as many
duplicates so I'm really gonna share
kind of my tips on how I avoid that
getting duplicates so you can change
your methodology to avoid it but the
thing I want to make clear first of all
is that dupes really aren't a big deal
in bug grounded hunting dupes are really
just a factor of life like it's the risk
we take thankfully in bug hunting all we
waste is our time and we don't have to
spend money
but they do suck like they just don't
feel very good and this talk is
specifically for people who are getting
more dupes than actual paying bugs and
findings or if you're not finding
anything not even dupes or if you submit
something and then you get like n a
so this is ready eight tips from me on
how I avoid duplicates now before I tell
you how to avoid duplicates I've got to
tell you how to get a lot of duplicates
and I would say these are the four ways
that people get a lot of duplicates in
bug Bounty the first is just doing recon
and nothing else Recon is great for
learning about your target it's super
helpful in finding assets but if you're
just scanning your Target and just
reporting like sub domains without
necessarily doing any additional
Research into if they might be
vulnerable to something what they're
actually vulnerable to kind of everyone
is doing that everyone is kind of
getting these Recon scripts together
they might be subscribed to
um things like security trails and
getting this data in and you're
basically racing against the clock who
gets there first and people who make a
lot of money on just doing recon they
already have infrastructure set up this
isn't just them having like a single bot
this is them having multiple servers
multiple scanners as a way of processing
reports in such a way that's really as
soon as something goes live they can
instantly report it
the second is by using nuclear or other
Von scanners now most bug Bounty
programs are already hardened targets
not necessarily always sometimes you do
get code that's just been released that
does have low hanging bugs however on
the off chance a bug was left in by the
time there's like a template added to
nuclei somebody else has already found
it and again it's more about speed and
less about the kind of bugs that you
find right so the one way this can avoid
getting dupes is if you take you know
the results and actually do the research
dig in find out why it's coming up as a
positive and you know show an impactful
POC but again you're limited there by
your speed and that's the issue with
using something like nucleate it's a
race against the clock there are people
who have got Bots that will do
everything from get invite scan those
with nuclear report everything and then
move on to the next
client super spammy yeah but again if
you're only using nuclei this is the
issue you're going to have
and this kind of goes into my next point
which is being slow if you do have a
really automated tool based approach you
really need the infrastructure behind it
uh people who do really well at this
approach and don't get duplicates have
got customer alerts they use slack or
Discord and react immediately they might
have Bots that even write the report
like the people who have these kind of
really highly automated flows have a lot
of infrastructure behind them and that
does cost them a quite a bit of money as
well
and the final thing is following bug
Bounty tips only Twitter is really
really helpful it's great for networking
it's great for connecting with hackers
but if you follow like bug Bounty tips
everyone is using the same tips by the
time somebody tweets about one of their
tips they've already been using it for
days weeks or sometimes even like months
so you're getting information that's
probably reported like two months ago
and has just been marked as resolved
you're not necessarily getting the tips
that are going to be helpful like right
now you're getting the tips that were
helpful for this one person and that
doesn't mean don't ever try these like
they've totally a place for things like
bug Bounty tips especially if you're
still learning but if your current girl
kind of move away from getting a lot of
duplicates getting a lot of paid bugs
instead like being able to um and if
avoid this is really really helpful
now the tips I'm going to give you to in
this talk is really boils down to like
wanted piece of advice which is be
different because that's fundamentally
what we need to be if we want to have
these kind of Highly automated
approaches if you want to use new kids
one use phone scanners we want to use
Recon it's build automation like that
the advice to avoid do because that is
build automation build quick
infrastructure make sure your data
centers are in the same location as your
target to be even faster it's about
speed
but there's another approach and this is
my Approach my Approach is be different
like my Approach is to look in places
that other people are look in ways that
other people aren't so what I'm really
giving you is kind of a slice of my
methodology and how I avoid duplicates
but you might be thinking all of this
okay be different it's really good
advice but how how do we actually be
different so tip number one look in
weird places and when I say weird places
I mean hamburger menus
so let's have a look at twitter.com so
Twitter has a bunch of common
functionality right if you think about
Twitter you might think you know post a
tweet reply to a tweet delete a tweet
you might think of following people
retweeting maybe adding something to
bookmarks maybe sending a DM editing
your Twitter profile and that's all like
the core functionality of Twitter
yes absolutely you should test that but
the high chances are that's already kind
of been tested and probably been tested
a lot instead we can look in weird
places so things like
um Twitter for marketing so on Twitter
you can run advert campaigns you can you
know have ads shown to people and
there's a whole bunch of settings around
things like ad spend and AD campaigns
and it's like a tweets you want to run
and who you want to Market to that can
still be an impactful place but it's not
necessarily something you instantly
think of
a similar thing is things like Twitter
communities
um things like Twitter circles where you
kind of having these like exclusive
places on Twitter that people can tweet
that might be vulnerable if they are
vulnerable to attack things like um you
know sharing private information uh some
other things are things like the careers
pages and applying for jobs or Twitter
for developers and creating apps you
have lists topics moments Twitter
circles newsletters Twitter for
professionals Twitter ads analytics the
setting and privacy things right The
Help Center all of these can actually
still be sources of bugs and often are
still in scope
but have like this much wider
functionality which is really helpful
you know for not finding duplicates yeah
everyone who tests Twitter is going to
look at posting a tweet but is anyone
going to dig into you know is there an
SQL injection or cross-site scripting if
you make an app in this particular way
like if you say you make your own
Twitter bot can you cause an SQL
injection or an xss attack right like
people aren't necessarily going into
that level of detail
so the kind of the weird places
um hamburger menu so any menu that you
don't think someone will click on go
into it go through all the functionality
uh third-party Integrations third-party
API Integrations
you know a lot of like business tools
integrate into things like Slack
test that integration you know could you
send a payload via slack and will that
actually fire on your target I actually
found something like this it was an ssrf
of you know it was in the integration
with another uh tool that then fired
uh plugins so for uh things like cms's
uh WordPress Joomla V bulletin PHP BB
forums all of those will have like
Standalone plugins that might do things
like keywords might do things like allow
people to play games might be adding
functionality like a chat room always
test plugins if something doesn't look
um like it belongs definitely dig into
the plugins and don't just report that
plugin is there report vulnerabilities
with it power user function so a lot of
you know people who use these tools
every day will have functionalities and
way of working around the limitations of
a piece of software that actually might
end up being a security bug on its own
so look at discussions people are having
look up forums look at stack Overflow
look at Reddit
and see what those lesser used
functionalities are
browser add-ons mobile apps anything
like that is just always full especially
browser add-ons no one really looks at
that but it can be a great place to find
injection points for things like
cross-site scripting or SQL injection
that might then fire on the main app oh
Isis RF as well customization options so
things like Tumblr
um Squarespace
will have these like customization
options that you can edit you can change
the background color you can add images
you can you know change the link color
that opens up so many more points that
are actually reflected on the page that
can be again huge for things like
cross-site scripting
image upload image manipulation so a lot
of people will go on a site like Reddit
and paste in their own link they'll
upload it to like imga but actually
Reddit has their own image upload
functionality so that can be a really
great place to find
um you know your standard like image Pro
things like image tragic
and especially if it's an image upload
people don't really know about
um you know people might try an avatar
image upload but are they going to chat
say try out I don't know a background
image upload for a customization or
something like that right
Community features can be great so
forums blogs support some of these might
be third party and we'll talk about
those in a minute but these can be
really great places that people aren't
necessarily looking in and even if you
don't necessarily hack the community
feature like the Forum it can be really
great for finding more weird
functionalities my favorite like place
to look for things is Google so on
Google I will look at my target as like
best hidden features of my target best
Integrations API developers tools
add-ons and I'll add the year advice for
their tart their like target audience so
tips for selling on Etsy as a small
business or YouTube advice if you're
just starting
they can be great for giving you like oh
by the way there's this whole analytics
platform that you maybe you didn't even
know about that actually you could um
you could be hacking on
um to any kind of updates RSS news like
what new functionality has just been
released that you can have a look at
um one of the great ways is like looking
at like configuration for those so I use
an example I was testing a version of
this app that was like essentially it
was like a Beta release so I couldn't
necessarily tell what was new in the
beta version that I had and what had
already been released so what I did is I
went and I was like Googling all the
little individual pieces of
functionality that I found to figure out
okay is this unique is it worth me
trying this or is this something that's
been in the app for ages again it's just
Googling and trying to understand the
app
and weird places doesn't mean the impact
isn't the same uh things like tweetdeck
on Twitter for example so you might
think as like I can't take over via like
account info right let's say you could
change anyone's email address super and
factful you can tweet as anybody you
could take over a verified account
whatever
high impact
now tweetdeck has this feature called
tweet deck for teams and essentially you
can invite people to tweet from an
account using tweetdeck teams now if you
could force somebody
to be added onto like your team and you
could tweet as them that could have a
similar impact to an account Takeover in
like being able to post tweets with
somebody else but
it's completely it's completely new
right like that isn't necessarily
um going to be like a duplicate with a
regular account takeover this is like a
completely new bug it's a completely new
way of doing things
now often when you kind of do this you
might come across the fact that a lot of
this is actually third party
um so they may only not pay out this
depends a lot on the client because some
clients absolutely will pay out because
they will fix it themselves
they have the money they have the
experience they have the developers to
actually fix issues with a third party
however a lot of people won't and they
will essentially send it over to the
third party and ask them to fix it as
like a customer
but they weren't reward a bounty because
again they don't intend to fix it
themselves so my recommendation for this
is to learn the common functionalities
you see this a lot in
um
forums if you see discourse if you see
zendesk freshdesk intercom
Greenhouse all of these are like
owned by third-party companies that just
tend to be branded and when you see
these a lot you'll kind of see the same
kind of systems across many different
clients so you end up kind of knowing a
lot more about it you can scroll down to
the bottom and often it'll have like a
powered by but actually you can pay to
get these removed sometimes and a lot of
companies will do that because it looks
a little bit less professional so you
really have to kind of recognize the
software
um kind of as you see it if you don't
necessarily recognize it I honestly get
like a bug hunting friend and be like do
you recognize this kind of forum
software and if they've seen it before
it might be a third party however some
things like things like the bulletin
um or that that like they pay for and
then they set up as their forums they've
got the codes they can actually make
fixes it really does depend on
um kind of the target itself and
especially what's in scope so the
fundamental thing is really can they fix
it if it's something that the client can
fix like updating to a certain version
report it if it's not something that
they can fix it's actually hosted on
greenhouse.io and it's just a sub domain
they probably can't fix that not worth
reporting
tip two develop expertise and this is
really the secret of the pros so the
advantage that Pros have is that once a
platform like bug crowd knows what
you're good at they'll send you relevant
invites so I do API testing I get API
invites and this kind of means that
every invite I get is is not necessarily
tailored made towards me but it's
something that I can get started on
really easily
now if you have these um kind of skills
you can actually just tell things like
bug crowd that you have them things like
certifications you can add resume skills
and interests you can connect different
accounts
um primarily what it will do is based on
the bugs that you've reported so being
active on the platform reporting bugs
that will get you better invites
essentially once they know the kind of
bugs that you find and that you get paid
for they will give you more invite which
means that you get fresher invites with
less competition there should be more
bugs there and there's less people to
compete against smaller cohort of
researchers things like a bug bash less
opportunity for everyone to find the
same bug but
but that doesn't mean the the it's low
like it's zero right it means there's
less likely that you find a duplicate
because you've got to remember that when
you get a fresh invite like this the
other people who also have an invite
have the same kind of skill set so
you've really got to like dig into the
data and see so common expertisers that
we see mobile applications iOS Android
mobile application is really common a
binary so that's like desktop
application super rare skill set
um really good to get into especially if
you want to look at like binaries that
are powered by like webview engines I
think about things like Discord that
essentially use JavaScript but are kind
of binaries a code review
um any kind of code review doesn't
matter what language is that is really
helpful Cloud now I think if I was
learning anything I'd go for cloud
AWS Azure Google Cloud platform all of
these are really unique expertises that
a lot of people don't have people like
me who have API API is actually fairly
common which is why I kind of pivoted
myself into more doing mobile
applications like mobile apis and they
do differ from desktop apis as well
things like Automotive iot Hardware
they're a bit more specialized but if
you have the ability to gain that
experience you will get so many more
interesting invites that are with
smaller cohorts any kind of
certifications you have if you've done
pen testing before then absolutely uh
you should tell people you've done pen
testing and make that you know a skill
you talk about because that might get
you on to things like next Generation
pen tests that bug crowd offer but this
bug crowd isn't the only platform that
kind of wants you see certification
certification can be really helpful
now if you look at the data so this
comes from the bug crowd Inside the Mind
of a hacker report
70 of uh
bug crowds kind of
like total pool nose web application
testing
so if you want to look at the kind of
hit this is the data as it's presented
in the report this is the data that I
have then put into a graph for us
because then you can sort of see the
difference right so 70 of everyone on
bug crowd knows how to do web app
testing so there's 30 that don't know
web app testing essentially now the
seven percent of their Network pen
testing but this is like not a
percentage of that this is like seven
percent and some of them might also know
web out testing if that makes sense so
we see the jump right between web app
pen testing and the next like skill
is huge it's like a older magnet like
it's 10 10 times as many people know web
app testing and when we look down here
iot Hardware like one percent binary
reverse engineering is one iOS is two
percent API is two percent code review
is two percent even recon at this point
was three percent so actually if you do
gain these skills you're already looking
in like one percent of the total bug
crowd population so if you think about
you know there's a thousand hackers who
have like a certain skill that might be
invited
actually you know 70 of them are going
to know where about testing but only one
percent of them is going to have like
binary or reverse engineering skills
so being able to get yourself out of
this web app Bubble into all these other
ones is huge and often the skills aren't
necessarily that much different like
they're not completely new skills you
can just learn them
so what aren't the pros doing so this is
I think a really helpful graph that is
kind of not really explained very well
in the report
um because like it's hard to read so
this is how I've chosen to to represent
the same data so the dark blue here is
like noobs so noobs here 70 of noobs say
they know web Ted testing uh regulars I
think as people who have found a bug
before
um are like up here and 80 and then
Elite so these are the top hackers you
know any very small portion of them uh
say like mainly web and you can see here
that actually beginners do try things
like iot Hardware are mobile or looking
at apis
but again the difference between this
and this right is huge so if you find a
few bugs and you'll say specializing
mobile there is less than 10 of regulars
that are doing at mobile and even less
when it comes to the elite right and if
we kind of break this down into some pie
charts of the elite hackers we've got a
huge amount of them all doing web right
and even regular is a huge amount of
doing web some of them are picking up
you know iot and Hardware but again it's
very small slices of this pie there are
opportunities if you're in the noob
group to specialize in these areas and
get into these areas of the pie chart
right the ones where you're barely
competing because everyone else is
focused on web
so how do you develop this expertise at
time
essentially this is kind of how I'd
recommend I've kind of done this in like
a linear like line because my slides are
landscape not because this is a process
that goes from step one to step two to
step three this is you're constantly
learning if you don't think I get like
books on API hacking you are completely
mistaken because I I read books and API
hacking but if you don't know where to
start number one easiest place to start
is a textbook textbooks are designed for
people who have no idea what they're
doing and importantly they give you the
vocab to do more research so
if you've just started saying mobile
hacking you may not know the differences
between like Android and Linux but by
reading a textbook they'll walk you
through it and that will give you the
vocab to be able to say oh okay they are
completely different things or like Java
and
um like Android apps Android apps are
written in Java but they're kind of
different things
they are really beginner friendly so if
you don't know where to start and you
want to learn something new start the
textbook 100 if I was learning something
new I always start with a textbook
step two is YouTube videos so I actually
wouldn't recommend starting immediately
with YouTube videos because although
they're beginner friendly they have a
playlist take you through the material
they kind of rely on you knowing the
vocab or you being okay with picking up
the vocab as you go I'm different people
like feel different like levels of
comfort with that
conference talks so conference talks are
designed for a specialist audience but
it doesn't assume expertise so what I
mean by that is if you go and listen to
like a Defcon talk you they like they
expect you to know what cyber security
is they don't necessarily expect you to
know in depth the specific area of cyber
security they're talking about they
assume specialism not expertise and
quite often they are marketing their
Works they do picture at a lower level
to get people interested in what they've
done
um articles and white papers so they're
slightly different to blogs
um so I've kind of put them together
here because blogs can really be for
very different audiences when I say
articles and white papers I'm kind of
referring to things like rfcs for
example
um they're kind of Highly specific to a
certain topic but they are kind of
designed for these different audiences
often again designed for specialism not
necessarily expertise but require not
just a knowledge of like the vocabulary
to actually follow these but maybe some
additional like information that you may
not have
now these are probably some of the
hardest things to actually read so
really when I put these next to you
should kind of be like going through
them by the time you get to this
um so CTF practice Labs if you are a
Hands-On learner getting experience in
an actual environment can be huge for
understanding something what I really
like to do is I like to make my own Labs
so my background is software engineering
I was like a data scientist and a
software engineer I know how to write
code I know how to write code in like an
Enterprise environment
um so I kind of understand what
production code looks like so when I
hear about a new vulnerability I use an
example of ssrf
being able to build a lab means that I
understand that better
now some people aren't necessarily
programmers they don't want to do Labs
um like I do but they can really range
in difficulty not every CTF is for
beginners we often kind of advertise
ETFs as beginner friendly
um but some of them are actually really
difficult and require really expert
knowledge and finally hacking eventually
you need to actually find the bugs you
have to actually practice so
what this can kind of look like is you
download a textbook let's say from no
starch press on
um iot hacking you watch some videos of
people doing it you might listen to a
talk
um or you might you know watch your CTF
being played you might read some
articles about other people find bugs
there you might you know get an iot
device and start hacking on it and you
kind of go back to the YouTube videos as
you're working like you kind of have
this you know backwards and forwards
aspect but you always learn like you're
always developing that expertise now if
you're not sure what to learn at the
moment I pick Cloud so cloud services
things like AWS
are so so so so so common nowadays they
are
um some of the most common ways of
Hosting websites they are
some of the most common ways of
um kind of storing things like private
uh like keys for example uh if you heard
recently about the Uber hack one of the
things I had was AWS and access to AWS
like got most of their hosted services
so definitely if you don't know what to
pick I'd probably pick cloud
now my third tip is about researching in
depth you should spend more time reading
about the bugs that you're looking for
than actually hunting for them and I'll
use an example so I was testing an app
recently it was an email app and
uh kind of like uh Gmail here
had like an unsubscribed link and I was
like hmm
how does that actually work though like
I can press the unsubscribe link I get
an email back saying you have been
unsubscribed
but how does that work like what what
makes that work
so I go and Google it and I say oh
there's this header on email called
emails called list unsubscribe and it
has this like mail to link and it also
has like an HTTP link like okay that's
interesting what else can you do
so I go through the rfcs for the list
unsubscribed email header to understand
what the requirements are for this email
header you know how does this link work
and I thought okay so list unsubscribed
mail too how does the mail two like URI
scheme work so I ended up looking into
that and I was kind of going through
this like ssrf at the time
um
this has kind of been my like summer
theme has been learning ssrf which is
why I'm talking about it so much but I'm
like okay so ssrf you know requires me
to get data this has like a header which
has this like mail to unsubscribe this
clicking this button is then sending an
email back am I sending an email so I go
into and check if I'm saying I am
sending an email okay so this is
clicking on this link automatically like
okay might be ssrf going through some
research in ssrf how do I test for it go
down the rabbit hole of an ssrf sheriff
and I kind of end up
in this Wikipedia rabbit hole right like
I'm I start out with this how does how
does this unsubscribe button appear and
I end up digging into you know how
emails work like all the headers in the
email because what are all the headers
in the email anyway right
so this ended up with me going down this
rabbit hole and I found a butt like I
found like three ssrfs by going into
this like rabbit hole and were any of
them related to the mail on like the
male 2 in the list unsubscribe header no
they weren't they were related about
something else completely but that idea
sent me down this rabbit hole which then
inspired more ideas I did a ton of
reading and a ton of research to try and
understand how this button was appearing
now the problem is if you look at things
like the WAFF bypass exercise that often
gets shared
you just see you know save to notion
links bug Bounty tips xss Academy bypass
but why does that work because when a
cami fixes this issue
like this particular payload are you now
screwed like do you can you not now
cause a xss because something about this
isn't working and I really like some Dev
sagwan if you don't follow me on Twitter
his tweets are great and he wrote this
really good it's like four years old but
it's still a really good
um
way of understanding uh WAFF bypass
and he created this really gray image as
well which like explains every part and
why a laugh bypass works this is so
so much better like it's so much more
helpful it's so much more in-depth and
you're understanding why it's not enough
to just copy a payload from Twitter like
if it doesn't work what you just give up
if it does work it might be a duplicate
or it's something they already intend to
fix for or it's like something where
they've already had it submitted a
minute earlier by understanding how
Exercise Works in depth you can modify
it yourself rather than wait for
somebody else do it for you you know one
laugh change can fix many different
laugh bypasses so being able to be up to
date on you know how laughs are working
you know as soon as they cut as soon as
it comes out because again this was not
posted the same day this bypass was
found there's no way because why would
you waste that right like bug Bounty is
competitive
now a lot of the marketing and hype
really frames bug Bounty as it being
easy money
so if the information on things like
payload all the things can't just be
copy and pasted people tend to give up
learning a vulnerability deeply it means
you're already ahead of people just
trying payloads you can create more
impactful reports and often clients
don't pay for an exercise they pay for
the impact of that exercise if you can
show you using an exercise to get an
account takeover P1 if you just proven
xss P3 the difference in like how much a
bounty can be can be thousands in those
in those two and really understanding of
vulnerability and taking the time to do
the research huge
now where can you research web security
rfcs I'll be honest like literally two
years ago I would have told you don't
bother reading them now I I 100
recommend reading rfcs if you're not
sure what a header does like you see it
in HTTP you see an email look it up in
an RFC figure out how it's supposed to
work and what the requirements are
listen to conference talks by people who
do uh web security portswiger have a
really good like web security uh
research like group within ports wigger
and they do things like uh cash
poisoning right like they're doing the
research there listen to the talks don't
read the like bug Bounty tips go to the
source go to that conference talk really
try and understand it
Twitter is a great source of information
and distraction but there are people
tweeting about articles they've written
on these re-technical subjects and again
listen to them don't just listen to say
me when I make a YouTube video right uh
Google Scholar if you're a student you
likely have like a ton of access to like
white papers that you may not even
realize blogs great resources but find
out what their sources are when they
write them like my videos for example
great places to start but
I'm not giving you all the details
absolutely ask me call me out and be
like Katie where are your references you
have a PhD shouldn't you have references
in your videos absolutely do
and some of this is about note-taking as
well now I'm not going to go too much
into this because I don't think anyone
wants to listen to a like hour of me
talking about how to take notes
um but I'm gonna go very very quickly
into how you take more thoughtful notes
so there's two ways of kind of
organizing information one is kind of by
content what the information is about
think about that as having like science
inside science there is biology inside
biology there is plants inside plants
there are cell walls right like you have
this way of kind of hierarchically going
down but a better way of note-taking and
a better way of thinking about notes is
actually thinking about the context when
you need this again what do you need to
search for so use an example
vulnerabilities you could sort your
vulnerabilities by vulnerability type
you could go injection SQL injection
but I would suggest you say sort them by
vulnerability location reflected input
then you might want to have
um SQL injection you might want to have
xss together because when you see
reflected
input being outputted
you can test for everything that affects
that particular location
or alternatively sort by impact
different ways to take over an account
but again it's if you need this again
what you need to search for so my system
and it's kind of developed actually over
the past few years is
um a zettel Caster method where you have
these kind of trees that form naturally
not because you're adding hierarchy into
your notes but because they naturally
appear as you go deeper into a subject
so you start off by looking at file
uploads you go into that and say oh
image uploads in image uploads you go
into that and say I know things like
image tragic and then you might have
another one which goes into you know
image manipulation after they've been
uploaded and it kind of forms this
natural
um
tree structure that appears kind of by
level of detail
now this can be really difficult to
actually sort through and kind of turn
into something you can actually use very
easily you can kind of take out like a
topic and like write about a topic which
is helpful but I don't think for this
particular use case
instead having maps of content create
this like
contents page of your notes so in here
you have things like understanding
habits defining what a habit is how
habits are formed these kind of have the
same topic of understanding habits but
you kind of organize them together with
like other things related to habits it's
about context of your notes not the
content of your notes
um but I'm not going to go too much more
into that but that's how to think about
it like don't think I need to sort my
notes by type think you need to sort
your notes by how you're going to use
them in like
two months time when you forget the
content and need to look it up
tip four
don't limit your bug classes if you only
look for one type of bug you can be
staring on right in the face you can't
see the bug through the trees like
if you're looking at an app and you've
learned exercise and you've learned so
much about access you've got all these
bypasses you've got everything in your
like note system and then you have an
application that
just isn't vulnerable like it uses a
waft you can't bypass the WAFF there's
nothing on Twitter you can't find a bug
if you're only looking for one type of
bug you're screwed when you can't find
it and if somebody else who has already
come ahead of you has already looked for
that bug
then you can really struggle and I think
this Show's actually on Twitter because
if you look at like what top bug bounty
hunters are doing like zwink here you
know he's kind of got these three
categories of idol exercise csrf and
then you've got people replying who are
like I can't find an xss I can't find a
bug
um I can't find an xss bug for two to
three months but if you're just limiting
yourself to xss then you're missing the
idols and csrf that zwink has got right
like they are effectively kind of
skipping out on these and this is kind
of a controversial thing to say right
because a lot of people do recommend
this as a place to start for beginners I
really don't I think you need to be able
to diversify
in order to avoid getting stuck in like
the duplicate Valley
um if you get an invite and you can't
find an exercise or an eye drawer and
that's all you look for even if you're
in that first cohort you have the
maximum opportunity you could be staring
another vulnerability right in the face
you can't predict when or what you'll be
invited to and this kind of goes back to
my point about learning context which is
learn the signs not the specifics you
couldn't always look up payloads you can
always get Intruder and run like 10
different payloads
so instead of sitting there like copying
those payloads into save to notion
instead look at the signs of bugs you
see reflected input you test for
exercise you see IDs you test for Idols
you learn those very quick litmus tests
my one is like if I'm looking for idols
I will see is the website checking my
access what happens if I remove the
cookie what happens if I change the ID
um what exactly is controlling the
authentic the authorization mechanism
that is it my authentication who I'm
logged in as is it my role whatever
learn the signs not the specifics
does this go against what I just said
because I said that you should learn
things in depth yes and no
you should definitely learn things in
depth and go deep into a bug but go deep
into lots of different bugs don't just
learn one because you really could be
literally just walking past others
tip five geographic or payment Gates or
even languages
some functions will be locked unless you
pay money like you have a free tip a
light tier and then some kind of like
high tier medium tier whatever
um you can get a prepaid debit card that
you put like just enough money for like
one month
um but that unlocks like a ton of new
features that you didn't have access to
before and as a tip sometimes if you've
been provisioned an account you might be
able to talk to support or talk to the
client through support and say Hey would
it be possible to get this level of
account so I can do this kind of testing
um getting access either via trials for
like a week or having a prepaid debit
card for just a month means you're not
actually going to keep on buying
something that you don't need but really
really helpful for accessing
functionality you didn't already have
and some people just aren't testing this
Geographic restrictions are really
common for me in the UK
um a lot of the times you have targets
that are restricted to specific
countries like the USA in fact I'm
testing something right now which is not
available in the UK so I have to use a
VPN I have to like fake my location it's
kind of a pain but
other people have to go through the same
pain unless they live in the US
um for me I also get blocked because the
websites don't want to comply with gdpr
they might have different functions in
other regions different pricing uh
really common bug is being able to set
the price like maybe the price is like
five dollars or five rupees and then the
conversion rate like between those two
you can just change the
um currency but not necessarily the
price so a price stays as five currency
even though the difference between five
dollars and five um
rupee is completely different
language is another common one if you
speak another language like you speak
French work on francophone targets
people who only speak English and if I
don't have an English language Change
option are scared of them
Game Changer if you don't speak like if
you speak languages look for targets
that use those languages
number six open source projects now this
actually got me a bug at a recent live
event so
um open source is everywhere and when I
say open source software I mean like
software that people upload
um that they're like hey you can use
this thing I made
now I really like this meme oh this
image from XKCD where it's like some
project a random person in Brassica has
been thankfully maintaining since 2003
which is powering all modern digital
infrastructure you need to sort data and
see there's an open source project for
that maybe you need to count calculate
rocket re-entry in Python there's an
open source project for that and by the
way I looked for and it took me
literally three seconds to Google for
open source code is everywhere and what
people will do is they'll discuss
security issues they'll like have issues
and they'll be discussing it between
them they'll be like hey by the way this
is a weird configuration
if you find out your target issues in a
specific language or framework or
Library you can actually find out what
one versions might be vulnerable by
looking at things like CVS look at the
error messages are great by the way if
you ever have an error message super
helpful for figuring out like versions
and stuff again it's something where you
have to learn deeply but can be really
helpful finding things that aren't bugs
because you're doing more reading than
hunting you're doing that research
now
difficult thing here is can the target
fix it because it depends if it's a
configuration out of date version using
an insecure deprecated method
something that's fixable by the client
it should absolutely still be rewarded
because they have to fix it if it's an
unpatched zero day for the open source
project there's not necessarily much a
client can do however clients may still
choose to go and fix that open source
code because that's a risk
for them if it's a complete third party
there's not much a client can really do
because they kind of purchase the
software but for open source there might
actually be a way for the client to fix
it so I always recommend reporting open
source issues
even if it's not necessarily something
the target is maintaining directly if
they can do something about it
um they should and they can fix it then
they should pay our bounty
tip number seven is to play for your
strengths now despite everything I've
told you about looking for weird bugs in
weird places ignore me if you know what
your strengths are if you know skills
that you are really good at if you know
ways of hunting that you're really good
at play to them play to your strengths
I'm looking I know my skills are an API
I will look in apis a strength that I
have is that I can write code I will
often go into developer apis and like
create the developer version of
something and test that myself I am
specifically playing to my strengths
that I know not a lot of people already
have because fundamentally learning is
energy intensive and time consuming
if you already know something if you
already know you're good at it take
everything I've said in this
presentation and throw it in the garbage
there is no point doing something that
doesn't play to whatever you're already
good at if you're a developer code
reviewing python it might be a strong
skill don't learn JavaScript code review
if you don't need to and you don't want
to it can be so tiring to learn those
skills and go forward and actually
there's no point you're going to be
behind people who already know those
skills and yes the competition may be a
lot lower but if you're the top already
you do not need to be throwing yourself
into the bottom of another category
great great example here is if you
already know an application just start
hacking it if you're a long-term user if
you're a power user you are a step ahead
of everyone else when I hack I if I
don't know an application I am sitting
there trying to learn the basics of it
right if you're already an already use
it you're a step ahead of everyone else
when I found my first book I found my
First Book on an app I was familiar with
granted I wasn't necessarily familiar
with the functionality I was testing but
because I knew the app I spent less time
on understanding the Target and more
time on hacking I was like ahead of
where other people I was competing
against were because I already knew it
and nowadays I do tend to hack a bit
more on stuff that I've never used
before
but I do still kind of focus on hacking
things that I already know or use
already if I get an invite for something
I'm familiar with I'm gonna instantly be
like okay yeah I want to hack that
because I know that that's going to play
to my strengths
because I already know I know that app
so my final piece of advice is program
statistics so this is my final top tip
so on bug crowd and on other platforms
as well but let's just focus on by crowd
um each program has statistics so some
of them will have
um like the disclosed bugs
um like you can see here and not
everything is like listed here so you
can see this is atlassian's program we
can see the priority we can see the
target
um and we can see uh when it was
accepted so we can see how active the
program is there but we can also see you
know what are being targeted the most so
we have like Confluence server
Confluence crap Cloud premium jira
service management server
um atlassian Marketplace jira software
server now this is just like a snapshot
of things I took when I made these
slides but if you were to like look at
say the last month of activity on the
program what's actually being targeted
are you seeing that say the atlassian
marketplace is barely tested in which
case you should be looking on the
atlassian marketplace and seeing if you
can find bugs there
if you see the Confluence server has a
lot of p1s but not a lot of you know say
p2s or p3s or p4s you might be there
might be a lot of p4s in there they're
just not been looked at yet there might
be a lot of low hanging fruit and
especially the
um activity level so you can see here it
was accepted on this date this
verification within is also based on the
client not bug crowd so this is from bug
crowd triage to when the client like
marks it
um
after after things have been triaged
right so it goes
um
like so you submit you submit it triage
gets to it in like two days and then
five days from when triage looks at it
the client then says yes this is
something we know this is a duplicate
this is you know whatever
the other useful thing here is the
vulnerabilities rewarded so this gives
you an idea of how active this program
is
and you see here it's like active payout
within the last X months combine this
with their bug Bounty table and that can
give you an idea of whether or not this
is something that gets a lot of p1s or
if this is something that's getting a
lot more p3s
um and because this is in three months
this is very good way of seeing how
active a program is as well so if a
um if you've got a less active program
you know this verification within is a
lot higher you might be waiting a long
time to find out if something is a dupe
and that can sometimes not be great
you can really start to make inferences
is this an older or a newer program if
it's older is the scope constantly
updating or is it stagnant an older
problem program plus stagnant scope can
really mean there's a lot of duplicates
a lengthy acceptance time so this is
again from bug crowd triaging it to the
client receiving it lots of bugs haven't
been accepted it might have more dupes
because bugs haven't been resolved yet
or alternatively there might be a lot of
bugs in triage which are the same which
might only differ by say a day
if there's a low average payout they
might be paying out a lot of p3s and p4s
rather than p1s and p2s p1s and p2s
especially in weird places are likely
not to be duplicates
so let's kind of Summer up all my advice
here
look in weird places develop expertise
research things in depth don't limit
your bug classes explore your Geographic
or payment Gates check if it's using
open source code play to your strengths
look at program statistics these are my
top tips and genuinely these are the
tips that I use every single time I bug
hunt and I don't get many duplicates
I've gotten duplicates
I think I've gotten like
around
one fifth of my bugs have been
duplicates I'm not sure after my head
but I think it's around one-fifth of my
bugs have been duplicates because I
don't look at the same place as everyone
else and if you were to watch this video
and you're like okay this is like a long
video I'm tired what's the one piece of
advice I need look in weird places
don't just limit yourself to the main
functionality of an app this doesn't
mean don't test the main app this means
don't test the main functionality of the
main app you can find bugs in the main
app yes even if you're don't think
you're that good at bug hunting but
looking in those weird places
looking where nobody else is is really
how you start to find
um those bugs and find them consistency
consistently
my second like if you're only gonna
listen to like two pieces of advice
don't limit your bug classes learn a lot
be open a lot keep your brain open write
notes make sure you are constantly aware
of
um
upcoming bugs or bugs that you might be
able to find recognize those initial
signs reach out to friends if you need
help exploiting something but make sure
you're not just testing for one type of
bug
so thank you very much for listening um
if you'd like to watch more of my
content you can subscribe to my YouTube
channel
um I make weekly videos that I've had a
bit of a long break
um I make weekly videos that all go
around kind of new to bug hunting web
application hacking and apis in
particular I've done videos and
everything from like modern web
development to tooling and automation to
how to use burp so they're very good
place to start if you don't know a lot
about bug hunting and I really recommend
this playlist here now that's what I
call bug bug bug bounty hunting 2020
which is really like a good I think
um
starting to bug hunting that goes from
like I'm just starting out to learning a
bit about API hacking
um
you can also follow me on Twitter it is
my personal Twitter account so it does
not fill up with bug Bounty tips but it
does fill up with you know other things
that isn't strictly related to hacking
so thank you very much for listening
feel free to follow me and if you have
any questions you can reach out to me on
Twitter on YouTube or in the comments of
this video and I will be responding to
them so thank you very much everyone for
listening have a great day and I will
see you all soon bye everyone