hey hackers nerdwell here
have you ever noticed that sometimes the
best bugs are hiding in plain sight
well today we're going to take a look at
finding and exploiting hidden
functionality in Windows software by
hacking dlls
before we start hacking Windows
applications it's helpful to have some
background about the patterns and
practices implemented by the developers
of those applications
and many of these patterns and practices
have been developed over the past 30
years and implemented by Microsoft
themselves
in many cases these have driven the
technological advancements available to
developers and the business processes
that developers Implement in their
software development life cycle
a big aspect of development in a
Microsoft environment is code
reusability and extensibility
and the basic premise here is developers
want to write once use many
so if they create some module with a
capability they want to be able to reuse
that module within the same app within
other apps and integrate with customers
vendors Partners all sorts of other
examples but the basic premise is don't
reinvent the wheel write something one
time and reuse it multiple times
another important aspect of development
in a Microsoft environment is the sheer
scale and scope of some of these
applications they're so large that they
require many teams working together
sometimes across continents and time
zones and definitely working under
different timetables
to build individual aspects of the
application independently but then put
those components together to produce a
final product that is cohesive and works
well together
along the same lines
by building a modular application we can
take a modular approach to maintenance
of the application going forward
so if we need to implement a feature
request or some security improvements to
a specific element of an application we
don't want to have to rewrite or rebuild
the entire application it would be
better if we can just work on the
individual components and modules
themselves and then reintegrate those
into the larger hole which is exactly
what we find in most Windows
applications today
lastly another very important aspect of
working in a Microsoft environment is
the ability to integrate with third
parties and a very common example here
is many apps today especially business
line of business type applications will
have some requirement to work with PDFs
even if it's just rendering a PDF or
maybe modifying them and all sorts of
other interactions
the developers don't want to have to
reinvent this capability every time they
develop a new app that needs to work
with PDFs
so third parties have produced libraries
that developers can integrate into their
applications and then redistribute to
the End customer that handles all that
capability for them
the benefits here are first reduced cost
to the End customer because the
developer doesn't have to worry about
creating all that capability
it also reduces the time to bring a
product to Market because the developer
can grab ready built modules and
integrate them into their application
lastly it provides a standardized
interface for a lot of these
capabilities that developers can become
familiar with and then reuse across a
variety of different applications
now while all these different aspects
bring many benefits to the table
they also bring some opportunities for
accidents to happen mistakes to be made
gaps to be present and in each of those
instances we tend to find security
vulnerabilities so as bug bounty hunters
we want to understand how these patterns
and practices impact the final product
and how we can take advantage of that to
find potential vulnerabilities to
exploit
so back in the day when Windows became
the most popular operating system on the
planet it was common to see applications
written in visual C plus
and when we did that they were compiled
into machine code they were the typical
binary executables that we've all come
to expect and that we reverse with
idapro and to really do much with and
and reverse engineer and make binary
patches to them you really had to bring
them down to assembly and work with it
at that level and then rebuild it from
there obviously that's quite a
cumbersome process for the hacker but as
it turns out that was also a rather
cumbersome process for the developers
and users as well
so even in the days of compiled C plus
plus applications we did have the the
concept of modularity code reuse and
dynamic loading of application
capabilities and in a Microsoft
environment this was implemented through
dlls dynamically loaded libraries
and
the way it would work is if you were a
developer and you wanted to use let's
say a third-party PDF Library
you would purchase that library from the
third party they would send you some
dlls you would include them in your
distribution and then in your app you
would specifically call those dlls and
then import functions
from those
dlls that you want to use in your
application
it was a rather manual and explicit
process meaning you needed to
specifically import that module and then
specifically import individual methods
and properties within that library that
you wanted to use within your
application
and while that worked well as time
progressed Microsoft moved to a
interpreted language environment a
just-in-time compiled environment just
like we see with Java and JavaScript and
Python and all these other languages
we got Visual Basic and basically when
you built a Visual Basic app it did not
compile to machine code it compiled to
interpreted intermediary language
and that led to the development of
the.net framework and most of your
applications today in a Microsoft
environment are
primarily.net and so we have multiple
languages the the
scale of variety in terms of different
languages in the.net framework seems to
grow every year
but some of the key languages are Visual
Basic and c-sharp
what's important to remember here is
when you build a net application it does
not compile to machine code it compiles
to an intermediary language
and actually regardless of whether you
wrote it in VB or C sharp the under the
produced intermediary code at the end of
the day is actually the same
so this provides a lot of flexibility it
also provides a lot of interoperability
so I can write a c-sharp app that is
able to leverage modular capabilities
published by a visualbasic.net app
it's also been integrated into
Powershell very heavily to the point
that as I've depicted here you can
actually
invoke.net code
in Powershell and if you care to take
the time you could build an entire GUI
based app
from Powershell command line itself with
all the functionality and capabilities
available to you in C sharp
so that's just a very brief history of
dlls and the progression of programming
languages in a Windows environment
and this is going to play a very big
role in how we target Windows
applications in modern systems talked
about some of the business cases for
using modular approaches to software
development let's take a look at some
specific technical implications of this
approach in modern applications
and when we're doing blood bounty
hunting I generally break the ABS down
into desktop apps and
server-side apps that doesn't
necessarily need to be a web app in most
cases it is but we also see a lot of
times like Network Services TCP UDP
protocol
services but in general those will have
very similar attack surfaces as your
standard web app especially in a
Microsoft environment as we'll see here
in a few minutes they've gone very far
to to standardize the interface that the
developers work with regardless of
whether they are riding a
net TCP app or a traditional IIs hosted
app or a SharePoint app
so looking at desktop apps
one of the big benefits of dlls and in
the net environment dlls of course still
exist but they are referred to as
assemblies so one of the big uses for
desktop apps is the modularity
for homegrown applications the whole PDF
viewer and modification Library
story that we talked about a minute ago
another application for this modularity
in desktop apps is let's say I am a
developer
and I work for a company who has come up
with some whiz-bang new software
and we have developed a core module that
provides this capability
and we've developed one application that
leverages that core functionality but on
our roadmap in our business plan we
intend to develop a whole Suite of apps
that use this core functionality in all
sorts of interesting ways
but of course we don't want to have to
rewrite and reintegrate that core
functionality every time we build a new
app in our suite
so by using this modular approach we can
develop it one time and then
tie it into all of our subsequent apps
in our suite going forward
that also plays into maintenance so as
we grow our suite and move down the road
map and now we have five different
applications that leverage this
capability
if we need to make a change to that core
capability we only need to make it in
one place and then make small changes to
the individual apps to make them
integrate that new capability but we
don't have to redo it five different
times
on the server side we see dlls and the
assemblies are relied heavily upon in
asp.net applications these are your
traditional IIs hosted web apps
and another good example that is
SharePoint SharePoint makes super heavy
use of of assemblies both Microsoft
produced and in many cases third party
produced so in addition to all the
capabilities that SharePoint provides
out of the box you can get add-ons from
Microsoft there's office web services
and then you can even build your own web
parts that integrate directly into
SharePoint and all these different
components are
compiled into dll's referenced as
assemblies in the web server
configuration
and as we're going to see here in a bit
that plays a very big role in exposing
the capabilities of some of these dlls
and assemblies to remote attackers
lastly we will see third-party
middleware vendors often will
use the same approach for server-side
applications that we see in the desktop
applications and that makes sense
basically build something one time
license it and then you can distribute
it to
any number of end customers to integrate
with their platform
likewise the reverse is true if you are
a middleware vendor a business a line of
business application developer
providing server-side software you
likely will want to provide your
customers with the ability to customize
that and so a common way of doing that
is to give your customers the ability to
reference their own custom built
assemblies to
either add on to the capability of your
middleware or
customize the default base behavior of
your application
now that we have some background about
the windows development environment the
patterns and practices that we can
expect our developers to be implementing
and some of the high level technical
aspects of the modular assemblies that
are in place in the windows environment
let's take a look at some of the common
bug patterns that we will encounter and
I think you may recognize many of these
and it's important to realize that what
we see with the Microsoft approach to
modularity is really just their way of
addressing common business needs that
many other vendors have also addressed
in their own ways and because these
relate to business needs we will see
some of the same bug patterns across
different technological implementations
of the same capabilities
so one that we'll see is deprecated code
not being removed from release builds
and the way this usually will go down is
let's say we let's take the example of
the developer who has built some
whiz-bang core application capability
and a suite of five apps that make
specialized use of that new
functionality
well let's say that four of those apps
are done using
some some element we've come up with a
new way of doing something and we've
integrated that into four of the five
apps but the fifth app we haven't gotten
around to it yet and so we need to
maintain backward compatibility
and so
maintaining the premise of code
reusability we don't want to have to
maintain separate modules for one app
versus the other four apps and so we may
go ahead and just keep the old
functionality in the module for the time
being
and
still deploy that module with the other
four apps we're just not referencing
that deprecated code
or so we think it's still there and so
as an attacker our job is to figure out
are there ways that we can still reach
those deprecated code paths in the other
four apps that the developer has not
anticipated
another pattern that we'll see here is
the reverse of that new application
functionality that has been prematurely
included in a release build
so expanding on the prior example
let's say now we want to Target app
number five the one that's on its
Lonesome it has not yet taken advantage
of this new capability
but because we are sticking with one
module one core module for our
application and distributing it with all
five apps
because four of those apps do use the
new capability obviously it needs to be
in the module and so that gets deployed
with app number five and even though app
number five is not actively taking
advantage of that capability the code is
there and so again as as debug Bounty
Hunter our job is to find ways to reach
those code paths and exploit them in
ways that the developers were not
anticipating
another example is inadequate
sanitization of
user input basically as I said many of
these will relate to like standard web
API vulnerabilities and you know you
can't get away from the fact that user
input cannot be trusted
and it's uh become pretty commonplace
for developers to expect malicious code
from web requests and so we tend to see
sanitization in most of those web apps
however developers may be less likely to
expect
malicious input from endpoints or
injection points that are not quite as
easily accessible so your standard user
on the on the desk is not going to
open up dlls and expose all the
different capabilities and start
throwing you know oddly formatted
object structures added just to see how
it behaves and but as hackers that's
exactly what we want to do it's a very
similar process to how we might Target a
web app but we're doing it through
basically a different interface is all
another book pattern that we'll see with
the use of dlls and assemblies in
Windows environments is naive routing of
web app requests and we'll take a look
at some specific examples here shortly
but at a high level
web request routing in a Microsoft
environment is a bit more complicated
than in your traditional Linux uh you
know multi uh
Apache environment or Tomcat or even
um microservices
in those environments generally there is
a clear and relatively statically
defined
set of routes that your requests are
going to take
and you can know with a relative
certainty that if a user provides some
crazy endpoint that it's not going to
reach any executable cut
wanting one exception or the closest
exception to this in that environment
may be like
let's say you know you have all your PHP
files in the in a CGI bin folder so if
you put a new PHP file in that folder it
just inherently will be executable it
could you know bring down your server
however because you can just simply list
the directory contents of that folder
web server admins are more easily able
to identify
malicious changes and inspect those
files themselves because they're just
clear text there's it's scripting based
capabilities
in contrast with a Windows
IIs hosted web app
it may just reference a dll and then to
actually understand what happens when
that dll receives that request you
actually have to kind of crack it open
and dig in there and do things that many
web server admins probably are not
familiar with and so it's that element
of
that lack of visibility that introduces
some potential vulnerabilities that
we'll take a look at
and
you would be shocked the number of
vulnerabilities I have found in Windows
apps that include hard-coded Keys
passwords and tokens
and I'll throw out a couple of generic
examples here
and many of these are implemented in
this modular approach so here's here's
how it can go down let's say I'm a
developer and let's say I'm that
developer with my whizbang core
functionality and my five App Suite of
products
let's say in this core functionality I
have some complicated cryptographic
operations that each of these five apps
needs to take advantage of
and of course I don't want to have to do
that five times I want to write that
difficult code one time put it in a
module redistribute it and so on
however let's say that even though I
only did it one time and I spent my time
on it I still messed it up because
crypto is hard and I hard coded some key
in my code
well now
the very fact that I'm using this
centralized module to distribute this
capability to all five of my apps is
working against me because now all five
of these apps are vulnerable to
exploitation of the same hard-coded key
and that opens the door to all sorts of
possibilities
uh maybe I'm a I'm a user of app one and
because it shares a key with act three
by way of this centralized module I'm
able to access the data from some other
user from some other company using some
other app who has no idea who I am
that's one example
another that I've seen
is it's relatively common for desktop
apps nowadays to host small little web
services for things like mobile app
integration or peer-to-peer
communication
and so a lot of times the nature of this
capability
requires it to be pretty low
low complexity the users who are
interacting with it don't want to type
in Long passwords or potentially don't
want to type in any passwords and so
that's a perfect example of where we
might see some hard-coded passwords
lastly
in the.net framework environment present
in modern Windows environments
what we have is basically an
object-oriented runtime environment
and the idea is you load your dlls which
are assemblies into the system and you
can decide whether you want to load them
at a system-wide level or just keep them
semi-private
but as you may have noticed many of the
benefits of using this modular approach
require you to register your assembly
with the system so that it is available
to any process that wants to take
advantage of the capability
and when it does that it's basically
exposed through object-oriented class
full bases
so if I'm an app who wants to take
advantage of the capability exposed by
your module
I don't need to know the name of your
dll all I need to know is the class the
object
that I want and I just include that in
my app and then windows in the.net
framework takes care of all the
background legwork of figuring out where
that dll resides and loading it into
memory and creating
execution entry points and so on and so
forth
however this also introduces some
interesting attack factors
because similar to insecure Java object
deserialization
many windows apps will instantiate
objects at runtime based on user input
and in fact Microsoft has gone to Great
Lengths to simplify this process for
Developers
the idea from Microsoft's perspective is
they want the developers to be able to
implement some of this standardized
functionality like object
deserialization
with the minimal amount of code
and even the minimal number of clicks
and so when you have a framework in the
background doing a lot of this stuff
automatically
it's inevitable that developers and
server admins are not going to
understand how it works or even when it
is at work
of course as bug bounty hunters that
presents a golden opportunity for us to
take advantage of insecure object
deserialization let's take a look at
some tools that let us peek inside
windows assemblies and executables in
a.net environment to glean some
information and in most cases reverse it
to human readable code
so just to reiterate in the modern.net
framework environment code is not
compiled to machine code at build time
it's compiled into an intermediate
language that is then interpreted by
the.net framework at runtime and then
converted to machine code
what that provides us as attackers is
the ability to trivially reverse any app
any.net app to human readable source
code
whenever we want and there's actually
many tools to do this and in fact
Microsoft themselves have produced a
tool that is widely available it's
called ilspy IL meaning intermediary
language and this actually is available
in the Microsoft store so if you're
running Windows 10 you can just open up
the Microsoft store type in ilspy
it's rated 4.9
and published by Microsoft and basically
it's a very useful tool it lets you
introspect into a dll or an executable
in a Net Framework environment and not
only see the human readable source code
but also the references that an app has
so it can get a little bit tricky to
determine all the different assemblies
that a given application uses
especially when some of those assemblies
are not even contained within that
application's program files folder if
it's registered with the system it'll be
in what they call the global assembly
cache the GAC and that's a system-wide
folder so the only way that you can
really understand all the different
assemblies that an application
references is to use a tool like this
which goes through and identifies all
the class references within that project
and list them here for you and from
there you can drill down and start
finding all sorts of interesting things
and so the way I usually use this tool
is with an application that I don't know
much about
let's say it's a Windows
executable.exe I will open it up in this
app and it will give me basically a map
of all the different
assemblies that are referenced by that
main application
and that drives the rest of my research
now while ilspy is a great tool and it's
free it's from Microsoft it's well
supported
it does have its uh its drawbacks it's
not the most user-friendly in terms of
searching for things through multiple
files and it has a somewhat outdated
user interface
so another tool that I will use is from
a third-party company called jetbrains
and the product is called dot Peak and
this product is actually
designed for developers and it's part of
The Suite you can get all sorts of
different products from jetbrains and
most of them you have to pay for but dot
Peak is one that they offer for free
and it provides some of the same many of
the same capabilities as IL spy but it
provides some additional functionality
and it also provides a more modern user
interface than IL spy
so usually I will use dot Peak for the
actual code review that I want to
perform so when I start to get down to
the nitty-gritty I've identified exactly
which assemblies I want to
dig into I'll open them up in dot Peak
and then go through them line by line
and and it is with this tool that I have
found several instances of hard-coded
keys in a variety of different types of
applications
and you know
there is the argument that you could
just run strings on some of these apps
and see those keys and that's true
however
at least in my experience I don't think
I would have found some of the ones I
found if I had just tried to find them
with strings because they're random
strings of data and when you run strings
on a Windows app you get a whole bunch
of nonsense some of it's you know 25
characters it looks like a password but
it's actually not anything
and that can be very easily confused
with something that looks almost exactly
the same but is actually referenced as a
key inside the code
so being able to look at the actual
source code and see
what the code pads are can take you
right to the place where you will be
able to make sense have the right
contextual data to recognize what is
being used as a hard-coded password or
hard-coded key and what is not so let's
take a quick look at how I use dot peak
in my workflow so we'll do a quick demo
and I will walk you through highlights
one thing that I like about dot Peak
over IL spy is that it actually lets you
add an entire folder to its tree here so
let's say I'm just going to go to my
documents and I've placed some
executables and dlls in this level up
exponent so I'm going to tell it to open
that folder and it's going to identify
all the executables in that folder
and one thing that's very helpful is
actually it will determine if it is
even supported by dot Peak meaning is it
a.net app so let's take a look here I'm
going to go ahead and open up command
prompt and um
so as you can see this is what I have
and I'm just going to run this well
okay we're going to run this executable
this is a little PLC Arrow it is a
visual C plus plus compiled binary and
executable old school and I did that on
purpose it's a command line app
but I did that on purpose so that we can
see when we
pull it up here in
um in dot Peak it gives us basically
some very basic information it reads the
uh the PE header
from the file
but that's about it
and what I find in in the wild is a lot
of applications actually still do
leverage some
old school compiled basically they call
it unmanaged code it's not DOT net code
and many times it will be like some old
third-party library that provides some
capability that that application needs
but hasn't been maintained by the
original vendor and so they basically
are carrying this Legacy code in their
product and this will help us to find
that and so just because dot Peak can't
deal with it doesn't mean we can't
Target it it just means we've got to use
some other tools in this case I would
use Ida Pro reverse that and
see what I can find
I would also go through the managed code
the.net code the stuff that is supported
by dot Peak and find where does it
reference that unmanaged code and how is
it referenced that interaction between
manage.net code and unmanaged old-school
compile code is a perfect Gap to find
very impactful vulnerabilities because
in that old school code you're going to
find things like buffer overflows
uh string format vulnerabilities integer
overflows
all sorts of good stuff
I also put some SharePoint files in here
I had just copied these from a
SharePoint server to demonstrate
so what we'll do is we'll start with
this one so Microsoft SharePoint
provides a basic
search
capability which is implemented by this
library and so if you look at the
configuration the web server
configuration and a Microsoft SharePoint
server you will see that it there's an
endpoint a virtual directory basically
that's mapped to an app that references
this assembly and it references it at
the top level Microsoft or
sharepoint.client.search
and that's where it stops it goes and it
loads this assembly
and that's important because
from that point forward how it handles
the request depends on
how this dll is written
and so as I kind of touched on earlier
in many traditional web applications the
endpoints exposed by the app are
relatively static
in a net application
it references an assembly and then looks
at that assembly to decide okay does the
specific endpoint that the request has
indicated match
a web exposed function method or
property in this assembly
and so it's very Dynamic and so that
opens up the door for let's say a
developer copy paste some code and it
doesn't realize that they've just copied
a very important attribute which makes
that method web accessible and all of a
sudden they've now exposed some backdoor
capability that they did not intend to
and believe it or not I have seen this
in several instances one very common
instant uh
one very common example of this is when
an application needs to implement some
sort of automation
like a bulk import or bulk edit
capability and it needs to be called by
other
scripts and processes and they don't
want to like put a password in a script
for example
and so
they will have the idea of okay well
we'll just make this quote unquote
hidden endpoint that only we know about
and when you call it it provides you
access that other endpoints require you
to have authentication to access but if
you call this specific one
you don't have to authenticate well
because we can go in here and look at
the code we can trivially identify those
now this is a SharePoint dll I have not
found any vulnerabilities in this one
I'm just using it as for demonstrative
purposes
so when you call this query
endpoint
I'm going to pull this up
when you call it
what it does is IIs actually goes in
here opens up the assembly and it looks
for this remote attribute
and so this can be on methods it can
also be on properties and so over here
on the left hand side these little icons
indicate these are methods these icons
indicate their properties so what the
properties mean
by being remote is they have Getters and
Setters and so basically this
corresponds to get and post and so
if it has this little remote
attribute
before that object
or that class member is what it is then
it also has to be public
so these two elements right here
together
make
this
property accessible through the query
interface
using this code forgets this code for
posts and
we can go through the code and enumerate
all the different
ways that we can Target an application
now this being a Microsoft app
these are all publicly documented if you
go to Microsoft's website if you just
Google
it's if you just Google Microsoft a
SharePoint a client that search that
query it will take you straight to a
Microsoft website that says the
Microsoft SharePoint client search query
namespace and it basically provides a
nice listing of all this stuff however
for third-party apps and apps that
you're going to encounter in bug bounty
they very likely do not have that kind
of
documentation and so that's where this
research can be helpful to help you find
basically undocumented backdoor
endpoints that provide sensitive
capability and you had the bonus of you
actually get to see the source code so
not only can you identify potential
endpoints that are undocumented you can
see what they do when you call them
you can't get much better than that
one last thing I'll show or point out
rather is this remote attribute is
actually like a Microsoft internal
attribute they tell developers don't use
that but in.net environments there is a
an equivalent and it says web method so
basically if you open up any assembly
that is used in an asp.net application
you want to be looking for remote in
Brackets or web method in Brackets and
if you see either of those then
odds are that member that class member
is accessible
through
the API the web accessible API
another tool that I find very useful
when I'm doing testing of a Windows
application is netstat
and so as I mentioned before in many
cases desktop client-side applications
are opening Network Services
for various functionality one common
reason is mobile app integration another
is local network peer-to-peer
communication
and so what I'll do is I'll run netstat
once before I do anything with the app
then I will launch the app
and then you know maybe exercise the
different capabilities of it then I'll
run that stat again compare those
snapshots and see if any ports are
opened
uh I when I run that stat in a Windows
environment I do the dash b as in bravo
a n is in Nancy o
Bano
Flags what that shows you is not only
the ports that are open but the actual
executable that is tied to it of course
you need to run this as an administrator
in an elevated command prompt
but in many cases this will tell you
specifically which application is
listening on a given port and from there
I will just run with it I'll open it up
in dot Peak and and walk the different
code pads and find some vulnerabilities
well thanks for joining me today I hope
that was helpful hopefully you got some
new techniques that you can integrate
into your hacker toolkit if you have any
questions please feel free to reach out
you can follow me on Twitter
and happy hacking