[Music]
all right thanks so yeah my name is Phil
Roth I'm a data scientist at endgame and
along with my colleague Hyrum we've
released amber which is an open-source
malware classifier and dataset so first
I want to talk a little bit about why we
would want to do this and what motivated
us so open datasets push machine
learning research forward so there's
been a lot of advances in machine
learning in general in a lot of
different areas over the last ten years
areas like optical character recognition
and you know machine translation and
also identifying objects and images and
there's a lot of reasons for that
you know hardware there's been a lot of
advances in Hardware datasets are
getting much larger but an important
reason I believe is the presence of open
benchmark datasets for researchers to
use so what you're seeing here is a this
is a plot of like 20 different open
benchmark datasets in the machine
learning research community and this is
just the number of times that they're
cited at a large machine learning
conference called nits and you can see
that benchmark data sets have been
around for a long long time but it's
really been in the last 10 years that
their use has taken off one example from
that previous slide was Amnesty this is
a open data set of like 70,000 images of
handwritten digits you can see some
examples there so what researchers can
do then is just train their model on
60,000 of those images and you know then
test how well their model identifies the
correct digit in the left over 10,000
images so it's become very important to
the community and one of the leading
researchers has said amnesty is the neat
new unit test and kind of what he meant
there is that the algorithms have gone
even beyond the point where M NIST can
measure how well they're doing but even
in that case amnesty is still important
as kind of like a sanity check on to
make sure that the algorithms are doing
what you expect them to do so security
locks these datasets and this is
something I've been saying ever since
kind of joined the security industry
four or five years ago yeah you can see
some examples of me talking about this
there over the years but there's a lot
of good reasons for why why security
locks these datasets
there's personally identifiable
information in them companies might not
want to release you know network logs or
network infrastructure yeah because
they're afraid that attackers would get
too much information from that and also
you know companies don't want to release
their own intellectual property that
last reason is a good reason why open
datasets don't exist in the field that
I'm in which is kind of static
classification of malware this is just a
one application of machine learning in
the security industry but it's the one
I'm gonna focus on on this talk so what
are we trying to do it pretty much it's
just the antivirus problem it's you have
a new Windows PE file that you haven't
seen before and you want to know is it
benign or malicious so there's a lot of
ways to solve this problem we're coming
at the problem with machine learning so
we're extracting all kinds of features
from these files you know as many as
2000 or so but in this simple example
let's imagine we're just using two
features maybe like file size and number
of imports if you take those features
from all these different files you can
then plot it in a two dimensional space
and the colors don't show up very well
but you have like a red bunch that you
can call malicious and a blue bunch that
you can call benign and then what you
want to do is classify a new dot as it
comes in or kind of divide that space up
into what you think is the malicious
space and what you think is that benign
space simple rules can allow you to do
this
but it's just not very effectively you
can see you know the red space here now
doesn't define those blobs and there's
some outliers that get misclassified
machine learning can really help by
defining better boundaries and giving
you better performance but there's so
many options for machine learning
algorithms how do we know which ones
best and that's where ember can come in
and Ember stands for endgame malware
benchmark for research we want it to be
known as kind of amnesty for malware
so the name uh the letters match up
I really like it it's a great name and
it also gives me the opportunity to say
this joke as often as possible I'm not
gonna get tired of it and so you better
not either alright so what are the
details what is in ember it's an open
source collection of 1.1 million PE file
hashes that were scanned by virustotal
sometime in 2017 the dataset includes
metadata derived features a model
trained on those features and also
there's a github repository with code
that allows you to work with the data
really easily but importantly it does
not include the files themselves and
that's just because you know the benign
files are company's intellectual
property we don't own those files and we
we can't release that inside information
to the whole world and so we're only
releasing like derived information so
the data set is divided into 900,000
training set a smaller testing set
they're the training set is divided
evenly between benign malicious and
unlabeled samples and the training set
appears chronologically prior to the
test data you can see this is kind of a
date histogram of the month that each
each sample first appeared we're
releasing that month data with each
sample you know it's not totally
accurate it's the month but it should
allow you to do a lot with that and it's
important to make the training set
appear before the test data because it
kind of reflects the nature of the
problem of antivirus is you want to
train your model at one point and you
certainly want to get all the samples
that you trained it on correct but you
also want it to get all new samples
correct you want to correctly predict
whether samples benign or malicious that
you haven't seen before that malware
authors are you know currently writing
or will write in the future so that's
why the test data shows up in November
and December of 2017 and the training
data is all prior to that oh and then
also by releasing the month we're also
allowing you to do kind of across
chronological cross validation
and also you can quantify how quickly
your model becomes out-of-date you can
train a model say through all the data
through May and then say well how well
is it doing on data in August and
September and October and you can see
how much worse it gets over time so this
is what the data actually actually looks
like you can go grab it now it's a 1.6
gigabyte tarball there on disk once you
extract it there's a 7 JSON files in
there when you look into each file each
line is a JSON blob and so here we're
just looking at the first three keys of
that first line and so that each JSON
blob has these first three keys which is
kind of metadata about the sample it's
the hash the month that appeared and
then also the label zero for benign one
for malicious and negative 1 for
unlabeled there's a lot more keys than
after that which kind of show you the
extracted features from each sample and
I'll get into more detail about what
those features are later but yeah right
now so there's two kinds of features
there's those that can be calculated
directly from the raw bytes of the file
that's like byte entropy byte histogram
and strings but then there's also
features that we're extracting from the
files that need that require us to kind
of parse the PE header and in order to
do that and to understand the PE header
format the PE file format we're using a
library called the library to instrument
executable formats or leaf and we got to
give a big shout-out to quarks lab for
open sourcing this very useful library
so calculating the features is kind of a
two-step process this code you can't
really read the details but it's just
this is just one one feature and the
important point is that there's two
different functions to calculate
features the first accepts the raw
binary the PE file itself and it
generates that JSON blob and that JSON
blob is kind of what we're calling the
raw features the second function takes
that JSON blob and then vector eise's it
into just a list of like float 32 s and
that's a
you're vector that you can then feed to
a machine learning model so the data
that were distributing that shows JSON
blobs
they need to be vectorized before you
can train machine learning model it's an
important step and the code we're
releasing allows you to to vectorize all
those features with without really you
know without doing any more work we've
defined that for you
so yeah let's go through the categories
of features that we kind of chose white
histogram is a simple count of how many
times each byte occurs in the file the
byte entropy histogram is kind of a
sliding entropy calculation that then
kind of benchmarks each entropy
calculation back to each byte that
occurs there's more details in that
paper that I linked to there and we've
also written a paper there's there's
more details about it in there section
information so this this is an example
of a feature that requires you to read
the PE PE file header so we list all the
sections and all you know the entropy
the virtual size kind of other
information about each section and then
also which section is the entry section
import information export information we
just have a list of all the imports from
each file and a list of all the exports
and for the imports we have what library
those functions were from strings we
can't just extract the strings and hand
them over to you we were a little
worried about personally identifiable
information or divulging intellectual
property but we were able to find all
the strings tell you how many there are
what their average length is a histogram
of the characters that appear and some
other things we've also done some
pattern matching so the strings that we
think look like URLs or registry keys we
count those up and we give that
information to you there's also more
general information just about the file
its size its virtual size and so on and
also header information directly from
the PE header that talks about where the
file was compiled and kind of the
compiler information and that sort of
thing yeah so I kind of mentioned this
but after downloading the data set
you need to do feature vector is a
vector ization before you do model
training the amber code based defines
that feature of vectorization after I
downloaded the data set onto this
computer right here
it took about 20 hours on this machine
we have a server of it does better
parallelization and it can take as
quickly as like 10 or 30 minutes so
after you've done that you can train a
model we've trained a model for you we
didn't make any special decisions on
this model this is a very generic model
but we wanted to train it and distribute
it for example purposes so that it can
serve as a benchmark it's a gradient
boosted decision tree model that's
trained with like GBM and that's an open
source implementation of that gradient
boosted decision tree algorithm it took
about three hours again three hours on
this machine here so it that was you
know that's pretty easy and then once
you have that model you can make
predictions on every sample in the test
set and it's going to that models going
to spit out a number between 0 & 1 if it
spits out a number closer to 1 it thinks
that the file is more malicious if it if
it spits out a lower number it thinks
it's more benign and then what I'm
showing here is a histogram of those
predictions on the test set again red
for malicious blue for benign so you can
see it's doing a pretty good job of
separating the two classes but there is
some overlap once you've made all those
predictions you can kind of make some
statements about how well you think the
model is doing we do that with a
receiver operator characteristic curve
and the area under that curve it's so we
get this score and then like I said you
you you get a number a score between 0 &
1 and then you want to pick a threshold
and say okay anything that scores above
this we're gonna define that as
malicious anything below that we're
gonna define that as benign and if we do
that how many do we get wrong how many
false positives do we have well I chose
that threshold in order to get a point 1
percent false positive rate and at that
false positive rate we get a 93 percent
detection rate so
a huge disclaimer this model is not
malware score on a 10-game we train
malware score and distribute it as
production model it's protecting
customer machines now it's great in my
totally biased opinion but this ember
model it just doesn't perform as well
it's malware score is better optimized
has better features it's constantly
updated with new data the purpose of the
Ember model is not like to protect your
machine it's definitely to just serve as
a benchmark to say ok the researchers
out there can choose a different machine
learning model choose a different
technique for classifying benign and
malicious samples and how does it
compare to this you know common
benchmark that everybody has access to
so yeah I would not suggest using this
model to protect your own machines along
with the data we're releasing a code
base it makes it very easy to vectorize
the features train the models and then
importantly make predictions on new PE
files given the model that we're
distributing and all I'll show you that
in just a second I what something I'm
really proud of is the the code
repository has a jupiter notebook in the
resources directory and i've kind of
defined the environment that I ran that
I train the model in with what Python
packages I used what versions and so you
yourself can run this notebook you can
train the model yourself given that
environment and this notebook will
reproduce all the graphics that are in
this talk that are in the paper and it's
a very good explanation of how to do
that in code so yeah I I hope
researchers in this area you know pick
up this model and they run with it pick
up this data and run with it there's a
bunch of different things we're hoping
people do with it this first category is
like we hope people beat the benchmark
you know this was a pretty easy model I
we didn't make many customizations to it
and there's a lot of things researchers
can do to improve the performance like
immediately you can you can throw out
features that were distributing that
aren't very interesting you can do
feature engineering come up with better
features you can do you can optimize the
like GBM model parameters with grid
search that's going to immediately get
you better perform
or the last one is kind of like
semi-supervised learning you can bring
in information from the unlabeled
samples to hopefully help you you know
learn some more about the structure of
PE files if the if the labeled benign
and labeled malicious data isn't enough
and we're because there isn't much about
semi-supervised learning in the academic
literature and we're hoping this kind of
Spurs that the second category of things
you could do is kind of going beyond
just gradient boosted decision trees and
well I've already mentioned quanta you
know how quickly do these models go out
of date we can definitely define that
with this data set but then also you can
go beyond gradient boosted decision
trees and look at featureless neural
network based models and and for that
you would need independent access to the
samples themselves we can't provide that
but I'm hoping there's research
institutions that have access to
virustotal any of these files can be
gained with a subscription to virustotal
or some agreement with them so hopefully
researchers with that kind of access can
release neural network type approaches
to this problem and you know kind of
show how they compare also you could
kind of take the offensive side and say
how can we use machine learning to from
an attacker standpoint and so you can
use the ember' model as kind of like we
want to beat the ember' model have a
malicious sample that ember the Ember
model classifies correctly how can I
change that it could bypass the
detection and I just want to make a note
you know offensive research is very
important to defenders as well because
we want to learn more about that and
it's it's going to help defenders in the
end all right demo time this is where
talks are won and lost so I wanted to
bring a little hat from a winning team
that I know of the 76ers and so
hopefully this will help me a lot
yeah trust the process all right can we
see that yes all right so I want to
download some of the most recent benign
files that are on virustotal and the
most recent malicious files and I want
to just want to see if the ember model
fyz them correctly so keep in mind this
is data that has just been seen by
people you know right now and so that
means the ember model which was trained
on data through October you know it's
going to be very out of date but when
I've done this demo myself the Ember
model has been you know as a pretty good
winning percentage just like the 76ers
so we should be good all right let's see
I'm running this through my phone so I'm
going to skip the five megabyte and take
a smaller one I'm going to download the
malware directly to my computer I'm a
trained professional don't worry I can
do this let's see this is a smaller
benign file download all right sweet got
those so now let's go over so I've
already downloaded the Ember model and
data and you can see that here yeah
that's the tar ball right there I've
already extracted it these are the JSON
features the cool thing about like GBM
is the model is like kind of it's
inspectable it's it's just in text and
so you know you have decision trees you
have a bunch of decision trees and you
can inspect what decisions the like GBM
model is making so that's pretty cool
so we downloads we got our two downloads
there so this is the repo right here
I've already installed it but you can
just run it again there's some
instructions in the repository itself
about what you know what requirements
you need to install what kind of Python
packages you need to install I've
already done all of that so
scripts so we give you a very nice
classified binaries script that will
just help you you know make predictions
on new PE files once you have a model so
let's specify the model ADA amber model
and downloads all right we're making
predictions all right we did all right
maybe I hope so it the model loads very
quickly and you see this one got a very
high score that's f82 let's hope that's
the malicious one
yes it was and the benign one scored
pretty high that's actually in all my
tests it's kind of the highest that a
benign file has scored so one four nine
yep that was the one we done found on it
so victory
just like the Sixers yeah nice all right
all right so this is all available the
links the presentation is in sched so
these links you know you should be able
to get them but we've we've released a
paper this is the highlight sentence for
me
evidently well so in the paper Hiram was
gracious enough to train a neural
network based model himself based on
some recent literature and we kind of
compared that performance to creating
this simple gradient boosted decision
tree model the gradient boosted decision
trees did you know slightly slightly
better
so we're saying you know you know at the
current state of the art these
featureless models are not you know up
to snuff from the from these older type
models so you know we think there's
potential in the field and we hope this
kind of data set kind of Spurs that kind
of research in on two featureless neural
network models and so I just want to say
bring it all right
download the data download the code
thanks a lot
how did I do do I have time for
questions okay do you want to bring the
microphone or you guys can just yell it
out if you want yep
secondly have you looked at packed
samples and the entropy features of
obfuscated code yeah as an if I give you
a packed wimpy sample how is your model
gonna detect it yeah packed samples are
definitely hard I haven't looked at them
in the Ember dataset specifically but we
deal with them all the time when
training malware score and yeah we can
definitely detect them like you said
with entropy base features and
everything so the model knows that they
it's just hard at to to make a good
decision because you can't learn very
much about what's actually in like a
packed file but so far we've done pretty
well good performance and you know maybe
people can take this and find even
better ways to get features from ops II
but I skated files and how do you watch
the score variance between two malware I
mean a malware belonging to family one
but its variant a and variant be so Yara
catches those pretty well because apart
from the shy you have different variants
that you can code up in a Yara rule how
do we do that how will amber detect
variants which are very similar but at
the different sample I have different
shots so you're saying if there's a
common family and there's just a little
little difference between something that
might exist yes yes oh I mean you would
hope that the machine learning model
would would find features that exist in
all the different in all the different
samples of the same family and would be
able to you know make decisions based on
the ones that it has seen and make an
accurate decision on something
family that hasn't seen before did that
answer your question yeah yeah okay good
but great initiative thank you okay
thanks yeah I'd liked your talk I had so
many questions while you're giving the
talk but you actually answered quite a
few toward the end I guess I'm a little
bit new enough to ml and deep learning
to be dangerous it's not my original
technical expertise but I was a little
confused about sha-1 using it because I
mean sha-1 unless you have an exact
match it's just gonna be different for
everything it and it's in theory a
uniform distribution - yeah definitely
advise you nothing is wrong I should
have been maybe more explicit that we're
distributing the Shaw's of all the files
the sha-256 but it's not meant to be
used as a feature that you would train
on it's definitely meant to be like if
you have access to these files then you
need this shot and you can go and get
the file yourself so it's more metadata
and not data that's meant to be trained
on doctrine now I think you had
information in here that I could
distinguish by operating system somehow
I mean I think you had some metadata in
there that made because like in my
environment I'm almost all Linux and I I
could care less about Windows for
example you know malware for Linux
windows you're talking about
can run this no other features of
features oh okay yeah I mean we're just
grabbing whatever is in the PE header
there okay but I can separate them all
defined they do when I'm training oh
okay like a different kind of like yeah
you could do that I mean combining
different models like training separate
models for different subsets like that's
definitely something you can do and then
now I've lost track of my third question
sounds good thank you very much very
appreciate it
you still have like five minutes of for
questions of you if anyone in the
audience I wants to ask questions now I
remember my third question one of the
things is I'm getting other data like if
malware comes in I'm gonna have bait I'm
gonna have logs
Splunk logs which will tell me the
behavior of something coming in and I
was wondering in the features I you said
you just had really three labels no you
know malware not malware or unknown yeah
and in the future you have more
distinction like you know like I know
there's a lot of different distinctions
well yes it sounds like you're getting
into like behavior and like what it when
this was downloaded when this ran what
did it do beyond this right and that's
definitely something you can do that's
kind of like out of the scope of just
static malware detection where you just
want to use the data without running it
and make a decision just with only that
information well I like to combine it
with the executive data yes yeah and
there's more opportunities for that yeah
we're not including information about
what these files would do if they were
run it's kind of out of the scope but
but yeah that's definitely you would
want to move beyond that and and make
more complicated models with all the
information these are in the public
domain so they probably have
descriptions associated with them right
how do you operate what they what's in
public I mean that all the data is out
there now no but I mean the the malware
that you've done the SHA ones on and
everything they're well known they have
behaviors associated with them
yeah yeah it probably a lot of it it
probably is commodity malware we didn't
pick it to be you know to be from
certain families or anything it's kind
of a uniform just not good random so
yeah there probably are very well-known
things in the data set so I can dig them
out yeah okay great yeah thank you
if there are no more questions let's
take the opportunity to thank our
speaker again