[Music]
ya see I see a lot of new faces at
besides I guess that means a lot of you
had guys have been breaking the first
rule of the besides Club it's gonna be a
lot of these going on I apologize for
that ahead of time so yes my name is
Anton Goncharov and we're going to talk
about semantic reasoning and semantic
technology and how it can help in a lot
of areas that we're struggling with
today this is an attempt to condense
about three to four years of practical
experience and a lot of really tedious
research with lots of long and boring
words into about 30-minute conversation
so I apologize if we go a little bit
fast there is should be in your schedule
so should be an attachment with a slide
deck there's a lot of links and
references in there I try to make sure
that you guys can follow up on any of
these things if it sounds interesting
and of course if you have any questions
just let me know after the talk so let's
just breeze through this all right so
what are we going to talk about we're
going to talk about why is semantic
reasoning is important how did we come
to the state of things where we are
today
what is the semantic technology is all
about how do we look at things versus
how do we look at strings and and
patterns and fields what is up with the
intelligence and how we can take
advantage of that
how does intelligence can be achieved
with semantic reasoning and also talk a
little bit about sort of stargazing some
of the cool things that we could do with
this tech in the future so that's who I
am I'm just gonna skip that I've been
around for a while I've done some things
you know take a look at my profiles long
story short I spent quite a few years
trying to figure out what is the story
that the data is telling us and how to
take this story and how to tell it to a
larger context how to solve problems
with it how to solve pains and how to
fix things in such a way that they don't
broke again
break again in the future so now that
you guys know a little bit about me I
would like to know a little bit about
you how many folks in the audience are
on the defense side how many of you
would say you're in security operations
fantastic I'm really sorry guys any
women in the audience whoo you guys are
the best
we need more of you all right
what does this talk about again two
parts talk about why things are broken
not just how but why and what semantic
reasoning can do to help but before the
Diane I promise myself okay I will do I
will do just one anecdote and I hope you
guys will like it
so you guys use lift right there right
there awesome guys
I like I'll take them over uber anything
and my experiences with lyft are always
phenomenal I always run into these
tremendously fun characters talk to them
they share their life stories so a few
weeks ago I was coming back from
vacation and the driver he just very
quickly kind of started talking about
himself and he's like yeah you know I'm
generally like a nice guy just got
engaged but my fiance doesn't know that
I have a gambling problem I'm like all
right and it sounds like something you
should talk about and it's like I'm like
well you know sometimes I'll just buy
things sporadically I'll sit on
late-night on QVC and I just I'll buy
things like I bought I put about two
Star Wars lightsabers for her for
birthday from my fiance I'm like she's a
Star Wars fan he's like no they're more
for me smart right like wow and he's
like oh my god it was the most recent
thing you bought and he says I bought
this litter box that's fully automated
and basically it's really cool it just
sits there and it comes through your
sand and it picks up the bits of cat
poop and he's like and it totally works
too like I tested it last night I melted
a little fun sized snicker bar
and I put it in the sand and it just
totally cleaned it up I'm like cool cool
wait even wait why do you put a
chocolate even have a cat
he's like no I just thought it was
really awesome so I think part of what
my conversation I want to have about is
that yes it's a talk about technology to
talk about technical capability but it's
very focused right and we have to be
very judicious with our time and
detector we're using that we are not
like that guy who has an awesome litter
box doesn't even have a cat you know we
actually want to to have something in
our environment that is useful we can do
something about so let's move forward a
day life of security analyst you guys
will probably hear this from during the
vendor sales pitches you know things are
horrible things are falling apart but I
always ask why why are they horrible why
is why is the life of the security
analyst is so difficult especially you
know for tier 1 tier 2 guys are just
doing triage and in to me it kind of
boils down to you know we we have this
data right and then we have insights and
we try to get from data to insights and
so how do we do that and that's the big
question what is the what does it take
for us to look at things that are coming
in all of the alerts all the detections
all of the you know third-party
notifications threaten tell and so
that's that's where the pain is right so
the pain is all of these things all of
the above I don't have to go into
details you know them better than I do
but essentially it's you know let's just
face it like it's not working out right
this whole security log based analytics
is wasting so much of our time and it's
making our life miserable and it's
making people leave and they go to
another place where they think things
are going to be better but they're not
here's an example a couple of vendors
that I love to beat up on I've added the
name so you don't know who they are but
so this is actually so this is an app
inside of from one better instead of the
other vendor and it's a threat Intel
feed which is you would probably pay
money for actually to get to this point
right it's gonna cost you money and
first of all look at that query right I
mean I know a little bit about SPL I
mean the query language but you know
like that would that would drive me nuts
and even after after you get this like
these are essentially reliable
indicators this go this should go
straight to the incident response right
well congratulations because now you
have to what happens now you have to
investigate every single one of those IP
addresses and figure out which system it
is who does it belong to what else do we
know about it when was the last time I
got patched who logged into it who
logged out from it what are the binaries
are so so that's just the beginning of
the pain and you know looking back at
how do we got here we started out with
log management you know grabbing pattern
matching very basic alerts then we went
to Sims that prota
you know a promises a single pane of
glass instead we got you know a single
glass of pain and but but why like why
are the Sims so painful and and part of
it it has to do with technology the the
you know identity models acid models
things that we need to do our job that's
as far as the Sims had been able to get
like even in Splunk there is sorry I did
say that there is maybe you know five or
six models in there but no more than
that right and we have to kind of
finagle a way through it and the more
things with string together the more
they break because of the joint
statements and and things just don't
scale you know in the end it all boils
down to this one very simple fact and is
something that I I truly believe in
something that I'm willing to scream
from the rooftops is that the tools that
were given to do our job just like the
guys in the factory you know beating the
rocks with hammers they're just not good
enough to do the things that we need to
do with them
it's as simple as that so how do we fix
that
yay all right so you guys have probably
seen kind of the traditional you know
data information knowledge wisdom
pyramid I like this one a little bit
better I stole it from a gentleman named
Sean Riley so I'll admit that but I I
tricked it a little bit and and
basically the idea is that most of our
time is spent on the left side of this
diagram right we dig in data and very
rarely we kind of get into the
information part and almost never we get
into the the knowledge part the
knowledge part is something that just
naturally kind of happens to you as an
analyst the more you spend time in the
data and if you think about it and you
don't have to answer that but think
about for yourself how does your
organization move things from data to
information and how do they move things
from information to knowledge and
chances are it's it's very manual and
very tactical and very occasional right
which as you can imagine does not help
things out another couple of nice
aspects of this diagram is that all of
that is context and yes there is overlap
obviously and so yeah some of the data
has context but really the context is is
between information and the knowledge
and yeah if you spend enough time in the
trenches eventually you start getting
experience which is kind of the superset
of of knowledge so how does semantic
technology help there's several very key
things that you know that enable us to
do things that weren't enabled there
were the possible before first of all we
can represent the things that we see as
a network of facts right which is very
important the data is stored the same
way that we humans think about it which
is super critical and very important now
that we store this information and
knowledge rather in in a network of
facts we can also automatically make
conclusions based on this information so
we'll talk a little bit about how how we
can do that in a few slides we can also
fill in the gaps in the information
provided by data right the data is never
complete there's always that missing
data stream or that the data source or a
parser or a mapping or a threat and tell
or you know notification or an alert or
some kind of a critical tie in between
the asset management database and the
you know the privileges in Active
Directory and the configuration file on
the server that just got deployed they
just does not connect together and we
have to be able to have technology that
fills those blank in for us when they
are obvious when they're obvious to us
as analysts when we look at them right
we have to be able to have machines do
the same thing all right it's if it's
obvious to me that IP addresses don't
exist in the vacuum and there must be a
system behind it we should be able to
represent that that it's not just an IP
address that talks to another IP address
they're just addresses it's actually
systems that communicate over over the
network identified by addresses but I
try not to ramble and most importantly
most importantly by automating these low
level this low level data analysis we as
humans can focus on problems of higher
order which is very important that means
our skills that are better suited for
things like remembering things
following our intuition hunches kind of
you know getting a hint of something
that's possible machines sucker right
but machines socket take this thing here
put it together put it over here let
them let's have them do that so that's
the that's the premise at least right oh
and by the way semantics means language
based just in case you guys don't know
which means it
looks and functions like language which
is guess what that's what we use smart
alright so there's gonna be there's
gonna be some components to this and you
will find diagrams similar to this there
are 10 times more complicated I
purposefully only left these blocks on
screen and there's essentially these are
kind of like the components logical
components that make this whole magic
happen so on the bottom you have a
triple store which by the way does not
have to be a graph database I mean you
can even model this in in a spreadsheet
right because in the end it's just
tables then you have RDF which is a
basic data model expresses everything in
triples meaning we're going to talk a
little bit about that so everything in
RDF world is triples everything right
and that makes things easy but also
mixing certain things hard we'll touch
on that then we have our DFS which is
kind of the extension of RDF and it
gives you more complexity and more
flexibility which is very important in
information security field because
sometimes one thing could be two things
and we need to be able to recognize it
as both for example inheritance you know
we can have a host that could also be
compromised so it's also a compromised
host but it's still a host you see so it
needs to be both for us we'll talk about
that and then owl owl is the mechanism
that provides the ontology which is kind
of like a data dictionary all right oh
yeah and then you have a graph query
language it just kind of goes in between
and essentially owl is what teaches the
the store how to store information so
then you can you can kind of query all
right all right moving along so this is
from I think this from up these sides
was Vegas maybe a couple years ago
somebody made these labels that said
this is not a camera and I don't think
he made like a thousand of them you just
like giving them away so like literally
in that in Tuscany Hotel had a label
others said this is not a camera I was
hilarious but the reason I bring it up
is that
you know we spent our most of the time
looking at what we call labels right in
in a semantic technology but actually
feel their field values and through the
field values and through pivoting
through these fields is how we do our
investigations it's how we figure out
what is what and how does it act and and
where does it go so you know I'm
obviously you know III picked a you know
a dumb example users Bob what is Bob is
Bob is Bob an account is Bob a log in
name is it an attempted credential is it
a person is it Microsoft Bob I hope not
so the point is you know a lot of a lot
of these standards or you know mappings
they're done for the analysts benefit
but they're actually not really that
helpful they don't they don't help me
understand what is a user mean here in
this particular case because by user I
can understand a whole lot of different
different things and for machines it's
even harder so we try to weed them out
and try to be as specific as possible
user account is much better I would have
been much better and having a domain to
which that user account is try to
associate maybe it's a host maybe it's
Active Directory would be even more
spectacular so for example route right
and I would say yeah okay but which
which one right I have yeah I have ten
thousand UNIX servers in my organization
each one has a root account which route
are you that seems important right and
that's part of of that complexity that
is inherent in in in in our everyday
activity now basically I'm trying to I'm
turn the dealer a very simple message
here
you know when thinking about things
versus strings we have to think of data
in terms of objects not not in terms of
these little strings and we do we do
that but we constantly have to translate
it from from the lines that we see on
screen
and then actually much less relevant
right so for example I'll tell you that
I have a friend and his name is George
what does it tell you like literally
nothing right you still don't know who
the person is but if I tell you that I
have a friend i have a friend I don't
know you know I'm not gonna tell you his
name but you know he does late night
shopping and QVC and you know he owns a
automatic litter box but he does not own
a cat you're kind of beginning to
understand what kind of person my friend
is right and that's the idea the idea is
that we understand our world by the as
objects and by the associations those
objects have with other objects and
that's why the semantic technology fits
into this model so perfectly because
that's exactly what it does so let's
talk a little bit about how that works
so semantic semantic concepts let's say
now I use this kind of loosely right I
can use my domain account to log in to
my laptop that can be represented as two
objects one is my account for Acme
corporation I have my laptop is an
object and an account as a credential
exists on this host so that's a triple
subject object predicate both of those
things are called vertices our vertex if
it's just one and the edge is the
relationship between objects in
relationships very simple right so now
let's take a look at how that looks like
for the event there we have basically
the same thing and they both have a
relationship to an event event is also
an object so this object this event is
actually been initiated by Anton so I am
logged in into my laptop and so from
this host I am trying to log in
somewhere I am typing in Anton and I am
trying to log into production server
whatever that is right now notice that I
have being able to infer a fact that
since I am logging in from my account on
the host then I can safely say this
account exists on the house otherwise I
wouldn't be able to log in from it but
because it's an attempted authentication
event it does not mean that Anton exists
on the prod server so in this case it's
not a user account
it's an attempted credential or
authentication took see how that works
it's very cool and the pro server has an
IP iners now that's basically so when we
look at when we look at strings right
when we look at the logs this is what's
happening in our minds every single day
but we don't even think about it it's
just happening automatically for us now
semantic graph can extract that and can
map that and it can put it as a part of
a larger network of facts so now you
have this gigantic knowledge base so you
can track you know what other accounts
exists on my laptop right who else try
to login into prod server what other IP
addresses have been assigned to prod
server and you can pivot on that on
those facts very quickly and very easily
and you don't have to know the query
language you don't have to care about
where the data came from which format it
was originally you don't have to
restructure your mappings that's the
whole point
so now let's a little bit talk about
ontology and this this is definitely a
favorite topic of mine anthologies is
basically what separates semantic graph
from just like general graph data source
it's a it's a formal way to describe the
way the knowledge should be structured
it's basically like a schema for your
schema if you a data dictionary so very
powerful stuff and you know using
ontology --zz gives you a very certain
benefits which I would like to actually
spend a little bit of time on so first
of all it federates data in a common
language so no longer we care which
firewall which format this firewall
vendor X is using or this vulnerability
scanner or whatever in the end there is
a model that says vulnerabilities
vulnerability a host is a host and when
the vulnerability exists on a host I
don't care where the data came from
the fact is vulnerability exists on a
host and it's tied to piece of software
and by the way here is the other things
too so that is the main advantage of
using ontology
you can search your data across domains
vertical domains without having to learn
the query and the data structures of all
of those things that have come in second
of all it facilitates reasoning so if we
can look at two things and say you know
what you give me two facts and you tell
me that they're true I will always give
you the third fact that's reasoning so
we'll see how that works in order in a
while but it also means that a lot of
this processing the low-level processing
can be done automatically
without having to go hunt for things
they're actually obvious to you but
they're not obvious to the to the data
that's coming in analytic pivoting this
is where you are actually able to dive
into the data and look at all the facts
that have been collected without
necessarily knowing where they're gonna
lead you so you can you can ask
questions like I wonder what interesting
has happened to this host in the last 24
hours and you can get this sort of a
network of facts where you did not know
that you you know you might see you
might see attempted failed logins you
might see account resets you might see
service interruptions right you might
see reboots
which you did not necessarily even know
how to ask but because they're connected
to that object they're right there in
your neighborhood of that object to be
able to be discovered and that's a very
powerful opportunistic sort of way of
doing analysis so you can test things
out very quickly and prove them if
they're true or not
you can also chain of announced right so
if we look at this beautiful thing and
see how many stages it goes through
that's just one tool right and there's
millions of that stuff out there being
able to string these things these things
together in such a way that that makes
sense and they can be represented as a
part of one data set is extremely
powerful and then guess what then you
can take parts of the chain and you can
see if you have other places in your
knowledge graph
where those parts of the chain take
place and maybe they will lead you to
some very interesting things you did not
even know that you had so that is that
is the other part of it okay so to make
these things work we're gonna need some
we're gonna use some concepts first of
all inheritance very cool stuff this is
something that we have used that my
previous plays Gemini data and it works
it works great so for example you have a
person and person has properties like
every person in the world has a date of
birth and driver's license or maybe an
ID of some sort right that's how we
identify and maybe it's a place of birth
but then if you have an employee that
employee will have yet additional
property which is an employee ID right
so each employee is still a person but
not every person is an employee and you
can query it either way
very cool reverse edges let's say we
have a host that belongs to the domain
and it's a one-way relationship we will
probably also want to be able to ask
domain hey which hosts belong to you
right so being able to automatically
read the outbound relationships is also
very important and support for accents
which is the automated rules that can be
built right into the ontology and help
filling the blanks all right here's a
very quick example of an ontology don't
have to go through that too much
basically you can see how class is kind
of bubble up to the up to here are key
there's a couple of things I wanna I
want to mention so generally the class
hardware has vendor as an organization
for example which means all of its
children will have vendor so it doesn't
matter if you're buying a laptop or a
printer it will have a vendor right but
only some of them like for example
stationery machines or stationary
computer they will have a deployed at
relationships to location and the
hardware wouldn't necessarily so you can
manage your knowledge in the following
way here's an example of an owl we're
kind of running close so what you see
here is the object of a class that
describes user account then one of its
properties which is the name
of that of the that is associate of a
person's name this is a che with the
class and then the third one is an edge
meaning that this object is allowed to
be a member of a group and you see in
the bottom it says range group which
means it's only allowed to have
relationships with the objects of type
group all right very quick here's a
slide I'm not going to go through this
here's some references to existing
ontology so some people have done some
work and published them in an
open-source possible way so you can go
dig in very useful so if you're
interested in this field that's like
that's a good place to get started
especially this I guess DARPA founded
initially a very cool stuff all right
getting close semantic reasoning very
quickly how does it work there is two
ways how reasoning works one is that we
can create an object which could be the
vertex or an edge that must exist always
no matter what usually by definition so
if if a person named IRA has an uncle
Olaf right we can say that always we can
say that one of his parents and we don't
even care which one has a brother
because that's what that's that's what
uncle's are by definition you see the
definition drives relationships another
way is to promote a vertex or an edge
into a more specific subclass based on
information that you receive so again
here's IRA in his beloved uncle Olaf I
don't know maybe he hates him but let's
say we find out that all of smother had
two brothers two boys right and not a
boy and a girl which means the second
sibling is male which means that IRA has
a father now so he had used to have an
edge has parents we don't know anything
about that object but we know that they
exist but now based on additional
information we can make that
relationship more specific how they're
working InfoSec very quickly say we have
a host let's say there is a software
release let's say that software is
installed on that house so the in
students of the software installed on
that host is its own object it's
somewhere in that path and let's say
that the software release over here has
a vulnerability so if we collect these
three edges we can say if these three
edges are always present between these
systems between these objects we can
always create a fourth edge which is
that host is vulnerable to that software
so that's an example of a hard logic
that I mean you can quantify it too but
for the sake of argument let's say will
always be true and we have figured out
that that host is vulnerable not by
running availability scan which we can
buy by simply using the three facts that
was given to us so that's pretty cool so
where does it lead us there is several
things that that enables that weren't
possible before contextual analytics we
talked about about that a little bit
more so instead of looking at the raw
data and statistics and top tens and
bottom tens and all that we should
actually look at the logical facts and
see which facts make sense in which
facts do not clustering is being able to
identify objects simply by the
relationships that they have you know I
have twenty web servers and this system
I didn't know there was a web server but
everything that it does and everything
that it says is exactly like a web
server so maybe that's a web server
outliers
hey this sales guy has a really strange
unusual permissions for a sales guy
because everybody in his organization
does this yet you know he's in all the
admin groups what's up on that and the
tricky one
similar subgraphs if this is an attack
find me another subgraph in my knowledge
graph that is very similar to that
because that means it's also probably
gonna be an attack I think that's about
it so parting words
remember Semantic Web technologies that
have been around for a while there's
been since the beginning of the web XML
is built on it google's pagerank was
built on it it's not just for Google
anymore let's get in there let's use it
even when you're looking at fields
you're always dealing with things
so remember that when you're doing your
data modeling keep that into
consideration pay attention to your data
modeling it's very important it's gonna
save you a lot of heartaches it's like
taking the trash out nobody wants to do
it but you got to do it manage knowledge
think about how you manage knowledge in
your organization how do you retain all
of these lessons and all of these
learnings that come after an incident
where do they go who takes care of them
can they be read later can can that
power to be automated so think about
that and stay in touch and thank you
very much guys
[Applause]