[Music]
all right thank you very much
let's start all over again so good to be
here good morning everybody so just some
housekeeping notes this is not the talk
about browser injections in JavaScript
if that's your cup of tea I'm told
that's in track one which is a really
cool IMAX theater you can check that out
it's also not to talk about the meltdown
and memory exploits if that's where
you'd rather be that's the talk in track
three which is theater seven so if you
are still in your seats that means
you're in the right room we're going to
be talking about overcoming obstacles in
operationalizing security I'm really
really excited to be here and talking to
you about that so a little bit about
what the talk is gonna constitute I'm
gonna introduce a little bit about me
I'm gonna introduce why we are doing
this talk and then it always helps to
define the problem right so I want to
make sure we all understand what is the
context within which we are operating
and why I thought about talking talking
to you about this topic and then they're
gonna go really specifically into some
of the obstacles that we are here to
talk about and not just leave you with
those obstacles but also try to discuss
what are some of the approaches that we
can use to overcome those obstacles and
hopefully we'll have some time remaining
for question and answers so you already
heard a little bit about me so I
graduated from Purdue University a
little over 10 years ago and then I
worked at a variety of companies that
are shown here so I've worked as a
researcher I've worked at a security
developer I've also worked on the
consulting side of things on the audit
side of things and then most recently
did did a gig at a startup where well at
that time a start-up and help them
become become of a public company as a
manager responsible for their security
and compliance efforts and currently I'm
with the healthcare startup healthcare
where I'm leading their security program
I also teach part-time at Santa Clara
University where I teach a graduate
course in information security why do I
do that because I realized that there is
no formal education
patient in this area and therefore you
know we we all learn from experience and
so I would like to share what I've
learned from my experience in in you
know mentoring the next generation of
security professionals okay so with that
said why am I here to talk about this
topic today well so when I joined
healthTap I thought that okay I've seen
it all I've been there more than 10
years I've looked at it from the inside
and the outside I've worked at companies
both large and small so what can go
wrong right except the fact that I had
never worked at healthTap doing the same
type of thing that I did there which is
building a security program from scratch
and so I learned a few lessons along the
way and I would like to share them
because I realized I believe I'm not the
only one who has ever done that or will
ever do that again and so I think it'll
be helpful for everyone to to understand
what it the process might look like so
this talk would begin where most other
talks on this topic usually end which is
you know that we we are told that okay
we need to learn how to communicate
risks we need to get buy-in from
stakeholders and we need to you know we
need to project security as an enabler
and not a blocker that's all good but
what I wanted to convey is what's
usually not discussed which is that
unless you have been in the trenches
you wouldn't know so hence the analogy
between MapQuest and waves maybe some of
you already got the analogy which is you
may know the direction right one of
these tools is going to give you the
directions to get there but one of these
tools is going to show you the obstacles
along the way and then you can steer
your course around that so the takeaways
for you will be what obstacles to
anticipate and what trade-offs you can
make so with that said let's let's get
into the problem statement and try to
define define you know what I'm going to
present to you when you are when your
job is to start a security program at a
startup typically that you know that
what is the
textbook ask you to do it will ask you
to look at these variables you need to
define your risk surface typically you
do that by threat modeling you need to
understand what your resources are which
would include a mix of budget resource
human resources you know talent and
tools and then you need to see how those
resources map to your capabilities so
that's all fine and good there is
another element here which is the rate
at which these resources change and they
might change linearly or non linearly a
little bit of college algebra there so
throwback twelve months when I started
the program at healthTap I did exactly
the same thing I created like a road map
like it's 30 60 90 day plan as you would
expect I would hit I would anticipate
that I would hit certain milestones by a
certain certain time period and that
would help improve the security maturity
of the program classic textbook approach
this was underlined by a linear
assumption and a linear assumption a you
know basically works as follows the
prong one is that the resource
availability is going to adjust itself
based on the risk surface so this is
where your your traditional approaches
come in you present a risk report to the
management you walk away with the
dollars and then you hire the employees
that's all that's all fine and good the
second approach is that the capability
is also actually improve in response to
the resources that you get right fast
forward a few months I quickly realized
that the reality is nonlinear which is
as shown here if you notice my security
roadmap I wasn't actually able to add
resources as fast as I had anticipated
to to address my risk surface and that
red line over there indicates the reason
why because if you see in the middle
column I have a few items that are still
not in the completed State despite those
periods actually being being over and so
what that really means is I hit a
negative slope this is why the linear
azar
chan fails because the risk profile did
not adjust itself or the resource
allocation did not adjust itself based
on the risk profile so if you are
starting a security program at a startup
you are going to hit a negative slope
and you should be prepared to first zero
it out and then start with the positive
the second important prong is that even
if you get the resources that you need
it is not always going to mean that it
translates into the capabilities that
you need to address your risks and
therefore it's an important combination
of making sure that you get the
resources and the capabilities we will
get back to this point about making sure
that you you hire right and it's a good
mix of talent and tools but for now you
might wonder that when I when I got the
stark reality stark contrast between the
textbook approach and what's the reality
you might wonder if I was scared and you
bet I was however I also wondered if why
why else aren't we talking about about
this right and quickly it all began to
make sense we are all part of the
security community the same security
community just working for different
organizations at different levels of
maturity we talk about what mature
organizations have done but we don't
talk about the struggles of them getting
there if you are starting a security
program at a startup you would find
yourself on the left to the middle of
this curve and this curve can be
considered as a bell curve of the
relative security maturity of the
organization's right and so when you are
planning for for your you know security
maturity you would have to look at it it
helps to get a sense of how far behind
you really are and and that sense that
can that can be actually scary but at
the same time you got a you got a better
understanding of what is the what is the
security maturity that you will actually
be that would actually be trying to
achieve and knowing where you are on
this bell curve is is really important
okay so with with that said I wanna I
wanna I want to start with this
realization that there's a big gap in
terms of the effort required to lay
proper foundation of a security program
so with that said ladies and gentlemen
it's time to start your engines
if you cannot build a Ferrari or if you
cannot build your own Tesla given the
resource constraints let's start with
the Prius
okay but there is an upside to this and
the upside is that you should consider
yourself lucky that you got an
opportunity to go through this challenge
because you don't get a greenfield
opportunity every day and that is where
rubber meets the road
so with that problem statements that
aside let's let's try to dive into what
what are the some of the specific
obstacles that that you might that you
might anticipate that you might face and
then how would you might overcome them
so I'm gonna start with the first one
which is picking your battles wisely so
the the textbook is going to throw tons
of stuff at you right and it's very
likely that when you are starting a
security program you're going to do some
research you might even need to catch up
on some trends right but be careful
because the lenders are going to create
a lot of hype for you they're gonna be a
lot of buzz words out there and so you
know the vendors are gonna remind you of
the worst breaches but keep that in
context understand for example what the
breach stands for if someone you know
what helped have what I started to do
was I started to publish what are called
security advisories I would take a
breach I would see exactly what happened
what was the risk is that same risk
applicable to my environment and what
can we do to protect that that is the
more helpful way to to internalize
what's actually important to you based
on what's happening around you similarly
you're gonna be looking at tons of
alphabet soup you know you're gonna be
looking at you know from a compliance
perspective you'll be looking at GDP are
you gonna be looking at AI ISO
again just because of those buzzwords
don't fall into the trap that you
necessarily need to invest more a lot of
times what's important is you do a base
lining and this is this is where your
traditional approaches will help you but
it's important too to do that base
lining because it helps avoid
duplicative and investment you mean you
may not realize but a lot of these
controls and all these regulations are
actually hitting at the same underlying
security fundamentals and if you got
your fundamentals correct it is my it is
my belief it is it is the way I'd like
to operate that if you have your
fundamentals correct you're probably
gonna hit all those all those checkboxes
so the lesson here is not every bright
and shiny seal is worth the paper it's
printed on I have been defending you
know various requests for getting one
seal versus the other with my management
and sometimes you know this is this is
the reverse cycle where I'm advocating
them not to spend more money we will
talk more about how that helps you gain
their trust in just a little bit so let
me give you some specific examples of
these trade-offs right one thing I also
like to mention is that you may also
want to find if there a simpler approach
of doing something and the answer is
almost always yes we'll see some
examples coming up as well and then
don't ignore the low-hanging fruit
right where which the things that you
can knock off without significant
resource investments and some examples
on this slide
so speaking of trends you might see you
know attack simulation red teaming bug
bounties we even had a you know keynote
on bug bounty or earlier this morning
you would have to really understand
whether or not you are at a stage where
all of this makes sense to you or not
right so in terms of attack simulation
and red teaming that the and try to
understand what the purpose is there
understood the purpose is if your
controls are actually working
effectively but if you don't even have
the controls right it's kind of like the
prerequisite of that is you need to have
some controls in place so why do that
investment again when you can wait
and see if you have some controls that
are operational and thence investing in
these tools
similarly for bug bounties their purpose
is to expose vulnerabilities ask
yourself if you have a process in place
to do something with the vulnerabilities
are otherwise wait until that process is
in place some other buzzwords like Web
Application Firewall DDoS protection you
need to ask yourself is your technology
or is your application built on a modern
technology with security principles in
mind that make valve type of protection
you know still relevant or not if you're
already making if your application has
already built on a platform to which the
vast protection does not apply you need
you don't need to fall for them for the
buzzwords are you a likely target are
you so you know are you so much at risk
of being a likely target of a tacit AK
this is this is a question worth having
or are you in a platform like AWS
where you you have basic protection to
begin with and then you need to start
worrying about it when you when you
scale to a level where you are a likely
target so once again you know these are
all the buzzwords but we but we need to
internalize our own priorities and
understand where we fall I want to give
a really specific example about endpoint
protection because EDRs and you know
threat hunting this this is the rage
these days you need to you need to
understand whether or not you need a
fully managed solution or can you do it
a combination of manual configuration
with auditing so at healthTap while we
are small enough the approach that I'm
using is we have something called this
user security checklist so it's not just
about the price point but it's also when
you ask the users to do these 10 things
when they when they on board it gives
them a better awareness of what the
risks are as opposed to getting a device
that's like out of the box configured
with with 10 things that they don't even
you know are not necessarily aware of so
when the users go through those 10 steps
they get an increased sense of awareness
of you
these are the important things and then
going back to the security advisory I
regularly publish when a particular
breach took advantage of a particular
thing on my list that was not done
properly by a user
you know like two-factor or some other
example going back to that how
generating awareness I would like to
point out that awareness training is
almost always going to be an immediate
priority it's just a matter of how you
approach it right I feel that as a
community we need to give more love to
awareness training we need to do that in
a way that actually helps promote
security culture so for example that
help tab when I when I joined we were
using a off-the-shelf software to you
know do security training and you all
know the feeling you go through it you
know you click different links but what
I what I decided to do was I decided to
prepare and deliver that training
in-house and that has had a significant
impact on you know the awareness and
culture of the employees and making sure
that everybody is actually aware of the
value of why we are doing that so that
that's another example of where you know
with a little bit or next to no
investment you can you can get it get it
get a lot of value out of your security
program so the next point I want to talk
about is identifying your allies and
gaps early so obviously you would know
that you cannot go the whole nine yards
alone right that's what the textbook
tells you you know David asked you to
identify the collaborators identify the
department's but what they don't tell
you is what if the department you really
need to get something done doesn't yet
exist okay
so the answer is you become that
department will we'll discuss some
specific examples but the show must go
on
the other thing that you should be
mindful office do more but expect less
to be done for you okay
so often when you come from large
companies there are specific people
responsible for doing specific things
and you are in the habit of you know
delegating certain tasks but when you
are at a small start-up you should you
should be aware of the fact that you may
not have too many people to delegate
those tasks
so the textbook will tell you you know
you know yet you have to be hands-on you
have to be an enabler but that doesn't
always mean getting your way
you know the textbook tells you get the
buy-in but what does a buy-in really
mean right so my answer to that is
impress them with your judgement and
then money will follow so let's talk
about some specific examples of these
trade-offs right so essentially the idea
here is that you have to chart your own
process when I when I started there
there wasn't a robust enough process for
us to be notified when an employee is
joining or leaving and rather than
waiting for you know a full-fledged work
the implementation to be there I took
advantage of simple JIRA based workflows
I tied them into whatever system you
know wherever a notification is
triggered of a new hire of a hire you
know joining or an employee leaving I
connected that to like a ticketing
system there you know some tickets will
get generated some spreadsheets will get
populated same thing with IT most likely
you are not gonna have a very robust IT
when you when you join a small startup
that is going to take care of your
identity management needs that is going
to make sure that all the identities are
streamlined all the access is you know
provision and deprovision timely you you
will probably need to get up to speed on
those workflows there are a lot of tools
out there that can help you with that
but rather than waiting for you know
an IT or an HR system implementation
just just be more creative about that
and and make spreadsheets your best
friends make JIRA tickets your best
friend and build some build some tools
around that how about actually
implementing security features and
building that in your in your you know
product lifecycle so you might be used
to working with a product manager who's
going to write the spec specification
for you and then follow up on that but
the reality is that there may be no
project manager so you have to be the
one who is writing the specifications
and keep pushing the product team to
pick it up remember that there will
always be plenty on the product roadmap
that you are competing with so you have
to stay persistent in my experience it
took me
several months for some of the features
that I really really wanted to go into
product roadmap to finally get in I kept
getting you know it's it's it's gonna be
the next and then the next and then the
next release but you need to keep the
pressure up and at some point know when
is the right time to escalate and then
remember we talked about how the
resources don't always translate into
capabilities so even if you have funding
you need to get some tools
you need to roll out some tools in your
environment to be able to take advantage
of that but if you don't have
procurement what do you do well going
with the trend you become the
procurement you need to learn the art of
negotiation you need to build the trust
to be able to do the right thing in my
example I did a negotiation for an
access control system and you know I was
thrown into that that situation even
though that was not my primary
responsibility but after I had done it
once and I did it successfully guess
what I earned the trust of the
management and now I I go in with a
request and they they trust me that I
have already negotiated down to the most
acceptable price okay so the other point
I want to bring up is the tension
between advice and practice so often
times when you know we are looking at
the textbooks we learned that you know
training the developers is important
train as early as possible in the
process and making it you know delaying
that it's going to make things more
difficult for you and in reality your
mileage will vary the key is how much of
an opportunity you have in the software
development lifecycle to do a careful
review and no amount of training can
actually compensate for the pressures of
releasing often and early which is the
DevOps mantra so I'll give you some
examples on how to trade that off the
other thing is the textbook tells you
write detailed specifications get them
reviewed and approved before the code is
written and the feature is implemented
good luck with that because building it
when you're joining a start-up you're
pretty much building the plane as you
fly it and a really good metaphor that
I'd like to use there is that specs are
like guideposts not gospel deviation may
be expected and lastly you know the
classic example of when to apply or
delay a patch the textbook tells you
that do not ever ignore a high severity
CVE but in practice there may be
competing trade-offs the system may be
on a critical path you cannot afford the
downtime there may be no redundancy so
how do you deal with those situations so
going back to our examples of these
trade-offs with respect to s DLC you
should balance the training with tools
what we did is one of the earliest
things I did was you know based on the
application security testing we did we
identified what are the most frequent
flaws in our code what are the most
frequent mistakes the developers are
making automate the checks for those
those type of issues in your you know
static code analysis tools and then
prepare guides like really handy guides
not like long lectures that help the
developers first of all understand and
realize that hey yes we are making these
mistakes and we need to improve and that
gets the message across very effectively
the other thing I'd like to talk about
is you know do not underestimate the
power of nudge so there's a thin line
between when the employers are you know
going to co-op whether the employees may
cooperate with you versus consider
security as becoming too intrusive and
so nothing can help you know a little
bit of nudging can help them even when
compared to an army of security tools at
our disposal so for those of you who
don't know nudge is actually an you know
an economic concept it's a
nobel-prize-winning economic theory and
even though in this context we are not
talking about economics but it's still
relevant to the ROI on your on your
security investments so I'll give you an
example
DLP reminders so
although I believe that a DLP tool isn't
necessarily making you know a
significant contribution towards
improving my security baseline
however the DLP tool has this nudge
factor every time you know we detect
sensitive information being shared which
we don't know is with a user who
actually you know has a purpose to
receive that or not we send a reminder
to the user that hey please take a look
is this information really necessary to
be sure to this person and with this way
with this nudging it gradually will
inculcate an awareness in our in our
employees that they have to be careful
every time they are taking that step and
that's also a good compromise between
you know clamping down on all sharing
versus making sure that your user base
is educated on proper awareness one
thing I would like to also emphasize is
it's okay to give unsolicited advice you
are working in an environment where you
know the feedback loops are not
streamlined there isn't enough
opportunity to for the teams to
recognize or to request help therefore
you know don't be afraid to offer advice
when needed
if the Specht has holes go ahead and
fill them there is there isn't going to
be a security checklist waiting for you
to put your stamp of approval on it's up
to you to insert it where it's needed
you know the best where where security
checks are needed and make sure that you
you provide that advice at the right
time and lastly on the topic of you know
when or when not to apply you know a
critical fix the idea is that if it
cannot go and immediately make sure that
you are monitoring it and monitor the
known vulnerability it is a reality you
will be running with some percent of
vulnerable systems you you cannot be not
vulnerable at all times so continue to
identify the first available opportunity
to to fix them and then my last topic is
going to be by what you must and build
what you can this is kind of like the
most common sense
of all the topics that we've talked
about where you know that the textbook
comes fairly close to reality but there
are just a few things that the textbook
doesn't quite lay down for you so
there's always going to be a right
combination of tools talent and training
what I really wanted to emphasize is
don't be afraid to go with modern or
newer vendors because oftentimes there's
a tendency to think that you know only
the established and entrenched players
are the ones that you want to go before
but with startups there are two reasons
why that may or may not always work out
they may have some you know they may
have like a lower limit of like at least
how big of a company if they want to
work with and and you'll be out of luck
there secondly discuss your use case
with them and you may be surprised that
vendors can sometimes be unbiased
consultants or advisers I've had this
experience where the vendor would very
frankly talk about their own technology
and say that hey they're using all these
buzzwords this part of it may not be
true may be may be exaggerated but this
is our real value so and often times you
know I know that we we want to show we
want to stay away from talking to
salespeople but if you if you're looking
at a like you know smaller vendor you
may find yourself talking to engineers
you may find yourself talking to even
the CEO and you can have a really candid
discussion and I have personally really
taken advantage of that fact so don't
shy away from doing that
the other is to put things between the
DIY versus the bio buckets again it's
kind of like a common-sense thing but
the point that I wanted to bring across
here is that you know make sure that you
take into account when you when you on
board a tool make sure that you have the
resources you have the right kind of
talent to support that or make a
decision between that the tool that has
just enough capability to keep you going
right that comes with the built in
features and then you have the remaining
amount of resources on hand to kind of
fine-tune that tool so for example if
you're making investment to an open
source tool or rather if you are not
making an investment and using an open
source tool then you'd have to make an
investment into the human resource
but if you don't have a human resource
then you would go with some something
that gives you a little bit to get
started with you to chew on and then
have someone that that can take it take
it from there so that's that's kind of
like a common-sense thing but I just
want to touch upon that in case that you
know in case that doesn't doesn't get
ignored and it's important to know where
technology will give you advantage so
automate where technology will give you
advantage and then rely on manual
efforts where it's best stood suited for
example security analytics or pen
testing type of work and a few examples
right here would be when we are when we
were looking at our including detection
system we wanted to see what's the most
cost efficient way so one way for you to
do that is to not have all of the raw
data being fed into your sim maybe using
maybe use another service that's gonna
give you you know an analyzed
feed off of threats and then have put
you know you can direct that feed into
into your sim similarly for a mobile
device management I was not a fan of the
huge service and implementation fee that
the large vendors charge and so I I'm
inclined to go towards a system where
once again going back to the user
security checklist you have a trust but
verify approach and so you know you
would trust the users to do the right
thing but at the same time you want to
make sure that you can audit them
frequently enough and while you are at a
scale where it can still be effective
and lastly Identity Management you know
are you one of those environments that
absolutely don't want to have ad in your
in your ecosystem if you're in Google
cloud go with a cloud-based LDAP that
connects directly with with the identity
store and if you are if you are
cognizant of the per user and
implementation fee for having you know
an identity system for you know entire
organization focus on the most critical
subsets first so for example I took a I
took a turn on on that and instead of
you know starting with the whole the
whole company first I started to focus
on just an engineering team and just
focusing on the infrastructure and
decided to go with the vendor that is
going to help me with the infrastructure
for
and then and then that can be explained
to the whole company and that really
brings a lot of cost savings for for
everybody so I think with that I would
take a pause and see if there are any
questions but thank you so much for
being here today
sorry can you repeat the question yeah
so I think the question of so the
question is with you know after all that
education how are you going to improve
on the hiring and retention so that is
that is something that again is part of
you know the nonlinear nature of
building a security program and that is
something a little bit more on the on
the personal side of things then then
what you can put in terms of you know
practical steps to you know directly
affect the security maturity of the
program but you know the hiring and
retention obviously is a challenge for
for all security you know for for all
companies particularly in the Bay Area
but I mean to to that effect I would say
that having having the right balance of
you know tools and resources on your
team and making sure that it's not one
person's job to to be you know the
end-to-end you know a soldier for for
every single thing that for me it has
been something that I've noticed as a
red red flag so don't don't
burn them out and then making sure that
you know you are you know going back to
what I said about creating incentives so
making sure that employees are
incentivized for for bringing forward
good security practices but at the end
of the day I mean it is it is a key
challenge you know hiring and retention
is something that you know is it's kind
of like a broader thing than just
limited to a security program so but as
a security team you can you can you can
do a lot of things by making sure that
you are not over burdening any any
single employee with a lot of
responsibilities and making sure that
you can hire right making sure that they
are passionate about the role that
they're doing and you can you can do a
lot of that planning but it's it's it's
it's unfortunately something where the
results are not always guaranteed I
think there is one more question yeah
that's a great question the ratio of
Junior versus senior is something that
is is a really critical critical piece
and on my team right now
the people who are dedicated to security
are relatively junior but the people
that are indirectly helping security but
are not dedicated to security are senior
people so I would and again hiring
senior people in security you know going
back to the previous question is going
to be challenging for a small small
start-up and therefore you know
leveraging as much as you can from
senior people that that are not directly
on part of the security team is going to
be very helpful so for example your
DevOps team make sure they are your best
friends the one of the first things I
did was you know make strong connections
with that with that lead DevOps person
and make sure that they are aware that
how every move they are making directly
or indirectly impact security and
therefore to answer that question yes
it's it's going to be a challenge to
have a lot of senior people in security
on your team directly but make sure that
you have good connections with senior
people in related
areas like DevOps and engineering and
make them indirectly part of your your
security agenda all right I think I'm
the last one standing between you and
the lunch so I'd let you let you go and
and have some had some lunch thank you
so much it's been it's been awesome
talking to you okay
Thank You Raphael and in the name of the
adobe and beside let me give you this