[Music]
thank you hello everybody
thanks for coming out to my talk I'm
Yeti I work at stack rocks it's a small
start-up and we do containers security
and container you're always on the
bleeding edge of container security
research so this is my talk and see if
finding malicious artifacts and
container environments so for all you
Harry Potter fans out there this is a
code from Dumbledore I use the pen sieve
one simply siphons the excess thoughts
from one's mind it becomes easier to
spot patterns and links when they are in
this form wouldn't it be great if we had
a pin sieve for container environments
as we should we shall see in the stock
we really do need a tool that transforms
containers into a form that makes it
easier for us to spot patterns and links
so imagine you're running your workloads
on AWS you have a bunch of virtual
machines and you recently deployed
containers to better utilize your
resources you get a call at 2:00 a.m. in
the morning and you just found out that
you one of the containers is breached
like what do you do for incident
response so containers have become
really popular among developers and
devops it's much faster to run a
container compared to your virtual
machine and it comes at a lower disk
footprint as more and more and
infrastructures adopt containers the
incentives to attack them also increases
security is one of the major concerns
when it comes to deploying containers in
production and industry is still
gathering slow momentum there and this
is even so true for Incident Response
forensic analysis and you know tools and
techniques in container environments are
barely known or even explored so this
talk is more about like how do we do
forensics and containers existing tools
and techniques work well with virtual
machines but it's not so efficient when
it comes to containers
imagine having to snapshot the entire
hosts memory in order to look at a
single process or even when your
workloads are entirely on container
managed services like AWS Fargate where
you don't even have the luxury
to run host memory capture tools like
Linux memory extractor for example so
existing techniques don't fundamentally
change but they need adjustments to make
sense of container artifacts so imagine
having to like if you have to extract
evidence from a single container there's
no tailor-made solutions when there are
hundreds of containers running on the
host so in this talk I'll describe what
considerations you have to make when it
comes to containers I'll first give you
an overview of docker containers and
then outline some of the methods you can
use to gather evidence and correlate
them to specific containers so docker is
an open source platform to easily manage
your darker containers and what are
containers containers are basically a
bunch of sandbox processes they are
given an illusion of isolation using
Linux abstractions called as C groups
and namespaces in darkus terminology
though a container is just an
instantiation of an image an image is
basically a file that encapsulate all
the metadata you read and you need to
create a bunch of processes and darker
identifies containers using this unique
identifier called as container ID and
images are identified by image ID
having these IDs makes it easier to
correlate artifacts found in containers
so what are namespaces namespaces
basically implement resource I process
isolation it limits water risk what a
process can see in terms of resources
such as files users or even file
directories and so on for example like
the bid namespace control speed mapping
and the net-net namespace allows Network
isolation and so on you could list all
the namespaces available on Linux under
the proc file system here's an example
where I create a new namespace and run
bash under it if you run a PS command
you will see that bash is mapped to PP
ID one but it's obviously mapped to a
different PID on the host imagine you're
looking at some logs produced by a
process running in a container
the pits log in in those logs might
appear differently
different than the hosts so having the
the context of hostname space makes
correlating them easy and control groups
or C groups are another real enix
abstraction that have been there for a
long time and they implement quotas for
processes so one can limit how much
memory a process consumes or how much
child processes that they can fork you
know they get they they limit what abuse
one can do and they also track resource
usage there are almost like 12c groups
in Linux today and they represent
various subsystems like devices memory
how many processes you can you can fork
and so on here's an example of creating
a memory C group and limiting it to
hundred bytes it's an unrealistic
example but it's just an example C
groups don't impact forensic analysis so
much but they definitely give you more
context on how much resource your
containers are using so it's important
it's important to understand how files
are modified in darker containers so
that you can perform forensic analysis
and you can reconstruct files and
correlate them better to a specific
container docker containers use
specialized file system drivers to
access files and they're based on what
is known as the layered file system so
what is a layered file system layered
file system is basically a file system
driver that gives you the ability to
create like a single unified file system
out of different layers and on the
right-hand side here you see an example
of a docker image basically it's
composed of various layers and when a
container is instantiated a thin reader
layer is created and it's set as a
topmost layer and all the rights that go
through the container are actually
executed in this topmost layer but all
the underlying layers remain read-only
and they they use the strategy callers
copy-on-write
to modify files that are present in one
of these layers basically and on the
hand side you see an example of
dockerfile dr. fire basically is a file
that captures all the instructions that
you need to create a darker image here's
another example of a layered file system
known as the Ola FS and it comes as a
default in the latest versions of darker
an overlay FS is basically similar to a
u FS but it's much faster and it comes
with a simpler implementation here you
see that it has basically two layers one
is called the lower directory or the
image layer which remains read-only and
the upper Dietary is readwrite and the
merged directory gives you like a
uniform view of the file system the
memory layout of a process running
inside a container remains pretty much
the same it has the usual stack heap
data and text segment like any other
Linux process but we need we really need
tools that can actually gather evidence
from a single process rather than having
to snapshot the entire host memory so
when it comes to disk forensics on a
docker host it's pretty much the same as
you do it on a regular system you'd
ideally create like a disk dump using DD
command and ideally the main memory but
using traditional tools will not give
you a complete picture unless the
specifics or darker are considered so
docker
there are several issues one must
consider when you perform forensic
analysis on a docker host like I
mentioned docker accesses files through
specialized file system drivers which
don't map to a block device and this
makes mapping recovered files to a
specific container tricky and files
could be deleted from the readwrite
layer or the read-only layer which must
be considered and the dog the container
itself could be dead which wipes out
most of the metadata and this makes for
insects really really challenging live
analysis implies that containers are
still running and you have several
options here basically a security
analysis could
like back up the continued file system
and all the metadata on a regular basis
and daca provides several options here
one could do a darker export to capture
or capture the containers file system
into a tar file or one could save the in
darker image into a tar file or one
could commit all the changes that are
happening in the container into a new
image using docker commit command and
all these files could be later used to
perform analysis using docker import or
docker load one thing to note here is
that docker export and import command
don't preserve the image history but the
docker save and load preserves the image
history and knowing the image history
becomes important if you want to find
out if the image layer has been tampered
with so like I mentioned having
container metadata is really important
when it comes to analysis when to
perform correlation and docker
usually by default stores all this
metadata under wallop docker and if you
can if you want to look at a specific
container you could go into the
container subdirectory and look at it
and here you will see like various
information related to contain layer
image layers the container ID the image
ID all the mounted directories and so on
so if a file is deleted from a container
there could be two possibilities the
file originates from the readwrite layer
or the file originates from the image
layer so when files are deleted from the
readwrite layer it's actually deleted on
the host file system and then to recover
those files you need to employ a
techniques that you would employ to
recover files from a host file system
there are two popular techniques one is
called the file carving method and the
other one is called the filesystem
analysis method file carving method is
basically a recovery technique that is
employed when there is no file system
metadata and what this technique does is
basically it scans the entire disk and
it looks for patterns and the patterns
typically used our head of values from
the from popular file formats like PDF
e.l.f JPEGs and so on but files are
often fragmented on the file system and
this technique does not guarantee full
reconstruction of files with all its
metadata intact and when you want to
relay it files to its originating
containers it becomes crucial that you
have all the metadata like the file part
and the file name
that's where the other technique comes
into play which is the file system
analysis this technique is driven by its
it makes much more informed decisions
based on the file system metadata it
uses the metadata such as the master
file table the inode table the directory
entries and so on and this technique
actually provides you some guarantees of
recovering the file with all the
metadata intact so this is much more
useful when it comes to analyzing
containers and correlating files to
specific container if a file is deleted
from the readwrite layer though what the
file system driver does is attack such
files and it'll Achatz a new inode and
tax it as a character type character
device and one could find such files
using a fine command under the images
directory so assuming that you record a
file using previous techniques I'll
describe how you can associate that file
to a specific container so the first
thing you will need is a docker ID and
docker ID can be found by running docker
PS command assuming the container is
still running and this example is based
on the au FS driver and all the files in
a EFS are stored in under wallop docker
au FS and here you will find a layered
subdirectory which has all the various
layers of the image but the file could
originate from any one of these layers
and if you look at the layers
subdirectory it has a bunch of a u FS
IDs so you really need the AFS ID from
the from the file path that you that you
recovered and once you have the au FS ID
what what you
do is go through all the containers and
look at the amount IDs and they the
mount IDs are nothing but the au FS IDs
and in order to associate a file to a
container you could match the AFS IDs
found here to D a of sids in the layers
and if you find a match
you basically found the file where it
originated from so traditional tools
that are typically used for memory
forensics such as memory linux extractor
requires you to snapshot the entire host
memory and this this is a time consuming
operation and several cloud providers
don't even allow you to run these tools
you'd have to file a service ticket or
something in AWS to have them retrieve
the host memory so this makes it
challenging for containers and even if
you have the host memory dump you it
it's really tricky to associate like
specific evidence you find there to a
specific container and this is where
newer tools like cry you offer much more
potential you should see that in the
next few slides
so what's cry you cry stands for
checkpoint and in restore and user space
it's been around for a while and it's
basically a tool that will allow you to
freeze a running process and checkpoint
it as a bunch of image files on disk it
basically walks through every task of a
process and it'll find out all the
resources that it uses and then it
basically converts them to an image
format and these image files can be used
to restore them back to a running
process and this opens up a lot of
interesting use cases like live
migration debugging load balancing and
so on if you watch like the coop con
like several years back they had a quick
game and they could like literally
freeze the quake game and they they
would do a live migration from Singapore
to London and they would resume the game
back that was that was done through pry
you actually but it also has
applications in forensics as we shall
see
cry you also comes with the stool caller
script or the cryo image tool and this
tool basically helps you to analyze and
decode the image files that you produce
during the checkpointing process it is
similar to volatility in that it
provides you a few plugins that makes it
easier to retrieve the running processes
the files that the processes used the
network connections and the memory
mappings and so on let's see this in a
demo and how we can use cry you to
perform on memory foreign six so in this
demo what I'm going to do is I'll spin
up a container and the container is
running a web application it's a very
simple app web application that's using
a vulnerable version of Apache struts
and this was basically behind the
equifax attack a few months back and
I'll use Metasploit to attack this
container and we shall checkpoint the
container and see what kind of evidence
we find in the container so here I
launch the container I'll take a
snapshot using cry U and here is here or
all the image files it produces and here
is an example of using crit and PS is
basically one of the plugins that you
can use to see list all the running
processes that at the time of
checkpointing here you see that there's
only one process running and we can also
find out all the network connections
that were active during check boiling
process there's two network connections
active that's listening on 8080 and 809
and you can also see all the files that
were open by the process sorry about
that it's flickering and
we can restore the continuum back so
that we can launch another attack so
I'll launch Metis flight and so
basically what Midas Floyd is doing is
it's using one of the exploit I'm using
the reverse shell here you could use any
exploit and so I'm establishing a
reverse shell on the container and just
make sure we are in the container I'm
running an IP other and the IP address
is actually the IP address of the
container and here I'm basically making
another snapshot and here you see that
there's another process running which is
basically the shell process for the
river shell and we can see all the
network connections and there's another
network connection and the four four
four four is actually the port on the
local machine and that's the IP address
of the local machine and we can also see
all the files that were opened by the
shell it's not doing much but get a
point so that's essentially what cry you
can do it has a few plugins but in
future you can see this expanding slight
volatility so to summarize my talk
basically we saw that we need more
container aware forensic tools to make
them much useful and you saw that docker
uses file system drivers which makes
associating files to containers tricky
we also saw that popular tools like
volatility need more darker context in
order to make them more useful we saw
how cry you can be used for forensics we
also saw that container orchestrators
and container manager services makes and
even deleted containers to make make
forensics really challenging and that's
pretty much it yeah these are all the
references I used and thank you
thanks for coming out I know it's the
last talk thank you if you have any
questions take it yes yeah like Oh for
the holster for the container itself the
talking container so for the docker
container there's not a lot of bigger
tools out there but cry U is one of them
that you can use to specific capture at
containers memory it actually can it
actually could captures a specific
containers memory only the main memory
not the disk memory yes any other
question yes yes you can use a tool
called contrac oh sorry
so the question was basically if you
could use the proc file system to track
network connections so yes you can use
the proc file system used like because
you have all the FDS in the proc file
system and you can identify fan ft is a
socket type and you can decipher I think
there's a tool called contrac that
basically like polls the proc file
system for a specific PID and it keeps
track of all the network connections
there
yes yes yeah you basically use the PID
to associate a container spread to a
hospital
any other questions
can't see Angie
okay well that that's the final talk of
the day thank you yeah here's a nice
gift for you from b-sides and Autodesk
thank you and let's give him a hand
[Applause]