[Music]
thank you Andy can you guys hear me well
in the front background cool coin miners
detection search by 8500 percent in 2017
how many of you here experienced at
least one corn miner related incident in
a memoir based or web browsing based any
answer yeah so obviously it's a big
problem my main goal here today is to
give you a set of tools and techniques
to deal with this emerging threat my
name is Omri Saiga of morale and I'm
co-founder and head of research at
Minerva into 2016 at my first encounter
with coin miners and been tracking them
ever since the rapid rise of this threat
have pushed me to create this
presentation to increase awareness and
help others fight it I would like to
thank my research team at Minerva and
other researchers such as bad pocket and
zero dot taking a really strong part in
this ongoing war coin miners are new
surging threat one of the biggest sign
for rapid emergence is multiples name
for it just to name a few
it's coin - Krypto - crypto jackin I
heard some cursing in there and and so
on I personally like to use coin miners
when I speak about the overall problem
malicious benign and crypto jackin when
speaking about web-based in browser
JavaScript attacks like wanna hive and
crypto mining when speaking about
malware based attacks so the rapid
increase is usually related to Kona I've
as well corn I've started last year it's
a framework and api's for developer to a
JavaScript to basically copy and paste
into the website and start earning
profit from mining on users it's usually
considered a malicious act malicious
attack if the user didn't consent to
start it if you use a consent it's more
likely like
an advertisement a replacement for
advertisement if it's even and run
without consent it's considered a
malware an exploit or at least that's
the way I see it the trend is also
joined by mainstream fair trade actors
like main boat operators switching from
broads and trojan and banking Trojans to
coin - crypto miners we also see a
really clear shift from ransomware are
starting to use crypto miners as well
probably because the ransom is dropping
in profit bad reputations user don't
think they're gonna get their files back
anymore anyway user awareness increase
of better security tools they need to
find another way to make profit and it
seems like coin miner is their new
method to do it since we can cover all
topics in this short presentation I will
try to focus on the key most common
similarities of crypto miners finding
repeatable patterns is always good for
defense if we know how to detect them we
know how they look like we know how to
prevent them as well so looking at
similarities Manero is by far the most
common mined coin for malicious actors
dub this XMR it has very strong
anonymity features for example if you
look in at Bitcoin comparing to it
Bitcoin address resembles more of your
home address wherein Manero your address
is kind of more of the equivalent of a
pillbox a virtual peer box as also when
you look at bitcoins everybody can see
how much coins you have in your wallet
and what transaction you did before and
how much you transmit or you got way
more now it's much more hard to track
the whole algorithms of this coin is
much more sophisticated in its much
newer as well in addition this is really
one of the most critical facts why they
use Manero is that the mining algorithms
for Manero is still quite profitable for
CPU and as we all know boats are mostly
relying on CPUs on computers and servers
and if you look at bitcoins even GPU is
not much profitable anymore so this is a
key thing to understand if coin hive and
other web-based services are also using
Manero and XM are anything that can run
javascript is basically it can be a
target a victim of corn hive etcetera
many attackers are like the benign users
of coin hive will obfuscate the code
into many layers but once you start to
peel off those layers you start seeing
that Rob rotten apple mostly corn hive
similar services as well if you want to
get really into coin I've and similar in
browser attacks there is a really good
research by bad pockets I think it's the
best research to date covering all this
topic the usage of known services makes
Cohen hive and similar crypto jackin
quite easy to detect and prevent
actually there is if you're not familiar
with it coin block your list is a really
good list of known IPs and domains
related to crypto jackin attacks zero
dot is doing a really good job at
maintaining it almost daily if you can
see the tweet this is from today where
is diddle is last update really nice
German guy so if you ever meet him give
him a good kudos to me or buy him a beer
I was really helping the word against
ripped or miners so basically one of the
key features of critter crypto miners PC
based crypto miners is XM rig and
open-source tools that they are relying
on it's basically not that easy to write
your own efficient crypto mining coin
mining tool so the attackers are moving
to using XM rig because it's really easy
to embed XM rig is supporting many types
of operation systems like Windows Linux
and Mac it's really easy to embed XM rig
in your own code and it supports all the
major public pools the joint mining
pools so it makes it really really
effective for attackers to
use this to use this tool if you look on
the top left or right from your angle
I've put it a really simple the RS
signature this year is just a few lines
but it will detect most unappreciated
coin miners and X Emery and maybe some
other tools that are relying on public
polls in addition if you want to detect
X Emmerich type of crypto miners they
mostly use a common command line to
basically to connect them and mining
pools to decide how many threads they
want to run etc and this is making them
really prone for detection however in
both cases most sophisticated attackers
will do two things like malware more
advanced malware they will pack their
code so you won't be able to just scan
static signatures on it however that TR
signature is probably also really
effective if you run it against memory
and also they will tell instead of
running the exome rig as a standalone
dll for example or PE process they will
embed the XML code in their own code and
the parameters as well
so it won't be that easily detectable
there isn't for xme common command line
is that it needs to support major mining
pools the reason for both benign and
malicious actors users to use mining
pools is because to to mine alone it's
really hard it's based on luck and you
need a lot of hash power if anyone
anyone here did some mining alone if
have you been profitable yeah so mining
pools really give you the benefit of
easy calculate how much profit what you
can make and for attack is speaking
about really large BOTS that's really
good and stable income but the relying
on public pools makes them easy to
detect on the network as well most of
the major mining pools domains and IPS
are known and you can use lists
like a coin block your list or I've also
shared he in a link at template or a
sample to detect on with snort certain
network activity and domains related to
coin mining there's also a more advanced
paid ones but this one pretty much works
so feel free to use it for IT and
security teams coin miners are pretty
much a pain in the ass sorry my language
it's killing your CPU if you got servers
it's gonna slow them down you're gonna
see a lot of browsers stop operating
they're gonna call the security and
desktop team to check what it is but
this is also quite of their biggest
downfall because once for example the
power user on windows sees that his
machine or her machine start to really
slow down what is the first thing
they're gonna do the public on open task
manager and see what is causing the
slowdown the hiccups so our little
friends in the coal mining malicious
coal mining industry have developed ways
to go around it they will constantly
look for this kind of processes and
windows like task manager process
Explorer and once that will be open the
mining loop will go to halt and they
will wait till the task manager is
closed and then go back again so you'll
find out some users will start the
leader chrome or what is that causing my
computer and they won't even they're
gonna miss the the coin miner and I
think one of the things you can actually
try might be run task manager all the
time but you can also try and deploy
fake processes did anyone try to do that
before to trick malware no all right you
might you might shoot so getting into a
bit of some fun parts as researchers I
very often get depressed where I try to
hound on down Fred actors and I usually
end up with nothing but when we do find
someone and we're able to track a real
persona behind a camp and it's usually
really fun so when we first started
looking at coin miners we thought that
because of the privacy announcement
of cryptocurrencies it will be really
hard to find those attackers but we
found it completely opposite and we
think that's because crypto mining is
really new technology and like defenders
attackers are like are really prone to
do some errors along the way to run
mistake
so just a few name a few of the stuff we
found is for example newbie mining pools
you will you will need to use your email
as authentication for the miners to
authenticate your miner and some of the
attackers will use personal emails and
some even use more like disguise emails
but are much easier to track if you look
at any traditional malware if you ever
find an email that's a really good place
to start when you try dogs and attacker
and we got the email right away some of
them actually are even by mistake put in
the password for the accountant in there
so you can go and hunt if you want them
I didn't tell you that so we might find
some interesting stuff there's also some
really common more technical mistakes
but pretty much not here to help
attackers will help defenders so if
someone really wants to know more about
it please feel free to ask
I might ask some background check so to
make sure an attacker but will be happy
to share so here's a little story during
an investigation two crypto mining we
found my malicious miner we called water
miner water miner was mostly in Russia
it was Trojan izing a GTA mode and
basically once you start installing the
mode running it it will be running
alongside disguised to an Intel or
Oracle but the attacker left a really
nice few breadcrumbs in his source code
which helped us lead to a real Russian
entity the whole story was published on
bleeping computers the link is below so
if you're gonna go and do a bit of deep
deeper reading into it please go ahead
so when when I first read in this title
the first thing that came in my head is
the Jerry Maguire scene of that show me
the money show me the money so alright
keep swinging in my head anyway doctor
Thaksin crypto mining is fun but we
really wanted to go deeper and
understand why this phenomena is so big
so we really want to track down how much
money what is the profit or many
Cincinnati for the attackers and what we
thought is a can really completely
opposite than what we expected
although XMR addresses are really hard
to track mining pool statistics is
really public so once you extract the
wallet address and you can automate it
you can do it really easily on a massive
scale you can start communicate with the
api's of those pools to communicate how
much money was actually not money but
how much XML was actually paid what's
the hash rate and overall agents and so
it was really interesting to see for
example you probably noticed I love case
studies so this is this case study about
malware crypto mining campaign called
photo miner photo miner was originally
discovered by God eco and fire in 2016
the revelation of it didn't really
damage its overall Ronnie and as far as
I know this is the longest and largest
running crypto mining campaign when we
did the automation and run around all
the wallet addresses and around 500
samples we found out that the profit
that made is going between 8 to 12
million US dollars from 2016 the reason
of the big change is that the the XMR
coin value is quite changing so
sometimes they took the coin when it was
260 dollars sometimes 180 but we're
looking at some couple of really good
million dollars here so that really this
feeling for us clearly showed why the
big transition is going there is some
money to be made here I may be not as
big as for the early run somewhere when
people speaking about 80 million dollars
or hundred and twenty million dollars
etc but taking down on anonymity of XMR
and the probability of the of them
actually taking the money to somewhere
they can use this looks really really
big incentive now looking at the some of
the strengths we wanted to pick up from
those coin miners
I use another case study it's called
ghost
ghost miner we started to look on after
preventing an attack at a customer and
we start Luka we saw a completely
powershell script that the partial is
propagating in the network and was using
things like brute force and some exploit
to go along but the interesting bit for
us in this attack is that lost minor it
was vicious against its competitors it
had many many set of tools to kill other
miners apparently the competition is
high it skilled processors with black
players look for schedule tasks look for
network activity and kill those poses as
well so what we we did and the result of
it is in the link below as well is a
open source partial script that you can
use in your network to eradicate coin
miners and it's really really successful
we still haven't found a coin miner that
doesn't get it by that tool but please
use with caution you don't want your IT
guys to call and say hey you killed one
of my application or maybe their coin
miners that they were running in the
background so use with caution
so a bit what next some good alright so
I like to do predictions because first I
know I never can really go wrong with
them you know no one expect 100% it's so
like defense and also it's kind of like
a gambling thing so first thing I think
we'll start to see is coin mods we're
gonna start use proxies between them and
the mining pool so the network will
first be able to be obfuscated and
second they won't be need to use those
domains and get easily detected by the
network second thing we didn't see yet
but we quite expecting is to see the
version of bulletproof hosting we're
gonna see probably malicious bulletproof
pools they're gonna be hiding the data
they probably gonna have more anonymized
way to connect to them this is something
we probably expect to see the pub Leo's
gonna use things like DJs and things
more advanced members are using malware
is using we're probably gonna see also
reducing in the mah in the CPU usage of
the crypto miners it's probably gonna
decrease profit and the for long term
but indels in sorry for short term but
in the long term is probably gonna going
to increase their profit because they're
gonna get less and less detected
just to quit a quick recap we looked at
the simulator features on coin - for
example XMR and the open-source tools
they use the fact they used public pools
and things like corn hive we looked at
methods to detect and prevent them like
coin blocker list we looked at network
detection abilities and we also look how
to track them down and DOX them so if
you want to have some fun please go
ahead and we looked at how to monitor
the magnitude and how much effectives
are those crypto - if you find a crypto
minor you can easily go and check the
size and how much profit they actually
make and we also look at some coin
miners self-defense or anti-competition
tools that we can use in our advantage
so if you have any questions please go
ahead if you didn't have time to ask
I can ask me offline I'm pretty pretty
easy to find and my details will be on
the next slide yeah do you mind a bit
closer I can barely hear you sorry yeah
so DJ is for someone yeah I'm sorry ask
if we spoke about DGA as a way to bypass
Network detection DJ stands for domain
generation algorithm and basically it's
a way to not have a static domain so
basically all of network detection use
signatures on the name of the domain and
DJ is basically a way to go around it to
keep changing for example I think the
first usage was configured when it kept
changing the domains it was using does
this answer your question
cool any other question don't be shy
alright so thank you it was yeah
so let me repeat the question do you ask
how do we get best practices for coin
miners or yes
there is some some really good sources I
think what I'll do is I'll post on my
Twitter account a follow up with some of
the good sources coughing will be too
long to name them here cool so thanks
everybody am any questions anything I'll
be around here and I always say you know
like if you see me any pot let's drink
your beer and have some fun