[Music]
hello yep thank you for attending the 11
o'clock session my name is Puna and I'm
gonna be talking about starting a
security program that thrills and spills
we are all here on a Sunday because we
all want to do better at security
some of us aspire to build that
application security program manage that
product security program build the
security program for the company and
back in November 2015 I got that dream
opportunity the dream opportunity to
build the security program for a
healthcare company which had at that
point no users not a product market fit
and we didn't really have any customers
pains for anything but we wanted to
start off foundationally with a solid
security program while we are building
those skills for that aspirational
opportunity we are thinking of like
technology skills we are thinking policy
frameworks we are thinking trainings and
certifications we are preparing for
project management skills team
leadership skills hiring firing and
whatnot and in the past year or two what
I learned was that all those skills are
great they got me the opportunity that's
why I got into the door and once I got
those opportunity the ones I got into
that opportunity
it was super filling to say look I'm
gonna be building this foundational
security program but the the spills came
in when I was unable to do so in certain
areas where it was for non-technical
reasons the skills give us that the the
confidence to go do something but then
if we are we are stuck on how to get
that done and in this talk I'm
discussing the scenario of where I
realize that the emotional intelligence
piece or emotional quotient for somebody
who has this responsibility is at least
as important if not more than the skills
themselves because otherwise the skills
that we build are marginalized if we are
not able to run through the program with
an even keel of mine so by way of
introduction
I have been building skills all along I
have a master's in computer security
from UCSD I was a software engineer for
almost nine ten years if you used
Netflix on Apple TV stony any of those
devices I built that then I manage the
product security and the application
security team at Netflix I built
security products for Netflix was trying
to at the same time build my own
technology company I gave it a shot for
about three years and in November 2015
when the lira health opportunity showed
up that's when I changed pivoted to
working on that one own single focused
effort I became the first security
engineer /c so at lira health what do we
do at lira health we provide a
comprehensive behavioral healthcare
solution for employees and family
members of the companies that work with
us we have everything the entire gamut
from like self-care apps that use
computer-based cognitive behavioral
therapies so that people can help
themselves see CBT as it's known in the
psychology world through you know how
you deal with like physical therapy you
have like a limited session set of like
coaching sessions and then yourself
serve so we have that for behavioral
therapy we have therapists who work
on-site and near sites we have clinics
at the companies that we work with where
the employees can just walk up to those
clinics and we also have
psychotherapists on our board where we
can prescribe medicine so end to end
behavioral health care that's what layer
I have to present so this is this is
where a wise man named Drake would say
starting from the bottom now we're here
started from the bottom now my whole
functioning teams here so in from the
bottom now so 2018
I just willing to be here earlier for me
at Lera health because we have we
achieved in the first year of my joining
the company we achieved hydros
compliance and high trust I'll talk more
about that later but it's it was great
because enter company rallied to get
there we have a lot of customers who
for stringent requirements and some of
them are probably in the audience some
of them are potential customers in the
audience who are whose InfoSec team has
assessed us and has helped us become
stronger based on their feedback we the
entire company rallies together when we
have annual compliance support disaster
recovery exercises external Red Team
exercises we all work currently pulling
the company in the same direction and
the security techniques are used not
just to defend but to creatively solve
problems I'll get more examples of that
as well
and when they occur security incidents
are immediately reported broadly
discussed and we take we do post mortems
and then prevent future recurrence in a
without blame or shame fashion so it
feels great to be there in 2018 back in
2015 I was starting at the bottom I
wasn't sure how to go about it I knew so
based my skill for telling me I'm not
gonna start with a risk assessment and
then a threat modeling exercise or
should I do comply like you know start
with a compliance program first take
action with like sdlc it's off a
development lifecycle figure out shift
left and have set cops you know best
practices like we have Oh ask top ten
stands 20 you know FTC has the start
with security program all those skills
are coming to me left and right and then
I realize that I'm one person number one
security engineer how much of this can I
do by myself and when you think about
SDLC and like you know implementing fine
SEC bugs and failing the build when you
know when you're when your security
issues show up the engineers are not
really incentivized to do that because
there they are measured on like did you
get that feature out in this friend did
you get that experience working there
and they don't necessarily need to do my
five sec bugs the product security team
is like everything I asked them in so
like you know changing the password
strength or
anything would be basically a thing that
would create issues with their funnel
right like their registration funnels
and their user experience funnels will
get a drop and when they implement
security features the the data science
team the data science team is always
hungry for more data have my Network
segregation diagrams I have my data
classification I have the the whole you
know how we will we will manage all
these different types of data and the
data science team is all about the only
privilege and access they want is all
privilege all accessed so that they can
run all their machine learning
algorithms on as much data as they can
to get to those insights so the instance
incentives are not aligned the executive
members are still trying to get that
round of funding or are doing their
first customer pictures or they are
trying to get those customer success
programs going they don't really care
about my you know let's let's do that
incidence incident response tabletop
exercises whatever scenarios because
they're like do you know how drastic
this is this what if scenario is that my
company might not survive your what-if
scenario of the tabletop exercises let's
priority right how do we rally company
resources to work on penetration tests
and what what would encourage employees
to report issues because that's not what
they're used to if you report something
where you did something wrong you're
gonna get punished that's the only thing
they know so I had to do a lot of
introspection I had the exclusive
privilege and responsibility to build
this program and I knew what I wanted to
do because my skills taught me that I
was contemplating on how so the purpose
of why did I take this why am I doing
this was super important so most of us
take the role because either there's a
title or a pay raise or improves our
commute gives us different experiences
like trails that we have in place so I
had done product security and
application security for Netflix I had
the ability to learn all the domains and
so that would be exact
and in the mission of the company itself
and to me what it boiled down to was the
the mission of the company transform
behavioral healthcare via technology
with a human touch that was so appealing
to me that the rest of it didn't matter
and I think that's where being
purposeful I drew a lot of strength I
lost my fear of like how I'm going to
approach somebody to ask for help and it
became very powerful and I also looking
back even two years later I feel like if
I hadn't had that sense of purpose I
would get burned out very quickly if I
wasn't creatively and passionately able
to participate I would not be able to
get lehre health there we are so light I
needed my purpose the company needed a
call to action right like why why would
the company do a bunch of small things
so I needed like a big banner like this
is what we're gonna get done and this is
when we're gonna do it by and for that I
got the business team and executive team
excited about getting leader health high
trust certified in 2016 one year we're
gonna spend time on that high trust
which is an which is a prescriptive
program which basically allows you to be
your company to be nest ISO HIPPA COBIT
all these aggregate all these compliance
rules they aggregate that and then
prescribe what you need to do so the we
took or that it was great because the
company like the executors and business
team was like excited because the sales
would be very easy with high trust in
there there would be trust for from the
customers who would want give their
employee information to us so that we
can provide them the care and with that
the entire company was like okay fine
let's get this done in 2016 so I took
her all the SAS accounts we had all the
like in a Google later use github and
sales for whatever you have you know
minimum privilege minimum required acts
and least privileged principles started
doing like I didn't know anything about
management of max using champ but I took
a training and jamp I went about taking
everybody's machine and like hard disk
encryption Application Firewall turning
on screensaver password management and
then took over all the mobile devices
that would ever want access to lehre
health and like if you install this
Google MDM profile then you'll get
access set up you know password
requirements to factor and all that
stuff and it's great because high trust
gave us 19 domains on which we would
execute these things and it was like a
playbook we knew and we would get it by
and everybody was railing again this is
only 90 percent of the time like there's
less than 10% of the set of people or
technologies or things that will not go
your way right so there were some people
in the employee population would be like
going 100 percent to the cloud in no
health care company that I have worked
at that was possible it's not it's not
something we would recommend we want our
data under our noses and all that so you
have those arguments through like why
would I want to turn on this 8 character
passcode on my mobile device I'm not
that's too much I don't like you know
like you either have access to lehre
health data with all these security
controls which is like the passcode for
your phone no jailbroken devices and all
that or you don't and you choose right
so you have to have flexible policies
whether like you either opt in or opt
out but if you want access same thing
for the devices say we're gonna give you
these devices with the expectation that
we've made we will turn it around at the
end of one year we will give you a
different device so use this device as
if it's on lease and if you store
information that is fine
but it needs to be backed up to Google
Drive we have enumerated Google Drive
storage space if you are a coder
everything is backed up to github
because at the end of the year we'll
give you a month month notice and then
we'll swap it out it may not be a new
device but this what this does is it
gives us the disaster recovery and
business continuity
leverage because they there's nothing on
the devices or data that will be lost if
ever we if we are in a situation where
we need to get their devices back
similarly you can store as much of your
personal pictures on there but know that
if you lose the device I'm going to
remotely wipe your device and because
responsible for it because I don't I'm
not gonna stop you from storing your
personal pictures but in the case of
scenario where we have to wipe the
machine
lera half the data is important for me
your pictures will be second and so with
that freedom and responsibility bars
have been established and my screensaver
kid ninh so the having a purpose for
myself was great having a call to action
for the company was great and then as I
started implementing implement this call
to action the emotional journey that
that I went through was was very
fruitful for me personally because I
needed to understand all my emotional
triggers because there would be a lot of
pushback from people who would be like I
don't know that I want you know like I
don't want to swap out my machine at the
end of the day or like I don't feel
comfortable going hundred percent to the
cloud and like how do we how do I answer
those things without because I as the
first security engineer I just don't
represent that in the security
engineering I represent the security
culture for the company I needed to have
an you know emotional balance so we all
have these right not all of these
thinking traps apply to all of us but
most of these applied to most of us we
all have those shoots statements like I
went in with like everything should be
two factor if it has that option it has
to be two factor you know you cannot
have shared accounts and like well
Survey Monkey account cost 2500 bucks if
you don't have shared account you're
gonna have how many shared at how many
individual accounts per person in your
company so all those are context based
right it has to be taken with a grain of
like it's not all black or white
it is gray and the emotional maturity
that I needed so personally I'm always
on a performance improvement plan if I
miss this note here I'm gonna be like
why did I miss that and like I have my
wife is on a performance improvement
plan my daughter three year old daughter
is on a pip so everywhere every
co-workers on a pip the world is on a
pep in my opinion and so those are my
thinking traps right I have initially I
started with like you are either with me
or against me and that is not gonna go
great if you are also representing how
this company should operate in terms of
security so there was a lot of learning
in there but it was great because for
for whatever I think my three-year-old
is a three-year-old she will grow up and
mature and so did I in terms of like
understanding everybody has a
perspective and if you answer it
differently or based on what they're
they are a product of their life's
experience if you explain it differently
things work out in the end at the end of
the day I'm running with the baton to
implement high trust in 2016 so I did it
so the first two things I talked about
which is purpose and self-awareness who
are internal looking the next one I'm
going to talk about communication is
external looking and like communication
to others has to reinforce the security
culture of the company and so there's a
lot of there are a lot of previous talks
and articles about how great
communication skills how to build great
communication skills there's like you
have to be concise and clear in your ask
you sometimes you have to be assertive
but other times you can be flexible
based on the context always conflict
issues will you know resolve conflicts
and prioritize things all this is great
right this is no no argument against
that but what I found very useful was if
we wanted to have a shared
responsibility then we needed to
communicate as a company with shared
values so what I found useful two key
values that I found useful for later
health was framing every discussion in
terms of user privacy and business value
the so the example of like the product
team not wanting to implement email
validation so I had to frame it in user
privacy is saying if somebody
fat-fingers an email when their argument
was we don't want to implement email
validation because that requires a click
into somebody's email and then like they
have to go from the app to their email
click on that link come back into the
app and we lose you know there's a
drop-off in the funnel like that's fine
but in the case that they enter the
wrong email at best it bounces and at
worst it goes to a legitimate other
person with and and we might be sending
pH I being a mental health care company
and when you sell phi2 the wrong person
that is disclosure we have to do a
breach response and talk to that user
and talk to that customer whose
employees information was disclosed and
fess up to fess up to this incident and
that's a tall order would you want to do
that how much of that is like that user
privacy is gonna cost us so much in
terms of business so let's just
implement email validation so we did
implement email validation the example
of like picking high trust as the
call-to-action was again business driven
because business like we are able to
talk to our customers but they're giving
them the confidence that a third party
has worked with us to make sure that we
are Hydra certified and we qualify for
all these third-party assessments and
then some tactics in communication we
learned was that we if you send an email
out and they don't respond that's not
because they're ignoring or you are
their hate they hate you or if you file
a juror etiquette and nobody responds or
you send them a slack message and they
didn't respond it's like some micro
cultures only look at certain things
some employees only look at certain
communication channels so
just the idea is to communicate broadly
and make sure that you know you're
communicating on all channels the other
thing was we security is only known when
people hear about security only when
there is an incident and so the idea was
to communicate more when there were
events so for example and at Google Docs
phishing scam was happening I send out
saying you know why we are not impacted
by this because of this setting
configuration setting that prevents us
from doing certain things in other
places but in these scenarios it was
great for us because we didn't get
fetched we weren't impacted sometimes
when you really want that security
question asked plant them I plant them I
ask like friends and like I also do like
raffles on a slack channel where I say
if whoever gets this question in which
all hands is gonna get a Phills coffee
so there's like so many people competing
to ask security questions it's great and
what brought well I welled up when a
member of the clinical team asked me
without any any incentives she asked me
about like what meltdown was and what we
were doing to prevent it and I was like
we have achieved it when a clinical team
member is asking me security questions
think we got there and and when we when
I go back from conferences I take all
the goodies and I like so if you we are
not a security company but there are all
these security company stickers on on
our company laptops it's amazing
because I feel like they they are more
aware so the last attribute I wanted to
talk about was presence and we
demonstrate presence in a way that we
don't want to say the security team only
found out later we want to demonstrate
presence in a way that security team is
just a part of every function of the
company and the
this might be a little controversial
we're like remote working remotely
insecure security like especially if
you're a first security engineer it may
or may not work there's the concept like
you know it'll work for like Oh Comcast
it's doing my internet at the new
building I need to go via for four hours
or like I'm going to work from home one
day a week or but if you're the if
you're not there it's like out of sight
out of mind people want to approach you
and have those impromptu conversations
where they want to ask those questions
if we are not available they will either
do the wrong thing or they will do the
they will not do anything and if they do
the wrong thing that's bad for security
if they do the wrong thing that's bad
for the company otherwise it's bad for
us so I what I tended to do was sit by
the coffee station sit by the lunch
lunch table and like have people come in
and have those random questions answered
or just chat because you learn so much
about other products other things that
other compunctions in the company are
working that was my window into what
they were doing it was every day lots of
decisions are being made and I felt like
I was being a part of it by being
present physically the next aspect of it
is participating right like you know I
attend like again this might not be
scalable as you grow bigger like this
I'm again the thrill of what I'm doing
was that it's a small company 60 people
with all the teams included so I'm able
to participate in the product planning
meeting I'm able to participate in
engineering sprint meetings I'm able to
you know even when we on put any vendor
like I'm involved right from day one and
the when the company goals are being
formed for every month we have like top
five goals we get in a couple of
security goals for example when we have
the third party pen test we say our
monthly goal for this month is like
we're gonna you know go through the code
again make sure we have run fine sick
bugs all that stuff make sure we have no
credentials in there
like I go to the customer called a
customer call supporting team and like
let's go through your scripts and make
sure that there are no and then practice
those scripts that there are no social
engineering attacks possible and then we
do our third party pen test a red team
test where like every every function is
pretty much exposed to an attack
so that was one monthly go we had
another goal where this was driven by
the SLA for the company like we have a
99.9% SLA which means at most one minute
26 seconds of downtime or fourth you
know 43 minutes for the month so we were
able to do a security we went ahead and
did a disaster recovery exercise where
we said here are all the dependency
graphs lest let's test every function
that exists in our system let's go
through a slight flavor of chaos
engineering that Netflix does where we
take down a function and see what gets
impacted and what the downtime is and
the output of this exercise for that
month was we got all our disaster
recovery automated in that all the
alerts and monitoring is in place but at
the same time if we were to take our
entire infrastructure and relaunch it in
another region we have all those
dependencies all those intricate calls
being mapped out and works in a
completely different region because we
automated that so the whole interest in
fruss structure as code we implemented
that because we had a monthly goal on
like meeting the SLA so keyword business
value drives Security Initiative the for
quarterly goals right so we have we are
a mental health company so there's a lot
of stigma associated so when our
customer asks us like any implement SSO
with our enterprise
SSO vendor we were like that might work
in other scenarios but for mental health
company we would enable other things
like sign-in with Google or optional MFA
within our profile because the employees
potentially don't want to log in with
their company's work email into a
offering because they may feel like oh I
don't know if my employer will find out
about what I'm going through right so
clever ways of getting the the security
features implemented like single sign-on
via Google which many people have a
gmail account so they would be more open
to that personal gmail account versus
like a company account enabling optional
MFA so that we give the end-user the
confidence that hey their user privacy's
going to be taken care of by to an
amount - to a quantity that they feel
comfortable with it was great
similarly contribute write presence also
means contribute so you know code if we
don't code and contribute why would
anybody listen to our suggestions so we
I fixed the so like I am going back to
my started at the bottom I fixed two
classes of like fine side bugs issues
and went through and told the engineer
team here's how I did it
can you please take it over and they
were like happy because like they knew
what to do it was bounded and they were
like let me let us start it in this
print and they went ahead and
implemented fine site bugs and they
failed a bill at the end of you know in
in a sprint they got all the other
warnings and errors similarly I wanted
to do application layer encryption for
poor customer so that we reduce the risk
so imagine if like our company got
attacked and like all the data got taken
over we wanted to do this by like really
encrypting each customer's information
with a separate key and have that
application layer protection and I was
looking for an opportune moment and
turns out there was one important health
plan that we wanted to integrate with
and they said we want hosted like hosted
environment that is dedicated to us and
the we were scrambling to figure out
that's that's too much of an ass because
we are as a service we don't want to
necessarily create an entire environment
for this company and so we said can we
do
application layer encryption with
customer specific key for you guys so
you have the virtual value of
as if you had your own environment and
your data doesn't commingle with anybody
else's and they were like you know that
we'll just work with us and they got the
approval for us and then I got to do my
project and the engineering team was
super happy because they got a prototype
built so again like when I code it and
gave that the engineering team the data
science team asked us for code reviews
not because I have a process in place
where they have to go through my
approval but they feel like I add value
to their to their work so that's again a
win a thrill for me
and similarly the hack days participate
you don't have to just sit in a corner
doing are looking at our alerts and
monitoring we one of the hack days I
learned from the business team that we
used to pay our providers with like
checks at their every so often and we
will mail them for their for the
therapies that they had conducted so I
sat down with an engineer and and the
business team member and like we mapped
out the processes we integrated stripe
we built the initial prototype where
payments happen the same day and you
know what the providers although all the
providers that work with Lyra hell they
loved Lyra health ninety-five percent
like rate is higher than anything else
that's out there because they get paid
at the same day or the next day because
if you are doing work and you're getting
paid the same day or next day it's very
important for them and we happen to have
built that hack so the security team is
viewed as a security team is viewed as a
partner in all the functions and that
that's again in a group and it's
possible right now again because we are
small and I'm able to participate but
you get the drift own projects and so I
had to be like so that I'm apart I'm
partaking in everything thanks to the
folks at Yelp they built out a last
alert I integrated last alert into our
infrastructure and then we I own all
auditing logging and monitoring what
that gets me is that if for every
critical action that happens on the
product or any of our services
I have that who did what and when and
what classified data I did it touch
write and we have that at a level
because I own that infrastructure
and everybody uses that to to integrate
with their product so again another
place where my presence I don't mean
physical presence but like being able to
contribute makes everybody see security
of the partner and I'm present in their
workflows the clinical team was working
on like they really wanted to get this
software for longitudinal care so that
like when a care seeker calls us when
the chat with us and they have this one
view of all the interactions that had
happened they really like this vendor
and they want it onboard but that vendor
did not have any third party at the
stations or like did not have like they
have a security white paper and which
most vendors are and if we are in the
world of so the clinical team was poor
now please please please please don't
fail them we want them to we want them
to be approved I you know and I was like
I am your partner I want them to succeed
as well and luckily to us one of our
partner company or one of our customers
had demonstrated how they value us when
we didn't have any of those
certifications they paid for a pen test
they did a dynamic assessment of us and
they paid for they waited for us to fix
all those issues for three months back
in the day and helped us become a
company that can work with them and so I
learned from them and I did the pay it
forward with this company which is like
I went there I introduced them to the
people that they need to talk to for
like kicking off their third-party
assessments and all that I went ahead
and like said let me look at your data
diagrams let me see how you can make
your secretary controls better and
basically did what I would do at my it
at our own company I did it for them
just so that they can be a vendor with
us right and the clinical team is
eternally thankful so anything that
happens they see me as a partner and
talk to me about that so bringing it
home our skills our absolute able stakes
there's no denying that the the my
thesis is that security cannot be
enforced we can build as many pavéd as
we want we can build as many gear car
drills as we
want we can make it as easy to be secure
by default but at the end of the day
security is a shared responsibility and
for anybody to share share our
responsibility they we need to work on
shared values and we need to work on
belief in the same purpose constantly be
self-aware and communicate in terms of
like what we all believe will take the
company to the next level and so for me
it is an exhilarating experience having
gone through this like just exercising
my skills and at the same time
emotionally growing up to be able to run
this and thank you for allowing me to
share my story
[Applause]
[Music]