[Music]
hi everybody hi my name is etai and I
have the pleasure today to talk about a
very very interesting one of the most I
think interesting attacks cyber attacks
but that were ever conducted and this
was the case of ccleaner hack so
ccleaner was a like a supply chain
attack that we're going to explain
exactly what happened there I'm sure
that a lot of you already familiar with
it but I'm also going to present our own
research about this attack and also
about the malware that was involved in
this threat so just a few words about
myself before talking about the
interesting stuff
my name is etai I'm the CEO and
co-founder of a company called integer
which is actually focused on malware
analysis and thready detection and
before founding this company about two
years ago I was leading the incident
response team the cert of the Israeli
military so really most of my daily job
was to deal with nation sponsored
threats and actually I'm really glad to
speak about this attack the seeking hack
because you know I've seen many many
many attacks from very sophisticated
threat actors but this is hands-down one
of the most compelling stories I have
seen so this is me and what I'm going to
talk about well my talk is going to be
divided into three parts
today first I'm going to speak about
what is a supply chain attack to begin
with just to make sure that we are all
on the same page secondly I'm going to
dive into the specific case of ccleaner
that was back in September last year and
lastly I'm going to present our own
company's research about very
interesting code connections or links
between the ccleaner hack and apt 17
so first of all really what is a supply
chain attack right so instead of the
traditional way of attacking an
enterprise which is directly infecting a
company through phishing emails open
ports you name it in a supply chain
attack you use a third party supplier
and in fact this supplier like a
software vendor or other you know a
company that the target company is
working with you infect this supplier so
in the end the target company is also
infected as well now I'm sure a lot of
you know about that but I think there
are two interesting points about supply
chain attacks in general so one is that
they are extremely hard to detect right
because you have already this open
processes in a trust relationship
between the supplier and the target
company so that you know most companies
and I'm saying it very in the nice way
most companies don't really check the
stuff that is going through their
suppliers right so tearing down even the
most sophisticated defenses can be quite
easily conducted using utilizing our
supply chain attacks and second the
second point that is very interesting
about a supply chain attack is that the
X the damage the potential damage of a
supply chain attack is actually
exponential because for one supplier you
have many many companies that are
working with them right there are
suppliers with hundreds thousands or
even millions of customers so if you
infect the supplier you basically can
infect all of its thousands of or
millions of customers and I think I
personally believe that the combination
of these two points that it's very hard
to detect and also the potential damage
is huge that what makes supply chain
attacks are really really big threat to
us in the information security community
right now I'm sure that everything that
I just said is not news for you but I
think that we always should remember
this if is a threat that was not um
let's say does not have yet a solutions
that solve the whole problem and we
should work on it right now one thing I
want to mention is that you know it's
not easy to conduct these sort of
attacks but if you have the resources to
do it you get much more for your money
as an attacker anyway
let's dive into our specific case which
is the ccleaner hack right so what is
ccleaner to begin with CCleaner is a
very well-known software a free software
that many of us use in our computers to
let's say clean up the junk right like
adware unused registry keys and so on
and because it's so effective there are
millions of users of ccleaner world
worldwide and actually this software was
developed by a company called piriform
that was acquired by the security vendor
avast yeah so so they have developed its
command this software and back in
September last year there was a very
exciting news I think that two different
companies both Cisco and also Mophie SiC
have discovered that the latest update
of this legitimate software was actually
patched and backdoored with malicious
code so just to you know say it again to
be clear we're talking about a
legitimate software that was published
in legitimate places like well their
official website and so on that was
patched with malicious code so everyone
who installed this completely legit
software was infected by this backdoor
or by this malicious code so the effect
is
that indeed everyone who downloaded that
download this update was infected but
this malicious code that was initially
implanted in the legitimate software was
actually containing only a small part of
logic only like a small a part of a a
code in this code what is it what did it
do so this code was actually only a
reading several pieces of information
from the target computer such as the
host name the domain name and that's it
right just getting the the most clear
indication about where what is the
victim that I'm currently installed in
and then this malicious code has has
basically sent the information this
basic information to the command and
control server for a further steps and
this is where the interesting part comes
along and this really one of the reasons
that this attack is so interesting the
attacker was apparently very very picky
he was very picky in his targets so
although millions of users because we're
talking about a software with millions
of users worldwide were infected
actually the targets were very very
narrow so after receiving the
information about who are the victims
then the attacker had decided who to
deliver the second stage payload right
so not not all the millions of customers
have received this very special second
stage payload but only just a few so we
are talking about 40 about four year
organizations
commercial companies very big commercial
companies who were the actual target of
this attack and by the way they include
Microsoft VMware Cisco and and some more
now the very very gifted and talented
the Cisco Talos team have received an
image
of the CNC server and they have they
could actually query the database of
that the attacker safe so we actually
learned a lot about this threat in the
eyes of the attacker by using the image
from the CNC server so see how many
infected computers there are see how
many government and banks were infected
really a very big potential damage but
in the right hand side you can see the
actual companies who were the real
targets of this attack so really only a
few right so all of this a description
about the attack itself is really a
publicly known information right and
although I think that is extremely
fascinating as I mentioned before I
think that even more fascinating is what
we discovered when we actually took a
look into the malware and the malicious
code that was injected into the into
ccleaner so just a quick background my
company integer is focused on analyzing
code and actually understanding code
similarities and code reuse connections
to other known malware or software and
this research was not different we spent
time focusing on researching on this
specific aspect of this attack we took
the ccleaner and all of its modules all
of the you know code that we can put our
hands on and we try to figure out with
our technology the connections between
the ccleaner attack and other well-known
software or malware we have seen before
and really just a background about how
we do this because you know this is
besides and I want to share also the
technical aspects as well so what we
created is a very cool database that
contains billions of tiny pieces of
binary code
right so we took a lot of software and a
lot of malware dissected it into many
many small pieces of binary code and
then we fed our huge database that we
like to call the code genome database so
you have for each and every piece of
code in that database you can know
exactly which software it came from how
many times we have seen it before
so a very rich information about tiny
tiny fragments of code now I'm not
talking about like a you know a white
lists or black list database that you
have you know information about file
hashes right I'm sure you you know
what's that but I'm talking about a
reputation database or an intelligence
database about tiny pieces of software
tiny pieces of binary code and when we
have an unknown file that is given to us
for analysis we are essentially able to
you know dissect it also to these pieces
of code and comparing them in to our big
database of code so in the end what we
can do and this is what we've done also
with ccleaner we can understand we can
identify the origins of every piece of
code in that file for in any given file
now a lot of people ask me in many cases
ok code reuse is you know a very big
phenomenon it's obvious that people do
not love to rewrite their whole code
from scratch right I I'm sure you know
what I'm talking about
but code reuse in a lot of cases is
consisting of you know using libraries
stuff that that compiler adds and a lot
of stuff that are you know mostly common
so if we find code reuse between a
certain you know malware to another
thread actor doesn't it mean that maybe
they just used the same library so this
is where the method of how how you
should you know detect code similarities
comes in place because think about it if
you have a database and you have this
piece of code that was that you know
you've seen in many other places such as
many applications or even both malware
and also legitimate software you are
able to distinguish between what is a
common code that was seen everywhere
such as libraries or you know and code
that is specifically unique to that
certain connection you have found so
everything that I'm going to present you
about our research is based on this
point right code connections that we
find are actually completely unique to a
certain you know that's a family so as
soon as we received the payload from the
ccleaner attack really let's go back to
our case then we immediately use it to
just throw it to our code reason
similarity systems system and then we
saw something really special Natalie let
me explain what you're seeing in front
of you so you have the let's say the
code similarity result of the stage one
payload which was actually injected in
memory so they had like a DLL that was
injected in memory and we just used it
to throw it to our system and
immediately we saw something very
interesting fifteen percent of the code
of that threat was already seen in apt
17 now immediately when we took a look
on that picture we try to remember what
we know already about apt 17 so they
they are a very well-known thread actor
group with links to the Chinese
government or specifically the Chinese
Liberation Army and these are very very
sophisticated Google Adobe and juniper
back in 2009 and they are specializing
in conducting supply chain attacks so
many years before our community has
discussed openly about supply chain
attacks they have actually penetrated
code inside the gates the SV ends
the TF SS of huge companies really - in
the goal to backdoor legitimate
applications that so many of us are
using every day so really like you know
we are all from the defense side
probably but I know how to appreciate a
good work the these guys are doing a
very very sophisticated attacks that are
very hard to both analyze and also to
detect anyway so after you know seeing
just the initial picture of you know the
connection to a PC 17 we dived in even
further and we saw that actually there
are four different variants you can see
I mean I don't know if you can see but
there are like four rows of file hashes
which are each and every file hash is
actually a different variant of apt 17
that shares the same amount of code with
the ccleaner hack so yet again four
different variants of apt 17 share more
than 15% of the code and then we even
dived in even further and we wanted to
see the exact code segments that were
that were similar but you know what I
just forgot to mention just as I said
before these pieces of code the 15% of
the code that was similar is completely
unique and was seen only in ccleaner and
in apt 17 and not in any other software
or malware in the world and we know that
because of that huge database I
mentioned before so this is a very
significant connection but let's see
exactly what is the similar code here so
for those of you who don't know a
assembly or don't want to know assembly
or can't see then this is a very
interesting implementation a very unique
implementation
of base64 so basics t4 is like an
encoding algorithm right that is used
many times in malware and also in the
jet applications and here we see that
the whole implementation of basics t4 is
completely unique and was seen only in
these two threats see cleaner and
different variants of apt 17 so this
might be a very weird and unlikely
coincidence right it can be but then
although although you know as I
mentioned before very very unlikely
since it was seen only twice but then we
had a look also on the second stage
payload so here we see that the same
coincidence comes again and we see
another code connection that was seen
only in ccleaner an apt 17 in the stage
2 of the attack so just to remind we're
talking about the stage 2 where only
specific organizations have received
only the target companies have received
and this similar code what does it do
it's basically in resolving an API
function a Windows API function to you
know to to continue its operation of
that threat so for example you can take
a look on the first piece of code this
is how normally you know programmers
will be resolving an API function they
would call low library and then get proc
address to resolve the AP the the
address of this API function what we
have seen that was unique in these two
cases is that they actually splitted the
string the strings of kernel32 and the
actual API windows api function to
different characters now why did the
attacker do that probably because they
just wanted to obfuscate the string you
know to avoid a VD tection signature
action I'm sure that you've seen many
cases like it's similar to these before
but yet again this is the only you know
here it's like fee plus plus code right
but in the end this is just to to
explain a bit more easily what the
attacker wanted to do and why is it so
unique but almost bite by bite this is
the same implementation and the same
code so the combination of these two
evidences makes it not so much of a
coincidence after all and if we also add
added up to the fact that this is a
supply chain attack this is exactly what
a pt-17 is specializing in we have a
more clear view of an attribution or a
classification of that malicious code
and malware now nothing is sure with
attribution and you know classifying to
thread actors really unfortunately I was
needing to do this on a daily job to
make attribution to other threats and
it's very very hard but the you know
when you take a look on the Achilles
heel of the attack of attackers which is
they have to reuse code right to not
waste a lot of resources you get a very
clear understanding about you know who
is behind the threat so just to mention
this although nothing nothing is sure we
have as an info set community a better
understanding about who we were dealing
with in this attack specifically and I
think it's very important for us to know
to better understand you know the thread
and landscape and also respond better to
future incidents because we know you
know what we are actually dealing with
so
just to just more like I sum up what we
learned what I wanted to to share so
first of all and this is a very
important point for me to mention you
know today we see supply chain attacks
that are sophisticated such as this one
being conducted only by nation sponsored
attackers or you know if you have
nations nation resources but what if
tomorrow this would be supply to
conducting supply and chain attacks
would be a commodity such as many other
stuff we've seen in the past like you
know all the case of the shadow brokers
and so on that very sophisticated
abilities were just now a commodity for
any kind of script kiddie so we need to
prepare as an community to deal with
these types of threats because I'm sure
I'm sure that two years from now maybe
even less or a bit more somebody else
will be talking about how much a supply
chain attacks have became a commodity
now we don't have a clear solution for
that to be honest but this is something
that we should know and we should be
aware of we have our own solution of our
company not specifically focused on
supply chains but you know there are
many great ideas in the community that
we should you know share and make happen
secondly I wanted to show you that
thread actors are actually prong to
every to the problem or let's say to the
phenomenon that any kind of developer is
is facing which is doing code reuse
because you know and and I really have
the experience I have the pleasure to
have the experience of dealing with very
sophisticated threats and there you see
that Nations and and just sophisticated
attackers cannot really afford to
rewrite their whole code from scratch
the the they just can't it's it's
extremely not cost-effective maybe a
scripted kiddie can but if you are
developing a serious malware you
probably wasted or spent a lot of years
to develop and you just can't write it
from scratch so here we see a case where
several years later the same attacker
still used their same codebase right so
software is evolutionary and also
malware is and we see it all the time
and lastly I wanted to show you how
detecting code reuse can not only you
know help us understand whether a file
is good or bad right because seeing code
reuse but also it can help us better
understand what we're dealing with and
how we can respond to to future
incidents and another thing I want to
mention is that everything that I'm I
showed you regarding like the code
similarities technology and so on so
it's actually completely free to the
community so you can just try it out and
and we would be happy to see more people
more faces in our community that we
worked very hard to to create and last
thing well and I I really hope that the
information that I share today was was a
helpful for you because for us as a
company to see this attack conducted in
let's say in real life it was really an
eye-opener to think about how to respond
to future incidents thank you so much
you