[Music]
my name is Andrew hey just briefly about
me and I'm going to apologize to the guy
doing the camera cuz I I'm just gonna do
this the whole time and avoid it so I'm
the CEO at Lara's I've been in InfoSec
for close to 25 years various roles and
responsibilities lived and worked in
Bermuda I'm actually I grew up in Ottawa
I'm from Halifax originally but I grew
up here in Ottawa went to Lisgar just
across the canal played rugby here for a
number of unsuccessful years and moved
to the States
because that's where all the money is so
one of the things that I do in my spare
time is I coach rugby because I made the
one mistake of bringing my wife with me
to the doctor's office when I had to
have an x-ray of my back and to ask him
you know how long was it going to be
before I played rugby again and his
response was ho oh you're not playing
rugby ever again like oh probably I
brought my wife into the room for that
diagnosis so I've also written three
books four books that you've never read
but that's fine and I blog very
infrequently but what I wanted to talk
about in this session is I've been a C
so for a number of years I've been a
security executive at various different
companies different roles
responsibilities and I've noticed that
we as individuals we tend to switch our
view on how to instruct or teach someone
something so who here has young kids or
has ever had young kids I can't pick on
either YouTube you guys won't give me
the good answers who says they have kids
over here you sir how old are your kids
alright as the four year old been
involved in any sports at all organised
sports all right what about kicking a
soccer ball back
and forth alright so the first time you
did that I'm going to just make an
assumption that they either missed it
completely and fell on their back or got
hit in the face based on every YouTube
video I've ever seen
started crying now there's probably you
know that may or may not be correct but
for the sake of this conversation let's
say that that's exactly what happened is
one of those two things there's two ways
that you could have approached it one
like most caring parents which is why I
couldn't call on you is to nurture and
encourage the kid the old you know this
is how you do it you should do this
better this is you know this is gonna be
a lot safer you'll do it better next
time or like we treat student athletes
usually after they hit around 12 14
years old we come down on them and say
what are you doing I told you how to do
this right do it this way you're being
an idiot
and for some reason insecurity and an IT
and just management in general we tend
to lean more towards the latter when
we're trying to communicate a security
program or some sort of concept as
opposed to the former which might be a
little different but might be a little
bit more successful of a tactic so that
autocratic coaching and if you've ever
this oh this presentation always works
great in the US because I always ask
people so I live in Texas and I'm like
who here played high school football at
the entire room puts their hand up and
then I asked them like what would happen
if you went to your coach and he he he
would have questions for you like well
you know how did I do at coaching was
that a good session did you learn a lot
from that and they're all like no no
coach of ours would ever say that
because he would be too busy screaming
at us for not doing the right thing and
that's kind of the way adult or young
adult sports coaching and Technology
Construction happens you know this is
the way you do something you follow
these steps and you get to the
successful conclusion where you win and
that's not always the best method so
every player and I'm going to use the
term player and professional co-worker
pure interchangeably because it's really
a lot of the same concepts so if you
want a good team you want people to
perform and people are going to perform
if they feel that they are important to
that overall team so this athlete Center
or athletic or athlete centric coaching
style is something that's preached by
the International Olympic Committee and
then that flows down to all of the
different sporting organizations around
the world so I'm a certified was it USA
rugby level 300 world rugby level 2
coach so that means I can coach an
international rugby team if they wanted
me to based on the last World Cup they
might want me to I don't know
but so I am qualified to instruct in the
manner that follows the International
Olympic Committee's model for
encouraging people to compete and that
IOC coaching methodology seems to stop
at a lot of the American sports because
it still reverts back to the autocratic
screaming yelling do what I told you to
do follow the PlayBook everything will
be fine so there's there's a great coach
who used to coach the New Zealand All
Blacks his name is Sir Graham Henry and
use arguably one of the greatest coaches
especially following this athletes enter
coaching style so if you ever watch
rugby or soccer or any outside of North
America type of coaching instructional
venues the coach is never on the
sidelines
they're usually sitting up in a booth
because on game day they know that their
role was done on Tuesday or Thursday
they're there to let the team
successfully execute the plan you know
they may have microphones and talking to
trainers and assistant coaches on the
sidelines but they're not there in the
face yelling at the players to do what
they're told because they trust the
players that they have been instructed
and they've learned the skills develop
the skills over the course of this
period to actually execute on the game
plan to get to their expected end point
so back to sir Graham Henry so he once
said that better better people make BLET
better all blacks and that's the case in
a lot of security programs and security
organizations you know better leaders
make better security individuals and
better security individuals make better
security organisations so it becomes it
comes around full circle so better
trained people make better security
decisions make better team decisions to
execute on a security strategy for the
organization so if I want you to take
away anything from this session it's to
think differently so you can go back to
your office and does anyone here a CSO
or a security leader in their
organization or hope to be at some point
careful you wish for sometimes it's a
really crappy job but if you want to
become a leader within the organization
that you work for now or in the future
these are some tools to help you
communicate either the objectives of the
organization the objectives of your
skills or at least just be a better
person to help them be better people so
this is another tool for the tool belt
so there are two distinct coaching
styles there's the coach centered
and the player centered so you can use
these interchangeably because different
people require different ways of being
coached has anyone ever been told that
they're been told that someone was a
visual learner have you heard that
before I'm a visual learner or I you
know I can only learn if I'm sent to
courses that cost $4,000 a week and an
hour out of the office
well that one's probably a little iffy
but the visual learner thing that's a
real thing there's science behind that
just like learning styles there's
different coaching styles so the main
difference and I'm not going to spend a
ton of time on this is that the coach
centric it's drills you're gonna do this
this this this and if you execute these
plans correctly you will get to a
successful outcome and this is only
gonna work if you listen to what I am
telling you to do don't deviate don't be
creative just do what I'm telling you to
do does anyone remember the old US Army
slogan the army of 1 that kind of
backfired because what they really meant
was we're gonna train you to be an
effective soldier but you're also gonna
have to work in a team and we want you
to be able to make those decisions on
your own for the greater good of the
entire team so I remember in college so
I went Algonquin College for a hot
minute and I didn't do very well because
well I went when I was 18 and well
what's the drinking age in Hull around
the same also I've looked like this
since I was about 15 so the whole
drinking age thing was never really an
issue but all my friends would turn 18
and we would go over to Hall and drink
and and not go to class the next day but
one thing they taught you in class is
how to be an individual and how to do
all these things on your own
go learn all of the skills to develop a
program to get your homework done
whatever it is then you get it into the
workforce
and what's the first thing you get
thrown into it's not a single person job
you're thrown into a team and you have
to work with other people that were also
told Oren taught how to work as
individuals so that has since changed
since I was in school so there's a lot
more team exercises and group work to
get people to work together because
let's be honest most development is
spent searching Google for the right
answer and then taking that code and
putting it back in the system if that
was around I probably would have passed
my classes a lot easier I am very good
at foosball though so I will credit
Algonquin for getting me very good at
foosball
uh this autocratic coaching and the
coach centric is also very
technique-driven so a good example is a
spiral throwing a football you know
there are certain ways you know don't
throw the football fat end forward it's
not going to go very far throw it pointy
end forward spin it follow-through and
it will go further and it will go
straight that is a technique and you see
it it's funny in the in the states you
actually see a just in the back yards
you see these like nets with like the
holes in it so that kids can learn how
to properly throw a football and be the
quarterback and be the star high school
quarterback because that's in Texas that
at least that's every kid's dream or
every parent's dream for their kid is to
be the star quarterback and you see them
all over the place that's not something
you really see in Ottawa you know I I
grew up with a hockey net did my parents
think I was gonna be a hockey star I was
not a thin kid or a very athletic kid so
they probably didn't think that in fact
I probably would have been like the
happy gilmore get caught taking my skate
off to try and stab somebody with it
which is why I played rugby so you know
those are techniques that are just
repetitive over and over and over again
and has anyone ever tried to teach their
kids something that they're not really
interested in
and do they lose interest let me tell
you a story about my father my father
loved to go fishing his idea of going
fishing was getting up at like 4:00 in
the morning getting in a canoe and then
sitting there in silence for eight hours
fishing we would do this and I'd be 15
and what do you what does a 15 year old
kid want to do more than sit in silence
for eight hours at a time after getting
up at 4:00 in the morning the answer is
absolutely anything but that so I did
not go fishing with my father and he
would try and teach me how to do
fly-fishing and I just couldn't be
bothered because it was so stupid to me
he made it miserable for me so I didn't
want to keep doing it so that
technique-driven method didn't really
work for me one thing that you'll learn
about a lot of coach centered coaching
is that it's all about winning people
with young kids that are involved in
sports have they been involved in any
sports that are we don't give trophies
or everyone gets a trophy kind of thing
how do you feel about that sir not in
your head it's interesting that's a very
politically correct way to say it I
agree it is interesting I don't have
kids I have two dogs so my statements
may not matter but I you know there is a
time for winning there's a time to learn
when to lose and maybe that is later in
life so a lot of coaches and athletes
enter coaches are showing kids how to
play the game and how to enjoy the game
as opposed to just trying to win the
game the old method is yelling at a an
eight year old till they burst into
tears because they're too fat or they're
not running fast enough I was also not a
very fast runner which brings me to the
Navy so I was in the Navy like I said
I've looked like this since I was
fifteen so
when I was told to run and then run
faster those are two things the
immediately I was no longer interested
in being in the Navy so boot camp was
not for me three I'm from Nova Scotia so
I'm not really that good at French where
did I go to boot camp se Zhao where were
all my instructors from Quebec so I
would be screamed at in French to run
and run faster strike three I'm out of
there I don't want to do this anymore
not my thing not my jam so not the best
method to motivate me could be because
I'm an only child I don't know I'm
spoiled
this coach centric method is also very
do what I say
I'm gonna show you once and then you're
gonna perfect it I'm never gonna have to
show you again just look at the playbook
it shows you how to do it no questions
good do this and then it's again you
know this is the way to do it don't
deviate from it because I've you know I
have years of experience as a parent of
a four year old so I know exactly how to
coach this team
well that doesn't hold a lot of weight
but you know I've worked with people and
I so not only do I coach adults I've
also taken ownership or I've been
volunteered to coach the high school
team which means I not only have to
coach high school students but I have to
now coach parents all at the same time
so it's a lot of juggling and it's you
know they're expecting me to come in and
show their kids how to win how to enjoy
the game how to balance their
expectations how to balance the kids
expectation so I'm doing this huge
juggling act but they look to me as K
this guy has to know all the answers
because he's now the head coach for the
high school team surprise I don't so
they will learn that very quickly so
it's going to be a learning process for
all of us now the player centric the
International Olympic Committee has this
concept and if you've got young kids
you've probably seen this it's the whole
coaching through games because if you
tell someone hey we're gonna do a drill
they immediately think crap we're gonna
have to do a drill if you say we're
gonna play a game like oh crap
I love games games are fun let's play
games so you're doing these games to
reinforce the skills and the
understanding over time so you're making
it fun and enjoyable and you're making
it a little competitive so that they're
working with one another to get to an
end goal but also to beat another team
so I promise this starts to float into
InfoSec very shortly with examples
player centric athlete centric focused
on the needs of the individual learner
or a small group of learners so if you
think of we go back to the individual
that says I'm a visual learner if you
give them nothing but books or a policy
on how to how the organization deals
with phishing emails do you think
they're really gonna care probably not
if you gave them a scenario or they
could click around and actually see
things might that be better for them to
comprehend what's going on yes does that
scale well across a large organization
no but the trade-off is that you are
tailoring the program for individual
learners to reinforce that skill so that
they don't have to keep running back to
you every time they have a question on
it so it reinforces the learning for
that individual based on their ability
to absorb and recall knowledge and
you're helping really develop your
players so the IOC is all about not just
getting people to become athletes to win
at the Olympics
it's to help perpetuate the learning
cycle so you Michael Phelps is a great
example arguably the best swimmer in the
Olympics ever
I guarantee you his retirement plan will
is not I'm gonna retire and I'm gonna do
nothing but subway commercials this is
gonna be awesome this is the pinnacle of
my career know they're hoping that he is
going to coach others on the US swimming
team how to be like him whether that's
from a direct coaching perspective or an
advisor or helping get people and
excited about the sports and bring them
in maybe he's just an ambassador but
it's perpetuating that need to develop
that player and that individual to get
other people involved so you're
developing a leader through following
this systematic approach that can then
be used down the road for the
organization in this case the USA
Swimming Committee it's also a very
democratic way of teaching people and
sharing learning so one thing that we do
a lot of is asking questions so it's
very hands-off democratic what do you
think about this what might be a better
way to do that what are the consequences
of not executing XYZ so you're having
people answer questions and you might
think okay well there's always going to
be a handful of people that kind of
stand back and let other people answer I
can tell you some ways to actually
encourage other people to jump in if
they're just wallflowers and don't
really want to be involved and that's
where games come into play and it's very
informal we want people to learn the
basics but also be creative we want
creative individuals that are going to
learn how to secure the organization how
to perform in a sports environment or an
athletic environment by setting the goal
giving them the tools to get to that
goal we don't care what happens in the
middle provided it's legal they can draw
on their skills and head towards that
end goal because ultimately that's what
we care about is the end goal and
developing the players
so this coaching continuing continuum
four phases to it so what you do is you
and I'll use an example here in a moment
so you're setting up the scenario you're
going to instruct what's going to happen
and explain what the outcomes are what
the objectives are you're going to
demonstrate so that visual learners can
comprehend what's going on because you
know we work a lot of people where
English is not their first language they
may not immediately resonate with the
way that you're communicating some
people that give presentations English
isn't their first language so the way
they're communicating doesn't just
doesn't mesh with the learner then the
instructor or the coach is gonna stand
back let them do the game do the
activity and then help them along the
way as needed for the individual
learners to succeed and then you go to
the feedback phase so it's not just
getting feedback from them on the
objectives but also feedback about you
as a coach and I guarantee you if you
ask an employee before going through
this continuing has anyone ever asked
for like a 360 review at work yes you
miss was it a glowing review no was
their name on it the anonymized reviews
are generally I'd say more biting than
the ones where you know if you have one
employee and you ask for a 360 review
they're probably not going to come back
and say well you're the worst boss ever
because you're going to know immediately
that it's them so that that's probably
not a very good career move on their
part if so if you ask a group how am i
doing was that a good way to do this
unless you make it an open communication
before you even get to that and this
process will build up they will happily
tell you how crappy you are and what you
could do better and it will be presented
and received in a way and perceived by
you as a way
to make things better for the next group
of people so you'll see what I mean in a
minute here so when you are doing the
instruction phase make sure you always
plan what you're going to say so at
halftime I was notorious for walking out
onto the field and we're either and
we're losing let's say we're losing by
like ten points and I would walk out in
the field I'd be all flustered I'd be
like well that wasn't very good let's
let's do better next half
you know let's all those things that we
sucked at in the first half we shouldn't
do that we should do that better that's
not how we learned all right so go go do
better and there everyone's like what
the was that like that that's not
gonna help me learn like what did I do
wrong
I think apparently everything so it's
not a very good way to communicate what
needs to improve and what was you know
what could be tweaked or nudged so
always plan what you're gonna say before
you speak because or plan what you're
gonna say before you speak because you
if you exude confidence people are going
to receive that as oh this person knows
what they're talking about and I will
listen to this person make sure you
always gain the attention of the person
before the people before you start
especially in this age of mobile devices
you don't want to keep rheic splaining
yourself so get everyone's attention and
then keep it nice short bite-sized chunk
type messages just sound bytes think of
it as sound bytes everything they need
to do to perform the task and that's it
no more the more flowery language you
put on it the more difficult is going to
be to move on to the next phase because
you'll start going down the path you'll
say oh I've got a story about that and
blah blah and you'll never get on to the
they'll lose the the short things that
you told them at the beginning and then
make sure you always ask questions and
this is the this is opening the door to
getting them comfortable around you and
around their peers to actually ask some
questions that they may not understand
so here's an example all right so we're
gonna do a fishing scenario so I'm going
to go in I'm going to
get their attention I've got my notes on
what I'm going to focus on I'm gonna ask
questions make sure everyone understands
what we're gonna talk about for this
phishing scenario gain their attention
Carrie hey everyone could everyone hear
me that's a great way to open it up can
everyone hear me because usually that's
when people will look up from their
phones I got crap I can't hear them so
we're gonna get started on this phishing
email identification group exercise it's
gonna be really fun and we're all gonna
get involved here short message so I
want everyone to take a look at three
emails and discuss with your partner if
they look legitimate or more like
phishing emails so I'm gonna give you
two minutes per email to discuss with
your teammate and then whichever team
has the best analysis is declared the
winner so that's a short message okay
three emails work with your teammate to
find what's wrong and document it
present your findings at the end and
you're gonna be a winner if you do it
the best note I've not told them what
they're gonna win it's just that they're
gonna be a winner and everyone likes to
be told that they are a winner even if
there's nothing at the other end of that
rainbow no pot of gold
they just know well should I want to be
a winner I want to beat my other these
other teams in here I'm gonna work
harder I'm gonna work hard to win
because I want to be a winner like I
said I'm an only child and that's very
important to me I want to be a winner
all the time so number four just clarify
so we're doing three emails two minutes
each discuss the features with your
partner does that make sense for
everyone does anyone have any questions
that is a great way to finish trying to
get clarification does that make sense
because if it doesn't make sense I'm
going to put their hand up and ask and
if no one answers that okay does anyone
have any questions before we move on
you're giving them two opportunities to
put their hand up and ask you a question
so the reason we ask questions is to
check for knowledge to check for
comprehension and to check to make sure
they know how they're applying that null
knowledge to a game situation in this
case the fishing exercise the fishing
training exercise and the players or
professionals use that information to
analyze themselves okay well this is
what they're asking of me I'm pretty
sure I've got this understood
synthesizing it so that they can okay
well he said this I think he means this
yeah he definitely means this so I know
what I can do and then evaluate okay
well I know that if I get the top if I
if me and my teammate here get all the
best answers we're gonna win and winning
is important and we'll be winners I'm
still not sure what I'm gonna win but
I'm gonna be a winner and I like that so
far so now before you get started you
could easily just say alright we're
gonna do this now jump into it do your
thing but there's a chance that someone
may not understand so that's when you do
just a short demonstration so make sure
that you can position position yourself
so everyone can hear you you know front
of the room just focus on one or two
points in your demo if you need to
repeat it again if you see some blank
faces around the room and then again ask
questions or invite those questions and
check to make sure everyone understands
so this is like there all right you know
what we're gonna go on this road trip if
anyone has to pee do it now not turning
the car around
I mean it this time this is like the
last chance obviously you're not
demonstrating how to pee that's maybe
that's the worst analogy I could have
used but you get what I'm going for here
so I heard two gentlemen over here
talking about rugby earlier was it you
sir maybe you're talking about Sonny
Bill Williams all right so I presume
that you know rugby not just the guy's
name have you played before alright so
can you instruct me how to perform a
sidestep
No so yeah so essentially what you're
asking you can tell someone how to do a
sidestep just do a sidestep and they're
like okay so I just do this instead of
running forward well there's more to it
so a sidestep is really
hey you're running fast at someone Full
Tilt and then you have to change
directions so that you avoid the tackle
and it sounds kind of simple when you
say it like that but there's a lot
involved there's a lot of mechanics
involved especially if you've taken
kinesiology or kinematics and dynamics
you know that there's a lot of muscles
and ligaments and tendons involved in
something as simple as changing
direction while running so these are the
textbook answers so you target the
nearest defender you're running with the
ball change direction as close as
possible because if I change direction
far away they're gonna know where I'm
going and they're gonna go that way too
so change direction close to the ball
you're gonna plant your foot and then
spring off of that foot with maximum
effort to change directions and then
accelerate in the other direction if you
do it too close you're gonna run into
them if you do it too far back they're
gonna know where you're going so you
have to find that sweet spot of knowing
when to cut and bypass them so let's do
another thing here Kelman my man I would
like you to instruct me how to drink
from that water bottle but the caveat is
I am blind see there's a lot of things
involved in teaching someone a seemingly
simple skill like you saying you know
put your arm out alright my arms out
move it down more okay move it to the
right all right like so we went through
this the last time I gave this
presentation
got to the situation where the guys like
okay well put your you're standing right
in front of it okay so I know where I am
put your hand at a 45 degree downward
angle okay move slightly to the right
okay okay now go slightly to the left
like okay yeah I found it
okay now grasp it bend your elbow
towards your mouth use your other hand
to twist the cap in a counterclockwise
position and then when you are ready
open your mouth and lift the bottle
towards your lips not at a horrible
angle because you may pour the water all
over yourself but just gently bring it
towards your lips and then you should
have an easy way to drink water like
that's a lot of instruction for
something as simple as drink a bottle of
water and some people require that level
of instruction so that's the need of the
individual learner so just like a
sidestep is more than walk to the side
it's difficult and it takes a lot of
energy to teach someone something new
but I guarantee you now if you go back
to your office and you do this same
exercise of the show me how to drink
water
pretend I'm blind you'll probably be
able to instruct those people after they
failed miserably the first time some of
the cues to actually coach them to
instruct someone in the future or if you
don't like them you'll get them to pour
the water all over themselves either way
it'll be fun for everybody so actually
one thing about positioning so everyone
can see in here if you're standing on
outdoors in a sports field and you're
addressing a team where should you stand
relative to where the Sun is
right so I'm facing this on why so they
can see me because you don't want them
squinting and you want them to be able
to see your expressions ask any
questions you don't want them getting
bored and looking away because their
eyes hurt because of the Sun you know
they don't teach that in the in rugby
coaching until the level 300 so after
you've already coached people for five
years only then do they say hey you know
what don't stand with the Sun at your
back and now whenever I'm coaching am i
all right where the hell's the Sun okay
so it's over there so yeah can everyone
could everyone stand here yeah you can't
stand with the Sun behind me so it's
just one of those things so in this case
we're standing at the front of the room
so everyone can see the screen projector
whatever we're gonna focus on to one to
two key points so before we get started
we're going to take a look at a sample
email so I'm gonna bring it up on the
screen note the suspicious email address
when I hover over the sender's name so
that's one thing and then also note the
sender is asking me to send strangely
sensitive information that they've never
really asked for in the past so those
are two things you might want to note
then repeat it if you have to all right
sample email number two it's an expected
email address when we hover over it with
the mouse the email is also asking for
information that this person always asks
for so it's not that strange so this
could be a legitimate email so you
should note that as well and then you
ask them you know these are a couple of
examples there are going to be more
things that you are likely going to find
in your analysis does anyone have any
questions so that's that final asking
for input and because you've gone
through this a couple times and asked
questions by this point you will get far
more people if they don't understand or
have further questions they will ask I
don't know what it is there's there has
to be some science behind it
but if you give people enough
opportunities to actually ask a question
and show that it's
it's an inclusive environment and then
everyone's on the same team and trying
to learn if they don't understand
they're probably gonna put their hand up
like I said there's got to be some
science behind it I don't know what it
is but in my anecdotal experience run
into it all the time so then you're
doing the the observe observe and report
so you're gonna focus on the key factors
key factor of this case being okay well
they they should probably mouse over the
email address we should look for content
we should maybe look at headers any
other information that might be
suspicious in these emails and then walk
around the room don't just stand at the
front of the room because if someone is
not understanding you can just go and
help that individual just nudge them
towards the right answer or ask them you
know what were we doing when we were
messing over all we were seeing if the
email was was legitimate or not okay
well does this email look legitimate no
it doesn't like okay well there's one
thing if you have any other questions
let me know and then continue walking
around the room and then when everyone's
done you can get everyone to present
their findings and really you're you're
helping them determine further actions
in the future so if there was something
that was wrong in your training plan or
the way that you communicated how things
were should have shaken out at the end
this is when they come back to you and
say well yeah this didn't really work
when we did this why was that and you
have a chance to actually help nudge or
help correct it around yeah along the
end way so there's two types of ways to
ask for feedback there's the push in the
poll model for any of you that have
teenagers you ask hey which I learned at
school today what's the answer
nothing surely you couldn't have learned
nothing you had to learn something nope
nothing so that's you're really trying
to just pull information out of them
with these clarifying questions and
that's a legitimate way to do it
if you've ever given or received
feedback for performance evaluation what
do they tell you state one positive
state a negative but then you know you
want to sandwich that with another
positive so you don't sound like a jerk
so you have that nasty one in the middle
and then two good ones on the outside
well that's you you're you're kind of
pushing for feedback there okay you did
this really well you did this well but
you kind of screwed up over here you
need to do that better the next time
and what this example doesn't show you
is that anchoring business school thing
of oh yeah you did this really well too
you know high five let's keep on being
friends let's be work friends the pull
method is really okay well what worked
what went well so at the end of that
scenario you could ask them hey what did
you guys learn or what do you guys do
that would help you recognize things
like this in your job you know can you
can you now identify phishing emails and
what are some of the things that you can
look for and the way I would do this
this isn't this okay well what didn't
work you know what are some of the
things that you expected to happen that
didn't really happen oh well you know
I'm most over the email it you know
there's no pop up or anything so I
didn't really know if that was legit or
not okay that's fair so what would you
do next time
okay well I could forward the email and
that would show me the email address I
could look at the headers like blah blah
blah and everyone's kind of contributing
at that point and you've got everyone in
a group and you're helping people answer
each other in a more democratic way so
everyone's helping each other we're
getting stronger as a team as opposed to
just individual athletes or performers
and that doesn't stop at the coach
either because that's when you say okay
well what did I do well in communicating
this scenario was I clear did this you
know what could I have done something
better you know what didn't I do well
help me learn so that next time for the
next group I can communicate this better
because I want to make sure that the
next group doesn't have some of these
questions that you
ran into so what could I do better as a
coach as a security manager as the see
so to communicate why fishing is
important and the ways to spot fishing
so it may seem like a very arduous task
but it's another way to help people
understand things and we've already
talked about over and over again how you
know not everyone learns the same way so
my wife is an instructional designer who
left tech had her midlife crisis and
became a personal trainer and which
means that I can never have a midlife
crisis because we can't afford it now
that she's had one but she yo she's
learned she's taken her knowledge of
training adults and taking it to helping
people get more physically fit so she
knows some of the key things to hone in
on for people that work in IT and tech
in general because they have office jobs
so she knows how to you know pull some
of those strings to help them relate to
one another and it's it's just one
method of coaching so she knows you know
questions to ask that only appear in
that type of scenario would be able to
answer or even ask in the first place
and understand so one thing I strongly
believe in is that security just like
coaching is not about you it's about the
team you know Bill Belichick might be a
great coach but he alone cannot win a
Super Bowl he may believe that but you
know he builds a team around the
organization to win Super Bowls you
can't just have individuals and if you
use these player centered coaching
techniques in the workplace you will
grow understanding you will reach people
that you were unable to reach before
that may have just tuned out because
you're tailoring it for them so if
anything I'll help you get better as a
security leader within the organization
and with that the red lights on these
are a couple references strongly
recommend
and that's how to get a hold of meat
[Applause]
[Music]