[Music]
my name is Douglas Santos and I work at
the security strategies for 40 guar labs
which is a division of for aguar that
specializes in threat research in
response and as a security strategies I
have a couple of responsibilities one of
them as I said before is to keep an eye
on the threat landscape understand how
the treads are shifting and working with
the developers not only to understand
how can we mitigate that given threat
but also how can we make our engines
better sometimes it's just a matter of a
signature update so let's say we come
across a new mower sample and we
understand that just with a given
signature with the given features and
capabilities of the AV engine were able
to mitigate the threat but sometimes
that requires something else so for
instance who here remembers their wing
hire AC vulnerability right that was a
vulnerability in the wing har product
that once you supply it with AC which is
a common encryption and compression
algorithm when you feed a vulnerable
version of wing her corrupted structure
ace with a corrupted structure that will
basically trigger a vulnerability in
suing her allowing for a remote code
execution so on that particular case our
AV engine was unable to deal with that
so we had to rewrite our AC parsing
engine because if we feed we before the
the engine has been revamped and
restructured if we feed a specific AC
file corrupted that had that
vulnerability the engine will simply not
not parse it correctly and it wouldn't
see that there's actually an Arab leader
and exploit on that other
responsibilities include revamping our
cyber threat intelligence feeds for
Annette does provide a cyber threat
intelligence feed in the form of
automated feeds that can be incorporated
into cm cm tools or trade intelligence
platforms but right now we're only
pushing
what they call automated feeds which is
basically IP our IP addresses URLs
hashes there's not too much context so
right now I'm one of the guys that's
leading the data science project to make
sure that we're able to understand
campaigns threat actors and extract
TTP's out of those malware samples to
make sure that the threat intelligence
feed has more context and more
information so that our customers and
our partners are able to have more
visibility and context around those
threats other than just IP our IP
addresses URLs and hashes so I'm gonna
be talking a little bit about handsomer
involution ransomware has been around
for more from our time that we give
credit for and it just seemed timely to
to talk to you guys about this because
at the very peak of ransomware evolution
it is targeting government institutions
and municipalities like never before
all right so ok so I'll show you this
this trend have started earlier and it
didn't actually started as encrypting
any files it basically just scrambled
some of the filesystem structures in a
way that wouldn't make we wouldn't be
able to access your of all your files so
naive and unexperienced computer users
would be helpless against this this
first strain of viruses then we will
explain how in a few slides how old
techniques have changed from
spray-and-pray
some very focused and targeted attacks
that trend has started somewhere be 2 or
2 or 3 years ago when a cloud computing
company has been held ransom for 1
million dollars
I think it was in China the so our
ransomware got ahold got a breach into
their networks and it got he got into
all of their Linux servers so most of
the their customers infrastructure and
services were held from him some and
they were requesting 1 million dollars
in Bitcoin
then we're gonna be talking a little bit
about what are the distribution vectors
being leveraged by ransomware 30 years
ago which started out very different
than it is today now we have four or
five main delivery methods some of them
are way scarier than others some of them
doesn't even require any interaction
from the user for the payload to be
triggered which is very scary and then
I'm gonna shift to some of the recent
ransomware attacks namely the Robin Hood
malware which is which is targeting
government municipalities in the US and
in Canada and I think it's very timely
for us to discuss this that distrained
and how it has affected lots of cities
in the US and what they are doing to
fight us and then obviously some key
recommendations that we usually usually
give to our customers and others
provides some of them are very obvious
they've been talking about this for a
long time some of us some of some of the
other key recommendations may not be as
as known as as the other ones and what
to do if you don't follow their
recommendations right how can you
recover from him somewhere what you do
when everything else has failed
what should we why should we focus our
efforts on so before I start diving into
the into the actual evolution of
ransomware I'd like to talk a little bit
about how has malware and malware
detection technologies how it has
evolved well in in in the very beginning
there was only signature basic solutions
right so you have one malware you can
calculate the hash of that malware and
you put that hash into a database you
push that database to your customers and
you have protection against those
specific specific file but that doesn't
scale very much or not at all actually
and if you take that specific sample of
virus and change just one bit of
information one bit that might not even
actually change any functionality of
them our boom you have another hash so
obviously this is not
this is not optimally this doesn't scale
at all so the second generation comes in
and then we're talking about send boxes
right so you're actually getting this
the specific malware we are running it
into a controlled environment you are
looking at open files make connections
op drop files opening other processes
address space trying to hide it's cold
into the other other process address
space and that was that was good for for
some time and it's some recent research
says that almost 50% of all Canadian
companies have some form of sandbox
technology if not on-premises on the
cloud so that can help you less and the
time to detect a little bit not not by
much but it does help and then we have
the third generation which is based on
machine learning solutions so we're
quickly trying to understand everything
that makes malware actually looks like
Mauer so basically we're employing
static and dynamic analysis so we can
extract what we call features from those
mowers and on top of those features we
try to understand on how how many pieces
of malware that specific thing appear
and it obviously if it's a one specific
feature that we've just found in one
malware that were just analyzed happens
to be found on 80% of them our then we
know via mathematical mathematics that
it is 80 percent or so good in actually
detecting malware but even so that the
the efficacy and how good that specific
that specific solution is depend on
where you are employing this specific
feature or visibility so I'm if you're
if you're looking at static and dynamic
behaviors awesome that is really good
but what if the instrumentation that
you're using to get those static and
dynamic behaviors are being made at the
operational operation of system level 50
if the mouse is doing syscalls it's
interacting with with the operating
system that might be good we may may be
may call it but what if the
it's an it's a malware that is being
written in a new language right so the
difference is calls different memory
layouts different opcodes and what if
mauer is completely reading in assembly
language that's gonna just cross right
over it right so but going back to
ransomware evolution the first instance
of ransomware
that we had notice off was virus that
was unleashed in nineteen nineteen
eighty-nine that predates the Internet
as we know it right back then that was
the sexiest haircut that I may you can
have not this guy obviously most of us
girls were looking for Mel Gibson right
well that in 1989 an American
evolutionary biologist by the name of
Joseph L pop thought it was a good idea
he was actually at that time working
with AIDS research so what he did was he
wrote a little program that was
disguised as a questionnaire II for
assessing the risk of somebody having
AIDS but he actually was a Trojan right
so he was attending a World Health
Organization at that time and he mailed
it mailed it via regular mail to 20,000
people okay so those people when they
started the diskette the questionnaire
was was presented to them they were they
were responding the questionnaire and
then after nine-year eboot this this
screen would be presented to them and on
that screen it says that he sent the
people my personal needs to send 189
dollars to our p o-- box in panama so
that was the first delivery method in
the way that they got paid and then in
the year 2000 when everybody was i was
worried about the the year 2000 bug we
had a couple of what they call fake
avian performance enhancement tools
those were mostly likely distributed to
torrent sites or our websites or
drive-by downloads where you
would install something that would
theoretically enhance the performance of
your of your computer and when you ran
it it was like oh I found a bunch of
issues in your computer and if they
didn't actually find anything there was
nothing they would actually make
something break something in order for
you to to make sure that you you pay
them right so obviously this was
initially a small fee around 32 to $100
and obviously they didn't fix anything
right so in 20 2006 it was the birth of
ransomware as we know it so the the
first the first ransom works you
actually use public could keep
cryptography to carry out its encryption
so there was no actual way to via the
decryption process to recover the the
plain tests so but even though even
though it it was employing very very
potent cryptography most of these most
of these mowers were riddled with bugs
the GP code in Iraq chivos had hundreds
of issues on their code so if I remember
correctly actually vales actually didn't
overwrite the file it deleted so you
will be able to undelete it and there
was some other issues with GP code where
even if you if you were able to get the
private decryption key to decrypt files
there was there were errors in the
decryption routine where they were what
are able to actually and decrypt the
file so they were pretty pretty buggy
and it was most mainly by individuals
were like just realizing the power of
the these two and what could it be used
for
and then 27 2013
cryptolocker came along and it was a
quip it was a attacked that was mainly
delivered via email and exploded
from five of September to late May 2014
it typically propagated as an attachment
to a similes seemingly innocuous email
message which actually looks like it was
sent from a legitimate company most
likely this the individual behind this
threat will have had a network of spam
bots who were actually sending those
from my actual company so he could feel
more enticing and more real so that we
would be more prone to open that so it
contains a zip file and sometimes a PD
an executable file but with the
extension as a PDF so it was gonna be
like invoice dot PDF DX dad
exe dot PDF so it was it was look like a
PDF but it was actually wasn't a PDF
obviously so this was distributed by a
well-known botnet called GAMEOVER Zeus
and it was the first creep ransomware to
actually demand the ransom to be paid in
Bitcoin with Meiji made it explode at
that time some some reports say that
they netted close to 27 million dollars
it was the first very lucrative
ransomware operation to date and in 2014
FBI via operation Tovar was able to
crack down a couple of their of their
network and servers and were able to get
the encryption keys so some of the
victims from from that Mauer were
actually able to recover their their
data without ever having to pay anything
[Music]
and one very interesting thing it
started using as well domain generated
algorithms so unless you had a solution
in your environment that has the ability
to via some kind of machine learning or
even statistical analysis to identify
that a forgiving domain is generated B
via domain generation algorithm
algorithm
you wouldn't be able to stop that threat
right so that's that's one of the things
that it had evolved into and then things
really started to pick he being picked
up by cybercriminals in 2015
crypto wall came along right and we had
close to five variation versions
iterations of that Mauer and it was it
was so huge mainly because of the way
that it was being delivered right so the
factors behind crypto wall actually
breached into a hundreds to thousands of
legitimate companies domains like a
Disney if I'm not mistaken facebook at
ad networks all of those big companies
that a lot of people actually navigates
you without giving a second thought so
what what was actually happening there
was they were leveraging a vulnerability
in Java so the victim using a vulnerable
web browser would we would browse to
let's say Disney comm and then on Disney
comm was kind of hacked it was hacked
and they implanted something called an
exploit kit an exploit kit actually
works profiling the browser that is
there is requesting the page from so
let's say I'm looking for a specific
Windows version with a specific browser
version and a specific plug-in if that
happens then it will redirect the user
to another page where it would be in act
will be exploited and the payload would
get installed into their computers of
course it was not it was not only via
what we call water-holding attacks but
also the is phishing emails and drive-by
downloads as well so they have a very
intrusive and complex network to deliver
those those mowers into Residex victims
into specific domains where the other
exploit kids were were actually hosted
so
[Music]
crypto wall actually had a lot of its it
amped the game in in a sense that it
started soon to hide deep into the
system it was the first ransomware to
actually employ code injection
techniques so once he got a foothold
into the system it would open up
explorador exe and try to hide its code
inside the process so it was the first
iteration of a malware that actually had
no processes running so it's by
basically one traits of a file s attack
so it executed the code as soon as was
able to execute it would open up an
other processes another projects party
x-ers vc host dot exe and he would try
to inject the code into a different
process so if you're looking at
processes you wouldn't find anything it
would be just a regular exploratory X
irani so that's nothing right well in
2016 there was the explosion of
ransomware as a service and that gave
around somewhere a very good advantage
and it was really something that if I
believe correctly it jumped from from I
think it was 300% I'm not sure about the
numbers but it was a gigantic jump in
handsomer samples but that just because
the the ransomware creators understand
that they would be they would be able to
cast a wider net and stay our way from
most of the of the of the investigation
that that is made so once somebody's is
one sample and when I tried to hunter is
actually looking at what how was that
malware delivered it's actually looking
at the infrastructure so where is this
maori communicating - where is his being
downloaded from so that part of the
infrastructure is not it's far away from
there ransomware creators right so they
just supply on the dark web or the deep
web they have this
this pages way they send they basically
sell what it's called malware builders
so you can specify specie parameters
like oh I wanna I wanna I wanna I want
these markets you have ran some of one
bit scoring I wanted to communicate with
this endpoint I wanted to use this kind
of cryptography so just pointing click
view on Mauer and then with that malware
in your hands were able to then deliver
it to a whole bunch of people so you
basically lower the bar so that anyone
could enter into this market to make a
quick buck right there's no need to know
programming at all there's no need to
understand cryptography you don't need
to do research on antivirus engines to
see if your virus is actually gonna be
gonna be effective or not we just you
just supply your affiliates with this
malware builder let them do the dirty
the dirty work and you and at the end of
the day you split your profits right so
in 2017 the that's when the s he death
so we had one a cry and pet here right
in I think it was a Friday and and 2017
that the when wanna cry started hitting
computers worldwide it was you me I was
using an exploit that was previously
disclosed by the NSA and had been
patched by Microsoft's two months before
and it's basically leveraging an SMB
vulnerability to get its way into the
networks and from there it had
self-replicating payload so it is it is
said most people think that the initial
infection vector was an SMB server that
was open to the Internet so most but
that's not being actually actually
confirmed so ransom worms were just
basically a response to people getting
wise well not so wise why we still have
a lot of
a lot of breaches that happen because
people aren't I even go and clicking
through everything but it was a response
to people getting wise ago about the
spread of traditional ransomware that
uses a spam social engineering and
phishing so with ransom worms you don't
actually need to click or do anything if
you have a vulnerable application if
you're running vulnerable web browser
like we've seen this it was like and
this is one of the most scary things
that we can see a zero-day vulnerability
on a popular browser being exploited on
the wild Google security researchers I
think one month ago or 145 days ago they
come across seven different iOS exploits
they were targeting Korean users so just
by visiting our website that's it you're
you're you are a victim already because
if you're running a specific vulnerable
version of that software all it need is
just communication and be the ability to
serve serve you pages so since you are
browsing to that page that's that's all
it takes right so it has the ability to
spread itself by using vulnerabilities
and not only from their abilities such
as eternal blue but also the credential
stealing so we had some instances where
networks were completely infected in
less than three minutes obviously those
were network that he didn't have in his
any segmentation or zero choice
architecture or anything but they were
actually doing credential stealing as
well there's a to call mimic ads written
by Benjamin Delphi that actually allows
you to steal credentials that are in
memory from from Windows and if you if
you don't actually profile your
environment and are you actually don't
have very deep visibility into your
network traffic and the interaction
between processes and the kernel very
advanced attacks will get through and
we'll be able to bridge our networks and
wreak havoc
so even even if you have zero trust and
okay I'm actually inspecting SSL traffic
I'm actually looking for IPS
vulnerabilities I have ng malware
between segments but if somebody is
credential doing credential stealing
that's something you will not see if
you're not deeply instrumenting the
operating system in 2018 gain crab came
along and over the course of six months
they released it five gain crab versions
to date was the first ransomware that
demanded ransom to be paid in the -
crypto currency and it actually utilizes
dns resolution via the beat top-level
domain that actually meant that no dns
server solution secure solution would be
able to stop it because the DNS requests
were being made via the blockchain so it
completely evaded that part of the of
the defense and it was the first malware
that we've seen that give us any
indicators that they were ruining they
were running something very professional
and well and well maintained they the
first version experienced a few setbacks
as the company BitDefender releases the
Decrypter for the earlier venation
versions so they were only able to
release the Decrypter because one one of
their gang crap servers got compromised
and BitDefender was able to get the the
public the private keys and was able to
send that as an update and as executable
for for decryption of specific victims
that had been affected by game crap
version 1 and 1.1 but gang crap 2.0 was
released on the same week that's that's
never been seen anywhere so we almost
looked like they were the release dodo
the the malware and they were looking at
vendors response and acting accordingly
very
fast okay so again crab has been
distributed via mucho spreading vectors
ming-lee spam emails but also exploit
kids and other affiliated malware
campaigns so one of the very interesting
things it was not the first one to do
this but gain crab generated one AES
keeper file so it did generate the
public key for encryption and the
private key for decryption but also for
every file it generated a new and new
AES key and it would encrypt the file
encrypt AES key for that file appended
to the end of the file and it would kill
the destroy the key from memory so there
was no there was no way to recover it
was even harder than just public key
encryption right almost forgot that was
very interesting that the when you when
you are actually doing our research in
your creating our we're obviously
testing that model against different
antivirus engines right by but when
you're doing this were actually
understanded deep and internals of the
the antivirus and they got so mad
because we are most most security
companies are really fast at the primer
seems that they released a
proof-of-concept source code to two to
three graph runner ability in one of the
one of the security vendors and an lab
had I think it was version for Afghan
crab actually had a vulnerability for a
given and exploits to exploit a
vulnerability on n lab so if you ran a
gain crab version four on a computer
that had an anti-virus from n n lab it
would break and lab because of that
vulnerability analysts would still run
so I was the first instance or that we
really saw very edge I when mature
development practices being incorporated
in some our next the Robin Hood and
targeted now cyber criminals are
focusing on organizations that came that
can pay
and have the drive to do so so that's
mainly two things municipalities and
government institutions right so what
they do is they don't actually work the
same way as ransom arms where they
breach a network and go scanning
everybody and exploiting everybody
making a huge mess in a lot of a lot of
noise they actually breached the network
and try to blend in with the traffic
trying to identify potential systems and
understand if you if the network that
was breached is a network from let's say
wasteman maze management or traffic
lights management for a given city
something that would make that intrusion
very very lucrative for them so right
now these attacks have started in FM one
is taken in May close to 200
municipalities have been targeted so far
and that's just a few of them Washington
gar few country Jackson County Airport
Augusta about city of Baltimore so all
of them or were breached there's a
couple of them in in Canada as well and
I think it was this week I think it was
this week there was a company in Spain
that was breached as well and we were
able to understand that the attack was
very targeted because once they
encrypted the files the extension was
the name of the company let speak so
let's speak so I feel things that
actually gives us the chills marred and
there anything else if we this I think
it was from the Ponemon Institute sorry
I forgot to supporting the other source
half of 600 survey several perfections
do not believe that their provenance
prepare a proprietary power ransomware
attack that means they have no zero
trust they are not instrumenting the
their operating systems they don't have
any type of data analytics or cm
solutions so they are just there driving
a car on a snowy road with their folly
windows right that's basically what's
happening
and this is even more scary almost 80%
of companies infected we ransomware
we're running up to date and point
protection so that that that says
something right that's not enough and
you we're actually seeing I have I have
access to our credit telemetry systems
within Friday night and we can actually
see that the numbers have going down
dramatically like ninety percent of the
of the volume of the hand somewhere is
gone but now the attacks are more
devastating and they're more focused so
the shifter hamster they be increasing
ly making the crypto more decryption
more difficult as I explained in gang
crap they're not only making use of
public key cryptography but asymmetric
cryptography as well per file so it's
absolutely impossible to recover this
file and this is true for all threats
that they were seeing they do not cease
to innovate and shift in order to avoid
detection and carry its intent without
raising any alarms so this makes this
makes detection very difficult
especially with the way that antivirus
companies are doing right now obviously
as I explained it before the use of new
languages make it more difficult to
catch because if you're even if you're
using machine learning if you're doing
lists and a static and dynamic analysis
if you're feeling ransomware that was
written in C Python in Java and then
there's a ransomware written in go
that's it you want boy won't be able to
catch it even if you're running machine
learning solutions on top of that well
we really think that the next focus will
be high profile individuals operating
technologies in mobile just because
there's a lot of our lifes are in our
mobile right now I have my token or my
finances are here so and I do believe
that if they make it ransomware with
just ten or ten or fifteen dollars
everybody would pay because nobody would
would will risk it yeah increasingly
compacts mixing behavior to 3kv engines
as I said knew that new languages are
one of
one of the ways that they can get
through it
distribution vectors we've talked about
this mainly in attachments in emails but
not only attachments links as well
social engineering since 30 years ago
still happening right that happens a lot
especially when you're receiving an
email from a company that you do
business with that's that seems to be
most of the cases now before deploying
ransomware these guys behind it they try
to understand the companies understand
which are the partners and try to breach
some of the partners to send you an
email from that partner to make it more
enticing for you to open up that email
drive-by downloads exploit kids and I
hope obviously there was one mower that
actually was able to utilize one
function of I think he was Microsoft
Office why just by hovering the mouse on
top of a link was able to trigger
something triggered a payload download
so there's there's a ton of tricks right
and obviously in it which mainly bugs
right if you have a bug there's that's
it there's nothing else you can do other
than patch so how does it actually work
considering that we're exploiting a
vulnerability on a browser so let's say
we receive an email with a link to your
to our bank in this case the Citibank
but it should be Citibank but you are
not actually paying attention because
it's urgent right and then you fire up
your Firefox it's gonna go to that
socially engineered site the social
engineer sites I would have an exploit
kit on it or just a single vulnerability
it will profile your Firefox or your
running windows and we have a vulnerable
version of Java then you would exploit
that vulnerability would call PowerShell
execute only in memory so there's no
traces or no artifacts whatsoever which
is mainly what today's 70 or 80 percent
of antivirus companies are doing they're
looking for things on disk still they're
not actually doing any
that that's about to change because
Microsoft has released advanced malware
scan interface that actually makes you
able to plug into the memory address
space of MSHDA powershell and other and
other and other avenues of attacks for
this for these mowers and then boom you
are part of a botnet right so as I said
recent born solar attacks are ready
really really targeted make sure that
they deploy Mauer to a network that they
know it is it is gonna pay or if not
gonna pay they're gonna have huge
impacts everything needs to believe that
the initial vector is not via RDP some
some researchers said it would but most
of them do not agree on that on that
that part in wheels inside the network
it behaves like a ransom word but not as
hectic right it's trying to jump for
systems to systems looking for systems
that are have actual value and have
actual date data that the given
municipality or government institution
needs to carry on this it's business
it's different to completely shut down a
company it's another whole other issue
to completely shut down City and they
know it
so municipalities in school are being
targeted in Maryland Georgia New York
Tennessee and Florida ten thousand
computers affected in the mouth
Baltimore and the ransom that they are
demanding is basically one Bitcoin per
computer or 13 bitcoins for our whole
environment but of course they did not
negotiate with terrorists right so
they're I think they took them three
months to completely to completely get
there for structure on on its tracks
where it was and they took eighteen
millions in damages whereas if they were
to pay the ransom it would be like a
hundred thousand dollars or something
like that but they know I'm gonna I'm
gonna do it from scratch but they are
correct there's no there is no there's
you won't be you there's there's no
guarantee that you're gonna have the
public key or that the decryption would
work so it might as well throw $100,000
on the garbage make sure that you have
security in place before right so eight
million won or lost in revenue ten
million recovery costs and recovery will
take months if you're not if you don't
do backup if you don't have zero trust
or anything in your environment and you
actually didn't know where it started or
where it has ended so one very good
thing that you guys could do to make
sure that you are on from the front and
then you are at least clear some of the
fog on your car is focusing on my dirty
TPS a lot of people talk about
indications of chrome compromise well or
indication of compromise means that
something is very rarely really really
bad in your environment and you should
act accordingly but if you are focusing
on indicator indicators indicators of
action you may actually be able to stop
that tracked on its tracks but in order
to do that you must be able to be
instrumenting the operating system so if
you guys don't have the actual budget to
go and buy a deep behavior analytic
solution or by deception technology
which is amazing because it changes the
economics of the attack so instead of
there they attack and it needs to be
wrong right one time it needs to be
right all the time for the attack to
succeed right so making sure that you
are you're you're looking at TTP's and
you are doing a proactive returns in
your unknown environment it's one of the
ways to go so recommendations
segmentation of course especially for
ransom worms if you're have the HR
department separated from the IT
department separated from the financial
department making sure that we have
inspection or all of those environments
you will be able to at least understand
that there is something wrong moving
from one domain to another backup data
of course and patching
of course recommendation security
mindset it's it is there's a couple of a
lot of companies actually that actually
do fishing on demand so be sure to
accommodate that into your security
mindset and set up setting up for
controller drills there are tractors
trying through beach showing defenses
right now why don't you do the same
right try to breach try to see what's
going on how your how your processes
stand up i or technology is able to
detect that because if you don't most
likely if you're not breached already
you will you know in a short period of
time and focus on TTP's right making
sure that you're looking not only for
indicators of compromise which are very
useful but actual indicators of actions
every every move that an attacker must
make and and mightier attack framework
actually has a bunch of them already
laid out i'll have to do is get those
informations into your trial
intelligence platforms making sure that
you have instrumented your operating
system so you can match all of those
well recovery from an attack
imagine that have not nothing in your
company is working so all-hands-on-deck
making sure that you are able to
recreate all the processes recreate all
the systems mostly the data won't be
there but you have to to make sure that
everybody is on the same room it's
trying to basically build the the
business from scratch right so it's
important to have a list of contacts
like lawyers vendors and system
integrators to make sure that you
understand what what is the message that
you're going to you're going to come
across and what information can be used
to try to recover some of the some of
your infrastructure
[Music]