[Music]
my talk today is kind of on the hardware
side of supply chains so when we talk
about supply chain tax and and all these
things but what we're really talking
about is specific different attack
vectors that are kind of focused the
hardware layer so I'm going to talk
about oh I did I use a clicker alright
so we're going to talk about the
different types of hardware attacks and
then techniques assessing the different
you know costs associated with each one
as well as access that it does provide
and how we can defend against them if at
all so it to recap in some previous some
attacks that have happened in the past
so my slides differ a little bit from
this but we have the big hack that
happened recently
so everyone heard about it all right so
I was attacked by ideally you know
Chinese spies reaching across many many
companies and the idea was that they
were back toward at manufacturing time
alright so everyone's heard about this
one and theoretically it was easy to
detect and then earlier yesterday we had
a discussion about shadow shadow hammer
and shadow pad different types of
attacks the Asus one was interesting as
it was actually mul weird but it
actually used the MAC addresses on on
laptops to target different types of
attacks and so this is just the example
in short of what happened during this
attack and so it's still a mystery
actually why attackers reduce the impact
of their payload to only about 600
victims even though it infected infected
money and then the shadow Pat attack was
interesting as it was actually targeting
the update procedure behind different
types of behind different sign binaries
I'm and on the right hand side here we
have infestation a popular video game by
Point Blank I mean it cane contains
similar malware injection
it was designed by South Korean company
Gepetto company whose digital signature
was abused in this situation the
signature was actually revoked however
as a pedo still use the certificate
through the end of February of this year
so now my slides are saying to this all
right so when we're unpacking different
types of hardware attacks we're looking
at the full stack right and it turns out
we're pretty good at defending against
these parts of our systems right we know
how to encrypt data we know how to sign
binaries we know how to put things in
virtual systems or sand boxes we know
how to audit code we can look at
hypervisors and and even the firmware
behind it we know how did that that
system works but we really don't have a
good solution for is the hardware layer
okay so the different types of hardware
attacks that I'm going to be talking
about our external standalone implants
external peripheral implants internal
peripheral implants as well as internal
implants at the chip layer and then of
course we have the firmware backdoors as
well so on this picture here we see the
external standalone implants so that
would be like a packet sniffer device
listening on your Ethernet or Wi-Fi
cables a camera or a microphone spying
on your keystrokes or on your video and
on the right-hand side we have a USB
maybe keystroke logger physically
plugged into your computer it's a
completely separate piece of hardware
and I'm sure everyone's played around
with these things pretty low cost
however it's it's very targeted right
we have PCB implants so so this would be
things like like pictured here where
inside the chip or inside the board
itself you have a specific piece of
hardware so this is a picture of what
purportedly was the super micro tech
where a small
a package or a piece was actually put on
the board at a specific part on the
board to leak data or or to gain access
to that system
all right so and then also not pictured
in these slides is the soccer IC
implants so actually a picture here but
most modern processors have many many
cores inside of a single chip so in fact
the integrated circuit or the IC chip
has on cell phones especially has
everything the device needs so it has a
USB audio/video ethernet memory cards
and they're all handled on one chip not
pictured here and obviously the cost of
performing this type of intentional
backdoor is much higher and more
feasible technique is what was pictured
previously with the super micro case
where you actually just put something
different on the board an example of the
integrated circuit backdoor is actually
the AMD backdoor which came out I
believe last year but it was idea was
that at the IC layer you had back cheat
codes in the game in the silicon
basically yep so the slides that you
guys have don't have these slides and
then that Victoria as well is firmware
implants so and that would just be like
bug doors which we'll be talking about
later today at about 3 for the hawawa
discussion all right so now let's look
at discuss techniques but we're going to
start with the super micro case so that
first example of of this PCB implant
okay all right so the big hack right
what was it so it was an additional
microchip on the motherboard not much
bigger than a grain of rice and it was
it deviated completely from the original
design so it would be something
if you knew what that board should look
like it should be different it was great
gray or off-white in color and the idea
was it an intercepted the CPUs temporary
memory and was able to read that off and
send that over the network through the
chip and they could do this because they
were connected to the base board
management controller which is one part
of that board that you would want to
connect to if you wanted to get data off
of it the idea was it as a signal
conditioning coupler which is just a
component so that was a specific
component they were saying it was and it
altered the memory operating system as
well so a most for the most part all of
Hardware implants actually a sister
facilitate a variant or a miss function
in the firmware I'm so they're always
your they're usually as a software
component to it as well and the idea was
that it was embedded between PCB layers
it was thin enough where you wouldn't
really notice it if you weren't looking
all right so what's possible here at a
network level we can use signal
conditioning couplers to do memory
processing or network functions so
ideally you'd have found suspicious
network activity if this case were true
downloading firmware that's altered is
also possibility in this situation so
Supermicro firmware could have been
updated and the malware was on the
network card drive or something like
that which would assist or be that
second stage associated with the
hardware implant built on the server's
Ethernet connector to get network access
you know it appear as if it had normal
functionality as well as secondary
functionality so that's what the big
hack kind of shed light on but what are
different other different types of these
backdoors so to display this we have to
take a step back and look at a new wafer
level chip scaling package that came out
in the past five years right so the WL
CSP provides a soldering and connect
directly between a device and the
motherboard of the end product so
as you can see here this is what it
would look like might not look like much
however it provides the TSV or through
silicon via which allows you to have 3ds
3d packaging so it would contain two or
more chips stacked vertically so they
occupy less space and this would be an
example of what one would look like on
the right for mobile so you'd have
different components all connected in 3d
space the resulting the result of which
would mean you'd have higher bandwidth
and lower energy consumption so
optimizations and saves money so it
sounds great right but from a security
standpoint an issue with this is that
you clearly can't see everything that's
going on so some of these vias might
actually differ and the differencing the
differences in where vias are placed
might actually affect certain initial
security components of the chip or might
actually connect a completely different
chip that's hidden in the sandwich and
so for example something could be hidden
right here that you wouldn't see at the
surface layer all right so the ad has a
different type of technique right so you
have the sandwich you have the ad the ad
would be what the super micro case was
alleged to be it'd be addition to the
board however the issue with this is of
course that can be a legit legitimate ad
all right you can move one component
from one pattern and the other to save
costs you would replace a component with
a differ different ones that has similar
functionality that also replace costs
there's different package sizes
available for certain things and
depending on logistics of that
manufacturing plant only certain ones
might be in stock however this would
differ from the original spec however
it's become almost probably improvement
across different manufacturing firms
that these replacements do happen all
right and so you can also have inside of
a package so you'd have different flash
memory packages as you see on in the
picture here there was actually
different 3d bonding patterns on this
chip now the reason for this was the
actually use it for many different types
of boards so they'll swap out different
subcomponents that have multiple
functionality and then just not solder
different vias into into the board and
they do that so they can reduce costs
increase the time from you know start to
finish that sort of thing all right so
this isn't a picture of Trammell
Hudson's example of what he would do for
a hardware implant he swapped a
component on the device this is just one
example of a different of what one thing
you could swap and this would mean that
the board would function as usual except
it would have a different functionality
they were able to flip ones two zeros in
flash memory using this swap and it
could alter enough data such that when
you connected to it or when the firmware
read on it you could actually get
command execution all right so PCB or
Die level attacks this is hasn't really
been discussed much except in academia
however it is possible and that would
just be an addition to the actual
silicon of of the PCB so it would be
very hard to detect these things are
really small so you'd actually have to
use microscope micro Sophia on a decap
chip and again this can be done inside
of a legitimate processor at foundry
time so one of the one thing I joke
about is you know every hardware talk
you can know it's a hardware talk by the
fact that all the pictures and the
slides are not actually screenshots but
these are pictures of the different
stages of manufacturing time and so you
know allegedly the manufacturing plants
claim that at each stage there are
checks such that if there were these
backdoors put in place they would know
about it
right because of all these different
tests that happen and for the most part
that is true so it'd be very difficult
for an unsuspecting manufacturing plants
actually have someone put a malicious
backdoor and at any of these stages
once their designs have been approved of
okay so what's the most likely attack so
in general counterfeit or e-waste parts
are often used to shave costs off the
manufacturing time this is probably the
most likely scenario of lowest-cost
it's the largest risk to firm so maybe
it's not even a security or a back door
that's put in but it alters a design of
the board's such that it reduces the
security of the design and so to prove
intentionality is it is a different
problem entirely okay so like for
example in Bunny's example of
engineering on FPGAs the most likely a
type of attack we would be these e-waste
parts and you know why does money talk
here a distributor makes about three to
five percent off of a chip so if they
can inject three to five percents of
fake chips in there also they would
actually double their profits just
because in engineering you know costs
are so high that profits pretty low so
these are actually from the super micro
boards here different components that
actually didn't match the ones in the
specification however they're different
models of the same thing so the idea
that we assumed was it was just a cost
reduction now to defend against this is
pretty difficult to you'd have to have
representative in that factory verifying
that each board has the approved of of
components on the board so it's it's
pretty unlikely that you'd you'd
actually do that all right so another
well example of the cost here is is just
bunnies numbers that he used in his talk
earlier this year where he was saying
that it would have really cost in the
low attend k4 a wire bound implants to
happen and the mid 100k for that double
ul CSP that 3d chip packaging implant so
it's it's much cheaper to actually just
change out a component all right so this
is just kind of laying out the different
types of hardware techs and what we
considered to be easy attacks to perform
and easy to detect
so obviously the add component one you'd
be able to know for sure if that was
different
however the substituting the component
one is actually quite hard so with
trammels example where as an active
component you'd actually have to do
additional analysis determine if for
example a passive component on the board
was actually active if it different
enough from the original the
specification of the board to cause
problems in your design that sort of
thing no I in my opinion at least
editing the IP list at manufacturer
before manufacturing time actually
starts so editing the silicon designed
the RTL files which are actually these
kind of dll's that are loaded in it at
manufacturing to help design the silicon
parts of the chip if you could edit
those then you'd actually have you know
pretty low cost but pretty hard to
perform modification to all these chips
so the example of that would be arm so
everyone knows that arm makes their
money because they license their RTL
files right the license about people
take those files they put them in a CAD
program or something and they print
those that silicon into the chip and on
the hip arm but in that situation if the
design actually has a specific problem
in that file or certain commands that
really shouldn't be there then that
would affect everyone and be very hard
to deduct it would be very prolific and
that was the example at the AMG cheat
code hack that came out earlier this
year
all right so how do we defend against
this though right so we have all these
different types of hardware implants we
want to look at the board and say this
is perfectly good or not now you know
one thing that people are playing with
is before fab time the actual RTL or the
silicon design of the chip can actually
be formally verified so companies like
Galois or are creating tooling to allow
you to say this circuit design is a
hundred percent secure this circuit does
exactly this nothing more nothing less
and that's one way to lock down the
silicon of the chip however if you have
your boy already what would you go about
doing so going through all my
transitions here okay so you'd have to
assess your security hygiene so no
matter what even if your boards are
backdoored if you know you don't have
good corporate security in general then
it doesn't really matter there's no need
for the hardware backdoor anyway they're
probably already on your system but then
also you'd have to assess your supply
chain risk so one thing that super micro
you know didn't have going for it was
there they actually outsourced their
manufacturing to a third party in Taiwan
I think and they actually outsource
different parts of manufacturing to
other sub companies as well and so at
that point it's becoming a larger and
larger problem and harder and harder to
lock down and so at every point in that
process something could happen - oh just
the design in a way that's undetectable
and so also you know obviously it's
focus on different areas of your
manufacturing so you have to look at the
code the build system programming
hardware there's a lot of different
components of a good chip and so when
one quote from the UK support on Huawei
was you know they said we couldn't
really determine intentionality for all
the for any of these bugs in in the chip
or in the software but these findings
were just about base
engineering competence in cybersecurity
hygiene and so in this situation you
know there could be bugged or is it
could be just really bad but the fact
that a lot of these problems with with
the design at all layers that weren't
addressed was really the critical part
here
all right so supply chain if you try and
break it down into the different
components of assessment this is kind of
the line that I like using you have a
software and hardware components that
eventually merge so after the boards are
made it shipped somewhere else and the
code is actually flashed onto the chip
so the first stage of course you know
security alright the first stage you
want to look at specification of the
actual hardware and software of the of
the board so you develop this
specification usually that's done
in-house for supermicro that was done in
California and that can be easily
checked so you know you have one
specification one RTL file for the
silicon formally verify or go through
and just code review this can be easily
checked for backdoors or other failings
in-house now this is the easiest time to
insert a low-level Hardware backdoor if
you do control this process right so if
you controlled everything the
manufacturing you could say okay we'll
just insert a back door here it's cheap
it's easy everyone's happy however in
stage two you start to reduce the
specification and design to practice so
you'd start to have you'd start to go
through and look and say well we've had
these this bits of code in here forever
ms was the case with Super Micro they
actually use libraries with the 90s and
some of their firmware development and
so you'd have to say well we haven't
looked at this in a while let's go
through it and so I three four and five
just labeled here manufacturing on the
other hand happens through a third party
so it's not as hard to to detect so that
would be the product line programming
provisioning
all done out of house in the hardware
integration as well so at all these
stages here it's it's kind of out of
your hands for the most part and so by
the time you get to the district
distribution channels you know in the
warehouse are in transits the customer
the company the customer has less
ability to claim the device matches the
specification so around stages you know
two four or five you start to lose
control of what that actual that
specification looks like and you lose
the ability to actually check easily if
it does match and then finally obviously
it's installed in the system and defense
really depends entirely on the customer
so once it's installed in the Amazon
servers something super micro can
actually easily help them out at all now
attacks are possible at 6 & 7 so you
know distribution obviously you don't
know who's shipping your stuff where
what's being done to it in that process
um however we're not really gonna talk
about that much today okay so super
micro claimed a lot of the R&D happened
in-house which it did they were using
code from the 90s but it was still done
in-house they sold the ability to go
through and check the design of the
hardware of the silicon everything
however they contracted out to a large a
large supply chain and they had a lot of
customers so able comm technologies
which is a Taiwanese company that I
mentioned is actually run by the Super
Micro CEOs brother which I thought was
funny and they actually only offer a
warehousing and coordination so they're
not they're the ones who manufacture the
device but in fact they don't do any of
the manufacturing and they take up 15%
of the cost of sales so they have a
pretty big stake in the company's
success in the success of the chip and
they basically do warehousing accuracy
and forecasts so they determine you know
where different parts are and where the
best place to manufacture certain
components are at that given time all
right so
stepping through this again super micro
designs that abled my able micro
coordinates contract manufacturers
produce and actually do the shipments
and they shipped to the San Jose in
other loans or Taiwan for final assembly
so final assembly of all the parts and
the flashing of the firmware actually
happens in only three locations and then
they obviously go through distributor to
customer all right so late last year we
were given task of looking at some of
these boards and so we sat down we had
some boards in front of us and I'm like
okay well it's gray or off-white in
color
we're looking for maybe a signal
conditioning coupler you know who really
knows and we're looking for things that
are unlikely to be to be detected
without specialized equipment so
something that probably has that hidden
behavior however this is a very poor
description and so actually just basing
it off this was impossible so we started
to simply look at everything and that
was answer for most of these problems
all right so first thing you can do when
you're just looking at the board is
follow traces on the board trying to
reverse out the netlist that's actually
physically in front of you and compare
that against the netlist from the super
micro design design spec a netlist for
those who don't know is just basically a
map of components on the board and how
they connect to each other and so
obviously this takes a lot of time it's
visually time-consuming and it requires
expert knowledge of how these things
connect no electrical testing is useful
for the cases where components are
actually active versus passive so that
would just be components that maybe look
the same but they actually do processing
of the difference bits that are going
through them instead of just passively
passing them on alright so how are we
going to look for the ad here well you
can try x-rays so if you have a IC you
can look through it with an x-ray
because the just looking at it from the
top level actually doesn't tell you much
so if this is pretty destructive as well
this is just a picture of the different
parts of the chip so as you see here the
top part that looks pretty normal it
matches the picture we saw a few slides
ago however if you look at it from the
side there's different layers to this
integrated circuit and each layer has
the potential to be slightly different
or to have slightly different
functionality based on how it's
connected and so that actually means you
have to start delayering this integrated
circuit additionally you can use x-rays
to detect passive versus active like I
was talking about earlier so here on the
right we see the x-ray of of a board
this isn't a Super Micro board but same
idea
usually these boards are much more
complicated than this this is pretty
simple so you'd have maybe thousands of
different components in this x-ray that
you're actually looking for for active
opponents so we have the resistor which
is just passive capacitor on the upper
right hand side and then we actually
have that chip which is active or the
inductor inside of the this di P package
which is pretty interesting however this
also is pretty destructive to the board
and it requires removal of the
components so the real problem with this
is that you can't do this on all of the
boards that you get in the shipment
right so you're getting a bunch of
boards maybe you can test one this way
but there's no reason to claim that if
you prove one's good and correct that it
actually means that all of them are
alright so specifically for the
Supermicro assessment we ended up
looking at a lot of x-ray images you
have to do about 500 per PCB just to get
the actual full image of what's going on
inside and get all the port details and
stuff so a lot of images look through
and unfortunately there's no real
automated tooling for this so
one idea that you know I think it's kind
of in research stages now is to actually
use open CV or something like that to
process all of these images of the board
itself maybe pull off that netlist or of
these x-rays to to pull off the
different interconnects between the
layers and maybe match that against a
known good PCB x-ray all right so each
person that was operating these x-rays
had five to ten years of experience in
electronics and had to analyze the image
twice for it this is just kind of
showing that you know it is pretty
difficult to do this this sort of
analysis following different wires and
connects and things like that and you
end up with you know a huge tub of SMD
parts from the motherboard all right
so going back to our earlier example
because the super micro vector was
allegedly on the bus not the SPI
you can't refresh
watch the SP but with spi bus by
clipping on set spi chip or replace the
spi chip because it probably won't
actually help in this situation
I'm so this is pictures from Trammell
Hudson's talk at CCC which shows the
different types of of diff of ways that
people would try to detect his implant
but it wouldn't actually work just given
the location of it all right so that's
all of the hardware stuff right but who
cares about codes
who cares about code in these sort of
supply chain techs and so in this
specific example there was a firmware
update that actually also distributed
malware as well all right so this is
what kind one thing I mentioned earlier
but one thing to reiterate is all
Hardware implants don't operate alone
you know they probably can however if
you actually want a successful useful
two
that's implanted it into the pants of
the board you'll actually have to have a
software component here and so what do
you do with that right so how do you
check that this the software isn't
actually abusing or using I miss a
misprint or a incorrectness in that
board and so you know that you can check
your code at compile time look at the
build system reverse engineer the
firmware that we actually you pull from
from the board which is what we did with
Super Micro however as the UK's report
on who always says it's not possible to
be confident that source code actually
matches what's on on any specific board
at a specific time so it might actually
match what's on the board immediately
but after an update or two it could be
completely different
all right so obviously different
different steps that you could do this
source code which would be those bug
doors which is what the UK was trying to
do to look at hallway you could look at
compiled firmware which is what we were
doing for Super Micro and and even
though you might not have the original
firmware you can look at boards across
different time periods to see if if the
firmware deviates at all significantly
at specific parts of the process so
normally they're not going to change
parts of firmware that interact directly
with a component that's been there
forever
so if you see a change a change in that
that's a red flag so and also at the
chip layer different citizens in lower
high bits actually matter a lot for
firmware are different parts so looking
at that as well yep all right so other
things to look at that I'm not going to
go into depth with and when what we
would have done if we continued on the
Super Micro stuff is look at once it's
turned on is there our art is there any
RF components to
it's operation or any Network anomalies
that can be detected or how it or does
do the network or RF outputs differ at
all from previous supermicro boards
alright so you know possible solutions
there you go
computer vision machine learning I know
I do think that there's there's a more
there's more room to be done on
automating the reverse engineering
process of these IC components as well
as the actual board itself so one thing
I really do want to see is better
tooling around lifting netlist soft
boards looking at inner integrated
circuit connects we need the ability to
which back to automatic automatically
trace or compare lifted netlist or
x-rays between each other and obviously
these are destructive and you know you
can't apply security you can't apply
security results from one boards the
other but it would actually help a lot
in this in this domain as most of it's
very very manual right now alright so
that's my talk are there any questions
[Applause]
[Music]