hey guys
my name is evan aka nph and i'll be your
instructor for today uh with
the recon 101 village called path to
college
so
this uh
in this 101 session
we'll be covering the basics of
pawning machines
how to find your first machine the
initial steps necessary steps that
you need to take and
that are essential to
getting the keys to the kingdom uh
escalation's root
all those things
so um
let's let's start
okay so basically here's the
current table of contents that i have uh
over
over the course
of the training um i'll cover multiple
aspects of
of
penetration testing
um
and
share a little bit of of common
vulnerabilities methodologies and
different technologies that you can use
to
successfully
gain access and
gain root to your your first box so
over here we have a pen chest
penetration testing
penetration testing and vulnerability
assessment
different vulnerabilities methodologies
and technologies
different tools
again
these are
only some and not not going to be all of
it and the
usual penetration testing approach so
the penetration testing approach is very
important because it's your
it's going to be your life cycle on on
your engagements and on how you're going
to
pawn your first boxes
all right
so over here we have penetration testing
so what is penetration testing
all right so penetration testing or pen
testing is uh
is the practice of testing a system
network or a web application to find
security vulnerabilities that an
attacker could exploit
so
it's basically
assessment a security assessment of of a
system network or web application
so that
you can
try to
discover it first before malicious
hackers do
right so the goal of penetration testing
is to identify weak spots in an
organization's security posture
so
apart from that it's also used as a
a way to measure the compliance of an
organization's security policy
test the staff's awareness of security
issues and
determine how
the company would react to these certain
security disasters
so a penetration test can also highlight
weaknesses in company security policies
for example
different
security policies that that focus on
preventing and detecting attacks
may not be
uh
may not be effective
if
uh if the
the system or the network is uh
is already compromised so
it also
also helps different organizations to
identify what they're lacking in and
put it in their security roadmap to
to say that
they are at the
the average level of security maturity
that they can ensure their customers
that uh no one
uh
they're they're not going to be
compromised that easily
all right
so in brief um
we'll have
a short
explanation about penetration testing
versus vulnerability assessment because
most people tend to
mix up these two
so a vulnerability assessment involves
vulnerability identification use of
automated tools
um this may not be backed with actual
exploitation
it may include false positives
so
it's basically
kind of uh an assessment on what
possible vulnerabilities there are that
are lying in the enterprise system or
network or application whatsoever
so
there's
there's going to be a lot of false
positives
most likely because
it only checks the rules based on based
on the script
meanwhile
penetration testing has the same
elements but the difference is there are
dedicated tools or exploits and there is
an attempt for
exploitation there are
there are also similar proof of concepts
that
are generated to
make sure that
um
this serve as evidence
that the system has been compromised or
is uh
is is vulnerable to to
the vulnerability identified
it's it's proved that
the hackers leverage the vulnerability
into gaining access to the machine
all right so next we'll go to
vulnerabilities methodologies and and
the different technologies
so the first and foremost the definition
of a vulnerability
so there are a lot of
vulnerability definitions scattered
across the internet
here are
some of them um as per
the computer emergency response team uh
it's regarded as a software defect
as as per the bug bounty platform hacker
one it's a software bug
as for microsoft it's a weakness in in
the cia of of the application or the
system which
which means
the cia is
confidentiality
integrity and availability
it's also
the same definition
it's also weakness according to the nist
but it's a weakness in logic
and as per isaka
it's a weakness in design and an
implementation of an application
so
there are a lot of vulnerabilities there
are a lot of types of vulnerabilities
that you'll encounter
sooner or later
but the most common ones are
going to be presented here so
you'll probably hear you've probably
heard a lot of these
already since you came to the talk so
first one would be
remote code execution
so remote code execution
is
the execution of of commands
remotely
so
if
let's say
you compromise the system and you're
sending you're sending different
commands via a vulnerable segment in the
application
and
it runs operating system level commands
or or
runs it runs the
[Music]
programming language that
you pick for example over here in the
screenshot
we have a
a php remote code execution um
example
so as you can see the php code includes
echo shell exec
and it gets cmd
so it's cmd because the target is
windows
so it's going to spawn a command prompt
and on the command prompt of course most
of you all know there are a lot of
things to do
because it's the equivalent of the
terminal in linux
so the way that
that this vulnerability works is there's
a client and there's a server of course
it wouldn't be remote if it's just
one-sided
so client
sends a request to the server
and
within that request is
uh
the command that
the client wants the server to execute
so the server then responds with
the appropriate command if the remote
code execution was successful
now
we use cmd date to check if if the
server is actually responding to
operating system level commands
and
the server returned with the current
date
so what if we try to execute a malicious
malicious
command like dir
so dir lists the directories and files
that are in the
present working directory
on windows
so it's it's
it can be used maliciously because uh it
gives an attacker the
file structure of
the present working directory also
allows the attacker to crawl around and
see
whether
different files are
accessible or whether
he can exfiltrate other
sensitive data
so
assuming that
cmd date work we'll try cmd dir
which return
the
directory contents
so over here you'll see that there's a
directory content called
index.php.html dot text and another.php
file
so
uh remote code execution in
in general is very very simple
you as a
client remotely
executing code on the server which
shouldn't happen because you don't have
authorization
so another example for remote code
execution an actual example is
uh the drupal exploit uh called
propogadon 2
way back 2017 2018
so as you can see over here um the
exploit is
using the echo command to test if
remote code execution is is
exploitable or the vulnerability is
explainable to
against the stack
so
as you can see on the highlighted
red
the echo command and on the highlighted
yellow
um
it got the result
of
the echo command from from cmd so after
that the tool deemed that
this is uh explainable for remote code
execution
right so
basically uh code execution is is very
very simple
this is just a straightforward example
there are lots of of ways of
how vulnerabilities are going to be
exploited how you're going to leverage
these vulnerabilities
so moving on to the next vulnerability
uh
denial of service i'm pretty sure you've
heard of this a lot because uh it's it's
one of the most common attacks that that
anyone can can make and the
information security industry
so denial of service
via resource exhaustion is is
a type of denial of service which
which spends the resources of the client
or the server
in order for it to be inaccessible
so
this is a java applet that
that basically is a a map
so it's it's downloadable
easy to reverse engineer or decompile
and once you decompile the code since
it's a java applet you can use
jd gui or jdx to decompile this and
browse the source code
um
you'll see over here that there's a
integer
that's
tagged with
the anti-carton value
so k1 is
also
uh used in in the for loop which is
basically
uh going to run
depending on the value of
the under carbon global value
so what if we change the global variable
uh value to
something like you know 10 million
so the loop is going to run 10 million
times before before it finishes
10 million if if it's uh
it's
probably something that
that's
uh
computing heavy uh it's not going to be
an easy task to perform so it's going to
spend resources way more
rather than
the the intended
so over here after changing the value 10
million you can see that cpus is just
spiked up to 100 percent
which means i can't do anything to my
computer
because you know what the cpu uses is
100 if if i'm going to try to do any
other thing it's going to be
awfully slow
so basically
i've exhausted my resources on
upon opening the the map application
that
i'm not going to be able to access the
map
at the same time i'm not going to be
able to access any other
application
that's readily available to me because
uh 100 of my
cpu has been spent
here you can see the proof that it's
taking up
of the cpu
it's a java applet
so the way this works
is
if we're going to weaponize it
we have for example two remote users an
attacker and then of course the web
server that serves the application
so the remote users
ask for the map
the attacker injects
the
new
high value
on
the
uh on the application
right so he changes the anti-carbon
value to 10 million which makes the for
loop iterate 10 million times
now when the web server
receives the
new value
of course the remote users that
requested the map
are going to be
shipped out
the malicious application that will
exhaust their resources so
once the web server gives the map
of course
the remote users are going to have to
deal with uh their
their
cpus
spiking up to 100 usage and it exhausts
their resources
so that they they can't use any other
any other application in their computer
so this is a denial of service via
resource exhaustion
basically it denies the service
by
spending the client resources instead of
just
bringing down the web server
right so going ahead um we have tools
different tools that
make up
the usual
arsenal
uh first one would be enough so enough
is pretty
important for you because uh this is
going to be your
uh
one of your go-to
recon
recon tools
so nmap gives you
a
a high level
output of of what ports are running uh
is it open closed so the state what
service is running on the specific port
and
uh if you if it can uh it detects uh
what version and what application is
running behind that port
uh nmap can also
return
uh operating systems uh users and many
more
next would be netcat so netcat is
commonly used to interact with different
ports and uh open
listeners or
connect to to listening ports
right so nmap is
and and
netcat is
uh
mostly used
to open up uh
to make
vine shells or reverse shells
so when when the target interacts with
the attacker and the attacker
interacts with the target so on and so
forth
so
what are these
these shells um of course first one
would be bind shell
so
uh
a bind shell is is
kind of like a remote code
execution vulnerability
um it's it's very similar
but
you're directly interacting with with
the machine itself
right so you can open up shells to
access the target remotely
and execute codes
remotely so a bind shell works by
an attacker sending an exploit to the
target
and the exploit would contain something
like open port 4444 and serve
cmd.exe on that port
and then
the target would would open that port
and then the attacker would connect to
the listening port that
his x-play is open
so this is going to be
one directional
the attacker is the one that connects to
the target
whereas
the reverse shell
we also have two clients
but
in in this
in this scenario the attacker is the one
that opens a listening port and then
sends the exploit
now the exploit contains
uh
code that makes the target connect to
the attacker's ip and
its port
um
basically it's called reverse because uh
the rules are reversed so the target is
the one that connects to the attacker
right next is dirt so derp is basically
your uh fuzzer um
direct directory brute forcer for
web applications uh derby's is still
okay i guess
but there are a lot of
faster alternatives right now like grow
buster dirtbuster
and deersearch and and many more
so if if you have
if you have
a different tool that's that's okay it's
it's not going to matter uh i mean
different hackers have different
toolkits
to each his own
tools only help you
achieve your goal
and is not going to be a basis of your
skill set
it's it's always going to be
how you operate it how you use it and
what's possible to do with it
right so next would be um sql map so sql
map is is an automated sql injection
um
assessment
tool
so
uh it tests for for vulnerable
parameters of vulnerable urls
checks whether whether
an application is
is susceptible to a an sql injection
attack
so it's automated but
yours you can also have these manual
flags and
i can also
put in custom exploits with it
this is usually used for for web
applications also
all right next hydra so hydra is is a
directory brute forcer i mean a brute
forcer in general not just a directory
so it can it can conduct password sprays
uh
it can conduct uh brute forcing login
brute forcing uh it can also
be your directory fuzzer if you want but
mostly it's it's uh it's used for for
logins
so over here you can see that it's
it's
hooked to
connecting to a
port a
service and is is spraying different
login combinations the username password
all right next is openvas so openvas is
an open source vulnerability assessment
platform it's a scanner
so it it's uh
it's a platform that that scans for
different vulnerabilities potential
vulnerabilities if i may add
and
it gives the the user an idea of what
possible vulnerabilities there are that
exists in the system so after after
scanning with open bas you can you can
try to
to leverage
these different vulnerabilities
try for a poc or or try to execute
but again you'll have to verify manually
because
this is
this is a
vulnerability scanner only
it's it's not going to give you 100
uh
success rate on on each uh vulnerability
at the text
not everything will be exploitable uh
some will be false positives
all right so next is is a swiss knife
for web application security testers
called burp suite
the main
function of this is to intercept
and
tamper with with requests
so you can also
you can also
brute force this
using the intruder i
also easily
resend requests using the repeater
sequencers
you can also use the coder uh you can
also use collaborator so there are a lot
of tools within this this application
that most web application security
testers use and is very very vital if
you're testing web applications
right so next would be a responder so
responder is mainly used on network
penetration testing engagements uh
say
nbtns lemonr and mdns responder
can also be used as smb relays
mtlm relays
smb you can you can host fake smb shares
to get credentials
and uh you can
try to
uh
poison
the
internal network with it
and then try to gain more uh more
information about
the users
the the available smb shares
which ones access which etc etc
right so next would be uh metasploit so
metasploit is
um
is a
platform that
is an exploitation platform right so it
has a collection of different exploits
payloads
that you can use to
make your life easier
so the exploits are already coded you
just have to set your target and
uh the ip address of
where you want the target to connect if
if you're if you're using a reverse uh
reverse shell
and many many more so basically it makes
your job easier of exploiting the
machine
and getting access to it
instead of manually compiling your own
code
so if it's
if it's already published ready
available you can just
update your metasploit pull the new
express from the database and
see if you can you can get lucky
alright so next would be wireshark so
wireshark is a packet capture analysis
tool
um there are a lot of uses for wireshark
mainly number one for engagements this
can serve as your golden ticket to
get out of jail free so
if if your testing goes wrong and
you're pretty sure that you didn't break
anything you can show them capture these
are the packets i sent
uh it was not made out that brought down
the network um
these these packets are
are
are the ones that i sent this is my
source ip destination ip everything is
recorded et cetera et cetera
i can also use this to
monitor the responses from
from different uh
machines
so this is overall uh this is a very
very useful tool that that can help you
and the network level and
uh
it's
it's widely used along network security
fantastic
next would be hashgat so hashcat is a
password recovery file i mean
application
it basically cracks different hashes
you just have to specify the hash type
and
give it a word list and depending on
your hardware it's going to crack it
really fast or really really slow
right so next would be mimikatz so
mimikatz is a
a go-to tool for red team practitioners
mimikatz is is
what it mainly does is to get
credentials
get credentials
get s ids get
possible tickets forge tickets to to
kerberos uh i've used the kerberos
service
so there's uh
the main the main uh
function of mimikas is to
gain credentials
in in the windows environment
this is
really really exceptional
and this is one of the essentials if
you're going to try to dive into active
directory pen testing
next would be a power split empire
so this is a
post exploitation framework that
most
red teamers used way back
because of
the different
techniques already embedded again this
is
this is for
mostly for for
windows active directory red teaming
tests because uh
it has these uh av bypasses uh different
code execution vulnerabilities within
the ad
how you're going to exfiltrate data
within that
the
active directory try to get domain
controllers uh try to get domain admin
so
um this is one of the
red team tools that are
used
way back it's not i don't think it's
it's that much
uh used up till now until now because uh
most
uh
avs uh have improved and windows amsi
has improved also uh there are also the
presence of
edrs so if they use power split empire
on engagements or renting engagements
it's more likely to get caught rather
than to
successfully compromise further the
active directory network
right so overall uh we're going to go
with the penetration testing approach so
we have
five different methodologies that
uh
that have
been the life cycle for for pen testing
and hacking in general
so uh there's first one is information
gathering or recon
as you all know information is very very
vital when you're trying to
hack a system
you're not going to attack unless you
know more about your enemy right so you
know more about your target
the more you know
the more dangerous it's going to be for
them
the more vulnerabilities you can
leverage uh the more the more attack
vectors you can think of
overall
every single
penetration test
involves in how you gather your
information what information is readily
available to you and
from there you can base
different vulnerabilities so going on
next is vulnerability identification so
after you've got
your different information
from from your recon
uh you can now proceed to identify
multiple vulnerabilities within the
system
that that you're targeting
and once you identify these
vulnerabilities you proceed to
exploitation
and try to gain access
after gaining access
you proceed to post exploitation
which is mainly established persistence
exfiltration of data
so that you don't have to run the
exploit again and again and you'll have
a more secure way of reaccessing the
target machine if ever your shell dies
and then after post exploitation of
course you're going to report this
because as you all know over here we're
ethical
so you report these vulnerabilities uh
of course together with the
proof of concepts if you successfully
exploited
and leverage that vulnerability
so overall these five uh
steps these are going to be
your life cycle when you're doing fan
testing or when you're doing hacking in
general
this applies to everything this applies
to all
it's going to be your bread and butter
into getting that first box
so information gathering
uh as you can see there are various ways
of gathering information for example
over here you use nmap to map the
different ports different services
over here we can see uh
the change log of of a
drupal uh
stack
that says
there's multiple security issues that
have been fixed
you can also see that the date is 2016
so which means it's very very updated
and the next is the penetration testing
approach
so
um
after you get your recon
you do
the search for your vulnerabilities
right so you search
apache exploits
drupal exploits
there's a lot so
the one we saw earlier was running 2016.
the pass was
over here is release 2018 so
since it's using a 2016 version
and the drupal
change log states that the version is
vulnerable
we now have our identified vulnerability
now we can try to use this exploit and
over here as you can see on on the
yellow highlight
code execution work
so it means that the exploit worked and
we are now
going to be
able to access the machine remotely
so after post
uh post-exploitation and
includes exfiltration of data
setting up persistence
privilege escalation
so over here
you can see that
after connection the remote connection
has been made
um we're trying to
figure out what files we can open uh we
can try
uh what permissions are there for for us
so over here you can see
important documents how we have no
permission over so
we need to escalate privileges into an
admin so we proceed to
identification of vulnerabilities again
so we now know the stack because
we have access to the system
so over here
uh we need to
check
the
operating system version if there are
any ways to
privilege
escalate our local privileges on the
machine
so upon searching x-ray bb
we can
find that there is an overlay fs local
privilege escalation technique
exploit that's readily available
since it fits with our
linux kernel version and our ubuntu
version
we can try to use this
so
after uh
compiling and executing the
exploit you can see over here that we
are root so our escalate
our escalation work we are now the
highest level of user in a linux system
so we do not have access to important
documents so we now own the system
basically this is this is going to be a
roadmap this is going to be your bread
and butter is going to be your your
usual methodology
this is going to be what's going to be
on your mind what's going to be your
everyday process as you practice
and after that you can you know take
certifications
if you have time and money and why not
right
so there's a lot of tracks within the
infosec industry uh you can go for
offensive defensive operations uh
management analysis implementation
so all these
these are very very broad
um
again
you can take these certifications as as
a baseline for for you if you actually
if you want external validation
that you you are an expert in this topic
or you are a professional in this topic
it's not required but it's good to have
right so
that's that's basically my talk um
i'm going to go over and
show you a couple of things um
over here
i have
a hands-on example of
the tools that i mentioned so
uh we have a metasploitable box over
here
that
we are currently running
and we ran an nmap scan against it
so nmap released
different information so there's uh ftp
service uh vsftpd234
uh there's ssh running telnet there's uh
smtp
and then there's a dns
and
an http server
so there are a lot of ports open
that can be
[Music]
that can
be leverage right so maybe we can also
see the service versions
so
apart from that there's also
different directories on on the web page
so this is uh durb
right so
there