hello everyone my name is kamel and
thank you so much for coming to my talk
keeping up with modern automotive
exploitation presented at root con 15 in
2021 today we're going to be talking a
little bit about some of the more modern
exploits that have been publicized on
vehicles in the last few years and kind
of get a better understanding of how
vehicles are being targeted in the cyber
security space in the modern day
so
quick introduction to myself i am an
automotive cyber security architect at
white motion white motion is a lesser
known company that's actually a
subsidiary of morelli morality is a
global automotive supplier that's
originally based in italy but a few
years back they actually merged with a
japanese supplier called calsonic kansai
a rather boring story but long story
short now they're one entity called
morelli and i work for a automotive
cybersecurity focused subsidiary wholly
owned by that corporation as a result
i'm actually calling in from tokyo today
so konichiwa
it's a pleasure to meet you
i'm a trilingual car hacking enthusiast
on this my short demo
just showed i am uh decently fluent in
japanese i wouldn't say i'm great at it
but i also speak english and arabic
i'm an ex-admin of the automotive
security research group branch in
detroit michigan where i'm originally
from
and i am the founder of the asrg branch
in japan unfortunately since moving here
the pandemic has kind of shut things
down so we haven't had a lot of
opportunities to have a very
how should i say exciting asrg
experience yet but in the future we're
sure to have a lot of cool things to
look out for so if you're interested in
asrg
hit me up and i'll put you in touch
so uh when it comes to automotive i have
a couple of areas of interest i enjoy
doing bluetooth research
research into the usb protocol rf and
some digital forensics and outside of
the laboratory i like to play fighting
games i love cooking and i'm a very poor
ukulele player i haven't actually
practiced in a long time so
unfortunately i won't be able to provide
any solos for anyone anytime soon
so
a quick look at the objectives of this
talk i want to to make this talk to kind
of bring anyone who may not be following
the automotive security industry so
closely into kind of a similar you know
common frame of reference right so i
want to talk about automotive cyber
security in 2021 and for those of you
who don't know anything at all about
automotive cybersecurity maybe this is
the first time you've ever considered a
car being hacked don't worry i've got a
very brief intro for you as well so
you'll be able to join us for the rest
of the talk
after that kind of intro and catching up
to the modern state of automotive cyber
security in 2021 i want to go over a
couple of significant
disclosures that have happened in the
last few years namely the texas texas
excuse me the lexus bluetooth hack of
2020 the tesla bluetooth hack of 2020
the tesla drone hack earlier this year
in 2021 and then i want to kind of look
at what these different
vulnerability or exploitation
publications have in common and how they
all kind of work into this view of the
vehicle as a modern security target
finally we're going to talk a little bit
about how it ties into iot security and
then about product vulnerability
management in the automotive industry
and why
these specific cases highlight its
importance going forward into the
connected transportation future
so
automotive security in 2021 all right
thanks to
chris and charlie uh
charlie miller and chris valasek two of
the most famous car hackers of all time
automotive cyber security has very
steadily become a rising concern for
both governments and industry all over
the world
in 2015 they were actually able to
display or kind of demonstrate
that a jeep cherokee was able to be
hacked from kilometers away without the
hackers ever having
come into physical contact with the
vehicle
of course this was done over a very long
period of time i think it took them
about two years total of research and
reverse engineering of the system but
the end result was they were able to
identify a vehicle through its vin
number and connect to it over the
internet
through the mobile carrier in use in the
vehicle
the the network that they were using
over their cellular modems was able to
be used to log into these vehicles and a
lack of security checks on firmware
flashing i'm simplifying things a little
bit to get through with this but
allowed them to reflash firmware on some
controllers in the vehicle and to take
control this allowed them to kill the
brakes of the car and there's a very
cool video of a poor journalist
experiencing this firsthand
out there on the internet i encourage
all of you to watch
but you know thanks to their their
efforts this industry has become much
more widely understood and there's a lot
more interest and conversation about
automotive security
but
you know six seven years later it's
still kind of the
the poster child for automotive cyber
security research and because it's the
holy grail it's you know long-range
remote takeover of a vehicle to some
extent right so it's the most
archetypal example you could give of a
car hack in the worst case scenario
but that's not what today is about today
is about making sure everyone is aware
of some of the more recent hacks that
have happened on cars
right but anyway so when it comes to
vehicles of course uh it's not just
about information security and privacy
as much as traditional i.t security is
right if you think about my phone
getting hacked or maybe my laptop even
you know worst case scenario
my
my company's network assuming these
aren't connected to any heavy duty
industrial machinery or anything else
that may cause someone physical harm the
the most realistic impact of a hack like
this is generally considered to be loss
of you know wealth it's kind of like
financial damage right for at least for
the for the average person when it comes
to vehicles it's a little bit different
we're talking about a
very large torpedo that kind of cruises
along
you know the street 60 70 miles an hour
or you know about a hundred kilometers
an hour and if this
you know thing this large two-ton
tonk of steel carrying people inside it
is ever compromised or interfered with
in a way such that an accident is more
likely or intentionally caused you have
a situation where public safety is now
a concern for automotive cyber security
so the stakes are a little bit higher
and that has actually gotten the
attention of governments and
standardization bodies all over the
world
so among these you have the united
nations and you have the
society of automotive engineers and the
international standards association
these bodies of course the united
nations i'm sure you've heard of them
before they provide you know guidance to
different nations and come up with
regulations
and
you know most mostly non-binding
legislation to help countries
more or less operate properly and this
applies as well to technology so the
ece wp29 is a document that was actually
published by the united nations in 2020
detailing some of their recommendations
for cyber security best practices and
essentially encouraging countries to
write into their own law
laws that mandate automotive
manufacturers to
undergo
cyber security tests for their vehicles
and make sure that these vehicles are
cyber secure to the extent possible
before they're allowed to be released
onto the street similarly the iso sae
21434 standard was actually released or
i guess finalized very recently the
draft has been in the works for several
years now but this document is more of a
technical guide that serves as a
a complementary document to the united
nations regulation
in which you know experts from the
industry have come together and provided
a list of best practices for how to
actually perform these cybersecurity
tests and checks for vehicles to ensure
that they're as secure as possible
before being released into the market
these are of course very lengthy
documents and could probably take up
their own talk but just the fact that
they exist is evidence that governments
and standardizing bodies alike are
putting a high priority on automotive
cyber security for the future of
connected transportation uh and then of
course uh one last thing i want a couple
last things to mention is that because
the industry is still relatively new and
not that mainstream especially when it
comes to
cyber security as a kind of a much
broader you know field of study there's
a severe lack of professionals and so if
you've ever been thinking man i wish i
had a job that you know i had a little
bit more of a niche in right if you're
an i.t
or traditional cyber security engineer
and you're thinking of specializing in a
field where you could really stand out i
highly recommend you to check out
automotive there's a lot of
fun in car hacking and there are a lot
of great resources to help you get
started if you're interested but
leave that for later and then finally
the massive supply chain this is
something you can't really escape when
it comes to talking about automotive
security right when you consider
for any of you familiar with the
automotive industry
just how many different companies have a
hand in deciding what goes into a
vehicle the prospect of making sure that
all of these companies based in
different countries with different laws
different regulations different
standards of practice different
budgets or even safety
protocols coming together it's very
daunting right because you have the oem
who at the end of the day sells the car
puts their logo their stamp on it and
they're the brand that you know right
most people in the world would know a
brand like ford or tesla but then you
have the tier ones who provide a lot of
the
modules to these oems right you might
know some of the bigger companies if you
you've ever been exposed to the industry
right continental denso etc but your
average everyday person doesn't know
that these companies exist right so they
may not have the awareness of how
daunting of a task it is to really
propagate cyber security best practices
throughout such a huge supply chain and
then of course it goes farther down into
tier two suppliers uh so on and so forth
but
that being said you know these oems and
tier ones the entire automotive industry
they're still doing their best to
incorporate cyber security into their
development processes right the
automotive industry is not a very
fast-moving young type of industry it's
pretty well established you know cars
have been around for a long time the
automakers have gotten pretty good at
doing what they do
and so they've kind of settled into
their ways for better or for worse right
they have a process they have a system
and it takes time to add changes to this
system right it's a very mature industry
you can't just introduce something like
a cyber security regulation or a bunch
of standards and expect them to be
applied to the whole industry overnight
it's just not realistic
so
this fact of the matter is that well
okay now the united nations has put out
this this regulation a lot of the
governments around the world are
starting to pick it up
the oems and the the manufacturers and
suppliers within the countries that are
applying this you know this new legal
structure they're doing their best to
catch up and try and incorporate these
into their their processes for
development but it is taking time and
it's still definitely going to be a
trial and error as we go into the future
of actual usage and implementation
of these standards but there's a lot of
industry groups encouraging
collaboration that i want to kind of
mention i mentioned the automotive
security research group briefly before
in my own introduction asrg is a group
that promotes open access to information
about the automotive cyber security
industry we have branches all over the
world it's completely free to join i'm
not doing any you know sponsorship based
plugging here but i highly recommend you
check out asrg if you're a
a hobbyist who's interested in learning
about car hacking and just kind of
getting into the industry
through direct contact with
professionals asrg is great for that
on the more
how should i say
corporate business side of things you
have the auto isac and j auto isaac so
the isac is of course an information
sharing
community based around the oems and tier
ones the actual
players of the industry who make the
vehicles that actually go onto the road
they have this community where which
they're able to share information about
vulnerabilities etc with one another
updated vulnerability information
training setting standards regulations
they have some ties to the government
that allows them to kind of
be on top of different regulations uh
and legislation before it actually hits
the books per se
which makes it uh very convenient for
people working in the industry but those
are not quite as accessible for for
outsiders right in the sense that you
don't already work at one of these
companies and then the j auto isaac is
just the japanese version of the auto
isaac so following the same model but
mainly attended to
uh by japanese companies so
i'm done with the boring stuff we can
actually get into some case studies now
and before excuse me before we get
started i want to make a quick
disclaimer
while i'm not directly related to these
uh pieces of research i'm a huge fan of
the work i always try to give you know
as much credit to the original
researchers as possible
but i believe that there's a lot of
value in being able to share this
information and the fact that this
research is going on with a broader
audience
of course uh i i do my own automotive
research as well but because my employer
is usually the sponsor for said research
i have the nda problem prevents people
talking about my own work most of the
time especially in japan they're very
touchy about confidentiality when it
comes to cyber security work um so
please forgive me if it feels like i'm
just a content vulture as it were but
we're going to talk about one of my
favorite ones from the recent future
the
lexus bluetooth hack of march 2020. so
this
hack
it affected
several lexus brand vehicles that were
manufactured outside of japan between
2016 and i believe
2019.
this particular disclosure kicked up
quite a bit of a storm in the japanese
community
especially because toyota is seen as the
big dog in the japanese automotive
industry right so if anything happens to
toyota all the other smaller oems are
kind of you know pay very close
attention like what happened like
is it okay like do we have the same
problems do we have to to worry about
this right so this one was actually uh
very very prominent when it came out uh
here in the japanese industry
so keen labs uh i believe they're
they're owned by cent in china
they showed that through a
vulnerability in the vehicle's bluetooth
stack they were able to execute commands
without having to be paired with the
vehicle
essentially remote code execution
through bluetooth but they didn't
actually reveal what vulnerabilities led
to this rce in their initial paper
some
vulnerability reporting websites
reported it as blueborne for those of
you who may not be familiar with
blueborne it's a very high profile suite
of
remote code execution vulnerabilities
that was released by armist labs in i
believe 2017.
so
that kind of lines up with the timeline
you know it's very possible that this
was the vulnerability that keen labs was
able to exploit in these vehicles seeing
as the start date for manufacturer
vehicles with this particular head unit
or infotainment system in them uh were
were initially created starting in 2016.
so but i i don't know if there's a an
official i guess identification for the
specific vulnerability they use but
there it should be maybe more
information online as they didn't want
to reveal too much information at the
initial disclosure of this research of
course for
security purposes and you know to
keep things confidential
but
anyway
because bluetooth was being run with
root user privileges the researchers
were able to send instructions to
construct a wi-fi based back door that
would automatically grant them a root
shell they were essentially able to
install a back door into the
vehicle's infotainment system over
bluetooth but
thanks to the fact that they were able
to pivot to the wi-fi protocol instead
they were actually able to enhance the
range at which this technique was usable
so while wi-fi itself wasn't exactly
you know the target of attack initially
they were able to use the wi-fi network
as a pivoting tool to expand access to
their
their their attack target right because
obviously wi-fi
has a rather a slightly longer range
than bluetooth they're both considered
pretty short-range communication
technologies
but wi-fi definitely has its benefits
when compared to bluetooth but so they
they chose to instead of continuing on
the bluetooth remote code execution
go for the root shell option over wi-fi
instead
and so from here the researchers were
able to abuse the linux board's
administrative position within the
in-vehicle infotainment system to
reflash the firmware on a secondary ecu
now
there's one device the in-vehicle
infotainment system inside this car
but it has multiple boards inside and
multiple different pcbs each of which
have a couple of you know computers
inside
and they have different privileges and
different roles that they play inside
this device right the ivi is the
infotainment unit it's usually what you
would see like a little screen on inside
the vehicle you can
connect your phone over bluetooth or
set up a wi-fi hotspot you know the
modern vehicles have all sorts of cool
gadgets built into their ivis these days
some of them even have games i think you
can download apps from app stores
but
the point is among these different
boards inside the ivi one of them was
technically the administrative board and
that's the board they were able to get
that remote code execution on so because
of this board's privilege in the ivi's
environment
it actually was in the position where
it's allowed to push updates to the
other
computers inside the ipi right so this
board was kind of the boss of the ivi
system and from there they were able to
reflash other processors and take
advantage of this unit they've actually
compromised right this is an issue where
there's a lack of
checking and making sure that any
firmware updates being sent to different
parts of the vehicle are properly signed
using you know signatures that can be
verified cryptographic signatures to
ensure that unauthorized firmware isn't
being written to your devices inside
your car
so
the secondary ecu that they targeted was
responsible for the interaction with the
vehicle's can buses
for those of you with no car hacking
experience can bus is control area
network it's a in-vehicle network for
all intents and purposes one of the most
common ones in the whole world
essentially these are specific networks
that are designed to allow different
controllers inside a vehicle to
communicate with one another over short
distances
but
the can device they had compromised and
reflashed originally had some filters on
it right they were not allowed to send
arbitrary ken messages it was kind of
restricted to a certain subset of
functionality specific to that
operational environment for for the
usual operation of the vehicle
but remember
they have the ability to change the
software so they were actually able to
disable those can filters and unlock
arbitrary can most camos excuse me can
bus message access through their
foothold on that authoritative board in
the iei
so of course once again this comes back
to the lack of firmware signature
checking on the secondary board and had
such a measure been in place even with
the remote code execution on the main
linux board there may have been
you know no opportunity for the
researchers to pivot to the in-vehicle
network which gives them access to a
much
broader range of controllers inside the
vehicle
of course separation of your you know
networks and sandboxing of course all
come into play here these are all
security principles that are very
relevant in automotive too right
so
following this rewriting of the vehicles
firmware the researchers were able to
send arbitrary can data including
diagnostic requests this in theory could
lead to even further exploitation of the
vehicle
as through diagnostics you can actually
reprogram other controllers in the car
they would of course have to re first
engineer the diagnostic protocol used to
flash these vehicles
the diagnostic protocols also use
something called a
security access mechanism when it comes
to programming as well
and so this may have taken more time but
it essentially is just showing that
there is an open-ended door for further
post-ex post exploitation
activities on this target
but you know of course that rabbit hole
is an entirely different conversation
and it's mostly theoretical
but the full technical details uh
are probably going to be a lot more
interesting for those of you who want to
read 10 cent did release a blog post
detailing in much more detail how they
did all of these a brilliant
should i say
all this brilliant research
right
so
the next case study is on some research
that was performed on tesla vehicles uh
and this was actually disclosed also in
2020 but more closer to the end of the
year
this one was actually done by a
gentleman named leonard reuters i
believe he he gave a talk about this
uh exact piece of research
in the 2021 defcon car hiking village so
if you want to hear him talk about this
i highly recommend you go and listen to
him he'll have some more details that i
wouldn't be able to share with you
but the
gentleman who
did this you know of course i'm so sorry
for my pronunciation if i pronounce his
name wrong but leonard wuters from
belgium he he showed that the
bluetooth-based firmware update process
used using tesla model x key fobs could
be abused to eventually lead to theft of
the vehicle
right teslas are generally seen as the
most
how should i say high-tech
state-of-the-art vehicles in the world
right now right a lot of people have
this impression that the tesla is the
the car of tomorrow right it is the the
all the bells and whistles possible on a
vehicle and to some extent that's very
true
but that also means it's kind of a sneak
peek into what the
security landscape for a vehicle is
going to look like
so when something happens to tesla
you better pay attention
excuse me
routers found that the
model x key fob responds to a signal
emitted by the vehicle's pcm which can
then lead to a reprogramming session
done by bluetooth right so bluetooth
traditionally in vehicles
has been used for things like
media control hands-free phone calls
sharing contacts with your vehicle there
hasn't really been a lot of cases of
bluetooth being used for anything
remotely safety critical
and in this case we're seeing that tesla
has decided to take this bluetooth
technology
and use it for something a little bit
more important right they're using it as
the actual
conduit by which they push software
updates or firmware updates
to their key fobs right it's kind of a
big deal right you're changing the
software on the key to your car
over bluetooth and bluetooth research is
something i i may have mentioned before
i have a passing interest in
there's a lot of really great bluetooth
research coming out in the last few
years but i don't want to go too far too
far into that but the point is right
this kind of
novel
application of bluetooth and automotive
is what led to this attack being
discovered so
the only authentication needed from the
bcm was derived from the vehicle's vin
the vehicle identification number the
vehicle identification number isn't
usually considered secret information
you can actually get this information
from any car you see by just kind of
peeking through the windshield right if
you take a look through the top it's
usually kind of
written
along the side
on the top of the dashboard so it's not
considered highly confidential
information by any stretch of the
imagination so
since there was no code signing checks
done on the firmware updates pushed to
the key fob
rewriting the firmware to share an
unlock code with the attacker's device
is actually pretty easy once this was
done a disassembled model x key fob
could then be used to transmit the said
signal to unlock the vehicle
so essentially what leonard and his and
his team did they actually got a tesla
bcm you know off of ebay or something
and messed around with it reprogrammed
it
and
used it
to request an unlock signal
from a key fob
so basically they tricked the bcm into
thinking
it belonged to the car
that the key fob the target key fob
belonged to so they could then request
for credentials to open the vehicle and
get inside
but you know at the end of the day this
particular vulnerability only granted
them access to the inside of the vehicle
from here
now you have physical access of the
vehicle
you have a rather broad attack surface
now right you can actually plug into the
in-vehicle networks now because because
of course these are very these are
physical networks so
you have access to much more targets for
post-exploitation and pivoting
so
through a port located under the model x
display more damage can be done through
the can bus right can bus coming back
again once once more from from the last
case study we went through
so can bus access to the bcm
meant that they were able to use a
different vulnerability
to actually pair the bcm the body
control module that was inside the car
to their new fake tesla key right that
third part that third tesla key
the third party tesla key that they used
to actually send the unlock signal
is now being reintroduced to this car
saying like hey look i'm your new key
you should recognize me and let me start
the car and this is actually exactly
what they did so they tricked the car
into thinking that the new key fob is
the original key fob
or something along those lines and we're
able to unlock all driving functionality
for the car essentially allowing them to
steal it
interestingly all of this the whole
process only takes about
i'd say about 15 minutes and everything
that you needed to be able to perform
this attack would cost you under 400
right
you could actually all fit it inside a a
lunchbox sized you know
backpack really you can put it inside a
backpack sneak up behind a family who
parked their tesla and maybe went for a
walk or go get some ice cream all you
needed to do is just follow them until
you get that unlocked signal then go
back to the car and do everything else
manually and well congratulations you
are now
the new owner of a stolen tesla model x
right so
there's a very practical attack from the
perspective of a motivation
perspective right because when it comes
to cyber security a lot of the reason
that car hacks aren't very widespread
yet is because
the
motivation to effort ratio
is is is very low right there's not a
lot of criminal benefit criminals aren't
interested in killing random people and
causing havoc on the road they're more
interested in stealing things they want
actual financial
return for their efforts and that's why
ransomware has become so
prevalent over the last few years
but this is actually a scenario where
you're using a very high tech method to
be able to steal a car now whether or
not this was ever used in such a
malicious manner is
something only god knows but the fact
that this exists is is you know very
concerning
so but interestingly enough
the model x key fobs do actually contain
unique cryptographic certificates that
should have prevented this reprogramming
of the bcm to accept the new key
as its as its key
however
the bcm
never actually implements this
certificate check
so
the certificate is there but the bcm is
just not checking it it's like they had
everything in place to be able to avoid
the same mistake that the alexis fellows
we talked about a second ago made
unfortunately they did miss the last
step
and
well that's why we're talking about them
today so but at this stage the attacker
now has the model x and can drive away
with it
and
you know
whoever comes back is going to be very
sad to see that their cars disappeared
without a trace
so
hopefully this case study illustrates
the importance of assuring that every
layer of system security is properly
configured
while the bluetooth implementation
itself wasn't
faulty this time per se as it was in the
last one right in the last example we
gave
the actual bluetooth stack itself had a
vulnerability resulting in remote code
execution
in this example the bluetooth stack
itself
more or less just fine they were able to
they didn't actually
how should i say
compromise the vehicle through the
bluetooth stack itself they used the
processes on either end of the bluetooth
stack
to actually make that happen
right
excuse me and then once again of course
code signing and making sure that you
have certificates ensuring that any
firmware being pushed to any part of
your vehicle is from the oem or another
approved source
is is rather important
so the last
where'd my car go i could have sworn i
had a car on the slide a second ago but
the last case study we're going to be
looking at today
is the
uh tesla drone hack or cutely dubbed
t-bone that was revealed earlier in 2021
this year
so this hack was done by some fellows
named ralph philip weinmann and benedict
jumps
i if i said that wrong i'm very sorry uh
of course once again my
pronunciation might be off but these
guys did a great uh bit of research here
and showed that
bluetooth isn't the only potentially
vulnerable network in a vehicle today
there's a lot more that can be looked at
so
this hack took advantage of a library
with a vulnerability that was accessible
over wi-fi as opposed to bluetooth
normally wi-fi wouldn't be accessible to
someone that's not connected to that
access point uh
in this you know on the same subnet more
or less uh as the actual vehicle itself
so it's a little bit harder to make use
of this kind of vulnerability you know
on a car you've just encountered but
tesla's have this very weird quirk about
them at least in europe where all teslas
will
automatically connect to a default
service ssid for any of you who've done
wi-fi testing before
and this ssid is called tesla service
wouldn't you know they're actually able
to find out
the the password in use for this ssid as
well
and through that they were able to
successfully create a fake access point
that this tesla vehicle would then
connect to
now
that alone isn't really
you know the end of the world right okay
you got the car to connect to your fake
access point you know that's awesome
but
what did they do next so the vulnerable
software in question
is called con man as i you can maybe see
up there on the slide i have the actual
cds that they were awarded
for this research 20 21 266 75 and 266
each of them giving that each of these
vulnerabilities giving them a different
level of
control over this vehicle and what it's
doing
so con man is a
commonly used you know iot
handler for dns and dhcp for any kind of
network devices device this is very
common in the iot world a lot of you
know smaller cheaper
iot devices that connect to wi-fi will
use con man for help with the dns and
dhcp
the version of con man that the vehicle
was using at the time was version 1.37
this was at the time the most up-to-date
version with no known vulnerabilities in
it actually since conman 1.34
had been pretty stable and there wasn't
a lot of security research done showing
that there was anything especially wrong
with it but the researchers decided to
fuzz it anyway given that some of the
handling of dns seemed suspicious to
them is more or less how they phrase it
in their paper which i have linked at
the end of the
talk
but they targeted the dns parsing
section and found a couple of bugs and
of course
after
expanding on these bugs with a i believe
it's a special emulator that they
themselves made
they found the area that caused the
program to crash and identified a
function that calls a mem copy command
without proper input validation leading
to the possibility of a stack overflow
attack being the brilliant you know
post-exploitation kind of
guys that they are the researchers were
then able to use a separate
vulnerability also listed here to gain
more information about the stack right
leaking information that allowed them to
put together a payload to give them more
access to this vehicle right allowing
them to bypass security measures such as
data execution prevention and address
space layout randomization
i see the aslr
and the dep these are common techniques
used to prevent
hackers from
getting execution you know on your stack
but thanks to this other vulnerability
that was leaking information
to the researchers they were actually
able to bypass those preventative
measures that were in place
interestingly enough they actually
initially came up with these
vulnerabilities hoping to use them in a
pwn to own contest that has featured
vehicles in recent years where if you
actually
hack you know root the tesla you
actually get to keep the tesla i believe
it's held in canada every year
unfortunately the con the convention or
rather the car hacking portion of this
event was cancelled due to the
coronavirus
and that's why it was revealed
last year instead to to a conference
called apsec west i want to say but
once they got their foothold sorry i got
kind of sidetracked they utilized some
other redacted techniques that they
declined to include in the paper for
sensitivity regions
to escalate their privileges to root on
the tesla giving them full control over
the tesla's infotainment system
from here they could invoke any action
possible through that infotainment
system any of you who have ever been in
a tesla
the infotainment system is like
this big and it's got this you know
beautiful screen and it's like you got
your map you got your music and
everything especially in the model x
it's really quite something you can
control your your seat temperature you
can control the cabin temperature the
air conditioner you can open and close
doors they could do anything possible
from that ivi remotely without even
being inside the vehicle including like
changing the music and stuff
so
they called this the drone hack because
everything needed to perform this hack
could potentially be loaded onto a drone
and this is significant because
well tesla's all around the world have
this little quirk about them right they
have to charge so you could essentially
the idea was you know you could take a
drone with all of this software on it
and kind of park it behind a
supercharger and just kind of wait for
unsuspecting tesla owners to come park
their car go do some grocery shopping
while it charges and come back to find
that oh someone opened my car and either
stole all my stuff or as leonard did in
the previous example use some other
vulnerabilities to give them the ability
to drive the car away there's any number
of possibilities from there once you've
gotten access to that infotainment
system
letting you open the door
it's a very you know flexible and fun
attack platform you know a drone and
they actually did show a proof of
concept in their original
release of this research that shows them
doing exactly that
right so very very very good work uh by
uh ralph and benedict i'm a huge fan
honestly
so
taking a quick look back at the three
case studies we went over
they have a couple things in common
right all of them were
essentially compromised through the use
of close range wireless technologies
either bluetooth or wi-fi in the lexus
example both of these technologies were
actually used one is the initial entry
point and another to extend the range by
which they could you know proceed to
poke at the vehicle
in all these cases
a lack of signature checks
or at least in the first two cases a
lack of signature checks allowed the
attackers to reflash software on these
devices without approval from the oem
leading them to be able to remove
filters on the canvas in the first
example
or just simply
tell the the bcm in the car to recognize
my new key fob in the second example
right both of these vulnerabilities that
were used both excuse me all of the
vulnerabilities we went over three
examples uh they're very iot centric
vulnerabilities right bluetooth and con
man are very commonly used in iot
bluetooth of course being a very
uh
well-supported wireless technology for
cable replacement your car supports
bluetooth your headphones are bluetooth
your smartwatches bluetooth your fitbit
is bluetooth
very common in the iot world and so is
con man for the same reason
it's easy to use it's lightweight and
it's very
popular among embedded linux devices so
that kind of
adds to that same iot
centric
you know
evolution of the vehicle where the
vehicle is now becoming part of the iot
and maybe somebody in the marketing
department took that a bit too literally
and now they're they're developing with
with iot software in these you know
production automotive industry-grade
vehicles now
right and they were performed on modern
vehicles right it's one thing i love
talking about is because remember what i
said tesla is the car of the future
yeah but it's also got all the
vulnerabilities of the future
so
the fact that all of these issues may
seem like oh my god how did they let
that get in there how did they implement
this you know this feature without
having signature checks on all the
firmware upgrades
unfortunately it does happen and and the
automotive industry is still trying to
catch up and get ahead of these problems
before you know self-driving cars become
very widespread in the world because
that's really when this kind of
lack of
due diligence on the automaker's part
may end up costing someone
the ultimate price right
um and then you know you have to give a
shout out to tesla and the ability to
update their software over the air
if this had happened to a car without
that capability right when you consider
two of our
case studies today had to do with teslas
the fact that they have the ability to
update their software and remotely patch
any kind of vulnerabilities of this sort
is really a blessing for them and
something we're likely to see more of in
the future
but other auto makers really have to
kind of follow follow suit there
and the fact that these are all
post-production vehicles ties into the
first the previous point these are all
vehicles that were on the road people
were sitting in these vehicles driving
them to work every day driving them on
the highway driving their kids home from
school
and you know god forbid if if this
knowledge got into the wrong hands
somebody may have been able to
you know make use of it in a malicious
manner uh and
it all ties back to
preventing this from happening in the
future so how exactly
would you prevent this from happening in
the future
of course we talked a little bit about
the new standards and legislation
that are kind of being introduced into
the automotive industry the united
nations wp-29 as well as the iso 2144
these security
recommendations and best practices need
to eventually make their way into the
development process for a vehicle and it
can't just be a one step okay we did the
cyber security check now it's over
security on such a complicated
product such as a vehicle is much more
involved than that you have to make sure
you're going through with all of your
suppliers and making sure their products
are secure and that they're doing checks
it's it's quite the task
a training for engineers and development
managers right maybe for the managers
they don't need to have knowledge of all
the different attack patterns and how
you might actually perform an attack on
a car but the
anyone in that position would still need
to have an awareness of what cyber
security means for a vehicle what should
they consider when making design choices
for the vehicle or their components to
ensure that they minimize the risk of a
cyber security incident as much as
possible of course it's too immature to
say that with enough
effort you know this device will never
ever be hacked until the heat death of
the universe that's simply not true that
just doesn't exist it's a it's a fact of
life that everything can be hacked given
enough time but it's our job to do our
best to to bring that possibility as
close to zero as possible
and then comprehensive product
vulnerability management
this is something that i think really
needs to take off in the automotive
industry every oem needs to be ready to
act on the new vulnerability manager
excuse me new vulnerability information
and understand
if and when this applies to any of their
products if we think back to the lexus
example
in the event that you know the
vulnerability that led to the initial
rce was as a matter of fact blueborne
blueborne had been you know
publicized for about three years prior
to this research's release
right
because it was
bluetooth vulnerability right maybe
no one made the connection that hey
cars have bluetooth in them
we should make sure that none of our
products currently on the market
have
you know susceptibility to this suite of
high
impact vulnerabilities that could lead
to remote code execution maybe that
context shift just didn't make it all
the way over
product vulnerability management
involves knowing all of your products
knowing what goes into them hardware and
software
and
triaging information right as
vulnerability information gets released
into different sources different
talks etc etc you need to have an intake
of that process it properly and be able
to apply it to your own products in the
event it's relevant make
excuse me make accurate decisions on
whether or not it affects any of your
products and then of course the action
part
is the most important how do you solve
it do you have to recall
two million vehicles so you send out a
software update do you just work into
the next patch of regular updates based
on severity all of these things are
parts of the automotive cyber security
life cycle that will come around i have
confidence in it but they're still kind
of making their way in and it's
definitely going to be a while before
they're
really very widespread throughout the
industry so here is a list of the
references that i used in this talk of
course once again i want to give all the
credit due in the world to the actual
researchers that did such a great job
on their
on
this research that they've presented and
that i was you know able to share with
you today hopefully you learned
something
car hacking is very fun and a very
how should i say enjoyable
field to be in and maybe if it's not
obvious i really enjoy what i do and i'd
be happy to help any of you get into car
hacking
if you are interested in any
way at all feel free to look me up on
linkedin or send me an email at camel
dot golly at whitemotion.com
so thank you so much i it was my
pleasure to be here at rootcon15 and
don't forget hack the planet