okay I guess we'll get started
all right so you're here for my talk
about how to start a podcast I want to
preface this with I'm not a pro but for
two years friends have been running the
podcast and it wasn't exactly the music
setup
so how I did it I also run some video
stuff on YouTube which was also not
exactly straightforward so I thought I'd
sprinkle that in here as well so who I
unclear system and of like 20 years well
20 years an IT admin assistant for about
half of that couple certifications I'm
also one of the admins in that area to
check it out fun time first Wednesday
everyone meetups and if I run the iron
system podcast this was you know I had
about two years ago my co-host right
here was the first guy that we decided
to just being one of the guy set this up
so that's one thing I do and the other
thing I do is I eat the busiest
about this light stuff they do in the
garage and trails and you know some more
my things it's just the things that I
know and the things that I know are the
things that I talk about well so there
it is so it's just a quick last item
making money is still sort of elusive
but on the top a little bit
both of my endeavors don't currently
make any money basically you know figure
out your show start recording ends with
what you got
host or show haven't approved once
you've got posted and you actually have
a listener base and how to improve
hosting and of course and what you might
do to make your YouTube channel or your
make some money for you so the first
thing we starting shows to figure out
what the heck you want your show to be
about so choose yourself a totally
unique topic totally agonizing about
this never talk about anything anyone
else has ever talked about it being
sarcastic what I mean to say is it
doesn't matter if someone else is
already covered the topic if you want to
talk about brain soon as you make the
surgery make sure you know what you're
talking about
but if there's a hundred other podcasts
on brain surgery then just make yours a
little bit unique and that's good enough
we started our show we talked about
systems administration operations stuff
mainly because I didn't find a lot of
shows that really build that means some
of them have showed up since then there
were a couple when we started I feel
like we do a pretty good job of it but
others did a good job too and really
it's just all part of an ecosystem right
so one more voice in the crowd isn't
necessarily nothing it's bring your own
perspective
then you want to choose a format so you
could do what I mean my format is not
media we're going to cover that later
but what kind of show do you want to run
is it going to be how to show is it
going to be like a new show is it going
to be something a little more freeform
than that is it going to be an interview
show I'm system is sort of accommodation
we do a little bit of news we do topic
and we also just have some general to
tender something like an interview show
what we've done in your to pro industry
or whatever but again just make it what
you want it to be it doesn't you don't
have to stick to a certain mold but
think about what you want it to be
before you start recording that way
you're not sort of scattered shot all
over the place that is just choose a
medium and by that I mean do you want it
to be just audio only podcast do you
want it to be video podcast which is the
thing that people do now you want it to
be just a plain old you know video
channel some sort of we're making
episodes of something and it doesn't
matter what those things are it could be
like I said how to use it could be maybe
you're making cartoons you know whatever
it is you want to produce and put out
there but you want to figure that at the
beginning obviously because that informs
a lot of how we're going to do it
and then choose hosts so I find this to
be really important I actually did not
record a single episode of wiring system
in until I found a co-host
luckily Jason was happy enough to to
join me once we figured out fiddling
that work for both of us I don't feel
like don't show my fire system it would
be successful if you're doing something
like an interview show maybe you can do
that because you've always got a partner
that is the person you're interviewing
right so you have a banter
not to say that two or three people can
interview a person but if you get too
many people then that could just simply
play out so I always use the example
they've got a bunch of hosts that rotate
in and out and they do interviews with
sometimes just with Paul or with one or
two people or sometimes they do it with
three or four people and sometimes it
gets really chaotic hard to follow and
sometimes it's really well put together
and he's been doing this forever he's
got a whole series of shows so just make
sure your hosts are dependable or at
least that you have enough posts that
you can always get at least one from
around two we have skipped episodes of
our system in because I couldn't get
hosts to show up on a given night and
it's fine life happens I hate missing
shows but whatever I'd rather have at
least one co-host than just me sit in
front of Mike because I think it's just
I don't know I don't think I would and
importantly make sure you have a rapport
with your photos this is just a quick
screen grab from one of our we record
live on YouTube so people can watch us
live when we're recording and this is
just a quick screenshot from one of our
sections you can see everybody's smiling
everybody's animated and I think that's
really important you have dry Cocodrie
show right so folks that I co-host with
are people I've known for years right we
carpool for a long time like before we
ever decided to make a show like this so
we've had a lot of conversations I knew
that we could chat together and even we
that means tips that are just people
that I consider friends not just I think
that's important otherwise you could end
up with just a bunch of arguments on
your show what you could end up with a
dry show or a show where things don't
that could be things that we do
sometimes there are things we disagree
on so you know that's that's fine so now
you've got the checklist you've got a
unique topic you've agonized over months
you've got before I dig that medium and
you've got a host or hostess I should
say so and this is the part where things
get a little working right getting all
that stuff together
is relatively I think the next thing
they did was I trying to pick out like a
theme for the show and whatnot but you
don't necessarily have to do that right
off the bat you can just start start
reporting take the microphone you've got
on your you know si tu use respect calls
or the
in your laptop or whatever and just get
on a call with your co-host or get out
of all the people you're interviewing
you just start recording
I don't care yet about the quality I
don't care if you've got syndication and
I Tunes and all the other places where
people get bypassed
I don't care if you even then know you
have an audience unit just start
recording get it out there let people
know that you've got a show let people
start listening to your show the biggest
thing that I've seen when people want to
start a project show or anything this is
your first show the first time you're
trying to set something up first time
you're trying to record something you
may not have expensive equipment right
just start recording something when when
we started I insisted in well talk a
little more about how to get recording
done when we start writing system and I
couldn't figure out how to get a
recording just just to like we were
going to use hangouts right I couldn't
figure out how to get the audio out of
hangouts on my machine so some so this
is the first video that I made for my
youtube channel
it's literally be sitting in my dining
room table recording me myself working
with some paracord on the camera on my
tablet okay and I can't play because we
didn't arrange sound basically I'm not
in frame you can't see my whole face so
the whole point was to show the paracord
but whatever Lori it's bad quality it's
just not a great not a great video
do you want to see if you look at what
you can channel it's one of the oldest
videos another video that I did was I
had bought this like portable little
tire changer nothing's ever change the
tire I don't just mean change a tire off
your car I mean like actually unseated
the tire from the rim normally fail to
do well I had this idea that I was gonna
try to mount my own tires for my team
and I bought from Harbor Freight which
everyone who's ever worked with like
cheap tools will know what I'm talking
about Harbor Freight they sell anywhere
from like cheap crap to like decent
tools for a good price and you never
know what you're gonna get to the body
so I got this cheap $20.00 manual
portable tire changer which is basically
like a post that stands this high and
has a flat surface to put a wheel on
it's got this big break you can unseat a
tire and receive a fire and I thought
I'm gonna record myself learn how to use
this thing and I'm gonna maybe you can
video out of it and that's going to go I
mean not agree I think I recorded on the
same talent I recorded dishonours
drive the sound isn't grades it was a
really long video which people think you
shouldn't really do on YouTube so I put
it down I was using open source tools
[Music]
and I didn't know what I was doing
not just recording for but using the
Danes fire truth I think one tire and
then I recorded the second one it's like
make myself sound terrible but I'll just
say that it's not a great example of how
to use this thing
it is the top viewed video on my channel
right people either love it or hate it
and they all talk about it there's
hundreds of comments you can tell me
what a moron I am or the sort of viewers
you're going to get but the point is I
didn't agonize over getting a 4k video
camera before I recorded my first video
I just made the day and put it out so
that means pretty well into how the heck
did we start recording and of course
this depends on a couple things one
whether you're doing an audio show - how
many you post you're gonna - so in case
of an audio show like I was hit again
before getting yourselves all on a Skype
call or a Hangouts fall or whatever and
doing a show is relatively easy just
make some time so I'm talking about
something recording it I found to be
less than two of them or at least two
years ago when we were doing this free
services generally didn't offer a way
for us to alcohol and then quickly
download a recording I know some do that
now
but at the time like Skype for example
there were these third-party tools you
could use to record Skype calls which
seems kind of hokey and I've heard from
other Photoshop other podcast hosts that
it was here it didn't work well or
worked well but it paid for it to get it
to work well or whatever and we were
trying to get this started with little
or no money out of pocket so what we
ended up doing if anybody's familiar
with the defensive Security podcast
though I had channel with durability
years ago aware because oh I
to put the guy and he just recently
started him slack channel so I went out
on a limb and I just asked him you know
I want to start a podcast how would you
recommend that report and he suggested
this looking back at it now I don't know
how he ever survived this way he
suggested this idea where Jason and I
both get on a fall
fire up audacity or something on your
laptop because your speaker's your
microphone goes into your laptop again
sort of thing and just record yourself
local right because that will record
your input but it doesn't record what's
coming back out of the call right the
trick is you have to get yourself
synchronizers right so I'd be recording
me he'd be recording him and to get the
conversation synchronized again we did
this like weird thing where we would
count down from five he would go five I
before you go three here I go back
before and then after the show was over
I have to upload that to me which would
take half an hour and then I'd have to
stitch this together and once it sticks
together I have to edit out any mistakes
I thought we made and have to put in
intro music I'd have to put in any
transition music we used which I don't
think there were at the time outro music
you know it ended up being in to our
production after the show's over just to
get the show back up so we're pretty
quickly upgrade is we did and our first
two examples I just gave you when I
finally decided like I'm going to make a
thing out of this channel I used just a
handheld camera that we had already
didn't even do 720p
thirty years old found in the Attic no
sound gear just you know set it up in
the garage start doing a thing again
that I've also improved
right so this thing I sort of already
covered started as kind of a repeat
slide but basically you get yourself a
mite of some sort could be the internal
life of your life good evening I'd said
we started for our mics let's see I had
a gaming headset from just the plain old
gaming headset that was decent quality
and I think Jason was using the
Bluetooth headset it was a couple years
old and you could tell the audio quality
difference we actually had listeners
write in and say like you sound great
but Jason sounds terrible
I don't know what's up but you should
improve this and that was like a running
gag for a while and it was because of
the Bluetooth mic
I'm sure there's my quality bluetooth
mics out there but for whatever reason
the one he had and I have the same one I
might even use it because I noticed this
before I started recording it sort of
digitizes your voice and when you have
the analog like I was using compared to
his digitized voice you can tell the
difference you could absolutely
we were both using digitized mics
probably wouldn't have been as
noticeable but I was like plain old RCA
jack analog of it just a little bit
[Music]
recording conversations I started
already
internet like I said this wasn't
straightforward I thought it would be
easy I thought it'd be like
all and there must be some way to record
it can I just hit the record button on
my laptop and get it all well doesn't
work that way we ended up once we
decided to do live shows we ended up
using hangouts on air which is basically
how you do YouTube live so iron system
has its own YouTube channel and all we
use it for is to do the watch filigree
and like I said I'm sure those services
out there that all you record your balls
look into that if you're going to start
show and you don't want to go through
the craziness that just described with
the two recordings see if you can find a
play you see if you find a service that
will let you just record the audio and
output it I'm sure someone exists but
recording videos like I said just start
with what you've got I mean I know a lot
of youtubers that are very successful
now we started by reporting on their
iPhone just get a video as best you can
stabilize it somehow so it's not all
taking weird and just do the best you
can with what you've got and start
producing videos and if your channel
catches on and you start making money or
you get a sponsor or whatever you can
upgrade later I still don't have a
really good camera equipment for my my
cheap stuff I actually use my smartphone
sometimes I have a couple GoPros
[Music]
or - but I've got a couple GoPros that I
can use for different angles GoPros are
great for this kind of thing at least
for that setting because they're durable
in there they have the nice wide views
whether or not some people don't like
the fisheye and then once you've got
your show established you've got some
listeners maybe you have they then start
thinking about what to improve and are
things the first thing with the mics so
we wanted to get Jason a better mic so
he ended up buying himself the same mic
that I had eventually purchased myself
which was my does USB or it does XLR so
you must be your edited computer works
just like any other microphone and it's
good to go I ended up putting in a mixer
and then I have an input for a tablet to
do like a sound board on and then I
bought a voice recorder that the whole
shebang outputs do so the whole show
gets reported it's recorded out of the
mixer right so my mic comes and so on
XLR into the XLR as those three or four
from Mike's you see like professionals
using that goes into the mixer the
output from my PC goes into the mixer
output from the mixer goes back into the
pcs this gets confusing right so the
people on this on the hangouts call to
hear me speak because my mic goes into
the mixer not the PC the point is the
mixture gives you the control to do that
kind of stuff right I can set it up so
that the input from my PC it's out to
the sound recorder but doesn't go back
to the Hangouts call because that would
cause an echo for all of people all
right so that's not a good thing
especially for the
so again that works out really well in
the little sound recorder is literally
like it's like the size of this thing
and I just plug the output of the mixer
into the recorder and then if I want to
take that on the road like come out of
conference and I want to do an interview
with somebody I can just take the sound
recorder with me
I can even plug in an external mic if I
really wanted to and I can get the same
quality recording just right there in my
hand and like I said about the cameras
in the car I'm still not up to 4k
cameras and whatnot for my cheap stuff
because cameras are expensive just I'd
really like one for lots of things not
just my YouTube endeavors just a report
like with you know so yeah I got a
couple little probes to get angles
hosting was not as difficult for me as
it might be for some people because so
it really wasn't that hard I ever had a
website stood up it was running on
Drupal which was not as easy as you
might think
Drupal is Drupal is a great platform but
it's really free form and it's not as
easy to use as something like WordPress
I was able to make it hosts the podcast
it was a lot of work and I needed a lot
of knowledge of how Drupal did things to
really make it work the way I wanted it
to so I would recommend unless you've
already got a Drupal site set up you
promo
for hosting your podcast and as much bad
press as WordPress gets it works you
just make essentially a blog entry and
attach an audio file to it and your
podcast is published simple as that
it already has built-in RSS feeds which
I'll talk a little more the RSS feeds
getting it syndicated and whatnot which
I'll talk a little more about that's
like iTunes all iTunes and Google Play
stitcher they all want a certain format
to your RSS feed Google has a service
called feed burner which if you've ever
subscribed to a podcast you probably use
the fee for every URL to do it if you've
done it into RSS feed feed burner cleans
that all up adds your logo art to it and
all the metadata that all of these
various consumption places one and then
publishes that back out for you even
keep some metrics for you so that's
that's handy and WordPress and peeper
just work really well together
so if you don't have a site already
hosted use I would say to WordPress and
you can pay someone to run WordPress for
you if you don't want to be a web
administrator just go someplace that
hosts WordPress you can find them all
over the place for like $5
right so I've already sort of covered
this this is almost a duplicate but
basically almost artist says let's
Bieber clean it up for you and then you
can syndicate that which is something
professional services for podcast those
I haven't gotten here yet but I know
some podcasts that have if you want to
avoid all that and you just want to
spend about 80 bucks a month on letting
a professional host the web host your
podcast for you you can do that with
places like listen and I think there's a
couple others but you pay them they give
you a website to host your shoutouts and
they give you media hosting for your
your audio files they give you metrics
you can pay a little extra and they'll
make you like a mobile app for your
podcast like they have all kinds of
these extra value-added services that
you don't have to worry about if all you
want to do is record and publish right
so lips is one of them I haven't looked
into a lot of them because we're just
not there yet
what we do is we host on WordPress and
then add a couple complaints about the
download speeds for our shows because it
was hosted on a server in my basement we
ended up putting a mother with Amazon s3
bucket and then from the podcast from
the WordPress site I link to the show on
the s3 buckets so when people download
the show it comes right from Amazon it's
super fast that of course lost money
we're spending like 30 bucks a month
right now on hosting our shows that goes
up a little every month obviously
because you're paying for bandwidth
you're paying for storage once that gets
closer to 80 90 bucks a month I'm
probably just going to throw it and
loosen because
I don't know if we're going to get there
anytime soon but when we do I think
that's forwarding so there is value in
spending that money as long as you're
not trying to do this all the super
Krete which is how we started I existed
because I do everything
the hosts think this one's not quite as
mysterious if you're going to host video
just use one of the platforms that
exists there's YouTube there's you know
I've seen a lot of contacts showing up
with Twitter I don't know what the
attraction is to twitch but a lot of
especially live shows are showing up
because these people are gamers they
like twitch because it's the platform
they used to stream gaming and they just
think all the contests or if it's really
that one's better for it than YouTube is
I can say that YouTube is convenient but
you're their product like any other
Google property getting money under
YouTube videos like in the case of my
youtube channel not firing system and
because iron system and I don't expect
to make money from my channel was
modified for a short time and then you
can change the game they change there
for me which was really annoying but
they're happy to show ads in your video
and they're happy to collect the money
for those ads and until you hit their
thresholds which are now really hard to
get for small channels you don't you see
those two you thought right once you get
their thresholds you see like fractions
of a dime so I always whenever I run
into someone who's like oh yeah you
really need to channel I want to be like
a good youtuber my first response is
nobody makes money on YouTube because
yes people make money on YouTube but
this many people make money
the people that are famous Logan Paul
and whoever else they're making money on
YouTube because they're this big right
little guy just don't make anything like
you do so if you're trying to pick a
platform because of its monetization
YouTube might not be a great choice now
we can talk a little more about how to
augment that with advertisers or
whatever in syndication I've already
hinted at this if you run the podcast
you're gonna want to get it on all of
the podcast platforms the ones that we
do for our system in our iTunes because
sorry a podcast a brand because
everybody if you have a podcast on
iTunes right there like the podcasting
and then stitcher is all about podcasts
some people have never heard of stitcher
some people have some people that's the
only place they go for shows and if
they're not most it true they don't
listen to them you know whatever so you
want to be on there too and then Google
Play podcasts I think just because it
seemed like a good idea I don't know
it's there and that's all from that RSS
feed ISTEP its own deeper every single
one of them I point to the feed burner
URL and they just do their thing there's
almost no work every now and you want to
check in and see if you got any reviews
or whatever but as far as getting the
show listed once you get it accepted and
they are happy with your URL with your
RSS URL it just works
and this is important I think especially
with a YouTube channel so imagine that
you're watching cable TV and there's a
show you watch every week on Tuesday
night you're going to tune in every
Tuesday night at 8 p.m. to watch it now
I'm going back to the days when
on-demand wasn't as easy as it is or you
didn't have a DVR right people have just
come to expect that from any content
they consume so if you're going to make
a show live you're going to want to do
it at the same time roughly if you have
to you have trouble with a certain night
don't get too stressed out you know so
last week two weeks ago I think it was
we were supposed to record irons
discipline and stuff and we just
couldn't get the hosts together alright
we'll record Thursday and then Thursday
ok we'll record Friday Friday didn't
work we ended up just a for the show
because that's the way it generally go
you know you've got I thought Wednesday
night picked and if we miss Wednesday
night probably there's a 50/50 chance
we're gonna record it later in the week
generally it just doesn't happen but
people are going to want consistency out
of your show so if I'm going to go
subscribe to the new podcast if they got
one show listed there and it was from
two years ago I might not even bother
subscribing because they don't appear to
be consistent they don't appear to have
a lot of content to listen to maybe that
one show is awesome in all this into it
but if they've got two dozen shows that
are consistent over the course of
several months or weeks or whatever I'm
going to be more likely to watch them
listen
just because you know it's just because
it shows that they're actually there to
produce something with a YouTube channel
that's even more important because the
more consistency you show on a YouTube
channel the more likely YouTube is to
recommend a channel to people and this
all comes down to Google's mysterious
algorithm you'll hear youtubers talk
about the algorithm as though it's like
this god they have to appease but
basically what it really comes down to
is if you want your videos to show up in
YouTube's search or if you want to show
up in that little suggested YouTube
viewers or suggested videos when you're
watching a video you need to have your
channel to fit a certain mold it's got
to have content it's got to be
consistent it's got to have a lot of
viewers and videos have to have a lot of
likes people have to be commenting on
your videos you have to make it look
like you're engaged otherwise YouTube
ignores you when you know one sees your
videos no one sees your videos you know
can subscribe if you don't get
subscribers you don't get money out of
your channel so it's it's annoying to
have to deal with all these weird
constraints when all you really want to
do is make content and put it out there
but if you don't do it you don't get
what you want out of your your channel
if you've got a channel and you're
producing content I'm assuming you want
people see it otherwise why would you be
doing right so it's unfortunate and
there are probably hundreds of YouTube
channels that just talk about how to be
successful what you do so there are
people that sell services that they'll
come in and help you build your YouTube
channel so it pieces it's kind of and
that comes down to make money personally
I don't love what I'm listening to
and they have to take a break for ads
but I now I understand why they do
because it's your time it's costing
money to run the show you're buying
equipment or you're paying for hosting
or whatever some people can afford that
you play that out of pocket and but it's
really nice to make a little bit of an
income on that so that you can really
produce the best show that you can
produce right the sort of stuff I'd be
doing both for hiring system and for my
ID stuff a whole different game right
cuz I'd actually have income to put back
into the channel it's just like running
a business except a much smaller scale
right that's business you've got a lot
for it so yeah a few ways that you can
make them without advertisements in
built-in monetization like I already
talked about with whatever platform
you're on that's mainly something like
YouTube video and I think twitch does
something with subscribers you subscribe
to a channel is actually a monetary
component on that but patreon is what
I've been using for both of my channels
my teeth channel has a zero matrix
nobody's giving me any way to do what I
do I wish I insisted minting sort of
ebbs and flows we were up to like 30
bucks a month we were getting out of it
that's dropped off because people are
essentially donating to you and unless
they're seeing a lot of value there
you know the drop off so it's gone up
and down if we're like 10 bucks a month
so but that's one way to do it I know
some successful podcasts make a couple
hundred bucks a month on patreon and
that would be plenty of podcast
so anyway that's most of all I got if
you have any questions you know feel
free this is me where you can find me so
I haven't really approached that because
we've made so little I think if if you
were making a decent amount again you
have to report that but I can't say I'm
a tax expert but I can say that if we
were making the show I'd probably be
recording it to my like I separated so
little it's more like pocket change
so with the mixer and everything
Podcast night is about three hours for
me in four hours right we'll start
around like 6:30 or so and all the posts
have to get together and then we're
generally live by like 7:00 or 7:15 and
then we record for anywhere from an hour
and a half to two hours and then maybe
an hour after that I'm editing because
the output from the mixer is almost
ready to go basically got the audio a
little bit handed out stuff that was
obvious mistakes or gaps or like you
know we made a mistake that there was
you know something said that should have
been or whatever the YouTube the video
we leave public afterward however we
recorded it it stays up there unless
somebody makes a really big mistake
which we only had it once one of the
guys now coats was on and he said
something about another person that he
knows about how they were doing a thing
technology wise and after the show he's
like you know I don't want to be leave
it in but can you edit this one little
piece out because I think that was data
that was something that they wouldn't
want to publish so in that case I went
by he published the live stream
downloaded in which you to lets you do
once you've recorded it and it did that
piece out with a video editing app and
Ryeowook and I otherwise
make certain all that stuff because
everything just comes out of the mixer
sure so I started with some generally a
Linux guy even though I'm running this
MacBook I started with an application
called kdenlive which is a KDE open
source video editing app and the bursts
okay the UI was kind of horrible and
crashed every now and then I'd lose the
work I was working on so I started
looking for a different one I upgraded
to another one called Lightworks which
is a little more popular you can
actually pay for this one if there's a
free version that'll do only up to like
720p ok that worked pretty well that
also runs on Linux I would have stuck
with it but I did run into a couple
issues with it the UI still wasn't great
this is the sort of you'll you'll notice
a trend when it's a software that you
can get for free it's generally not as
intuitive
eventually I realized that through work
I had access to Adobe's suite of
applications and I started gives me
premier I checked the work first to make
sure it was ok I'm all just on your work
laptop go ahead Adobe Premiere is night
and day different than any of the tools
that I use I'm not saying you should
rush out and spend all the money on W
camara but if you have the means do it I
also use Adobe Audition now for the
podcast Saturday which isn't quite as 90
day audacity was a pretty good app
yeah what's your listener base how many
people view what do you like men rich is
a part thinker I'm not good at this sort
of thing I can tell you that we have
what could be thousands of people
downloading the show like that's just
from the metrics that I get out of the
vestry sort of other service called x3
stack which just basically gets you like
weblog analytic analytic just out of
your s3 bucket I don't know if those are
box I don't know we really have
thousands and thousands of listeners it
doesn't feel that way because we don't
get a lot of feedback from people I do
say we have a decently strong listener
base and we have people tune into our
YouTube channels and whatnot are the
YouTube channel to watch it live which
makes me feel like people are really
listening and they're tuning in to
really see us do this stuff I can say
that on the YouTube channel after the
live broadcast is done almost no one
goes back and watches the videos maybe
it's because the channel too small maybe
it's because I don't attack them well I
don't know but people are just so yeah I
can say that we have listeners we have
more than one or two but I trouble
believe it to be a thousand even though
that's what the statistics for miss for
yourself so that's another thing that
something like lips in would help with
they put the work into getting
meaningful statistics
I want to make scientists sounds
reportable the mixture of the chatter
for ya you say how I wanna be I'm asking
about my guitarist concentrated I want
to say that the mic the mixer and the
audio reporter might've Romney if I had
bought them all the same job I've been
like 300 bucks
the mixer was under 100 bucks if I
remember correctly the mic was like the
sound recorder believe it or not was
like Tanner's the most expensive and all
the cables to connect everything buy the
coffee out of the 30 bucks or so so yeah
it's not terribly expensive it was
enough that I had to think about