the second day
besides Dell my name is Joe Klein if
you're here for anything besides fast
tracking your happiness I was here the
career watching slow road so I'm part of
the community for years I've been
mentoring and helping others get through
this particular process
mostly because I've played everything
from a firewall guy to who achieve
security officer several times chief
information you know I basically played
our roles and I've basically been doing
this and give back to the community so
others can get into this career
successfully and grow into whatever you
want to do okay so yes I'm affiliated
with mitre corporation and this is my
position this is my opinion this is my
employment
so this look that first thing we're
going to talk about is understanding the
job process a lot of people tell you
that I play both sides of this process
and disturbs me using it so this will
simplify the process of coming on board
and be able to create relationship and
set yourself up to really succeed we'll
talk about ways to think about how to
manage your career from the time you get
a job you want to basically leave the
jobs into a career something that you
can go to some goal that you can say I
want to be them someday or also
now there are places that you can't find
Cyrus appear to jump reserved places you
can find a lot of jobs but it's based on
a role of what you want to become and
where you are today so you can find the
best places importance of mentorship and
then a bunch of resources which I'm
going to take some time you go through
these resources because I think that
they're so critical nobody puts them in
the same place so cybersecurity so you
have so you have an organization over
here and I'm somebody with a job title
this job title maybe the manager that
you're gonna report to this may be an HR
person it may be some VP that has no
idea of what your activity is going to
be what you're tasked what you're going
to be performing is going to be so
that's bent over here that's why some
job titles you you basically have job
experience education training
certification and special so on their
side they have to define the
responsibilities for a job they're
looking for they have a set of
expectations and they're trying to meet
up those expectations sometimes those
expectations are pretty outrageous
so does a my right go the go programming
language the pro-growth
the go programming language has only
been around
six years for those that are interested
most people just started recently I have
seen resumes or job requests to say I
want somebody with 10 years of gold
experience okay this is the kind of
expectations that these guys have we
have to understand and help bring in
what they need
second thing is they're looking for two
types of jobs for you and you want to
position yourself as the strategic not
active tactical many times is there
hoping that you're the cog that fits
into this machine and okay but you want
as you want strategic strategic will
give you they have future plans for you
then you're hired on to do this project
for the next year six months two years
but they have a plan for you to actually
drive you and help you succeed your
career not just the job when you're
going to get a resume which I hope you
have one you've had a professional word
friend and cybersecurity review and help
polish I saw one no right there okay so
there's a there's a process you also
want to have a bunch of interview
questions why coming from the side we're
on the hiring manager and I'm asking all
the questions and I'm just about to say
so do you have any questions and I get
it doesn't work okay have some questions
engage we talk about how to frame that
particular right so this is what this is
the gap we're trying to get past so the
job manager again we talked we spoke
that
this may or may not have any idea what
this role is especially if it's cold
they may not have any idea how to frame
your role if it's an existing role
they'll typically take the other
person's resume and oh yo yo yo that's
it that's it okay so there's again
there's some expectations that don't
work so what they'll do is they'll break
down two tasks because they're hiring to
accomplish specific things I want you to
manage the firewall on a successful way
make sure it's logged I want you to look
at the IDS when you're doing fantastic I
want you to win every single time you do
a pen test whatever that may be and then
by the way rate the report so they're
going to find this based on tasks so
this will take some time again a lot of
times they don't have the experience on
how framework we're talk about that
because actually hiring they can help
you through this process to help you
know fill those they tasks from a
strategic and tactical standpoint tasks
can be learned in from a notate T
standpoint in less than 90 days if you
click with the individual and you
identify what those are you can actually
say look I don't know that today but
with some help like to do this in 90
days or right now before you start doing
the job hunting maybe you're in school
may you consider picking up some of the
classes and some of the actual
techniques you should only go to a for
90 days a few hours a week maybe lots
hours with me what
you gotta get off the Xbox for a while
so recognize this becomes real important
the more of these you have and by the
way you know one of these are that a lot
of people see as their strategic when
you're here we have a lot of people that
want to be in the cybersecurity business
but if you guys are you anyway but it's
it's real important you include that on
your resume that you're attending
community events via meetups on a
monthly basis whatever it is next thing
is the hard part for them they don't
have to figure out for each task based
on usually somebody else's resume or
some general idea they have what's the
knowledge skill and ability that you
need to accomplish these tasks and as
you can see that there are some
abilities across everything there's some
abilities that only only support one tax
okay and what they typically do or
should is create questionnaire to help
them understand where you fit here a lot
of times people will fake this also
based on your time you spend here and
here you have the ability here to start
discussing so if you guys have bonuses
or retraining the support additional
training what is your training process
and I go to conferences you know what is
that and the candidates need to will
have other things that you can't learn
in 90 days if you're in town and
sophomore freshman and junior this might
be a chance for you to spend the time
and get some of those longer-term
techniques and learning behind you
so the next thing haha
once you go through this whole process
recognize better make sure that your
training certifications past employment
everything is straight it saves the
process this is the process that these
guys gave it takes forever because I
have to send it through a background
check of some sort I have to do they
have to send it through other people to
validate this can take a week by two
weeks depending on some times a month ok
so if you have all this straight it
simplifies the whole process so the goal
really is sorry the goal really is to
fill this gap okay
straightforward anybody ever seen
anything like this this is really what
we see on both sides and this is one of
the problems from the cycle times
business and trying to hire this is the
one of the cycle time improvements you
look at is how now if you are like
recruiting okay for recruiting there is
a document to a tool that's free that
will allow you to help fill in the tasks
and knowledge simplify this process okay
it was created by lots of different
people and update multiple times there
we go
so the big check boxes for your homework
match the job with the experience figure
out if that experience and the job can
be done in 90 days where it's going to
take a lot longer what does that mean is
sit down you look at some YouTube videos
you do some reading you figure out how
much you set realistic expectations on
how you fit into that particular job it
also perhaps you for now includes
education training and certifications we
have a panel discussion after this on
discussing some ideas around here but I
won't go into that set of special
circumstances how many of you have a
professional blog okay you should have a
professional blog it should include I
went to be sides and here's some notes
so I took at these sides they're
important but be songs here's a
conference that I went to here's a book
that I read and here's my
it doesn't have to be long it can be 115
500 words it can be a reference to some
other persons materials okay keep the
Fred professional blog next thing
Lucas LinkedIn take that blog entry cut
and paste it to LinkedIn so people that
are looking for people like you will see
it on LinkedIn click on and actually
start discussions does anybody brake
software and how to get say my brakes
offer okay you have a github repository
yeah
how to get your club repository that's
again an important part anybody that
doesn't brake software or lots of you
okay take documents that you created
that can be open to the public and put
those documents on get up get up
not just for software it's also for
documents matter of fact if you look
around you'll see people that post their
standards documents up there to get
opinions from other folks okay
get yourself and get home these are free
okay twitter twitter now okay this is
this is the twitter handle not you had
when you were a kid or teenager or maybe
in college this is your professional
twitter by the way please make sure you
also have a professional Facebook that
other one has to go away professional
email like teensy-weensy crazy drinking
guy you know that's not a real good
email address to have
that's funny okay so please have a
professional email address this this
simplifies this whole process okay did
you attend any security groups and
conferences so which ones and where how
often you can be presenters you know
have that information with you
can you volunteer so how many people
have volunteer or done internship okay
volunteer okay volunteer at a security
conference why because you get to meet
the most amazing people you get to meet
the speakers you get to sickness need to
speak your presentations and ask them
questions so you get to go have lunch or
dinner or breakfast with them to ask ask
questions oh okay this community is very
giving we want more people in this
community we want amazing people to help
us solve it from a big big big tall okay
so please attend those let's see
volunteer also how many people have a
home lab how many people and I have
links to this for exercises you can use
to become better in forensics networking
system admin all the other basic
features
that it costs you nothing you just have
to spend the time to go through the
process okay
and in recommendation for friends we
have it again we're a pretty open
community we're trying to bring people
in talk to people at the at this
community and say hey I'm looking for
position this is what I'm looking for
very few people turn you down okay
maybe they'll require so about the
company we must think called open source
intelligence this has they might heard
of it okay guess what you get to get
really good at this because you want to
know about the company what do they sell
what do they do they do services do they
any product what other products are
there big products little products who's
their customer when you walk in and you
know the person you're sitting across
from about what their business is
they're far more excited than saying I'm
a security guy and I'm here to help you
okay
versus hey I understand you can
transportation you have these kind of
threats based on maybe trucking or
whatever can you talk to me about that
so I understand what your environment is
it becomes the two-way discussion and
discussion changes to go I'm fine with
the industry size locations locations
are important if you want to live
someplace else they may have their data
center and aspirin Virginia versus here
or they may have their it may give you a
chance to work at home in some cases so
those kind of things read their blogs
what's important to their management
right now what's their goal what's their
vision newsfeeds before you go in for
two or three days watch their news maybe
same can bring that up as a conversation
piece just start the conversation so
what is it about well also for companies
if you know someone they are great if
you don't ask the community I bet you
somebody will know somebody that works
in security at that content okay only
makes sense
we're a big community I mean our our big
get-together is you know thirty
approximately thirty thousand in here
best friends called that okay so there's
a lot of really good people plus in this
area you have lots of these sides and
other events always thin about five
hundred four hundred three hundred
months what technology do they use go
take a look at their other job requests
are they using Oracle are they using
Microsoft are they using blanks are
using AWS those are the skills that
they're going to ask you for not only on
the resume but everything else lastly
what interview questions do you think
they're going to ask based on all this
knowledge yes Google actually
they here's the 10 questions Google asks
did anybody do that for the company
you're going to work for or maybe the
industry get a heads up this is a recon
exercise and by the way both source
intelligence in this community this is a
skill set that will save you lots of
time and money and effort
accomplishments ok so the job is
something you simply earn money for a
career is something to connect your
employment opportunities together a job
has a minimal impact on your future so
you're just looking for a job
that's a one-shot thing but with a
career wise you experience a fuel
wherever you want to go in your future
so that's the graphical representation
of my career
ok yes I took a lot of experience right
so I like then and I've worked for
people like people that created robots
for Disney I've done electronics I've
programmed for just all kind of things
that work for a banking company they
does ATMs and States and all kind of
things like that and I've worked for
medical companies I've worked for a walk
salting the only company
so work for government contractors who
have gone through a whole plethora of
crazy experiences with this each one of
them have different expectations so my
career was going to some school learning
learning learning learning taking
classes taking classes continuing
certification continuously move and
understand what's going on by the way
how fast does knowledge about this
technology change as a haploid certify
every three okay think about that you
know if you were a physician and the
long moves on a regular basis that
wouldn't make things really difficult
wouldn't it okay
this is why it's called the hardest
career most intellectually challenging
career on earth right now okay you're
the people can help
so let's talk about the meniscus
National Institute of Standards and
Technology out of the Department of
Commerce takes information from the
community not only the government
community but community at large to
determine when there's gaps in the
problems one of the problems they
identified was the ability for to
educate workforce and the brain
workforce in this particular career so
they worked on something called the
national initiative for cybersecurity
education workforce framework just like
any very good government document it has
a really great things references or
technology partners employers and things
like that the more important part is
take a look at the category of
specialties work roles and everything
else okay
the recruiting stuff okay great
bring your eyes to is this right here
can you see that okay we have many major
roles when I started the job was
something's matter with their computer
or marinara
then it became I think maybe something's
really wrong with our computer could it
be one of those curse and then it became
hey I think somebody's attacking their
application then it became wait a second
our business applications being taken
down it must be a security issue
can you go fix that okay our career then
career this domain we changed our
relationship with the business people
and with the people running the systems
so these are the major two major titles
again when I would started there was one
major title guy that fixes stuff okay
now we have all these major categories
if we go down a little bit further we've
a breakout of each thing perception okay
so for security provision error ready
maybe a risk manager here's what your
role is or oversight valuations or
documentation validation does that make
more sense to be able to go through
something like this to figure out what
matches you versus just going through a
resumes so I would suggest taking some
time looking through this yes you may
have to have a lot of these your choice
but this will help a lot and also
recognize in the and most domains they
say junior senior experts they use lots
of terms for this documentation here's a
framework
any federal business or any government
business this will describe to them what
happened okay back to the show
so it is recognized is this we didn't
have a standard lexicon there are some
jobs that have 85 different names in the
field that's pretty crazy we didn't have
any critical analysis on where do people
come from in this field the people that
were most successful
where did they start and also you know
how about analysis so they basically
created a framework to define this so
that we have capable workforce you're
the workforce workforce here are some of
the ideas again the major
categorizations look at us
33 specialties that's pretty amazing 52
work ropes okay and then within the
corporate world there may be slight
variations matter of fact if you're
doing forensics you may be a forensics
person that does computers you may be a
friend's each person who does dead boxes
or hard drives or phones or IOT devices
that's actually in these major
categories okay so the next thing to
look at is looking for specialty areas
appearing in digital forensics there you
go leadership management project
management creating education defense
analysis right there risk management all
that
okay so let's try an experiment
okay so I have a leak the bottom that
goes to this can anybody see this okay
so can i okay okay
so basically these categories analysis
operating collecting an operating
investigating whatever what's
interesting you to you okay which
category is important for you basically
cyber defense analysis defensive
structures support in response so here's
a set of related classes or build here
is the ability to remember we talked
about the abilities from looking for
here's the general abilities or no pain
trace rel and it's lookup we're there
okay
how about your knowledge okay
[Music]
and just cycle through so this is what
they call capabilities indicator I'm
going to give you a capability indicator
I prefer but what the capability in air
is okay I'm how to do pain I know how to
use the command line on painting you
other two things I know how to use pain
and I can look at Wireshark and see if
there's any variations I can write pink
okay that's the for loop that's the four
levels that you need to consider when
you're going through your understanding
of any of these tasks rolls and they
have their their own equivalent here is
they like including that you must have a
PhD and things like that because the
majority did this was our academics so
not even playing just reality
so I'm going to suggest that go to this
link do some research you may find out
you have a lot of knowledge already
because you've been doing on teeth okay
kind of cool and then it gives you a gap
on what you need so the big picture
based on analysis of everybody that's in
the field today and exited already these
are the roles the major roles that
people have and a lot of times they did
that because maybe they were doing
biological science of some sort and they
had to learn how to do a database to do
their to do their program so they had to
learn how to be lighty and their
database in any way and hey are like the
cybersecurity thing and they slipped
into it for historians that how to do
lots of searches and how to use
analytics and had to go through that
particular process so this is the
majority of major roles that people
start from here when here in the IT
here's the next level the major roles
the next level for mid-level and the
advanced example of so say one of your
systems engineer there's the optimal
path through through your roles
I like that service to me the consultant
is match to nothing
you are actually what I've been waiting
for I left my phone to see how many
people were picking on me and watching
it I people at home so this is an
example you see system engineer Maps to
please and say you want to become a pen
tester so you probably want to become
incident handling so you have an idea of
what type of attacks are being performed
you can learn about those attacks and
death and then become a penetration
tester and then go into security
architecture as an example so that you
can defend against these guys which by
the way really upsets it when you use
their techniques experience okay the
other thing is you want to map to how
many job openings for you my general
tasks what else sound effects thank you
also contact Amin job titles that you'll
see in the commercial world education
top certification skill level
requirements and
old skills that you want to basically
start picking up one okay so that warm
list is consolidated into this
particular love so somebody and
networking say you do networking
okay so networking 245 you want to go
from here we go
there's the optimal path for that down
below starter security specialists
average throughout the country here's
how many jobs are available job openings
right now here's the title should be
looking for in maintenance we call or in
one of the major categories of 17
categories its operations maintenance or
prevention so you could actually fall
within two of those major categories
here's the make up of education
certifications and other things you
definitely okay you see how you can use
this to figure out and understand how to
go through this process
okay so anybody else any programmers
okay I knew you were going to say sorry
security architect right here okay so
from sabe security architect here's the
things to get there here's the things to
get there okay
so cyber security architect basically
one drive through either pentesting and
when drive through these capabilities
through fantastic and then there's your
cyber security architect by the way your
cyber security architect that the
problem salary type number of job
openings right now and all the other
items is that beautiful okay so the
other thing we can do is it's really
cool that we have this list of all these
jobs Carmen Sandiego problem where are
the jobs
so fortunately have an interactive okay
so these are the states that have the
jobs except there's one little problem
there are places in those states those
jobs don't exist it's because a metro
area that's actually the highest
possibility of getting a job anyplace
and they're come up here to there we go
right now in your area
that's a job that's basically how many
openings I want to make note of this
there are some decisions you'll make
that you want to move someplace to get a
really good job this area has a very
large peer community so you can actually
learn from peers and things like that
in one of the places I used to live it
was myself and for other people okay
and we were the security guys but we
really didn't have a lot of interaction
you know almost an auditor ones pen test
or things like that this is an idea that
of making that decision also what's the
ratio of supplied workers that usually
allows you the ability it's the average
and within the region here's the titles
that you'll say I'll take a look at this
rattle this is a breakdown of how many
things you want to do as an example say
that you want to become investigator if
you're new and trying to be an
investigator in the middle of Wisconsin
you may find one person or two persons
but if you go to here you may say off
the welfare if the 41 investigators
forensics people things like that that
is open jobs those are opportunities for
another match I want to mention is
certifications red is the holders if
you're going for CSP so it's a half step
so you don't have to sit for this crazy
certification that's extremely hard for
a lot of people okay some of you guys
get to go to boot camps things like that
I had to read the 40-plus books because
they didn't have those things in an
outline an outline outline and stressed
it so it's the test we used to be a
five-hour test you sit down this big
room full of people you have to drive
you know I got it all wrong so I spend
another round looking through everything
and I did well I passed but just like
they do certifications you have to
actually match what the customer wants
[Music]
see IPP this is yes there are there are
more jobs that actually put that but
this is only reflecting the ones that
have those letters stand correct
there's more than just reading this and
saying oh okay let me go here you
actually have to research some of this
understand hey this is a privacy
I'm glad you say that I can assure you
and look good so so recognize this is
current state you're totally correct
there's a future state of things I was
at a conference just last week talking
about how we going to protect connected
cars how we're going to protect nana's
how we can protect limbs that are
computer controlled how you protect all
this other technology so your Raynal
target privacy is a big issue but
recognize this at least into a baseline
and something to work from
now if you're interviewing you're going
to be asked specific questions questions
are you would have knowledge of the last
something like I know how things look
for the unemployed class I took a class
and I did a forensics of a file I had
experience in I can teach a class from a
bull because I spent the time to write
the write and then you have the next
category which is expertise which is I
altered new material like author
training I written a book or I've helped
write RFC's and standards okay this is
how the community needs to look at this
stuff because not a lot of people also
have different capabilities different
areas
I'm known for my bt6 expertise because
I've been working on for 18 years I'm
working on a book can help do a lot of
these things okay but there are some
things I'm up here at okay so that's
depending on each person what they're
focused on okay geography yeah if
opportunity doesn't knock build the door
yes you will have to move
you may have to fly through your work
and you have to ask that question
especially if you have a family or
prepared having family or whatever I
mean I've been on the road for a while
at one point curve 300 a year it's
really cool until the day that I woke up
then I say my country my for you to
chase this down and spend the time put
it on your calendar and do this Bundys a
holiday put it on your calendar spend
the time good I need more peers in my
community
please be my peers ok yes because a lot
of people want to go today
I just want to include this because I
find the offset of all the
certifications look at how few peers
they are compared to here and look at
how few expertise in each area they are
from here so those areas of the country
that you can be able to learn faster
you're going to have bigger communities
especially early in your career
considering there to go to those later
the career name want to move to
someplace else that has less people you
know and the
you fly someplace or have your company
lived as an example this is an indicia
you must have in the DC area you could
go to one to two security events every
day of the month sometimes three okay
just that many people doorstep many
events there's that many specialists so
mentors mentor is a brain to pick and
here to listen and push you in the right
direction consider finding a mentor
throughout your life throughout your
career it's not your job because your
jobs will pay people to mentor you or
they get trouble because if their mentor
in you which is a whole other
interesting conversation these are the
major roles that I have found that are
most successful and pushing people into
this career and helping them succeed we
take a look at the Challenger they're
going to say you know if you spend a
couple more hours there's a good chance
that don't you let it figure this out I
you know you can do that or hey I
challenge you to get together
presentation today so you can be a
speaker okay you need somebody there
that challenge cheerleader hey coach you
know what is the big picture why you're
doing this I bring you back to your
career
if I go out to Josh I can say Josh I'm
looking for somebody to us soma so do
that okay fine connectors in your life
they're fun because you ask different
questions you may find it Wow I learn
about this to happen to be at the
conference and your connector will be
able to introduce you and stitching down
with that person and by the way it's not
uncommon in these conferences to find a
connector and you're sitting down across
from the person that write wrote that
code rode that exploit rode that blog
entry or rode that book it's a cool you
know what is your next step might be a
generous somebody will sit down if you
go I don't know anything about works
well okay so what do you want to do with
it and obviously spend the time and wait
forward some ideas so that you can then
take that library has big questions
Superstars somebody that basically can
help you focus your goals on how to get
to that next step and lastly a teammate
one of the things I try to do whenever I
join a company is finding team mates
somebody that I can work with that I can
help succeed and they'll help me succeed
it makes all the difference
two or three people community everybody
in this community that is succeeding has
a mentor everybody in this community
that's succeeding has people they mentor
one of my mentors is Vint Cerf the
father of the Internet okay
conversations a couple times a year
really fun but he gives me some insights
that other people can go find these
people in your life and then find people
who can help through the period again we
need a lot of great people in this it
references
haha so here are the national security
training over 3,000 jobs are related and
map specifically to these specialties
they may be sands they may be local
areas yes some of them are going to be
for the some of they're going to be for
free
one note is the dirty little secret
don't don't tell anybody
don't say anything some training wall
here some volunteer work will pay for
your hotel room okay Sam's has a program
Isis word
I stack up okay from those communities
but also DEFCON black at the bigger
conferences you can basically volunteer
not just a great community but they're
gonna pay for your hotel room in a
pretty cool place savings so recognize
now anybody okay other things anybody
looking to know for masters or bachelors
PhD double or quadruple PhD is written
we're going to be living forever so
we're going to need lots of phd's PHP so
remember pay that bad back
this is actually why one actually
mentioned this disparate right here and
this time but you in have been
experience the same time so these are
places that you can do it and not you
know put you in depth till your whole
other things
thank you
there's a really great resource for you
today and they add to this all the time
doing the network federal work a
contractor I word if your state or local
there's a good chance you get access to
this right here okay that's pretty
training that's paid for it and also
other training based on your background
pretty cool communities college does
anybody know
okay here's material here's a whole
course on information assurance that has
been published it's certified okay so
please pass this on the professors in
any University we want more people
trained in this and this is free Oh
including educator course max K through
12 did you notice all the little kids
running around awesome aren't they so
for a long time we forgot about
something when prices of conferences
became anything from from $10 to $25
until they became 250 or 300 dollars or
more black hat is now $2,500 or
something like that that does include
the hotel and everything else we forgot
we lost the whole generation people the
people running around the ones we're
trying to build that community a lot of
us participate and also contribute our
time for that so for educators here's
the classroom things do they have a
cyber competitions for junior high and
senior high which is pretty cool
there's summer camps for velocity of the
things we also have things like DEFCON
we have the roots program besides we
have crypto kids we have
we have the group we have here by the
way this and he sees in my opinion
besides DC are the best for kids they go
away thinking wow I had these all these
new ideas and things like truck in fact
my my brothers are here and they and
they are how many have lab oh sorry I
did that already
so labs these are great references for
Security Letters and why do we do this
have your virtualizations and labs ready
you may end up having the weekend and
you see some article published and you
went redo it you want to try it you want
to see if it works you wouldn't try
these software against it you want a pen
test
no forensics you want to see in taxes
these are these are just a few I have
dozens and dozens of you provide me you
know email resources there are linked an
update your LinkedIn your professional
in this field your IT professional
you're a security professional you want
to get into roles this is a good
reference for getting there your
WordPress get WordPress for free and set
up a professional blog in a few hours
you're done write something make sure
you have a URL you can include on your
resume it's that easy conferences there
are more conferences everything it's
management these are the top 500
conferences and yes these are just the
these sites around the world the b-sides
as of four weeks ago so I have no idea
how many board
and usually these are great okay
and also the lens this link right here
how many people their legs how many how
many people can read the documentation
how many people can can do something
with it
how many people think you can write a
class okay seriously this will help you
all of you to be able to write a class
on okay this is great it's perfect
and honestly as you could say yeah and
honestly how many servers are using Unix
Linux right now most those cloud
services Microsoft and recognized a
couple weeks ago the majority is Red Hat
just got bought her half hour half
provides and Google's of Google's of
dollars with lastly here's some of my
references notice that most of them are
go our hair on fire oh my god we don't
have enough people take a look at this
one right here the minute about the
shortage this is what started me writing
this because it meant that the story the
this is we need to help you understand
how to get the field and what you need
to know concisely we have to help the
people hiring understand the community
wants to be hired and they're passionate
about it otherwise you wouldn't be here
on a Saturday but also that you're
competent and ready to move on to that
and they should use some of the same
terms to come out of this framework okay
a job is something someone else controls
and invest in your future that's what a
job is careers something that you
control your future and both parties and
best they think about that that's what I
hope free because honestly the first one
is April and you go crazy and you leave
jobs the second one is if you want to be
a Mountie of her be active get out there
don't sit just walk play xbox
unless you're hacking the Xbox
okay so I work for a company called
miner the things I've seen in these
logos or burning these things this is
what we do we basically have our mission
driven teams were dedicated for solving
problems here's a list of their code we
make code available all the time so if
anybody wants to try so our community is
basically focused on fixing classes of
problems and then making it public and
yes we also support so these are things
that we're passionate about and that's
why I'm here today
besides the riddle and if you're
interested there's a bunch of jobs and
about bachelor's degree this summer we
have a vast bachelor's master's PhD
you're preparing for that we actually
have a new professionals program which
is specifically for you to get lots of
experience and training
turn ships and all kind of fun things so
feel free contact negative got my email
otherwise do you have any questions more
pictures
[Music]
I stay inspired because I because
something like this
holy crap I could use that or I see
presentation I want to learn something
and honestly we are very in demand and
very common so you know inspire and also
there are several presentations on
people like good enough to actually
accomplish some of these things there
are several presentations cos person
number one is what's called the
community is called Alan's I mean this
community is pretty cool because we have
this kind of stuff we discussed postures
in German you also deal with the
stresses with the job sometimes and how
not to just go off the rails I don't
know any other plus okay
showing up and seeing something funny
like worse that we didn't show up see
out there
there was somebody running around with
so that's what keeps me motivated just
the fun things are anybody else any
questions seriously go back to that
framework it will make it really simple
but some of the baselines are to know
Atlantic's
cleanse is so important matter of fact
make sure you take your vlog your your
computer your laptop partition it at
least if not make it whole Linux VM ware
and with that other operating system
okay use that because that's where where
things are going learning programming
language Python isn't language today
that's easy not to learn that's
impacting all of us in every part and
then it becomes very dependent on we
already want to go with your career
those are two basements oh yes and being
comfortable and eventually get to mid
range to stand up here tell stories
I'd be round here for us today so don't
[Music]