for uh coming out and sticking around I
was looking back and I we've done like
maybe eight presentations over the last
year or so and like three or four of
them then last on the last day of the
conference so we appreciate having an
audience to talk to so our presentation
today is on building a cloud test lab
and how we messed some of ours up along
the way before we get started into
things just some introductions my name
is Chris I'm Bharath what we do
currently right now is we provide
simulated corporate networks for our
clients to have a realistic safe place
to practice penetration testing and
doing that we've built a lot of cloud
and test labs all of our stuffs posted
in AWS so we've had a lot of headaches
along the way and we kind of wanted to
do this presentation to share our
experience with you there provide some
tips and tricks to help you guys set
your own up more easily and you know
share our funny pitfall stories so we're
going to be talking about is kind of the
steps to build one of these that's using
a cloud provider what are all the
networking things that you have to set
up beforehand launching your different
lab systems setting up multiple apps and
then you know why you should do things
in the cloud and some of the
disadvantages that has there and we kind
of reworked with this whole presentation
since yesterday we had the bright idea
that instead of just telling you now
this is how you do it and what it'll
look like we're gonna live build a lab
during the presentation today so
hopefully things go smoothly
definitely a lot of switching between
PowerPoint and doing demo stuff so keep
your fingers crossed for us so first
step before you do anything is to choose
a cloud provider there's kind of a lot
of the major ones that you've heard of
out there and there's others too is the
windows digitalization and that sort of
thing in the end it's pretty much going
to come down to personal preference if
you're going to pick one of the major
cloud providers they all are pretty
competitive with each other but there's
some things that you should consider
before narrowing down in the final
choice first of all you got to figure
out which operating systems you want to
have in your lab some people just want a
pure Linux environment or just one pure
Windows most of the time you're going to
want both with that directory and that
sort of thing so that goes out the pure
Linux providers like my node you gotta
be careful since this is a penetration
testing lab that you're following all
the terms and conditions most providers
have some language around what you're
not allowed to do and ways that you can
do penetration testing in their
environments but almost all of them kind
of exclusively disallow things like DDoS
attacks and attacks on the underlying
infrastructure so you should expect to
be able to do any of that you've got to
figure out the cost which we'll talk
about the cost of our example lab that
we set up a little bit later they're all
gonna be pretty competitive there as
well and then some of them are different
from Windows licensing but for the most
part it's how to bring your own
now Amazon and maturer will handle that
stuff for you so we went with Amazon for
all labs that we build just because we
were kind of familiar with the platform
already going into it it's got a lot of
different when it's flavors you can
throw in there and a lot of other
services that we use as well that we
like about it so before setting anything
up you need an account but it's super
easy to do just need your basic contact
info there and a valid credit card and
phone and when you're setting up your
account they will actually call you so
it has to be a real phone number for you
to get that account setup they also have
a nice breach here doing your first year
and if your live environment is pretty
small you're basically going to pay
nothing for it a lot of your services
are going to fall under the free tier
type stuff it's actually have an account
you can start setting up your network so
these are all the things that you're
going to need kind of to get your basic
networking setup down so with Amazon
sorry I forgot to mention we picked
Amazon this lot is going to be in Amazon
so all the examples and everything our
AWS specific just won't really help you
if you want to go do it at Google but
hopefully ok they just do this so you're
going to need VPC or a virtual private
cloud to segment your systems into a
local network there that's going to
create a route table and an Internet
gateway to help some of the
communication between the lab systems
themselves and the internet and then
you'll have different subnets security
groups that will define what traffic can
get in to and out of your systems and
then you need some way to connect to the
you see so you're gonna have to set up
connection so the first step is to
create the VCC
so if Eric's gonna handle all the demo
stuff and dive into that alright so this
is already WS console here
[Music]
hey there's a mask on phone okay you'll
see a really good service isn't here for
what we're gonna do today we're just
going to use ec2 and and these are you
can make the whole short links up here
so you won't see those so first we're
going to create the BBC I will take easy
as possible right here which is that
little wizard button that gives you did
you see with a single subnet and all I
need to give it here is a name
and we're going to all the IP addresses
so it's going to make the BBC and all
the associated resources underneath it
so it will give you everything you need
for have your basic lab environment
you'll have a subnet and Internet
gateway to provide Internet access to
the subnet and the route table division
communication something here and
something that is a rough table which
we'll come back to once we add more
stuff in accuracy we've got our local
route and then route to the Internet
through the internet gateway it made for
us alright so first step done BBC is
created you have your own little private
local network that you can start to
build out whoa so this is kind of just
brief overview we'll just did we created
a V PC needed to find the name cider
block for the Bowlby PC and then the
cider vlog for the subnet that's going
to get created you can create more
subnets so it all the labs of we build
we have you know five or six different
subnets it helps kind of keep your lab
more interesting and more realistic and
you can do things like create ACLs
between sub s which is not worth it for
now certainly not in this demo because
that gets pretty tough they don't let
you play with security groups where it's
going to make one of these when he does
assist some launch in a second but
essentially security groups are almost
like viral rules and that
they're gonna define your inbound and
outbound traffic to your individual
systems however they're not like ACLs
and that if you define inbound traffic
allowed on port 80 to a system once that
connection is made it's definitely going
to allow the traffic outbound from there
so you don't have to define it going
both ways if you allow something and
down and then make the connection
inbound that trap is going to get back
to you so now we have our BBC set up the
first thing we need to do is to connect
on so there's two two options to connect
you can you go with the software VPN or
Amazon has their own VPN connection that
they'll provide you we usually give up
the software VPN you can just use
something like Open VPN there free which
is why we like it it's relatively easy
to set up and that's going to be an
actual lab system in the BTC that's
handling you connecting and getting
access to the other PPC resources if you
go with an AWS VPN connection you have
to pay for that it comes out of your
civil Griffin every month and generally
you need a static IP and to do a bunch
of other configuration so we get a
software VPN and that's what we're going
to set up now yep so we're just going to
launch a system in our V PC here and
install and setup going to be depend on
that so we're gonna hop back to ec2 in
the console I can launch an instance so
if you've never been down this menu of
watching distance before there's a lot
of steps all these
to be thought about answered so these
are all the a eyes which is like system
templates that Amazon uses so these are
a bunch of quick ones that Amazon
provides for you you can make custom
ones there's a marketplace for vendors
and upload once with free configured
software and whatnot on them and charge
money for those to watch out click and
randomly a lot of times they'll be it'll
tell you at first like zero dollars for
the software just ec2 charges that all
want to be a free trial so later it'll
get you with the subscription and then
community is more or less anyone who can
upload these images so you can find
useful stuff in here but you also can't
trust them to the same level as the
other other sections in here anyways
we're just gonna go with a brand new
vanilla coupon to server micros
definitely fine for the PM there's a
million options we kind of stick in the
first three or four there cover your
general system for allowed these cases
she was our VDC that we made only wanted
some of that in there we do want to
assign a public I'd be especially
important here it's the DPI we need to
be able to get that from here and the
way we're doing internet access you need
to assign a public IP to a box for it to
be able to reach out through the
internet it doesn't mean that anything
on the internet and touch it inherently
unless we specify that but instead of
creating an active way or something else
for systems to talk out we're just doing
them
like these one other option we're going
to make use of on this screen is user
data here you can specify a script that
will get rotten when this machine gets
launched so instead of waiting for this
to boot up login going through it would
be ten configurations we're going to do
it through this so this is a script I
made it'll do with the OpenVPN install
and setup will link the gist Slayer in
this presentation so you can use all
this stuff let's hope you can can get
real confusing the setup but we can take
just a shortest path here so we download
that script make it executable and run
it and it takes two options which are
the domain name and the DNS server so
these are DHCP options that are going to
get pushed down to our VPN clients when
we connect to this so later when we
connect our Khaled box to this lab it'll
know from the network connection okay
we're on the b-sides demo domain and the
DNS server is this demo server is not
that yet because we haven't watched that
system yet but so begun before that
system so we make up an IBM ELISA later
that's about it but we really need to do
what's storage defaults time restoring
opportunity and no tags necessary these
are great for organizing things at you
AWS resources it's not going to matter
for this here we're going to make a new
security so we're gonna allow SSH
because we're having to download a VPN
certificate this box is going to be the
BPM self the default probe and be done
is UDP traffic on 1194 and understo
connector right here if you have a
subject you know you connect brahmer
just want to have it opened everywhere
and then this one we forgotten a couple
times over the course the last two days
you need to allow the lab traffic to hit
your VPN box yeah we tried to
reconfigure this VPN server and get the
script working correctly because we
couldn't get any traffic back from the
live system but we just told Amazon to
not let that happen so yeah we've
automated all this and been several
months since doing it manually so kind
of reinventing the wheel on few steps
anyway that's all we need there and we
have to create a key pair I have to lead
it them so that this would be like the
first run-through that's going to give
us an ssh traffic you
so the key pairs of how you either SSH
into your Linux systems for all the dams
on provided one anyways or how you get
decrypt your windows local admin
passwords to the RDP yeah
this is how so I did that ProSource
shows yesterday this is the keys that
you guys were talking about when you
were saying you had access to our boxes
from SSH immediately he will bypass the
logins because you already have the key
pairs our store I presume it's the same
thing but yeah for now that I'm okay
anyway we're gonna copy that over to our
attacker box here for many years
the right permissions on that for a
cessation to let you do anything with it
and then we can specify it in our
connection actually we're not in SSH
we're gonna SCP copy down yeah so that's
good we read created and open VPN
configuration files so that we can just
use that to connect it so if we go look
at our instance here you have a public
IP address which we allows access to
from just here oops
[Music]
I
so that is nobody came to the duration
about that'll connect to our content
server
all right
mouth rolls downhill on this thing and
then I'm at the end so the BGM creates a
new network adapter Network device on
here and you can see we have a 10.8
that's here at 6 address
that's the default range that opens up
things in you don't otherwise mess with
the end thing it's important that those
IP addresses apart within the submenu
choice for your EPC because something
like Amazon will get real confused about
if it's talking to its own system error
and needs to send that traffic to the
video so we just went through all the
different steps to launch a system it
happened to be our VPN system and now we
should have access to the environment
and be good
we should be able to start you know
getting C to channel and stuff like that
that's what we thought for like sound
like a couple days while trying to
figure this out the first go-around so
we had an issue where after we did all
this we we had configured a Jenkins
system that had no authentication we
went on there
we dropped a payload to get a C Tube
channel and nothing happened we were
like what's going on we don't know so we
sent back a request to our IP now let me
explain sorry this little diagram first
the red boxes are big answer every which
has a $10 dress and then the attacker
boxes the client connect there which has
a 10.8 address so all your payloads and
everything are going to have I
be listening on the 10.8 address so
that's what you're compromised Otis is
going to reach out warm so how that
happens is it tries to reach out to the
route table and say where should you out
this 10.8 traffic turns out we've never
said anything there so it didn't know to
fix it you got to go set a route for
that traffic to your VPN so that it
knows ok if there's something and that
10.8 range that's not in this BBC route
it to this specific box and let it
handle all that traffic so once you do
that you can get your normal c2 to that
can and communicate just fine yeah let's
go do that
so this is give the same name as I gave
us we need to under networking change
source destination check this is
Amazon's checkup like is this network
document for this box and since we're
going to send packets to this box that
Amazon doesn't think belong there we
need to turn that off and then under our
V PC specifically under the subnet and
that subnets rough table we add a route
to our media so we want all the 10.8
traffic to go once you remove that
source destination check your system
will show up in this drop-down so you
don't see it there go
all right so now all of our systems that
we launched in the lab should be able to
actually talk back to clients that
connect to the beginning because the
route
knows where to send that traffic to one
more caution on the networking side of
stuff and one of the disadvantages of
doing things in the cloud is around
responder and broadcast multicast
traffic so if you recognize the screen
shot this is from a tool called
responder and what it does is it will
listen on a local network for multicast
and broadcast traffic and essentially
allow an attacker to capture Network
credentials and then you can go crack
them and use them to gain access to the
domain so we try to do this in our labs
and we were just hearing nothing it was
crickets on our network and we didn't
know why it turns out in ec2 it kind of
takes over all of that latitude
networking for you so there actually
isn't any broadcast or multicast traffic
happening so if you want to run a tool
like responder or a similar man metal
tool that's going to look for traffic
like that on those lower levels of
networking you're probably not going to
see it because Amazon and I'm sure the
other cloud providers are doing
something kind of magical in there and
to handle all of that
so now we can move on to launching other
lab systems so for the Linux systems we
just launched one they lost Ubuntu
Amazon has a really good selection of
other just available Linux flavors out
there so they even have their own called
Amazon Linux which if you're just trying
to do something real simple like an
Apache web server it's going to be super
quick and easy to set that up you can do
a bun to Rosendo us SUSE probably a
hundred others you know there's a lot of
Linux distributions and that kind of the
point of a pen test lab is to have
vulnerable systems there so there's a
lot of horrible Linux distributions like
Metasploit Abul or a damn vulnerable
Linux and those you can get into ec2 as
well but they're not going to be
available through the marketplace if
Amazon doesn't want normal stuff out
there someone would definitely complain
about that all right put this system on
my network and then it got owned and I
don't know why so to do that you have to
first download it yourself in your own
virtual environment and then you can
import that to Amazon and it'll be
available as part of the my ami section
so you can still do that for Windows
systems the first thing we always make
sure our labs have is Active Directory
so anywhere you go everyone's going to
use ad for all sorts of things in their
environments authentication and access
control all that there's a couple
different ways you can do it
Amazon has a built in Active Directory
service more or less that you can manage
users in and manage authentication to
your Windows boxes but that's not really
what we're going for here so instead
we're going to launch a system and
create a new forest and make that system
a domain controller and it will serve
the service in our lab environment and
also give us a nice realistic box to go
back
that's going to be similar to what you
find on all of your actual corporate
networks the licensing is taken care of
and it WS they have to worry about that
and you can take servers back to like
2003 so they have a pretty good
selection there alright we're gonna go
and launch that first domain controller
and turn it into anime trailer yep
so same launching process here we're
going to choose a 2012 r2 server this
one we're gonna go with medium you can
definitely use small but for the
purposes of waiting for things to happen
doing it demo go a little faster but it
is that same subnet we are going to need
to give it internet access because it
installs some windows features on the
way to becoming NPCs don't you just be
able to talk to home for that and again
we're going to use this user data to
specify a script to run on startup there
it'll look a little different for
Windows we're doing PowerShell
so it's got these powershell tags around
it know how small that is
so we're we're installing this windows
feature domain services importing the
deployment module and the powershell and
then making an Active Directory forest
here which will make this machine
primary domain controller role that it's
also going to be the primary DNS server
for our environment so in this network
interface ii right over here we're going
to specify that same IP address that we
told our VPN server that the DNS server
was going to be at
another useful tip bit about the user
data is that those will run a system or
as roof so if you need to do powerful
stuff like turning this box into a
domain controller you can do that from
there that's a good way to make
something happening without having to
RDP into your box or anything since now
we have a VPN and access into the
network we're gonna make ourselves a new
security group here just going to call
it our local Platt Network and allow all
traffic by just go inside
be good we use the key again here you'll
see in a few minutes we can ask Amazon
for the local admin password that it
generates for that box and it uses the
key to encrypt that so we have to
provide the community birthday
go soft we're gonna let that do all of
its becoming domain dance to Windows
systems in particular take a bit longer
just spin up turns into a controller and
we think that'll take a couple minutes
and it's got to do a reboot so like five
minutes or so here and we actually the
OM Azam will not even let you get the
password until like it says you have to
wait at least four minutes or something
for this system to get it to life
together nothing for you to have a
password and be able to access it
so in the meantime we have some stories
of things that blew up and also a word
on workstations so most environments are
going to have actual user workstations
in them so Windows 7 Windows 10 Amazon
is not going to let you do that very
easily so you can launch all the servers
in the world and they do have a
mechanism to do like a PDI set up it's
called Amazon workspaces but you can't
just launch those into your BTC and have
them act as part of your environment so
what we do usually is to turn a Windows
Server 2016 into a Windows 10 bucks or a
2008 server into a Windows 7 box to be
clear you can run Windows 7 and 10 in
Amazon but you're on the hook for
dealing with the licensing which if
anybody's ever done Microsoft licensing
stuff it just gets terrible real fast
yeah and even if you do like the
developer licenses or anything like that
that are free they'll expire after 90
days then you'll have to go back every
90 days and make this happen again so
you can do a couple of things to Windows
Server this is a screenshot of Server
2016 looks almost identical to Server 10
and in most respects it is kind of
identical to the Windows Store where
does 10 sorry and you can also do stuff
like limit the
concurrent remote desktop connections
and kill off all of the server specific
executables like the server manager
you'll notice isn't in that bottom bar
there so they really do work and feel
just like workstations so unless you're
trying to do something really specific
that's probably going to be enough for
you some of our pain points on blab
systems are around those key pairs so
don't lose them if you lose them if not
all is lost but it's super annoying to
fix so what you have to do is shut off
the instance that you lost the key pair
for unmount the drive from it launch a
new instance create a new key period
that you do have access that and the old
draw out that you unmount it mount to
the new system go in there place your
SSH key or grab the admin hatch or
whatever otherwise get access to that
system I'm not that remounted back to
the old system and turn it back on it's
like a super long process and really
annoying so just hang on to those key
pairs and don't lose them yeah you can't
read download those things from Amazon
like when I generate it and downloaded
it that's the only time you'll get it
yeah yeah so a my passwords were keys
they're generated kind of three ways so
Amazon will custom generate your Windows
passwords for you so that just if you
launch a new Windows Server from Amazon
it's going to generate the password for
you some other ami is out there on the
marketplace will do some other custom
generation or if you take if you take a
server that's been launched it makes a
random password and you create an ami
out of that and then you relaunch that
ami later it's going to have the same
password that was a
created that auto generation won't
happen again so just be aware of kind of
all the different ways that those
passwords and access gets handled and
make sure that you know before you
launch something where am I getting the
password or the key to connected this
with all right what so far domain
controller is closed up so this is what
getting though we just passed it looks
like it's just a right click off of
there
you give Amazon back password
stick within calculator just have one
connection that's where you always need
quotes around the Amazon passwords
because we just crazy characters in them
and then the IP
yes
we can take a look at the nice stuff
here so after this DC is fully up
so we're gonna go ahead and create a
actual domain user here pop the user I
logged on that was the local
administrator for this which is now the
administrator for the domain it's
actually going on here so here's our
domain a new guy
we like to check the password never
expires once is that way to feed your
lab for a month then come back you don't
end up getting locked out with mix
Bioware domain accounts
we're not exactly worried about our
purposely vulnerable and that's why
being secure so we'll just attack back
in make him into a nap and freezes a
counter domain join the next system that
we watch so he does need to have ways to
do that
so before we domain during that next
system we'd have one DHCP configuration
to make here so in our V PC you can
specify DCPD options so currently it's
setting this PC to internal domain name
I'm using Amazon provided DNS servers so
this next system we want a domain joint
which means it needs to know where that
domain is that is joining which means we
need to tell them that that DC is its
DNS server so we're going to create a
new one of these give it our domain name
and our server
funny story that days we tend to try and
pick domain names for our lives that
aren't real because it just gets
confusing like you could make one called
google.com and instead of domain but
then you try and browse to it and if
your DNS isn't fully happy was going to
be the end and you end up on actual
master just confuses all your stands and
opportunities for skimming things that
are errors and things there's an RFC
that says the dot test TLD should never
be used so if you always like yeah yeah
top levels pretty safe my my domain top
test yeah so we make them up we were
making a bank environment so every
wanted to call it Eagle Bank and evil
that back didn't resolve so we decided
that was solid made a whole three
domains to forests eagle that Bank and
Golden Eagle that bank and then we go
and set up a bunch of vulnerable
applications and everything connect in
there and errors and crumb can't load at
any one of our websites
turns out dot bang is on the HS TS
preload list in chrome so every dot Bank
domain has HSTs enforced which mean do
you know me visit an over SSL with the
balance and none of our boxes have so we
had to regain freedom and yeah no idea
the preload lists or thing especially
for an entire TLD
anyway we just got to attach this do you
see D Hawking said do you see so now
we're going to launch another server for
environment - there's two systems there
we can show you how to domain join
something as you're launching it so you
don't have to bother with the look left
and pass right at first and going in the
same place another little PowerShell
thing here this is usually we just
created example and this will
domain join our server and also rename
it to your server one and that on our
same local security group
security groups get associated with your
VPC so once you create one if you're
going to launch something into that VPC
again you can go back and pick the same
security group but if you're in a
different VPC you'll have to make it
again so if you've lost one or something
just swishing PVCs that's what happened
to it
this will take another couple of minutes
to come up but it should be a little
faster than creating a whole domain
controller so now we're going to have
two systems are in our environment we
can get to like the purpose of pen test
labs which is to have vulnerable
applications and things actually go and
attack and practice with right so it's
kind of a lot of resources out there for
this already a few of our listed here my
favorites buggy web app and what good
web application is that are purposely
vulnerable from Hamas you've got a
dimple or web application as well and
then you can also do things like Tomcat
Jenkins J balls ColdFusion other
applications that aren't necessarily
vulnerable but maybe you can miss
configure them to have default
credentials so if you get an old version
of Tomcat on there or a new version and
maybe credentials default that's a
common misconception
so there's a great types of things to do
as well something that people don't
consider when building their live
environment is to put in downloadable
applications I think it makes a lot
really a lot more realistic and it's
going to feel more like what we feel
when we do a pen test on an internal
network so having those types of not
intentionally vulnerable applications
can be pretty nice too
and I wanted to say that just because
they're not intentionally vulnerable it
doesn't mean that the applications
aren't vulnerable if you go to source
borage or web gallery there's a lot of
like really bad and open store
ABB's that can be fun to learn because
you know I look at it and you say this
thing's definitely vulnerable to
something but there's not any
documentation out there on how to you
know do it through steps one to ten on
buggy web app or anything like that so
they can be really fun to help and then
kind of an extension of that is to put
in realistic data in your environment so
after you have something you have to go
find some target data in your corporate
network whether that's credit cards or
other PCI data or employee data so if
you build your lab with that in mind and
create those users and files and target
data to go after it also makes it a more
realistic experience and helps you kind
of learn closer to what it's going to be
like all right let's go check back in on
our server here
I think we're going to actually have
this lab built in the time doesn't have
so that's good our example user
cool so that's a doing engine system
we're gonna skip actually installing
vulnerable software I just started being
very time-consuming well we can take a
look at kind of what what's he doing
Active Directory
now we have these two systems that's
like the most basic pen test lab you can
go do we have our VPN we have a domain
controller and one system joins the
domain so if this is all you did you
still have the minimum to get C 2
channels practice doing different Active
Directory enumeration and attacks there
and you know practice different lot of
movement techniques and all that stuff
so we'll try to get a CT channel here
real quick just to show you that it does
actually work and then G can do some
things with it
so this is PowerShell Empire if you're
not familiar with it it's just a post
exploitation command and control
framework it's free and open source so
you can download it and install it
without any licensing issues or anything
like that and it's pretty good so we
tend to do all of our demos and stuff
with that so people can not rely on a
commercial alright presentation so when
you establish to a CT channel with
Empire it's going to give me back what's
called an agent and you can interact
with that agent to do different things
like gather information on the system
derivative show options we saw a feature
there you have it
you can also do stuff with ad and
everything through your agent here I
don't know if we quite have enough time
to go into that too much yeah play
around there you have some of the
advantages the advantages of working
with cloud labs that we found and kind
of advocate them for it is they're
really easy to back up your whole
environment am sahn's going to manage
all your snapshots and everything so if
you create a lab snapshot it in a good
State at the beginning when your pen
testing stuff blowing it up you're going
to be able to revert to that no problem
and everything should be kosher having
it hosted in a platform like Amazon also
means it's super available if they're
like you know nine nine availability or
whatever it is if people like Netflix
and all those providers can rely on
Amazon for their infrastructure your pen
test lab would definitely be there too
and it's almost always going to be
better than your home network then the
surprising one year is about cost so a
lot of people have this misconception
and there's fear that why would I put
all my stuff up in the cloud I already
have you know a server at home that I
can use or whatever it's going to be so
expensive well the lab we just built
which is the VPN and then the two
systems if you were running it 24/7 will
cost you fifty five bucks roughly a
month but no one can happen for 24 hours
a day seven days a week so if you're
only using it a couple hours at a time
and turning it off and on it costs you
seven and a half cents per hour so you
could run this thing for two thousand
hours a year
and it's still how to be relatable it's
not all bruises though there's some
disadvantages with the cloud so the
backups are super easy but you have to
be careful
so this Brittany a forest with time
travel if you snapshot a domain
controller and there's no other domain
controllers your other systems go on
living for a while you revert to an
alteration of your DC for the opposite
you get a newer version of a DC compare
to the rest of the environment and throw
it back in there all the trust between
your domain controller and your other
systems will be lost
it's a time with just DC's and systems
it's one of multiple DC's yes lost
between them yeah so doing that can mess
up your forest and you'll have to
rebuild the whole thing we did that a
few times it's not fun it's very
available being on Amazon but it also
makes you need an internet connection
anytime you want to use it so you can't
take you know a couple VMs on your
laptop and go back from somewhere
without internet connection which is a
slight disadvantage and then the only
real one here that is pretty bad in my
opinion is that it's hard to do any sort
of hardware stuff so if you're trying to
mess with ICS or raspberry pi is a lot
of people like raspberry PI's you can't
really easily integrate them into your
lab environment without doing like a
hybrid cloud home setup in which case
you're going to go through all that
trouble like just also put the rest of
your lab at home also comment in that
category routers switches your level
networking stuff
all right so that's it for us we have a
lot of environment there now all the
gist all the scripts we use to kind of
make that configuration for you easier
up on github right now is just so
they're in there and that's our contact
info if you have any questions or
questions no it's been alright and what
usually with actual pen testing we'll
have windows VM or just pen test from a
host so forth we can connect using
Windows there it's kind of a smoother
user experience to just connect with
Windows but it things like you have to
remember to include the clipboard tag in
your connection stringer you will have
shared clipboard mini RDP session in
your host so there's some weirdness
about it but it's fine a lot of people
recorded roll with I never got to work
yeah that's definitely the easy road all
right well thanks a lot everyone
you