- Well, hi everyone again.
And welcome to this talk,
which is about one vulnerability
that we have found in Microsoft Windows,
that allows an attacker
to inject key strokes,
impersonating, previously
paired, the legitimate keyboard.
But before going farther
in the presentation,
let us try to get your attention
and put the cart before the horses,
and show you this very,
very accelerated version
of our demo video.
And please pay attention
because it's gonna get,
it's gonna be quick.
This is the scenario.
This is the legitimate
keyboard going disconnected.
Then this is the attacker
launching the attack.
And then as soon as the
attacker launches the attack,
the fake device is going to
be present in this space.
And then the Windows box
connects to the fake device
and the keys get injected.
(audience applauds)
We hope that everything
is clear for everyone,
but if it is not,
we have the rest of the talk
to try to explain it to you.
(audience chuckles)
So please be with us.
And hopefully we explain it right to you.
- Hello everyone. Now I try
to explain the video again,
but this time, slowly.
So the first thing we need to know is:
Who are the participants in the video?
And we have a Windows PC here,
Bluetooth Low Energy keyboard,
and the attacker that are using Linux PC
with a special dongle.
Before the video starts,
a Bluetooth Low Energy keyboard
and the Windows PC perform
the Bluetooth pairing
in order to establish an encrypted channel
and all the data that are,
they are communicating, are encrypted.
So every time that the
Bluetooth Low Energy keyboard
re-connects with the Windows PC,
the encryption channel,
encrypted channel, is established
and all the data will be encrypted.
As the Bluetooth Low Energy keyboard is
a low-energy device, after a few period,
after a little period of time,
the keyboard disconnects in
order to save some energy
and it is in this moment when an attacker
could impersonate the
Bluetooth Low Energy keyboard
and send some key strokes,
some not encrypted key strokes.
But how is this possible?
Because, we said before
that the Windows PC
and the keyboard establish
an encryption channel
every time that it re-connects,
we send not encrypted data and
are accepted by the Window,
by the Windows. So that's
what this story is about.
And let's start from the beginning.
He is José, and I'm Fernando.
We are security researchers.
We like to play with security
and with communication protocols,
we also climb and ride motor bikes,
as you could see in the
photo, in our spare time.
We come from Spain and work in Layakk.
And what we saw in this talk,
we start with a brief description
of Bluetooth Low Energy concepts.
Some concepts only in order to
understand better the vulnerability.
Now, then we detail how
this attack is possible.
And what parts of the specs,
of the Bluetooth specs
and Windows allow this attack.
Then we show you two
approaches of how we try
to exploit this vulnerability,
and the first one doesn't work.
And the second approach
is the current exploit.
We continue with the proof of concepts,
showing all the hardware
and software that we need
to perform the attack and some
demos and conclude this talk,
showing some data about the
vulnerability disclosure,
some related publications and
reference that help us to find
and display this vulnerability.
(mouse clicks)
- As you will see during the talk,
the attack is extremely simple,
but we think that it's important
to introduce some Bluetooth
Low Energy concepts
that help to understand the attack,
especially if you're not familiar
with the Bluetooth protocols.
And the first one of these concept
is this concept of pairing.
When two Bluetooth devices want
to protect their communications,
they must finish this pairing
procedure as they call it.
The objective of this procedure
is to establish a key,
which is called the Long Term Key.
That will be used, by the way,
this is only performed the
first time they connect,
and then they keep this
long, long term key
and they use it every time that they want,
they want to connect to each other again,
to derive a session key.
That is the key that is going to
protect this particular connection.
We are not talking about the
different pairing schemes
or association models,
because they're not
relevant for the attack.
We just left them here for your reference.
But we do want to talk
about another concept,
about Bluetooth Low Energy protocols.
Is that the layers,
the layer set is split into two parts.
The host part, which holds the
upper part of the protocol,
which contains the LTK protocol.
Also the ATT protocol
that manages and shows
and interacts with the
attributes of every device.
This upper part talks with
the application layer,
which is above it. In our case,
the application layer will be the HID,
the Human Interface Device,
which is because we are
attacking a keyboard.
And the lower part of the protocol layers
are called the controller one.
And you will find several
different configurations of that.
For example, in the keyboard case,
you'll find that the host
and the controller are both
implemented in the
keyboard. But for example,
if we are talking about a
windows box or a Linux box,
the host is implemented
in the operating system.
For example, you have Linux,
the host is the blue set
implementation of that.
And the controller is
implemented in the firmware
of the device that you're using,
either an embedded device or cheap set
or an external dongle.
This firmware implements the controller.
The communication between these two parts
is very straightly forward
called Host to Controller Interface, HCI,
and the host sends
information to the controller
by one thing, that is called commands.
And the controller sends the host events.
That is just a question of names,
but one of the important things,
or one of the things that
we want to emphasize here,
is that encryption
happens at the link layer.
So the host part doesn't do
anything about encryption
except maybe, no, not maybe,
except just managing the
state of the encryption
and calculating the Long
Term Key. And that's all.
And whenever the link layer
needs the Long Term Key
to calculate the session key,
then the host part provides
this long-term key.
So this is a very important concept,
and you will see why
during our presentation,
because it's very directly
related with the attack.
And we have still one more
concept to introduce to you
before explaining the attack,
which is, let's imagine
this is scenario where
we have the master device
and we are using here,
the Bluetooth file that used
specification terminology.
In our case, in our scenario,
the master device is the Windows machine.
And we have the slave
device in our scenario,
the slave device, is a
Bluetooth Low Energy keyboard.
And we have the situation here.
The start point is the situation where
these two devices have previously paired,
completed the pairing procedure
that I told you before.
So they both have the
Long Term Key associated
with this connection, and
they want to reconnect.
They want to create a new connection.
And we are going to see right now,
what happens here and how does it work?
So the host part of the master instructs
the link layer to create a connection.
It just provokes in the link layer
that the link layer starts listening
for the slave to appear in the
air. And more particularly,
to advertising messages from this slave.
The slave is sleeping right now,
because he went to sleep to save energy.
And he restarts whenever
the user presses a key.
And then it provokes that
the host informs or instructs
the link layer to start
advertising himself
with this command set,
advertising enabled.
And then eventually one of
these advertising messages
gets to the link layer of the master.
And then the master answers
back with a connect indication,
link layer message to the
link layer of the slave.
Please see that this, everything
happens at the link layer.
So the host is only participating
in the controlling part
of the state of protocol.
At this point of the protocol,
the connection has been created
and both link layer inform
their correspondent,
a host part, that the
connection has been created.
The connection is created,
but it's not encrypted.
Not encrypted yet. This is
what is going to happen now.
The master that holds
the long term key knows
that this connection should be encrypted.
So as soon as the connection
is created, it should,
and it usually does, it
instructs the link layer
to start encryption.
Then at this point, the link
layer calculates its part,
the master part of two random values,
The SKD, which is the
Session Key Diversifier
and analyzation vector.
This to, this part is sent to the slave,
to the link layer of the slave,
with the encryption request PDU.
And the slave calculates
is part of these values.
And send back it with the
encryption response PDU
to the link layer of the master.
If you think there is
one thing left is that
the slave does not have the long term key.
The master, the link layer of the master,
do have the long term key
because it has been provided
with the enabled encryption command.
But the slave doesn't have that.
So it has to ask for it.
And if the slave has,
if the host of the slave
has the Long Term Key, which is the case,
it will answer back
with the Long Term Key.
At this point,
both devices can calculate
the Session Key Diversifier
because they have both parts
and the analyzation vector,
which I just remind you that
these are random numbers, okay,
and they both can
calculate the session key
that is going to protect
this particular connection.
The session key is
calculated by encrypting
the Session Key Diversifier,
using as encryption key,
the long-term key and as
an initialization vector,
they calculated initialization vector.
So at this point, both have
calculated the session key.
And the only thing that left
to finish the encryption,
to the start encryption procedure,
let's say that, is to let's say,
agree on the point in time
where the encryption starts.
And this is made with
this kind of handshake.
We, you say that,
that starts with a start
encryption request command,
sent not encrypted by the
link layer, and then, sorry,
by the link layer of the slave,
then the link layer of the master
answers back with a standard
encryption response.
And this message is already been
encrypted with the session key. Okay?
So, if the slave receives this message
and it is able to decrypt it,
then it's, so to speak, kind of
authentication of this master.
And it does exactly the same thing,
encrypt this encryption response command
with this just calculated section key.
And so both are, let's say authenticated,
and the connection is
encrypted, is protected.
At this point, it's very important.
And this is very, very important
for the attack that we
are explaining here,
is that at this point, the link layer
informs the host that the
encryption has started.
And it's at this point that
encryption has started,
and not before.
And you will understand
just in a couple of slides,
that's why I'm emphasizing this.
Every next, or every subsequent PDUs
will be encrypted from now on,
for this particular connection.
So we've seen these three or four concepts
of about Bluetooth.
And now we are going to explain
how it is possible to inject this
with all these contexts
that we have explained.
So, what makes the attack possible?
In fact, there are two things
that make the attack possible.
The first thing is one thing that,
we don't call it a vulnerability.
It's something that is
present in explicitly defined
in the specification, in
the Bluetooth standard.
And it's the fact that
when the slave, sorry,
when slave device receives
the encryption request, PDU,
it is explicitly allowed to send,
any remaining PDUs that he
has to send to the master.
And he has in his queues
in a non-encrypted,
in a not encrypted way.
It's explicitly allowed.
And I can show you the
part of the standard
where this is written, written down.
This is from our point of view,
this is not a vulnerability.
It's just something that is
there to allow the slave to
empty its queues, before
continuing to send in encrypted,
encrypted PDUs, or encrypted data.
But the second one, the second thing
that allows the attack,
this is the vulnerability.
Sorry, before that, what I wanted to say
in this slide, is that this characteristic
that I just explained, creates
a window of opportunity for an attacker,
trying to impersonate this slave device.
Where he can send data
through the connection,
through the Bluetooth connection
and the master, sorry,
the link layer of the
master will accept this PDU.
These PDUs. Will accept this data,
and it's the responsibility
of the upper part
of the protocol to consider
that this data is valid or not.
And this is precisely the second thing
that allows the attack,
which is the vulnerability.
It seems that Microsoft Windows
does not wait for this event, which is
the encryption change event,
does not wait for this event,
to consider that any PDU coming
from the slave, it's legit.
So it seems that it considers
that encryption has started
as soon as the host part of the master
orders the encryption to start.
Which is not the case. You have to wait
until receiving this
encryption change event.
So this allows us to try
to impersonate the slave
up to this point and send
all these unencrypted PDUs
without actually knowing
the Long Term Key,
which will be needed to really
complete this procedure
of starting encryption.
And this is the thing
that allow the attack.
This is the two things
- Okay. Now we will explain
the two approaches that we follow
in order to try to exploit
this vulnerability.
As I said before, the first one
is working at the host level.
Work with the host level
has a very big problem
that we don't decide when
the message are really sent.
We only tell the controller part to
send some data to, some high level data,
but we doesn't decide where
exactly this data is sent.
We are trying to put some PDUs
between the encryption request
and encryption response,
and we couldn't decide where the PDUs
we try to send are exactly put.
And to implement this approach,
We use an HCI adapter,
a common HCI adapter,
with the only particularity that
it allows to change the VD address
in order to impersonate
the Bluetooth keyboard
and use the Mirage framework.
The Mirage framework
is, among other things,
allows among other
things, to hook some parts
of the communication, and change
the normal flow of this communication.
And we use it to intercept
the connection event.
And after this event, we
start to send keystrokes
and doesn't send anything else.
As I'd said that, we doesn't decide
where the message are effectively sent.
We need some tries to succeed,
and put some of these key strokes
between the encryption request
and encryption response.
And now we will show you
some captured in the air.
We just sniffle to capture this message,
that is a Bluetooth, low energy sniffer.
In the left side, you could
see the, hm, la direction?
- La direction.
- The direction of the communication,
master to slave or a slave to master.
And as I say, the connect request
is sent by the master and
received by the slave.
And just after that, we
start sending key strokes,
but you can see that there
are some link layer message
that we have not control, and are sent.
And then the normal flow
of the communication
on the start-an-encryption request
is received by the fake
slave, by the slave.
And the slave is trying
to send more key strokes.
Then the controller part of the fake slave
respond automatically with
an encryption response
and ask for the Long Term Key.
As we haven't got the Long Term Key,
the key missing is sent
back to the controller
and it is translated to
link layer indication.
Once master received this message,
it closed the connection immediately,
because the encryption channel
could not be established.
And our fake slave, continue
trying to send some keystrokes.
The most important thing in these slides
is to understand that we are trying
to send a lot of key strokes between
encryption request and
encryption response.
And as we have good control about
when the H level that is sent,
we can decide that these key strokes hit
between encryption requests
and encryption response.
There are only one notification
message that hit there,
and it means that there are
only one key stroke that are
effectively injected and
processed by the master.
So we realized that if we want to
exploit this vulnerability,
we should go down and develop something
that works in the controller level.
- And this is what we did.
And this is the actually
implementation of the attack.
We implemented the attack
at the link layer level,
at the controller level. In
order to do that, we use this,
let me say that's fantastic framework,
which is called the Zephyr.
It's completely, from top to bottom,
open-source implementation
of the Bluetooth
Low-energy protocol stack.
So this, you can compile that,
and create a firmware that can run in one
of these dongles, which
is a Nordic RF, 50 52 H40.
That has part no very,
very, very few costs.
It's very small cost.
And when we implement this
and at the link layer,
what we can do is to control
where these keystrokes
that we want to send can
fall into the protocol state.
So we can control that all,
we can allow the protocol
at the link layer to reach this point,
and then we can freeze
the protocol and send
all the keystrokes that we want to send,
as if is there is no tomorrow.
And then just wait
for the master to
terminate the connection.
The master will terminate the connection,
because he's actually waiting for
the encryption response
command, PDU, sorry.
And this, this will never arrive,
because we are not going to send it.
So at timeout will expire here.
And after this timeout
expires, the master sense,
the terminating indication PDU,
just dropping the connection.
But at this point, all the
keystrokes that we have sent
have been already accepted by the master.
And we can see that in air capture,
like I'm going to show you right now.
In this air capture, you can see that
the connect request comes and then
all the subsequent normal
link layer messages
that let's say, advance in
the state of the connection,
which, objective is
eventually to encrypt it.
But as soon as we received
the encryption request PDU,
what we do is to freeze the
link layer in the fake slave.
And then instead of continuing
the normal functioning of the link layer,
that will be to send encryption response,
to ask for the long term
key, to our host part,
et cetera, et cetera,
we just don't do that.
And instead of that, we
send all the key strokes
that we want to send. As you can see here.
And we send all of them,
and when eventually
what we send all of them, and then
we just stop sending things.
We just wait for the master
to drop the connection,
but all these keys have
already been accepted.
- Now we have an exploit that allow us
to inject some keystrokes into the master,
but we want to try to increment
the number of keystrokes
that we can inject in one connection.
So we try to send a lot of keystrokes
with no waiting time,
but this cause a problem,
because at the beginning
of the communication,
if we try to send a lot of keystrokes,
some of these message are lost
or aren't processed by the master.
So we implement this exponential
increment of waiting time.
That starts waiting four seconds.
That is a lot of time, but it works.
And then every time that
a keystroke is sent,
divide this waiting time by two
until you reach 20 milliseconds.
This implementation allow us to inject
more than 13,000 key strokes
in one connection of 30 seconds.
And we have a demo at the end of the talk.
We implement other upgrades
in order to make easy
the, the configuration of the dongle.
We implement these HCI vendor comments
to program the dongle with some
special characteristics of each device
and what key strokes we want
to send in every connection
without having to recompile SEFA
every time that we want
to change something.
We include an HCI comment
to program the handle,
the record size and the operation type.
And to clear the list of the
keystrokes that will be sent,
and the add some keystroke
to add a keystroke,
to be sent when the
connection is established.
We also implement some
specialized actions.
For example, this is the action to sleep.
We can tell the dongle to sleep.
Some milliseconds between
two keystrokes are sent.
In this case, it's
sleeping 500 milliseconds.
And we implement another option.
That was the rule forever.
That is, we think that is
only for testing proposed.
To, and it allows us to repeat
the list of keystrokes in a loop
until the connection is
closed by the master.
(mouse clicks)
So now, let's see what we
need to perform the attack.
And we need the Nordic
dongle. That cost about $30.
It's a Bluetooth, low-energy dongle.
We also need, the or
modified Zephyr firmware,
that you can find it in our GitHub.
I don't know it, is it
published now? Yeah? (laughs)
You can find it in our GitHub.
With these two things, you
can program the dongle,
but it is quite hard because
you need to use the HCI tool
and put the bites there manually.
And we develop some
extra tools that help us
to program the dongle in a
more user, user-friendly way.
Okay. Before we can perform the attack,
we need to know some characteristics
about the Bluetooth Low Energy keyboard
that we want to impersonate.
And basically we need to know
how these specific keyboards
send the report data to the
master, and the Mac address
of the real keyboard that
we want to impersonate.
(mouse clicks)
The first data that we need
could be extracted using
Replica, analyzing the communications.
It's very easy because you press a key
on a real, legitimate keyboard.
You could see on Wireshark,
that it's sending a report
using a specific handle, in this case,
is the 13 with specific
structure that has 11 bytes
and the operation type, or opp code,
that is under notification
and (indistinct) notification.
And to get Mac address, we
could listen in the air,
the real keyboard, and
we use separate modes.
The first mode was when the
keyboard isn't paired yet.
And before, when the keyboard
enters in the pairing mode,
it starts sending advertising indications
like this, that has the appearance.
That is the, a keyboard and the company.
In this case, we use a Microsoft keyboard,
and it include, this message
include the VD address,
or the Mac address during this month.
It also send a scan response that includes
the full device name and
the advertising address.
But it is not realistic that the attacker
were always, when the
pairing is performing.
So there are another way to
get the Mac address, and it's
when the keyboard is
re-connecting to the Windows PC.
And it's this kind of
message that are advertising
that indication, that
includes the BD others
of the keyboard and the
Mac address of the PC.
Once we have all this information,
we could write the configuration file
that we need to run the tech.
And it includes the report handle,
the report size and the operation type
that we collect before
analyzing our replica.
And the last attribute
on the configuration file
was the types of script,
that are the characters
that we want to send to the victim.
We could include in this characters,
some special characters
like: left Windows,
or enter, using braces.
And we could send two
keys pressed together,
like left Windows plus R that
are on the first example.
In this case, for example, is to open
the room dialogue of
Windows, the shortcut,
to open the room dialogue.
And we also use the special actions
using the common name,
common name and arguments.
This example of types of script
opens the run dialogue of Windows, right?
Power shell, press enter,
and then sleep for five,
500 milliseconds and then open a card,
that is a common proof of concept.
Once we have this
configuration file written,
we could call the KB
injection pile that only needs
the HCI where the dongle is identified,
the video address of the
keyboard that we want to
impersonate. And the confirmation file.
We add two more options.
That is the rule forever
that I before send in a loop,
the keystrokes that we want to inject,
and no act that prints common HCI comments
instead of running it directly.
(mouse clicks)
- And we are approaching
the end of our talk.
This is demo time again, but this time at,
let's say the real time pace,
this is the actual demo of the attack.
This is the scenario that you
can find here, the victim,
the legitimate keyboard and
the attacker, the Linux PC
that is connected to this dongle here.
And what we can see here
is that the legitimate user
is just typing its work
onto to the Windows machine,
just typing his regular work,
as we can see right now.
And eventually what is going to happen
is that this regular user will stop,
stop typing because he
wants a coffee or whatever.
And at this point in time,
this inactivity period is going to start.
Now, we are going to see that
while this inactivity period is counting,
the attacker launches his attack
and it launches using all the techniques
that we have explained to you.
The important thing here is that
the attacker does doesn't
have to synchronize himself
to the point in time where the
legitimate keyboard is
going to be disconnected.
He doesn't need to do that
because as soon as he launches
the attack, the fake device
will start advertising.
And this advertising messages
will be just ignored by the
Windows machine, because the
Windows machine is just still
connected to the legitimate keyboard.
So the attacker can launch the attack
and just wait for the legitimate
keyboard to disconnect,
which is what we are doing
right now with fast forward.
We are fast forwarding time,
just to reach the point where
the legitimate keyboard is
going to be disconnected,
to save energy. As we
have explained before.
Which in this case, for this
keyboard was about 10 minutes.
And, as we can see right now,
the keyboard is going to be disconnected.
We can see here in the
control panel window.
And at this point, the Windows machine,
acting as a master, will try
to create a new connection.
Will try to reconnect or
create a new connection,
to be activated as soon as
the keyboard appears again.
But the keyboard that is going to appear
is not the legitimate one,
is our keyboard, that we are trying to,
we are impersonating
the legitimate keyboard.
And all these key strokes
have been injected.
As you can see.
In this case, we've
launched a power shell,
and we've just written a downloader
that downloads this malware.
That just for the proof of concept,
just shows this image. And that's all,
(audience applauding)
Thanks a lot. By the way (laughs)
we have this other demo to show you,
that this attack not only
works for keyboards, it all,
it also work for other,
HID devices like a mouse.
In this case, we've,
we've just recorded the proof of concept.
The principles of the
attack are exactly the same.
The only thing that changes
is that the format of the PDUs
that we're sending
contained a different data
because the HID format of the mouse
is different from the keyboard.
But other than that, the
principles are exactly the same.
As you can see, the
keyboard gets disconnected
and then, the fake mouse will,
the Windows box will
connect to the fake mouse,
just as it did for the fake keyboard.
And we program some movements
on some clicks of the mouse,
just to show this square in on
the Paint program of Windows.
And we have left another demo for you,
is the one that shows how many key strokes
we are able to produce
in only one connection,
in only one shot. And this is the demo.
I'm going to let it run at real time,
because even if it
lasts for a few seconds,
we wanted you to see the
real time of the attack.
So at this point in time,
the attacker has launched the
attack. And as you can see,
keystrokes start coming
and they keep coming,
coming up to the point that the master,
which in this case is the Windows machine,
will disconnect it, will
drop the connection,
using the terminate indication command.
As you can see, this is real time.
This is all the keys that we can send
to the master in only one connection.
In this case, we are sending it to the,
just to the note pad, just to illustrate
that this is just a proof of
concept, but just to count
how many key strokes
we are able to inject.
And at the end, as you can see here,
more than 13,000 keys have been injected.
And we think that this is more than enough
to write some downloader or
even some power cell malware
or whatever. So the impact is that way.
And finally, we did the
vulnerability disclosure
with Microsoft. They,
in February, this year,
they immediately acknowledged the bug,
and the bug is already solved.
The patch has been issued.
So please patch your systems.
And if you want to play with it,
we have made this publication.
We have, I mean, you have this talk.
If you want to review the attack,
or to understand the
attack, or to play with it.
And if this talk is not enough,
because our English is
not very good looking,
then we have tried to write down
all the things here in
our post, in our blog.
And we also have all the tools
and our modified firmware
in our GitHub page.
And we left here some reference for you,
the reference for the tools
that we have used for make the
captures, the Zephyr
project and other things,
and also the references
to the specifications
and some previous words that we have read.
They're not directly related with our work
because they're quite different,
but we have read them.
So we left here also for your reference,
and that will be all from our part.
And we thank you very
much for your attention.
If you have any question,
we will be around
and we'll have more (indistinct)
(audience applauding)
Okay.