- Saturday first talk of the day,
let's give them a great
big DEFCON welcome.
Come on.
(crowd applauding)
Chad, yeah.
- Yeah, woo.
All right.
Hey, welcome everybody,
we're really appreciative.
I think it's wild,
just to think about how far DEFCON's come,
we're at DEFCON 30, how insane is that?
You look around walking through
the halls, there's marble,
and this is just so,
it's interesting to see where we've come.
So I think its worth a
second to just look around,
see who's where, see how much
we've grown and appreciate
that we have just begun to burn down
all the shit that's wrong in this world
and fix it with our hacker mind.
So guys give yourself a round of applause,
like that is important
(chuckles)
and you being here is part of that,
and we really appreciate that.
- Thank you so much for being with us,
especially at 10:00 AM on a Saturday,
which in DEFCON time
is like three in the
morning in the real world.
So really appreciate it.
My name is Jeff, my
friends call me Replicant.
I'm a pediatrician and an anesthesiologist
and I do some security research
about clinical medicine
technology with this guy.
- I'm Christian Dameff,
"quaddi" is my handle.
I am an emergency medicine physician
and security researcher.
- And I'm Cory Doctorow.
I've worked with the
Electronic Frontier Foundation
for 20 years in different capacities.
I'm currently the special advisor.
I write science fiction novels
and I'm on the computer science faculty
at the Open University and
the library science faculty
at the University of North Carolina.
- So a little known fact,
quaddi actually brought
me to my first DEFCON,
which I think was DEFCON 18 or 19
back when we were baby medical students.
And I was thinking the other day
about what has happened
in medicine since then.
I mean, it seems like the 10 plus years
have gone by quickly, but in
medicine that's a lifetime
and there have been
some incredible advances
in some of the ways we used our
technology to treat patients
that we can really look
at with two lenses,
a lens of promise for the future
and the incredible
achievements we can make,
but also one of peril of a future
in which we want to avoid
really significant concerns
and tensions with privacy and autonomy.
And so just to kind of
give you a little bit
of a consideration for that,
we have gene therapies now
that treat diseases that
were fatal to children
when I was in my pediatric residency.
And that's incredible.
That's incredible promise.
Looking at it the other way though,
if you don't have insurance,
you gotta pay half a
million dollars a year
to keep your kid alive, right?
We're gonna talk about
artificial pancreas's,
incredible technology that
hackers have pioneered
that can help to improve
your diabetic control
and really increase your quality of life.
But we can see a future where some people
may be forced to use a black box
that they don't fully understand
that collects data that they can access,
that depends on DRM shackled consumables
that they need in order to
continue to have a function
or a future in which telemedicine
is available to everybody
and people can see a primary care provider
and they can use personalized medicine
to customize treatments for them.
You can see a flip side of that coin
where private equity is buying
up your primary care provider
and Amazon's acquiring
your doctor's offices
and you're starting to get targeted ads
based on the data they're mining from you.
So really wanna explore those
tensions today as we talk.
- And we thought no better a person
to help us talk about this than
the activist Cory Doctorow.
So we're gonna like Cory,
take it over for now.
Give it up for Cory, give it up.
(crowd applauding)
- Thanks gentlemen.
Thank you all.
So I wanna talk about a group of people
who rely on med tech and also
rely on modifying med tech
and some of the ways that
their own safety has been
weaponized against them.
And some of the stuff that's come out,
that's made life better
for people who rely on it.
So I'm talking about people
who use power wheelchairs,
which are a significant part
of the $50 billion durable
medical equipment market.
There's about 3 million Americans
who use powered wheelchairs.
It's the complex rehab
tech area of Medicare
and Medicare is pretty
dysfunctional in this regard.
They very narrowly
interpreted their mandate.
And so if you use a power wheelchair
and you rely on Medicare
to provide it to you,
Medicare will only give you
an indoor powered wheelchair,
although many of us
like to leave our homes
and they will also refuse
to cover any preventative maintenance.
So this is a recipe for disaster.
You have a chair that's being used
in ways that it's not supposed to be used
and you can't perform
preventative maintenance on it.
One problem of the way that
Medicare procures these chairs
is that they go to lowest bidders.
And the way to generate a low bid
is to have economies of scale.
And so two private equity rollups,
a company called NewMotion
and another company called
National Seating & Mobility
have bought virtually
all the other companies
that make powered wheelchairs.
So people who use power wheelchairs
buy from one of those
two companies typically
and private equity firms,
they have a common playbook,
which is to load up their
acquisitions with a lot of debt
and then squeeze them
to service that debt.
They pay themselves a special
dividend on acquisition
and then to make good on that debt,
they then have to squeeze them.
One of the areas they've
squeezed is by cutting service.
And so parts are billed
at very high prices
and it takes a very long
time to get serviced.
So all of this was examined in detail
in a report that came out
this spring called Stranded
from the Public Interest
Research Group, or PIRG.
Stranded found that 93%
of the power wheelchair
users they surveyed
had had a need for
service in the last year.
62% of them had waited four
weeks for that service,
and 40% of them had waited
seven or more weeks for service
and, or seven, yeah, seven or more weeks,
sorry, I thought that was
months, no seven or more weeks.
And you have to understand
that in some instances,
this meant not only that you
couldn't leave your home,
but possibly that you
couldn't leave your bed.
So it makes it very hard
to be, have a family life,
have a personal life, do shopping,
maintain your job and
do all of these things.
So the question is
why can't people who are
literally stuck in bed
for seven weeks waiting for a part,
why can't they just fix their own chairs?
And partly that's because
the part stream itself
has been starved by the duopoly.
So in Stranded, PIRG collected stories
from people who use power wheelchairs
about their problems
getting parts and service,
they found multiple people
reporting that the $6 inner tube
that their chair used cost
$300 as a Medicare build part,
and that it would take six
to eight weeks to procure.
So you would have a flat
for six to eight weeks
while you waited for
your chair to get fixed.
There was an instance
of a $20 power button
that literally turned on the chair
that cost $500 and took four months.
But even where people can
get parts and they do,
they source them from eBay and
they source them from Amazon.
And there's one great story
about a stability wheel
that they were having
trouble sourcing a couple
and then their son looked
up and he was like,
"That's just a skateboard wheel"
and showed them how to
buy that wheel with cool,
like orange glitter and whatever.
And they just replaced it, right,
So sometimes you can just fix your chair
by going around this
treating them as damage
and routing around them,
but sometimes you get blocked
by digital rights management.
So these chairs use
digital rights management
to restrict access to
their management consoles.
That means that you can't
get diagnostic information
out of them,
it also means that you can't
make routine adjustments.
So for example,
there's often a delay built
into the steering mechanisms.
As you get more proficient
with your chair,
you might wanna reduce that delay,
you can't do that on your own.
Also, if you change the
pressure on your tires
for different terrain
and you wanna adjust the
torque and the motor,
that's also an alteration
needed security dongle for.
So the good news is that
Colorado and June passed the HB
221031,
the consumer right to Repair
Power Wheelchairs Act,
which substantially fixes
a lot of these things.
They did run up against a
really important problem though,
which is that removing DRM as
a felony under federal law,
section 12.1 of the Digital
Millennium Copyright Act
provides for a five year prison
sentence and a $500,000 fine
for providing a tool to bypass DRM.
And so they couldn't authorize people
who wanted to fix wheelchairs
or who used wheelchairs
or used wheelchairs and
wanted to fix wheelchairs.
They couldn't authorize them to make
or provision each other with tools
that would allow them
to affect these repairs.
So instead they did an end run around it
and they ordered the wheelchair companies
to just provide the tools
that would allow them to read
at the diagnostics and so on.
This is a good solution,
but really it's not enough.
And so I just wanna finish by saying
that Electronic Frontier Foundation,
we're representing Matthew
Green and Andrew Bunny Wang
in a lawsuit to overturn
section 1201 of the DMCA.
And finally to say that, as I noted,
there's some deep structural problems
that make it hard for people
who use powered wheelchairs.
Right, there's the duopoly,
there's Medicare only
paying for indoor chairs
and not supporting
preventative maintenance
and better repair doesn't
solve any of those problems,
but it does fix wheelchairs.
Right, and that in itself
is something worth doing
and we can walk and chew
gum, we need to do both.
- That story,
how many people out here were
surprised about that story?
Have you guys experienced
modern healthcare
that raised your hand?
(crowd chuckles)
Raise your hand if you've been frustrated
with the inefficiencies,
the lack of communication,
the broken insurance system.
Yeah, okay.
We can all relate with that, absolutely.
As clinicians, we relate with that.
And as patients ourselves, we do.
We're gonna transition a little bit
to another very strong
theme in modern medicine,
which is just that we often are unaware
of how the tools we use actually function.
And so (indistinct) can take us away.
- So my day job, I'm an anesthesiologist
and I somewhat (indistinct) say
that I hack people's brains.
So I turn you off and somebody
pokes you with a hot knife
and I turn you back on again.
If it's a neurosurgery,
we blow on it before we put it back in,
but
(crowd chuckles)
it's widely accepted among our profession
that it's less than ideal
to wake up during surgery.
And so one of the things
that we used as a monitor
that helps us in addition
to a couple other variables,
kind of keep track on how deep a patient
is under anesthesia, it's
called the BIS monitor.
We've used it for about the last 20 years,
it has been the topic of
1000s of academic papers
that really investigate
how anesthetics even work.
So it's something that we're
all very familiar with.
And without getting too much in the weeds,
this is a monitor,
the name BIS is derived from how it works,
it takes electrical signals
of the brain, the EEG,
and it processes it to
produce a unit list,
dimensional list number
that people can trend.
So 20 patients nice and
deep under anesthesia,
80, they're about to wake up
and sue you from malpractice.
So for a long time, that name BIS
was derived because
most people understood,
this is something that looks
at what's called the bispectral index,
which doesn't matter,
it's just a way that you
can analyze that EEG.
Last year, a really
awesome doc at Harvard,
Christopher Connor
reverse engineered these
previously proprietary algorithms.
So there's a black box,
nobody's ever really
seen under the hood here.
He reversed those algorithms
and showed that actually this device
isn't producing a
bi-spectral index at all,
it's looking at a completely
different aspect of the EEG,
which is a little unusual
because a lot of the
research that we've based
and used this monitor to conduct
has operated under this base assumption
that the manufacturer
has never bothered to correct or operate.
And it's kind of a little bit unfortunate
because I think in situations like this,
when we're using these clinical devices
without fully understanding
where they're getting their information,
how they're producing and how we use it,
we miss opportunities to innovate,
we miss opportunities to be
able to use these devices
in different situations,
or to say that they may be less than ideal
for a particular use context.
And I just don't really understand
why we have to live in a paradigm
where these things are so
locked down and proprietary.
And if this is a concern
for clinical devices
that are relatively reliable,
that we've used for the last 20 years,
I'm even more worried
about this coming tsunami of
clinical AI/ML algorithms.
If I had a Dogecoin for
every Silicon Valley guide,
a medical conference, who said,
I've got this AI algorithm
that's gonna revolutionize
the way you practice medicine,
save you billions, I'd have like $4.
(crowd laughing)
So Corey, like why should
we not lift our hands
and welcome our new
clinical AI overlords?
- So, I mean, think that
this is probably an audience
that is well up on all the different ways
that ML can go very wrong.
We have a whole village here at DEFCON
where you can see people giving ML
all kind of hallucinations and
tricking it in lots of ways,
deliberately and accidentally.
It sometimes has some weird failure modes.
And of course that's true of people.
People make mistakes, people
have biases and so on,
but there's one thing about a number
that's given to you by software that is,
I think more dangerous
than a number that's
given to you by human,
which is the degree of
trust we put into it,
that if you take a process that
would normally take someone
aback and have them say,
"Wait a second, that can't be right."
And you have a computer emit
that as a precise number,
instead of as a kind of squishy judgment,
you can empiricism wash your
weird ideas and people go,
"Oh yeah, and I guess
algorithms can't be racist.
There's no such thing as
racist math", to which I say,
meet my friend, the phenologist,
he'd like to measure your
skull with his calipers.
So I think that when you combine
the already difficult situation
in which people often defer
to medical professionals
about things that they're
uniquely situated to describe
because they're part of
their subjective response
to their pathologies,
and then you add a computer
in the mix that says,
"No, everything is fine, it
becomes very hard to imagine
how patients are gonna be
able to exert bodily autonomy,
and autonomy over their care."
And I did wanna add
about that awesome paper
about the BIS monitor that this audience
I think will appreciate,
the guy who reversed the BIS monitor,
one of the ways that
he was able to do this
is by building an emulator,
which turned out to be really easy
'cause the core DSP in the BIS monitor
is a TI DSP that's used
widely in video game systems.
So he could use MAME, which is just great.
(crowd laughing)
- It's rad.
So we've talked about algorithmic bias
and empiricism washing
and how we're all kind of
really aware that these
algorithms can have bias
unintentionally sometimes
just so fully based on the
data that you put into it
or the training set of the
demographic composition
of the individuals that comprise it.
But then it becomes even more concerning,
and a lot of this talks talking
about dystopian futures,
when you consider
adversarial machine learning.
And so if you're not familiar with that,
I meant many of you are,
think about ways in which
an intelligent adversary
could attack machine learning algorithms
to manipulate the outcome.
Right, they could attack classifications,
they could attack training sets,
change what the ground truth is
and design an attack
that manipulates the
outcome of the algorithm,
that could be done in a
variety of really scary ways
for a lot of really scary purposes.
If it's to manipulate you
into buying something,
you can see a financial motivation
in the healthcare space,
you can imagine organizations,
companies, entities
doing that as to compete with one another
and make their particular
AI algorithm less effective,
for example.
There are even some papers out there
that are quite concerning where
it's not necessarily the entire population
that may be impacted by
adversarial machine learning,
but you can craft attacks
that the outcome of that only impacts
a certain group of people,
terrifying implications there.
And one of which
that I'm gonna have a little
bit of a call to action,
and this whole talk is
kind of a call to action,
but of the people in the world
that are best suited to
understand the perils of this
and be equipped
to help defend the future
of humanity in this,
I think hackers are probably
right there at the top, right?
So two things, one,
continue the transparency
that we've talked about,
these BIS monitor as an
example about how we as hackers
are generally in support
of far more transparency,
especially with these algorithms
that touch every aspect of our life.
And then also that we
possess a unique skillset.
One that can understand
how malicious adversaries
just can attack these,
how we can defend against them
and how we can better
secure the infrastructure
that will then
hopefully with the promise
of a lot of this technology,
potentially give us huge insights
into clinical care, right,
improve treatments, new
medications that can completely
do away with pathologies we
never thought would be possible.
And so that kind of peril and promise,
we need you out there
to make sure
that these things that
would thwart that future,
that promising future
don't come to fruition.
So we're hopeful in that.
- Let's switch a little
bit from the doom and gloom
to flip the script and talk about
what happens when hackers pone themselves
and are actually able
to take the initiative
and innovate on some of this stuff.
- Yeah, absolutely.
So as you probably know, one
in 10 Americans has diabetes,
92 million Americans are pre-diabetic
and diabetes while anyone can get it
disproportionately falls
on marginalized people,
it's a disease of poverty.
And so people who have
diabetes are structurally,
find it difficult to
demand high quality care
and to push back against abusive practices
by med tech firms.
So in 2013, some people with diabetes
decided to do something about this,
two hackers, Dana Lewis and John Costak
took continuous glucose monitor
and figured out a way
to hook it up directly
to a insulin pump
and wrote an algorithm that
monitored your blood sugar,
tried to predict where it was going
and tried to dose you with
insulin as you went along,
and the closed loop pancreas
artificial pancreas was born.
They call themselves "loopers"
and they gather on a
platform called openaps.org.
A lot of the people who
built these tools early on
were parents of young children.
So my friend, Soul Kajaro who
is a video game developer,
he worked on a bunch of
Solarky games in the old days,
his young son who was
two years old at the time
had just been diagnosed
with type one diabetes
and was in daycare.
And the people who worked at the daycare
were very diligent and caring,
but they weren't experts
in managing diabetes.
And so he wanted to be able
to oversee, partially automate
and correct and get alerts
on his son's insulin levels,
blood sugar levels.
And so he became a core
developer on the looping tools.
And there's a lot of hacker
overlap with this looping stuff,
and it's one of these great examples
of hackers helping normies,
where the stuff that
we build for ourselves
ends up sort of leaking out
into the rest of the world.
And there's a reason
that hackers want to
build looping software,
and it's not because they're too lazy
to manage their blood sugar,
it's because doing a routine
task perfectly all the time
is why we have computers.
There's a reason we replace
all of our routine tasks as
hackers with shells scripts.
Do you remember when
Unix systems used to ship
without a prebuilt cron job
that rotated the log files
and they would just crash every three days
'cause no one could remember
to rotate their log files?
And replacing the routine
things in your life
with a shell script is
especially important
if when you screw it up, it's
hard for you to think right,
and if you screw up your blood sugar,
it can impair your cognition.
So we lost a dear friend
last year, excuse me,
I always get choked up at this point,
but Dan Kaminski died last
year, he had diabetes,
he had management problems with it,
he was in lockdown, he was isolated,
other people couldn't
see what was going on
and you can see how even
someone as brilliant as our
Powell Dan couldn't manage a routine task
perfectly all the time
and could experience a literally
fatal cascading failure,
which is why we love this stuff.
So you have these hackers
who are hacking hardware,
hacking software,
and making their own algorithms
and to do this stuff,
they need to rely entirely
on jailbroken hardware
so they can affect these changes.
So I'll bring it back to you guys.
- Yeah, I mean
a question that we very commonly
get is this sounds awesome,
why aren't more doctors
recommending these
systems to their patients,
why aren't more patients
coming and asking for this type of care?
And we just wanna kind
of hit a little bit on
some of the reasons why we
need to do some more work.
So the first is education.
Again, these were not
tools and technologies
that existed even 10 years
ago when we were training,
let alone the endocrinologists
who's been out in practice for 30 years.
And even as widely adopted
as these are in the hacker community,
I think Loop, which is one
of the biggest platforms
has about 9,000 people using it,
and there are 1.9 million
type one diabetics.
So we really have a lot of work to do
to sort raise awareness there.
Doctors who learn about this
are going to just
inherently worry about its
clinical efficacy and safety.
And put aside the fact
that we give diabetics
a vile of a 100 units of insulin,
tell 'em to go figure it out on their own,
but people are gonna say,
"Oh, can't they screw it up
if they set this up themselves?"
and we're starting to just now
get some really interesting data
to support the efficacy of these
different types of devices.
There's a really interesting
paper published last year
by some folks at Stanford
and Loop in Miami,
that was really unique in its design
and kind of demonstrated the promise
of decentralized clinical trials.
They basically just found people
who are signing up for Loop.
so Loop is one of the
systems and they said,
hey, we're just gonna
pull some data from you
if that's okay with you,
give us your baseline data,
we're gonna see how you do
over the next six months,
but we're not gonna tell
you how to use this tech.
And all of the patients
who were in this study
had to work with the community,
troubleshoot guidelines on their own.
So it was really not a very
paternalistic platform to say,
"You need to follow
this protocol exactly",
but the results were pretty incredible.
Patients after using
this closed Loop system
were able to spend longer time
in a normal blood sugar range.
They were able to avoid,
release significant low
blood sugar episodes,
and there were no episodes
of sort of the more
feared complication DKA.
So really impressive technology
that we're starting to see is efficacious
and is pretty low risk
that people can use.
One thing I do want to kind of comment
on some of these studies
and in the population in general
is that it does sort of
trend to reflect some of the inequities
that we previously discussed.
So the 500 or so patients in this study,
90% of them were white,
85% of them were college
educated or higher,
70% of them made more
than a $100,000 a year
and 95% had private insurance.
So there's work for us as we continue
to push some of these
open source platforms
to make sure that the inequity
that pervades modern medicine
and formal clinical trials
doesn't persist in these spaces.
Lastly, we'll just talk
really quickly about
this idea of risk.
So in order to give
something to a patient,
you need to have a discussion with them
what's called informed consent.
We talk about the risk, we
talk about the benefits,
we make sure that you understand those.
Claudia and I are working on
developing this concept of
a cyber informed consent
that we'd be happy to
talk about with people
if they're interested.
But if your doctor
is gonna be giving you these
connected technologies,
we'd like to think that
they should be able
to have that kind of discussion
about the potential risks.
And there are risks
that arise from the connected
nature of the techniques.
- Yeah, just someone to just
quickly pull the audience here,
like who here has had gone into a hospital
and had a procedure done and a doctor
or someone else has gone to them
and talked to them about the risk?
Like, okay, you might have an infection
or you lose blood or anything
like that, raise your hand.
Okay.
How many people have out
there have ever had someone
talk to them about the risks,
their privacy or security
of connected medical devices
when they get them?
Anyone?
Yeah, that's a problem, right.
But it's a problem in so
many really interesting ways.
First of all, it's a problem
because it's not the right
thing that should happen.
We should be informed of these things too.
Often you do not have a choice,
right, what dictates
what insulin pump you get
when you're a diabetic,
isn't necessarily a free market thing
where you can go and decide
and look along all of them
and say, "This is the one I want"
because it's the one that
protects my privacy the most,
or it's the one that has the
greatest hardware features.
You don't have those choices
in our modern healthcare system.
It's an insurance thing.
And the last thing I would say
about cyber security informants
that I know cyber got
I, this isn't whiskey,
but I'm not supposed
to say that at DEFCON.
But the other interesting thing
is that the people telling
you about the risks
have no idea what the hell
they're talking about.
Like how many of your doctors
could even articulate basic
security and privacy concepts?
So the people tasked with asking you
to consent to this don't
themselves understand it,
don't talk to you about it,
and there are structural reasons
why that's a really hard nut to crack.
And so if changing that
requires education, awareness
and a lot of other things.
We're gonna also talk about
the elephant in the room now,
which is a lot of the features
that the Looper community
was able to accomplish
with this technology
were because the devices
themselves were vulnerable.
That is an interesting prospect.
And I have a hypothesis here,
I want to just do a
little thought experiment
in the audience
because I think this is
a unique composition.
Who here would wear a
vulnerable insulin pump,
infusing insulin into their body,
it has Bluetooth connectivity
with no authentication
that you can change the settings off
just by connecting to it,
who here would wear that device
and rely on it to take care
of them every single day?
Please raise your hand wide.
Yeah.
I'm sorry.
- If it allowed you.
- If it allowed you to do
those feature sets, forgive me,
I put a little caveat on it.
You can wear this device, it's vulnerable,
but it allows you to have
all those cool features
that the Looper community has made.
Please raise your hand.
- [Woman In Audience] I have a question.
- Question.
- [Woman In Audience] I
guess, is there research to
sort of securing it from
an outside perspective?
- Yeah, so there's a question about,
is there a way to secure it
and have all the feature sets?
We're gonna get to that in a minute,
but the question to the audience is
who would wear a vulnerable pump
if it allow you to have
all these cool features
that the Looper community is making?
Raise your hand.
Who here would never
wear a vulnerable pump
that had no authentication?
Well, so this is the elephant in the room,
this is that the seeming conflict
between the Looper community
and the security space.
We've had multiple security
researchers over the years
discuss real vulnerabilities
in these connected medical devices
that pose really scary safety risks,
not just to your privacy,
but to your physiology,
to your wellbeing.
The FDA, in my opinion,
has done a fantastic job
over the last 10 years
of pushing device manufacturers
through the right thing about security.
They've done the postmarket guidance,
they have a pre-market
guidance document that says,
"If you wanted market a
device in the United States,
you have to be this tall
on the security side,
you have to do these basic practices."
And I will say this,
the FDA also is the first to the podium
to defend security researchers
when device manufacturers
try to take a shit on them.
When device manufacturers
tried to intimidate
and or do less than desirable things
for security researchers,
the FDA is at the podium
defending this work.
So, but they're tasked with
the safety of medical devices.
And so if there's an issue,
if there's a vulnerability
in a medical device,
they might issue a recall.
Then those devices
are no longer going to be
in the community for loopers
to innovate on.
This is the seeming conflict.
And one of the points of
this talk was to try to say,
we want our cake and
we want to eat it too.
What we should be doing
instead of fighting
between a looper community
against the FDA is instead
using this as an example
of a market failure
that consumers, patients,
parents of type one diabetics
want access to the data.
They want better control
over the technology
that keeps them alive.
And that's something that
they demand and they deserve.
At the same time, we want
secure medical devices
that don't have hard coded passwords.
What we should be doing is
pushing device manufacturers
do the right thing.
And what we also don't wanna
do in this dystopian future
is allow for documents like
the pre-market guidance,
recommendations that
devices should be secure
to be a reason medical
device manufacturer's site,
as to why they can't be open.
Why you can't have access
to your own damn data,
because they'll say,
"Oh, we can't expand the attack surface."
Why don't we just challenge
that paradigm and say,
"Why don't you deploy better
secure development practices?",
retool your security
infrastructure to be both open,
transparent,
allowing for our patients
to have access to that data,
and then far more defensible
from a security posture.
Is that fair to say, is that
the best thing we could do?
Yeah.
Well, we need you to
out there telling people
that it should happen.
(crowd applauding)
- So I wanna close this
out by talking about
how this all interacts with cyber law
and the stuff EFF does and competition.
So med tech companies don't like
that patients are jail
breaking their devices
and they use laws like the
Digital Millennium Copyright Act
to take down software
that allows you to change your firmware.
It might allow you to change your firmware
to make it more vulnerable,
it also might allow you
to change your firmware
to make it more secure.
So for example, Abbott Labs got GitHub
to take down LibreLink,
which was software for the
Libre 2 glucose monitor in 2019
citing the Digital
Millennium Copyright Act.
And they argue that this
was about patient safety,
but a thing that is a common
motif in med tech research,
especially around medical implants
and especially around medical implants
for people with diabetes
is that firms do not
respond in a timely fashion
or sometimes at all
to really significant
vulnerability disclosures
about their products when
they're not being used by loopers
to give themselves a better
healthcare experience.
So for example, in 2019,
a couple of hackers,
Billy Rios and Jonathan Butts
did a responsible disclosure to Medtronic
to tell them that their
mini med paradigm pump
was super vulnerable.
And they sat on that bone for
two years, and then last year,
a black hat, the researchers
who revealed the bone,
released a proof of concept
called "A universal remote
for killing people."
and that's what actually got
Medtronic to take action.
So this is a pattern
that's repeated across
all the major hardware vendors,
including companies like
Johnson and Johnson,
this track record of foot dragging
when there are issues that
are live threats to patients,
but leaping to action
when there's a live threat to profits.
In the shareholder communications
that these firms make,
they're pretty blatant
about what they want to do,
they want to build closed
ecosystems for closed loops,
where you have a single vendor
providing the algorithm,
the glucose monitor, the pump.
And sometimes they talk about
proprietary consumables,
right, either proprietary formulations
or proprietary packaging
for the formulations.
Basically they want to turn
your artificial pancreas
into an inkjet printer
and use all the printer tactics
that we have historically
seen in the printer world.
And this has triggered an absolute inferno
of mergers and acquisitions activity
as private equity companies
see a lot of potential upside
from building these closed ecosystems
and the closed ecosystems beget
get more closed ecosystems.
So there's a great
advocate for this stuff,
a woman who calls herself
"The Savvy Diabetic",
her name is Joanne Milo.
And in June, she sent a letter to the FDA
objecting to the merger of
a glucose monitor company
called Dexcom, with a
pump company called inlet.
And although this was
super anti-competitive,
there's a reason Dexcom was doing it,
which is that Medtronic
had bought another insulin pump company
and locked out Dexcom.
They did that with a
company called Companion
and in tandem had also blocked them.
So here you have this company
that makes the glucose monitor
and is watching all the insulin pumps
get bought up by other
glucose monitor companies
and locked down.
So they're like, "We have to
have an insulin company too,
we have to an insulin pump company too",
but for all that, they're
the victim in this,
they're also a terrible company
with a long history of
threatening their patients
when the patients take actions
to try and come out
and extract their data.
So none of these firms
have their patients backed
all the time.
And if we allow them to merge
and create these closed ecosystems,
it comes at the expensive patients
who have idiosyncratic
problems with their health
that they wanna resolve by
mixing and matching pumps
and algorithms, consumables, and monitors.
It also harms them in that it
makes the supply chain brittle
because if your pump only
works with one glucose monitor
and that glucose monitor can't be found
because of a supply chain problem,
then your whole pump breaks down.
We saw what single sourcing
vendors did during the pandemic
and after the pandemic
with things like the
baby formula shortage.
So it is true when these firms say
patients might harm themselves
by modifying their devices.
It is true,
and it is true when they
security researchers
or security staff say,
"We are only locking these down
because we want to help our patients."
It's true that that's a thing that they do
and it's something that comes up a lot
when I speak at DEFCON
and in other hacker forums
about competition more broadly,
I work on the competition team at EFF,
and we're talking about
dismantling big tech
and letting smaller
firms enter the market.
And oftentimes I'll speak
at an event like this
and someone will come up
and say, "You have no idea
the eye wateringly terrible stuff
I block every day in my job at
Apple or Facebook or Google."
And they're absolutely telling the truth.
But the thing that they need to recognize,
that we all need to recognize
is your boss will pay you to
defend me from his enemies,
your boss
is never gonna pay you to
defend me from your boss.
And this is why ultimately if
we're gonna have an arbiter
that decides what mods are
safe and which ones aren't,
it can't be the manufacturers.
There's a role for the
FDA to show up and say,
"No, don't do that, you'll kill yourself."
But if we rely on the
manufacturers to do it,
sometimes they'll be sincere,
and sometimes they'll be
talking out of their ass,
and what they really mean is don't do that
or you're gonna spook our shareholders.
And we shouldn't have to
figure out which one they mean,
we should have access to a
democratically accountable system
that tells us what the truth is.
- Can we just clap on that.
(audience applauding)
- On that note, we have a
little less than 10 minutes,
if anybody has any questions,
we'd love to get a couple
of those outta the way,
we've got a mic back there.
Folks are able to get in line and yeah,
thanks so much for coming out.
- [Male Audience Member] You
talk about these acquisitions
and why isn't the FTC
getting involved antitrust?
- Yeah.
You know what?
I got good news for you about that,
so the FTC for 40 years took a nap.
The official doctrine on
antitrust enforcement in America
and most of the world for 40 years
has been something
called consumer welfare,
which basically ignored
all monopoly problems
and allowed for example, Microsoft
to corner 95% of the OS market
and lots and lots of mergers.
Two companies make all
the beer in the world,
there's one professional wrestling league,
all the glasses are made by the company
that makes all the frames
and owns all the retailers,
it's terrible.
But five years ago, a law
student named Lena Conn
published an astoundingly
good Yale law review paper
called "Amazon's Antitrust Paradox"
that demolished the arguments
for antitrust forbearance,
today that law student of five years ago
is the chairwoman of the FTC.
She has promulgated amazing new guidelines
to block future mergers,
and she's just announced
antitrust scrutiny
of privacy practices by firms
bypassing the deadlock in Congress
and promising to regulate firms on privacy
directly through the
administrative branch.
She is a hero, she needs our support.
There is a public listening
session on September the eighth
that the FTC is holding on privacy.
You can go and intervene.
Your position as technologists
is really gonna make a difference.
We are in a moment in which we
have better news on antitrust
than we have had since I was 10 years old,
I cannot overstate how fucking great
the antitrust picture is right now.
It is amaze-balls.
(crowd applauding)
- [Male Audience Member Two]
I have a question about trust,
as somebody who lives and
breathes, this is a BIPAP user.
- Closer to the mic, please.
- [Male Audience Member
Two] Hi, as a BIPAP user,
what you've been describing as
sort of the dystopian future
is already kind of reality for me,
Phillips Respironics
has been killing people
knowingly for years
and took them three years to
actually recall their products.
Similarly, ResMed, if you
don't pay them enough,
they're not gonna tell you
that you have changed oaks breathing,
even though it's just a flip
that you need to do all that.
How can we actually have trust
in the medical institutions today?
- That's a really good question.
Sunshine is the best
disinfectant and Cory,
I mean, why is this black
box proprietary aspect
of some of these things
seen as a competitive business practice?
Why is there this or borrows between,
oh, if we can't keep these
things secret, we can't innovate?
- So I think the problem
is, again, an antitrust.
I think that when you
have an industry dominated
by like five firms,
if they all settle on the
same convenient bullshit,
if I told you about it,
I'd have to kill you.
No one who's credible,
which is to say no one who works
for a comparably sized firm
steps up and says, "No, no,
no, wait, that's nonsense."
We absolutely can share this
information with people.
Not only that, but when
firms are very concentrated,
they have a lot of money
to spend on lobbying.
So the way I think that
you get good regulation
is by making sure that firms
are neither too big to
fail nor too big to jail.
People looked at that
photo of Donald Trump
at the top of Trump Tower
with all the people who
run all the tech companies
around a table in 2016 and said,
"Isn't that terrible
that they're meeting with Donald Trump?"
And I'm like, you know
what's really terrible?
That they fit around one goddamn table,
because if they can fit around a table,
they will sit around a table,
and when they sit around the table,
they're gonna figure out how to screw us.
And so this is why as a
prerequisite, it's not enough,
but it is an absolute
prerequisite for good regulation.
Sectors have to be diverse
with firms who will blow
the whistle on each other
when they're telling
convenient commercial lies.
(audience applauding)
- [Male Audience Member Three] So I saw
the five minute mark, so
I'll try and make this quick.
I have one of the
Abbott, Freedom or Libre,
whatever it's called.
It's gen one, it's NFC only.
And your question about,
would I trust this with,
I don't don't need insulin, thank God yet,
but there's a gen two with Bluetooth.
I'm not getting that.
So I have to upload my data to the cloud
as a necessity to inform my doctor.
Also, I had to advocate
myself to get this,
and then I was gonna pay outta pocket.
It just happens to be on my insurance.
So I'm very lucky, I'm very
privileged to have insurance.
So that's kind of where we're
I'm with diabetics in general.
Yeah.
I had another question,
but I don't think there's enough time,
so I'll let other people go.
- Thank you.
- I think that one of the
things all firmware can do
is let you disable the
Bluetooth on your device.
And that's one of the reasons
that we should support all firmware.
- Real quick addendum,
also, the other thing
that I could have done
with that hacked firmware
is not have to replace
this every two weeks.
- Right.
- [Male Audience Member
Three] I'm fortunate
that I have good health insurance.
However, my insurance dictates
what devices I can use.
So I'm wondering if you have any comments
on where the insurance
companies fit in all of this,
and if you follow the money,
there's quite a bit of money
in the medical insurance business.
- That's a really great
question and comment,
I mean, I'm sorry that
you're in the position
of so many other people,
which is you may wanna select a device
for a particular reason,
but you can't because of your insurance.
One of the interesting arguments
I've heard or opportunities
is to talk about how these devices
pose risks to some of those payers.
And what am I talking about?
Health insurance is gonna care
if they have to spend more money on you,
they also care how much the devices
are that they have to spend
to treat your illness.
And so if we can talk
about risks to privacy,
risks to security and what
the ultimate outcome of that
would be from their bottom line,
it may be a persuasive argument.
They also are very commonly
looking for reasons to try to save a buck.
And so as these things become
more and more connected,
as these devices and there are
more and more vulnerabilities
found in the wild, their
recalls can be quite costly.
That'll eventually hit insurance
company's bottom lines.
And I could see them in the future
doing a risk calculation to say,
"Well, this pump might cost
50 bucks more than this other,
but it's more durable, it's more secure,
we're having less headaches with this."
And so more and more as we can,
they themselves can realize that,
I think we'll move in a better direction,
but also you as a patient
should let them know,
that is really important.
Being a voice and advocate
for choice and of that choice,
privacy and security being
part of that is very persuasive
to the people that regulate
insurance companies as well.
And so it's gonna be a
long haul, keep going,
but raise your voice in that
so that we can change that dynamic.
And then also just try to advocate broadly
so that it isn't so stark a contrast
between device manufacturers.
Really, we wanna raise the
entire device ecosystem
into their security and privacy,
that would help all people
across all types of insurance.
- Yeah, we don't wanna
create a market where like
if you're lucky,
your insurance lets you
eat in the restaurant
where they're forced to wash their hands
after using the toilet,
but otherwise they don't.
We just wanna eliminate the restaurants
where they cook your food
without washing your hands,
without washing their hands.
Right, that's what we actually want.
We just wanna abolish the bad devices.
- What an advertising metaphor to end on.
We got 90 seconds before
we turn into a pumpkin
so I don't want someone
to ask a great question
that we can't answer.
So thank you guys so much for coming.
We're gonna head over here,
anybody in line who wants
to come and find us,
we'd be happy to talk outside.
Really appreciate everyone
coming, have a great con.
- I'll be at the EFF booth later as well.
(crowd applauding)