- Let's welcome Christopher on
and he is a first time speaker,
so everybody knows what that means.
(audience applauding)
How is it going?
- Good cheers.
Good evening everyone.
So I'm here to talk about SCCM,
a couple of passwords that it stores.
How to get them from different
attacker perspectives,
and a little bit of my story
in figuring out how this all works.
So I started my career in cyber security
around eight years ago,
as a penetration tester
with an interest in internal
infrastructure testing.
Quickly pivoted to doing
some red teaming as well,
and part of that skill set
was needing to develop
the ability to attack AD.
And after doing a couple of
assessments in that line,
I realized that oftentimes AD Security
isn't necessarily controlled by AD itself,
it's controlled by the configuration
of large scale enterprise
solutions like SCCM.
So my story with SCCM started
in a client engagement
where a client had configured
it to use network boot.
So for the uninitiated,
like I was at the time,
this is what that looks like.
If we're connected to the
same network as a SCCM server
that's set up for network boot,
we can prompt to do a network boot,
it'll get an IP address,
figure out where the
network boot server is,
and then start downloading an OS image
that it's going to boot into.
After it's done downloading that OS image,
it proceeds to boot it,
and at the end of this
boot process we end up
in something called a Windows
Preinstallation Environment,
so WinPE, it's a stripped
down version of Windows
that has like the bare minimum
libraries, no Explorer,
and it can run things like
a Configuration Manager
client like this one.
at the end of it's set up
we get prompted with this password screen.
So if we look at the screen,
it's asking us for some random password.
On that client engagement that I was on
the only thing the client gave me
was the password for the screen.
So put in the password,
click through a couple of dialogue boxes
and I ended up with a VM
that was domain-joined
that had all of the
clients security software
and software installed.
This kind of blew my mind at the time
because I knew that if I'm ending up
with a domain-joined machine,
then there has to be some
domain codes somewhere
that are doing the domain-joining.
So I chatted to the client,
we figured that let's go
searching for the creds,
see what the creds are, and
that's where the journey began.
So one of the first
things that we discovered
is in a lot of these
Windows PE Environments,
if you press F8, it
will pop a system shell.
Now, that's more or less useful
depending on which part of the
deployment process you're in,
but it gives you the ability
to interact with the
environment and run tools.
One of the interesting
things that you can do
once you have this command shell there,
is you can dump out the
environment variables.
So after you start an
operating system install,
you can write a VB script file
that dumps out the environment variables,
and one of the really interesting ones is
_SMSTS reserved one and reserve two
Those are the Network Access Account creds
that the Windows PE Environment uses
to talk to the SCCM server
and download the software
that it's going to install.
So this is stuff like the
operating system image,
and the individual software packages
that need to get installed.
This however, is not the
set of creds that are used
to domain-join the machine,
so we carried on our search.
And eventually, after
interrupting install midway
and mounting it in a different VM,
I figured out that if you look
at the Unattended.xml file
after you've started an
operating system deployment
in the C Windows Panther
Unattended folder,
you actually find the domain-joining creds
that this machine is gonna use to domain
yeah, to join to the domain.
That was really interesting
in this specific client's estate
because it ended up being that
these credentials had
workstation administrative access
to all the workstation and laptops
across their entire AD environment,
which was a big deal for them,
they had spent a lot of effort
trying to harden their AD.
Over the years, we've seen
this kind of story repeated,
so I've pulled the Network Access Account
on certain clients and in one estate,
it ended up having administrative access
to the SCCM service itself,
and then we could do some lateral movement
and credential theft to get
domain administrative access.
In other states it's actually configured
as domain admin out of the box.
So kind of the TLDR of this is,
there was sufficient evidence
to figure out that these
kinds of credentials
that are exposed to the
PXE boot environment,
a lot of times have
quite privileged access
over the active directory
environment that they're in.
So they're kind of like a
worthwhile target going for,
and it's worth understanding
how to pull those
credentials consistently.
So that was my target,
I knew what I wanted to go after.
And the specific thing
that we're looking at here
is Microsoft Endpoint
Configuration Manager, or SCCM,
or System Center Configuration
Manager, or Config Manager.
In this talk you're gonna
hear me use all of those terms
they refer to the exact same product,
it's basically a software
management product
developed by Microsoft
that is used to deploy,
update, manage, and manage
software on workstations
and servers across an estate.
It's used to patch all kinds of machines
from the most critical domain controllers
and exchange servers
to every single employee
workstation and laptop.
So probably the most important thing
that we need to know going into this is,
what kind of credentials are we targeting?
We've already talked about two kinds,
the network access credentials
and the domain-joining credentials,
but I've actually found three locations
where credentials can be configured
where those credentials
will be pushed down
to Configuration Manager clients.
So the first is the
Network Access Account.
Again, this is used
primarily by Windows PE
because it's not domain-joined,
so it needs some sets of credentials
to talk to SCCM to download software.
There's a lot of recent
research that come out
on how to pull those credentials.
And I'm going to in this talk add
kind of the operating system deployment
and PXE deployment method
of pulling these credentials
to the current view.
In order to properly
understand the second place
that credentials can be configured,
we need to understand how
task sequences work in SCCM.
So task sequences are
ultimately a set of instructions
that allows us to take a blank machine
and apply certain steps to it
in order to make a domain-joined machine
that has a bunch of software installed.
So inside a Network Boot Environment,
the task sequence selection screen
is effectively what is shown
in the screenshot here,
and practically speaking
in real life environment,
each of the different types of machines
that you want to build
will end up having an
associated task sequence.
Those task sequences are made
up of task sequence steps
that define the order in which
you need to do operations
in order to get a working machine out.
One of the steps is to
domain join the machine,
this is actually called
Apply Network Settings
and there's a nice convenient box
inside the Configuration Manager console,
where you can set these credentials.
There's also additional places
where these credentials can be configured,
so I'm just gonna run through
them really, really quickly.
So one of the features that SCCM supports
is the ability to make
a new reference image.
That reference image needs to be written
to some kind of network
share in order to save it.
And in order to write to a network share
you obviously need credentials,
so it allows space for those
credentials to be configured.
The second place where you
can configure credentials
is that when you build a
machine, you can obviously set
the local admin password of the machine.
This happens before any
software is installed,
so lapse would take precedence over this,
since it would happen
after the machine is built.
You can run arbitrary
commands as any domain user,
but then you have to
provide the credentials
for that domain user.
And lastly, you can connect
to an arbitrary network folder
in order to pull files down,
if that's part of you
building a new machine.
And as part of that, you need
to provide the credentials
that you're gonna use to
connect to that network folder.
And lastly, in order to
understand the third place
that I found credentials,
you need to understand
how collections work
in Configuration Manager.
So collections are a concept
where we want to apply certain settings
to an entire group of machines
rather than to machines individually.
So what we can do is,
we can create a collection
of those machines,
add all the machines
that we want to apply these settings to,
to that given collection,
and then apply things like task
sequences to the collection.
Now, collections have
an interesting feature
called collection variables,
these are effectively
environment variables
where you can specify a name and a value
for that collection variable,
and these get pushed
to all of the machines
that are in a given collection.
Now, there's nothing
specifically requiring
these collection variables
to store passwords,
but interestingly enough,
SCCM treats it as if it's sensitive,
so it still encrypts it.
It's possible to use
these four credentials,
if they exist and they're configured,
it's worth pulling them down
to see if there is
anything sensitive in them.
And the last thing before we
dig in to how things work,
and how PXE boot in
Configuration Manager works
is some terminology.
So as we have discussed
something like a task sequence
needs to pull down software from a server
in order to apply it to this
machine that you want to build.
That software, whether it's
an operating system image,
whether it's an MSI,
whether it's EXE installer
is what is known as content.
Content is downloaded from a
specific server role in SCCM
called distribution points.
A Configuration Manager client,
like the one that we saw running
inside the Windows PE Environment
has to authenticate to
the distribution point
in order to prove that it has
the authorization, I guess,
to access the content that
it's trying to access.
Similarly, in terms of other things
that a client needs to do,
that might have a bunch
of configuration settings
that it uses to control
which software packages
it decides to download.
And those configuration settings
are what's known as a policy.
So policies are not downloaded
from distribution points,
they're downloaded from
a different SCCM server
called a management point.
Again, the Configuration Manager client
needs to authenticate
to the management point
to prove that it is authorized
to ask for the policies that apply to it.
All right, now that we've
covered all of that,
how does network booting actually work
in Configuration Manager?
So one bit of context that's
kind of useful to understand
is that network booting
and Configuration Manager
is actually part of a
broader set of functionality
that Configuration Manager supports
called operating system deployment.
Operating system deployment mostly
is made up of a task sequence
that is aimed at deploying
a new OS to a machine,
and the policy settings that are needed
in order to make sure that,
that task sequence applies successfully.
There's multiple ways to kick this off,
the video that we saw in the beginning
was using network boot
in order to kick-off
operating system deployment,
but you can actually make ISO files,
or WIM files, or a USB drive
that has the necessary files
on that you can boot off of
in order to start a new
operating system deployment.
What's important to note about this,
is regardless of what method you use
to start your operating system deployment,
all of them boot into a
Windows PE Environment,
run a Configuration Manager client,
and then start to talk to
SCCM to figure out what to do.
Okay, so how does network booting work?
Well, first let's say
we have a blank machine
that doesn't have an OS on it.
We plug it into the network,
and the first thing that we're gonna do,
is we're gonna press the key
that makes the machine
ask for a network boot.
It's going to do a DHCP request
to figure out its IP address,
and to figure out where
the network boot server is.
It's then going to,
after it identifies where
that network would server is,
it's going to make a specific DHCP request
to that DHCP server to tell it,
"Hey, I'm a PXE client,
"I wanna figure out what's going on.
"Please tell me what I need to download
"in order to boot successfully."
And then after it gets
that information from,
in this case a distribution point,
distribution points are responsible
for running PXE as well.
After it gets an information
from a distribution point,
it will then use TFTP in
order to download the files
and kick off the operating
system deployment method.
So once we get all of that done,
we'll boot into an environment,
it will run a Configuration
Manager client,
and the Configuration Manager client
will ask for some kind of password, okay.
So what's this password for?
It's not a username and a
password, it's just the password.
So what is being protected
with this password?
Well, if we investigate what's
going on, on the SCCM server,
when it receives that specific
DHCP request from the client,
it turns out that there's
a specific folder,
RemiInstall, SMSTemp
and inside that folder
specific files are being generated.
So we see two files, a
.var file and a .bcd file.
The bcd file is your standard
boot configuration file
that tells the PXE client
how to boot the image that it received.
But the var file is
actually quite interesting.
this is what is known as
a media variables file,
and it actually contains
all of the configuration
information, I guess,
that the client is going
to be configured with
so that it can authenticate
later on to SCCM.
Turns out the password is
being used to derive a key
that is used to encrypt this file.
We can confirm that that's
kind of what's going on
because using our nice command shell
that we have inside the WinPE Environment,
we can start to analyze the
files that are included.
So WinPE is Windows
running inside a Ram disk,
it actually uses the xDrive by default,
or at least SCCM WinPE does.
And inside there, inside
that specific drive,
there is a Configuration Manager
specific folder called SMS
that contains all of the
binaries and configuration data
that this WinPE Environment needs
in order to successfully boot
and continue the operating
system deployment method.
Inside one of the bin folders,
there's a Config file
called TsBootShell.ini,
and that defines the first command
that's run inside WinPE.
So we see that there's a reference
to something called TsmBootstrap,
and this is what the
Configuration Manager client
is inside a WinPE Environment,
so that screen that we see
that's asking for a password
is the executable TsmBootstrap.exe,
and we can see that it's
called with reference
to a different configuration
directory XSMSData.
Inside that folder there's
a file called variables.dat,
which suspiciously looks the same
as that .var file that we saw earlier.
And it turns out that this executable
does all that DHCP stuff,
pulls the .var file
over TFTP and renames it variables.dat.
So the password we type in the screen
is then used to try and decrypt
variables.dat, all right?
So we know how it works at a high level,
how do we turn this into an actual attack?
Well, the first thing is we
know that the password is used
to try and decrypt this
media variables file,
so we need to get our hands on this file
because we need to use
the contents of that file
for any kind of attack
that we want to perform.
I've written a set of Python
tooling called PXE thief
that I'm planning on releasing
sometime this weekend,
that implements all of these
DHCP requests that are needed
in order to first find
where a PXE server is,
and then prompt the
Configuration Manager server
in order to generate
this media variables file
and find the location of it,
so that we can download it over TFTP.
It looks like this,
so if I run this video,
yes, that worked properly.
We can see that there's kind
of like two main steps here,
we issue a DHCP discovery request
to find the location of an SCCM server,
specifically a distribution point.
And then once we figure out
where the distribution point is,
we issue a specific request to that server
in order to generate
the media variables file
and find out where it is stored on disk.
How does this work?
Okay, first thing we
need to start off with
is with a DHCP discover.
This is a very general thing,
but if you try and prompt
for a network boot,
what is effectively happening is
you're issuing a DHCP discover request
with DHCP option 66 and 67,
so you're asking for those options.
If that environment is set
up to support PXE boot,
the main DCHP server will point
you at the PXE boot server
in the DHCP option 66 in the response.
Once you have the location of that folder,
you can then talk to a port on that folder
that sets aside specifically
for PXE support 4011.
So we generate another DHCP request,
but this time it's a request
packet, not a discover packet.
And we provide the options 93, 250, and 60
inside our own request that
identifies us as a client
that is attempting to do a PXE boot.
The only really weird option
there is the DHCP option 250,
it's a random binary string.
Looking up the documentation,
this is like a Microsoft specific thing
where they identify the
architecture of the machine
that's asking for the network boot.
I haven't actually run into any issues.
The very first DHCP request
packet that I captured
has worked on every single SCCM server
that supports PXE boot that I've run into.
But yes, if theoretically
it only supports x64 or x86,
the string would need to,
the string would be
set to different values
in order to match the
architecture of the machine
that's asking for a network boot.
All right, so if we
provide correct information
and SCCM likes it, then
inside the response,
we get a DHCP option 243,
which is another random
binary string or hack string.
Now, this hack string is kind of special
because there is a field,
a portion of it that is demarcated,
it starts off with a hex bite 01,
and then a length identifier.
And then following that
is the actual location
of the media variables file on the DHCP.
So if the DHCP server likes,
if the SCCM server likes our DHCP request,
it'll actually tell us where
the media variables file is
in this portion of DTP Option 243.
All right, so that allows
us to use any TFTP clients
to download it because
we know where it is,
and then we can move on to the next step.
Now, the important thing is,
we can't really use a password as it is
in order to attempt to decrypt the file.
There has to be some kind of
key derivation that's going on.
So in addition to writing Python tooling
to prompt the SCCM server
into giving us the media variables file,
I've also written a custom Hashcat module
that implements the key
derivation, so that we can perform
a password guessing attack against it.
I decided to use Hashcat
because I like GPU support,
and Hashcat seemed pretty
far along in that space,
so I went with it, it looks like this.
So first obviously, we need to start off
with getting the data into Hashcat.
So my Python tooling
can extract the portion
of the media variables file
that's kind of the header,
so we can confirm that the
encryption is what we expect
because we can check
certain bites in the header
to make sure that it matches
what what we're looking for.
And then the last portion of this string
is effectively some of the encrypted data.
To jump a little bit forward,
the media variables file
is effectively just an XML document.
So we actually know the
beginning of the string,
it's always going to be constant.
So because we have known plain text,
when we are developing a Hashcat module,
we can treat it as a hash
because we can take
our key that we derive,
encrypt it, and then
compare that encrypted value
to the known value here,
and if that matches,
it means that the key that was derived
was from the same password,
so we figure out the password.
Okay, so we have this data,
and we need to feed it into Hashcat.
So I just write it to a file,
and then I start running Hashcat.
I'm gonna skip ahead
because it takes a while to initialize.
But when it actually
starts running the attack,
what I've done here is
I've run my Hashcat module using Roku,
it doesn't really matter,
the module supports all
kinds of cracking options.
You can crack with rules, you
can crack with dictionaries,
you can do a brute-force attack,
all of that kind of works.
Sorry, I didn't want to do that,
let me skip forward again, sorry, okay.
So struggling with PowerPoint media.
Okay, so yes, we can run through Roku.txt
with the known password
at the end of the file,
it cracks successfully.
If we do a benchmark of
the same Hashcat module,
we can see that this is running
at about three giga hashes a second.
It's not the fastest thing in the world,
it's definitely not cracking
at the rate of an NT-hash,
it's not MD4, but it is still pretty fast.
It's about 50% faster than
cracking an NTLM challenge,
NTLMv2 challenge/response.
So if it's a weak password,
it's probably gonna fall,
and you can actually crack
using dictionaries pretty fast.
How did I figure out
how all of this works?
Well, there's one thing to note,
which is SCCM is probably
one of the most logged pieces
of software in the world.
So both on the server side
and on the client side,
everything that each of those pieces
of software is doing is being logged.
If we dig around the WinPE Environment
inside C Windows, Temp, SMSTs log,
we find a text file that contains the log
of what the client is trying to do.
Looking through that at some
point, there's a entry called
loading media variables from
X SMS, data variables.dat,
which is exactly what we're looking for.
We know that it's trying to decrypt that,
and exactly after that, it
logs a call to crypt decrypt.
So crypt decrypt is a function
in the Windows CryptoAPI
that is used in order to, yeah,
attempt to decrypt the file.
So we know that it's using
Windows crypto (laughs),
it's using CryptoAPI
in order to attempt to decrypt this file.
Now, because we have the shell,
we can actually inject custom software
inside the WinPE Environment.
So I used x64dbg loaded it on a random CD,
the CD drive is accessible
within the WinPE Environment.
So we can actually run x64dbg,
and since we know that we're
running TsmBootstrap.exe,
we debug TsmBootstrap.exe,
and we can search for
all intermodular calls.
Here highlighted in red
is effectively a series
of intermodular calls,
where it seems to be setting up
and initializing the crypto functions,
then calling them deriving a key,
and destroying what it's initialized.
So that looks like roughly
what we're looking for.
So how does it work?
Well, if we actually debug
these individual calls
to try and identify what's going on,
one thing that we'll notice is that
when CryptCreateHash is called,
the second function, the second parameter
that is passed to it
is the hex value, 8004.
If we look at the function
definition CryptCreateHash
in the Windows documentation,
the second argument is
an algorithm identifier,
and 8004 corresponds to a SHA-1 hash.
So we are creating a SHA-1
hash of the actual password
that we're passing in.
So the argument to CryptCreateHash
is the password that
we typed into that box.
In this case, I typed A, so we see A as,
the there's a pointer to a string value.
So we are hashing A with SHA-1,
and then we are calling
CryptDeriveKey using that hash.
The second argument to
CryptDeriveKey here is 66OE.
The Windows API functions are
actually pretty consistent,
so it turns out that CryptDeriveKey,
the second argument is also
an algorithm identifier.
And if we go look up that
algorithm identifier,
it is telling us that we're deriving a key
for an AES-128 encrypted value.
Okay, so we have an
idea of what it's doing,
but we don't really know
what CryptDeriveKey does
in order to get its key.
Turns out if you just scroll
down in the documentation,
Microsoft was kind enough
to actually document
exactly how the key derivation works.
So we take our shell and hash,
do a bunch of stuff to it,
and then we get an AES-128 key out.
What the Hashcat module involved doing,
was re-implementing this in OpenCL.
Hashcat is great,
it has some really nice
standard cryptographic functions
built into the libraries that it provides.
So we can actually use all
of those standard libraries
in order to perform the same actions
that are documented here.
And then at the end, we'll
get a key that again,
we can encrypt a known value,
compare that to the data
that we provided in.
And if it matches,
then we know that we've
guessed the password.
If we've guessed the password,
we've guessed the key,
which means that we can
decrypt our variables.dat file,
that we were going for in the,
yeah, that we were going for.
So which are the important variables
that we wanna pull out of this?
Well, they're highlighted in red.
The most important is not the
one that's highlighted there,
it's SMSTS media PFX,
which is a public private key pair
that is effectively the
certificate that the client uses
to authenticate itself
to the management point
in order to pull down policies
that PFX, as most PFX's
are, is password-protected.
There is a value called SMSmedia GUID.
Let me actually just
highlight this, laser pointer.
Okay, so I think you can see that.
Yeah, so SMS media GUID
which is a string value that
is used to encrypt this PFX.
So the first 31 characters
of the media GUID
is used to encrypt the PFX.
And then lastly, there
is a value called SMSTSMP
that points at the media, sorry,
the management point
that we need to talk to
in order to pull down the policies.
So we have, at this point,
all of the information that we need
to actually successfully
start communication with SCCM,
because we have the certificate,
we have the server we need to talk to,
and we have the password
for the certificate.
Okay, so how does client comms work?
Well, let's go back to our password screen
that we started off with.
One good way to figure
out what's going on here
is to actually start using wireshark,
to monitor the HTTP traffic that's passed
between our Configuration
Manager client and the server,
so we type in the known password.
What we see then is this HTTP request,
this is a CCM post to CCM system request
with a request assignment's XML message,
this request assignment's XML message
is effectively the client asking for,
"Hey, I'm a Configuration Manager client,
"please tell me what
policies I need to install."
This request is actually authenticated
by a bunch of signatures.
We see client token signature,
we see CCM client ID signature,
and we see CCM client timestamp signature.
All of these, if they are
provided, are kind of verified
by the SCCM server to make
sure that they check out.
Okay, so assuming that all works,
we will receive from the SCCM server
a reply assignment XML document,
and that contains a bunch
of policies with some URLs
that point to where we
can download the policies
that our SCCM client should apply.
Now, we already discussed this,
there's actually three policies
that we're specifically interested in
because we know that
they result in passwords
ending up in our client,
task sequences, Network
Access Account config,
and collection settings.
So we can filter our reply
assignments XML document
to kind of figure out these
are the sensitive policies
that we're interested in,
let's go download those.
And if we actually download one of them,
we again need to authenticate.
There's some signatures here,
but the data that we received
back is an encrypted blob
that is encrypted using the certificate
that we already have.
Okay, so we have a high-level
picture of how it works,
how can we use it to pull out passwords?
Well, like this.
So because we have our
media variables file,
we can take our media variables file,
take the password that we cracked
and provide it to PXE Thief.
It's able to then issue requests to the,
well, generate the signatures
that we need to authenticate,
issue requests to SCCM to
pull first the assignments
that it needs to apply,
and then the policies,
the specific policies
that we're interested in.
And then after it receives those policies,
sorry, let me just skip forward.
It is then able to take those policies
and decrypt them in order to
get the clear text passwords
that are stored within those policies.
Okay, so the key bit to understand here
is how does the signature work,
because that's really the
thing that's stopping us
from doing this just out of hand.
Turns out that if we go using x64dbg,
if we go on an active debugging spree,
we can see that
CryptSignHash from CryptoAPI
is used to generate these
hashes, these signatures.
So we have some kind of known value,
like for example, let's
take CCM client ID,
it's provided to us in
the media variables.
We take that value, we sign
it using the PFX value,
we provide both of them
to the SCCM server.
And because it also has a
copy of the certificate,
it can verify that this
signature is legitimate.
Okay, so that's how we authenticate.
Now, how do we decrypt
these encrypted policies?
Well, again, if we go on
an active debugging spree,
we figure out that the, yeah,
that binary blob is encrypted
using crypt, encrypt message,
which we can decrypt
with CrypDecry message
using the certificate.
That leaves us with a
plain text policy XML
that will be dependent
on the specific policies
that we're looking at.
Most of these will just be
clear text at this point,
but if they can contain passwords,
SCCM isn't done with the encryption yet.
So in this case, I've
highlighted the value here,
TS_sequence it's marked as secret.
And that means that they've implemented
some kind of obfuscation
to make sure that we can't
just read it outright.
It starts off with the
Hex value, 89130000,
which will be relevant later on,
which is why I'm telling you now.
But effectively again,
if we go in this active debugging spree,
we'll figure out that the string
is actually just tripled DES encrypted
with a key that's inside that hex string.
So we can pull the key, decrypt the value,
and get the clear test task sequence.
Once we have the clear test task sequence,
things start to make a lot more sense.
If we look in the
Configuration Manager console,
there's a bunch of steps
in each task sequence
for the steps that can contain passwords,
we actually just get the straight
care text passwords here.
So in this case, I've highlighted
the domain-joining credentials
that are associated
with the applying network
settings task sequence step.
Okay, now, the interesting thing is that
I've discussed how to do this
when a password is required,
but you don't necessarily need a password.
So if we look at the
specific place in SCCM,
in the SCCM console where you set up PXE,
you can untick the box
that says require password.
So when you boot into it,
the Configuration Manager
client just tells you,
this media is not password
protected, click next.
How does that work?
Well, if you encounter an
environment that has this setup,
we can actually just
go from the first step
all the way to decrypting variables.
Because there's no password to protect it,
we can pull the key, I'll explain how,
and then we can just
immediately decrypt it
and get clear text, creates out.
Now, the secret here is
essentially in that response
to the specific DHCP message that,
we send to the SCCM server.
I already said, there's a portion
that starts with 01
that points us at our
encrypted media variable file.
The media variable (chuckles)
media variable file is still encrypted
in the case where we
don't require a password.
But the key is actually sent
as part of DHCP option 243
in a portion that starts with 02.
So 02 a length field, and
then we have an encrypted key.
Now, SCCM at least encrypts it
because it realizes this is
being sent over the network,
so we don't want to expose
the media variables file
straight off the bat,
but we can't really do much
to prevent this from being decrypted
because the client still
needs, at some point,
to access it, and there's no
real secret involved here.
So it turns out that there's
another layer of obfuscation,
and going on an active debugging street,
we can find a function
called extract password inside TS.PXE.dll.
Inside that function,
there is a call to decrypt buffer
that references a hard coded
key inside the same file,
and then refers to this
DHCP option portion
that we just discussed.
So it turns out that this is encrypted
using the hard coded key there.
So what we do is we take
the DHCP option 243,
pass out that second option,
decrypt it using the hard coded key,
and then we have a random key
that is used to encrypt
our media variables file,
but because it's being
sent in that DHCP response,
this is easy to do straight off the bat
once you know what's happening.
Okay, so now we've run through everything
that can happen with network booting,
but if you remember in the beginning,
OSD isn't just network booting,
it does include media
files that we can use
in order to initiate
operating system deployment.
How does that work?
So inside the Configuration
Manager console,
you can take a task sequence
and generate a media file that is used
to initiate this OSD method.
There's three main
types, standalone media,
bootable media, and pre-stage media.
Pre-stage media is a
file that we can ship off
to a laptop manufacturer so
that when the laptop comes up,
it will attempt to contact
our specific SCCM server
and complete the installation.
Bootable media is effectively
an ISO file or a USB
that will just boot
into a WinPE Environment
and start a client like
we've seen already.
And standalone media is probably
the most interesting one
where it is designed
to not use network communications at all,
but still complete an
operating system deployment.
So it needs to package all of the software
and all of the policy
settings onto that ISO file
in order to be able to
do it completely offline.
If we look at the contents of these files,
so I went and I generated one of each.
If we look at it,
we actually see a lot of
similarities with our Ram disk
that's sitting inside WinPE.
So there is an SMS folder,
inside that SMS folder
there's a data folder.
And for both the bootable
media and the pre-stage media,
there is just a variables.dat file
and then a configuration file,
our TsmBootstrap.ini
that's just telling us
how to run the client in the first place.
If we look at the standalone media,
there is also an additional
file called Policy.XML
that contains all of the policies
that this media needs to apply
in order to successfully
deploy the laptop.
Okay, so how do we turn this into creds?
So I'm going to talk about
standalone media primarily,
because that's the interesting
one that has the new file.
It turns out that both bootable
media and pre-stage media
have a certificate inside
their variables.dat file.
And we can use that certificate
to perform the exact same attack
as we would once we
obtain that certificate
from a PXE perspective.
Okay, so in the case of
a standalone media file,
we can take, if we know the password,
again, we can perform
cracking if we need to,
because the variables.dat
file for media file
is generated in the exact same way
as it would be for a PXE file.
We can generate, once
we know the password,
we can provide the password to PXE thief.
It can derive the key and
decrypt both the policy
and variables.dat files.
And then we are, because
all of the policies
are sitting inside that Policy.XML file,
it works exactly the same
as if we were operating
in a PXE environment.
Again, with our media files,
we can also choose to not set a password.
If we don't set a password,
there's just a static string.
So we can take the static
string, derive a key from it,
use that to decrypt the policy
and the media variables file,
and then we are off to the races,
we can decrypt our policies.
Now, the important thing to note,
actually for standalone media is
unlike when a password is set,
there's a different key that is used
for the Policy.XML and
for the variables.dat.
We always use the password
to decrypt variables.dat,
but in the case of a standalone media
that doesn't have a password,
we take the SMS media GUID
from that variables.dat file
and use that to derive a new key
that's used to encrypt the policy file.
Okay, so at a high level,
bootable media, pre-stage
media, we get a certificate,
we use the certificate,
pull policies, get creds.
If we are on a standalone media,
we have to decrypt that
Policy.XML file somehow.
How do we turn this
into a realistic attack?
Well, if we're sitting in an environment
where we can do a PXE boot,
what we need to do is we
need to prompt for PXE boot,
find out where the SCCM survey is,
get our hands on that
media variables file.
And once we have the media variables file,
crack the password if there is a password,
or use the key that was
sent to us to decrypt it.
If we crack the password,
we can then use the certificate
and get all the creds.
If we have low privileged
domain credentials,
we have a number of other
options available to us.
We can actually, I showed you the folder,
Ram Installed SMS Temp,
that in general is actually
a share on the SCCM server
that all domain users can read.
So even if you're not in the position
to prompt the SCCM server for a PXE boot,
you can use credentials
to go look at the contents of SMS Temp.
And if there's a variables file in there,
you can download that file
and attempt to crack it.
On the other side of things,
obviously, these media files are files
that are lying around
somewhere on the network.
If we can find those files,
we can attempt to, again, crack,
if there's a password set.
If there isn't the password set,
we just use the default string and cool.
We have the certificate,
or we have the decrypted policy
that gives us the
credentials that we want.
Okay, is there any post-exploitation
potential with this?
Turns out that there is.
If we have administrative
access over the SMS,
SMS server (chuckles),
the SCCM server,
we can actually ask for
specific registry keys.
And the certificate that we're looking for
is actually just stored as a registry key
that we can access remotely.
So we can pull the identity.Guid,
which again is used to
encrypt the certificate.
We can pull the certificate bite,
try and import it, use the
password to decrypt it.
And cool, we have the cert that we need
in order to persistently
be able to do this
going into the future.
Now, the reason this is
useful for post-exploitation
is because it's actually
a really nice persistence technique.
If credentials are stored
within task sequences,
the Network Access Account
collection variables,
you can reset all of the passwords
across the entire active directory domain.
If you're updating the passwords in SCCM
to make sure that it's still functional,
this certificate will work
to get those credentials after the fact.
Another thing that's kind
of interesting is that
if we look at the SMS DP Identity key
and the value reserved one.
I mentioned earlier, anything
that starts with 89130000
is probably just using obfuscation,
so it turns out that
the actual PXE password
is also stored inside this registry value.
So we can just feed it through
the same deobfuscation function,
get the clear text password.
And again, nice persistence technique
because even if you're
recovering the domain,
you're probably not
resetting the PXE password.
So you can use this to
perform the exact same attack.
And lastly, can we get
credentials on endpoints?
How does this work?
Okay, so the really well known method
is to pull the Network Access Account,
the Network Access Account,
and most SCCM configuration options
are stored inside the WMIC
database on a given host.
So if we ask for the SCCM
Network Access Account clause,
we can see the Network
Access Account password,
and the Network Access Account username,
these are marked as policy secrets.
And if we look at the actual
data that is being protected,
it's actually protected just using DPAPI.
There's a lot of tools
now that can decrypt this,
Benjamin Delpy actually released ages ago,
like about a year, over a year ago,
he built this functionality into MiniCat
so that it can decrypt
that specific DPAPI blob.
Recent research from SpecterOps Subat0mik
has built SCCM decryption
of that specific
information into SharpDPAPI.
And I'd say one of the most interesting
pieces of recent research
is by Adam Chester,
where he's looked at how to register
an arbitrary certificate
for a new domain-joined machine into ECCM,
so that we're able to
perform those HTTP requests
in order to pull policies.
So all of these is targeted
towards getting the
Network Access Account.
But if you remember, I
said, there's three places
that we can pull creds.
So it turns out the collection variables
can also be pushed to endpoints,
so if we query instead of
CCM Network Access Account,
if we query CCM collection variable,
we can pull the collection variables,
these are also marked as policy secrets.
So we can decrypt it using DPAAPI as well,
and task sequences might
be pushed to endpoints.
So if we query CCM_tasksequence,
there's a value called TS_sequence
that is also a policy secret,
and is also encrypted using DPAPI.
Okay, so let's tie everything together.
We've talked about a whole bunch of ways
to pull out credentials.
What are the issues?
Well, the very first
issue is the fact that
could the accounts configured in SCCM
might be overly permissioned.
So right in the beginning,
I discussed how the Network Access Account
can be domain admin,
or it can have administrative
access over the SCCM server.
At the end of the day,
this is just an account
that is used to download
software off the SCCM server,
it doesn't need privileges,
it needs the ability to
log onto an HTTP endpoint.
It should only have those privileges,
never mind the fact that
you don't even need a Network
Access Account anymore.
And that applies to every place
where you can configure credentials
in Configuration Manager.
The Microsoft documentation
on how to configure these
accounts is really good,
I've put the link to the page
that discusses this in detail here.
Read it, it's really good at informing you
how to configure these accounts
so that it doesn't contribute
towards a privilege escalation vector.
Another issue is that we
often have entire teams
that are dedicated to setting up SCCM.
So because they're responsible
for setting up all of the
accounts that SCCM uses,
they might set the same password.
So we might use different accounts
that are even appropriately permissioned,
but if we're taking our
administrator account for SCCM
and setting the same password
as the Network Access Account
that is exposed in this way,
we can just attempt to use that password
to gain access to the admin account.
And if they were set the same,
cool, we have access to the admin.
Lastly, we often see that an
account configured in SCCM
is used for multiple purposes.
So it is pretty well defined,
you can set a domain-joining credential,
a Network Access Account,
a set of credentials that's used
to connect to a network folder.
All of these are really well-defined,
and the problem comes in when we decide,
we don't actually wanna use
different accounts for this,
so we'll create one account
that fulfills all these roles.
What you're really doing there
is you're adding additional
permissions to accounts
that don't need them.
And if you compromise that,
you compromise all of the roles
that, that account is being
used for, not a great idea.
Okay, key takeaways.
Configuration Manager, super powerful,
there's a reason it's used so widely.
I think Patch's management
on Windows estate
is actually pretty painful
without using this,
so it's gonna stick around for a while.
As long as onsite AD is still the thing,
Configuration Manager is
probably gonna be a thing.
We've seen here that
operating system deployment
is viable for attacking
corporate networks.
So if we guess the password,
we can get the certificate,
we can pull the policies.
If the accounts are badly configured,
we're going to get sensitive credentials,
and that's going to allow us
to privileged escalate in the environment.
It's a really, really, really good idea
to set a password, and
to set a strong password
and to make sure
that you're following
good password practices.
Something like using an
enterprise password manager here
where the creds are
rotated every now and then,
and everybody that needs
access to these media passwords
can actually access those passwords
is probably a good idea.
If this password is guessed,
obviously that certificate is compromised,
and these certificates generally
at least have a lifetime
of around two years.
And it's very, probably
the most important thing,
is we should make sure
that the specific accounts
that are being pushed to endpoints
do not have elevated
privileges associated to them.
None of the accounts
that we've spoken about,
that you can get access to
need admin access to anything.
They don't, do not put them
inside these policies (giggles)
because they are exposed,
not just to PXE clients,
but also to every client,
if you configure task sequences,
for example, on Windows endpoints.
If you want some more information,
I've written up a lot of the stuff
around the HTTP communications
at my company's website, MWR CyberSec,
go have a read at my blog post.
Again, the tool is going to be released
on my company's GitHub.
I'm not there yet, planning
to release it this weekend.
If you wanna know exactly
when it comes out,
feel free to follow me on
Twitter or follow my company.
And that's it, I'm done.
(audience applauding)