- All right this afternoon,
we're gonna learn a little
bit about Darknet OpSec.
Pretty interesting talk,
please welcome our first time at DEF CON
and first time speaker Sam Bent.
(audience applauding)
- Thank you, it's great to be here.
I never thought I'd be up on this stage.
So my talk is about Darknet OpSec
from the point of view of myself.
Some of the precautions,
some of the things that
I did as a darknet vendor
to try to keep myself safe
from the federal government
and other adversaries
that existed out there.
So these are my aliases.
I have a couple of them.
My day job involves me
writing documentation,
pretty dry stuff, but I enjoy doing it.
While my night job,
I'm a prison advocate,
so I do a lot of outreach
work and try to help people
and guide people through the myriad
that is the federal prison system.
Whether it's them going into it
or their family members going into it.
I have about 54 slides,
so I'm gonna have to move
pretty quick once I start.
So I've worked not only
as a darknet vendor,
but also worked on
multiple darknet markets,
done PR work for them as
well as resolved disputes
for customers, things like that.
My objective with this talk is to give
a different perspective
than typically what's given
at conferences or on the mainstream media,
from someone who's actually been there,
not just studied it from a
distance or speculated on it.
So there are a lot of similarities
between the darknet subculture
and the hacking subculture.
Both of them typically
involve some kind of paranoia
and a lot of times that
paranoia is there for a reason.
Both very much value
their anonymity, secrecy,
intellectual dominance,
especially in the hacking
realm or in the hacking scene,
but also there's a bit of
a learning curve to each.
I would argue that the hacking scene
has a much greater learning
curve than the darknet,
especially because in
order to be a hacker,
you don't just start up tour.
There's a lot that goes into it,
depending on what you're doing.
So the paths between being
a hacker on a darknet vendor
can differentiate too.
As a hacker, you start off really
with no adversaries whatsoever.
You don't have anyone
that's out to get you.
You know, when you hop on
IRC for the first time,
you can learn almost everything.
As far as the process goes for a pen test
inside of things like
the pen test standard.
A lot of what we do is
open source at this point.
You can watch a DEF CON
talk and learn a lot about
what it is that hackers do or the culture,
or just be here in this room,
come to DEF CON.
That doesn't exist in the darknet.
You can't, you know, just hop on
and watch a YouTube video and learn
about darknet subculture.
It's something that you
have to hop on the darknet
and you have to explore and learn
and meet people and hopefully
be safe in doing it.
The sources for information are
completely different for me.
My favorite always was
as a darknet vendor,
darknet news sites,
dark.fail is one that's been
around for quite a while
and is pretty good.
Dread is a forum that's
one of the most active
on the darknet from what I've seen.
So there's a book that Kevin Mitnick wrote
called "Ghost in the Wires"
and I took his approach when looking
at operational security from that,
specifically the part where he called up
law enforcement and social engineered them
to allow him to use the
NCIS system that they have.
I feel that a lot of the information
that you could want or would be relevant
is located in manuals.
And if we know how law
enforcement operates,
we're trying to be criminals,
then we know what
they're going to do next.
It's like having a cheat sheet.
So with that,
I ended up going and looking and finding
United States Postal Inspector's manual
to see what he classified
as a suspicious package.
I needed to know that if
I was going to be shipping
narcotics through the United States mail.
So this information's out there,
this is not it, but this is an example
of some of the things
that you would look at
when evaluating things like this.
It'd be an eclectic process where you take
what's valuable and leave what's not.
Some of the things that
would raise suspicion
when you're trying to move drugs
through the United States mail system
would be using too much tape,
handwriting the labels,
if you don't use the official USPS boxes,
fake names on recipients
or return addresses,
all of these things add up as red flags
that ultimately leads to the
United States postal inspector
possibly applying for a
search warrant for a box.
So in order to avoid these,
you just don't do those things.
It's pretty straightforward.
It's like reverse
engineering law enforcement
to some degree.
For me, I had a moral dilemma
when I wanted to ship drugs,
which is kind of ironic.
I didn't want to send,
say cocaine from some
random person's address.
You know, there's a lot of
hardworking people in the world.
And to me sending out four ounces of blow
to some guy who's a construction worker
and just trying to make ends meet
and have DHS break through his door
really wasn't the best way to go about it.
And I was sure that
somewhere there existed
a database of people that
I considered personally
to be people okay to screw over.
(audience laughs)
So I searched for it and
I tried to figure out
what that database would be,
how it would look and how I
would be able to access it.
And the only solution that I
could come up with was this.
(audience laughing and applauding)
So remember I said, you need
to have a valid return address.
It needs to be the correct name.
It needs to be the correct address,
all of these had that.
So they qualified and they made them real.
And if it got sent back to them
or if they got raided,
I didn't really have any qualms in that.
And it was interesting
because the Department
of Homeland Security's
special agent that was in charge
when they ended up raiding me,
felt the exact same
while this crowd feels,
he laughed about it too, he
thought it was hilarious.
(audience laughs)
So when I ship,
the thing that I came to my conclusion
was you can pick obviously you have a ton
of different services that you can use
to ship anything nowadays.
My favorite by far is the
United States Postal Service.
And there's a few reasons for that,
private services like DHL or UPS,
they can open up your
package whenever they want.
There's no rules in that.
They're a private corporation,
but a warrant is required
for USPS to be able
to open something.
They also have more
locations than anyone else,
and they can get to your
door from tour to door
in three days, which is great,
especially if you're
going for good reviews
on the darknet, you know.
(audience laughs)
So it is run by the federal government,
which is kind of, you know,
it's kind of an ironic thing
that the people that are hunting you,
you know, a branch of their system
is going to be enabling you
to traffic drugs on a national
or an international level.
It's kind of, I guess you say
like a spiteful thing to do
where you're having the feds
send you drugs for you.
So the other thing to take into account
is the amount of packages that exist.
How hard is it to find my one package out
of that 21.5 billion?
You'd probably have a better chance
at winning the powerball,
especially because I'm well aware of
what you're looking for
when it comes to a suspicious package
and none of my packages are
ever gonna look that way.
And we compare 'em to some
of the other shippers,
and you can see the
numbers are pretty drastic
in terms of differences.
Drug sniffing dogs compared
to like a lot of people
think, drug sniffing dogs, they don't work
eight hour shifts.
They're sporadic.
You can't work them like you
could an Amazon employee.
(audience laughs)
So that's one thing,
but then you take into account permeation,
which is where a smell
can go through an object.
All those things come into play.
When I would ship, I would
ship two to three day.
There's not enough time for it
to come through vacuum sealed bags
and a visual barrier
in that amount of time.
So on top of that, like when you get,
if your drugs do get intercepted,
what happens is you get a notice
and we call it a love letter
and it comes from USPS typically,
or customs if it's an overseas order.
And they just say that we've
intercepted your drugs,
they don't say it like that.
They say, we have your package,
please come to the post office
and pick up your package.
Once you show up with that letter,
you're acknowledging
that that's your package.
Because aside from that,
they can't prove it's yours.
They can't, you didn't
order this on Amazon.
So they can't hop on and see, you know,
your credit card transaction,
where you bought these drugs.
You bought it in Bitcoin or your Monero
or any one of the available
options that existed to you.
So they rely on things like that.
So, you know, your
countermeasure for when you get
a love letter is to burn it
or throw it away, it's relevant.
So the other thing that
law enforcement likes to do
on occasion is controlled deliveries
and controlled deliveries,
a little bit more aggressive
obviously than a love letter.
But again, you have
countermeasures for that as well.
You have no obligation to
open your door for anyone.
And if they had, you know,
even if there was the police,
if they had permission
to come into your house,
they wouldn't be knocking, right?
They'd be kicking in the
door and they'd be coming in
and they'd be taking you out.
So it's all voluntary.
You answering that door
and it's the same thing
with delivery services.
You can just not answer that door.
I mean, a lot of the times darknet vendors
are not gonna require signature
because it would be like,
you know, requiring you
to give your real name when you're using
a handle as a hacker.
It's just not something you're gonna do.
If I ask you on an IRC
chat, what's your real name?
And we just met.
How willing are you gonna be
to give that information over?
Probably not likely.
So from that, there are
countermeasures for it.
So sometimes they'll
put devices in the box
and we'll just let the
box sit for 24 hours
or 48 hours or three
days until the batteries
in that device if it's small die,
or if they're using something local,
like a radio frequency,
we travel open the box up 10 miles away,
any transmitter they have in there
would be well at a distance.
So if you do it well,
this is what they should know about you.
It should be nothing.
It should be, oh yeah,
he's the computer guy.
So in making an image for
yourself on the darknet,
one of the best ways I found
to do that was to be helpful.
And, you know, just like on a
social engineering campaign,
if you're disingenuine people
pick that up very quickly.
It's like flattery, you
know a lot of times,
flattery has the opposite effect
that you intended to have.
So being disingenuous
in darknet is something
that can be picked up by some people.
And a lot of people find it repulsive,
just like you do in real life.
When someone compliments
you for the fifth time
on your shoes.
So my move was to contribute 5,000 posts
and I did that on Hansa in a month.
And by doing that, basically
everyone in that community
now associates my name with good things,
with helping out with OpSec,
with, you know, enjoying
helping other people.
And that's the kind of the
irony is everyone seems
to think about the darknet
as this horrible place
where, you know, there are
really bad things on there.
It's not up for debate,
but at the same time,
not everyone on there is a psychopath.
You know, a lot of times it's just people.
So with that,
I was able to establish rapid
rapport in that community.
People knew me
and when someone came in there
just like any other community,
if you come into any
community and you start,
you know, threatening someone,
or like, you know, if someone came in here
and started saying a well-known speaker
didn't know what he was talking about,
the community would probably
revolt against that.
They wouldn't like that very much.
You have the same thing in the darknet,
but instead of having that trust,
you have that verification through things
like PGP signatures and sign messages
and all, you know, stuff like that.
When we look at the
history and the present
and the future of reconnaissance
and information gathering
when it comes to law enforcement,
there are a few different countermeasures
a darknet vendor can
take if he's informed,
if he knows enough about it.
My thing was to hop on PACER,
like you might see the
department of justice
announce a darknet bust,
but they don't really
give you details, PACER will.
PACER is the place where
you can find federal cases.
You can find the United
States attorney's wording
and how they caught that person,
what that person did,
where they screwed up.
Again, if we can look and we can map out
how they screwed up,
we can make it so that we never screw up.
We never make those same mistakes
that our predecessors did.
And we're playing in this game
you're playing for keeps,
you know, messing up here doesn't mean
that this particular assignment,
you have to go find another
penetration testing engagement.
It means that you're
going to federal prison.
So it's not something you wanna screw up.
So tend to tread a lot more carefully,
even when it comes to things
like cashing out crypto
or, you know, making it so that the chain
that law enforcement uses to trace you
or trace your transactions
is a lot harder to uncover.
So from what I've seen on the darknet,
the majority of the time
that darknet sites actually
get taken down is not from law enforcement
being highly talented.
It's from just a administrator,
making a stupid OpSec
mistake or not updating
or getting complacent, right?
Because we have that kind of sliding scale
where we have complacency on one side
and security on the other.
And time seems to be a
variable that wears that down
to the other side where
they become complacent.
So Reddit ended up banning darknet markets
and our response was to create Dread.
Hugbunter is famously known
as the one who created it.
He created it and he ended up making it
and making it public as a replacement
for darknet markets,
which is a massive subreddit
and their ban of it
came out of nowhere.
And what it did was it
made it so that people
on the clearnet or people
that weren't using Tor,
it made 'em a lot harder to
get their questions answered
on how to navigate the darknet.
And that removal of
information was a tactic used
by law enforcement to try to stop people
from using the darknet.
And that was our answer was Dread,
which I was an administrator on.
So when you get started,
you wanna look at a few different things.
Your main goal obviously
is to avoid incarceration,
avoid arrest.
You wanna create a secure persona.
Sometimes it's good to
create multiple personas
and have them all age.
Your ultimate goal is to not get arrested.
And if you do screw something up,
that's what's going to happen.
You are successful as long as
you're not in federal custody.
And once you are as far
too late to go back,
my suggestion is to map
out and have responses
to any type of incident that may occur.
Just like a major company
has security policies,
you know, they set up
and countermeasure set up
to be able to handle
anything that goes wrong.
It's the responsibility of that person
who's going to be, you know,
dealing in transactions
to make sure that they do the same.
So some of the threats that
exist are physical threats
like DNA.
If that darknet vendor
doesn't know anything
about physical security
or operational security
or anything like that,
he might assume that, you
know, they're not gonna
go through the effort of
looking for skin cells
or analyzing a package heavily.
And the fact of the matter is
if you don't know it for sure,
then you're always better
airing on the side of caution.
Noisy neighbors, these kind of, you know,
if you have issues with your neighbors,
they don't like you that's an adversary.
You know, they can call up,
even though wellness check,
anyone can write an email to the FBI.
You know, I see 'em come
in with 20 packages a day.
It's abnormal, it's a red flag.
Bluetooth, wifi attacks, all those things
that we know very well,
you know, people in this
con understand very well.
Trash is another one.
It's always better to shred
it or burn it if possible.
It's a lot of these same security measures
that we take in this field,
safeguarding corporations are the things
that you will see a responsible
darknet vendor take.
The only difference is
instead of having teams do it
and millions of dollars to do it,
they're stuck trying to figure it out
and do it all themselves.
Which is why, one of
the things that creates
that low hanging fruit
for law enforcement,
those people who don't
understand encryption
or don't know fully about OpSec,
and maybe they're just drug traffickers.
They don't have a background in that.
Another thing is linguistical analytics
is something I always
try to keep mindful of.
If I'm writing on the darknet on a forum,
I'm from New England.
So we tend to say the word like wicked
to describe something as very,
you know, so if I say this
is a wicked good talk,
it means it's a very good talk.
And with that said,
if I use that terminology in a forum
and law enforcement picks that up,
now they know, okay, this
guy's from New England
or this guy's from Massachusetts.
You know, tey can get detailed information
on where I am based on
that and that's a threat.
That's a problem and something that,
again, a lot of people,
they don't think about
when they go into it
and there's no manual for this.
You know, unlike the hacking culture,
we've been around a long time,
you know, it's a big culture
and darknet culture isn't so much,
it's a lot more secretive.
What's interesting is everything
I'm telling you today,
all of this is freely available.
You know, so if you're
from the Department of Homeland Security
and you're here hoping to learn
some elite, you know, thing,
it's just not gonna happen.
It's all publicly available to anyone
who seeks this information.
My internet service when
I was a darknet vendor,
it didn't exist.
Again, I drew a lot of my
inspiration from Kevin Mitnick.
I liked a lot of the stuff that he did.
I thought a lot of his
things were ingenious.
And along with those was
something I borrowed,
which was a little bit more
localized than what he did
with cell towers was grabbing a Yagi
and connecting to a neighbor's internet,
who I had no visual barriers to,
meaning I could see his house,
but it was far enough away
for me to feel secure.
So if I saw, you know, a bunch
of black SUVs rolling up,
I could assume it was safe
to burn everything I had
and get rid of everything, clean house
because my neighbor was getting raided.
So one thing I would always check,
I would do perimeter
checks on a regular basis.
I was a homebody, I didn't like to leave.
I'm definitely not big
on social interactions,
personally, the guy of a
little bit of a agoraphobia.
So this talk is extremely
challenging for me.
However, it was something that
I felt I would love to share.
And I'm glad that DEF CON
gave me the opportunity
to share with you guys.
But one of the things
that needs to be stayed
on top of is security checks.
Just like in a corporation,
you constantly have to make
sure that everyone's staying
on point, cuz again, complacency
is the enemy of security.
So that was one of the
big things that I had.
I had weekly, daily and monthly checklists
of things that I would
make sure that I was doing.
At the end of the day, we all feel safe,
when we're at home, we all feel safe,
we all feel secure.
And then one day we lose our keys
and then all of a sudden
we're all penetration testers.
We can look at our house and we can say,
oh, I can card the door,
oh, I left that window open.
Now all of a sudden you can find three,
four different
vulnerabilities in your home
and you stop feeling so safe
until you get those secured.
And I think that's something
that as a darknet vendor,
it's very easy to get comfortable,
just like it is for our average people.
Checking out your
weaknesses and making sure
that they're fixed, evaluating your OpSec
on a regular basis to me is mandatory,
especially because the
repercussions are on a data breach.
They're incarceration
in the federal facility.
Staying away from emotional decisions,
things like drinking and
typing will get you raided,
will get you a 10 to 25 year sentence.
So it's suicide, career
suicide on a little bit
of a different level
than what we're used to.
I like to always advise to never,
never answer questions
even to this day I don't.
I only answer questions after this talk,
but, you know, like in general,
(laughs)
when it comes to law enforcement
or obviously someone you don't know
calling up, you know,
and asking you questions,
a really great, you know,
thing to watch is to go
to the SE village and see
people calling people up
and those people just
giving out information,
obviously we all know
it's not a good idea.
So I'm always leery of that.
And in turn, I always like to answer
that question with the question.
So once you actually pull that trigger
and you start being a darknet vendor
and you start having to
actually deal with customers,
you have to write terms and conditions.
You know, when are you
gonna refund a customer?
How long is it gonna go?
How long are you gonna
wait before, you know,
if someone buys something from you today
and tomorrow they say, hey,
I wanna tracking number.
Are you gonna give it to 'em?
Should you give it to 'em?
You know, if you give it to 'em,
then they'll know where
you shipped that from.
Maybe you want a little bit more time
before you're willing to give that away.
So all those little kind of things
are things that need to
be seriously evaluated
when you're considering
building a platform
or when you're considering
being a darknet vendor.
And again, I have it as number six here,
don't drink and type, it's essential.
So changing your PGP key,
not a lot of vendors do this,
but it lets you switch up.
You switch up your identity,
which means your reputation dies
and that's unfortunate,
but you can always build
that reputation back up
and it'll take a massive
target off your back.
So your point of you doing
this is to make money.
That's how I saw it is to make money,
is to get in, is to get out.
And that was my goal,
so having that mapped
out with your ingress,
your egress and your regress,
as far as things like
changing your PGP key
or things like that were
essential to me before I started.
And with things that I kept in mind
during the whole time.
Once you start building a
reputation on the darknet,
it's in spider out.
So what I mean by that is like
you as professionals right now,
if you have, you work
for a big company, right?
Or you write a book,
you're building a reputation,
you can use that reputation
to get a better job
and you can do the same
thing on the darknet.
Except instead of me
offering a former employer
might be a verifiable,
PGP signed message to a new employer
and a new darknet opens up
and I message the admin.
And I say, hey, listen,
I can help you out.
I have these previous accounts,
I can validate them.
You can check them and I can prove
that I've done this kind of work before.
And it allows you, again, to spider out
and end up getting
multiple different jobs,
which pay sometimes a lot
better than if you're just
starting out as a vendor.
And that reputation is
something you can buy
and you can sell and you can trade on.
And, you know, your PGP key, your identity
is much more restrictive.
And it's restricted to
darknet market admins
as opposed to all the users.
So me personally, I hate Bitcoin tumblers.
I never use them.
I just didn't like them,
I don't like sending my Bitcoin to someone
and I don't know who they are.
It always kind of rubbed me the wrong way.
So what I used to do
is I used to convert it
from Bitcoin to Monero
and then back to Bitcoin.
And I was happy with that because I knew
that the link between
the two different types
of Bitcoin that I had
was completely broken.
It's kind of like robbing a bank
and buying a bunch of weed
and selling all that weed.
And now the money that you
have is completely different.
Whether or not you made money
on it is a different fact.
Alternatively, also buying drugs.
So if I sold $20,000 worth
of narcotics in three days,
I could turn around and
I could buy narcotics
and I could sell them locally
at a much steeper markup
and still have anonymity.
So then you get to retirement
if you make enough,
you know, if you're lucky
enough, you get to this point.
And surprisingly, a lot of people,
I've known a lot of darknet vendors
who have gotten to this point.
They say like, drug dealers
don't get to retire.
Well, darknet vendors do when
I've known a couple of them,
it's completely possible.
I'm not encouraging anyone to do it.
If you're at this con,
you're obviously intelligent.
I suggest that you don't do it
cuz it has horrible ROI.
And it's a lot of stress
and, you know, I'm 37
looking with the gray hair I have,
(audience laugh)
you know, it's not an easy job,
so I don't recommend it to anyone.
And that's one thing I
definitely like to make clear.
So, and I talk about here that, you know,
we do switch up PGP keys,
again, that kills all your business,
but that's a necessary.
So when my Department of
Justice announcement came out
where they announced me
and about 33 other people
that got raided, they said that it
was cuz of Operation Dark Hold.
And I'm from Vermont,
you can see the little
arrow going up north from,
well, maybe you can't.
Yeah, you probably can't on the screen.
I'm sorry about that.
But that's what they planned,
basically Operation Dark Gold
was they caught someone
who was laundering Bitcoin
and they had this guy continue to do it.
And people would cash
out their Bitcoin to him
for 10% and he would send
them cash in the mail.
At this time, KYC the know your
customer policy for Bitcoin,
wasn't really prevalent
and it only applied to banking
institutions at that point.
So personal Bitcoin
transactions are not illegal
and, you know, quoting trying to say that
because someone bought
Bitcoin from someone,
this was how you caught them.
To me, I thought it was asinine
because it made absolutely
no sense whatsoever.
To me, it was just a way
to collect names of people
who were on the darknet.
And that's exactly what they did,
but that was how they said
that they ended up catching me.
The issue that I had with that was that
at the end of the day, you have a hearing
called the Frank's hearing in law.
And Frank's hearing is when you can prove
that law enforcement
violated the law in order
to catch you doing something
or to get a warrant
to search your house.
They themselves broke the law in trying
to ascertain that information.
That was in my case, the
United States postal inspector
opened a package that he
didn't have a warrant for.
Again, one of my favorite reasons
why I used the United
States postal service
was it requires a warrant
for you to open a package.
And this went back to my
OpSec and they broke that,
but in breaking that,
they also gave me a way
to exit out of my 10-count
federal indictment that
they also hit me with
because they broke the law.
We didn't get to that point.
And that was because before
we could bring that up
after our Frank's hearing was granted,
my cousin had already written a statement
which established conspiracy
and the feds can give you
a mandatory minimum for
a conspiracy charge,
can be anywhere from 10 years to 20 years.
So it's not something that you really want
to take a gamble with.
So after I was caught, was convicted,
but only after I pled out,
I agreed to a maximum term of
108 months in federal prison.
And I was actually given 60
months, which is awesome.
I thought it was awesome
cuz then I didn't know anything
about the federal system.
When I first got charged, I
had a 10-count indictment.
When I looked up those charges,
I saw each one came with
a maximum of 20 years.
We do the math that's 200 years.
So that's what I thought I was gonna get.
I thought, well, I'm gonna get 200 years.
I'm never gonna get out of prison,
which it was, its just,
it's not how it works
in the federal system.
So I studied law for 18 months
while I was in federal prison
because I inherently, I
saw a lot of power in it.
Just like a lot of you see a lot of power
in learning how to code.
Those things allow you to do things
that, you know, the
person who doesn't know
how to code, maybe not,
they can't do or they can't automate
or they can't get as much done as you can.
So for me, the code I wanted
to learn was federal law
and that's what I learned.
And by doing that I was able
to get myself out of prison.
They have a thing called
the compassionate release
where, you know, if you can prove
that there's a danger from, you know,
because of your health, then you can apply
for compassionate release.
And I did, I wrote a 200 page motion
and I mailed it in to the federal court.
So that was essentially
my boot force attack
to the federal courts and it
worked and they released me,
but it was after a lot of
studying, a lot of hours,
a lot of 12 hour days reading federal law.
So this year DEF CON's
theme is hacker homecoming
and for me that's especially true.
Technically, my release
date is for the third day
in January of 2023.
So I'm very happy to be
here standing on the stage
talking to all of you as opposed
to being in a prison cell.
(audience applauding)
So I made a stupid mistake
and I got myself in trouble
and I paid the consequence for what I did,
but at the same time,
that hacker mentality of never giving up,
of always wanting to fight
and just continually bashing
your head against that wall.
It ended up paying off in
a totally different way
than a lot of us see on a regular basis.
You know, it wasn't that code
finally ran without crashing.
It was that, you know, I wasn't stuck
in a small cell with a bunch of
sociopaths, you know,
who have life sentences.
So that was a great thing.
But it's one of the
things that really made me
appreciate both communities
because I started out
in the hacking community
and I ended up going into
the darknet community
because it's such an easy transition.
You know, one of the most paramount things
is understanding security
and being in this field
you already do that.
And I think that's the
really dangerous thing
that exists is because it's
so easy to just move over
to that side, you know,
for me, I was anyways.
So in conclusion, moving
over from being a hacker
to being a darknet vendor,
it was ridiculously easy,
but again, you know, you
can have the perfect OpSec
and still get fucked
over and get fucked up.
You know, there's no such thing,
we all know there's no such thing
as an unpickable lock, right?
There's no such thing as a foolproof plan.
There's no security
application that we can install
that's gonna make us all safe, guaranteed.
It's the same thing.
No matter what side of
that fence you're on,
whether it's law enforcement
or you know, criminal.
Thank you for letting me speak here.
(audience applauding)
I think they're gonna
open it up for Q and A.
If you guys have any questions.
- [Host] You want mic?
- Yeah, can I use this one or-
- [Host] I can get a
field mic if you want.
- All right, either way
I'm fine with this one.
- [Host] Just have them raise your hand.
- All right, questions anyone?
- [Audience Member] Should I
use more than one sock puppet?
- What's that?
- [Audience Member] Should I
use more than one sock puppet?
- Should you use more than one sock?
I don't know.
(laughs)
Anyone else?
- [Host] If you have a
question, come on up here.
- [Audience Member] So how
did you originally find out
about the darknet markets
and what all markets
did you operate on?
- So I operated on
probably a total of about
15 different markets.
I remember the first
time I really heard about
Bitcoin was from a friend of mine
and he was discussing how
there's a site called btcfaucet,
which used to exist back in the day
where like you could hop on once a day
and you get anywhere from
like 5 to 50 Bitcoin.
And we'd done that a bunch of times.
And then I got to a point
where we had like 300 Bitcoin
and we were like, this is a waste of time.
Just crap, you know, we
just threw away the wallets.
(laughs)
Big time regret there.
Yes.
(audience member faintly speaking)
Oh yeah, yeah, yeah,
yep, yep.
Sold them too.
(laughs)
Yep.
- [Audience Member] Hey,
so you talked a lot about
like operational hygiene and stuff like
that relating to like-
- I'm sorry, I can't hear you.
- [Audience Member] Okay, so
like you talked a lot about
like operational hygiene.
So like in a week or
in a month you had like
these routines and things
you would do to try to like
promote like a good SecOps hygiene, right?
To make sure-
- I can't make out-
- [Audience Member]
Okay, sorry, I can't...
So for things like, you have like,
is there any strategy you would use
specifically for like trying to determine
what your weakest points are for trying to
establish a good, hey,
this is what I'm gonna
check this week, right?
'Cause you can't check everything.
You can't check every
failure point, every area.
What kind of things would
you specifically look for
as part of like your
strategy to protect yourself
OpSec wise?
- Yep.
So initially I spent six
months doing research,
looking at previous cases where
the feds had raided people,
why they had rated them?
And that was kind of my
starting point for that.
And then once you start to grasp that,
you start finding your own little hacks
and things that you can
do to make it improved.
Yep, but to answer your question,
it was mainly history, right?
Cuz history predicts the future.
So I would try to look at
what happened in the past
to evaluate what was going to happen
or what I would need to do to evolve
and not be the guy in
that DOJ announcement.
- [Host] You have time for
about two more questions.
- [Audience Member] Hey,
you said you would burn
identities with some regularity,
to not leave any tracks
about who you were.
Did you ever get caught
on any of these markets
by people you interacted
with as being somebody
on a different market
using a different identity?
And if you did, did that cause any issues?
- So I heard the first part of it.
What was the second part?
- [Audience Member]
Did you ever get caught
using multiple identities on a number
of these different websites
by people you interacted with,
whether it be other staff,
other users for being, you know, a vendor
under different names?
- Yeah, so you see it's interesting
because once you're there for so long
and like that kind of
anonymous environment,
you can start to see people's mannerisms.
It's a lot like with 4chan, right?
When you start having,
you started having people
who would use the same kind
of terminology or wording,
you could tell who's who,
even if their name changes 50 times,
you still know that person,
cuz you spent a lot of
time talking to them,
you know their idea,
their ideals or their
politics or whatever it is
that they're discussing.
So those things, that using
your identity for other things,
to me, it wouldn't be something that,
I wasn't really there
for the socialization aspect.
You know, I was there
strictly to make money
and anything that helped further that goal
I would be there.
So when it did come to having
to establish an identity
and, you know, just make a
ridiculous amount of posts
to the community,
that's what I would use it for,
but I wouldn't use it anywhere else.
I actually remember reading a case about
a darknet vendor who had
his PGP key on the darknet.
And then the idiot decided to use that
as his Gmail PGP key.
You know, and he didn't last long.
(laughs)
- [Audience Member] All
right, interesting talk,
thank you.
I was wondering to get
your thoughts on like
some markets had exit scams and kind of
what was involved in that
process were mods behind it.
And this, also second
question is the DDoS attacks
on a lot of markets,
is that really revenue depleting
for them or money losing.
Did they pay off the DDos
people to stop that happen?
- So I've seen really, to
answer the second question
real quick.
I think the primary motive
that you see for DDos
is when it comes to darknet markets
is mainly federal agencies.
It's like, well, how can you prove that?
Well you can't, you know,
but really it's one of the only ways
that you can really see
them take down markets
with any kind of regularity,
but even then, you know, they just create
new URLs and good luck they move on.
But aside from that,
I've known darknet market
admins who have wanted
to conduct those campaigns
against competing darknet markets.
- [Audience Member] Hi, can you explain
if and why certain
drugs or pharmaceuticals
aren't as targeted?
- I explained why.
- [Audience Member] As
in, like for example,
like health wellness drugs
or something like that,
as opposed to cocaine or heroin,
and then also it kind of ties
in with my follow up question,
but what goes into the
ability for someone to order
internationally from like a
drugstore internationally?
And why is that legal
to import certain drugs
when you don't have a prescription?
Do you know anything about that?
- So one of the more lucrative trades
that I found when I was doing it
was just that was to do retail.
So you have a lot of people
who aren't comfortable
ordering internationally
because internationally
is when it goes through customs.
If I'm sending you any kind of narcotic
through the mail here in the US,
it doesn't go through customs.
So there's not a whole bunch of scrutiny.
So it's fairly easy to do that.
But when it goes through
customs, it's a little bit more.
So I know that one of the
things I started doing
after a while was looking
at which countries
would produce the best of
a certain type of drug.
So for example, LSD,
there's a vendor and again,
this isn't a secret,
he's very well known called GammaGoblin
who makes some of the
best LSD that exists.
And he lives in the Netherlands.
That's where he's located out of,
if you get a package from him,
that's where it's gonna
come from sometimes.
But the Netherlands is
really known for having
good quality LSD and good quality MDMA.
So for me, I would source the countries
that had the best quality
and then I would find vendors in that
because you can always refine
those search parameters
in almost any darknet market.
And then with that information,
I would go and I would look on sites
like Dread and I would cross-reference
and find their reputation,
find out what people said about them.
So I would find the
countries that had the best
of a certain type of drug.
Then I would find the guy in that country
who has the highest reputation
in marketing that drug
and I would order it through him.
And like, you know,
sometimes the profit margins
would be insane.
Like I know with acid,
from GammaGoblin I could grab
it for about 5 cents a hit
and sell it for about 10 to 15 locally,
on the darknet it would
usually be around four,
but again, it was still
an astronomical return.
I'm on investment and with
something like the acid,
it's a piece of paper.
There's no smell to it.
So it's very easy to do.
- [Host] Last question.
- [Audience Member] Hi,
what platforms did you use
to launder the Bitcoin to Monero
and then how did you vet those platforms?
- So when I did it,
the one thing I'd like to remind you
is when I was doing
all this was years ago.
So, originally, it was Changelly.
I really liked Changelly.
There's another one, ShapeShift.io,
any service that I would use,
I would try to investigate
them as much as I could.
And I had learned that
ShapeShift was really open
to the DOJ and I just wasn't for that.
I didn't really see too
much about Changelly.
So I liked using them, but again,
like anytime I would visit their site,
it's gonna be through
Tor anyway, you know.
- [Host] Thank you very much.
- Yep, thank you.
(audience applauding)