- We're about to get started.
I'd like to welcome Justin and Samuel.
Welcome to DEFCON.
First time speakers.
They'll be given a speech
on Crossing the KASM,
about an exploit that they performed.
And as a reminder, this is a
public service announcement.
Watch your schedules online
and use Hacker Tracker
to be able to see the latest information
and what's going on.
There's a lot that goes on at DEFCON.
So once again, please give a
warm welcome to our speakers.
Welcome guys.
(audience applauding)
- Hello.
(audience clapping)
Hello.
So, I'm Sam.
So, this is Crossing the KASM,
a webapp pentesting story.
So, this talk will get
a little bit technical,
but it's worth it in the end, I promise.
So, who am I?
I am Sam, AKA erbbysam.
I'm a hacker and I also
have two DEFCON black badges
from a few years back.
And most importantly,
I got a puppy about six
months ago. (laughs)
And so there'll be more puppy
pictures later, I promise.
(audience talking)
- Nice, and I'm Justin
Gardner, AKA Rhynorater.
I'm a full-time bug bounty hunter,
and here are some
additional facts about me.
You can find me on Twitter
at my handle Rhynorater,
and my DMs are open if you
guys have any questions
about the presentation or
have any similar interests.
So, when we're dealing
with a product called KASM,
we had to do something punny, right.
So, I figured I'd make
this little presentation
for you guys here,
representing what it's like
to be a bug bounty hunter
on a pretty hardened target.
So, here's Sam and I, in
the middle of the desert.
And on the other side of this KASM,
we can see a mirage of
RCE in the distance,
but we have to go for
it, we have no choice.
And unfortunately, this
mirage is separated from us
by a technology called KASM
and represented here by the deep chasm.
This is a VDI software enterprise
for essentially managing what applications
your user can run and in
what context they do that.
So, we threw a bunch of
exploits at it. (laughs)
Nothing was working, nothing was sticking.
But, in the end, we did find
the bridge over this chasm.
And this is that bridge.
And we'll explain that a little bit more,
but all you need to know for
now is we just hooked this up
and hopped right on over the KASM
and we made our way to the RCE.
So, I'm gonna give it back to Sam
to give you a little bit more context
on what the heck we're
talking about right now
and hopefully it'll make
a little bit more sense
in a moment.
- Cool, thanks.
So, for some important background,
before we get into hacking,
so KASM Workspaces is
streaming containerized apps
and desktops to end-users.
So, it's really intended
for the enterprise world
where you want to
administer your end-users
running uBuntu or Chrome or Windows
inside of Docker containers.
And it will deploy them for
you and then allow end-users
to connect to them and
then you can monitor them,
do various things,
enterprisey things with them.
And it's built on top of Docker and VNC.
And so it'd give you an idea
of just how Dockerized this world is.
It's turtles all the way down.
It's Docker containers all the way down.
And I apologize for putting so
much information on a slide,
but I'll give a visualization in a minute
of what all this looks like.
And so at the bottom of this list,
you can actually see the uBuntu desktop.
The uBuntu Docker
container that I deployed.
And at the top of this list,
you can actually see the NGINX
container that I deployed...
Sorry, the NGINX KASM proxy.
And so the KASM proxy is
actually listening remotely.
And then every other Docker container
is listening on local ports.
And if you're not familiar with Docker,
you can kind of think of
it as a virtual machine,
but instead of running on bare metal,
it runs on top of the operating system.
So, it's really just kind of one layer up.
And then it has a bunch of access
to underlying operating system,
depending on what permissions you give it.
And so diving into a little more detail
into that KASM proxy,
when you actually spin up a new container,
a new NGINX configuration
actually gets pushed to the KASM proxy.
And so this container is our D folder
will be updated with a new file.
And so when you push a new container,
this folder gets updated
and then NGINX actually gets restarted.
And then the end-user can connect
to the newly formed Docker container.
And throughout this talk, we'll
try and share at the bottom
the commands we ran as well as references
if you wanna repeat this
or learn more about this.
And so at a high level,
if you deploy KASM workspaces
onto a single server,
this is what it'll actually look like.
Your end-users will connect
through, as well as you,
will connect through KASM proxy,
and they'll be able to connect
to their end-user containers.
So, every blue square here
actually represents a Docker container.
And in the bottom row
are the kind of command
and control containers
that are used to manage
the rest of the system.
And they're all built on top of Python.
It's either gonna be Tornado or CherryPy.
And so these are the purpose
of all the containers,
the most important one being KASM proxy
with route cellular traffic
and then KASM API,
which is actually the API
you're interacting with
when you're using the application.
KASM agent is also important
because that actually has the ability to,
and permission to deploy new containers.
So it's a privileged Dock container
in the Docker (indistinct).
With multiple servers,
you actually end up with
a series of secondary,
or when you wanna deploy this
into a real enterprise environment,
when you have multiple users,
you wanna deploy it
across multiple machines.
And so, in order to accomplish this,
it actually will, on the primary server,
it'll keep KASM API.
And then KASM proxy will proxy through
to the secondary servers
to run KASM agent,
which will then deploy your containers
or your end-user containers.
And this allows you to scale infinitely.
And so, very high level hand wavy way,
this is roughly what credentials
look like in the system.
Your end-user session tokens
will get past the KASM API
as a cookie.
It'll also get passed
through to their containers.
And then KASM API will
interact with the rest
of the system using secret keys,
which are all internal to the KASM system.
So, at this point, we were
given user credentials
to a bug bounty program,
and we were asked to look at this
without source code access.
We didn't find any vulnerabilities.
This was actually really secure software.
And this talk wouldn't be here today
if this was insecure software,
it would be a very boring talk.
So, at this point,
we given up looking at
this without source code,
and we wanted to start
testing this with source code.
And so before we did that,
we actually stopped at their issue tracker
and just made sure
that nobody else reported
any security issues first.
Not really finding anything,
we moved on.
So, we went to their website
to see if we could download their software
and we came across this page.
And this page is the most
exciting thing you can see
as a bug bounty hunter.
I'll add some arrows to show why.
I'll add a few more arrows.
This button means that you
don't have to call sales,
You don't have to put
your credit card down
for some hopes of finding
some bug in the future.
You can just download
software and see how it works.
And as you can see in
the community addition,
it has all features in enterprise,
which is exactly what you wanna see.
So, at this point,
we went through and
installed this onto a server.
And when we looked at
the installation process,
we saw it was actually
downloading from Docker hub
and installing the Dock
containers that way.
We then played the game
of "find the API that you're calling."
And, in this case, (laughs)
we picked one called "API
get user attributes."
And we looked through all of
the servers that were running,
and we were able to find
it in the KASM API binary.
So, we copied the binary out
of that Docker container.
This is the proper way to reverse it.
The actual way that we went about it
was running strings on the binary
and then Googling a whole bunch of stuff.
But this is the actual
way that you're, (laughs)
this is the actual way that
you're supposed to identify
that it's running as a Python binary.
You can then identify the version,
drop into a Python environment,
extract the Python files,
compile Python files,
and then decompile them using uncompile6.
The steps are listed here,
in case you wanna repeat this yourself.
We then dove into client
underscore API dot P-Y
and we were able to find our
get user attributes function.
And this actually gave, well,
this concluded our game
of "find the endpoint."
And now we can actually
do the real security work
of looking at all the endpoints
for security vulnerabilities.
And so at this point, I'd
actually given up almost entirely.
And then Justin came along and said,
"Hey, there's when you create
a new KASM, a workspace,
there's a host header
that gets passed through
as one of the inputs."
And so we were a little bit
curious to see how that worked.
So, like a good bug bounty hunter,
we spun a Burp Collaborator
and we got callbacks.
And so we immediately
thought this was a crit
and game over.
We found the coolest vulnerability ever.
And, unfortunately,
we were only getting our
own session token back.
So, it's not really a credit.
It's more like a really limited blind SSRF
from a security standpoint.
It's not super interesting.
And so we obviously wanted
to maximize payout as bug bounty hunters.
So, we decided to dive deeper.
So, now's hacky time.
- Alrighty.
So, let's look a little
bit more into this.
We've seen so far how we were able
to reverse engineer the software,
get access to the code,
and now we're gonna start
finding some vulnerabilities
and figuring out why we're
getting that callback.
So, as we mentioned to the beginning,
(laughs) the configuration
for NGINX for this software
is a little bit strange.
Whenever a container is spun up,
there is a new configuration file
injected into this
containers dot D directory.
And the callbacks that
we were seeing from this
was other parts of the system
hitting these internal routes
that they created to
communicate with our new API.
We can see that here in
the proxy pass definition
for both of the locations defined here.
So, we had something interesting here.
After playing around with
it a little bit more,
we realized that it would
actually leak the session token
of anybody who visited the page
where the thumbnail of this
container was displayed.
So, if an admin came and
they viewed that thumbnail,
then their session would get leaked.
So, that made us feel a
little bit better, right?
'Cause we have a vulnerability
that we've definitely got secured.
But, like Sam said,
and my lovely desert graphic
in the beginning showed,
we saw RC in the distance
and we wanted to follow it.
So, we continued.
So, looking back at this
configuration right here,
we thought about what
other things we could do.
And, of course, when you're
injecting into a proxy pass,
most people would think of SSRF.
We already had blind SSF.
Let's see if we can get
it to be full read SSRF.
So, the way that proxy pass works
is when we passed this host header
that we were able to
inject from the command,
the HTTP request we did before,
we just changed the host header,
that got injected right
into the proxy pass here.
And if we could hit these routes,
then we could hit any arbitrary host
from the perspective of the server, right?
And in today's modern cloud environments,
this normally results in at
least something a little fun,
if not full RC or takeover
of the (indistinct) account
that this is hosted on.
So, we thought this would
be a good target to go for,
but we ran into some issues here.
Yeah, so the goal would be full read SSRF.
We ran into some issues here,
hitting these NGINX configurations.
The first one, as you can probably see,
is the first entry here
has the internal directive.
The internal directive and
NGINX only allows this route
to be routed by internal redirects
or other internal requests.
So, there was no way
that we could possibly hit that endpoint.
The second one, we also
thought looked great,
but that GUID is not leaked
to the user in any way,
shape or form.
It just gets pulled
straight out of the database
and used by other pieces of the API.
And we couldn't leak it to ourselves
because it's being overwritten
by mod rewrite there.
So, that resulted in a big sad.
So, we had to think a little bit more
about what we were gonna do.
So next, we noticed that
there are some variables
that we can access within
NGINX configuration file.
The remote address is one of them
and, actually,
NGINX provides a really nice
(laughs) alphabetized list
of variables that we could go through.
So, we went through,
I don't know if you can see
it in the screenshot there,
but all 222 of those variables
and there's nothing
interesting in there, at all,
not even one.
So, we went through all of that
and couldn't find anything
fun to do with that.
But, then we started thinking,
"Okay, variables. What about
environmental variables?
Could we leak environmental variables
from the host machine?"
So we started, like any good hackers,
we Googled how to get (laughs) access
to environmental variables
in NGINX configuration,
and this lovely Stack
Overflow article popped up.
And it mentioned running
arbitrary Lua and Pearl
in the context of a
NGINX configuration file.
So, don't mind if we do.
So, we decided to quickly
pivot and go down that path
and
yeah no, it's not gonna
be that easy for us,
unfortunately.
There is no Pearl or...
I mean, there is no Lua
or JS modules loaded.
And even though they did
tease us a little bit
with defining a Pearl's module
path in the NGINX command,
that path did not exist.
So, there was no Pearl
modules being loaded
and we couldn't use the Pearl modules.
So, we're back to the drawing board
and we're trying to
come up and we're like,
"Okay, well,
maybe we can modify this
NGINX configuration file
to do something funky."
So we start,
this is the vulnerable request,
we start injecting valid, or
what we thought was valid,
NGINX syntax into the host
header and, big surprise,
NGINX fussed at us and
said the front-end proxy,
from Sam's explanation earlier,
was not accepting that host header
because it had spaces and slashes in it.
So, this is getting more and more,
this is getting more and
more difficult, right?
So, what's the sitch here?
Just to summarize.
We have a blind SSRF,
via NGINX configuration file injection.
We've got callbacks that
contain the victim's cookies,
but we kind of wanted to
avoid any social engineering,
'cause this is bug bounty
and that's how it is.
And we can't get full read SSRF
because of the internal directive
and we couldn't find the GUID.
There were no interesting
variables to leak,
no access to code modules
and that we couldn't use
any spaces or slashes
in the host header.
So, this was looking really rough.
We were feeling down
at this point. (laughs)
And then Sam has this lovely idea.
I'm gonna read.
"I'm going to try and
call the API directly
from within the container
and see if Python is okay
with the spaces in the host header,"
which was a lovely idea.
So, essentially what he's doing here,
is he's using those end-user containers
that we're able to spin up
and he's trying to communicate directly
with the KASM API from
within the containers.
So, he spun up a nice
uBuntu box here and boom,
we could reach the internal API
without NGINX getting in our way
and, low and behold,
CherryPy is a little bit less finicky
about their host headers
and will accept pretty much
whatever you throw at it
and a little extra,
which we'll find out later.
So, that was great.
We thought we had a way
to inject into NGINX configurations
and we proceeded to write up an exploit
and take it to prod.
And
Nope.
The prod was running the
multiple server configuration
and we cannot access the KASM API.
So, at this point,
Sam and I are about to lose our minds
and we've been going back and forth
on this vulnerability for a while
and we were stuck.
We were really stuck.
So, we tried a bunch of things here.
We tried HTTP request smuggling,
We (laughs) dove in...
I don't know why we were so obsessed
with this vulnerability,
but (laughs) we just really were.
And we started reading the NGINX source.
When you start reading NGINX source code,
you know you're in trouble.
So, we started (laughs)
reading the NGINX source code
and we couldn't find
anything in the host header,
parsing logic or anything like that there.
But then, we repeated
this process for CherryPy
and we found something really interesting,
regarding ISO 88 59 dash one headers,
which I had never heard of before.
So, upon finding this,
I sent a frantic message to Sam (laughs)
and I think you can see above, me saying,
"Man, this bug,"
and then 15 minutes later,
"Dude, I've got it."
So, you can kind of feel
the bug bounty hunter drain
right there and the lows
and the highs, right?
And so let me explain a little
bit about ISO 88 59 dash one.
If that looks familiar
to you for some reason,
that's because it's used
often in SMTP headers.
So, if you've ever clicked
see original in your emails,
inside of Gmail,
then you be looking at
something like this.
And one of the things
that neither of us knew,
and that I think is not very widely known,
it's that headers are actually supposed,
according to the original RFC,
are supposed to be able to be parsed
via 88 59 dash one,
ISO 88 59 dash one encoding.
So, that was exactly what we needed.
And the CherryPy code,
you can see up at the top-right,
says, "Yeah, if there's an equal sign
and then a question mark in the beginning,
let's go ahead and try
to decode this value
as ISO 88 59 dash one."
So, the format of this
is actually very similar to URL encoding,
which is super convenient for
encoding web vulnerability
or web payloads.
And we can do something similar here.
We have to define this little
header in the beginning,
the 88 59 dash one question
mark Q question mark part,
and then, essentially, we can base 60
or URL encode our payload,
and then just replace the
percentage signs with equal signs
and you get a fairly close
to valid ISO 88 59 dash one format.
So, I think this is one of
the takeaways from this talk
is that if you're having
trouble smuggling headers
through some sort of intermediary proxy,
whether it be a WAF or
a proxy in our scenario,
this could be some way to bypass it
if any of your web
servers are, in the stack,
are accepting in decoding
or normalizing this ISO 80 59 value.
So, you can see right here,
just the character-to-character
translation
of what it looks like
for that to be decoded.
And the value that you see in red
is what is gonna be passed
to CherryPy in the end,
when the header is parsed.
And over to Sam.
- Cool.
So, at this point,
we have a way to get
through it, the KASM proxy,
and we have a way to inject host headers.
So, we're almost there,
but we first have to get
through NGINX configuration.
And so here,
what we're actually injecting
into is we're not...
We're injecting into multiple
places with the same string.
So, we're injecting into
two proxy pass directives
and then four add header directives
where the string is wrapped
in single quote characters.
And so this was something
that we had to bypass.
And our end goal here really
was to add our own location
so that we could add
arbitrary NGINX configuration.
And so we tried adding
to a new location point,
to the top two injection points,
and we didn't use any
single quote characters
so that it would be okay
for the remaining four injection spots.
Unfortunately, this doesn't work
because when NGINX sees
a duplicate location,
it rejects the configuration.
And so that didn't work.
We got this error, duplicate
location slash new.
So, we then tried something
a little bit more creative,
where we actually used some quote magic,
as how I'll describe it,
to inject into the top
two positions using quotes
and then a comment to
break out successfully.
And then, on the last
four injection points,
because the single quotes
would take priority
over the double quotes, we
won't escape from that string,
this should have worked
except for there's one evil dollar sign
in a regular expression,
right in the middle of where
were trying to inject into
and NGINX rejected this
because a single dollar sign
is an invalid variable name in NGINX.
There, as an aside,
there is actually a solution to this
where you can put this geo
dollar default dollar sign
into your NGINX configuration,
but it has to be done at a higher level
than we had access to.
We only had access to the location block.
And then we could also break out of that
into the server block.
This had to be placed in the HTTP block,
which we didn't have access to.
So, this didn't work.
So, at this point,
you've reached the most boring
part of our presentation.
I promise you, it gets better from here.
So, now is the time to
wake up if you're sleeping.
(person laughing)
So, this is really exciting.
So, it turns out you can't
repeat static locations
in NGINX configuration,
but you cannot repeat regular expression.
And this is due to the way
that NGINX parses the configuration file.
It will first compile
a list of prefix paths,
quickly find a match,
but then if it falls back
to regular expression,
it will actually go
through them one at a time
and, first match it gets,
it will send it through.
And this allows you
to actually send through
multiple identical,
regular expression, location paths.
And so this was a huge bypass.
So, as I was gonna say,
so you can repeat regular
expression and just respond.
That's big.
It was big. (laughs)
So, at this point, we built gadgets.
We weren't quite sure exactly
how we were gonna exploit
the system yet.
So, we built a full red SSRF, finally,
we built a local file inclusion
where we could actually
pull files off the system.
As an aside,
they were very secure and
they built the NGINX proxy
as a read-only file system,
so we couldn't write any files to it,
which also made this more difficult
than it should have been.
And we built a cross-site
scripting payload as well.
And so we spent a lot of time looking
for other interesting
tags that we could use
to either achieve remote code execution
or somehow cause interesting
things to happen here.
And there really weren't very many,
but there's one other one,
and this is a little bit obscure.
So client, body and file only.
And so what this will do is,
when NGINX receives a post payload,
NGINX will save the post
payload to a file on disk.
And the expectation is you then have
some sidecar Python or
Pearl process or Lua
that would then pick
it up and do something
with that post payload
and then delete the file.
So, it's more of a functionality
than it is like a security
feature tag directive, sorry.
And so why does this matter?
So, we can actually
combine this with our...
So, if we could find a secret
key that we could save,
we could combine this with our LFI payload
to steal some secret key that's
somewhere in a post payload.
So, that's exactly what we did.
So, if you remember this,
where we had these secondary servers,
where we had connections
going to KASM agent,
one of the requests that
went through to KASM agent
was a health check, and this
went through about 30 seconds.
And in that health check post body,
there was a secret key that
could be used to communicate
with that KASM agent.
So we asked, "What if we get
access to that secret key?"
And so we tried to get it. (laughs)
So, putting everything together,
ignoring what's on the
right side for right now,
I'll get to that in a second.
So, we carefully intercepted
a single KASM major request
using that client body
and file only directive.
We then forwarded along so
that the system wouldn't think
that the secondary server was unhealthy.
If it thought the secondary
server was unhealthy,
it would take it offline and
break the whole attack chain.
We'll then use our LFI
payload to steal that secret.
So, breaking this out a little bit better,
what we're actually doing here,
we're putting this into a host header
using our ISO 88 59 dash one encoding.
So the first, in the yellow,
we're using that to keep off
working for this workspace.
We're then, for the top
two injection points,
we're using...
Oh sorry, for the bottom
four injection points, sorry.
We're putting this into a comment
so that everything is
commented off correctly,
that's in blue.
And white is really the magic here
where we're intercepting the health check
and then we're stealing the
secret that contains in there.
Then we're using a regular
expression location
to create an LFI backdoor
that using a dot secret end.
So, any path that ends in dot secret
will be interpreted by
this regular expression.
And we're going use
that to steal the file,
and then we're gonna
put an unused location
at the end of all this
to close it off nicely.
So, we're also hit by
a 255 character limit,
which is why this is a
little bit code golfed.
So I do apologize, that's not super clear.
So, running this,
we, as you can see here,
you end up with a series of files
and we get our host token
in each one of these files,
which is super exciting.
So, what can you do with
KASM agent at this point?
So, with KASM agent,
it actually has a well documented API
where you can either
spin up new containers
or you can make privileged calls
to other containers to run commands.
So, in this case,
what we actually wanted to do was
we wanted to have KASM
agent make a Docker API call
to run a command on itself.
And so, because it was
a privileged container
that would allow us to access
the internal operating system.
So, using our host token,
we sent that request to the...
We sent the request on the right side here
to the KASM agent to run a command.
This command
mounted the underlying
operating system as route.
And we simply touched
a file to demonstrate
that we had access.
And as you can see here,
we were able to achieve
file right as route,
which would've led to RCE
if we had actually
exploited this for real.
At this point,
we were asked to stop.
The response we got back
from the bug bounty program
was, "Well that's worrying."
And we got our RCE.
So, we were very excited.
(person laughing)
(audience clapping)
Thank you.
So, no good slide deck is complete
without a vendor response slide.
So, NGINX doesn't consider
this to be a vulnerability,
but they might introduce
some checks in the future
to prevent certain characters
that are obviously invalid
for host headers from going through.
CherryPy actually address
this for the host header.
So, other headers are
still vulnerable, however.
KASM Workspaces has a
configuration fix for this.
And if you're running this, we
would recommend you apply it.
Additionally, in the latest version,
it's been fixed as well.
And in terms of a timeline here,
this is just to give you an idea
of roughly what this looks like.
We submitted this on three dash one.
On three six, we reported
the additional ways
that we could exploit the system.
It then took us another 22 days
to demonstrate the Docker
container breakout.
So, some takeaways.
So, from the blue team side,
you have to ask yourself how
your organization is handling,
running a server that has
multiple domain names in general.
You'll have a QA and prod.
How do you handle the host header there?
Are you trusting the
end-users to supply that?
Because that could be
a little bit dangerous
if they are doing something with it.
You also have to be a little bit careful
with local Docker networking.
I mean, that's true in any
networking environment,
but that's especially true with Docker
and mixed low and high
privilege environments.
And then on the red team side,
we know you're spraying
payloads everywhere.
So, why not just add ISO
8-8-5-9 dash one to that list.
And then, similarly, build gadgets.
And then constantly
reevaluate what you have
and what you can do.
What we presented here.
We tried to follow a logical plot.
We jumped around quite a bit
when we're (laughs)
actually exploiting this
and then, similarly, collaborate.
I think there were multiple times
where we both wanted to throw in the towel
and completely give up on this.
And then one of us found something
that just pushed us that much further,
which is really why we worked
on this for a month, (laughs)
I think, which is overkill. (laughs)
So, that's it.
Questions?
Going once.
(microphone thudding)
- [Audience Member] Hey.
So, you found the CherryPy,
you're able to use that
different encoding.
So, was that also affecting NGINX
for the host encoding when you did the-
- Could you say it one more time?
We can't-
- Yep.
Oh, sorry.
Test, can you hear me better?
Okay.
So, when you did the actual exploiters
on the CherryPy server,
did the actual encoding trick
bypass on NGINX as well?
- [Man] Can you hear him at all?
- [Audience Member] Oh, sorry.
(people chatting)
- [Audience Member] Oh, yeah.
So, when you're testing the
actual proof of concept,
you were on the CherryPy, correct?
- [Man] Yeah, I think the-
(people chatting)
- [Audience Member] Yeah.
So, when you actually exploit
it on the CherryPy server,
but the actual exploit was done on like...
You able to do the encoding
trick on NGINX as well?
- [Man] Okay. Sorry, the speakers are-
- Yeah, I know.
Sorry about having a hard time hearing.
Yeah, so the question was, I think,
when we actually did the exploit,
were we able to do it
through NGINX as well?
And I think the...
Yeah, so we were.
And so the cool thing
about the ISO 88 59 dash one encoding
is that all of those
characters are valid characters
to be in a host header on NGINX.
So, just what ended up happening
was all of those characters
that were causing the problem
in the NGINX configuration
just were encoded
and then flew right
through the NGINX part.
And then were decoded by
CherryPy on the back-end.
And that's what allowed us to
bypass that little mismatch
between the parsing of the headers
on the reverse proxy there.
So, yeah-
- Can I actually say
something about that as well?
- Yeah, go for it.
- So, within NGINX itself,
the configuration parsing
logic is heavily dependent
on certain control characters,
which were blocked by trying
to traverse through NGINX.
So, that's why we had to do this.
Yeah.
- Any other questions?
All right. Well, you can find
us on Twitter afterwards.
If you have any other questions,
our handles are down at the bottom
and thank you guys so much for listening.
(people clapping)
(Justin laughing)