- [Announcer] The talk
going on next is by Ionut.
So let's give him a big Defcon 30 welcome.
Come on!
(Round of applause)
- [Ionut Cernica] Hello everyone.
My name is Ionut Cernica,
and I will be presenting
the organization of
TOR HTTP hidden services.
So I will have an introduction
about TOR then I will speak
about non, the organization techniques,
then how downgrading the HTTP
protocol can leak the IP.
Other techniques developed
by me then how to
fix these issues because
it's a configuration issues.
Then demo time and closing remarks.
Who am I?
I'm an application security engineer
and I'm working for UAP.
This is my own research,
personal research.
CTF player, PhD student,
security researcher,
former bug bounty hunter
and former entrepreneur.
The Onion Router known as TOR
helps you to anonymize on the internet
and helps you to reach the dark net.
Where you can find the hidden services
and that the URL that
ends in onion dot onion.
The hidden service allow users
to publish their services
and it hides their
identity, on the internet
on the TOR network and the internet.
Configuration a basic
configuration is when you
declare a service directory
where the TOR configuration files will go,
then the service port
for, for the network.
Then when we start the server service
you'll have a URL like,
a long URL dot onion
for your hidden service.
Known Deanonymization
Techniques are server status.
Key certificate, another
Deanonymization technique is search
for the Onion address or the Gzip deflate.
This is not the Deanonymization
it helps you to make a,
I don't know
to make an idea where the
server is located in what,
which country.
favicon hash and if you are skilled enough
maybe you can hack the server.
So the server status
technique implies to it's,
it's only on a apache way,
apache two web servers.
And when you go to server
status, maybe they didn't disable
because it's enabled by
default on web servers
like on the apache web servers,
and maybe on the virtual host
you'll find a public IP or public domain
which you can visit and see
on the server status of
the TOR, hidden service.
The key certificate implies
that you can take, parameters
like serial numbers and so on,
and you can look for them on Shodan
which indexes information
from the internet
including the TLS information
like serial number.
And maybe you can catch the,
maybe the hidden services
use the same TLS certificate
on the internet, and you can make a match.
You can also meet, okay,
It's not a big chance of success
but you can search for the
onion address on the internet.
And you can search on search
engines like Google, Bing
DuckDuckGo, or Shodan, deserve a try.
The Gzip compression,
it's about to gives you an idea
where the server is located
and Jose Carlos found it.
And he said that around
10% of the web servers
leak the remote data when
compressing HTTP responses.
The favicon is that tiny
icon from the URL bar
and it is possible to make a hash
of it and then try to search it on Shodan.
Maybe some other website is using
and an example for this is
the Quantum ransomware group
which were Deanonymized on TOR
because they use the
favicon on the internet.
And Talos found it
equivalent on the internet.
Or hack the server with a
remote command execution
local file, or make a
research on the server,
maybe you'll find something that leaks IP.
So downgrading the protocol.
How did I find this?
Some strange requests
were in my access logs.
Something like get slash not found along
not found, not found, not
found exactly like this.
And it ends with HTTP/1.0
the protocol with a 400
bad request, and masscan
and the user agent were, was masscan
and for more information, it
gave me a website where to go
and read more information about this scan.
So when I entered in on that website
it was about university from Germany
which they said they scan all the internet
and they tried to find something.
They didn't reveal what
they are were looking for
but this behavior keep
coming for days on my server.
Also, I was seeing this
behavior on my honey pots
and I was thinking to
dump the whole request to
see what's going on there
because it's strange to
see such request and what
they are looking for.
So when I dumped their
request, the whole request
I was thinking they have been exploiting
in the header and the access
log doesn't have the parameters
in headers in the log file.
I replicated and I saw
that one of my virtual host
was publicly revealed
in the response server
and this was, I realized that
this have a big potential
on TOR or even in the internet,
because you can find unknown
or unplugged, unpublished, domains
virtual domains from one IP.
So why this behavior?
So is not a security problem apache
but based servers like apache two
Nginx or tomcat, it's
all about configuration.
The server must choose one
of the domains to forward the request.
So if you downgrade the protocol to 1.0
you don't need the host header anymore
and you can erase it from your request.
So the server will choose
the first virtual domain
from the configuration file.
And in the response, you'll find the IP
or maybe something that doesn't
help you maybe local host.
So do leak is in the triggered exceptions
like 400 bad request, 403 forbidden
or even in 404, not found sometimes.
But the best way to leak the
IP is in server redirect,
you have to trigger redirect
on the server on something else.
And this is working on
Nginx, apache two and tomcat,
and it's very easy to trigger
or redirect on every server.
Now, I just want to show
you how the response
is when we try to go to slash dot HTML.
So it's a 403, forbidden.
We have that server at my onion domain.
It's a big one and dot onion in the end.
And if I remove the host header
and I downgrade the protocol,
now I have my IP leaked.
So I just click my IP.
With 400 bad request, long
header, via long header,
if you put a long header enough
you trigger the bad request.
And as well, we have the IP address
in the response server
at my real IP address.
Again, the result with long URL
like the university from
Germany, I said earlier
they did with the long URL,
it's triggering a bad request.
Maybe that's why, I don't know,
maybe that's why they are,
they, they were doing this
or a file upload that
exceeds the server limits.
There are other ways to do
that to trigger a bad request.
You just have to find other ways.
The 403 forbidden is triggered
when you visit something
with slash dot ht.
That's because the
default configuration file
of apache tries to protect
files like htacces or htpasswd,
so you can easily trigger
these 403 forbidden
and you downgrade the protocol,
remove the host header.
Then you have the server
at with something in there
maybe on local host
or something that doesn't
help you or the public IP.
Maybe the server directs the best way to
trigger the server directs
is the best way to find
out the primary virtual host.
And an example is like, if you
have a directory that exists
on the route of the server
you can try to visit it
without the last slash.
And the server will auto redirect
to the same directory, but
with a slash after the final.
So in most cases you can find a directory
on the first HTML page of the web server.
Maybe you are dealing
with an API server and
you don't have directories
but you can use the predefine
directories from apache server
like CSS icons js, and these
directories are available only
if you visit from the local host IP
and in TOR most of the
hidden services are visited
with the local host.
To trigger the redirect.
Look at the, as I said
you look on the source code of the HTML.
You find the directory
like CSS in this case
and then you try to trigger the redirect
like get slash CSS without the last slash.
The server tries to correct this,
and tries to put a slash
at the end, but redirects
to your virtual hosts,
the primary virtual host
because I already downgraded the protocol.
So applying this on internet
maybe you can find important information.
If you are assist admin
you have to be careful how you
configure your virtual hosts.
I didn't make a research on
this because I don't know,
I I'm at the limit of legality.
It appears that others did
this before, but I don't know
if they follow this problem,
with the downgraded of protocol.
So I expect to exfiltrate domains
that normally you cannot get from an IP.
It's kind of DNS reserve, reverse.
Another technique which would be the Etag
from the response header.
You can take its value,
and if the first page is a static page.
Maybe you can look for it
on the Shodan search engine.
Another, an example of ITAG, you can see
I make a request on the
first page on the slash
and the server respond with
Etag and it's a unique value.
You should not find this on
other servers only if the same
it's a, I don't know, it's
a VMware image or something.
Other techniques, same
network techniques implies
that you have an Onion.
You try to deanonymize it.
You didn't find anything
but you have a list of all
the onions, all the onions,
a lot of onions from the tour network.
And you try to replace the host
Header with each one at a time with the,
which with every onion
address from your list.
And maybe one of them will response
as you would request at that onion.
So this implies,
this can help you to
increase the attack surface.
You don't need to attack the first onion.
Maybe you can try to
deanonyamize the second one.
So right now put on the
demo, at the end of the demo
I have something very,
very, an impressive finding.
So right now I'm trying
to access an HT anything.
to see if that I can
trigger the 403 forbidden,
but I have the HTTP 1.1
which the host header of
my onion address on TOR.
Now, if I remove the
host header, ah okay, now
I, I'm showing you that I don't
want to make a lot of noise.
So I put a h dot html, not really big URL
like not found, not found, not
found, like how others did.
And if I remove the host header
I downgrade the protocol,
you can find a hidden
domain on my web server.
And maybe that domain
it's publicly available,
you can come from the internet
on it and you can disclose its IP.
Now I try, I'm trying
to trigger a bad request
by putting the long header.
So I put a long, long header
to trigger the 400 bad request,
and the response will be the
same server at and the address.
So the server at hidden domain dot ml.
Another technique is, as I
said, is the redirect technique.
So the CSS directory should be available
by default on apache servers,
but only if you visited
from the local host.
And right now, if I visit
with my HTP 1.1 protocol
with the host header
it redirects me to the onion address.
So nothing was leaked.
If I remove the line and
I downgrade the protocol,
now in the response again,
we have the domain leaked.
So hidden domain dot ml.
Right now, what I can do it
I'm going to find out
more about this domain.
Let's take it's IP
address, make who is on it
and maybe it's public from the internet.
That's what I, I'm trying to do right now.
And after that
I'm trying to see if
this public address it's
really hosting the TOR hidden service.
So I'm looking at the ETag.
It responds from the, I
came from the internet
and it has an ETag.
If I go, I'm going back
to the TOR network,
in the next few seconds,
you'll see that it has the same ETag.
And in the end, I will
show that the server status
will show me that there is the same server
for this onion and the
IP address I visited.
Okay, I'll go to the,
Last demo it's from here.
So I'm right now I configure
the hidden domain dot ml.
So this is another configuration.
I configure the hidden
domain, in front of,
so I have the in front of
hidden domain, the CloudFlare.
So I'm trying to leak the IP address
of a cloud domain,
of a CloudFlare domain.
So I just try to, even I
don't downgrade the protocol
for the long header exception,
just for the long header
exception it'll treat will it'll
serve me the first virtual host
from the configuration file.
So I can leak the IP address of the server
which is protected by CloudFlare.
This is not a problem
in CloudFlare, it is just a
problem on the configuration.
Either is not a problem
in apache two server.
It's just a problem
in the way we configure the
virtual host of our web servers.
So right now I'm trying
to insert a long header,
and we'll see what's happening.
This is a default configuration.
So I installed a apache, I put CloudFlare,
then just,
I put a virtual host and then I just send
a long header and let's
see what's happening.
Look, I just leak my IP address.
So now maybe it's open
for direct requests.
I don't need the CloudFlare anymore.
No, no.
(Round of applause)
So in conclusion,
triggering bad requests for
403 forbidden and so on,
maybe can leak the IP address
of your apache server.
You have to choose very carefully
what virtual host you
configure, even on CloudFlare
this doesn't help you.
It's not a problem in CloudFlare,
its a problem in how you
configure the virtual host.
Try to not to use the certificates
from other projects and
disable the service status.
When you give access
to other persons to access
your server from local host.
And thank you,
I'm waiting for your questions.
(Round of applause)