- So today we have Slava Makkaveev
talking to us about
digging into Xiaomi's Tee
to get to Chinese money.
It's Slava's fifth time
speaking at DEF CON.
So please welcome him back.
(audience applause)
- Hello everyone, thank
you for that little talk.
I'm Slava, I have been doing
mobile security research
at Checkpoint for many years.
Rivers engineering and build
research is my daily work.
When I hear the phrase trust
zone or trusted environment,
I imagine some secure place
on a device where
cryptographic is passwords
and as a security sensitive
information is stored, I imagine
that protection is implemented
with hardware assistance
and major mobile cheap
manufacturers, such as media tech
and Qualcomm are responsible
for the business logic.
Okay.
In general, all my assumptions
are correct, but in fact
and this surprises me a little
not only cheap manufacturers
can change the logic
of the trust in quote
running on a smartphone.
Device manufacturers such as Xiaomi
also have the ability
to page the trusted
code and add new items.
In my research, I consider
the trusted code provided
by Xiaomi as a target for text.
And I will show you
several vulnerabilities
in Xiaomi trusted environment which rely
on regular Android application
to steal money from ordinary people.
Well, according to the latest
statistics, the far east
in China account for two sorts
of world's mobile payments
and this is about 4 billion dollars
in mobile wallet transactions.
Let's zoom in, WeChat Pay and Alipay.
are the largest players
in the Chinese mobile payment
industry, to get the account
for about 95% of the all
Chinese payment market.
Each of these platforms
have over 1 billion users.
So actually it's nice to hack only one
of them to get rich.
Today, I focus on a WeChat Pay
built in Xiaomi devices
powered by MediaTek chip.
Why is this particular combo?
Because Xiaomi is the most popular Chinese
smartphone manufacturer.
MediaTek is the most popular
mobile chip manufacturer
in the world.
And WeChat Pay is the most
popular payment platform
in China.
Okay, now let's talk about
the Trusted Environment
a.k.a TEE.
As I mentioned, mobile payment signatures
are carried out in the TEE.
So as long
as TEE is safe, so are your payments.
On the internet, you can
easily find many articles
about the TEE architecture
so I know only
the key points
TEE creates a
virtual security world mainly showed
by a trusted operating system
which runs the trusted applications.
Each trusted application
implements a specific
security feature and the normal world OS
in our cases is Android can send a command
to a trusted app and receive a response.
Xiaomi devices empowered
by qualcomm chip sets and
uses
trusted OS and media tech
based devices use Kinibi.
In both cases, Xiaomi can embed and sign
their own trusted applications.
On Xiaomi devices, you can easily find
trusted apps
in the directory
Thh/ta. Each app is represented
by an encrypted binary file and usually,
trusted applications of the Kinibi OS
have the MCLF file format.
But Xiaomi decided to come up with
one of their own. Actually,
we don't need even to
understand all the format
fields because the initial part
of the Xiaomi's trusted app is a file.
Trusted applications can
have multiple signatures
following the magic fields,
and the magic fields are the same
across all trusted apps on the device.
More the same,
same these apps fields,
overall are the devices.
As you see, the version
control field is emitted
in the trusted apps file format.
It means that in an attacker can transfer
an old versions of the trusted
application to a device
and use it to override the new app file.
As the signature of the
old trusted app is correct,
this app will be successfully
loaded by the GE.
Knowing this an attacker
can bypass security features
and pages
of Xiaomi and MediaTek
in the trusted applications by downgrading
them to an unpatched version.
I will use this vulnerability in my POC.
Okay.
Xiaomi fools the global
platform TEE client
API specification, which
defined the interface
between the client application
and the trusted environment.
This API is implemented
in the libTEEcommon.so
library
and we can use it this library to access
the trusted applications from an Android.
But unfortunately in a
previous Android application
has no permission to
communicate with the TEE.
So Linux prevents access to
the correspondent, the driver,
and it's possible to work
only from a limited number
of produced users, such
as DRM and Media Product.
To bypass we need to use vulnerability
and I will show you one a bit later.
On this slide you can see an example
of how to call a trusted
application from Android.
In this case, I sent a command
to the TEE main trusted app.
This app expects to
receive one input buffer
and one output buffer as arguments.
And the comment ID will be ignored.
Okay,
Trusted apps
implement TA in all common
entry point function.
It handles the command ID
and buffers sent from the Android side.
This function is a perfect
target for finding base on
review to research
And I use classic combination of a fail
and renew emulator to fast
Xiaomi's trusted applications
on to a (inaudible) machine.
A bit, a little later,
I'll show you vulnerability
related to mobile payment.
Okay.
Now we know what is Xiaomi's
trusted environment is.
Let's talk about
payment system. Okay.
More Xiaomi devices have
an embedded mobile payment
framework named Tencent Soter.
Tencent Soter provides
an API to create, sign,
and verify payment packages, transfer it
between the mobile application
and a remote backend server.
WeChat Pay based on the Tencent Soter.
On this slide, you can see
an Architecture of the Soter
and this platform deals
these three levels of keys.
This is device key ATTK,
application key ASK,
business key AuthKey.
Okay.
They are all very safe keys.
And the device key is generated
in the trusted environment
before the device leaves the factory,
and the ATTK public key is
safely transmitted by Xiaomi
to the remote,
to the Tencent TAM server.
Third party, Android
application, such as WeChat
can request to create an application key.
In this case, the private
ASK key will be stored
in the TEE and the public ASK key,
and its device signature, will be uploaded
to the apps backend server,
which forward furthers to the
TAM server
for verification of device public key.
In case if the ASK packet is legitimate
third party store the
application public key
on its remote server for futures.
Okay.
For each business scenario,
such as logging the business
or payment business app,
should create a business key.
The generator,
the generation process is the same
with the application key generation.
Okay.
To make a payment transaction,
an application ASK
change factor from its
remote server, usually
its random string as an object for sign in
and after user fingerprint
authorization, application
sends this challenge factor,
finger ID, device information,
and payment data to the backend server.
All this data is signed with
the business key in the TEE
and the public business
key will be used to
verify the transactions.
Tencent Soter does not
provide a key related code.
Tencent leaves the implementation
to the cheap old device
manufacturer.
So Xiaomi implemented their own soter
trusted application to store
keys and manage key operations.
On this slide, you can see
across snippet of the
soter trusted application.
I just listed a few supported commands.
To start the design session, soter trusted
application exports a command
or function in its time
which expects to receive
business key areas
and change factor as argument.
And this function creates a session ID
by calculating both this string to
and to heap based buffer
without checking
for overflow and an attacker
can provide arguments
of such length that they
overflow the heap memory
after the session buffer
is controlled to values.
Xiaomi's trusted applications
don't have ASLR for protection
so this vulnerability can be exploited.
Okay.
Now let's get back to
the Tencent Soter itself.
And this slide you can
see its implementation
on the Xiaomi devices.
Soter server is system
application, Android
application exports, I mean
fair for public Soter service.
This soter service binds vendor
point, micro trust point,
hardware point, soter system
service to communicate
to use trusted environment.
As I mentioned, an
operation rate application
has no permission to communicate
with the TEE directly
but it can use the soter
service as a proxy.
This Java code binds the soter service
and then calls the vulnerable
in its sign function.
Okay.
So Xiaomi didn't implement an Android
permission to protect the soter API.
Now I'll show you earlier, a simple demo
when an unprivileged Android
application, is visible,
an ability to pay in the WeChat.
Okay.
So on the right side, you see command line
actually is just to show you what is going
on and on the left side, this a telephone.
Okay.
So I implemented a simple tool.
This name, soter holder. This tool I used
just to send commands,
specific commands to
the soter trusted application
and output will build the store
in some files provided
in the command line.
So first of all, I just want to show you
that soter, tencent soter,
is okay, it works and
return some results.
For example, using this command
I ask to generate ASK application command.
And after that, and in signed
so we have two results.
And also, in the Android kernel log,
we see that everything is okay
so tencent soter responded to our request.
Now I just opened an
unprivileged Android application.
So this is a malware.
This application can be
downloaded from play store.
And moment of launching when
I implemented a button
block payments.
So in this moment, when you
press an unblock payment
I just sent a used chain
of vulnerabilities to
break the tencent soter.
And it's mean,
as you see on the right side.
So I tried again to send a command
to the soter and we see the target death.
And the same situation in the kernel log.
So it means that nothing happened.
So we can't open a session
with the tencent soter.
It means that at this moment
if we're trying to open WeChat
application, when we open it
we see that it tries to create a session,
open a session with a
soter twice actually, and
but soter is dead and means
that WeChat pay application,
WeChat application,
does not provide actual
button to make a payment.
That's all.
So it means
that malware application
can close the ability to pay
in the WeChat.
Okay, but actually we don't
want to block payment.
We want to extract a private pay because
(inaudible) completely
compromised the sorter platform allowing
to unauthorized users to
sign fake payment packages.
To steal one of the private keys, I use an
add vulnerability is this
is (inaudible) vulnerability
in the old version of the
sorter trusted application.
If you remember, we can
can downgrade the trusted
application on Xiaomi devices.
Let's see in the TEEc operation argument
of the Invoke Command function
which we used to call soter
trusted app from Android.
The caller can provide
up to four arguments
such as a number or buffer
to the trusted application for processing
and the common types I encoded
in the param types field.
Each trusted application must
ensure that the data sent
from the insecure side matches
the expectation of this app.
What happens if
an trusted application
expects to receive a point
or two buffer, but we provide a number.
In this case, if this application
does not check the type
of incoming parameter.
So our number will be recognized
as, is a virtual address.
And soter application we will read
or write to the memory (inaudible).
Okay.
So I found that one
of the old versions of the
soter trusted application locks
checking for incoming parameters,
and we can use this to,
we can use it to achieve a better memory.
So if we hold the target
device in our hand, we can send
HAS_AUTH_KEY command and specify
the address we're interested
in as the second argument.
And in this case, we will see a content
of this address in the Android kernel log.
So on the slide.
If we don't, don't want to deal
with kernel log and just want
to get information from our code,
we need to send
has our generate HAS_AUTH_KEY
command and define
the target address, again,
as a second argument
and soter trust application
generate the business key
based on the content of the
address that we specified.
And after that we can use HAS_AUTH_KEY
HAS_AUTH KEY command many
times to find the value
which match
the generated key.
Okay. So we have a read vulnerability.
In addition, there is no a SLR.
So all we need to steal the
data is just to shape the heap.
Okay. I just want to note here that the,
to force load
for example, private device
key, we need to send export
ASK_KEY command to the
trusted applications.
And in this case, this public key
will be loaded from the security storage
to the heap of the soter trust tech.
Okay. Now I'll show you POC.
How, how to extract,
how to extract device private key.
Oops. Okay.
Just a second.
So it's, it's already technical.
Sorry for this.
So I will use the same
tools that I implement.
It's really simple too, just to provide
to send some information.
First of all, we doing downgrade attack.
So we override the
new version
of the soter trusted
application with the old one.
This is the first step.
After that,
we sent form export ATTK key
this comment to ASK
official public device key.
This is a public key.
Just, I want to save it
in the sound file to
validate the transactions.
This, after that, I ask, use
the export ASK key command
give me please identification,
application key, and
signature application key.
And again, we store it in specific files.
Next step we use readability
to extract private key.
Actually this key
is represented
by say private exponent
and (inaudible) models.
And so now we have all
the information we need.
We extracted private
key, public key, packet,
and we just need to validate this.
Our signature is correct.
How we can do it.
We can use open S.
So using this command, I
just validate the public key
and signature of the
regional packet is correct.
It should be correct
because we didn't fix any data.
Verified, okay.
Next we're going to patch packet.
This is ASK packet.
Okay. This we're.
We are going to patch some key
some packet this with any data.
And after that, we are going to sign
this packet with extracted private key.
We can use open S here
because open S' doesn't
know how to proceed
with private exponent and modules, but
metrics as a cell, no.
This is open source too,
metrics are the same.
So we sign packet.
And the last one, again
we use an open S to validate
that the new package packet
which we fixed
is correct and signature is correct.
So verified.
It means that we extracted private key.
We use it to sign and actually it means
that we can sign any packet we want.
Okay.
Thank you
To summarize, okay.
OEM
provided TEEs
a very promising area
for security research
because many security
critical features implemented
by OEMs and not by cheap manufacturers.
To prove this, we analyze the
tencent total platform built
in the Xiaomi devices
and found two ways to attack WeChat app.
One is from an unprivileged
Android application
by exploiting the overflow
vulnerability, and the second one
by downgrading the soter
trust attack, okay.
Xiaomi has fixed most of the
vulnerabilities
we reported two months ago.
So thank you for your attention.
You can find a lot of
good security research
on our research board.
(audience applause)
Thank you.