- We're gonna get started
today with Bill Woodcock
talking about the Internet's
role in sanctions enforcement,
and Russia/Ukraine and the future.
So let's give him a warm welcome
up here in the DEF CON stage.
(audience clapping)
- Howdy! I'm not the world's
most organized speaker,
and this is gonna be my first time
running through these slides.
Oh, okay. Can you guys hear me?
All right. I was just saying,
I'm not the world's most organized speaker
and this is my first time
running through these slides.
So I may not balance out the
amount of talking per slide terribly well,
but we'll try and get through this
and leave enough time for a
little bit of Q&A at the end.
So, what I'm here to talk
about is the question of
what the Internet's role is
in sanctions enforcement.
So, you're probably all, at least,
a little bit familiar
with what sanctions are.
Governments impose
sanctions on some party,
and then banks, for instance,
in the country of the government
that's imposed the sanctions,
have to not do business with that party.
And sanctions more generally
apply to things not just banks,
and the internet is a thing,
and their internet service providers.
So there's this question of
what internet service providers
should do with sanctions
when they're imposed.
That was brought to ahead
in March of this year
because, when Russia invaded Ukraine,
Ukraine asked ICANN and RIPE,
which is the IP and
Autonomous System Number
allocation authority for Europe,
essentially to cut
Russia off the Internet,
to deactivate route
name servers in Russia,
to revoke Russia's use of
IP addresses and domain names.
Both RIPE and ICANN refused that request,
which was the right thing to do.
But these are internet
governance organizations,
and they refused the request summarily,
they did not engage their
internet governance process,
they didn't talk with their
constituency about this.
They just said no as a
sort of executive and legal matter
rather than an internet governance matter.
As a result of that request,
the internet community never got engaged
to discuss this.
Obviously, from ICANN's point of view,
and from RIPE's point of view,
this is a pain in the ass,
and they'd rather not be
asked something like that.
And having been asked,
they don't really want to
have a discussion about it,
they just want the whole thing to go away.
So, each of them very quickly said no.
But their responses were pretty brief
and to the point,
and didn't really help
Ukraine, as a country,
figure out what they
could have asked instead.
Like, okay, so the answer
to that question is no,
but you are a beleaguered
country under attack,
and it's perfectly reasonable
for you to be looking at your options
and trying to figure out what you can do.
So, Vince Cerf and Steve Crocker, and I,
and about 70 other people
who are routinely involved
with internet governance
got together and we spent 10
days hammering out a letter
that provided a more in-depth response.
So the answer was still
no, but it pointed out why,
and it said what other options there were,
what things they could have asked for
that might have been easier
for somebody to say yes to,
or specifically, easier for the
internet governance
community to say yes to.
So, that in turn led to an engagement
of the internet governance community
with this issue of sanctions,
and what would that look like.
So let me run through a
little bit of the basics
of what sanctions are.
So, sanctions are things
that governments do.
If you decide that
you don't wanna do business with somebody,
that's a boycott.
So if it's private, it's boycott,
if it's public, it's a sanction.
Sanctions don't actually require
any internet governance engagement
because they're just a matter of law,
and you decide whether
you're gonna follow the law
or not follow the law.
It's not really a matter for third parties
to have policy discussions about.
And the parties that
need to decide whether
they're gonna follow the law
are internet service providers,
people who are carrying internet traffic
that may be either bound
for a sanctioned entity
or coming from a sanctioned entity.
Internet service
providers are incorporated
and do business in specific countries.
Those countries have governments,
those governments may be doing sanctions.
Not every government define sanctions.
A lot of them just default to
the United Nations and say,
"Well, whatever the
United Nations sanctions,
we will go along with.
We will enforce that,
but we're not going to
define new ones of our own."
But the US, Canada, UK,
Australia, New Zealand,
all of the European
Union, the African Union,
Switzerland, Sweden,
these are all countries
and intergovernmental
organizations that do sanctions
over and above what happened
in the United Nations.
It's a little bit hard to
get consensus in the UN
on sanctioning anybody
because the UN's big
and there are a lot of
folks who can say no.
So, where there are problems
for internet service providers
with sanctions are not
if you're in a country and
you need to follow a law,
that's pretty simple.
It's when you've got operations
in multiple countries
and you need to follow multiple laws
that are not in agreement with each other.
Now, if you're working
in the US and the UK,
and the US says, "Sanction party A"
and the UK says, "Sanction party B,"
you can sanction both parties, A and B,
and that's not in conflict.
But sometimes there are laws that say
that you can't mess with something.
So that's when you get a conflict.
So Russia, for instance,
has passed domestic laws in Russia
saying that you can't
sanction Russia, or that
internationally imposed sanctions
cannot be enforced inside Russia
by a party that's doing
business inside Russia.
And those are recently passed
laws and you can guess why.
So, sanctions are
a punitive measure, it's a punishment.
But they're deescalatory
relative to launching a missile.
In theory of armed conflict,
this idea of deescalatory
measures is an important one.
If you're trying to get out of a conflict,
the notion is that you
should respond in kind
but in a deescalatory manner.
So, respond, but not as much
as the other person did,
and that signals that you
want the conflict to go away.
So, sanctions are deescalatory measure.
You can show that you
still care about something,
but you're not trying to make
the fight a bigger fight.
There are these two different terms
that are important to distinguish between:
cyber sanctions and internet sanctions.
This is a completely
artificial-contrived distinction.
It's two labels that
are being used to denote
two different concepts.
Cyber sanctions denotes
a sanction of any kind
that is imposed because
you didn't like something
somebody did in cyberspace.
Somebody does a cyber attack against you,
steals your intellectual
property and publishes it online,
and you block their bank accounts.
That's a cyber sanction.
Internet sanctions are sanctions
imposed via internet means,
in response to whatever. Anything.
Doesn't necessarily have
anything to do with the Internet.
So, somebody invades a
city and blows up a school,
and you wanna sanction them,
but you want to sanction them
by cutting them off the Internet,
by blocking the routing
of their IP addresses,
by revoking their domain names,
that's an internet sanction,
and that's what I'm talking about today,
not cyber sanctions.
The other big distinction
that is worth understanding
is between comprehensive
sanctions and targeted sanctions.
Comprehensive sanctions are,
"We're sanctioning Russia.
We're sanctioning Iran.
We're sanctioning Cuba."
Targeted sanctions are,
"We're sanctioning this
specific military unit.
We're sanctioning this
particular business.
We're sanctioning this aircraft."
Targeted sanctions are
what everybody does now.
Comprehensive sanctions, 50 years ago,
yeah, that was a thing.
It's just not anymore.
Governments have by and large
really gotten past doing that,
but in the public perception of sanctions,
that's what a lot of people imagine.
They imagine, "Russia invaded Ukraine.
Therefore, Russia is gonna get sanctioned.
Therefore, I can't do business
with anybody in Russia."
But that's really not how it works.
In fact, you could go and
you could download a list
of all of the sanctioned
entities in Russia.
And it would be, depending
on what country you're in,
about 1000 entities.
But those entities are gonna be like the
St. Petersburg troll farm,
Wagner, the mercenary company,
a few ships, yachts
belonging to oligarchs.
These are gonna be the
sanctioned entities.
Blocking all of Russia is over-blocking,
that's over-compliance with the sanction.
That's doing more than
what government actually wants you to do.
So, over-blocking, over-sanctioning
is one of the primary problems
that happens with sanctions.
A government says, "Well,
we've got a problem.
We're gonna do this very
targeted intervention
to try to fix the problem."
And then somebody says,
"Oh, well, I'll just
block the whole country."
And that has a pretty bad effect.
We don't really want
to block all of Russia
and make it difficult
for regular people to
get access to international
news, for instance.
So, real-world targeted sanctions
are what people need to comply with.
And so, understanding
what those sanctions are
and who the entities that
have been sanctioned are,
is the most pressing problem
if you're trying to be compliant.
So if you talk with governmental
folks who do sanctions,
what they'll tell you is that there are
three purposes to sanctions:
signaling, constraint, and coercion.
Signaling is basically just
saying to the whole world,
"We really don't like what
these people are doing.
So, we're sanctioning them in
order to tell the rest of you
that we don't approve of this."
That's easy to do, and it
tends to be very successful,
in the sense that if you sanction somebody
and you communicate what you're doing,
the rest of the world will understand
that you disapprove of something.
Constraint is using the sanction to try to
stop the sanctioned party
from doing something.
Shutting down their bank accounts
so that they can't use
those bank accounts to
continue to conduct business,
or conduct a war or whatever.
Constraint is rarely an
all-or-nothing thing.
If we talk about internet sanctions
and talk about blocking
Russian domain names
or blocking Iranian IP
addresses or something,
it's not gonna kick them off the Internet,
it's not gonna keep them
from using the Internet.
It may make it more difficult
and more expensive for them.
Just like a financial sanction
where you shut down their bank account
isn't gonna keep them from using money,
it's just gonna make it a
lot more difficult for them.
They're gonna have to use more cash.
They're gonna have to set up
other accounts under other names.
They're gonna have to use their
grandmother's bank account
instead of their own, whatever.
So, the constraint thing
is, again, it's not an absolute,
it's more about creating friction
that makes things more expensive.
Coercion is where you're
trying to get the person
to stop doing the thing
that you don't like.
So, this is forcing them enough
that they actually will
change their behavior
where it's not just a constraint
to keep them from doing
something involuntarily,
but actually changing their mind.
That's a tough one.
So, if you talk with
governmental policy people
who do sanctions, what
they'll tell you is that
going down from the top,
a really good success rate
on constraint or coercion
is like 10-20% success.
And since sanctions cost governments
very little to implement,
it's worth doing, it's not a big deal.
It may not have a huge effect,
but it's also not expensive.
And the signaling part is
important for a lot of folks,
so, why not?
So sanctions are a thing.
Governments have been using
sanctions for thousands of years
at this point.
So, there's plenty of build
up expertise inside government
about what works, what
doesn't work, so forth.
They've got realistic expectations about
what they should expect of the
sanction in terms of success.
They don't think that
sanctioning something
is just gonna immediately stop
the behavior that they don't want.
They understand sanctions
with respect to the movement
of money fairly well.
Governments have a lot
of internal expertise
around tracking the movement of money.
And so, if a sanction is not
being enforced, they can tell.
They don't really have that
kind of internal expertise
around networking, around the internet,
internet service providers, telecoms.
So they don't really
know what's gonna work,
they don't really know what's appropriate,
they don't really know
what degree of compliance they're getting.
So this is an area where
things could improve.
Internet service providers,
network operators
could communicate more with government,
educate them about what's
possible and what's feasible,
and also communicate more about
what they're actually doing.
Governments also don't
really have any expertise
at identifying what could be sanctioned,
associated with sanctioned entities.
So if we look at the St.
Petersburg troll farm,
and you ask a government person,
"Okay, how do we sanction this?"
They go, "I don't know.
Cut them off the Internet.
Don't know what that means, but."
But if you talk with an
internet service provider,
they're like, "Okay, well,
we'll stop routing their IP addresses.
How do we do that?
Well, we're gonna look in the RIR who is,
and see what IP addresses they have.
We're gonna see what autonomous
system number they're using
to originate that.
We're gonna see what
other IP address blocks
are being originated from the same AS.
We're gonna see who their
upstream transit providers are,
we're gonna go have a
chat with those folks.
We'll see if they're multihomed, so forth.
On the domain name side,
look and see what the name servers are,
what the contact information
for the registration is,
who the registrar is, all the things.
And we'll build up a little
set of the domain names
that we think this party is using.
We'll look to see what email addresses
they have used on things, who
their email providers are.
All of these are things that,
from the internet perspective,
we're very used to doing
in association with abuse.
So if somebody is spamming,
if somebody is running a botnet,
we've got a lot of experience
with tracking these things
down, doing the detective work,
figuring out what the
associated resources are
and shutting them down.
This is no different. It's
exactly the same problem set,
it's just a different
definition of badness.
It's not our internet
definition of badness,
it's a general human rights
and international law
definition of badness.
Now, as we got into all this,
what we discovered is that
the thing that governments
are really bad at
is publishing their list
of sanctioned entities.
You'd think that would be kind of basic,
but the way governments
handle this is like,
"Hey you, take a memo.
Put it on top of the stack of other memos
from other sanctions that
we published before."
Trying to get this
electronically on the internet
is really, really tough.
The only government that
publishes their sanctions list
in a machine-readable format is the UK,
and that's been down for
the last four months.
So normally it works,
but just not recently.
So they actually have
JSON files at a known URL.
Everybody else is like, "Oh,
well, we can fax those to you.
Or, let us scan them. Publish the PDF."
So, that needs to be fixed.
Internet service providers
wanna to be compliant with the law.
They don't wanna be in
trouble with the governments
of the countries that they do business in.
But they're mostly unregulated.
This is completely different than banks.
Banks have to deal with
a ton of regulation,
and government regulators who
understand their business,
know what's going on.
ISPs don't have that
connection with government
because they're not
regulated in most places.
They also don't have
Know Your Customer laws
that apply to them.
If you're an ISP, you don't
have to sit your customer down,
interview them, understand their business,
take lots of records about
them and hold those records,
and then check back with
them once a year to see if
they're still doing the same
business they used to be.
Whereas, in a lot of countries,
Know Your Customer applies to
pretty much any financial service.
So, that doesn't really
prepare ISPs for dealing with
sanctions enforcement stuff.
But at the same time, ISPs
face all kinds of risks.
So there are fines and criminal
prosecution possible for
over-compliance, under-compliance,
non-compliance, miscompliance.
Getting it wrong has liability.
But then there also the secondary effects.
So, if you have customers, and
the customer gets sanctioned,
and you don't sanction
them but their bank does,
suddenly, they're not
gonna be able to pay you
for the service that they've used.
So, if you look at the
Russia/Ukraine conflict,
this is actually what wound up happening,
a bunch of internet service providers
cut off all their Russian customers
because they were sort of
looking out a few months.
They were saying, "Well,
it's March 3 right now,
and we bill monthly, net 30.
So at the end of March,
we're gonna send out a bill for March
and it's gonna be due at the end of April.
So, 60 days from now,
will some of my customers
have been sanctioned,
have their accounts frozen
and be unable to pay me?
Don't know. Let's just
get rid of that risk.
60 days from now, will Russia as a whole,
be having trouble paying bills
because the Ruble will have collapsed
because of banking sanctions?
Don't know. Okay, well, let's preemptively
get rid of those customers."
So we saw this wave of over-compliance
back at the beginning of March
of internet service providers not knowing
what they should do, and doing too much.
Some of them. Others
didn't do anything at all.
And one, notably, said that,
well, nobody can tell them
who to do business with.
They were gonna keep
on selling services to
Wagner and the troll farm.
Then they lobbied the US government
to get the US government
to put in an exemption
for them to sell internet services
to sanctioned entities at Russia.
I have no idea why the US
government went along with that,
and all the sanctions
people in other countries,
looking at the US and wondering
what the hell happened there.
Anyway. So, there's also a problem that
we discovered with network operators.
There's a libertarian
streak that comes from
how the internet got set up,
switched from being a
US governmental project
to a private sector thing
in 1992, dot-com bubble.
A lot of people in this
"this isn't a government
project anymore" mode,
and there were also a lot of people
who are very into privacy.
And so you get some people
running internet service providers
who feel like they really
need to defend their customers
against their government.
Like, "If we're gonna choose sides here,
we're always gonna choose
our customer's side."
Now in principle, that's fine.
But if, out of your 100,000 customers,
two of them are really awful
human rights violators,
and they get sanctioned,
maybe those aren't the two that
you choose to go to bat for.
So, this made a bit of a conflict there.
And also, this sort of notion of
the internet should be open
and we shouldn't judge people
based on their content.
And fine, if your customer is a furry,
don't judge them on their content.
But if they're killing lots of civilians,
maybe judging that is okay.
Internet network operators are also
really, really good at blocking stuff.
Lots of practice at blocking things.
So again, this is really
just a question of
matching up the sanctions
with the already existing
skills of blocking.
So, the German internet service providers
went to their regulator and said,
"We'd like some guidance here.
Please tell us more about
what you want us to do."
And the German regulator came back
with a pretty clear statement
that basically said,
"Well, you do too much, you do too little,
you're either gonna get
prosecuted or hauled into court.
Your choice. So maybe
you'd wanna just figure out
what we want, and do it.
So, the Germans anyway were pretty clear,
but that's probably representative
of the response that any
other government would give.
You go asking governments whether
you need to follow the law
or not, and the answer
is usually gonna be yes.
So, we got this project going,
internet style, just a
bunch of folks, volunteers,
doing their thing, to
try to work through this
and figure out how to get
internet service providers
and governments into alignment on this
because they both want to be, right?
The internet service providers
want to be in compliance
with the law, they don't want
to get prosecuted or sued,
governments want to be
able to define a sanction
and have it enacted by the private sector
as intended, not overdone
or underdone, or whatever.
So everybody wants to meet in the middle.
There's a lot of goodwill.
Now it's just kind of a question of,
since March we've been working-
- [Attendee] I think it's only one, right,
'cause he's on the left?
- Hello? Okay.
Working through the specifics
and figuring out where the problems are.
And like I said, number
one biggest problem
is getting governments
to publish the list of
who has been sanctioned
in a way that we can
consume electronically.
So, this organization, we
got five working groups:
policy, intelligence, oversight,
operations, and research.
The policy group is trying to figure out
who's been sanctioned.
The intelligence group
then tries to figure out
what internet resources are associated
with sanctioned entities.
The oversight board then
looks at the result,
does a last sanity check before
handing it off to operations
who publish the resources
of the sanctioned entities
as a realtime feed using RPZ and BGP.
So, RPZ for the domain names,
BGP for the routes and autonomous systems,
or the IP addresses,
not autonomous systems.
And then the research group is there to
track how all this is going,
collect statistics, run
the beacon, so forth.
So where do things stand right now?
The main thing that's
going on right now is
we've had a lot of talk
in the European Union,
among a lot of governments about this.
Everybody is happy with the idea.
Now it's this question of
working through the specifics,
and the OECD seems like
the good place to do that.
And so there's been a
work program going for
3/4 months now,
well, since the beginning
of April, in the OECD.
So the OECD is like the
civilian counterpart to NATO.
After World War II,
there was the Marshall
Plan to rebuild Europe.
The OECD, the Organization for
Economic Cooperation and Development
is the civilian side of that,
NATO is the military side.
So for dealing with economic stuff,
the OECD is the place to get
standards and best practices,
harmonized, then published
for the member countries,
which is the 38 largest
free market democracies.
So, the thing that we're
trying to get standardized is
how the list gets published
because different countries
have different lists.
And right now, it's a huge mess,
I'll get into the details
of that in a little.
We also need governments
to be really clear that if
a network operator uses this mechanism
to enact a sanction,
that that is not over or under-compliance,
that that is sufficient compliance.
Right now, all the technical
mechanisms of doing this
are proven out,
and we're not
putting anything into the feeds yet.
And all of these working groups are up,
except the intelligence group,
we didn't want to have a
bunch of frustrated detectives
trying to detect things
if there wasn't yet
a clean feed of data
coming in from governments.
So I mentioned this earlier,
I just wanted to have a slide about it,
"Do sanctions disconnect
anybody from the internet?"
If you tell internet service providers,
"Cut off this party,"
are they gonna be off the internet?
And the answer is no.
Just like if you shut
down their bank accounts,
it doesn't prevent them from using money,
it just makes it more difficult.
So, then there's sort of this question,
there are people on the libertarian side
on one hand
and people on the
extreme human rights side
on the other hand,
who think that,
because communications are a
defined human right,
that messing with people's communications
is a really bad idea.
So, if it were the case that
sanctioning somebody's
internet communications
would cut them off the internet,
that would be a valid point.
But since it's really just a matter of
increasing friction for them,
their human right to communicate
has not been violated.
So then there's this question about
what does this friction mean?
We're not opening up their bank account
and taking money out.
So, what's happening there?
Internet communications is
all about collaboration.
Internet service providers get together
at internet exchange points,
they collaboratively operate them.
The bandwidth is produced
in the exchange points,
ISPs take it and deliver it to end users.
And all of that happens
through cooperation.
When we cooperate, we get efficiencies.
If we work together on something,
that efficiency makes
something more valuable to us
or cheaper for us.
If we choose not to
cooperate with someone,
their costs go up because
their efficiencies get worse.
So, what's happening, if we stop routing
IP addresses on behalf
of a sanctioned entity,
it's not that we're cutting
'em off the internet,
but we're saying, "We're
no longer going to
cooperate with you to make
things more efficient for you.
So, your costs are your costs,
whatever those might be,
not my problem."
So that's the mechanism
that's happening there.
A few other problems that we ran into
that there aren't
necessarily good answers to.
Let's say that the troll
farm goes and finds
the public school next
door and gets on their wifi
and routes all their traffic
through a public school.
We got two choices.
One choice is, "Okay, now we
block that public school also,"
or, we say, "Well, we were trying to
sanction the troll farm,
but I guess we're not gonna do this one."
Neither of those is a great answer.
If you decide to block the school,
the answer that sanctions
people have come up with is,
"Well, yes, that harms them,
but we're not the ones causing the harm.
We're the proximate cause
but we're not the ultimate
cause of that harm.
It's the party that used them
to try and circumvent the sanction
that's causing that harm."
That's not an answer that's
gonna satisfy everybody.
We've got another problem
specific to domain names,
which is, if we block a domain name,
then somebody creates a subdomain of that,
should that also be blocked,
or, are subdomains fair game?
Again, there's the risk
of over-compliance here
if we block the domain
and everything below it,
that may catch other parties, who knows,
might take a little bit
more detective work.
We've also got conflicts with
privacy and anti-trust law.
In a lot of countries, the
information needed to identify
a sanctioned entity is
gonna be PII, right?
It's gonna be protected
personal information,
and there are gonna be a lot of rights
that they have around that.
And so, if government wants
us to take that information
and use it, not for the user's benefit,
but for the government's
benefit and public benefit,
then we need a carve-out in
law saying that that's okay.
Likewise, if we're gonna work together
with other internet
operators to block somebody,
we need an exemption under
law from anti-trust that
would allow us to talk about that.
And now we're getting into the trivia
and I'm gonna blow through a lot of this,
but I'm leaving it in the slides.
So if you guys are interested
and wanna look at the details
of how all this works,
it's in the slide deck.
The beacon is an artificial
set of domain names,
networks, and autonomous system numbers
that are getting sanctioned, artificially,
not by an actual government,
but as part of this
process so that researchers
can check and see how far the effects
of this mechanism are propagating.
And it was important to
get this up and running
on day zero so that the
baseline would start at zero
for the effectiveness.
Number one problem
we're having with the
data is transliteration.
All these governments decide
that it's simpler for them
to use their local character set
than the character set
used by the language
of the place where the
sanctioned entity is.
So, you get Cyrillic and
Arabic transliterated into
Roman characters, and everybody
does that differently.
So here we've got two examples.
The first one, Anatoliy,
common enough name,
three different common
transliterations of it
into Roman characters,
and that problem is just rampant.
Every single sanctioned entity,
sanctioned in three different countries,
they're gonna spell it
three different ways.
So, Unicode is our friend, right?
Unicode solves this problem.
Take the official name of the entity,
as defined by their own
government in their own documents,
use that in Unicode as our primary label,
and then, sure, have transliterations,
but mark them as not the canonical data.
Likewise, we've got all kinds of things
that get abbreviated a
zillion different ways.
So, Open Joint Stock Company
gets abbreviated a zillion different ways.
That is just a property.
It's a property of the other
name that can be tokenized.
That token can be represented
in local language wherever.
A lot of these problems get solved
by having the right database schema,
and defining the data types in
the schema in a sensible way.
And I am going to blow through slides
explaining all the different
things that we think
we've learned about how to
do that database schema.
But you go to the sanctions.net website,
it's a Wiki,
your contributions and thoughts
are very, very welcome.
Okay. So, folks have
questions about this stuff.
Sir?
- [Audience Member] Yeah.
Thank you for that talk.
It seems to me the problem
with transliteration
that you were just talking about,
artificial intelligence,
natural language processing
and standardizing that could go a long way
in solving that problem.
So, are you looking into that?
- Alright. I don't know
if everybody was able to
hear the question clearly.
Question is around natural
language processing
and artificial intelligence
and machine learning,
could those help in identifying?
I think the problem here
is that machine learning,
if you've got millions
and millions of things
to train it on, sure.
This is more like the no-fly list
where everybody named Mohammed
is suddenly no longer
allowed on an airplane.
It's pretty easy to get wrong.
If you get it wrong, it
has pretty bad consequences
for somebody specific.
There aren't a lot of cases to train on.
And knowing when you've gotten it right
and when you've gotten it
wrong is not necessarily easy.
And it's not like the
answer is unknowable.
Knowing what somebody's name is
as spelled in Arabic,
it's their name, it's on their passport,
it's on a zillion documents.
If we can identify the person at all,
probably we can identify them
in their native language.
Is that name gonna be
unique? Not necessarily.
But, put together with
a bunch of other things,
like, if it's a person, their
height, their date of birth,
identifying characteristics.
You put enough of those things together
and you've got a unique identity defined.
This kind of thing, yeah, there
is a lot of technology for.
I mean, we spent the
last 20 years developing
machine learning so that
we could identify consumers
uniquely and make absolutely sure
that we can sell everything
to the right person.
Sure, we know how to identify people.
There are ways in which
machine learning can help,
but the name part is not that big a deal
and doesn't need giant fire power.
It just needs government
people to understand
what Unicode is. Sir!
- [Audience Member] Bill, can you hear me?
First of all, I think you did a great job.
So, this beginning thing
about not doing necessarily
a good communication, I thought
you did an excellent job.
There's number one.
Number two. Could you expand
or give your opinion on
the registrars and registers of
the who host these
domains and then forward,
or integrate them into
everything you were saying,
using that as an example, please?
- Okay. So question
regarding the integration
into all this of the
domain name registrars.
So with domain names,
we've got the registrant,
who is the ultimate end
user of the domain name,
or the party that bought it.
We've got the registrar,
who is the party that sold it to them.
We've got the registry,
which is where the unique records of
who controls what are.
The registry almost never
has a direct relationship
with the registrant,
the registrars always sit in the middle.
It's sort of like you buy a car,
you're not buying it from Ford or GM,
you're buying it from a dealership.
And so your relationship
is with the dealership.
That analogy is gonna seem really dated
in about 10 years,
probably. But there you go.
So, if we're gonna engage
parties, the issue is that
once the car has been sold,
the dealership is not involved anymore.
So once a domain name has been registered,
the registrar isn't really involved
unless there's some
registrant-initiated change.
So if the registrant says,
"I wanna change my domain name servers"
or, "I wanna change my
address" or something,
then the registrar gets involved
by sending those changes
up to the registry.
There's a protocol called EPP,
Extensible Provisioning Protocol,
that runs between registrar and registry.
That's all automated.
And so the registrar's
job is basically just
feed information into EPP.
That's a one-directional thing.
It goes into the registry,
there's nothing that comes back.
So there isn't really much to do
with the registrar.
The registrant is the problematic
party in the first place,
so we can't really deal
with them directly.
The registry can remove a domain name
at the registry level,
and that is exactly the right point to
do that blocking most effectively,
but that's a 100% blocking
of that domain name.
So there are gonna be people
who are gonna say that that's overkill.
Having looked through the
list of who gets sanctioned,
I would disagree.
The people who get
sanctioned by and large are
pretty bad folks.
And I am perfectly happy
with having them not be on my internet.
But there's a question of
how much fight you want to get into with
libertarian folks and internet
freedoms folks and so forth.
So the other place that
you can do that is at the
DNS recursive resolver level.
So, Quad9, and CloudFlare, and Google,
between the three of them,
right there, that's like half
the world's DNS resolution.
So, three organizations could
pretty effectively do this.
All right. I think that's it for our time.
Thank you all very much.
And I'll be over there somewhere,
if anybody has further
follow up questions.
Thanks a lot.
(audience clapping)