- All right, so to start
this off officially,
Ben Gardner and Chris
Poore are here to talk
to you about trailer shouting.
Please help me welcome them to the stage.
- Thanks everybody.
- [Man] Also, waters
are here for you guys.
- That's going to be
needed. Thank you very much.
So, yeah, Chris and I are here to talk
to you about some
research that we have done
together with NMFTA and AIS.
Should be 45 minutes. I
hope we are going to end.
It's definitely gonna be 45 minutes.
We are gonna end with a demo video.
So they said that actually
trying to do this remote
induction attack on stage
in this RF environment
was a bad idea.
You're probably right. So
you'll see a video instead.
First about us.
I'm Ben Gardner
with the National Motor
Freight Traffic Association.
I'm a cyber security
research engineer there.
I have a career in reverse engineering
and embedded systems development,
and I like to volunteer at various things.
And I've had the pleasure
of being an instructor
at the cyber truck
challenge for every year.
And this is Chris Poore.
- Hi, I'm Chris Poore
and I'm a senior reverse engineer
at Assured Information Security.
My company does a lot of things,
but one of them is work
with people like Ben here
to find vulnerabilities and come up
with me mitigations for those.
You may see me yesterday
at the demo labs showing
off Fissure, the RF framework.
Some of the tools in
this talk are included
with that software, so check it out
at my companies Github
page if you get a chance.
- And it goes without saying that Chris
and I are just the lucky
two people that are up here
on stage we're, we're part
of a much larger team.
I actually see one of
them in the audience.
So Dan Salone right there,
Eric, there is on our team.
We had some anonymous
people as well, help us out.
And of course,
what we've done would
not have been possible
without the member fleets.
The people that own the
trucks that our members
of the NMFTA so big thanks to them.
So we're here to tell you
about an issue with J24-97,
also known as PLC4Trucks and for you
to understand the issue, you have to know
what is this PLC4Trucks?
The PLC that we're talking about
is not programmable logic controllers.
It's the other PLC it's
power line communications.
This technology dates all
the way back to the 1950s
when it was introduced as ripple control
and has been applied all
over the place since then.
You can see a chart here
from Xavier Carcelle
that has a survey of a bunch
of different types of technologies.
Today, you might be most familiar
with power line carrier when
you're dealing with HomePlug,
if you have ever installed
ethernet adapters
that plug into your AC main
and they extend your ethernet network,
that's HomePlug.
HomePlug is also found in
the combined charging system
for plug-in electric vehicles.
And that's a reduced subset
called HomePlug GreenPhy.
That technology is actually
produced originally
by Intelon which was
bought then by Atheros
and then was bought by Qualcomm.
And you can see there's
a whole bunch of Intellon
in this power line carrier
chart from Xavier Carcelle.
This talk though is really
about a different Intellon technology.
They made it in the SSCP-485
and PLC4Trucks has been
around for 30 years.
So it kind of fits into
the chart right there.
It has some similarities
with the CE Bus technology
that you can see pictured.
Similar frequency ranges,
but the signaling is slightly different.
And this talk is not
about HPGP or HomePlug,
it's about this weird
PLC4Trucks technology.
The reason we have it is
actually that you needed
to send trailer fault
data from the trailer up
into the tractor and the
fleets wouldn't accept
any more connectors.
So they added Power Line Carrier
onto the existing 12 volt line to send
that data over to you,
PLC4Trucks was implemented
as a spread spectrum technology.
You can see we're showing you
where it sits in the spectrum,
which is down in the a hundred
to 400 kilohertz range.
It's much wider than a lot
of the other power line
carrier technologies
that are out there.
It was developed to be
sort of a bridge for UART.
So as an analogy, when
you bridge ethernet,
you're obviously putting
ethernet power lines.
This technology is like you
UART over power lines on trucks.
The chirps go up and down in frequency,
and they last about 400 microseconds each,
but they get put together into
larger millisecond messages.
And if you see it on your
spectrum spectrogram,
you might see these horizontal lines
because it's a spread spectrum
technology that's short
in time, and that's a waterfall plot there
on top of that chart,
the signaling is actually pretty clever.
It has a different preamble
and a different body.
In the preamble, it uses
amplitude shift keying,
and then it switches over to
phase shift keying in the body,
using the same chirps with
slightly different timings.
And there's a lot of kind of
interesting design decisions
that are put in here.
And most of them were
made for this reason.
To make it wire compatible
with the technology
that predates it called J1708.
So they made this chip, the SSC P485.
That's a bidirectional bridge.
If it receives 1708 messages,
it wraps them in additional
information for the preamble
and these signalings that you
can kind of see highlighted
on the outsides of the
message on the bottom here.
And if it receives that on
power line, it does the reverse,
it creates the J1708 message in response.
So it's this bidirectional
transparent link
that kind of bridges the
J1708 UART technology
over power line.
So another J standard that
you need to understand, sorry,
it's J1708, what is this thing?
1708 predates J1939,
which would be the normal
way that you would deal
with communications on trucks today.
J1708 was introduced for
really the same reason
that CAN was introduced, it's
to move time varying signals
around the vehicle.
So they would pack the
data into small fields
and move them in smaller frames.
So they could have just two wires instead
of one wire per signal, right.
So a lot of 1708 is actually
encoded in J1587 messages,
which is like the application layer
that defines exactly how
everything is packed together.
So by an analogy you can
kind of think of J1587
as the data standard like J1939 is,
on top of CAN,
but here you can put
J1587 on top of J2497,
or you can put it on top of J1708.
So 2497 is just like an
alternative transport for J1587.
Now 1587 has more than just
the time during messages
that it was intended
for during mission time.
All the diagnostics are put in there also,
and there's data link escape messages
that people use for
doing their diagnostics
and 2487 adds one other thing,
which is dynamic address
claim for the MIDs,
which makes it a little bit different.
So that's kind of our crash
course on J2497 and J1708.
There is a lot of other
details in the previous talks
that Chris and I have done as well as
in Dan Sloan's talk on
1708 that you can find
on the media server.
So this technology was
introduced, as I said,
to move the fault
information from the trailer
to the tractor,
but it didn't come without a
little bit of funny business.
And we'll talk to you about the patents
that surround this technology.
Back in the 1990s,
NHTSA had been telling
the fleet for some time
that they were gonna require
that the trailer fault
information was displayed
on the dash of the truck and
they knew this was coming.
And so the industry
actually worked together
to select how they would do this
without adding another connector,
because the fleet said they couldn't have
another connector added between
the tractor and the trailer.
And they actually settled on
this technology PLC4Trucks.
And you can see the quote
here that it was selected
because it was generic and
wouldn't have any licensing,
but surprise, unfortunately,
the next year,
SAE actually withdrew
its blessing of J2497,
because there was someone
that was in the meetings
and filing patents around
what they had been hearing
in the development of these technologies.
So eventually what happened
is everyone that was involved
did end up paying licensing
fees to the individual
that held the patent,
including the company
that bought his company
since the licensing had to
be done to the individual.
And that was a bit of a surprise too.
And SAE did eventually issue
the draft anyways for J2497,
despite the patents.
I was told that at one meeting,
this individual walked in and
was given an award for J2497
and then asked to leave the
room, which is kind of funny.
And this also, this part is disputed,
but I've also been told
that the reason we read
those IP disclosure and patent statements,
and I see some SAE people in the room,
we read those every single time
because of what happened with J2497.
So let me tell you a little
bit about what we've discovered
now that you know what this technology is.
Previously, Chris and I in 2019,
we told everyone that you can read 2497
from a distance of about six to eight feet
with active antennas.
Since then Chris has improved
some of the receiver antennas
and got those green ones working.
And I hope you tell people
about the other thing
down the road.
Today, we're happy to tell you that
not only can you read this traffic,
you can also write it.
So it's possible to write it.
The distances and the
powers involved vary.
And I'll tell you a little bit about that.
When we were dealing with
CISA to get the CVE allocated
and to do this disclosure process,
one of the things that
was kind of difficult
was they need to do a
categorization to CVEs.
They have to put a CWE against the CVE,
but there really isn't a common weakness
for inducing RF messages.
And the closest thing
they could come up with
is this improper protection against EMFI
which is electromagnetic
fault injection protections,
which is something that you might assign
to a microprocessor that isn't guarded
against fault injection.
Hence the title of the
talk, "Trailer Shouting",
which is a nod to the
amazing Colonel Flynn.
And then finally there was other research
that's been put out about HPGP,
which is that combined
charging system technology
that we talked about
earlier from Intellon.
Back in 2019, when we said you could read
the technology, the PLC4Trucks remotely,
Martinovic and baker
from Oxford University.
They put out research saying that, yeah,
you can actually read HBGP remotely
from charging stations and roughly
at about the same time that we did
our coordinated disclosure
for this remote right
They also put in another
paper called "Broken Wire"
which shows that they can interrupt
the HPGP charging sessions.
The big difference between the research
that they released this year and ours
is that we're writing valid
J2497 messages onto the bus.
We're not interrupting the communication.
We can create brand new valid messages.
So this is how our testing works.
We set up this antenna next to the trailer
at varying distances.
We start close, we play something
we call the Unichuff signal,
which is a recording of all the possible
solenoid test commands, which
are diagnostic commands.
And I'll tell you more about that.
And we play that in a loop
and we dial up the power
until we can hear the
trailer breaks, clicking.
We can hear the solenoid test.
And then we know we've confirmed
that the trailer equipment
has received that signal.
The tables here are a little bit weird
and they don't line up.
You'll notice that the minimum
power for a distance kind
of caps out at different
numbers, unpredictably.
And this is because I
had a really bad habit
of blowing up the power
amplifiers we were using to test,
and they just wouldn't work.
And we would look down
and say, what's going on?
And then we would notice
that the test was invalidated
at various points.
And that's why it's 50 here
and 45 in the other location.
So yeah, I had a bad
habit of breaking things,
but you can see that on the left here,
we have a drive van with metal decking,
and it is possible to
actually induce messages
on drive vans with metal decking.
There is no table for
drive ends of wood decking
because we found that we weren't able
to get signals induced at any power level,
even for close distances.
So that change from wood
decking to metal decking seems
to make the equipment more susceptible
to the induction of the messages.
The one of the middle
is tests on a tanker,
and this is really the
most unfortunate situation
for about a hundred dollars US,
you can put out 12 watts
at these frequencies,
and that is enough power
in our test to get you
from 12 feet away from the trailer
to successfully induce the messages.
So for tankers it's particularly bad.
And then the third
table on your far right,
is when we took drive van
trailers with wood decking,
but extended them into
a triple road train.
And once they're in this triple
road train configuration,
then we find that they are
once again susceptible,
but the costs involve
end up being much higher
than in the tanker case.
We estimate upwards of
$10,000 for the kinds
of power amplifiers that are required
to accomplish the successful induction.
So we had two CDs issued.
The first is the fact that
you can induce the messages.
The other is sort of
this otherwise non-issue.
The diagnostic software that's implemented
in all these trailer ECU controllers
has no authentication or authorization,
so you can just send the
correct bite sequence
at it without any back and
forth challenge response
or anything, really, even a password
and it'll just respond.
And if you think about it,
the era where this
software really comes from
is sort of the '80s
the SSEP 485 was created as
a bridge between existing
J1708 and the new J2497.
So people were able to just
forward port their firmware
and stick the chip in front of it.
So we're dealing with diagnostic software
that predates 2497 itself,
and it would be unreasonable to expect
that it would have authorization
and authentication.
It's the era of peaks and pokes.
But when you combine the
fact that you can create
these messages with RF
and that there's no
authenticated authorization
when you get this problem.
So, Chris, I hope you're gonna help fill
in the blanks on some of what's happening
with this RF black magic.
- So let's try to go
over some of the voodoo
that we're doing to these trailers
and navigate the RF
black magic that's going
on in the background.
When they first told me about this idea,
I thought there's no way
you're going to be able
to get a meaningful signal on that wire
at those low frequencies
and such wide bandwidths.
I didn't think it was possible.
It was such a complicated signal too,
but I decided to let it play through.
And we did the testing and we
ended up getting it to work,
but there were a lot of
things that didn't work.
We went through and we tried all types
of antenna configurations.
We found that loop antennas
weren't that effective.
We tried making our own loading coils
by taping a couple buckets together
and just wrapping wire around it.
That didn't work for us.
We tried rolling out our own ground planes
along the length of the trailer using
screen door type material and not so much.
And then someone suggested
that we try using the signal
that's produced from a modified truck duct
using the GPIOS pins.
And that's not really a good idea.
You shouldn't do it
because that signal is much less quality
compared to the real thing.
It just doesn't really compare.
Then, as Ben mentioned,
we had the habit of breaking
the power amplifiers.
You can only imagine the joy of going
across the country and then
when the first 10 minutes
of testing, you break the power
AFL amplifier accidentally.
- [Ben] Yeah, that's my bad.
- [Chris] I hope yes, but what does work?
Surprisingly, the FL2K dongle work for us.
For those of you that don't know,
it's a USB to VGA adapter
that can be used as an SDR.
And surprisingly it
provides more output power
at those low frequencies than a lot
of the SDRs that you'll see.
And it's much cheaper,
especially with prices
going up these days.
So in the picture there,
you see the FL2K plugged
into a small five watt amplifier going
into a (indistinct)
and a couple of wire
antennas connected to that.
And we found that lengthy wire runs placed
along parallel to the trailer,
produced the best results for us.
We recently updated our
gr-J2497 code that's found
on my company's GitHub page there.
Before it only did receive,
but now we put in transmit capabilities.
So if you're using a FL2K or an RF,
you can transmit directly
at those frequencies,
or if you have a different
SDR that doesn't go that low,
you can use a down
converter and you might have
to amplify the signal coming
outta the down converter,
But what's really going on in that wire?
What makes the chip understand our signals
as we transmit onto it?
There's a couple things
working in our favor.
For one, there's a lack of
differential signaling going on.
It's just one wire and ground.
It's not like there's two wires going
along the length of the trailer.
And then there's the residence effect
that Ben was mentioning where doubles
and triples may behave as better antennas
than just a single trailer.
Then there's the high sensitivity
of the chips themselves.
I mean, typically they
work on the order of volts,
these messages peak to peak,
but we can induce a signal
and it gets interpreted
as low as a few milli
volts, which is great
if you're trying to inject
something onto a wire,
and then there's other theories
that we're thinking about
about why it's doing this.
And one could be that it's getting
onto the ground better
than it is the wire.
And the chip only cares
about the difference.
So our signal could be stronger
on the ground for all we know.
So we were able to do it
despite my earlier doubts,
things like the low frequency,
the wide relative bandwidth,
it's all near field at these
distances and frequencies.
The trailers, the wires,
they're not comparable
to the wavelengths that we're trying
to work with here.
So they make for bad transmit
and receiving antennas,
but it's still good enough to work.
And then there could
be reflections going on
and impeded mismatches,
it's not meant for RF and
the chirp frequencies go
from 100 to 400 kilohertz.
And there's a big difference
between 100 and 400 kilohertz
in terms of wavelength.
So certain frequencies
might be transmitted
and received better than others.
And I've also seen just by
traveling down the highway,
I've taken my receive antenna
in the passenger seat,
held it up to the window
and I could see that certain trailers
transmit the signals
naturally better than others
based on the configurations of the wires
and the metal in the trailer.
I've seen some cables tucked
away in like metal tubing,
and you can't really get
much from the signal.
So it depends on the
trailer configuration.
And then you gotta manage your amplifier,
harmonics and signal
conditioning challenges,
which will come up when
you're trying to transmit.
Now Ben will give you a timeline about
how we discovered all this
and went through it, Ben.
- Thanks, Chris.
Yeah, we've actually
been at this for a while.
Since 2019, we started and as you know,
we did disclose that you
could read this stuff
back in Safe Mode, Safe Mode DEFCON,
but in 2019 we were
actually doing some testing
and we did start the
public disclosure process
about remote read.
At the time, we also had
results that did suggest
that you could do a remote right,
but we couldn't actually
confirm that our testing method
at that time, wasn't due
to galvanic coupling.
Which means that,
so we had an oscilloscope that was plugged
into the mains power
and we had a signal
generator that was plugged
into the mains power.
And we couldn't discount the possibility
that the signal was actually
traveling through the ground
and or mains lines from
the signal generator
to the oscilloscope and that
it wasn't being induced.
And that was true.
So we did set up out to then test this
to make sure there was
no get galvanic coupling,
but of course the pandemic
happened and got in the way
of our darn testing schedule.
Well that's okay, there's more
important things happening.
Thanks to our member fleets
and some anonymous
equipment suppliers though,
we did manage to complete
a gauntlet of testing
in late 2021 and confirm that yeah,
you can write these signals.
There's definitely no galvanic coupling
because we stopped measuring the signal.
We found that we were making
signals that were very small,
so small that they're within
the noise of the oscilloscope.
You could resolve them
with a very sensitive SDR,
like 16 bit SDRs,
but you couldn't resolve them
with something like the eight bit hack RF.
They were very, very small signals,
but they're still small
enough to trigger reception
on the trailer equipment.
So yeah, we stopped measuring.
I'll talk a little bit more about that.
We work with CISA to get
a coordinated disclosure
and it was very quick I
think, and it was nice.
We wanted to get done in time to talk
to the American Trucking Association's
technical maintenance council.
They have a task force
that was putting together
in the new specifications for
tractor trailer interfaces.
And we really wanted to make
sure that that task force
and the stakeholders thereof were aware
of the problems of J2497,
so that the new interface wouldn't inherit
all the same problems that have been there
in 2497 for the past 30 odd years.
So we are able to do that thankfully
by the time that they had
their meeting in March,
and eventually we were
also able to contact
the American Tanker Truck Association,
which is good because the
issue is the worst on tankers.
So about the Unichuff signal,
because we stopped kind
of trying to measure
how much we could induce,
because it was way down
in this very dirty,
noisy 12 volt line on the trailer.
We put together a signal
be called Unichuff.
It contains the diagnostic commands
for all three trailer brake suppliers.
And we send them to all five
of the possible trailer brake locations.
And we just do that on a loop,
because if you remember
the CVE that was issued,
there is no authentication
or authorization required.
So we just play it over and over again,
which lets us move where our
antennas, change our powers.
And eventually we hear clicking
and then we know that it worked.
And we did this for solanoid test
because you can hear the clicking.
It's very useful as a test,
but this is also applicable
to other diagnostic commands.
And we'll talk a bit about that later.
So Chris, how can they do this?
Should they do this?
- So if you're on the highway,
you should not do this
to other people's trucks.
This is not a good idea.
They're big machines. You don't own them.
Don't mess with 'em.
But if you have your own truck
or you wanna make your own bench set up,
I strongly encourage that.
And there are different things you can do
if you have a bench set up.
You can tap directly into the
wires and view these signals.
One way to do it is with
a DC block to get rid
of the 12 volts that's on the power line
and just see the signal and
you don't harm your scopes
or your SDRs or whatever
you got plugged in.
Another method is you can
get a hardware hacking,
diagnostic adapter.
They sell some that go from J2497 to 1708,
and you can plug it in on one end.
And then if you get your hands
on a supplier diagnostic
adapter that goes like right
into a brake controller or something,
you can view entire session
traffic and capture that.
If you wanna make your own
FL2K adapter like we did,
there are schematics out there for buying
or just buy a board that
goes from VGA to SMA
and you're off and running there.
And if you're making
your own bench set up,
you can add bonus features
such as wheel speed simulation
or pressurized air.
And then if you wanna go
online and see our code,
you can do it yourself with the SDRs
and the down converter
and amplifier methods.
This is an example of event
set up that Ben's been using
for the past couple years.
I'll let him talk more about
it. It's pretty interesting.
- [Ben] Yeah this is
actually a CTF challenge
at the car hacking village.
We have it again this year.
This year, the contestants
have to use an SDR.
In the past, we've given
them a diagnostic actor
and because it's DEFCON,
(indistinct) also helped me modify it.
And we started a launch war
with each other yesterday.
So it's pretty fun.
And you should come
check it out if you like.
And yeah, I mean, bench
setups can be really key.
If you want to take on the challenge
of doing your own J2497
research on a bench,
it might behoove you to know
that if you find something,
whatever you find is now
remotely exploitable, right?
So this is the environment
that you would have
in the situation of possibly
remote inducing messages.
Not that you're gonna do it,
but your bench set up may
be set up to look like this.
You're gonna have at least
a tractor brake controller
and one trailer brake controller,
but here in north America, you
could actually run triples,
meaning three trailers.
A lot of those triples actually
require converter dollies.
And that's what kind of changes
the back of a normal trailer
into something that looks
like the back of a truck
so that you can put another trailer on it.
And these converter dollies of course
have their own trailer brake controllers.
So even though you can
have a up to a triple,
you could have up to five
trailer brake controllers.
So if you want to have
an authentic test bench,
you might want to consider
all five being present
and yes, hang on a second.
I lost my notes.
Right, so when you're looking
at this stuff on your bench,
keep in mind that the only
required functionality
while the truck is rolling at mission time
is sending the lamp messages
from the trailer to the tractor
to show whether there's a fault.
There's a lot of other stuff going on,
but most of that is really
value add from the vendors
and doesn't necessarily need
to be happening on J2497,
especially when we get to new
tractor trailer interfaces.
Our experience with J2497
has kind of uncovered
that it's a little strange.
And there's a lot of
things about what we found
that suggest that either
it's not been explored
or that possibly this patent
had a real chilling effect
on the technology.
You can see this picture at the bottom,
which is sort of this weird
chirp fragment coming out.
And as soon as we started
capturing these signals,
we were seeing these chirp fragments.
And we couldn't tell if it was us
or if it was something we
were doing on the software.
Eventually we broke out the signals
and it really was just
this tri-state output
on the bridge.
A tri-state is when you kind of try
to turn off external amplifiers
and this output was just going
high for some unknown reason.
It's highly unlikely that no
one has ever seen this before.
There's a lot of really smart engineers
that work on this technology.
We suspect that this and
other things really suggest
that whenever someone
encountered this stuff,
the answer was probably, well,
this is patented and we
don't do anything about it.
We can't make an alternative technology.
How could we change it?
So we think that all of the
weirdness here that you see,
we summarized really did
have a chilling effect.
And Michael Osman has talked about this,
how patents can be harmful to innovation.
In his case, he talked about forceps
and that really caused really bad things.
This has thankfully hasn't hurt anybody,
but we do believe that
the patents being present
has had a chilling effect.
And I've heard of that as well,
that in 1998, when they
evaluated this technology
amongst the other ones,
there was a whole list of dozens
and dozens of features
that they could integrate
over J2497 and to this day,
really none of them have been implemented.
And I've been told by some engineers that
that's really was because
of licensing and the patent.
So the other thing to
note here is the preamble
is discarded on receive.
We previously had reported
that you can make frames
that have a different priority on 2497
than they have on J1708
when they received.
It's actually worse than that.
It turns out that the
preamble isn't used at all.
And we found that in one case,
this one brake controller
was just sending random bites
for its preamble.
It never was sending the
correct lamp message.
And which explains why
we couldn't decode it
that first time we had a capture.
So another mystery solved
and the other two brake controllers,
only one of them implements
arbitration correctly.
And that one actually has
a priority inversion bug,
'cause it's doing it correctly,
it still can hold up its transmit
if it has a low transmit priority,
ahead of a high transmit priority.
So even though it implemented
arbitration correctly,
it messed something else
up, which is unfortunate,
but kind of funny.
So solenoid tests,
a lot of the testing we've done,
a lot of what we've disclosed
here is all about these tests.
When the trailer break
controller receives them,
it makes a clicking noise
if there's no air present,
if the air is present
and the driver's foot is
on the brake,
it will actually release compressed air
through the exhaust port of
the trailer brake controller,
which makes a chuffing sound.
And that's why these
are called chuff test.
The difference also is in dollies,
Dollies don't have traditional air brakes.
You don't need the driver's foot to be
on the brake to chuff air.
If they receive a solenoid test,
they will chuff air regardless
of the configuration.
So when you have a road
train with dollies,
you'll actually exhaust
air much, much quicker,
but it's important to remember that even
though we're talking about solenoid tests,
they were a good stand in
for us to do our testing
'cause we could hear the
results when they were received.
They were also kind of bad enough.
There were fleets that
got upset about just this,
but there is more that's possible.
On tractors, the tractor
units are really supposed
to be receiving those lamp messages.
That's their function, but
they're doing more than that.
Some of them are actually
resetting in response
to messages that they
receive on the 2497 bus.
And when a tractor
brake controller resets,
it sounds off its modulators,
which is another chuff test.
So it does four or more chuff tests
in response to these reset commands,
which is actually a well
defined J1587 message,
not even a hidden proprietary one.
There are a lot of the brake controllers
that are doing bridging.
Thankfully that bridging
is from 2497 to 1708.
And we don't find 1708 on modern trucks.
Although there are a lot
of trucks on the road
that aren't modern.
So it's not a zero impact thing.
There are tractor brake controllers
that enable diagnostics from 1939 to 2497.
So we know that some of
the software does include
higher privilege bridging
and it's not clear
whether it goes backwards.
We certainly haven't found
any that do that so far.
And we haven't found any
tractor brake controllers
that respond to legitimate
diagnostic commands on 2497,
which is good.
Back to trailers.
There are other diagnostic commands
on trailer brake controllers
that aren't solenoid tests.
You can change the tone ring size,
which tells the ABS controller
how fast is the wheel
going based on the signal
that it sees.
The good news is that when you
give it nonsensical values,
the ones that we've tested
don't do anything bad.
We thought maybe if you
gave it a nonsense value,
it might start ABS events.
It doesn't, which is good news.
You can also change the axle number.
You can do all your DTC reading
and clearing, et cetera.
Now 2497 is really the only interface
to access trailer brake
controllers in North America.
And so all the engineering
tools also work over 2497.
And even though those
tools aren't supposed
to be in customer hands,
the software that receives
the engineering tool commands
is in the trailer brake controller
and will respond to them.
So things like uploading scripts,
some of the manufacturers
have scripting languages
that they put in their
trailer brake controllers.
And we're also told that firmer
updates do happen over 2497
on some of these trailer
brake controllers.
So there's a lot more than solenoid tests
that are all possible.
So with all this happening
and there's some bad stuff happening here,
it's not a zero impact.
Why would we come up here
and tell you all about it
at DEFCON?
The timing was really
kind of important about it
and it does present a dilemma
and we recognize that the
dilemma is not unique to us.
This happens in a lot of situations
with security disclosures.
On the one hand, if we talk about it,
it's gonna put unwanted
attention on thousands
of deployed vulnerable devices.
On the other hand, if
we don't talk about it,
then the issue can't be widely understood
and people might just
keep doing the same thing
they've always done.
And this last part is
particularly important right now
because we're starting to define
the new tractor trailer interface.
And if they said that it had to maintain
complete backwards
compatibility with J2497,
which is something that
fleets would reasonably want
because they want to make sure
that their old equipment works
with their new equipment.
The fleets would then also inherit all
of these security problems with J2497.
So because right now that
task force is working
to define these things,
we felt it was really important
to do this public disclosure
with CISA so that we could
tell the various task forces
and tanker associations
and carrier associations
to make sure that everyone
understands the issue.
We have asked the task force
to make sure that J2487
is deprecated in the next interface.
And that will actually come
to a vote in September.
The in-person ATMC meeting
and we hope they will agree,
which brings us to probably
the reason you all came here
is let's look at some
trucks chuffing, right?
Okay, now actually getting time
to test trucks is pretty difficult.
So we'll just show you how Chris
and I prepare for tests.
Right? Okay, got it.
Thank you for those of you that laughed.
I appreciate that.
Okay, in all seriousness, we
will show you chuffing trucks.
This is our demo setup.
We have the Unichuff
signal in that black box.
We turn that into a J2497 signal
with some code that's
now public and available.
We serialize that and
play it an FL2K USB dongle
that Chris told you about.
That goes into a variable attenuator,
which feeds a power amplifier.
The reason for the variable attenuator is
so that I don't blow up
any more power amplifiers.
That's important.
And then we feed that into the antenna,
which is sitting next to the truck.
So let's do the demo.
Oh, there we go.
So that sound, you're hearing.
That's the chuffing sound.
That's the trailer break
controller exhausting the air.
I can see it down here.
You can kind of see the antenna
here, strung on the pylon.
So it's those two red wires
that are just to the left
and we're at a pretty
decent distance here.
This is a triple with grain haulers,
which are type B trailers,
so there's no dollies.
It's just three trailer brake controllers
on these grain haulers.
And of course the driver is in the cab
and he has his foot on the brake.
And because he's in the cab
with his foot on the brake,
that's why we're hearing
the air chuffing out.
Here you can see the laptop
and the programmable attenuator
and the power amplifier
that feeds the antennas.
And there's nothing else between the setup
and the truck, very independent.
Now what happens if you
do this test for a while?
It's not super easy to
hear here at DEFCON,
but the air stops to chuff.
So we ran the test for quite a while
and you can hear just the
solenoid clicking much
more than the air.
There just isn't enough
air in the reservoirs
to keep up with the
continuous chuffing commands
that we're sending, right?
And you definitely hear that
it's different at least.
And of course,
if they don't have enough
air in the reservoir,
then they can't release the
brakes to move the truck.
So if a truck were caught in
this situation long enough
for roughly two to three
minutes in this configuration
for that tractor and these trailers,
then it probably wouldn't be able
to roll away until its
compressor could keep up.
Back to that. Okay.
So I think you'll find that Chris
and I have showed you that
it's possible to both read
and write these messages remotely
on some tractor and
trailer configurations.
And in the worst case,
writing remotely can be
done for pretty cheap.
$300 US at a very large separation,
something that would work for ditched road
and the rights don't just
reach the trailer equipment.
They actually reach the tractor
brake controller as well.
And both the trailer brake controllers
and those tractor brake
controllers are doing more
than just the regulation
required lamp messages.
We could not have done the cool stuff here
without the assistance of AIS.
This was a really great team effort
and we're very grateful
for your assistance.
And Dan, thank you very much.
And Eric, who's not here,
but on the stream hopefully.
This would not have been possible
without the support of the
NMFTA member fleet carriers.
So thank you very much to
them and a huge thank you
to this a long list of
people that I won't read out,
'cause it'll embarrass
those of you that are
in the audience.
But thank you very much to you
and we're happy to take
your questions now.
Thank you.
(crowd claps)
Yes, sir.
(man talks indistinctly)
- Yeah, so the question is we mentioned
that there's some interuptability.
I was saying bridging between 1939,
which is a CAN bus and this 2497,
which is a power line carrier,
the tractor brake controllers,
they connect J1939,
'cause they're responsible
for actuating the brakes
and responding to torque
and all the other messages
on the bus,
those tractor brake
controllers in North America,
they also have to for regulation reasons
receive 2497 messages.
So they're like the nexus
that connects to both
of those buses and the
software in them does
in some cases move data
for various reasons.
Does that answer your question, sir?
Welcome.
Yes.
(guest speaks indistinctly)
- Okay yeah. So is that's a good question.
It's definitely a natural question.
We have tested something
like this when it's moving,
the results were negative.
So what we found and we
mentioned that if you change
the tone ring size, it doesn't
make things bad either.
What we found is that
because these are ABS units,
they have wheel speed sensors
built right into them.
The software knows intrinsically
how fast it's going.
All the ones we've tested
will just not receive
any diagnostic commands
while they're in motion.
I think you'll find in
one of the slides earlier,
I didn't say it verbally,
but it's there that if
they're in a fault state,
some of them will actually still respond
to the diagnostic
commands either in motion,
they have a fault and they will respond
and that's for some of them,
for some versions on some things.
So your mileage may vary.
(man talks indistinctly)
- I mean, so we're talking about, okay,
so the question is what would happen
if this was somehow theoretically possible
in motion or happened, right?
And sorry, is that the question?
Yeah. Okay.
So these are air spring brakes.
If it's just rolling
and you start to deplete
the brake pressure and
no one has their foot
on the brake or anything,
the effect is not really
gonna be anything,
unless you get all that supply air out
and then the brakes would start to close
and it would slow down the vehicle.
So it's pretty decent failure state,
I think in terms of impact.
the thing that kind of
bothers the fleets about it
is the access to the
other diagnostic functions
and the potential immobilization
of tractor trailers
that are stationary and then
made to stay stationary,
'cause they're big and hard to move
and that would make things
bad in a lot of cases, right.
Does that answer your question, sir?
Welcome.
Okay.
Thank you. Oh, do we have
a question back here?
Yes please.
(guest talks indistinctly)
It's a good question.
So the question is can
we use the same method
to actually block
activation of brakes, right?
So brake control in North America
at least is all pneumatic,
which means it's all through
pressurized air control.
So application of the brakes
and release of the brakes
is both through the blue line
that signals relay control,
but it's all pneumatic.
There's no way to control the breaks
with any of the research that
we've done here in that way.
Yes, sir.
(guest talks indistinctly)
- Right and so the question
is sort of the talk last year
that was involved with stealing and
or completely disabling
all the shopping trolleys,
which is a great talk and
is seven kilohertz similar.
Just like kind of Chris mentioned,
there's a big difference
between 400 kilohertz
and 100 kilohertz.
There's actually an even bigger difference
between one and seven.
The thing that is similar is that
there's no authentication
or authorization required.
So that loop that he did
that just play the thing,
that's kind of what we did
with the Unichuff as well.
The other really important distinction is
that those trollies,
the equipment that he was
attacking had antennas
that were designed to receive RF.
They were electrical engineers,
real electrical engineers,
did the thing and made the
antennas to receive it.
What we're doing is
convincing a power line system
to receive RF when it really shouldn't.
And so we need a lot more power
and oomph to make that happen.
You're welcome.
I think we're good. Thank
you everybody very much.