- The COW Who Escaped
The Silo, by Eren Segal.
Since it is this speaker's first talk,
we are going to do the DEFCON tradition.
But before we do that, I
have two announcements.
Number one, if you're sitting,
please wear your masks, it's required.
And the second announcement
is please don't loiter,
or sit along the walls or the back.
Just find yourself a seat,
come on down, come a little
closer, and enjoy the show.
All right.
(audience applauding)
- Welcome to my talk,
The Container On Windows
Who Escaped The Silo.
In this talk, I'll demonstrate
a malicious Windows container image
can impact the OS it is running on.
My name is Eren Segal
I have been in the cybersecurity
field for over seven years.
Currently, I'm working
as research team lead
in SafeBreach Labs.
My experience involved research
on Windows and embedded devices.
I'll start with the background
of Windows process isolated containers.
Then I'll continue with
how to gain NTsystem
inside of the container.
After we gain NTsystem,
I'll explain the method they use,
in order to find two vulnerabilities
that can impact the host.
And then we'll talk about
them and show a quick demo,
and we'll finish with Q&A session.
So the goal is to find the
impact of an attacker-crafted
Windows container on the
host it is running on.
I chose this research because
containers are everywhere.
This attack vector, of a
malicious Windows container,
is a real world one,
and reverse engineering
Windows kernel is fun.
So let's deep dive into
Windows containers.
Containers are similar
to virtual machines.
Each container is created
from a container image,
which contains all the
dependencies of the container.
For example, the application
that the container will run,
the file system, or its
configuration, registry,
and even permissions.
The container image contains
all the dependencies,
therefore it is easy to manage and use it.
And just like virtual machines,
containers are also
isolated from the host,
in order to validate
that the container won't
be able to impact it.
Windows containers can
be deployed in two modes:
process isolated and Hyper-V isolation,
which defines isolation that
they will be executed on.
Hyper-V containers are very
similar to virtual machines.
Each container have its own kernel.
The Hyper-V containers
can't interact directly
with the host kernel, which
means that they're more secure,
but it comes with computational overhead.
Process isolated containers are
similar to Linux containers.
The entire container
runs from the user mode.
Process isolated containers
interact with the host kernel,
but the container is
isolated from the host
via multiple aspects,
which we will focus and talk
about them in the next slides.
The goal of the isolation
is, prevent the container
from being able to impact the host.
And because the kernel is shown
between the container and the host,
some validations were added to the kernel
to block a container from doing activities
that can impact the host.
In this presentation,
I'll focus only on process
isolated containers.
When running task lists
inside Windows container,
we'll see lots of system processes,
which are related to the OS itself,
unlike Linux containers,
which doesn't contain any
system processes inside of it.
And the reason lines the differences
between Linux kernel architecture
and Windows kernel architecture.
Both Linux and Windows containers
are running from the user mode only,
in order to validate
that they won't be able
to impact the host.
Linux kernel is monolithic.
Therefore, all its basic functionality
is implemented in the kernel,
unlike Windows, which
some of its functionality
is implemented in the user
mode while other in the kernel.
Therefore Windows containers
contain system services
such as SVC host.
So let's deep dive
into how process isolated
containers are implemented.
There are two parts
for Windows containers,
the engine, which manage all
the containers, loads them,
as you might know, Docker engine.
And the second part of the
operating system of the Windows,
which are responsible for the isolation
of the container from the host.
And we will focus only
on the Windows part.
When a new Windows container begins,
it creates an environment
required for the container.
For example, the file
system of the container,
object namespace, job
object, and of course,
the processes that are
going to run inside of it.
Windows container isolation
is separated into three parts,
job objects, namespaces, and layers.
I'm going to focus on
bypass the kernel isolation
of the job objects.
So let's focus on, what are job objects?
Job objects were created in
Windows a long, long time ago
to group processes as units
and manage the resources.
For example, manage the CPU
time, memory limits, and so on.
But in order to support isolation as well,
the job object is required
to be converted into silo.
Silo object provide basic isolation,
but it is not enough for containers,
which require much more.
So in order for a silo to
have all the capabilities
required to support containers,
it must be converted into server silo.
So any server silo is also a silo.
After we converted our
silo into server silo,
which support redirection of resources,
now we can use the process-
now the processes inside of the container
can use object manager,
registry, network stack,
that were loaded from the container image
and not from the host.
But this isolation is not enough,
because the container can
interact directly with the kernel.
So some validations is
required to be added
in the kernel itself.
So let's understand how the
kernel block dangerous syscalls.
So if a container does dangerous syscalls,
for example, loading driver
that can impact the host,
the kernel won't allow this activity.
And as you can see in
the slide, it's validated
if a process, the thread
that did the syscall
is inside server silo,
which means that it is
inside of a container.
Let's deep dive into how it detect that.
When the kernel need to detect
that the current process is
isolated, as a container,
it checks for server silo,
all silo in the ETHREAD
or EPROCESS structs,
which are the structs that represent
the process and threads.
The kernel need to check
all the job objects,
which attach to the thread or the process,
because it is possible to
attach multiple job objects
to a single thread or process struct.
Another example of a flow in the kernel,
which required to validate if the process
is inside of the container or not,
is a flow of the process list.
In this flow, the kernel
just skips the processes
that are outside of the container.
And because of that,
when a process inside of the container
queries for all the process list,
it gets only the processes that
are inside of the container.
So before we try to break
out of the container,
we need to know if we are
running inside of the container.
Using a single task list command,
I'll show you how to detect
if we are running inside of the container
and with which isolation
method we are using.
It is possible to detect
that the process is running
from Hyper-V container by
listing all the processes
and checking: if the
process CExecSVC exists,
Dockerd must not exist on the task list,
and CExecSVC must run from session one.
Similar to Hyper-V isolation,
it is possible to detect
process isolated containers
with all the first condition.
But the last one, the third,
the session ID of
CExecSVC must not be one.
So after we understood
that we are running
inside of the container,
let's detect if we are
totally isolated from it.
When I began my research,
I found couple of indications
that containers aren't that
isolated from the host.
This methods are trivial,
but important for our understanding.
The process IDs inside of the container
and outside of the container are the same.
In the slide, you can see
that the PID of CExecSVC
inside of the container
is the same as outside of the container.
When looking and comparing
all the other ones,
we will see that they are same.
I guess it can lead us
to side channel attack
between two containers by knowing the IDs,
but it is doesn't valuable enough.
I want much more.
So I continue to research.
When running a container
as container user,
I noticed that Process Explorer,
which running outside of the container,
doesn't detect the user, container user,
but it did detect all the
other system processes
that are running inside of the container,
which raise the question,
why we have system processes
inside of the container?
And do they have the same permissions
as system processes
outside of the container?
So basically, system processes
inside of the container
have almost the same permissions,
but if there are isolation
checks, as I showed you before,
we can't do that.
So we need to find a way to bypass that.
So before we jump to how
to escape the container,
let's gain system permissions.
When running Docker run command
with the user flag of container
user, which is a weak user,
I would've expected we will
run only container user,
which, weak processes.
But if you see the boot process,
lots of system processes are starting
from the container image.
The only process running
as the user we defined
is the CMD, which we executed,
which means that our
process can communicate
with system processes.
And more interestingly,
this processes are loaded
from the container image,
which we control.
So if you can control the executables
we can gain NT/System.
So it doesn't matter with
which users container will run,
we can get system permissions.
But how exactly can we do it?
In order to craft a container image
that will run as system always,
we need to follow just these four steps.
First, run the container as system,
to add our backdoor inside of it.
Then we'll create a service
that will run as system.
We'll start it,
and convert the container
into container image,
that we can deploy for future use.
But this method is not the only one.
It is possible to do it with
much more than this method.
For example, we can override
system32 executables that
are found in the image,
use DLL side-loading
and modify the
configurations, the registry,
and even changing the
permissions of the container user
to have admin startup permissions.
So we gained system permissions
inside of the container,
but we can't do anything we want yet,
because we are blocked.
We can't load DLLs- drivers, sorry.
And we are isolated from the host.
We can't access the file system.
So in order to break the isolation,
we need to learn first
about past vulnerabilities.
I'm going to explain two examples
of past container escape vulnerabilities.
Each one of them represent a
different method to look for
in container escape vulnerabilities.
The first method to look are APIs
that Microsoft just forgot to
block them from the container.
Unit 42 found a vulnerability
in object manager symbolic link,
that let processes inside of the container
access any hard drive they want.
The second method is to try to
bypass Microsoft mitigations.
James Forshaw found a way to bypass
the kernel validation of the server silo,
by creating a new silo object
which is not a server silo.
Microsoft added the support for containers
after most of the kernel was implemented.
Therefore, I chose the first
method to look for syscalls
that Microsoft just forgot to block.
I didn't put a lot of effort, right,
to bypass existing
mitigations and validations.
It looks much harder
and less cost effective.
So in my research, I looked
for vulnerable syscalls,
but over five hundred,
it is not possible to go
over all of them manually.
So I had to find, to
narrow this attack vector
into much better and more
interesting functions.
So, as I said before,
it has to be a syscall
because otherwise we
can't interact with it.
The second, this syscall must
not have isolation checks,
which means that Microsoft may or may not
forgot to add isolation check.
And the third one is tricky.
If the syscall must
require system permissions,
the higher the privileges, the better.
Then it assured that the
impact of the syscall
will be major info leak,
or let us impact the host drastically.
After I build this recipe,
my life become much easier
and I began to find vulnerable functions.
I did a quick triage of syscalls
that matched the pattern
and the syscall NTQuerySystemInformation
caught my attention.
This function contains a huge switch case
over the parameter SystemInformationClass,
which is an Enum that
contains about 200 options.
I could not go over all of them manually.
But luckily I had symbols,
I knew which one does what.
So I wrote a small code,
go over all the interesting ones.
And I found an interesting option.
If I called the system call
with inner value of
system handle information,
it return to me a list of
all the handles and addresses
of the objects, from all
the processes on the host.
It is not possible to use
these handles or addresses,
because we can't open processes
that are outside of the container.
And we can't also duplicate that.
So what I found is a minor info leak.
We can gain all the
process IDs on the host.
But I want much more,
so I continue to look.
Additional interesting syscall
that matched the pattern
was NTSystemDebugControl,
which sound much better.
NTSystemDebugControl is similar
to the previous function.
It is huge and enumerate over
the Enum SysDebug command.
This syscall called multiple
interesting functions,
for example, enable kernel debugger,
but all these options were disabled
if the kernel debugger is not enabled.
Even enable kernel debugger requires that.
But all of them except user dump,
which won't give me any actual value
because I need a handle to user mode,
to a process that I can open,
only processes inside of the
container, and kernel dump.
That sound much interesting.
So let's understand how to do kernel dump
using this syscall.
In order to do kernel dump,
I need to fill the struct
SYSDBG_LIVEDUMP_CONTROL,
which contains two interesting variables:
handle to a file, easy,
and flags to the dump,
which specify what the dump
will contain in the kernel.
I took a source code from the internet,
that triggers the kernel
dump, change it a bit,
and now I can dump the entire kernel,
from inside the container.
But let's understand what I can dump.
So the flags that control
which information will be
included in the kernel dump,
are listed here, they are undocumented.
And the most interesting
ones are, dump Hyper-V pages,
and user space memory
pages, because of LSASS.
I attach VM kernel debugger,
and I tried to do a kernel dump
from inside of the container.
And it worked.
I managed to dump all user processes,
including LSASS, on the host.
But on a clean Windows machine,
dumping user mode is not possible.
And the root cause, again,
is that kernel debugger is not enabled.
All the other flags worked as expected,
without kernel debugger.
So I can dump the entire kernel,
I can dump additional pages,
but I can't dump the user mode processes.
But I still want to access
passwords on the host.
So let's understand how to access them.
There are multiple ways
to access passwords on
the host without LSASS.
The first one is via the command line.
The kernel dump contains
all the information
about all the processes on the host,
including the command line argument.
So if you pass a password in
the command line argument,
all the environment
variables on the process,
so I can access it from
inside the container.
Another way that sometimes
passwords are stored
in the registry, which we can also access
using the kernel dump.
And if the kernel bugger is enabled,
it is possible to dump LSASS directly
and access all the passwords from here.
And of course, kernel dump
from inside of the container
can discover much more.
It can discover which
EDLs and security products
are running on the host event on Windows,
stack traces, kernel
memory, and much more.
So, additional vulnerability I found
is related to the UEFI.
So in order to understand the impact
and how can we use this vulnerability,
I'll give a bit of background.
When we boot a new Windows PC,
it probably boot in
this following sequence.
First, the UEFI image the CPU,
loads the UEFI device and drivers,
then, the UEFI loads the configuration,
from the NVRAM memory,
in order to know how to continue the boot.
Then the execution forwards
from the UEFI to the Windows.
On the third step, Windows
begins the boot sequence.
Windows pull the configuration from BCD,
which are stored in the EFI partition.
Then it continues the rest of the boot
until Windows completes the boot.
Let's focus on the NVRAM storage.
The UEFI NVRAM contains the
configuration of the UEFI.
These configurations are not
stored on the hard disk itself,
but on a chip in the motherboard.
This memory is not shared
between the operating system and the UEFI,
and the multiple name spaces in the NVRAM.
So in order to access a
specific variable there,
we need to know its GUID, its namespace,
and the variable name.
Two examples of major variables are found,
Boot, and BootOrder.
Boot is a variable that define the UEFI,
how to boot using a specific method,
for example, boot from
hard disk or boot from CD.
The content of the Boot variable
sometimes point to files on the hard disk,
but they're stored in the
UEFI partition on the FAT32,
so the container can't access them,
so we can't modify them.
The BootOrder defined in which order
the UEFI will try to boot,
whether it's going to try
to boot from the CD first,
hard disk, network, and so on.
There are multiple types and
flags for the NVRAM variables,
which can be classified into two sections:
storage method, which defines
whether the NVRAM variable is
going to be volatile or not,
and the access, when we
can access the variable,
whether we can access it only on the boot,
or we can access it on the OS
part from the Windows itself.
So let's jump to the vulnerability itself.
This vulnerability is
related to multiple syscalls,
which all are related to the NVRAM.
So the first capability we want is
listing all the NVRAM
variables on the host.
We can do that using the syscall
NTEnumerateSystemEnvironmentValue,
which let us discover all the
NVRAM variables from the host,
but it is possible to do that
from the container itself.
But this operation won't be
useful without reading them,
which lead us to the second syscall
NTQuerySystemEnvironmentValue,
which let us read a value from
a specific NVRAM variable,
which is stored on the host.
Microsoft didn't block this syscall
from the container as well.
And the last capability we need
is to read and write NVRAM variable,
which means that we have
read, write, and listing
all the NVRAM variables.
So it raised the question,
what can we do with it?
After the container is
killed and start over,
sometimes the storage is reverted,
which means it is not possible
to store permanent data.
Writing and reading NVRAM
will let us store persistent storage,
that will store between container reboots,
even reboots of the host.
And because NVRAM is stored
on the motherboard itself,
we can even stay after formats.
Additional impact is communication
between two containers,
isolated containers.
Because both of the
containers can read and write
from the same memory
variables on the NVRAM,
we can extricate data between them.
And the most interesting impact
is triggering permanent
denial of service of the host.
Because the UEFI parse
the NVRAM variables,
it is possible to change some of them
to make the host unbootable forever.
Changing the variables Boot and BootOrder,
which we talked about before,
doesn't prevent the UEFI
from booting Windows
because of backup configurations,
which we cannot touch.
Therefore, had to look for
other flows and variables.
Another NVRAM variable,
exists on some UEFI, is HDDP.
Writing non-valid value
to it will do the job,
and it will cause permanent
denial of service to the host.
The impact of this writing
will happen only after
the host restart itself.
It will shut down as expected.
Everything will work perfectly.
And when the host will
try to boot up again,
it won't be possible.
The UEFI won't be able
to pass the execution
to the Windows part.
So it doesn't matter how much restart
you will do to the machine, to the host.
It won't start.
The impacted UEFI was VMware UEFI.
So, if you run Windows
container inside Windows VM,
running in Windows machine,
for example, EF6 or VMware Workstation,
the UEFI of the Windows VM
is a vulnerable component.
When writing the HDDP
variable from the container,
it will cause permanent denial
of service to the VMware VM.
Sadly, the host machine won't be impacted.
So let's deep dive and
find the root cause.
The UEFI built from multiple parts.
The vulnerable part is BDS driver,
which is responsible for selecting
which device to boot from.
The root cause in the BdsDxe
is that it reads the HDDP variable.
And because it is invalid, it
called to ASSERT_EFI_ERROR.
This function stops the boot sequence
and cause the UEFI to loop,
to enter into loop that it
won't be possible to enter into,
or trigger a brake point, which,
no debugger will be attached to it,
so the UEFI will stop.
Which means that the
boot sequence will stop
and it won't be possible to do it.
So let's jump to a demo
containing a chain of vulnerabilities,
we will do a privilege escalation
using a malicious Windows container,
and how we can cause a
permanent denial of service
to the VMware VM?
So here, you can see a container
that we are about to start,
which will run with weak privileges,
and it will load a
malicious Windows container.
So you can see that the user
doesn't have admin privileges,
but there is a background
service, that I created before,
and it reads and writes to the
input file and output file.
So we wrote the whoami command,
and we will read the output,
and you can see that we have system.
And if you override the
HDDP variable of the NVRAM,
it's possible to see that we
override that by six time A.
So now, what we need to do
is wait for the restart.
So you can see that it'll
restart as expected,
no special actions, Windows
won't detect that as an issue.
And once it will start up again,
the Windows part won't be able to boot.
The UEFI will just be stuck on that.
So here, with the UEFI start,
and it's in the resources,
and when it will continue, that's it.
We won't pass this step.
(audience applauding)
So let us explain how the demo worked.
So before the demo,
I created the malicious Windows container,
contains the backdoor
service that run as system.
It read and write from the
input file and output file.
And when we executed using this service,
the NVRAM executable, which
overrides the HDDP variable,
and restarted the machine,
which triggered the
permanent denial of service.
So let's jump to mitigating this.
It is not easy to mitigate
these vulnerabilities
without official patch from Microsoft,
but there are few
workarounds that we can do.
For example, instead of using
process isolated containers,
which are easy to use,
and doesn't have overhead
of computational power,
we can use the Hyper-V isolation,
which costs more in performance,
but it is not vulnerable to the UEFI
and the kernel dump vulnerabilities.
Another flow is to run
only signed executables,
which you can trust, and therefore,
you won't fear of malicious
Windows containers,
but it's really hard to do that.
And another one is to assume
that container image will run as system
and use it in the network topology.
Container image scanning
is used in order to ensure
that no such issues such
as privilege escalation
in the Windows container
exist on the container.
So I tested my container,
with a privileged escalation,
and they didn't detect that.
But only after I dug into the
website, I discovered that
they don't support Windows
container officially,
but they did mark the container as clean.
So if you are using container
images and you scan them,
please ensure that the product
is support Windows containers.
Sadly, I could not put my hands
on Windows container image
scanning product that
support Windows containers.
Regarding the vendor response.
Basically, Microsoft said that,
because administrators
can start containers,
the privilege escalation that we can gain,
NT-system inside of the container,
is not a vulnerability.
Regarding the kernel dump,
that we can dump the kernel
from inside of the container,
they answered that it
is not a vulnerability,
because we need administrator
user inside of the container,
which we gained in the
privilege escalation.
But they do plan to fix it in the future.
Regarding the open NVRAM syscalls,
which we can write, read,
and list NVRAM variables,
Microsoft defines this attack as
moderate denial of service,
which is outside of the
Windows security update,
but they will fix it.
And regarding the VMware UEFI HDDP,
which cause the permanent
denial of service to the host,
VMware treated as functional issue
because it impacts only the VM itself,
and requires admin privileges from inside,
but they do plan to fix
it in future releases.
I uploaded all the tools and
modifications that I use,
how to do privilege escalation
and create the malicious
Windows container,
to GitHub.
In addition, in this repo, you can see,
you can use the code
that does the kernel dump
from inside of the container,
and manual to how to cause
permanent denial of service
to VMware VM.
So, some acknowledgements, I
would like to thank Mickey,
for helping me reversing the VMware UEFI,
and additional researchers,
that I based my research on top of theirs.
Thank you for joining.
The Q&A will be happening there.
So, thank you.
(audience applauding)