- Our next speaker
literally hacked the planet.
So please give a warm
welcome to Karl Kosher.
(audience cheering and applauding)
- Hello, DEF CON.
I am Karl Kosher,
otherwise known online as Supersat.
This is a collaboration
with another member of the Shadytel cabal,
Andrew Green,
who unfortunately couldn't
make it to DEF CON this year
and we're gonna be talking
about hack the hemisphere.
Whoo!
All right.
(audience applauding)
So this was done as a project
under the Shadytel organization
and Shadytel sort of started out
as a Twitter parody account
but now occasionally
provides real service.
Let's see.
Yup, real services at
events like Toor Camp.
And as part of our commitment
to always be in your business,
we're constantly looking to
improve our revenue streams
by expanding into exciting new areas
such as offering triple play
packages including TV service.
So this is a talk about how we
explored offering TV service
and legally broadcast our hacker content
to all of North America
and a little bit beyond,
tiny bit of Russia,
using an end-of-life
geostationary satellite
and how you can set up your
own event broadcast, too.
So to explain what an
unprecedented opportunity we had,
we first need to talk about
some satellite basics.
So when you think about
satellites orbiting the earth,
you might picture something like this,
But in reality, these are only
low earth orbit satellites.
And these satellites can't really be used
for broadcast communications.
Because they're constantly
going around the earth,
they're not in a fixed position in the sky
and for our broadcast communications,
you really want to be able
to have a dish pointed
at a particular point in the sky.
And so if you were going
to do 24/7 communications
with low earth orbit satellites,
you would need a whole
constellation of satellites.
And until, recently that
wasn't really feasible.
And so, sorry, Starlink
but LEO isn't cool.
You know what's cool?
GEO.
All right, so what's GEO?
So that's short for
Geostationary Earth Orbit.
I'm making sure the animation works here.
So, Elon's there.
We are out here.
So basically this animation is showing
that the position of the satellite
follows exactly the rotation of the earth.
But where are we gonna get
a geostationary satellite?
Well, somewhat unfortunately
but fortunately for us,
satellites have limited lifespans
and there are a bunch of reasons for this.
So you can't get into quite perfect orbit
and stay perfectly in sync.
So you need a little bit of
fuel to do some station keeping
and fine tune your position.
There are batteries on board.
Batteries obviously wear out.
There's space debris that
might just blow a hole
through your satellite.
There's radiation that
might cause bit flips
or single event upsets
or things like that.
And so, satellites are engineered
for a specific lifespan.
And once they are at their end of life,
they are moved into what's
known as the graveyard orbit
which is just beyond GEO.
They don't de-orbit it back to earth
because that actually
takes a lot more fuel
than just pushing it a
bit further out into space
where they can bump into each other.
And so, this leads us to this
unprecedented opportunity
that we had to use one of
these end-of-life satellites.
So, this is Anik F1R.
It was launched in 2005 with
a design life of 15 years.
So if you do the math,
it's basically dead or beyond
the end of its design life.
This is the coverage map of Anik F1R.
It's a Canadian satellite
supporting Canadian broadcasters
with excellent polar coverage.
I've been told that satellite
services can't be offered
in Canada without covering
the entire country.
So that might be why
back in the late '90s, early 2000s,
pirating DirecTV dish network
was kind of in a gray area.
Anyway, coverage extends
beyond the Southern US border,
reaches Hawaii,
and covers a little bit of Russia.
All right.
So, how did we actually get on this bird?
So to go into detail about how
we actually sent a broadcast
from the satellite,
we need to first talk a little bit about
how these broadcast
satellite transponders work.
And they're basically dumb analog systems
or sometimes they're called bent pipes.
So they basically receive
some signal from earth,
does some band pass filtering on it,
translates that frequency,
amplifies it out using a linear amplifier,
and then sends it straight back to earth.
And so the fun thing about this is that
it sends any RF signal it
receives back to earth as is.
There's no de-modulation.
There's no authentication.
There's no nothing.
It's just analog in, frequency
translation, analog out.
And the fun thing is that...
So on these satellites,
these transponders will
have a bandwidth of like
36 megahertz or 27 megahertz,
but you can actually pack multiple users
into a single transponder.
The only issue with that is
that all of the uplink power,
all the users of that uplink
or that transponder have to be
at approximately the same power
because you can overload
these transponders
and basically push them into clipping
where you get distortion.
You know distortion from electric guitars
where it's intentional,
but basically that just
flatters your frequency
all over the spectrum.
And so if you send a signal
that is too powerful,
you will actually cause interference
with other users on that transponder.
So this is the Anik F1R
transponder configuration.
There are 24 C band transponders
that are 36 megahertz each.
In North America,
TV channels use 6 megahertz of bandwidth.
So, it can theoretically support
six different channels there.
There's also 32 Ku band
transponders at 27 megahertz each.
And what's interesting here is that
the frequencies of these
transponders actually overlap
and the way that they're
able to do that is by
doing different polarization.
So one transponder is
horizontally polarized
and one's vertically polarized
where basically you can
get some frequency reuse
essentially for free as long as the uplink
and downlink dishes are
configured correctly.
So with Anik F1R,
these transponders were sold
for the lifetime of the satellite
and then companies would buy a particular
transponder allocation
and then sublease that out
to different companies
either in time or frequency or both.
And as it turned out,
we had someone who had
one of these subleases.
Let's see.
Yup.
All right, cool.
So since we had one of
these transponder leases,
we also had a license to
uplink at this unnamed facility
and they had moved off of Anik F1R
because it was already end of life.
So they were using alternate services
or alternate satellites,
also some IP TV services
for their broadcast.
But they still had the lease
and they still had the
license for the uplink.
And they wanted to make
sure that this satellite
or this link still worked in
case they needed a backup.
And what happened is hurricane Ida came
and hit this dish and
knocked it out of position.
And so, they weren't receiving any signal.
And so they wanted to have
a way of testing this dish.
Turns out it didn't work because
the receiver, the antenna,
the low noise block was
crowded hell and back.
Just a quick note on what an LNB is,
that stands for Low Noise Block.
It's an integrated antenna
and low noise amplifier.
So basically, it's at the
focal point of the dish
where there's an antenna
and then it has a specially
designed amplifier
to minimize the amount of
noise that injects the signal.
So we replace the LNB
and we started getting
some kind of signal,
but then there was the
problem of the hurricane
knocking the dish out of position.
And so, we weren't quite lined
up in the right direction.
But as it turns out, we didn't
need to use the usual...
So there's this picking up method
where you have these test tools
where you get the signal strength
and you kind of adjust
the satellite a little bit
and you hone it in to
get it perfectly placed.
And it turns out that was not necessary.
All we did is move the satellite back
or the satellite dish back
to where the rust marks were.
So, that worked.
So at this point,
we were locked onto a
different transponder,
one that was still active
and had not been vacated.
And so then it was time to
test out the transponder
that we actually had a lease on.
So once we verified that the
satellite was still there,
we needed to test the uplink facility
using existing commercial
equipment in there.
So the way that basically works is
they take in a video source,
it goes into a DVB-S encoder into a BUC,
which is a combined up
converter and amplifier,
which takes it from about 1.2
gigahertz up to 6 gigahertz
which is the uplink
frequency for this satellite.
And then that gets sent out to the dish.
So what this looks like
on a spectrum analyzer,
so there is a downlink on C band
that's about at 3.8 gigahertz.
So our transponder slot is about there.
When we turn on the amplifier,
we get a carrier there.
And then when we turn on modulation,
we get a nice wide 6-megahertz signal
and we received that test
signal back without any problem.
It was just the right power level.
It was about the same as everyone else.
A right amount of occupied bandwidth.
So we basically just verified
that everything was hunky-dory there.
But that wasn't the end of our story.
So we wanted to do some custom content
and unfortunately at this uplink facility,
we had this DVB-S encoder,
which was this Tanberg unit,
which accepts this input known as ASI,
and ASI is basically an
MPEG 2 transport stream
over a B and C connector
that is 270 megabit serial.
It's very weird.
It's kind of designed to be
compatible with another...
Electrically compatible at least
with another video standard called SDI
for doing digital video.
But there was really no easy way
to generate this ASI signal.
I was lucky enough to
be gifted a prototype
of one of the Great Scott Gadgets, LUNA,
which is this USB multi-tool
that they're coming out with.
Unfortunately, chip shortage
has delayed that a bit,
but the idea there was to
go from a USB interface
to ASI out of one of the coax ports
that you could add on there.
Unfortunately...
With an FPGA.
So, it was designed to
do this serialization
and deserialization.
Unfortunately, that's a lot of work.
Also, maybe this encoder is old
and we want to do something more modern.
We also thought about buying a
dedicated ASI interface card.
Eventually, we did later.
But the problem with those is that
ASI is kind of an old enough standard
that you can only find them as PCI cards.
And so that was a pain
in the ass to implement.
So we decided to bypass this Tanberg unit
with something of our own.
And it turns out that is very easy to do.
So there is a DVB-S2 encoder
example in Canoe radio
using some of the GRDTV blocks in there.
And this DVB-S2 sample takes
an MPEG 2 transport stream in
at a very precise bit rate that
I'll talk about in a minute
and generates a DVB-S2 signal
with the desired modulation parameters
and then we just fed that into a HackRF
which sends it out in an L band frequency.
So it was like 1.3-35 gigahertz
which the HackRF can easily do.
And then once it goes out there,
it looks the same as the output
from the Tanberg unit into the BUC
which up converts it and amplifies it
and sends it to the satellite.
So I mean,
this is the sample graph
in Canoe radio companion.
We didn't do anything in this.
It just sort of worked as is.
I guess we did change the
sync from a USRP to a HackRF
and the source from a
file to a TCP socket,
but it is basically pretty easy to do.
So we got a test stream up
and running pretty quickly
with a HackRF and a commercial IRD,
which is an integrated receiver decoder.
So, an off the shelf
satellite TV set top box
connected via coax in the lab.
Unfortunately, what these
IRDs do is they send out power
via the coax to power...
Or they send out a DC
Bias to power the LNB
and they actually change their voltage
to change the polarization
between horizontal and vertical
or things like that.
So we were sending 13 to 18 volts
into the HackRF front end
and that just blew it up immediately.
And so we were able to bypass
it with this sketchy amp
shown on the right here
where we basically bypassed
the final amplifier stage
of the HackRF which is kind of notorious
for being very, very delicate.
So, be careful when you're doing that.
So we successfully replayed
a test strand support stream
into a commercial receiver decoder box.
There is a spectrum analyzer.
This is one of the test videos
from this site, w6rz.net.
The bit rate wasn't perfect,
but we got basically some
choppy MTV video on there.
But now the question was,
how do we generate our own
MPEG 2 transport streams?
So to talk about that,
well, let's talk about what these
MPEG 2 transport streams
are in the first place.
So, they are designed to carry
multiple programs or channels
over a continuous stream.
They're basically used everywhere.
People might hear MPEG 2 and think,
"Oh! Well, that's dated.
We're on MPEG 4, MP4, MP5, or whatnot."
But no, the MPEG 2 transport streams
are still used pervasively.
They're used in over-the-air TV
with both DVB in the rest of the world
and ATSC in North America.
They're used in cable TV.
They're used for satellite broadcast
and even your cable modem
uses MPEG 2 transport streams.
They actually take...
Well, except for Voxes 3.1
which does something else.
But basically, they take ethernet packets
and they chunk it up
into different MPEG
transport stream packets
and just send it as another video channel,
which is very weird.
Anyway.
So what MPEG 2 transport
streams do is they take these
different elemental streams or ESS
and they mux them together
and they assign a program
ID or packet ID to each one.
And then there is some
metadata which says,
"Okay, a channel consists
of this ES of the video
and maybe two audio tracks."
And in fact, you can actually do a program
with multiple video tracks.
Some DVDs used it to
change the perspective
of a certain scene.
It is not a popular feature.
But basically, MPEG 2 transport
streams are codec-agnostic.
Originally, you could
do the MPEG 2 standard,
video codex standard H.262,
but now you can do H.264, H.265.
You can do AC-3 which is an audio codec,
all sorts of different audio codecs.
The problem with MPEG 2
transport stream is that
they are designed to be transmitted
at extremely specific bit rates
and I'm talking down to several
decimal digits of precision.
And the reason for that is
that bit rate is derived
from the modulation parameters
of how you are transmitting the signal.
So I'll show some demos
or some diagrams of different
ways of modulating signals,
but you can have a different
number of bits per symbol
that gets it.
You can change the number
of symbols per second.
You change the amount of
bandwidth that you're sending,
your stream over.
You can also add a bunch
of error correction.
And one simple way to think about
this error correction at least,
the very simple retool
man error correction is
you can sort of represent data as a...
What?
Degree N minus one polynomial.
And then if you have more than end points,
you can precisely recover what
the original polynomial was.
So you basically just add
some redundant data there.
That's kind of an old way
of doing error correction.
There are some newer advanced forms
that can take advantage of
what's known as soft-decoding,
I'll show an example of
that on the next screen,
where basically you're not sure
if something is a zero or one
but it's more likely to be a zero,
so you kind of use that to tune for
or to do some advanced error correction.
And then you're gonna have
some variable bit rate content
coming into your muxer
and so you need to actually pad that out
with some null packets to
keep the bit stream constant,
and a lot of this is beyond
the scope of this talk.
So if you wanna know more,
you can search for it.
Let's see.
So, I wanna quickly talk
about constellation diagrams
because this relates to the
different modulation schemes
that I was talking about
on the previous slide.
And so at a very high level,
when you send a symbol over DVB-S,
you could send not just a
single bit but multiple bits
and without getting too
much into the weeds,
when you add more bits,
they are sort of closer together.
And so when you receive a symbol
and it's not perfectly on one
of these constellation points,
you can...
Well, the more constellation
points there are,
the more uncertainty there is.
And so basically the simpler
modulation scheme is,
the easier it is to receive.
One thing that I will note
here is that these diagrams
on the top are phase shift keying
where you basically change the
phase of the carrier signal
that you're sending.
But since it's sort of in a unit circle,
the amplitude of the signal is constant.
And so, you don't actually need
a linear amplifier for that.
The schemes on the bottom,
some of the Quad schemes
or a PS Keying schemes do
need linear amplifiers.
All right, so this is a depiction
of what an MPEG 2
transport stream looks like
when you play it in one
of these test tools.
So, you can see a bunch of metadata there.
So there's like the program table
that defines various channels
and then each channel or program says,
"These are all the
associated video streams,"
and things like that.
All right, so this is basically
what the complete broadcast
chain looked like.
So what we do is we take
in some RTMP sources,
Real Time Media Protocol
or something like that,
and that's generated by OBS, for example.
And I'll get into how
we did that in a second.
We ingest those multiple RTMP streams
into a program called Flussonic.
Flussonic basically just altered
the PIDs of the RTMP stream
so that we could have
multiple streams together.
And then we sent this into
a program called TSDuck
which was actually mentioned
yesterday on one of the...
On the satellite talk yesterday.
And basically, that would mux
all these different streams
together into a very precise bit rate.
Then we send it into Canoe radio
either over a TCP socket or a Unix pipe
or something like that,
and then it goes out.
The HackRF goes through the up converter
and out to the dish.
All right, so we used OBS,
Open Broadcast Studio,
to generate these RTMP data sources.
I pointed this at a server running nginx
that basically just
provided a sync for this.
And then on the uplink site,
they could connect to my nginx server
and pull down the same
MPEG 2 transport stream.
Yeah.
Went over this.
All right, so now that we have
something that might work,
what do we actually put on the satellite?
So why don't we do an entire conference?
So this satellite was expected to be sent
into the graveyard orbit
in November of 2021.
And Toor Camp was happening
in October of 2021.
So we approached them and
we actually got a permission
to re-stream the entirety
of Toor Con San Diego
that they were selling virtual
passes for for 50 bucks.
But if you had a dish,
a new word to put it,
you could get it for free.
So this is what the OBS site looked like.
So we logged into the content site
with the browser embedded in OBS.
We had some cool intermission
content between talks
and during the night we would
like to play hacker movies.
Andrew also allocated...
So because we can
multiplex multiple programs
onto the same transmission
and we had extra bandwidth,
we added more content on there.
So the second video
channel was more movies.
The fifth channel was actually tied
to a phone conference bridge.
So, there was a number that you could call
and just have your
voice broadcast to well,
North America and beyond.
There were plans to include
a number station in this
as part of a long running
ARG called OTP 22.
Unfortunately, one of
the creators behind that
unexpectedly passed away
before we could do this,
so we weren't able to do that.
So, this is a look of us testing
our custom hacker transmission on there.
There's the up converter.
There's lots of cables there.
On that screen, there's
the up converter status.
On that screen,
we have the output of
this Cisco decoder box.
And when we tune into the channel...
Oh, yup! There we go.
All right.
We've got word games on there.
Pulling that off the satellite,
we can change channels to get
different things on there.
Unfortunately, I think the only thing
that's on there is audio.
And I said there wasn't
any audio in these videos.
So, "Oh, oops!"
Anyway, that's showing...
Oh, and we had this
fun little Shadytel bug
on our videos there that was
done with an OBS overlay.
Let's see.
Here's another test going
between different channels
on this decoder box.
So, we had this great
movie "Antitrust" on,
which is very emulsy.
Then...
Let's see.
We can probably...
I think we were gonna
switch channels and show...
Yeah, whatever.
All right, so how were
people supposed to be able
to receive this?
So we sent out this very vague tweet
from the Shadytel account
with this giant C band dish
just saying "Soon."
And really the reason why you need
this large of a dish is
because the wavelengths
of C band are relatively large,
same to Ku band.
So, 3 gigahertz or 3.8
gigahertz versus 11 or 12.
So we did some rough figures to figure out
if people actually needed
one of these C band dishes.
So a little back of the envelope math,
we figured there was
about 37 decibels of gain
in this C band dish
if you got this eight-foot C band dish.
If you went down to three,
you went from 37 to 29.
If you find one of those free
repurposed DirecTV dishes,
you get somewhere between 23 and 26.
So this is the proper way
to actually receive these C band signals.
But we were curious if you
could actually repurpose
one of these other satellite dishes
like a DirecTV dish or a dish network dish
to pull these things in here.
Unfortunately, the satellite went away
before we could fully test this.
So caution, there's
some speculation below.
If this was at ShmooCon,
I'd encourage you to
throw shmoo balls at me
if there's some errors in this slide.
So, this is somewhat speculative.
So we got about a 16-decibel
carrier-to-noise ratio
at the transmitter site.
And that was way up in
Canada and Northern Canada.
So in the continental US,
you should probably get a better signal
because it's more, more overhead.
So going from one of
those nice C band dishes
down to a DirecTV dish would lose us
about 14 decibels of signals.
So that would give us a
carrier-to-noise ratio of about 2.
But luckily we control
the modulation parameter
so we can add more error correction.
We can lower the bit rate.
We can basically make this signal
as easy as possible to receive.
There's some stats on the various
carrier-to-noise ratio requirements too
to receive various modulation schemes
with different error correction overheads.
So if you did a QPSK with
1/4 error correction,
so you send four symbols for every symbol
that you actually want to send.
You can actually send
something below the noise floor
and pick it up.
And yeah, so if you do that
at five mega symbols
per second with pilot,
you get about 2.4 megabits per second
with about 4 dB of link margin there.
So it's not gonna be perfectly
receivable all the time.
There'll be some noise
that'll knock it offline,
but it'll basically work.
And I just looked at what
the DEF CON documentary was
at 1080p encoded with the H.265 codec
that averages about 1.6
megabits per second.
Now, I'm kinda cheating here
because that's the
average and in practice,
it's a variable bit rate.
So, you would occasionally go over
that 2.4 megabit per second,
but you can set your
encoding parameters too
to make sure you're
always under that limit.
All right.
So we looked into doing this
before the satellite got de-orbited
or sent off to the graveyard orbit.
Turns out you can buy these at...
So our plan was to repurpose
some of these old dishes.
Not that one,
it's too bent.
No, don't use that one.
We could get these new C band LNBs.
This was like 42 bucks
for the top of the end
model off of Amazon.
You could get one as low as 29 bucks
depending on the quality.
Unfortunately, you can't
really do this anymore
as of January because these are designed
to pick up the old satellite
L band or C band signals
and the FCC just reallocated
some of that for 5G.
And so you need a new LNB to
basically filter those out.
Otherwise, you're just
gonna have this antenna
being bombarded with 5G noise.
So unfortunately, these
aren't sold anymore.
Maybe they'll come out
with better ones now.
The second hurdle was that
these DirecTV dishes have
these custom LNB mounts.
I got a friend to 3D
print an adapter for that.
That was kind of was held
together like a little clamp.
All right, so where do you get...
So, that's the antenna.
Where do you get the receiver box?
Well, Amazon, of course.
This is a decoder box that runs Linux,
supports H.264, H.265,
is networkable,
sits on the wifi,
probably hackable if the firmware is,
in the clear, not encrypted.
It's 31 bucks.
So that actually worked well
at least with some local tests.
This was our initial attempt
at putting up a dish.
It kind of looks like the
LNB there is not pointed
at the right part of the dish.
There's also...
It's missing what's
known as a conical scaler
which basically blinds part of the LNB
so it doesn't pick up background radiation
from beyond the dish.
And we didn't really have
any good idea of exactly
where the focal point of this dish was.
And so I did this kind of a hacky thing
where I just added a bunch of
reflective tape to the dish
and had a distant light source
to determine the focal point
and basically adjusted the LNB
to be right at that focal point.
Unfortunately, I went
home and we left this out
and the sun came out and I
guess we found the focal point
because we melted the plastic of the LNB.
So, there's a proper way to do this
which is to actually go
to one of these lovely
satellite TV sites.
And you can get one of
these Ku band dishes
and actually convert
them to receiving C band.
So one of these cost...
I don't know.
It's like 150 bucks or
maybe up to 250 bucks.
Basically, it gets you a larger dish,
gets you known parameters
like where the focal point is.
I was talking about this
with someone recently
and they said,
"Oh yeah, you did a mini bud."
I'm like, "What's a mini bud?"
And it turns out a mini bud is modifying
one of these Ku band dishes to
receive C band transmissions.
And so we got about 5 to
10 dB of carrier-to-noise
off of one of these dishes
that a friend brought
and bought over.
If you actually want to do
a proper C band dish size,
well, you can always go
over to China and Alibaba
and there is one for...
I don't know, 150 bucks
or something like that.
Once again, you need new LNBs
because the FCC reallocated
a bunch of those frequencies for 5G, so.
And of course, well,
all of this is moot now
because the satellite's gone.
End of life.
Bye.
But you might still be able to
do this for your own events.
So for what we did, you
need a very large dish.
You need a way to up
convert that to 6 gigahertz.
Apparently, the amplifier
wasn't actually that powerful.
The total power out of
it was about 15 Watts.
There was a lot of gain in the antenna.
Of course, you need permission to do this,
like a transponder lease or
an STA or something like that.
You could do this with Ku band satellites.
Those uplink frequencies are
more like 14.5 gigahertz.
So you need some more esoteric components
and apparently you need
a higher power amplifier.
So, maybe it's a bit more
difficult to do there,
but there are a lot of Ku
band satellite parts available
on eBay because they're
used for a lot of things
like internet access.
I don't know, like news gathering
with those TV trucks and stuff like that.
All right, so how feasible
is this for some...
All right, yeah.
All right.
What if you don't wanna do
something with the satellite?
So almost nothing in this talk
is actually specific to satellites.
So there's a variation on DVB called DVB-T
which is used for terrestrial broadcast.
And as it turns out,
almost everyone at a Hacker
Con has a DVBT receiver.
It's one of those RTL-SDR Dongles.
That's what they were
originally designed for.
They have Silicon to actually de-modulate
these DVB-T terrestrial TV signals.
So you need to change some
of the modulation parameters
and Canoe radio uses the DVP-T
version instead of DVB-S.
But basically, the rest of
the chain is about the same.
You still need to amplify the signal
to get it beyond a couple of
feet or something like that.
You could use some amateur TV amplifiers,
those for like NTSE.
They are linear amplifiers.
They will work just
fine for DVB-T as well.
I found this lovely Russian LTE amp
and it turns out that
Russian cellular frequencies
overlap with...
Or some Russian cellular
frequencies overlap
with some Ham radio frequencies in the US.
So theoretically, you could
use one of these devices
and by applying proper filtering in
and monitoring what you're sending out,
you could probably set this up.
So, this is what it looks like.
It's basically RF in and a lot of RF out
and a lot of RF porn there.
So the final thing you need
to do this is permission, of course.
So one creative way of interpreting
the amateur radio rules is that...
So normally, you can't send broadcasts
over the amateur service.
They need to be either
two-way communications
or seeking two-way communications,
but there is a special carve
out for information bulletins
directly only to amateur operators
consisting solely of subject
matter of direct interest
to the amateur service,
like this talk.
I could have broadcast this talk live.
Unfortunately, we couldn't
test that in time.
So, nevermind about that.
The other way to do it is
to get a Special Temporary Authority
from the FCC for testing
in unused TV white space
or actually any frequency that's unused.
So Shadytel actually
got an STA from the FCC
to run a GSM network.
When you're at Toor Camp,
basically you send out...
You apply to the FCC and you say,
"Here's this test that I wanna do and..."
Yeah, let's see.
Here's what we said,
"The purpose of this test will be
to user verify the functionality
of an open source GSM network design
and an outdoor test range."
Blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Yeah, you could do something like that.
Similar if you are at
Hacker camp or Burning Man,
or something like that.
All right.
So what's all this good for?
So with the large enough audience,
these RF broadcasts are a very
efficient use of bandwidth.
So, DEF CON TV could be done over this.
And then if you're in your hotel room
trying to pull it up on Twitch or whatnot
and you're not getting a good signal,
well, you can just pull it over the air
because it's broadcast.
Also the range for these
depending on your power level
and what you're allowed to do
can be significantly larger.
Works if the internet is down.
So if there's geopolitical conflicts,
maybe the internet gets cut,
maybe some sources of
information are being censored.
So, the EU decided to ban RT.
And so you can't actually get RT
from your cable company in the EU,
but you can pull it
directly off the satellite.
But you know, in some
places where reception...
Some places still like...
Especially, some countries
regulate the reception
of TV signals like that.
So, just be careful with that.
And so that's the end of my talk.
I am Karl,
Supersat online,
from Shadytel Labs,
and we are always in your business,
and thank you.
(audience applauding)