- Today we are having
the PreAuth RCE chains
by Jeff Hoffman.
I got a couple of announcements
before we get started.
Please, everyone continue
to wear your masks
while you're inside.
And please don't
congregate around the walls
around the outside, just
come in and find a seat.
If you want, come up a little
closer, that'd be great.
Here's Jeff.
(audience clapping)
- Hi, thanks for coming to my talk.
PreAuth RCEs on KACE SMA.
Today, I'm gonna be going
over what KACE SMA is
as well as the interesting
attack surface of the product.
The vulnerabilities that I found,
how I conducted my research,
and I have a full exploit
and demo to share with you
at the end of the talk.
So who am I?
My name is Jeffrey Hoffman.
I'm a security engineer at Nuro.
I have a background in
web and desktop apps,
as well as cloud and reverse engineering.
I love to do security research
and exploit dev in my free time.
And anything else that you
might need to know about me,
if I'm willing to share
it, is on my website.
So what are MDMs?
MDM stands for mobile device management,
and they're typically
appliances used by IT
to manage corporate devices
like laptops or workstations.
The way they usually work
is they'll install a privilege binary,
usually referred to as an agent
on whatever workstation you wanna manage.
And that agent is going
to phone home to the MDM,
pick up jobs to run, run them
and report back the status of those jobs.
And so the jobs can be anything.
They need to run as root or system,
because sometimes those jobs
require those privileges.
For example, installing
a certificate authority.
But really, they're pretty versatile,
that's the whole point,
is that IT can fully manage your device.
And that's good news for attackers.
It makes them, essentially
single points of failure,
for an organization.
You could, if you got
admin access to an MDM,
could do something like,
push out ransomware
to all of the workstations at once.
And more and more MDMs, these
days, are on the internet.
With the rise of COVID and remote work,
as well as the push for people to offer
software service offerings.
Some of those MDMs just
have to be on the internet
out of necessity.
So you have this great impact.
You have them generally being available,
if you support remote work
and you have this really,
really interesting scenario
where if a company,
dog-foods or uses their own MDM,
you could get into their
employees workstations,
start pushing malicious back doors
and even reach people who
only host these MDMs on-prem.
So generally, pretty
interesting attack surface.
KACE SMA or KACE Systems
Management Appliance
is an MDM developed by Quest.
It's written in PHP.
It's a relatively popular choice
for hybrid work environments,
where you have windows,
Linux and Mac workstations
all in the same organization.
There's about 2000 of these
things on the internet,
including a SaaS offering
that Quest hosts.
And a decent chunk of these
are .gov and .edu domains,
which imply to me that you might have
a lot of very interesting
PII readily available
if you were to compromise
something like this.
So in terms of what would be valuable,
admin access is really the end-all be-all
for these types of appliances.
Every vulnerability that you find
is more of a means to an end to get admin,
because at the end of the day,
you don't really wanna exploit
any kind of vulnerabilities
on the MDM itself.
You wanna use the intended functionality
to pivot down to multiple
devices at the same time.
And just a little caveat
for all the vulnerabilities
I'm gonna talk about.
I didn't look at anything
that would require user interaction.
I felt like that was less interesting,
and so I have no idea what it's out there
in terms of XSS or CSRF
or those types of vulns.
So because Quest, or rather KACE SMA,
is written in PHP, getting
a initial unrestricted shell
was my top priority.
That was gonna let me pull
all the PHP code off the box,
and then I could start source review
and find more in-depth vulnerabilities.
And so I'm gonna show
you three tricks today
that have generally been fruitful for me
when attacking appliances,
your mileage may vary,
but I always try these three things.
So the very first thing is
just trying to break out
of any restricted shells that
might have been implemented.
And so I just installed
KACE, I read through the docs
and there were two default
users, konfig and netdiag.
And so, they both had restricted shells.
Konfig's was more of a text editor
to change network settings,
and it didn't have an
immediately obvious way
to run binaries, so I moved
past that pretty quickly.
And netdiag did have a more
typical restricted shell.
So I gathered all of the
binaries that you could run,
ran them through gtfobins,
which is a website that
collects shell breakouts.
And the only thing that I found was
this arp-f partial file read,
which wasn't super useful for my case,
because I wanted to read
full PHP files, not partials.
So that first trick didn't work.
This second one is gonna sound
a little tongue in cheek,
but a way that I always try
to get my unrestricted shell
is to look for PostAuth RCE.
And the nuance here is
where that PostAuth RCE
can usually be found.
Typically appliances, not just MDMs,
want to have some sort of
backup and restore process.
That way you can support
migrating to a new appliance,
if you need to, or just
generally backing up
what IT has already set up, right?
But the issue is a lot of times,
those backups and restores
are implemented as
holistic backup and restores.
And so if they include
anything important in them,
like maybe a binary or
a very important konfig,
if there's no integrity
check on those backups,
you're gonna be able to overwrite it.
And from there it's
context dependent usually,
but the trick is just
looking for important things
in backups.
And so in the case of KACE,
there was the web root actually
included in the backup.
And so my first unrestricted shell
came from just planning
a web shell and a backup
and restoring it immediately.
So I got excess as www,
which was definitely great.
It was a good start.
This is, not to beat up on Quest,
this is just a really
hard problem to solve.
You have the desire to make your backups
as holistic as possible,
it's generally hard to
sanitize those backups,
the integrity check is
probably the way to go.
But it just,
generally is gonna be a
fruitful attack surface
for those reasons,
combined with the fact that
you almost always need
admin on the appliance
to trigger this functionality anyway.
And the separation of privileges between
being an admin on an MDM and
being able to get RCE on it is
almost nonexistent, the admin
is the more important feature.
And so RCE as www is
definitely a great start,
but ultimately you're gonna want root
to poke around a little more invasively.
And so from here,
I could have either looked for
a privilege escalation, or...
And this is what I actually
did, is try my third trick.
And this third trick
is essentially the same
as the backup and restore process,
but you don't go in
through the application.
It revolves around the fact
that if you own the appliance,
you own the virtual machine's disc,
you can simply unmount
that virtual machine disc,
mount it in a new virtual machine
of the same operating system
and start overwriting whatever
you want on that file system.
And so I targeted ndsh,
which was the name of
netdiag's custom restricted shell.
And I compiled a setuid
wrapper around bin/sh.
Set the setuid bit on
it, ch owned it as root
and I overwrote ndsh with it.
Once I logged in as netdiag,
I was given a root shell,
right from the get go.
And from there I could do
all the really nice to haves,
like adding a new user that's
root equivalent, enabling ssh.
And generally, I was able to
be a little bit more invasive.
So the first thing I did was
gather all of the PHP code,
and I also took this opportunity
to just orient myself in the application.
The logs directory was incredibly helpful,
just prepping for strings
that I saw in source
and using that to validate assumptions,
but just with root level access,
there were no files that could hide,
I could read everything.
So I just spent some
time trying to figure out
how the appliance actually worked.
In terms of attack
surface, only 80 and 443.
So the web UI were open
to the world by default,
there was this high end port
that was exposed during
the update process,
but it was just a going binary
that served a update log,
so not particularly interesting.
And so, because only
the web UI was exposed,
I could gather all of the
unauthenticated attack surface
by making a word list
and just using gobuster
to brute force over all of the files
that were accessible in that webroot.
You filter out the 403 forbiddens
and you have a pretty good
list of where to start.
And that approach is great,
it was definitely a great
start, but it's a little naive
and you can do better by
looking for the actual
requirement statements
of the authentication checks.
And so in this example at PHP,
the way it imports code is
through the keyword, require.
And you can imagine auth.inc
includes all the off checks,
but generally you're looking
for the imported file and
you're filtering out all the
files that actually include it.
And so that will give you
an actual source of truth
rather than this gobuster method.
The lists generally
didn't differ that much,
but this is just a
little bit more reliable.
And you should note that
it's not gonna include
recursive inclusions.
So you can imagine auth two includes auth.
You're gonna have to grab for
things that don't include
auth two or auth one.
So at this point I had a PostAuth RCE
and I started thinking
about whether or not
an authentication bypass would be enough.
And unfortunately, I didn't
feel like it would be
at the time, my PostAuth RCE
already required admin privileges,
so that was already goal,
it wasn't really an extra
vulnerability that I wanted.
And that meant that I
would need a PostAuth RCE
with less privilege requirements,
or I would need to find
a privilege escalation
within the app.
So I went hunting for those
types of vulnerabilities
and there were calls to extract
all over the application.
And if you're not intimately
familiar with PHP, that's okay,
a screenshot of the extract
docs can be seen on screen.
There's this big warning that says,
do not use extract on
attacker controlled data,
and that is because extract, by design,
overrides the symbol table in PHP.
And so what that means
is you can specify an
attacker controlled key
and an attacker controlled value,
and if those are passed
into a call to extract,
a variable with the
attacker controlled key name
will be instantiated and it will be set to
that attacker controlled value.
And so that's generally pretty useful.
You can define whatever
variables you want,
but the cooler thing is that
you can redefine variables
that already exist.
And so two really great targets
to go after are the globals,
because they'll always be
there and the session variable,
because that's how PHP
tracks your identity.
So an unauthenticated
call would let me set
all of my session variables
to whatever I wanted,
essentially creating a
full session from nothing.
So that would've been
a great one shot vulnerability to have,
but unfortunately I couldn't
find any unauthenticated uses
of extract.
Luckily though it was still
called in about a 100+ places
with attacker control
data throughout the app.
So tons of different exploit strategies,
one cool one was you could bypass 2FA
because your 2FA configuration
was set within your session.
So you could log in,
hit an endpoint and say,
you didn't have 2FA and you're good to go.
The thing that's gonna be really
useful for this talk though
is the direct privilege escalation.
And so in KACE,
they defined all of their permissions
as just integers and they
map to different roles.
And so exploiting--
Or privilege escalating rather, is as easy
as going to a vulnerable endpoint.
So I'm picking on mailthis.php
and setting your KB permissions
to whatever number you want.
And you can just declare
yourself a global sysadmin
and you are good to go and you can
start using all the admin functionality.
Now I didn't pick mailthis.php at random,
this is a pretty interesting file.
I looked all over at these
calls to extract for,
like I said, ones without
authentication checks.
And I didn't find any of those,
but mailthis.php had a
lighter authentication check
than normal.
And so it's not important you understand
what the full authentication
check looked like,
but what is important
is that you understand
checking for KB valid user session
was one of many checks
that Quest intended to do.
So this is just an ad hoc
partial authentication check.
It essentially meant you logged in,
not you had a fully realized session.
And so that just lowered
the bar ever so slightly
in terms of the kind of
authentication bypasses
that would be useful.
Now I have PostAuth RCE.
I have a great privilege escalation,
multiple endpoints in the app.
So I'm gonna be able to hit
admin and even trigger that RCE.
So looking for bypasses
or authentication bypasses
is now worth the time.
So here's the first one I found.
Essentially, Quest appeared to use md5
and sha1 password hashes once upon a time.
That was no longer the case
when I looked at the app,
but they did have to leave
the legacy comparisons in.
So that users who had
created their account
when the password hashes were md5 or sha1
could still log in.
Essentially you'd log in.
If one of these checks succeeded,
they would rehash your password
and it would be rotated.
And so what that coder view told me was,
there wasn't gonna be any
md5 hashes or sha1 hashes
readily available, but if there was one,
say an old account that had never
had their password rotated,
the loose comparisons there
in that code block on screen
was significant.
If you're not intimately
familiar with PHP, that's okay.
It's dynamically typed
language and equals equals
is the loose comparison operator,
as opposed to other languages
where you would normally assume
it's a strict comparison.
And so what that means is
PHP is going to try to infer
the actual type of the
variable it's looking at.
And that's typically
referred to as type juggling.
It'll try to coerce the value
to a bunch of different types
and if one of those checks succeeds,
the entire loose comparison succeeds.
And so there are three
examples on screen right now,
those two bullets in red return false,
but the bullet in green returns true.
And that is because in PHP,
oh well, just generally,
a number and then E is
interpreted as scientific notation
for exponentiation.
And so when you have a hash or a string
that starts with 0e and then
has all numerals after it,
during that type juggling process,
PHP will interpret that as
zero to the power of something
and zero to the power of anything is zero.
So if you have two strings
that aren't actually equivalent strings,
but are of that magic hashing format,
when you do a loose
comparison between those
it'll evaluate to true.
And so I said that there
probably wouldn't be any sha1
or md5 hashes in the database,
but I needed to go and check anyway.
So rather than recovering
the root password,
I just restarted the database
without authentication, locally,
and added a root equivalent user
so that I could poke around.
And when I started looking
at the actual password hash table,
it confirmed my code review.
There were these new actually
salted hashes for passwords.
And that meant, to actually test,
I had to add a new user
and fake them having
an old md5 or sha1 password hash.
And so I planted this 0e333 value,
I have no idea what could
possibly hash to that value,
but it is of the magic hash format.
And so to test, I used
a pre-computed value
whose md5 hash is gonna--
The output is going to
be another magic hash.
And the hunch was that
when those two things would be compared,
it would evaluate to
true and I could log in.
And so in practice, after
I planted that magic hash,
I just submitted the pre-computed value
as my login password.
The hashing went through and you can see
in the location redirect,
I wasn't kicked back to the login screen,
it actually took me to a dashboard.
So I successfully authenticated.
And just to confirm my code review,
I went and looked at the table afterwards
and the password migration
did actually happen.
So this vulnerability
effectively amounts to
a password change.
Now this is super cool
and definitely an authentication bypass,
but it has a few issues.
So first off you have to get lucky,
there's no way to control
what somebody's password hash
is going to come out to.
And so you are just hoping
that whatever someone has submitted
will somehow hash to
this magic hash value.
There was one interesting code path
that made this attack a
little bit more plausible,
essentially KACE, they supported importing
your entire user directory from LDAP
and how this seemed to
work in practice was
you would point it at LDAP.
All your users would get imported,
but they were imported
as unprivileged accounts.
And it seemed like what
you were supposed to do
was give the accounts that actually
were supposed to access this
app privileges manually.
But during that import,
the password hashes were
actually set to md5 values
and you're importing your
entire user directory.
So not only do you have one md5 value,
you have tons and tons of
these unactivated accounts.
They don't have any permissions,
but because of that ad
hoc authentication check
and mailthis.php that
doesn't actually matter.
So when you log in as one of
those deactivated accounts,
this is what you'll actually see.
You get kicked out to the login screen
and it says access denied,
you are not authorized to
access any of the tabs.
And even when you look at
the request in response,
it appears like the login fails.
You can tell this because
it's resetting your kbox ID,
which was the session cookie.
And so normally when an app does that,
it's saying, hey,
restart the authentication
flow, this did not work.
But if you look at the session on disk,
it actually has KB valid user session set.
And so you can resubmit that
old session ID hit mailthis.php
and privilege escalate to admin,
just from these unactivated
or unprivileged accounts
that were never really
supposed to be used.
And so this is definitely a
fully plausible attack scenario,
but like I said, you have to get lucky,
it requires them actually
using this feature.
And the odds aren't even
that good if they are.
So I moved on looking
for something better.
The second authentication bypass I found
was definitely slightly better
in terms of exploitability,
but it was a non default feature.
And so, Quest doesn't make just KACE SMA,
they make a bunch of different appliances.
And one thing that they wanted
to support for all of these
is this magic login.
And so you would pair two
Quest appliances together
and they would generate
tokens for each other
that were redeemable
at the other appliance.
And so when you are in one appliance,
you click on a link generated for you.
You've redeemed your token
and you are logged in
as your user, but in
a different appliance.
And the token generation can
be seen on screen in bold.
It is an md5 hash, but there's
no magic hashing going on.
The real issue is that the
input is essentially guessable.
So unique ID is taking two arguments,
the first is prefix, the
second is more entropy.
The more entropy does not
actually matter for this attack,
but the prefix is generated by micro time.
It's just the current
time at microseconds.
It's definitely not a
secure, random value to use.
And when you look at the unique ID docs,
you see that most of unique IDs entropy
also comes from the current
time in microseconds.
And so you essentially have the randomness
coming from two calls to
a totally guessable value
and the attack in practice would
look like you brute forcing
a bunch of different outputs
for these two micro time calls
and generating your tokens
with the md5 hashing,
but you would just continue to iterate
until you guess the right token.
And so this is definitely more
exploitable and in practice,
there's no luck involved,
but it's non default.
No one's forcing anyone to
buy two Quest appliances
and even if you have
tons of quest appliances,
no one's forcing you to link them
and actually use this
functionality in the first place.
So those are two of the three
chains that I wanted to cover.
They're not so great.
They're really not reliably
exploitable in practice,
but the third one I'm about to cover is.
So those were the only
authentication bypasses
that auditing the user
attack surface turned up.
And after I was done with that,
I turned to the agent communication.
My hope was maybe authentication
was implemented a little bit differently,
and I could find some more
authentication bypasses there.
And I actually landed in this file,
download agent installer.php,
and there was clear command injection,
but it was behind this ad
hoc authentication check
where you had to submit some
secret parameter called, serv.
And so the command
injection should be clear.
Org ID is a attacker controlled,
it's obtaining temp location,
which contains zip name
and then both of those variables
are used in the call to exec.
So I started digging into
how serv was created,
it was the only thing stopping me
from triggering the command injection.
And as it turns out serv
is the hashed serial number
of the appliance.
It's essentially meant to be
a boot strapping secret for agents that
I guess, just wasn't
unique to every agent,
but that's a little bit easier
than making a unique username and password
or doing something else.
So it was like that for convenience,
but it was also good news for me.
The serv parameter was the
sha256 hash of the serial number.
And so an unauthenticated LFI would work
because the actual function
that retrieved the serial
number, just read it from disk.
So if I could retrieve the
serial number like that
with my LFI, I would be able
to calculate serv myself.
And I would be able to
exploit the command injection.
Unfortunately, depending
on the installation type,
there was one, the serial number
would be stored in one of three places.
And one of those file
names had the MAC address
of the device appended to it.
So I would need a way
to leak the MAC address
of the device before I
could actually exploit this
in the worst KACE.
Luckily for me, when you log in,
the MAC address is presented to you
and that contents of the message
is actually stored in etc
issue, which is world readable.
And so if you had an LFI,
you could read etc issue,
pull the MAC address,
then you could read that
final name and the worst KACE,
pull the serial number and calculate serv
to bypass authentication.
Now, knowing that I went around
and audited high and low
for unauthenticated LFIs
and I came up empty handed.
So I took a step back
and started thinking
about what I could use
as an LFI equivalent.
And as it turns out, the
SQL queries made by the app
were being made as the root user,
which meant that if I
could find SQL injection,
I would be able to use
directives like load file,
to read contents from disk.
And depending on the
SQL injection quality,
I would be able to use that in
the same way I'd use an LFI.
So a single LFI was all that was needed.
And this code block on screen is actually
in the same file as the command injection,
but it comes before serv--
Or the check for serv rather.
So technically it's not authenticated.
And it's not important that you remember
exactly what's going on here.
What is important is that you remember,
validate org comes first
and validate agent version comes second.
If either of those queries
fails, the app 404s
and it'll exit immediately.
So validate agent version
has clear SQL injection.
You can see org ID is just directly placed
in the SQL query string,
but validate org is going to come first.
And unfortunately, org ID is
properly parameterized there.
So when I was doing code review,
this looked unexploitable, org IDs,
the ones stored in the database
are stored as integers.
And so I can't make an
SQL injection payload
out of integers.
Luckily for me though,
I was just spraying around
some testing payloads
to actually locate the relevant logs.
And I had accidentally
hit the SQL injection
invalidate agent version.
And I didn't really understand
how that was even possible.
So I had to work backwards from this,
but what had happened was
MariaDB actually type juggles.
And so this is in their docs,
it's some convenience feature
for strings with differing units.
An example use case of
this feature is on screen.
It's inferred that the
developer writing this query
really does wanna operate
on these two values
with differing units.
And so if it sees a string
that starts with numerals
and then contains non numeric text,
it interprets that as units
and it will just drop them.
And so the validate org query
looks exactly like this.
If you just append the
SQL injection payload,
it will get dropped and MariaDB happily
treats that as just a one
and the query actually returns
successfully so, pretty cool.
So that means that we
can actually hit the SQLi
in validate agent version, but
there are still a few issues
that we have to work around.
So first off SQL responses aren't visible.
Secondly, basename is called on org ID,
which means that we can't
directly pass it in paths
of the files we wanna read like etc issue,
because the payload will be truncated.
And finally org ID has
to actually be valid SQL
and command injection because
we need validate agent version to succeed
when we actually trigger
the command injection.
So to start working around that,
the first thing I did was
create a blind SQL oracle,
and I essentially abused the behavior
of that immediate 404.
So when queries fail, the app 404s.
When queries succeed, the
app eventually returns a 200.
And so just by looking at
the HTTP response codes,
you could infer the
outcome of the comparison
in the SQL injection.
Now that's definitely useful,
but we still have to get
around that second constraint
of base name being called.
And so the way that I did that
was just using the concat directive.
And so all of this is nested
within a call to load file,
but xerox 2F is the ascii character
or the integer value for ascii/
and so that output of the concat call
will result in etc issue,
which then could be passed
directly to load file.
Now, I still need to pull out single bytes
to make my oracle useful.
And so the way that I chose to do that
was dynamically rather
than hard coded offsets.
And so I used locate with load file
in order to find the starting address
of the actual things I
wanted to bruteforce.
And then I used substring
to pull out a singular bite,
and then I could just
bruteforce the MAC address
and serial number because
they were alphanumerics.
So, relatively small search space.
And the full strategy as I
just described, it will work.
You can use the SQLi to
read your two local files,
calculate serv and then
you can trigger your command injection.
We just have that last pesky issue
of needing a payload that is valid SQL
and valid command injection.
And so the way that I got around that,
the payload can be seen on screen.
Essentially, the semicolon delimits SQL.
I used a hyphen hyphen, which
is a comment in MariaDB.
You can't use the pound sign
because it'd comment out
your command injection,
and then the dollar sign and parentheses
should be pretty recognizable
and to get around base name for payloads,
I just wrapped it all in base64.
And so from here,
I could trigger my RCE
unauthenticated as www,
but I really wanted root
just 'cause I thought
it would be more fun.
And so I ripped this methodology
straight from the OSCP,
I just looked for custom
things running as root.
And there were a few PHP files
that I immediately started looking at
because they were gonna
be really easy to audit.
And so one of the things that I looked at
was called kbserver.
The long and short of it was,
it listened on a world
rideable Unix socket,
and it was listening for commands
in the form of command,
argument and argument.
And so there were a bunch
of different handlers
or commands that you could run.
One of the interesting ones
is shown on screen now,
and it does essentially
what the name of the command applies.
It takes an attacker controlled source,
moves it to an attacker
controlled destination
and then for good measure
CHown's it is www.
And so that is relatively straightforward
logical privilege escalation,
you could override an important binary
or some important file,
but I chose to abuse the command injection
that was in the actual
implementation of the handler.
So here's the current state,
the two chains on the right and
left aren't really reliable,
or so great, but the middle one is,
and you can execute commands as fruit
from an unauthenticated perspective.
And so now I have a demo to show you.
Oh great, it's already up.
(Jeff laughs)
All right, so the first thing it does--
So the first thing it does is check
that it can trigger the SQL injection.
So it knows if the appliance
is vulnerable or not.
And right now it's just using
the techniques with the SQLi
to leak the MAC address.
After that, it starts
leaking the serial number
from the file in that worst KACE,
which is what was used in
virtual box installations.
And so, interesting to note that the timer
that you see spinning
is actually getting spun
every time a response comes in
and you can see it hang
on the successful guesses
because KACE does a little
bit more processing,
so even if we couldn't
have made this oracle,
we could have done a timing attack
or maybe some other
technique to leak this data.
And so after this finishes,
you're gonna see it run commands as root.
It's actually gonna set
up a set UID bash shell
so that I don't have to go through two
command injection contexts,
makes running payloads a little easier
and it's gonna happen
really, really quickly.
It's gonna make a new admin, make a script
that gets pushed out to all
of the devices in the org
and that script is pretty mundane,
it's just going to change the background
to that cowboy cat picture,
but it happens just as quickly.
And in a few seconds,
you'll see that device
that I'm running this payload on top of
it's registered in my org
and it'll pull down that job,
run it, and the background will change.
All right, and obviously--
(audience clapping)
So obviously a real
attacker wouldn't do that,
they would probably do
something more malicious,
like deploy ransomware,
but hopefully that gets the point across.
And so I should say the
full exploit for that
is available on my GitHub.
It was also shared with
the speaker materials.
I defanged the exploit
script a little bit,
it didn't seem so appropriate to release
something that just works
like that outta the box,
but it does run commands as root.
And so it's enough to demonstrate
that these vulnerabilities do
work like this in practice.
Now, in terms of detecting this,
the general access log for KACE
is actually good enough
to catch all of this
because org IDs are
supposed to be integers.
And the initial SQL request is--
SQL injection request is just a get.
So you can filter for any org ID
that's not strictly an integer
and you'll be able to know if the attack
had actually happened.
Now, I have some closing reflections
that I wanna share with you.
So first off, as much
as I wish I could say
this was new and novel
work, it actually wasn't.
Some firm called Core Security reported
very, very similar vulnerabilities,
if not the same ones in 2018.
And so the SQLi was reported
and I never got to see
this unpatched code,
but my best guess is the fix for that
was actually just parameterizing
org ID in the first place.
And that totally makes sense to me.
I, through code review,
missed that this would be exploitable too,
so I could see how even the
security researchers, Quest,
they all could have missed that.
I definitely would've missed
it too if I didn't get lucky,
but it just goes to highlight
the importance of explicit
versus implicit sanitization.
If you had done the explicit sanitization,
this weird convenience feature, MariaDB,
would've never mattered.
As far as the RCE,
I'm a little bit more
confident that this was new
because the payload that
they had shown and described
didn't include this MSI parameter
that was required to hit
the vulnerable code path
for my command injection.
And so, regardless of whether or not
it was a reintroduction
or maybe regression,
it was probably also assumed that org ID
was never gonna be attack
or controlled like that.
Again, that convenience feature in MariaDB
really bit the developers in the butt.
So definitely explicit
versus implicit sanitization
is the way to go.
You just remove so much unknown,
unknown when you do that
and effectively guarantee
that you'll never have
to worry about it, but
both of these vulnerabilities
together also,
for me at least,
highlighted the importance
of defense in depth.
I never would've been able to read files
if SQL queries weren't being made as root
and the exploitation
would've stopped there,
the command injection
would've never been reachable.
And so here's the total
timeline for the disclosure.
I contacted them on 4/20
and the very next day,
I had a meeting with the Quest team
to explain essentially
everything that I found,
they were pretty concerned and responsive,
and they released a hot
patch relatively quickly.
And we actually mutually chose together
to withhold the CVEs.
So I haven't talked about
any of the CVE numbers,
they aren't out now, but I
didn't get a chance to put them
in my speaker materials
because they were due
a little bit earlier than
the CVEs were released,
but the patch was out on
5/11 and they sent very,
very strongly worded
communication to their customers,
consistently urging them to patch.
Patch acceptance was relatively high,
even in those first two weeks.
And the CVEs were withheld essentially
because the app's PHP.
So patch dipping is almost trivial
and it wouldn't really have
been fair to those customers
to release this very critical CVE
and have the motivated attackers patched
quicker than they can
schedule a regular patch.
And then finally, I just wanna
give some credits and thanks.
So again, it really pains me to say this,
but credits to Core Security
for beating me to this.
I wasn't guided by their research.
I didn't know about the
CVEs until after the fact.
Probably my fault, I would've
saved myself some time,
if I hadn't found existing CVEs
before I had started looking into this
and credit to Michal Spacek for
making that pre-computed
magic hash value that I used.
And then finally, I just wanna thank Nuro,
which is the company that I work at now
for giving me the opportunity
to do such interesting
and impactful work.
And then I just wanna give
a huge thanks to John Novak,
who is a former coworker at Praetorian.
He taught me a ton about appliance hacking
showed me some of those neat tricks
that I got to share with
you today and by extension,
thanks to Praetorian for just
being a great environment
to learn in.
So I will take any questions,
thank you for coming to my talk.
(audience clapping)