- Welcome everybody. Yeah.
So, I'm gonna be talking about my journey
the past few years, reverse
engineering Xbox Live.
It was my COVID project,
for lack of a better word.
I'm Tristan.
Also go as Monocasa on the internet,
when I have hot takes of
questionable veracity.
So, that's what I'm using today.
Today, I'm gonna go over background.
We're gonna go deep into
what the protocols are
themselves a bit,
or look at how I took a look
at reverse engineering it.
If somebody wanted to repeat this work,
what you'd have to do to do that.
I'm gonna talk a little bit
about the replacement server architecture
I've built up so far,
where it's going, what
exists at the moment.
And then, I'm gonna go into a brain dump.
As I've gone through this,
I have very strong feelings
about how to support people.
How to put this?
What's the ethical way to
support abandoned software
in a increasingly networked world?
And then, we're gonna go into questions.
Unfortunately, the demo
gods weren't with us today.
My Xbox actually got the click of death
literally last night,
so I'll put up a video tonight,
but source is up too, so you
can go take a look at that.
Starting off, who am I?
I'm Monocasa, Tristan.
I'm an engineer. I've
got a lot of experience,
with binary reversing,
firmware development,
cloud-based device and
identity management,
and experience with
custom tunneling of IP.
These are all a perfect
storm for taking a look
at Xbox Live, taking it apart.
There's the skill sets you would need
to take a look at other
video game networks.
If you wanna get in touch with
me, I'm monocasa@xombie.org.
Xombie's the name of my
particular replacement
Xbox Live infrastructure.
It was live, then it
died for original Xbox,
so now it's back again.
I thought it was a cute play of words.
Before we get much farther,
I wanted to just give a
shout out to the other people
working in the same space.
There's M. Borgeson, who
has put in a ton of work
into the emulators for
Xbox, called Xemu, X-E-M-U.
There's also a guy by
the name of Luke Usher,
who's working on similar
replacement server architecture
called Insignia, for Xbox Live.
I think they both have Patreons.
I'm sure they both
would love some support.
I've got nothing but love
for both those people.
And interestingly, for a talk
about early 2000s era Microsoft code,
I am gonna rag on them a little bit,
but I was actually kind of
surprised, looking back on this,
with historical context,
with at least most of the obvious flaws;
Microsoft,
it actually makes sense in context.
This is actually a
pretty good protocol set,
and from what I can
tell, it's 20 years old,
but other than upgrading
the crypto primitives,
a lot of the basics are still here,
and a lot of the structure's still here,
and a lot of it still
continues to make sense.
Yeah.
We're talking about Xbox Live today.
My focus has really been on
for the original console.
That's the only system
that Microsoft so far
has shut down access for.
That was from November,
2002 until April, 2010.
There were some people that managed
to keep their in-game sessions
going for a month later,
which was really interesting,
because ultimately as we'll see,
a lot of Xbox Live is ultimately
the signaling pathway,
and then they generate.
Once you have an in-game session,
that's for most games,
doesn't actually communicate
that much with the backend.
It's like web RTC in that regard,
for a more modern context.
I'm also trying to stay away from systems
that are still online,
and give Microsoft some space,
to where they're still making their money.
In the Xbox hacking scene,
there was some people
who didn't quite live
by that same standard,
and I don't think anybody won that game.
Yeah.
Going back, Xbox Live
is really the first
modern video game network,
in a lot of ways.
There's a lot of other ones before it.
It obviously took a lot of
inspiration from Seganet.
But I mean, video game networks
actually go really far back.
There was this really
cool network called X band
in the mid-90s, that was a game genie,
and a modem stuck on it.
And then, they would ROM-hack,
more or less in real time,
to add online multiplayer
to SNES cartridges.
Then this was a commercial product
that I didn't even hear of at the time.
Super cool.
But like I said,
Xbox Live is the first modern
video game console network.
And by that, we mean
there's a cohesive service
across the games.
Otherwise, previously,
these networks will
provide network services,
but otherwise, each game is
sort of an island unto itself.
At release, it expected
broadband to exist.
They did try to support
modems, it looked like,
in development,
but they didn't actually
release with that,
and so, it set a standard of bandwidth
of you essentially have to have been able
to stream a simple Netflix,
which is a very nice baseline
for these sorts of services
we expect out of modern systems.
The Xbox shipped with a
hard drive on the console,
which might have been the first
to ship with a hard drive.
Was definitely the first to expect
that kind of large amount of storage.
That gives you enough local storage
to be able to update games,
make sure everybody's consistent.
It brought up DLC, which I've
got mixed feelings about,
but it can be used for good
and can be used for bad.
It was actually moderated
for one of the first times,
so you can attempt to have
a pleasant experience,
despite the other people
you're playing with.
These are all new features,
and these are all table stakes
now for a video game network,
so it's really interesting
to, at least in my mind,
take a look at the first stab
of how these got created.
We're gonna jump right in.
The base protocols it uses: it's all IPv4,
so if anyone has a slash 24
they want to give me for free,
I'd appreciate that, but
probably not gonna happen.
Uses DNS then, to actually bootstrap up
to the different services.
Ends up using Kerberos to work
as the Authz and Authn component,
which is actually really core
to the security infrastructure.
And then, there's always
been this mysterious UDP
port 3074, which is a custom VPN protocol.
That's really the core of
honestly all Xbox networking,
including system link,
but is also the core of how
boxes communicate to Xbox Live
and each other, is this VPN that uses
the cryptographic attestations
of identity from the Kerberos
to connect and communicate
with each other.
Crypto primitives:
this is where that
historical context comes in.
This is a great who's
who of crypto primitives
you shouldn't really use anymore.
MD5, SHA1 for hashing, RC4
for symmetric encryption,
and DES and 3DES for symmetric
encryption on the VPN.
Yeah, you shouldn't use
any of these anymore.
Microsoft agrees with you.
That's probably why original Xboxes
aren't allowed on Live anymore.
That, combined with there were
some of the other constraints
and the Xboxes themselves.
All these Xbox Live libraries
are statically compiled into each game
on original Xbox.
That's something they fixed in the 360.
But they would have to go
back and release updates
for literally every original
Xbox title to allow it.
So, that explains why they
ended up cutting them off,
but still allow 360s,
which are pretty old.
So, DNS.
We actually only hit three
different DNS targets.
There's MACS, which we'll get into.
AS and TGS are fairly
standard Kerberos servers.
And then, SG012N
is the security gateway
that is the VPN itself.
And then all other communications
go through that VPN,
other than talking to other boxes.
If you get into the binary reversing,
you'll see hints of Partner Net,
which is Microsoft's private instances
of all this stuff used for testing.
So, it'll be as.part.xboxlive.
If you see that, that's
what that stuff is.
That's Microsoft's. They can have that.
I don't want to touch
that, or piss them off.
Sweet.
Once you are up and
talking to these servers,
like we said, we're using
Kerberos for Authz, Authn.
If you've played with Oauth,
it's very similar ideas from
a very 1980s perspective.
It uses this thing called ASN.1,
specifically the DER version,
instead of JSON for their communications.
And particularly, they use
tickets instead of jots,
or tickets instead of tokens.
ASN.1 is actually really interesting;
if proto buff had a ton of
different possible encoding,
where DER is a fairly
byte-packed encoding,
if that makes sense?
You'll also see that
too in exit 509 tickets
are DER-encoded.
If you care about every
bit, there's a PEM encoding.
But there's also JSON encoding.
There's an XML encoding.
It's really from the '80s,
and has picked up a new encoding
every time somebody cared.
It's also been a thorn
in the side of security,
particularly like blue
team kind of people.
I guess been really nice,
for red team people.
It's an extremely complex spec,
and a lot of our encoding for
security purposes these days
takes ASN.1 in context,
and tries to not be that, and
tries to be a lot simpler,
because pretty much until the advent
of memory safe languages,
there weren't safe ASN.1 parsers.
Up through the '90s, up
through the early 2000s,
ASN.1 was really easy to
find buffer overflows in,
for a very long time.
That's why we don't use it anymore.
But this
was what you used at the time.
Super interestingly,
even though it's Authz Authn,
it doesn't use public private crypto.
There's no signed by a private key
that could be validated
by a public search,
although that was technically added
as a extension to the RFC.
I think it came out in the
newer RFC. That's an option.
But that's not the core of how it works.
And it's all about pre-shared keys,
and having a key here
means I can encrypt in
HMAC different pieces.
And then, I can use that to then negotiate
the next key of the process in private.
This is all ultimately
the underlying piece
of how Windows domain logins work.
Your pre-shared key in that
case is your actual password
you type in on the Xbox.
It ends up being keys that
were pre-added to the console
at manufacturing time.
And so, there's an EPROM on every console
that has all sorts of
manufacturing time information.
And there's a little online key.
It's a heavily extensible
protocol as well,
so there's these arbitrary dumping ground
of pre-auth data fields.
Microsoft ends up using
these very, very heavily.
We skipped over MACS originally,
which is the machine
account creation service.
MACS uses Kerberos, but
arguably to the point
of not even being Kerberos anymore,
and is just using those
pre-auth data fields
to communicate not tokens,
but other information that
we'll get to right now.
Yeah, MACS is the machine
account creation service.
Original Xboxes,
I haven't quite figured
out why this is the case.
They have a key available in the EPROM
that was put there at manufacturing time.
Then, an Xbox will use the Kerberos
to convert that secret on the EPROM
into a full account for the box itself.
However, that account, that
key has exactly the same
key length that was negotiated.
So, it turns a 16 byte key
into another 16 byte key
for reasons I'm not totally clear about.
Maybe they were still
figuring out the Xbox.
Maybe they were still figuring out Live,
and they just wanted to get
all those pieces together,
so that when they released Live later,
they'd have something.
I'm not really sure, but we move on.
It ends up using just standard
Kerberos AS-REQs, AS-REPs
to verify that shared
secret, create an account,
and from then on, the
machine uses that account
to present itself to the security gateway.
Like we were saying, there's
a bunch of extra pre-auths.
There's a client version
that you sign with secrets,
which basically tells you what executable
is being used here.
So, it a lot of times ends up,
if it's just the machine itself
and just trying to bootstrap this thing,
it ends up looking like
the Xbox's dashboard.
You've got this thing that
they call the pre-pre-auth,
that I don't really understand.
It just hashes the
console serial and secrets
in an interesting way.
The only thing that makes any sense to me
is it helps some look up that they have,
but it's not really necessary,
and doesn't really add anything
from a security perspective
that I can see.
Then there's this 131,
that's a constraint on user data in a way
that's sort of meaningless.
It's a MS-KILE thing,
which is another extension to Kerberos.
And then the current time stamp.
Otherwise, it looks like
a normal AS request.
Then the MACS service
comes back to the console.
It gives it a ticket.
Like we said, it's like a 0auth token
that doesn't make sense
and gets thrown away.
In my case, I set the
expiration to Unix Epoch,
just to make sure that it
can't be used for anything.
And then, it gives it a
account creation pre-auth,
which contains the whole
machine user identity.
And the box then ends up storing all this
on this un-partitioned
space on the hard drive.
I haven't really figured out why.
There's this, I wanna
say, a half-Meg space
on the hard drive that
isn't in any partition,
and I haven't really
been able to figure out
why information gets stored there.
The best theory I have is that
the underlying storage there
was originally supposed to be on a flash,
and they migrated it,
because they didn't have an extra flash,
or didn't wanna touch
the flash or something.
But it's not really hiding that much,
because it's very clear from
the binary what's happening,
because it's the only thing
that's opening the raw partition
pretty much on the system.
So, it's not really even a
good obfuscation technique.
I mean, maybe if you were looking at it,
but they're already using weird partitions
and weird partitioning schemes.
I don't know, it never really made sense,
but that's where it is.
That's what that partition space is.
Ultimately, all of that
un-partitioned space
is cached information,
so anybody who is super
concerned about preservation
of that un-partitioned space,
and afraid that if they
modded their console,
and never restored that piece,
you can still get on Live.
All that information isn't there,
isn't necessary to get on
Live re-implementations,
which is good news.
A lot of people were very scared
that they had written their way
out of being able to be on Live.
Users. User is this really
interesting concept in Xbox Live.
This is probably one of the cooler things,
that made me want to
talk in front of DEFCON.
A user on Xbox Live is
a very broad concept.
The machine itself is a user,
in addition to what you would think of
as people sitting there with controllers
in their hands, in each controller port.
It's a really interesting take
of one of the first stabs of IOT security,
and this idea of the machine itself
being given a full identity.
For a lot of Authz Authn systems,
you see what device they're on
end up being metadata for the user,
as opposed to combined,
like a user in its own sense,
and then smearing users together
into a combined authorization.
Boxes have their own ID.
They have their own gamer tags.
It ends up being like SN.serialnumber.
I ended up sticking them in
a different Kerberos realm,
but I haven't been able to find
an original machine account,
so I don't know what
Microsoft originally does.
Just like regular users, machine users,
they both have 16-byte shared secret.
That's ultimately the
bootstrapping of Kerberos.
They have domains and realms,
which are just basically name spaces.
So, you can think, @blahblahblah.com,
@blahblahblah.net.
Everyone's got a XUID,
which is a 64-bit user ID.
Everything on original Xbox
seems to start with 0009,
for some reason.
I don't know why that is, but
the boxes don't seem to care.
And then, non-machine users
will have flags and a passcode.
There's this flags.
There has two different concepts.
One is for guest accounts.
If you ever wondered how that worked,
you have the same XUID as your host user.
You just have different
bits in the flags that say,
"I'm a guest account of this user."
Then the rest of the
flags are things like,
"I was a shithead, and
therefore I am completely banned
from speaking on everything, globally."
Those sort of cross-communications
black marks on the user are put in there.
And then, also in the user account,
they've got the passcode,
which is a pretty simple,
"Keeping your little brother
from getting on your account."
It'll just be, "AABB
up down," or something.
Cool.
That brings us to the
actual authorization flow
at this point.
At this point, your Xbox
is signed into MACS,
it's gotten a full account.
Then, it moves into
actually trying to connect.
And so, this is a pretty
standard Kerberos flow,
for the most part.
We end up creating a
ticket granting ticket
that gives you a cryptographic
proof of identity
of the pre-shared key,
and gives you a ticket
that you can present
to the next piece.
It's like a 0auth bearer token.
It essentially lets you prove that you are
who you think you are to other entities.
It can be a very multi-step process.
This is what I was getting at,
where it'll first build up
a ticket granting ticket
with the machine's account.
And then, it does this
combined identity thing,
where it starts layering all
of the other users on top of it
and sort of smears all of
the identities together
into this one cryptographic
version of identity,
which is a really interesting concept,
and one I haven't seen
used very much these days.
Cool.
From there, we talk to TGS,
which is the ticket granting service.
You give it a ticket granting ticket.
It gives you back a service
ticket. Pretty simple.
This will be a little
bit shorter timeframes.
You'll tell it that you want
certain backend services,
and it'll give you a ticket
for those backend services
for those users.
At the end of the day,
this is another really interesting part.
Probably, one of the
cooler parts of Xbox Live
is even before you are fully connected,
you have this cryptographic
attestation of identity
that is combined with
which backend services
you can talk to.
That's the mid-level of
their backend system,
which is really, really neat.
It reminds me of how Facebook has added
to their TLS connections on their backend.
They really try to tag
the identity of the user
that was the cause of the
request to everything,
so that they can really track
it through their systems
very well.
This could give you the same way to do
that kind of information;
to track user identities through requests,
to restrict users on a
per-game basis, per-user basis,
and handle it all very holistically,
all underneath the
individual game protocols.
All the other protocols
and what they expect.
It brings it back to their pre-auths.
They've got 201, 202, so
we have a service request,
which is basically the game saying,
"Hey, I want to talk to
matchmaking. I wanna talk to stats."
And then the service address.
You'll get a address of
which security gateway
you can talk to,
and which underlying ports to talk to.
Well, security gateway
was gonna be on 3074,
but also, once you've
connected into the VPN,
which ports you can talk to,
and which services they're connected to.
It has very almost SDN kind
of underlying components,
which for something that
was created in 2002,
is kind of nutty to me.
Brings us to the security gateway.
That's that port 3074.
This is a custom VPN.
It really looks like IPSEC.
Also really looks like wireguard,
which looks like IPSEC a lot.
It signs and encrypts
pretty much all traffic.
It sits at layer two.
It smears TCP and UDP
into itself in a way,
that you also kind of
see an IPSEC to a degree.
It's very, very, very, very
focused on saving bytes
wherever it can.
I think some of that probably relates
to trying to get this thing
running on modems originally,
like it seemed like they were doing,
because they go to absolutely heroic ways
to save a byte here, save a byte there.
Yeah.
Cool.
Here's the underlying packet format.
First byte contains padding and an opcode.
How about this?
The padding for the actual payload
ends up being eight-byte aligned,
because that's the block cipher size,
so the padding tells you
how much of the block cipher
goes past the payload.
You've got an opcode.
So, zero ends up being control packets.
Then you've got three each for TCP, UDP,
and another protocol called VDP.
You've got three bytes for a SPI.
That is security parameters index.
That's essentially a session identifier.
You've got payload, which
when we talked about.
That can just be anything.
For things like TCP, that'll
be the actual fragment data.
It won't be the headers or
that kind of information.
For the control packets,
it'll be just kind of arbitrary data.
Diffie Hellman.
It'll be all those sort of pieces
that need to be negotiated.
Pretty arbitrary amounts of data.
For TCP, UDP and VDP, you have a footer,
which contains what would normally be
their header information
in a really cool, but one of those ways
Microsoft is going to
heroic ways to save bytes.
The protocol footer doesn't
need to be encrypted.
It'll be signed, but if there's padding,
it can be stored up.
It can basically be optionally encrypted,
if that helps you save bytes,
because the encryption step will happen
before trying to parse
the protocol footer.
We'll have two bytes of sequence number.
Then there's also sequence number.
There's also an additional
two hidden bytes
of sequence number,
where you just have to
remember where you were.
You start at zero.
Once it rolls over,
each side will bump up.
They're higher bytes,
but they don't actually communicate that.
I think that's also true of IPSEC though.
That's not a super crazy thing.
Then, there's also a signature,
which is 10 bytes of a
truncated SHA1 of everything,
including the hidden sequence bytes,
with keys that were
negotiated at the same time
as the Diffie Hellman.
One thing I am gonna rag on a little bit
is the way the signature
check is computed here.
It ends up being you do it
over the protocol footer,
then the header, then
the rest of the payload,
then the sequence number.
Something like that.
It pulls them all out,
which means that you have
to do a significant amount
of processing of this packet
to understand where the boundaries
of these different pieces are,
before you validated the signature.
I mean, don't roll your own
crypto is kind of rule one
and two and three and five.
But if we're at rule six,
and you are implementing your own crypto,
just keep it simple and sign
everything in a linear way.
Don't force somebody
to interpret something
before they've been able to
verify the signature on it.
It looks like Microsoft did it right.
I didn't find any bugs in it.
It's just hard to get right,
and I wouldn't trust myself
to get it right, basically.
Cool.
Yeah, we've got the control packets.
It's opcode zero.
A lot of Diffie Hellman
parameter negotiation.
If you're shutting down
the VPN to talk to it,
there's a piece for that.
There's kind of keep alives,
that keep the connection going,
and the service will kill it off
if it doesn't see keep alives in a while.
Interestingly, there's
this event queue too,
that sits at this protocol layer,
where a lot of server side events happen
at this layer two,
sitting underneath the TCP and all that.
If you've ever seen your
friend wants to invite you
to a game,
or they started playing another thing,
and it pushes an event to your console,
and it makes a little pop-up,
that event ends up getting
pushed down at that layer two,
which is really interesting to me.
There isn't a equivalent of a web socket
or something that they have.
Obviously, they didn't
have web sockets in 2002,
but there isn't some higher level protocol
that's being kept together,
but it's all sort of
negotiated at this low level
that these events are taking place,
which is really interesting.
There's also a bunch of
throttling and QOS management
that happens in negotiating at this layer.
The other opcodes, we have UDP and TCP,
but they remove a bunch of stuff.
If every packet is signed,
then you don't need check sums.
I think they removed the urgent bit
out of their TCP stack, which is awesome.
Urgents, awful. I wish
everybody could remove urgent.
Each of these has actually three opcodes,
because they do a cute scheme
where, if you're port 1024,
you don't actually have to list the ports.
If you're within like 127 of that port,
then you can list the ports
as just single byte offsets.
But if you're one of the other ports,
you do normal two byte
ports, like you would expect.
There's also VDP, which I hinted at.
And so, that's UDP, but
with part of the payload
that is outside of the encrypted segment,
and that's where it stores voice,
which means that voice in
Xbox Live is unencrypted
in the air.
And that is ostensibly
for lawful intercept,
so that the cops can
get a wire and trace you
and look at everything you're saying.
That is what that is.
Don't plan an insurrection over Xbox Live,
I guess is the point there.
Cool.
And then, at that point
you have a full connection
into the VPN.
You have a cryptographic
attestation to your identity.
That identity also contains
which services on the backend
you're allowed to talk to.
There's about 20 of them,
at least on the original.
I haven't checked in recently.
There's this one called
presence that always gets used;
essentially, that's where you
end up pushing your event,
that you are in a game,
and it ends up being a dumping ground
for a lot of
the ancillary pieces
of Xbox Live, as well.
Games can have custom services.
So, if you think, classic ones are MMOs,
will have custom services
for their backends,
so they'll just negotiate a different one,
and they'll connect through there.
Even if you're an MMO and
you're running your own servers,
all of these communications still end up
initially hitting this VPN.
Everything is encrypted
through and through,
and is this one protocol stack.
Unfortunately, as I've been
reimplementing the stuff,
I played a lot of Halo 2 as a teenager.
I joke that I am doing this,
so that when I hit my midlife crisis,
I have what I wanted to do
when I was a teenager as well.
But Halo 2 uses a custom service as well,
so it doesn't come for free,
but I'm sure we'll get there.
These backend services
actually tend to be HTTP.
They tend to be with
custom binary payloads
on a per-service basis,
but I wasn't really expecting something
as forward-looking.
Really, really strong inclinations
that they're primarily
written in C# ASP.net servers.
There's a lot of .ASHX endpoints,
which in context, would've
been like a beta version
of ASP.net, I think,
which is really, really,
really forward looking
for, at least in my mind,
how to release internet
connected service for 2002.
And really, once you have TCP up,
to just treat everything
as HTTP, for 2002 era,
was quite forward looking.
So, going through it, presence,
like we said, always exists.
That's where client push events come from.
Like we said, there is
that event queue where,
for server pushed events,
this is where the client
pushed events for the most part
end up coming from.
Matchmaking.
This is a matchmaking service that will,
for games that aren't
ranked, for the most part,
but you're just trying to
find somebody close to you,
maybe somebody close to your Geo IP,
or somebody with low
ping, for whatever reason,
ends up going through matchmaking service.
There's a string service
that I think does internationalization
and maybe sanitization for
moderation so they can update,
"These are the words you're
not allowed to say and query."
There's feedback, which is,
"This guy called me a slur."
So, moderation requests
end up going through there.
Stats. There's leaderboards
go through there.
I figured out a couple more of these
since I wrote up these slides.
For ranked matches, that's
where it ends up building up
your ELO and or whatever algorithm
is off of the stats information.
There's also a arbitration service
that looks a lot like matchmaking,
but it ends up generating
sessions for ranked play.
Messaging: you can send
users messages, pretty clear.
Auto-update.
This is one of those key
pieces that was, like I said,
newer to Xbox Live,
because they had the
storage on each console
necessary to do this.
Making sure that everybody's
playing the same version
of the game.
And then, there's team
management, is a team service.
Let's see.
Oh, and there's also a
NAT detection service
that'll let you do NAT punching,
and at least NAT understanding.
A lot of the NAT stuff
is actually interesting,
because by sticking
everything on that port 3074,
you get a lot of NAT punching for free,
because you've already communicated
to the external services.
And therefore, any incoming game request
can also come in on that port,
because you've already
done 80% of NAT punching.
So, it's a nice way to do that.
Sweet.
Then, we have match, or
just joining a game session.
What does that look like?
You end up using the
matchmaking service to query for
or create a session.
That session information
ends up containing a host,
and a lot of the random parameters
of what a game will contain.
There'll be a session identifier,
there'll be a key exchange key,
which lets boxes talk to each other
without Diffie Hellm-ing to each other.
Once a box gets a list of
potential hosts to join a game in,
they end up logging into that host
with more or less the same VPN protocol.
That VPN is ultimately the base layer
of even that piece, and
system link as well.
We already covered NAT punching.
System link.
Yeah.
System link's about the same.
They will throw out a broadcast packet
encrypted with essentially the same key,
but
it'll be like a per-game
key that's on the disc,
so that they can see each
other's game announcements.
And then, ultimately, the host
box will set up a VPN server
and the other boxes will VPN into it,
and that's how system
link ends up working.
It looks like actually games
don't have a TCP stack,
other than based on this VPN protocol.
So, they couldn't even do
anything if they wanted to.
Cool.
How do you go about reversing this stuff?
Lot of staring at Ghidra.
I wanna give a shout out
to whatever contractor
had to add Xbox executable
support to Ghidra.
It probably didn't need to
happen at that point anymore,
and he probably was
wondering what he was doing
with his life, but I really appreciate it.
It was probably one of the best
uses of my defense dollars.
Going looking at it,
Gauntlet Dark Legacy ships
with a PDB just on the disc.
It doesn't have the online capabilities,
but you can get your bearings
about what an Xbox game looks like.
Red Star is an online game that ships
with the full symbol map,
including the online shared libraries.
Jedi Knight: Jedi Academy
GPLed their Xbox version,
and that includes
all of the online components,
not the Microsoft code
directly, but how to call it.
And then, in every
executable XONLINE, XNET
is broken out into separate sections.
XONLINE is the online component.
XNET is what you just
need for a system link,
and contains the VPN stack, essentially.
All crypto is cleanly
exported by the kernel,
so you can see that on the import list.
You can go here,
github.com/xombieonline/xombie
is AGPL source for reimplementation.
Very proof of concept.
PRs are welcome.
Xombie.org, whenever I end
up updating DNS entries,
will be where you go
to sign up for an alpha
to get at it back online.
Yeah.
I kind of wanna move the industry
towards a theory of software
security harm reduction
when it comes to network services.
And so, where I'm at:
people are gonna use software now online
that they can't update anymore.
Rule one is don't do that,
but people are gonna do that.
So, I'm open sourcing a lot of this stuff
to really start thinking about
how we can protect people,
even in these very unsafe conditions,
and start opening things up,
and doing so by shining a
light and adding knowledge.
I don't think we have time
for the demo as given,
and I don't think it's gonna work.
Yeah.
So, sweet.
(audience applauds)