- Now, this morning,
we have Winn Schwartau,
talking to us about his history,
which is really legendary.
So sit back, enjoy, and please
give a warm welcome to Winn.
(audience clapping and cheering)
- Am I supposed to ask
for you to do that again
to make me feel really good?
No, no, no, no, no.
(audience laughing)
(audience clapping and cheering)
This'll fuck up the audio
guy in the rear, right?
Am I fucking it up really bad?
(audience laughing)
This is gonna be a rant.
I haven't spoken at DEFCON
I guess in 15 years,
because I'm not the traditional hacker.
Network protocols, I
lie, I cheat, I Google
and I have a lot of good
friends, a lot smarter than me.
But I began and I didn't really
realize that I was hacking.
And what I want to show you
is some experiences that
I had starting in 1958.
Anybody alive in 1958?
Fuck you, Barry.
Really, okay.
(audience laughing)
- [Barry] Two.
- Oh, you were two?
And I grew up in an engineering family.
My father went to MIT at 15
and worked on radar development
during World War Two.
So he gave me a non-optional
education on electrical engineering early.
My mother was the first audio engineer
at NBC during World War Two
and got a whole series of patents on...
(audience clapping and cheering)
Yeah, my mother, I wish
she could come to DEFCON,
but she'd like be 140 now.
So not gonna work out.
That was my first DEFCON
and my first beer.
And this is my father giving me...
Every week my parents split up,
so on the weekend I went down
to my father's house in Greenwich Village
and watched the tourists
get mad at the beatniks,
and he gave me non-optional
electrical engineering education
and that went on for years and years.
So that ended up being weird.
But I ended up doing TV
repair work at six years old
because how hard was it?
You take the tubes out of the TV,
you go down to the drug
store, you test them,
you take the two dollars, get a new 12AX7,
go back, plug them in,
and a neighbor in the apartment
building gives me 50 cents.
(audience clapping)
But that was in the 50s and they thought,
oh, how do you know how to do that?
Well, my father told me
how to use the tube tester.
That was really it.
That's what our electronic
stores used to look like
when we had to build shit.
And this is the world of
computers way back then.
So my first hack was in 1958,
and anybody know what these
are called other than Barry?
Rotary telephones, of course.
So we had these obviously,
and some of them were four digit numbers,
and this is what a bill looked
like back in those days,
when you actually had to
pay rental fee for a phone
and a rental fee for the wire.
Phone calls, and this is in New York City,
were still 10 cents a minute,
even if I'm calling
just across the street.
So things got expensive very quickly.
And apparently I was an
unruly child and talked a lot.
So my mother locked the phone.
(audience laughing)
And, well, I wanted to make phone calls.
So what do you do in
a non-destructive way?
How do you hack a rotary
telephone with no tools,
no destruction whatsoever?
Well, here is the old people up here
and they're all giving me this.
Now, don't interpret that too
sexually, please, from them.
That's them.
(audience laughing)
Inside of these are what's called
stepper relays, decade relays,
and when you dial,
basically it's click
click, three or a seven,
and if you get your timing down
with the lock on the phone just right,
hello operator, may I help you?
And please connect me to this
long distance number in Greece
or to my friend across the...
A non-destructive hack
that my mother then on
the next bill came along
and it was too much and she goes,
so you figured it the fuck out, did you?
(audience laughing)
Was it smart?
No, it was just a kid not accepting
that there was a lock
that I could not bypass,
even though it was a
completely non-technical hack.
So I'm screwing around
with analog computers
and stuff throughout the years,
and everybody know who
Richard Stallman is?
I grew up with him,
but I didn't remember that until I hit 60,
because we knew him as
Dickie, Dickie Stallman,
and so he and I built
little transistor radios
and all sorts of crap,
and his mother was a MILF, just saying.
(audience laughing)
Shut up, Ben, out.
Now, the neighborhood drug
stores back in those days
would hire a bunch of us kids
for like three hours a week each
to spread a little bit
of the 80 cents an hour
wealth or whatever,
and inside of there, of course,
you see there's a phone booth.
And those were the phones of the day.
And of course, we wanted
to make phone calls,
but we're like 10 years
old, how do you do it?
How do you do it for free?
Well, that's the way
these things used to work.
Stick them in the slot,
and this is the US
system, it was different,
and you couldn't do this hack
in other countries and not everywhere.
So here are the pieces to the hack.
Chinese laundry cardboard and a penny.
What we did, and there was
a design feature or fault by AT&T,
depending upon how you look at it,
you take a sliver of
one of those cardboards,
slide it down the dime slot,
all the way to the bottom,
pick up the receiver, put
a penny in the nickel slot.
It registers as a dime and
you get your penny back.
(audience laughing)
So if you have a pocket full of pennies,
calling Greece with the operator,
long distance operator on
the phone, is a no brainer
and they're getting a
legitimate money trigger.
And we lived at that drug store for years
making those kind of calls.
And again, it was a stupid, stupid,
but highly effective way
to bypass the security,
the features, the controls that
were built into that system.
So then I go on to high school
and they've got a computer thing,
and high school and I
didn't get along very well.
So I sort of left in 11th grade
and decided to go into
the family business,
the recording industry,
music, TV and all that stuff,
and I was 16 years old.
So that was the first
studio I got to work at,
which was fairly overwhelming,
except for the fact that my father did it,
and I had been exposed to the studios
and it really wasn't all that scary.
Anybody know who that is?
My first recording session.
Shout it out, anybody.
Nugent, it was the Nuge.
He would get naked in the
studio and hump the console.
Just saying.
Please don't repeat
that and publicize that.
And then this was my
first mechanical system.
It was a cyber mechanical system
for cutting records, vinyl.
Some of you may remember vinyl.
And this is how we used to do that.
Now, later on in life,
I was at the studios
and there was a thing
that used to be called
telephone credit cards
and there's one of them.
And once you got the number
and you got the number by paying a guy
on Eighth Avenue and 42nd Street a dollar,
you do that until the FBI
decides to wrap you around
their heads a little bit.
So that was my first visit from the FBI
for doing some sort of crime.
So that was 1969.
It was not a hack, it was
pure out and out theft.
So then I get involved with Hendrix
and all these guys doing
complex systems, Robert Moog,
and that's the first synthesizer
down from Electric Lady
Studios in New York.
So I kept seeing and being
involved with complex systems.
This is where I learned
that assembly language and I
do not get along either.
And I built it, it semi sort
of worked, and that was enough.
That was a computer that
we used deck computers
to do synchronization for TV shows.
And this one was from Applause!
And trying to make a deck
computer back in those days
actually do what you want it to do
was an incredibly slow process.
Back in, this was the day
in our studios in New York,
we had our own telephone
exchanges back in the day.
So how do you hack that?
Because what we needed to do
was get audio from the New York
studios into the LA studios,
but AT&T wanted $1,500
an hour in 1970 dollars,
to be able to do that connection.
But we had a switchboard.
And once you have the
switchboard and the PBX system,
you can bypass very easily the controls
and get directly out to LA
and move the audio back and forth.
Again, is it a hack by today's standards?
From our standpoint, it got the job done.
So being broke back in
those days and a roommate,
we used to get our utility
bills on punch cards.
Did anybody ever do that?
All right, one old guy,
two old guys, fair enough.
Is that you, Mark?
- [Mark] Yes, it is.
- It is.
Well take your mask off
so I can see your face.
Thank you.
Yeah, let's hear it for
G Mark, come on, yeah.
(audience clapping)
So, we used to get our bills
and what is it we want to do?
Not pay them, and keep
the power and the phones.
So we had access of course
to computers at NYU, what have you,
and then we discovered by
looking at the punch card,
the dollar amount, let's say it was $7.32,
there were no fields to
the left of the number.
So what did we do?
Add a minus sign.
(audience laughing)
Every month, we got a check
for the amount of service
that we used the month before.
(audience clapping)
Wait a minute, is this
doing a live thing of me?
Oh, shit.
(audience laughing)
I wonder if we can say that.
Oh, shit, okay (laughing).
So, that's how it worked
for about two years
and they upped their security at that
a little bit after that.
So then I got hired to do
a build a studio complex for some guys,
and while they wanted to pay me
reasonably good money back in the day,
they had virtually no
budget for equipment.
And what we needed to do was tie together
all of these studios
throughout the facility,
and there were eight or 10 of them,
and instead of the big patch
bay, they couldn't afford,
or the wiring associated,
which they couldn't afford,
we decided we have another option here.
Who pictures this?
Yeah, AT&T.
AT&T owned the universe.
Them and IBM owned the universe back then.
And the AT&T building
was about five blocks away on 11th Avenue.
And what did we do?
We did what is now called dumpster diving,
looking for old AT&T
equipment that they threw out,
because if there was
one little thing wrong,
they would just toss it out,
which meant from our standpoint,
all we have to do
is find the one little
thing wrong and fix it,
but it was all free.
So by putting all of this stuff together
and repurposing this equipment,
we were able to build recording studios
and switching networks,
using stepper relays
the same way that we used to,
I hacked the phone when I was a kid.
And the stepper relay was the key to it,
because you could dial up
anything you wanted to do.
So there was a rack of dials
and it rerouted all of
the signals everywhere
throughout the recording complex
and it didn't cost us a dime.
Thank you, AT&T for that one.
My first home computer,
where again, I learned,
I'm a really shitty programmer.
I'm awful.
I got it to work semi
sort of kind of kludgy
and that was when my wife first said
that she was now a computer
widow, and that was in '78.
Oh, there's my wife, and
what happened with my wife...
(audience clapping)
Well, thank you, Mike.
My wife, she built recording consoles
and this was the first computerized,
automated recording console, 1979.
Never fucking worked.
(audience laughing)
I kept blaming my wife
for it and she goes,
I didn't wire those.
But it was one of these...
You had to know 700 control commands
and do all phase shift antenna metal
in order to make anything
attempt to work and it didn't.
And that was one of the projects
that we were trying to make it work,
and fuck it, just completely gave up.
I had a studio in New York for a while.
So, that was the background
on which we started,
or I started learning
there's always an answer.
It's like that Apollo,
one of the greatest scenes
in movie history, Apollo 13,
this is what they have up there,
that's all you get to
work with, nothing else.
So back in these days, I was
doing a lot of studio work,
I was on the road with
various music artists,
and as we always say at DEFCON,
something's always gonna
fuck up completely.
Well, I'm gonna tell you about
a couple of those fuck ups,
and we had to hack our way out of them.
1975, 1976, I don't
even remember the year,
we were in Kingston, Jamaica,
and it was a thing with
the British government
and they were trying to make peace
because there were troubles down there,
and Stevie Wonder and Bob
Marley were the big acts.
So we had to build riot
cages into the stage
because of the suspected
possibility of terrorism
that the British embassy
had told us about.
And I remember, I think I'm
23 years old here going,
terrorism, concert, fuck me, get me home.
Well, concert goes on, soccer stadium,
120,000 people in the soccer stadium,
and keep in mind that Jamaican
police don't have police.
Ergo, the riot cages built into the stage.
So the chaos was suddenly
all of the lights and
all of the sound went off
with 120,000 reggaeing
people in the audience.
The fuck do you do?
We're in a foreign country,
we don't know where the...
It was like, give us a plug.
It's like what we say,
give me clean internet and
I'll take it from there.
That's all we wanted.
Give us some good power.
Except in this case
there was so much power,
the pole transformer went.
120,000 people.
What do you do?
Well, one of the absolutely
stoned out of his mind groupies,
it was his, not mine, CO2 cools
things down really quickly.
So we had two of the group...
Not the groupies, roadies,
sorry, not groupies,
roadies get the CO2s
that we happened to have
because we had two of
equipment and it gets hot,
went over to start cooling
down the transformer
as they start to get
arrested for terrorism.
And it took a few minutes in
order to get them to realize
we would like your help
keeping this, and it was a...
But we hacked the entire
power system for the stadium
with several cans of CO2,
and the concert finally went on.
Sort of like Jeopardy last
night, we finally got there.
Took a while, but we...
And again, is this a true hack?
I don't care what word
you want to use for it,
it was when the shit really
fucking hits the fan,
what do you do?
And you've got to pull
out every single stop,
and I get into rants
about graceful degradation
and enterprise networks and things,
and I talk to the CISOs, I say,
where's your graceful degradation
and segmentation plan?
And I go, say what?
All right, well you've never
been in rock and roll, dude.
(audience laughing)
So there's a few takeaways
and the slides will all be
available for you guys later on.
I absolutely love Liza Minnelli.
We recorded Liza With a Z,
and what she did in the
studio was rather amazing.
She drank a bottle of scotch,
took her clothes off
and proceeded to sing.
All right, if that's the
way you want to do it, Liza.
So the whole object was gonna be a TV show
called Liza With a Z.
She was coming back and doing,
now gonna be famous again.
So live shows, live thing
went absolutely fine,
but we need to go back to the studio.
Now, in those days we had film, deck,
we had a video (indistinct) a little bit,
but made mostly film,
and an audio machine with
a thing called pilot tone.
Nobody's probably ever heard...
Anybody ever hear of pilot tone?
Oh, Masuchi, of course you
have, you're as old as...
I went to high school with
this motherfucker up here.
Ninth grade, I've known him 56 years.
Thanks for coming, Mike.
So you get back to the studio
and you expect the pilot tone on the film
and the mag stripe to work
with the audio, right?
Well, not so much.
Completely out of sync.
And we have a live
broadcast coming up on NBC.
The fuck do you do when
you're completely out of sync?
Well, you cobble together.
This is very sophisticated equipment
compared to what we have.
We cobbled together a set
of oscillators and power,
two power amplifiers,
to drive a set of hysteresis
synchronous motors,
for anybody that may
remember what those are
before the DC motors came along,
and that (indistinct) pattern,
the one that you see there,
we had to take dials on the
oscillators and the machines
because they introduced
friction into the system,
and maintain that (indistinct) pattern
for four hours by hand.
Did it always work?
No, sometimes the high hat
and the video was off a little bit,
but in general it was the
best that we could do.
We cobbled together some
equipment that didn't exist
and we went to the shop and did it.
Again, is it a hack?
We got the job done when otherwise
there would not have been
a TV broadcast at all.
Synchronization failures were a disaster
in the early days of
the recording industry
because everybody in the late
70s and early 80s is saying,
we're gonna go digital,
digital will fix everything.
Except for those of you who
remember what digital was like
in the late 70s and early 80s,
it was really highly experimental.
So we did a lot of experimentation
of how do you get,
instead of just 24 tracks,
how do you get 48 tracks?
And can I record 24 of
the tracks live in LA,
the other 24 live in New York
and keep them all
synchronized with equipment
that doesn't work from England?
No offense to my British
friends out there.
Well, synchronization was awful.
Remember the song, Do You Think I'm Sexy?
With Rod Stewart.
We were on that session for
72 hours, 72 straight hours,
just trying to keep the drum
tracks from that song from LA
in sync with the audio
and the voice being recorded in New York.
That was 72 hours of absolute
hell where we had to, again,
revert to graceful degradation
and a manual mode of
working, completely manual,
and you could grab a few seconds of sync
and it would fall out again.
So it was an absolute nightmare.
But synchronization in our world
is about what makes everything work,
and getting the timing right.
We've all heard the stories
of, well, my clock was on CST
and their clock was on
Central European Time.
We were eight hours off.
Or I'm using an Imperial
measurement system
versus a Metric system,
and everything completely fucks up.
The synchronization issues
that we faced are very similar
to the types of synchronization
issues that we face today,
but are much more profound
aspects of what can go wrong.
And that's why thinking synchronization
is so incredibly critical.
Charlie Daniels, I got flown in from LA
to record him in Madison Square Garden.
My crew was there.
Everything should have gone very smoothly.
However, what we were supposed to do
was record Charlie Daniels
and the event and the bands
through a fairly large console
onto a 16 track tape machine.
Fairly normal activity
for us back in those days.
So you have 40 microphones
go into the console,
branch them out and record them properly
on the appropriate channel
on the audio machine.
Except, and no offense to any
union people in this room,
but back in the day, Madison
Square Garden, (indistinct),
hired the most incompetent
people known to man
to assist us in our professional
recording endeavors.
Every single microphone
signal was ground looped.
So every single input,
all 40 of them had
exactly the same signal.
Right.
No isolation, no differentiation,
and we actually had to do it all live
with massive amounts of
equalization and digital filtering,
such as existed in 1981,
to be able to get it
down to a mono machine,
and then have to go to the studio
and rebuild the whole thing from scratch.
So audio quality, if anybody's interested,
I actually have the vinyl from that,
the audio quality is absolutely awful,
but the radio stations
didn't seem to give a shit,
because they were broadcasting on AM
and the quality was so bad anyway.
So this was about
preparation and architecting
and never really trusting folks to do it,
do the jobs that you expected,
especially in that environment
back in those days.
So there's plenty of realities,
and I spent a lot of
time doing remote work,
and remote work is where
if it can go wrong,
it's gonna go fucking wrong
and it's gonna go wrong in a big way,
and these are just a
couple of the examples.
There was a studio we
worked at called R One
and it was a jingle
studio back in the days
and the money making for
the recording industry
that would support artists
was from the jingle
houses for advertising.
So it was pretty straight ahead stuff.
So the studio was roughly like this
and 40 musicians out there,
the producer from whatever company it was,
like I said, this one was Alka-Seltzer
and the jingle house,
they're all sitting there,
and then they'd say to me,
Winn, is there supposed to be smoke
coming out of the console?
Oh, fuck.
So we got 40 guys and we got a console
that just went up in smoke.
What do you do?
Well, you panic.
And back in those days,
we had these things,
and I think some of the
AV guys still use them,
they're called SM.
They're mixers, little tiny,
sure, four channel mixers.
So what did we have to do?
We had to get all the
gophers in the studio,
extend all the microphones,
wires about 100 feet,
wire them into the studio,
put them into the back
of these little mixers,
take those mixers, bypass the console,
go into the tape machine
where we can manually control the levels
throughout the entire session
and never be able to
hear what was going on
until we did a playback
to see how good it was.
That was sheer chaos.
But again, there was a way to do it.
We understood the architecture
of what we were trying to achieve.
We understood what we had in the consoles,
how do we replicate
the console feature set
into something else in under 20 minutes?
And it's a bitch, but these are the things
that have brought me into
the security industry,
always thinking of what
the hell can go wrong?
And maybe that's why I wrote
several of the books on these topics
of what can go wrong when you
don't really think about it.
Charlie...
That's Hank Williams Jr.
We were doing a thing in New York.
Anybody ever hear of the
Lone Star Cafe in New York?
Yeah.
We had a studio in the basement of it,
and every week we'd record
whatever the act was live
to 570 radio stations across the country.
Not really a big deal technically,
we knew what we were doing,
we had the tie lines and
everything went well.
Hank Williams is up
there, and he's playing,
and a couple of guys whose
particular orientation
he was not thrilled with,
decided to have a beer fight
and throw beer on him on stage.
It's a little tiny
stage, smaller than this.
And he up and walks out
and we hadn't been through 30
minutes of the live show yet.
Gone, no act.
What do you do?
Well, we had the radio announcer,
Mike Fitzgerald was his name,
he was the New York radio announcer
for the station that sponsored all this,
and I said, Mike, vamp, vamp.
And I said, I need 10 minutes.
So what did we do?
We were live recording everything.
So I rewound the tape
to the very beginning
of when we began recording,
when we introduced him live.
I pressed play and replayed
for the second half of the show
exactly what was done in
the first half of the show.
Nobody seemed to give a shit.
Again, back in those days
and I think it's still the same rules,
if you don't fill the air time,
the FCC's gonna get on your ass.
So whatever it was, fill
the air, fill the air,
and again, we kind of got
through that one as well.
The live stuff.
When you're doing any
technical stuff at all,
and you say, oh, this
is gonna be really easy,
the answer is no.
How many years of hacker
jeopardy have we had
where we, ah, we've got it wired this year
until somebody decides to put
Vista on a machine for us,
and the first time I think anybody
ever yelled at jeopardy,
hacker jeopardy was,
hey, does anybody have a
non-Vista machine we can have now?
And I finally worked our way through that.
As we build our systems,
complexity is our enemy, absolute enemy.
And we want more features.
So we see the increase of
sophistication of software.
We see the increase of
sophistication of hardware.
Not necessarily so much
because we need it,
but the vendors want to be able to say,
we have 22 new features
and it's worth another thousand dollars
for us to give it to you.
And we're increasing our
complexity without due thought,
without proper planning.
Again, what do you do
when the IT hits the fan?
And that's why I go back
to these presentations,
and my prior career of it was all analog,
we had nothing digital that
worked in those days at all,
with the exception of a couple
little pieces of equipment,
everything was guessing, trial
and error and it was a mess.
And today we're still
doing this trial and error,
but we should learn from history
that a little bit more planning
in when the IT hits the fan,
how do you function?
What is your minimal viable
operating capability?
Do we plan about that?
The businesses go, no, IT,
you take care of the business,
folks don't understand enough.
You guys do.
And that is part of the
hopefully the lesson here
is to be able to plan for
absolutely everything.
One of the things we used
to do back in the day,
get a recording console.
Let's say a new recording console's in
or we've done an overhaul of
a particular part of a studio.
One of the things, as we
called it, turn all the knobs.
What we did and the reason we did it,
we wanted to crank up the volume
in every single circuit on the console,
and we're looking, oh, 4,000
knobs maybe on a good console,
because we wanted to
stress it to the point
we wanted it to break
under our lab conditions
versus break in a live
situation, the TV situation
or live recording in the studio.
So cranking all the knobs for
us helped identify problems
similar to where airplane
engine design is done,
stress the hell out of it.
And one of the things that I
think I've missed in our field
and if somebody's doing it really well,
I would love to know about it,
is do we have any sort of
protocols for stress testing
of our networking infrastructures
to be able to say,
okay, we need to put a
limiter or a compressor
or a restriction control,
because it cannot handle all
the traffic, all the thing.
So back in '91, we were building this...
Steve Katz, the world's
first (indistinct),
brilliant guy and a dear
friend from J.P Morgan,
they wanted to do the first
single sign on system, 1990,
and I was on that team
and we tied together security
dynamics which became RSA.
There was Sun Microsystems with Solaris,
Delphi Project from MIT was involved.
So we built this whole
single (indistinct) system.
We were so proud of ourselves.
So proud.
We're showing it at a couple conferences
and it works brilliantly.
Where single (indistinct)
is finally a reality,
until it fucks up.
So Steve says, let's deploy it.
Deploy it where?
Well, we're gonna do it at J.P Morgan.
Cool.
They deployed it company wide.
Sounds good, right?
Well, what we had not considered
was the time factor of authentication
when 10,000 people try to log on
at 9:00 AM at the same time.
What happens to your network
when you don't have accelerators,
you don't have spread bandwidth,
you don't have balancing circuits?
All the shit we have today, we didn't have
and we completely fucked it
up by spending all this money
and designing something that
was great for 10 people,
not for 10,000 people.
So turning all the knobs,
stress the shit out of things,
I cannot impress enough
that we need as an industry
to really develop a stress mechanism,
a stress protocol for various
of the environments that we're in.
And it's turn all the V knobs,
we can do the same thing
and we should be able to very easily
automate that stress testing process.
And I see Dave Fiz is up here,
he's designing it right now.
Do you have the patent shift for this?
Yeah.
So incident response.
Whether it was the incident
response with my mother
and the rotary telephone,
and my response was, fuck that,
I'm gonna make a phone call somehow,
all the way up to catastrophic failures
with a couple hundred thousand people,
live TV, with all of those,
and I didn't even show you
some of the really nasty ones,
it's all about incident response
and appropriate planning,
understanding your architectures
and then making sure that you have a way
to degrade and a methodology to recover.
And on that note, I wanted
to thank you so much.
I'm here for some questions if you like,
but that was my hacking
career beginning in 1958.
I am still a really,
really shitty programmer.
I have no idea how to do it anymore.
And you guys have been wonderful.
Hope to see you tonight
at Hacker Jeopardy,
and if you have any questions or comments,
there's a goon with a
microphone out there.
(audience clapping)
Oh, thank you.
All right, if there's no questions,
again, thank you very much,
I'll see you tonight at Jeopardy.
I appreciate it all.