alright are we ready everyone I think
we're ready
alright everybody we're ready to start
ed are you guys ready
alright so welcome to shrink on 2016
we're going to start the toxin I first
one is breaking bulbs briskly by bogus
broadcasts news regarding bogus
broadcast allow us the opportunity to
appreciate it my name's Joe nine then
today with some tools work against the
wave networks as well as discuss
exploiting Wireless automation systems
in order to break your ass and balls in
a rather quick manner so what you see
there in the in the animation is just
the hardware components that go along
with the software and tools that will be
talking later in particular some one
suffered find radios z-wave devices was
just a basic information about the
Weyburn those that might not be familiar
it is a proprietary low rate wireless
network protocols operates in the 900
megahertz spectrum even if you're not
familiar with the protocol they probably
come across devices every day
realize it there are several hundred
companies out there that neither
manufacture or sell the wave capable
smart devices in the bread and butter
for this protocol right now is really
the
home automation and security systems
with over 35 million devices sold as you
it has a fairly large market share
ranging from simple as smart plugs and
light bulbs will be more complicated
devices like door locks environmental
sensors like smoke detectors are sensors
and an even more physically robust
devices like a water leak detection and
energy meters then he has been security
research on a similar wireless protocols
for quite a while now when I started
working for him not to long ago he said
Joe wants to go do some research on the
security of this proprietary protocol a
good security researcher the first thing
I do is I start looking for what's
already out there nobody really wants to
recreate the wheel that takes way too
much time however since the protocol is
proprietary requires signing an NDA in
order get your hands on this site for
development in there wasn't very much
out there so first there's a open source
project called open z-wave provide
suffer libraries for interacting with
z-wave USB stick this is great if you
want to develop your own automation
software but doesn't really allow you to
operate outside the bounds of the
protocol which is really what a lot of
security research is about so I decided
to just force that was presented the
black hat 2013 seemed really promising
other than the closed source nature of
the custom firmware and software for
this presentation they talked about
using this Texas Instruments transceiver
in order to
exploit a.m. implementation law in the
key exchange program one particular
z-wave door lock in order to reset the
private key unauthorized access to the
door and be able to control the door
lock
really promising however when we were
unable to replicate the functionality of
the stool which was awesome
asking questions of the developer taking
down of course instead of trying to
figure out how to force the school to
work for my needs to move on and I don't
know maybe radio again presented black
hat so this isn't really a z-wave tool
it's more of a framework allows you to
build your own wireless sniffer and
injector on top of his list AP radio
framework uses the well-known Stevie
packet packet manipulation many of us in
this audience are familiar with and then
it also uses the capabilities to control
sufferance and radios radio which is a
much more specialized even better this
presentation the guys into a basic
support protocol in order to demonstrate
a packet replay attack while there's not
really a robust set of z-wave
exploitation tools on par with a killer
bee framework for me for those that are
familiar with that there is at least the
foundation allowed me to start playing
with prices and today he wanted to make
available a tool that collectively I
call the heat wave it is built on top of
radio with extended support for the
protocol so the state radio for their
presentation the basics implementation
of the protocol that has three command
classes which are groups of device
functionality extended that to my total
of 33 I'm so we can do more stuff with
easy way of includes three stand-alone
tools the first one is called easiest
under a yes it's named after a bee stung
work on the killer bee framework again
from this number does not work discovery
and enumeration next we have easy recon
which integrates individual devices on a
network in order to solicit information
to see less that they're just happens to
me information that would really be
useful for security researcher who's
trying to figure out if there's actually
any security in the UAE was of course my
job at the time and environment we have
easy fingerprint which exploits
differences in transceiver design in
order to distinguish between different
generations within the target device
does this by manipulating the physical
layer preamble in such a way that the
older generation transmissions and
respond
whereas the newer generation model was
not able to see her eyes with the
physical layer frame and therefore can
respond that allows us to determine what
generation module arguing with so when
limitation to bring up at this point is
if the target devices using encryption
tools not able to get the current state
or the configuration settings of the
target of eyes everything listen there's
is the fair game
encryption and because we had a really
spirited discussion with a particular
device manufacturer just last week
security within the protocol does
support AES 128 awesome completely left
to the individual device manufacturers
in order to use it in each of their
devices security researchers wanted to
find out how
repurchase 33 popular z-wave devices
available today on the market with only
nine of them actually I'm supporting
corruption that out of those 9505 them
were door locks hope that all door locks
would all wirelessly controlled or
licensed use some action they're not
really lost it all meant for the other
four devices were some of the newest
devices currently available in the
consumer market note about those four
however is that the three of them used
often security and what I mean by that
is you see a picture thereof of one of
the devices so the user manual
instruction in the use of the user the
device in a non secure mode and then
buried towards the end of the user
manual is a little snippet this is a
secure mode of this device added to your
network in this way the way we are told
you who reads that far in the device
manager especially have already added
it's your network in working so the
story here is that a yes the protocol
supports encryption many of the devices
currently available
don't and the ones that do not always
used by default
demonstration of the tool
what we have here is to a carafe ones
are defined radios transmit one is used
for or received because they're they're
not duplex of course you didn't change
without with whatever other software
defined radio you want to as long as
it's compatible with with you radio
chosen because they're fairly cheap
compared to something like a star P
over here I have small z-wave network
with just a couple devices for
demonstration and then over here is the
lamp install out of my room just for you
guys and it is connected to another
z-wave I stand here that you can really
see because of the shower so for time
sake I'm going to skip the the network
discovery portion because it really is
just passive scanning until traffic is
observed and a unique network
identifiers found the home I D 40 wave
and resume skip ahead to the network
enumeration a small network up here
already uneasy stellar using the the
whole idea that we assume that we found
their passive scanning so what's going
on right now is we are sending out
broadcast messages that solicit
compulsory acknowledgments from all the
devices on the network that are within
range of the suffered by radio so
windows devices acknowledged that
message they're making their presence
known and you see them pop up on the
screen their second year thats Tamil
finished with a report
so the stand found 50 devices on the
network now that we have the new devices
on the network
go ahead interrogate one of them do is a
device that's not configured with
encryption at the moment now that the
note I D from the previous can as akin
to the the IP address on the local
network for this protocol can device
number three or interrogated by summer
three what's going on right now as I'm
sending out a host of messages
requesting specific information from no
source authentication in the z-wave
protocol is not used the devices will
happily oblige and send that information
back to me and then the tools going to
convert it into a human-readable format
as you can see there on the screen
I'm so the device that we just and you
can see is a narrow text marks which six
below that you can see all the the
software and firmware version
information
followed by a list of all the
functionality of this device and then
there are the bottom you see the the
basic status of the device which is
currently off the continuous scanning
the configuration settings for that
takes more time we have for this this
presentation but I think you get the
idea so now just in case you're curious
and two to make a particular manufacture
a little bit we're going to interrogate
a device that is currently set up with
encryption right now you can see the
difference again it's gonna send the
same stream of requests for this device
asking for a specific information and
you can see that that this device we
still get the information that the
manufacture we see that it say in a text
I range and five same with the
some information for this software
version firmware versions and
capabilities down the bottom of the
basic status is unknown because there's
encryption we can't figure out if this
devices running on whatever understated
his escape the configuration stand again
it's so gifted but in this case it would
show that it was unknown because it's so
you might be asking yourself at this
point no we're more than halfway into
this presentation will what the hell
does this have to do with breaking balls
briskly I'm sure that's what a lot of
you came here for so naturally the easy
way of Dorset is geared more towards
reconnaissance however the messages used
to control or controlled devices is very
similar to the messages used just to
interrogate the devices are actually
really easy to control these devices
with suffered radios so naturally once
you have the ability to wirelessly
control advised the next question is
where can I break something and that's
what we set out to do we want to see
having access to a wireless automation
system how quickly can we break out
something like industrial source
involved in residential CFLs as he
brings back and went kinda zoom out
we've been looking at the way of kind of
soda straw z-wave as you probably know
is not the only wireless smart energy
protocol out there we have a ton of
solutions all them competing and
security is is a hot mess to use
something my wife would say so wifi in
2001 to 2004 gigahertz band these
protocols are fairly well understood and
there are tolls in like Cali Lenox first
blessing Bluetooth ZigBee you have an
outdated version of killer be in Cali
criticized gigahertz like like z-wave
Insteon and neutron and these others
that 900 megahertz really helps
the range of these devices and so this
is help Seaways take the majority market
share for the wireless market and so
what we really want to help contribute
to is the tool sets and in the attack
thinking for these are subject her
articles so for what we did here was a
case study these these power switches
are connected to something no one no one
just has them in our house for no reason
they're gonna be used for Christmas
lights and so for the case study here we
look at Horace involves in the home
there in a hotel rooms but more
interesting are the overhead lights in
in warehouses factories office buildings
as smart energy keeps getting plugged
there's been a lot of push on how to
automate this stuff and so even if it's
not a wireless system it's a wired
system that's not secure and we can get
into it we went to figure out how
quickly can damage something in the real
world from the network so how do you
break a fluorescent lamp you turn it off
and you turn it on really quickly but
it's not as simple as turning on and off
ten times a second and it'll be dead
it's actually a little bit tricky so
I'll talk about there is a publication
in the Journal of industrial technology
back in 2011 and what they did is they
took 35 compaq's less involved and they
cycled them to second power 98 seconds
powered off and they did this over and
over again until they sailed and what
they report is a talk about 7,300 cycles
and so if you look at that time from an
attack point of view how quickly can
break them that's about twenty that's
pretty good but there are two issues
with that one it couldn't be done with
his single night and that was kind of
our goal and there's also a wide range
so what happens when you brake inflation
bulb every once in a while it won't fail
catastrophically it'll just
and that damn limits the current doesn't
have the thermal stress
in order to survive for a long time and
that's how you get that long tail of
sixty hours so that the research
question looking for it is how do I
optimizes how quickly is it possible to
breakthroughs involves both the compact
fluorescents in the home and if you have
an industrial control system is
compromised how fast we break the
industrial lights the first thing we do
research we gotta replicate the results
so we we took eight goals can justify
their site had a pocket that we have
evolved and we ran until they failed and
the distribution looks really good
compared to the journal very consistent
on the left of these slides you've got a
box plot of the
the distro and then on the on the right
we had a very consistent they were
telling the truth so we won't see ok so
how quickly so this is for the compact
fluorescent no one has looked at the
industrial items as far as we can tell
how fast it goes well the overhead
lights in industrial settings are not
meant to be toggled on and I every time
you go in another room like the complex
or essence so that the mean time to
failure is is actually less than six
hours or so so what we do and we broke
those and we tried different patterns
and so we tried having each of the cycle
so instead of two seconds on eight
seconds off we did 1940 in the
performance improved we were able to
break them much faster so we kept going
in like a kind of alluded to before we
tried cycling you know ten times a
second course without that thermal
stress of the device turning on the
light heating up and then you going down
without thermal stress the device will
last for its intended life as 30,000
hours so what we found a sweet spot to
be was one second on three seconds off
that's about as quickly as you can kill
a horse and lamp when it comes to the
the other headlines so
easily within half a night at the
warehouse is known as a rounder I fell
asleep and the damage is cumulative so
if you perform these cycles you will end
up breaking these bulbs and the cost of
replacement can be substantial and so
going back to the compact fluorescents
we want to see well sure enough magic
number of one second on trees
significantly improved our attack
performance so we can break these are
known and again in less than nine hours
that's how you take away here as users
when you are connecting things in the
real world to the network to be mindful
of what will happen is someone got into
your system has physical damage is now
possibility in the Internet of Things
and then read the manual course and the
manufacturer uses just using corruption
if its wireless encryption and make it
the default period there's no reason not
to so easy way is available at the ural
listed there before he began questions
the question was is used for doors as
well so yes there are quite a few z-wave
enabled door locks on the on the market
that's actually one of the one of the
big selling points for this protocol is
that the use of door locks using it in a
smart home is one of the first things
that people want to get home I have one
of my house they're actually pretty
convenient questions
thank you very much