they've seen in the things you've done
online feedback and also that we still
have a bunch of t-shirts for sale and
also previous years he searched for sale
if you didn't get those previous years
are half price and of course all of the
benefits go to the charity of your
choice so please help our charities I
have at least some I know how much is
large t shirt you can wear life it's so
wonderful and when this like you know
someone who has a large for the best
response
dickey's and is not afraid of getting
hit on the head with him right there see
how far I can get this isn't gonna gonna
throw it all the visits to like that and
this one video this way to be sitting up
front to get up and move right and I
hope that you had a good time to talk
today because I'm very interested in in
new ways to classify malware so that we
can use them for other data analysis so
jon is has been a while you were 16
ok he went to Fidelis security he's an
avid travel but he teaches at the
University of Illinois as well and when
I asked him what he did for fun he said
he has four kids and no time for fun
mr speaker
thank you hope you're not too hungover
from last night or at least you
recovered somewhat from it can you know
I'm John beyond but I talked about
building an encyclopedia of malware
configurations are you read the bio a
little bit part of what goes into why
I'm doing this right
several takedowns oriented groups some
very active with law enforcement trying
to prosecute actors behind their
criminal operations so that kind of goes
into why I develop and how I develop the
things that i doing creates some biases
in my data collection that that we may
or may not get time to get into you know
the short version of that is I just like
to burn things I i grew up in the
eighties and nineties you know I
attention span of 30 seconds and I get
bored easy so generally start on my
talks you know this general problem
statement and all of your family with it
caused some form of this right you know
as defenders of the white house crowd
right there are more criminal operators
and there are people doing work right
we've got unlimited job security forever
as long as we're right there is much
more malware then there's reverse
engineer reverse everything we do is
public and it is very very hard to
actually get criminal prosecutions to
happen the two that i've been involved
in that actually gotten T and Verizon
stage almost about a year and about 10
different countries involved so you know
the economy does not favor us this talk
more about an hour or so
this little brat fearsome virustotal by
shows the number of submissions that
they've gotten the last seven days had
suggested it right and the orange line i
think is the most pressing one night
that's the number of distinct new files
detected by something roughly 400,000
Iraq alright there's no way that any
human being can process all of that
stuff you still need reverse engineers
but you need to get useful information
out of that and more humorous way of
putting that is right that Chinese
hackers can't hire enough people to keep
track of all of our abilities right for
those who saw the Onion article from
three months ago it's hilarious right
because it's true so short version is a
bad news we're doomed good news is I'm
gonna job security so you know so first
right
talk a little bit about threat
intelligence a lot of people talk about
this and and and you know there's a
Twitter account but I really makes fun
of a lot of people do it wrong you know
but this is important to where I'm going
with some aspects of this talk right
there's data right you know tons of IP's
domains whatever pick list of data
everything all right you know that's
just information that doesn't make an
intelligence intelligence you know is
critically examining information to
create some actionable conclusion there
has to be some fraud involved and to get
an idea of what the day
is really telling you a list of IP
addresses domains hashers whatever that
you can buy from X security company that
got fifty million dollars in VC funding
isn't necessarily intelligence that just
tons of times data and part of that
involves analyzing the adversary in and
getting in their head which won't talk
too much about here but knowing their
their motivations you know their
dispositions and what they intend to do
so how to deal with you know a million
plus samples of malware potential
malware
reverse engineering is off the table no
one you know no one has the bandwidth to
do that cuz it takes that takes too much
time dynamic analysis yeah you can do
some of that but the standard analysis
window for a sample from a sunny
dynamics and boxes about five minutes
right so you need a small data center to
start processing all of that stuff and
there's problems with with dynamic
analysis that we won't go into
antics and boxing now you can do some
static analysis if you know how to put
the pieces out and that's what we're
gonna talk about here and that's very
very fast I was able to process maybe a
quarter terabyte of malware just to the
static analysis piece within about an
hour window and not not using the
high-end hardware this is very very fast
and get you a lot of information from
malware that you know how to work with
and pulley information statically to get
all that data and then start pushing
stuff that you can't do statically to
dynamics and boxing and then to human to
human
reverse engineers the idea of making
things a little bit more so more
efficient so starter kit to start this
almost everything except the future
malware you know is open source you can
need this talk and do this today if you
want and by all means go have fun if you
if you choose to do it so you start with
an original we started with rats but now
we're doing more than that we'll talk
about that a second but whatever you get
is fine and the reasons rats is that
there is a rat two quarters out there
that's open source we'll talk about the
second figure out what selection
algorithm to say okay run this decoder
and then run whatever is appropriate
rip all the information output in the
database alright so internally like the
Splunk that's everybody's favorite
bitbucket but then we'll share it out
using this once that something available
all that's open source in to have links
here in a second
you know so why are rats kind of a
prototype for doing this kind of stuff
single-stage malware you know the
configuration of what really matters
right
anybody can use dark comment one of the
most prolific rats out there but you
really care more about the configuration
than you do that all you really need to
say about our common as its dark comedy
shareware to be going up to in some of
the other attributes
but rats are not only just you know the
script 2000 and 2001 Telligent agencies
use it I N attackers use it right it's
it's a good espionage tool you know
whether you're fifteen year old and new
moms basement trying to spy on
somebody's webcam or you wanna
bank executives it's it's a good tool
for the job as long as you can deal with
keeping an undetected dozens of
well-known types to work with but again
you know we do it we do it from what
amounts so the idea is a good start
prototypes to start developing the
tradecraft move along so you know you've
got this what can you do with all of
these action figs well you can start
burning them all right I can whack
thousands of these you know in one pop
when I'm bored on a Friday night so
ultimately I said this gonna go to law
enforcement starts to start trying to
clean stuff up automatically sync
calling this a possibility and that's
that's its own talk right now we're
gonna talk to your ignore is is the
mining the data correlations because
that's where things start to get really
really interesting when you start seeing
how an individual is changing their
malware overtime or changing the
configuration or for that matter
switching now where families now you can
start knowing something more about the
adversary other than this is engineer at
this is talking to this hostname
right now you can kind of see where
they're moving and get a better idea of
what what's going on behind them this
year is the first piece a puzzle I said
malware decoders Kevin Breen makes us
not mine right as thirty-some-odd I
forget exactly thirty to forty some
oddities that he open source right so if
you get a malware samples it dumps out
to configure an example of that
but uses Python very fast and very
efficient cause you know it's it takes
you know whatever pieces
binary that its configuration items and
that changes between our tights and says
here's what you need to know here's all
the configuration that's relevant and
that's all pretty much all anyone would
ever need to know about maybe samples
actively developed a few melhem you know
he'll he'll make changes so you know
Kevin Cummins a good guy loves what he
does some sources of power
virustotal being a commercial one right
everybody knows virustotal for
enterprises that have security programs
Microsoft has a buyer programme Pires
information Alliance where they can give
malware and some of their telemetry out
it's a good program to be involved in
and that's saying something cuz I'm kind
of an anti Microsoft but this is
something that Microsoft us you know and
they're sharing programs internal
sources that we develop and in the end
of the day it's about a quarter terabyte
of malware that word processing right
now and hopefully get that up a whole
lot higher and if you have now where you
wanna trade then by all means let's talk
and figure out what kind of exchange
looking for for that every malware has
some kind of configuration items at the
very minimum c2 information now we need
to talk to somewhere needs to figure out
where that is in practice though there's
a lot of other items that go into it
some of the richest just configuration
right do I want to turn off McAfee do I
want to have anti Sandboxie into the bug
and do I want to install on this path
right to this registry key there's a lot
of information and there's also some
free-form text fields now fewer criminal
I love criminals writing tax and free
form text deals that really makes my job
easier I have no idea why you do that
but please keep doing it so you know
that's
really you know where you can get some
interesting correlation get some
interesting data
there's also some fix things mutex being
a good example we can correlate based on
new tax everything else changes but the
mutex being random you have to push a
button to re- randomized that provide
something that lets you map various
campaigns together to the same after
overtime so as an example of some of the
configuration right here is dark comet
now not typically sophisticated but it's
out there is eight to ten thousand
samples of dark comedy you know in a
given month right so campaign campaign I
D why in the world
anyone would do anything but a default
value for campaign idea I have no idea
just 16 as the fall right you know but
dark comment wall so happily allow you
to use FTP to get you looks so we'll
have to authenticate to an FTP server so
you see username and password not this
particular sample right so a lot of
information right that you can use a
fairly fairly quickly and some things
that are a little bit you know a little
bit less clear that how high you would
operationalize it immediately you know
me text and Genco trends so I will talk
about that again and Jarret you see
similar things but different different
field it's a different now where does
things differently right this case
writes the registry registry value again
as a randomly generated thing you gotta
push a button to randomize it so that
can provide some ability to correlate
between different samples you know host
domain name pour some configuration
items
dumping this place at the wrong text
version of this you know into a CSV
you know like this you got hash value
description
campaign I D you see the third one in
their right that's obvious know
something discreet that I could say
who's using my campaign campaign idk
other things the last night I'm on there
is username and password for an FTP
server I redacted it sorry I didn't
think it was entirely appropriate to put
somebody's username and password on a
slider to talk but there were also the
same values so on top of putting that
stuff in their malware they're done
they're not even doing that
authentication so they go to greg is
that the brothers on amuse why people do
that I have no idea but thanks for doing
so between all the families and actually
this whole lot more fields are just ran
the ball all slides you know this gets
to how difficult it is the kind of data
normalize all this stuff every piece of
malware has its own configuration items
that are called something you've got all
of these lists of fields and not all of
them were used and not all of them are
necessarily useful you know from an
intelligence perspective whether
something turns off eighty or not I
don't know if it's not irrelevant but
it's probably not the most useful
information there so you know I said you
know how can you win in the venture
capital gains you know you could take
all these si toos or just rip it from
virustotal
with a low cost of an epi ki you know
anything that ever to text get the
network information you know get your
venture capital funding you know
create some map right and there then
there's your money and people do this I
don't know if the viable business model
of people get real money for it but
that's really not the most useful thing
other things need to be done with this
data and we talked in depth more before
using it
before making conclusions based on so I
store all this data locally
virustotal kids a lot of it the
virustotal doesn't keep configuration
information there some aspects that it
will have you text and cases network
information of the sample runs you know
but if you have all of that
configuration information local now
you'd start correlating and and will
show a little bit about that so the key
point however is that the key point for
this however is that when you observe
stuff the time you may not even know
what you're looking for a very very
often it's just like a week later
citizen incident almost all incidents
are already in use in an organization by
the time they were observed by time
someone responds to it if you knew what
to look for you have a rule in place to
stop something if I knew what malware
malware si toos where I can block at a
perimeter firewall right probably not
the most efficient thing to do but you
could do that this allows you to kind of
go back now I know something more about
what I'm looking for now let's see
historically what is also mapped to that
pattern tonight even that backwards in
time depending on how long this runs and
I'm hoping to run ten years of malware
threw it at some point the future now I
can map back somewhat somebody's been
doing for eight months which is very
useful information a lot of the
prosecution's happen because it's not
just a discreet attack a discrete-event
its ability to map that actors behavior
over time and to find the point where
they screwed something or did something
to expose her identity as an example
didi for BC did Oscar bitcoins guy was
arrested last month in
in eastern europe and the way that
prosecution happened a very generic
level that I could talk about right is
taking all of the emails all the
indications that attack in the hole in
total and be able to map all the
behavior back to a single person doing
that term one discrete event one bid
when wallet one email and headers very
hard but being of the process over all
of it then patterns emerged that start
to be able to correlate back to an
individual that's why the historical
information important
the other thing is I'm more of a network
oriented guy again I don't really do
much endpoint stuff it's not as
interesting for me that's fine we all
have our preferences so when I first
started gathering this you know I focus
more on the sea to stop you know give me
the network indications because I know
what to do with that stuff but then
somehow space guys come on hey you know
what we can do IOC's we can we can use
this data in forensics or whatever and
some other pieces become more useful so
even then my particular use cases
shifted over time so I get a co-host
base IOC backtrace it all sorts of
interesting things you can do here so
most of these rats malware families have
you know they're free-form items
campaign I D past mutex registry keys
you know these tend to be the
interesting things to correlate offer
just doing you know basically you know
histogram statistical model another some
have authentication information thank
you very much
malware you know all of it can be
correlating to specific things for some
particular reason
criminals like using campaign IDs
containerized thanks I have no idea why
you would do that unless you're making
sure you change your campaign idea every
time but people do that so in the case
of dark comment right here is just wrong
counts campaign ideas that was seen just
16 get sixteen men the fall then you
have a whole bunch of other things
kurbaan you'll see a bunch of iterations
of that which is Turkish victim recalled
right there some Spanish stuff in there
occasionally have some things in Iraq so
you know you in that campaign and he
might tell me something about the
language somebody likes to speak not
enough to make a conclusion but it's
interesting you know I don't know many
people who have picked the Turkish
language to choose campaign ID's unless
you're familiar with Turkish language
but it could be somebody who's trying to
deceive but useful information
anybody does constitutional analysis
usually write the interesting data at
the margins the most frequent and the
least not so much in this particular
case was the most frequent going to fall
values the least frequent is going to be
a one-time observance and that doesn't
give you much like the interesting
correlations will be somewhere in the
middle and and we'll show you that you
know sometimes interesting names right
so this is for JSOC a java-based rat you
know discrete campaign ideas right and
obviously the one in Boulder someone
just looking at this and what's
interesting an obvious specific
reference August 21st to 24th fadely
seems familiar to me you know was there
a bombing on August 24
well in fact it was
right this this happened to be a
discrete terrorist event and aircraft
bombing in the Russian Federation 2004
alright so now this seems to be really
interesting so now let's just dig deeper
says I'm not correlate on anything any
JSOC it then with bombing the title I
met this probably not the most readable
slide but you'll see in bold the same c2
and then you see fresh underscore bomb
August bombing july first bombing 1st
July bombing August 24th bombing
September 30 same after you know and
then you know some iteration of bomb you
know in their title so looking a little
bit deeper right us- based see to an
aggressive you know after which is no I
P so you know nothing a typical there so
this is kind of a counter example of
correlation just because people like
making spurious correlations right and
that's the biggest outcome of big data
spurious spurious conclusions and that's
that's obviously sarcasm right you know
but despite the ominous name right this
individual just likes calling his his
attacks bombings right has nothing to do
and just happened to be you know I'd
coincidence
you know however you know if you're a
media media driven security researcher
you know you're gonna see this and you
gotta write a blog post about some you
know probably chechen dissident who is
running J socket and memorial
this bombing attack right you know but
being able to pull a backward shows that
that's pretty much crap
correlating with me taxes and we talked
about that a little bit now we're gonna
do in practice right interesting data is
in the middle right you know so this is
all of them right
1867 I think that's just one decoder
just has everything a mutex Pune many
CDC underscore mutex dash and a random
77 character alphanumeric string right
you press and the dark comedy venue
pressroom randomized it regenerates that
72 strength so I just picked one of
those right 1 p.m. SPT not terribly
likely in the real world that you're
gonna find two separate individuals who
end up with the same attacks
theoretically possible but not probably
likely running back you know everything
that map to that mutex you know what are
common I see things that despite the
discrete IP addresses or host names you
know time for starting from July to
December so five months
uses all except in that one incident
right there in August all use the same
campaign idea of urs tsunami able to sit
there and take a look at an actress is
now I know where he's been for about
five months you know which is very
useful information because I might be
able to you know have a Boxee is
whatever grab it and then get some more
information but this is very useful now
I can see patterns of behavior which
gets you to analyzing adversary
capabilities and motivations because
one-time event doesn't give you a parent
is does nothing much to analyze except
the technical and a one-time of that
knowing this for instance I can start
manipulating this guy and then see how
he moves I can provoke him and see what
happens I can you know do network traces
are flows on those addresses and sees is
this just contain rising operations
whereas one set of victim talking here
one set of it to talking there you know
get a better understanding of exactly
what this person is doing right and
those dates
isn't you know it's just a date when the
bell were restricted to write this
probably coming from virustotal this
malware could be going out all the time
just because something is in July
doesn't mean that that malware is not
still in circulation so very interesting
things that you can do like some with
new taxes this next one to call the
Ashley Madison correlation password
correlation tracked by everybody
remembers him Ashley Madison Ashley
Madison half-right somebody sit there
and took a look at all the passwords in
the database and found that 400,000
female accounts were created by the same
for people because they all use the same
strong password right you know so you're
able to create people based on strong
password to tell everybody do a strong
password you know which is good for you
please do strong passwords but it also
becomes a unique identifier correlate
somebody even if everything else is
different
odds are the same person is not going to
have the same strong past work so in
this game is a funny thing for Ashley
Madison right you know 1 2008 Gmail
accounts which shouldn't be surprising
but we can do that also with this new at
this database could be some there's also
FTP user names and passwords some
malware families will have in essence of
password to authenticate client to
server so you can start using some of
that here is a case of you know
basically a royalist just pass word
count unique password councilman in the
database right so something's admin
administrator so even even hacker
criminals can't do good passwords that
pic something in here
version 2013 highly specific Middle
Atlas there so let's see you know bob's
are somebody's probably not going to put
that in there to individuals are going
to do that twice so your case points to
three different seats whose you know
samples man is one of the last one is in
hong kong actually yeah and the other
two are in hong kong so don't know too
much rice poison ivy so to rack don't
know too much else about that but
concurrent correlate things just based
on that password right so very
interesting things that you can do the
technique can also feed domain
generation algorithms right there's a
lot of malware out there right that used
eg ace and you know soon
a mathematical formula to create
pseudo-random host names to use of c2
communications so I usually based on
some cedar some set of inputs right so
you can process now we're just to get
that information and be able to pull
that out because in this case for 10
bucks the maybe a hundred hundred twenty
different sets seat information for tiny
banker to write so just being able to
keep track of that how that changes and
feed that into whatever you're doing in
in terms of surveillance different talk
entirely but you see here
top
CNC if you the first host name that it
uses see all these at the bottom and
then the seidman top ERC board so what
those three things given 10 but DGA
script which is I'm getting downvoted
you can now generate the domains for the
sample which might be all that you need
for coming back now all this generally I
should say not all of it about
two-thirds of it use DNS right for c2
communication right now my dad is biased
heavily towards rats for now so that
affects you know the reliability of that
data right a lot of people say hey
listen I've got a database of 400,000
configurations here come by it well
those hundred thousand configurations
can be complete crap so what this shows
you right here is that you know the
biggest percentage roughly sixty some
odd percent of DNS information in those
configurations is an ex domain does not
resolve which means I'm so anyone
indicator that is no use to you you know
now we'll talk about that that's that
you know there is there is reason to
keep that around but I but in the
present point in time it is useless
information right there's always a next
big chunk RFC 1918 addresses could be
testing could be something else will
talk about that specific case in a
second and then 0000 right which is when
no ip suspends a suspends one of their
host names they pointed to Quad zeros
are not just what they do so
a fair bit of these were already
suspended by suspended by the provider
so most rats right certainly
historically or not no longer actively
resolving now you could use passive DNS
or some other techniques to figure out
where those who are that's useful for
investigative purposes but passive DNS
does miss quite a bit right just cover
rush a quiz about 25% of the host names
and I saw Miller configurations we were
not caught by passive DNS not entirely
scientific because I kept running
against maybe I'll admit they kept
shutting down but the other key point to
remember this is just something because
because something is an ex domain or
something
resolves to 1918 space doesn't mean it's
not still militias right DNS is under
control of the adversary for their names
of their domains they can do what they
want
many sophisticated attackers up to and
including intelligence agencies get that
they don't need to have their si toos up
24 7 365 they only need their seat is up
to the 15 or 30 minutes at their
operational so we'll have it resolved
the malware happily beacons out for 30
minutes while they're doing whatever
operational goals that they're doing and
then they're done and they turn it off
so it's just because something is an ex
domain doesn't mean it's useless useless
it just means it's not valuable
information right now so still keeping
that around and possibly resolving it
every now and then to see if it changes
and track that is is very important
information certainly get to those times
when they are operational and now I know
where they live and the other thing to
keep that host hostname around us to the
thing to bear in mind is that most rap
protocols don't have hostname in the
header they're not HTTP days so you
still have to do something with those
host names to make that into a network
detectable item so you know where the
rats live in terms of a weird to see
Tues live right is a top cities top
countries right and if you're an
unsophisticated venture capital fund
intelligence from you gonna say hey look
the FSB has internet business you know
it's it's the most common second most
common country you know Cairo Egypt
Istanbul we saw the Turkish stuff before
baghdad
you know interesting stuff maybe its
Isis whatever no no not really you know
it's time for your trip but Jack White
just because something is somewhere
doesn't mean a country is behind it
which is the biggest source of all of
these over-hyped news articles that we
see you know there's there's a malware
seats who in russia that means the
Russian government shutdown this
powerplant cool story bro so yeah if you
do that just stop just stop I'm tired of
figuring out why the way these stories
are crap so he point correlation is not
causation you know just because
something happens to be russia doesn't
mean russia's involved with it but again
to keep in mind almost all of the data
in security investigations is generally
under the control of the attacker who
has the ability and means to deceive you
DNS is a great example you know for all
of these hutus i think is the first
example right is a malware configuration
dot com
third line to the top probably can see
if the domain the seats who is quite 888
how many people here think that Google
is in running a dark comedy too I think
if I Google doesn't need to run iraq
walks right
you know they have it all you know so
you know this is somebody
testing something screen with data you
know a subset of attackers who do know
we mind virustotal we do know we mind
DNS indicators actively tried to poison
that information on another aspect of
what I do is DGA surveillance to resolve
all the domains and active DGAC I've
seen people put quite a tener the
adversary himself resolve it the quality
and I got a call I'm using your IP list
and will block in Google why you doin
man stopped you know before no I'm not
gonna create a white list of IP
addresses to DNS reservist in there just
because that would be very very
destructive but no I'm not gonna get the
business of waitlists just because
something points in there that there's a
member configuration doesn't mean it out
some other thing has to be done with it
right so attackers know we're doing this
they throw money in the water we talked
about the DGA stuff but attackers could
have easily submit stuff and he GNE do
so all the time and just because a seat
in a given country or whatever doesn't
mean anything in and of itself it is a
data point that is not sufficient to go
to the analysis so example 273 makes two
colors their public and if you look at
all those records are public out there
has 141 forge a socket that particular
actor knew that Kevin bring was writing
a decoder forge a socket so he would
change the encryption key then encrypts
the dropper that
is sent out from the builders he changed
the password is changed to Kevin
bringing is the game right so
intentionally trying to change something
but also intentionally knowing what
we're doing right that's just an example
is that what we do is public right the
attackers can operate in pipe private
but generally we're making products are
doing something almost everything that
we do is public and the attackers
response talked a little bit about this
DNS resolution point in time
some tankers will resolve when actively
in operation and point them elsewhere
when not in use right and they could
point to quite soon just to get somebody
say you know what I'm not looking at
this skunk binary whatever know it
actually could be something so being
mindful of bad in the data right now
there's edged cases right so gripped
along right has configuration it's
ransomware but their configuration
contains a list of compromised websites
and have PHP files that begin the
process of getting encryption key to
encrypt data on Invicta machines right
so you could block over this compromise
sites that that's not a bad option I
don't know particularly good one this
compromise sites are probably blocking
potentially valid use right and it's not
just click the wall that uses
compromised sites in doing stuff or for
that matter you know how many times has
a delivery networks served up
wishes / block New York Times because
they they do
interstitial ads that may or may not be
compromised so you know maybe a block it
maybe you don't write a similar problem
with worthless based eta is where you
know they used the Declaration of
Independence to create a hostname
you know those may have interesting
collisions with real stuff for one of
the domains generated by Rob next couple
of months ago was independence dot com
that's not a malicious site that's a
thing right
it just so happens to collision with
reality and then last in which is really
interesting right there is a small
subset of now where that uses basically
in coded IP addresses what I mean by
that is something and DNS against you
and IP address and then some function
takes an IP address and converts it to
what it really should be so you may be
pointing to an IP address just doing DNS
resolution that says hey you know it's
195 whatever but really this is
processed inside the malware that
converts the DNS resolve IP address to
what actually the IP address should be
this all these interesting edge cases to
deal with you know using this also you
can sit there and look for si toos you
might not otherwise see my data relies
on otherwise getting there were two
processes you know but I don't have 100
percent disability right the more
targeted an attack is the likelihood of
me seeing that anybody seen it drops off
significantly so you can use so many
strains to use run-ins showdown to find
seats who's right so a search here a
couple of drinks and then you start
finding put 1604 which is the default
are common part but it can be anything
you want so showdown can find some of
these heat Tuesday didn't start adding
to your own data and there's also some
parts of data that are in the
configuration itself that also might be
of interest so in a case of SSL
Certificates J socket for instance the
the builder the builder also doubles as
a controller and it is all over SSL
which all builders have the same SSL
certificate because it's just built in
it doesn't randomly generated so pulling
that out
can give you some interesting
information right so first you know
you've got necessary that she knows no
malicious anytime you see that certainly
handshake you know you've got a problem
ok that's certainly a viable you can
also do some searching with a showdown
but
it's not working quite right yet but
it's an interesting thing with the issue
of the silliest right
oddly specific thing you know french
organization the silliest thing the
silliest right it's oddly specific of
something that doesn't look so I google
it goes to this blog post of somebody
who talks about how to create but it's
just a job hippie store thing which is
how to create input in SLC SSL
certificate and a job a keystore and Jay
socket uses that certificate to make
sure no man in the middle work because
if it gets a certificate doesn't expect
it then it just drops the connection so
the author Jay socket use this blog post
specifically follow these instructions
up to and including the issuer name and
country for awhile he even used the same
password that was in that blog post of
storms pass he was smart enough to
realize that that was a bad life
decision and change that you know but I
can try the blog post he was using for
instructions so I said
some families some families of rats and
malware also use apks apks have to be
signed so those signing certificates
then become useful stuff to go find
other things right
you know a lot of a lot of Android
malicious apps I mean it's kind of
tricking people outside the App Store
but there is a fair bit of malicious
apps that still make it into the App
Store and now if I'm able to sit and
observe hey this builder bill to this
you know this
apk signing certificate now I can go
hunting the App Store not only Google's
but some of the other third-party app
stores and they'll find related malware
right and in hundreds and thousands but
certainly in the hundreds of cases you
know we'd we found malware in the stores
just by doing significant correlation
yeah so this for jason has an Android
park part of it right so this the
details for its builder what was most
interesting out of this and why I think
Google should have called it on their
own right
some third party in AU writer for
Android is not gonna have or as a sign
in as the issuer for a signing
certificate that ought to be something
that's caught and the other thing is
there is actually a Cincinnati work done
or was about a hundred years ago now is
known as y'all are something like that
so but it's certainly not in the
European Union all of that is invalid
right it was even skipped past your
ballpark you know state or again
country-code European Union I'm sure the
search engine of the world could manage
to figure out that piece of data just a
thought so what's next I said all this
DNS stuff this point in time so there
needs to be something on the front end
or something on the back and that takes
a look at that information to do some
kind of validation right if somebody
isn't hell bent on creating firewall
rules right
resolve all this stuff get its IP
addresses all the continually if it
doesn't resolve find drop it and then
just to kind of us in JFK has put 1604
open on 889 890 Google doesn't read our
comment so that should come back to get
you some basic information with which to
us now I can at least create a
relatively high confidence fire will set
but still take additional scrutiny on
tape or 25 and 80 and 443 a small
handful number of ports you know but if
the ports open the IP to DNS resolves
nine-page firewall rules you know and
and and start getting to operationalize
in it I wanna get to a point processing
historic 18 months right now but going
back you know fire still has a huge
datasets Microsoft anybody who has won
right I thought I'd love to run my stuff
over to get into the databases and
eventually I will share this out with
missed so pay attention for that we will
give this back to the community I do
work for security company but this is
something here everybody here is a great
intelligence tool have fun with it and
tell us tell us what you can do I said
said you know my long-term goal is to
burn incense all the things I can't shut
shut things down and put somebody in
prison and sinkhole it and start trying
to clean up coming to see junior you
will be Bullet Bill anytime hulaville
so final point we are hiring you know
I've got three or four openings at the
center of the day so if you're looking
if you like this stuff by means get in
touch you wanna share malware otherwise
work on any other things I'm interested
in do dat das however an somewhere you
know come find me and let's burn things
thanks everybody who's helped with this
my team in particular any questions yes
this this is just a domain the question
was whether any DJs DJs part of this DNS
resolution so let me answer is No
this is this is just a static stuff for
DJs if you like I was saying if you
strip out sinkholes it's like 99% 98 99
percent and you know the biggest the
biggest registrant of DGA domains
security companies and other questions
true
the question is how have I used sponsor
and analysis to correlate whether a
given host name as a DGA there are
people who have done that the problem
comes into his first two problems money
is the only Latin I used non Latin
language host names that make sense
right you know somebody translating
China Chinese into last night for domain
name you tend to get some weirdness
there but the biggest problem with that
is yeah I can be fairly confident tell
you somethings the DGA
domain but mapping that back in reverse
engineering it into an algorithm to go
to a family is where things get
difficult because our kind of flexible
classification of EEG aces character set
thanks to oldies we don't have much else
to work with you so
there's there needs to be more work on
that particular piece that makes sense
there was another question this general
regional daughter and other hand
let me off easy nobody wants to throw
anything at me the side YouTube yes
what about miss attribution and nation
states who are trying to mimic other
entities our nation states to create
geopolitical tom foolery right why
policy using the stuff in and of itself
there has to be more analysis done to
really call it intelligence but this is
this is this is Dana I mean you can make
some intelligence conclusions and some
cases but yeah if I were if I were the
CIA or the NSA yeah I'd be making people
think I was China all day long
somebody else oh absolutely intelligence
agents will do that but that takes data
and a human spending time to figure it
out because eventually given enough data
enough observable events you can start
saying well that doesn't really matter
to what they ought to be doing if i were
intelligence agency and an error and
seeing that the max on anybody else
Bayesian analysis where you may believe
something as malware but don't know they
can do that I don't know if I have a
long enough data set where where that
would yield as much fruit but but yeah I
mean if I get ten years of malware then
yet and we're talking Bayesian and other
really really neat things
anybody else or another question
all right thank you