well over a decade
some of the recent research but a lot of
the stuff I have here goes back over 10
years another contribution to an outline
of what I'll be talking about for the
rest of the talk will talk a little bit
about bug hunting look at the internals
of free artisan like we did he get some
contacts will talk about stack smashing
in practice also talking some other bugs
and I'll go through an example of
authorization issues are vendors are
being back doors into the system's
overall you know but I wasn't focused on
the research I was restricting my focus
to memory corruption only and as I
mentioned developers everything from the
west to the application in C
really expecting usual in my case I
started by auden whenever I get my hands
on it so there's a lot of their so look
at our top lightweight AP particular as
receives there are costs lots of
contributed servers are likely to
constrain and so on
bugs are you as well as causing honestly
some of the most serious
possibly a lot of course we are
constantly I did finally said
contributed servers SDKs and in
particular as per seats Internet of
Things so far disclosed something like
nineteen and even fixed which is great I
have had problems disclosing and I've
playing or crashes
bugs are hard just to give you an
example of the kind of talking about
this is in misperceived international
spot warm built on top of screen artists
and what they have is a client that runs
and communicated with a cloud server and
what it will do is send request up to
this that they control and process
responses use their cards are too like
managed by so quickly as possible
reading on skype yet so we look at this
boat is doing is our CDs and officially
takes on line 226 everything between
the nonce to Jason attribute and the
comma phone calls on the staff does so
we can impersonate the server compromise
it then we can execute code to talk to
and as it turns out dude other
vulnerabilities
64 corruption despite a web server the
lessons and we are seeing you all what
it does is basically copied everything
between you and HTTP requests into this
year old friend instruction that out so
it's really easy to any oversight is one
example of how
server so really the nineties never and
these are
it's clear that these are new and in
space you know memory corruption is
really easy burglars introduced
developers that are you know parsing
requests and responses by hand handling
requests for Android application and so
on you know request that violate
standards that don't intentionally
trigger immigration issues and manners
are always helping so for example on
scene as he gazed at disabled yup
debugging assertions that actually
perform security function or include
updated versions of libraries so we
won't understand you know what's
happening under the hood in the context
of three artists were triggering one of
these blogs and I'm really decide if
these bugs are exploitable in the
context of three artists in order to put
the bugs in context will look more at
the internals of us so it's a real time
operating system is made by a company
based on the UK called real-time
engineer's has been in development for
over a decade and it's a really low s
what it gives you is task creation
tasking process and management
inter-process communication using to use
some of wars in new taxes for
synchronization did you hit them
multiple implementations for memory
management and broad strokes that's
really about it doesn't have to say your
YouTube user doesn't mandate the use of
a particular tcp/ip implementation you
can use different implementations with
it so it's really grew for you know
putting together a system and as a
result it's quite tiny I mean it weighs
in at under twenty thousand lines of C
you can order to a new platform in under
a thousand lines of C and assembly and
in terms of the memory footprint you can
run it in under a cave memories so this
can run really constrained platforms
which is great and I think it's been so
successful in caen porting to so many
platforms lightweight I P it's a really
popular embedded tcp/ip stack was
originally written by Adam jungles and
disliking particular supports a lot of
different protocols including SNMP DNS
and so on and includes a lot of
contributed servers web servers DNS
servers and so on and you'll also find
that a lot of you know commercial and
obvious developers develop a lot of
service to take advantage of the data
footprint in context and can you can you
read the ok so we look at this picture
on the left here we have the knack for a
separate assets running on three artists
and on the right there's the system he
and all tasks as well as the colonel
share a single keep our costs and
there's also statically allocated buffer
down in the bottom right and if you look
at the test accuracy that it's going
downwards d the functions currently
executing his part euro and it was
called by process request so we know
that this task is it's reacting some
data coming over the network and has a
couple different kinds of data that is
using the process request function has
allocated 40 bytes we see this red chunk
on the heat
has been allocated by that task there
there's a pointer to this article
allocated buffer user agent last user
agent and parts URL has allocated an
array on D one stack if you look over
the heap we see that that chunk that's
been allocated has better than includes
pointers next chunk in this case is no
because it's been allocated and also
includes the size which is 48 bytes
being a place for the header and then 40
bytes for the data that was allocated
and there's also an orange chunk and and
this is memory that's been allocated by
another task in the system and we can
see that the free chunks there are
arranged in a singly linked list so the
memory manager can find free memory when
tasks requested so we've already
mentioned some of the key data
structures here we saw the task have a
thick stack region that allocated
actually on the system he was addressing
because it combines the settings for
stack and heap overflows in this context
talk about the scheduler the schedule
maintains multiple lists that he uses to
decide what asked ron was already list
of suspended tasks was to be terminated
tasks that need to be cleaned up and
when the scheduler is doing with these
tasks it maintains metadata for an
executing task in a task control blocker
TCB and when the scheduler is actually
went when a task is running the
scheduler will set a pointer to the GCB
of the currently executing task
antes de Weert saw that there's a a
single system heat that shared by all
tasks and the colonel and lightweight I
P also maintains its own seat where
allocates memory for inbound packet data
data structures for tracking network
connections and so on and there's also a
system stack and that's the stack that's
used when the system initially boots
that's the stock were that's where the
main functions stack frame lives for
example and that's also used by
interrupt handler
so we mention the schedule a little bit
about context switching real systems
they're always going to have multiple
tasks at the very least we're gonna have
a server network thread that's
communicating with the network and
always has an idle task that runs when
no other tasks are able to execute and
scheduler handles context switching and
when it's switching contacts between
tasks what it will do is first of all
the register state for the executing
task including the program counter and
pushes it onto the stack for that task
and then it updates the TCB to keep
track of ok where is the top of the
stack for this task now after I pushed
all the execution state onto it and then
it kicks ass to run and the reverse
process it restores the state including
the program counter offer that a stack
and then what citron so to see this
visually here again we have this example
of the Asura task and executing parse
URL if you look over to the right
there's the TCB for this task and you
know we can quickly go through the
entries in this TV so the first entry is
tracking the top of the stack and she
disappointing actually into the middle
of the stock for this task and that's
the value that was the top of stack when
the task is scheduled for since then the
stock has grown there's list the
scheduler uses 24 entries that the
scheduler uses to track information
about the task in various lists a
priority and extract which that's the
beginning of this tax the region of
memory continuous tastic in memory or
you could think of it as the women for
for this for the stack for this task on
their last name
of these priority that's also used for
scheduling and a runtime counter that's
used for tracking performance statistics
Dr context switching it happened we see
that we've pushed all the the execution
state of the task onto the stack updated
top with top of the stack so the
scheduler knows where where the state of
lives and the runtime counter has also
changed because additional tax talk
about the artists like we saw that three
times are organized a single so less
efficient find regional peace in Sri
Lanka starting the Legion strange ones
each memory socket her stint in size
next chance and uses first outpatient
strategy so it walks you find that the
next and also as the unused part of that
show back in 20 write a new check into
the unused portion and good music and
memories 34 for most of the season
johnson said he got two adjacent regions
supports multiple API's programmers need
to be the last there's the neck on media
and I mentioned earlier it's very simple
the way works has been driven clinton's
registers registered handler that's all
no relevance occur for argument sake and
in the case of UDP and where the
signature of the function looks like
this and if you look at the third
argument is a pointer to people that
actually allows landlords to access so
that's how we actually did as I
mentioned like a manager and he lets us
has some features that when I first
heard about them I thought ok maybe this
is some sort of explanation one of the
things that supports his stack overflow
detection ok some kind of Canary carry
implementation it turns out it doesn't
have service security purpose the system
will halt if it detects Stack Overflow
and it's not meant to detect overflow
offers that have been allocated on the
stack the way it works says if we look
here we have the stack region for a task
is going downwards and the scheduler
will perform up to two chaps after a
task has been suspended
check of the stack pointer has gone
beyond the beginning of that stock
region in memory limit of the stack we
can see that on the bottom it's seen as
you know stack pointer points beyond
that limit and also writes a kind of a
canary value at the beginning of this
memory region and will compare that to
expected sequence of bytes to see if it
was overridden at some point if the
stock grew into this canary area while
the task was executing so we see if we
were if we were able to overflow a stack
allocated buffer somewhere in the middle
of this tax will be riding towards
higher dresses in neither of these
checks were detected so it's not doesn't
give us doesn't buy anything in terms of
security I mention a few artists
supports the MPU
John cortex m3 and what this allows you
to do is you can create restricted tasks
and define memory regions up to three as
well as the the stock for that
particular task and then few ensures
that the task can only write to those
memory regions the OS doesn't implement
any controls to prevent restricted task
from reading a regular task so you know
restricted tasks
restricted task you could ask escalate
privileges by creating a privilege task
and doing the rest of what everyone is
doing at that point so the MPU support
its really intended to protect those on
system system and its not review
security concerns so so we've seen some
bugs and now they have some sense of the
internals of the operating system I'm
sure a lot of guys are already trying to
connect the two so somehow I think like
an attacker will talk about 10 bilities
and specifically focused on stack buffer
overflows because they tend to be common
in the code bases when you're reviewing
source code and you spot a potential bug
it's only the first step at that point
you need to investigate and in practice
that means deploying these offer on real
hardware developing payloads and see if
you could trigger the vulnerability
remotely and in my case I need a lot of
hardware in the process
see some of it in the picture here and
yeah it's it's tough to type in terms of
hardware that work particularly well for
me these samples
with the same i GTG blogger really work
well to build software using gcc
GDP I really didn't have to rely on each
60 site deal next year's pages 86 ed
with the secretary lynn pictures here
allows you to detail but a warning when
one student said it's very painful to
see ya so
proposals are now that we know a little
bit more about internal operating system
we know that we're redirecting execution
in the context Stack Overflow that's
happening that's happening in the
context of the task and we see on the
right here to function of a long now
work is going to turn dressed and ready
to execute with you know unlike simpler
embedded systems that asked that the
task of Honor bility has dedicated staff
so that stock isn't being shared by
interrupt handlers so we have sort of an
undisturbed space for exploitation I
wasn't sure if this is the case but
probably not surprised scheduler eats
everything running alone execute so you
know I'm asking robert is actually sweet
asian and pacific me an army can put the
people that were executing anywhere
beyond a stock but it can also be
elsewhere in memory because the system
and everything is executed
so the problem we're trying to solve you
know now that we have the ability to
execute payload in practice the appeal
is going to be quite small
you know it's going to be subject to the
limits of the particular vulnerability
and we're looking at and we want full
remote code execution we really want to
demonstrate that this is a serious issue
so there's two general questions that we
have to answer that one always has to
answer in this context is one where we
gonna redirect execution and with three
artists in particular we need to clean
things up when you're done we need to
make sure that the task that's being
exploited keeps functioning and the
reason is that task for example could be
the thread that handles network
communication so that has doesn't
survive then the system is inaccessible
anymore but in practice in either of
these things are hard so we'll talk
about execution redirection first and
simplest solution can often work in
artists are generally allocated when the
system starts and dole in a case to be
allocated unknown location if you're
creating cast dynamically and it's being
out in the heat then you may not know
where that stack region falls for the
task but that's right much rarer in
practice these tasks are generally
created right when the system starts up
so we know exactly where the stock for a
given task will fall in memory and
furthermore for looking at other bility
because these systems are simpler we
also know exactly where r inbound
payload where the data from the request
that's actually triggering the ball
lives on that staff so
inaccurate me know exact address and
execute a situation where we don't know
exactly where the deal is unstoppable
multiple firmware version has multiple
code past we still have a window
dressing is quite small
where we know the feelin so no need to
budget ninety style will not slip
something like that
assuming the architecture allows iraq
has a better approach in a lot of
situations in practice and we have a
register that you know references that
imbalance payload that triggered the
vulnerability then we can use dropped to
manipulate the register
led addressing the register and then
call it so then we don't have to make
assumptions or reason about where that
people's lives in memory is just a side
effect of that it contains a reference
to be mentioning robbins because we're
not trying to buy passing on the
stacking certainly we use dropped
because the gadget addresses are
predictable in cases where he appealed
against me were using rock we can
trampoline to argue that you can even
use
iraqis him to perform their hits and
we'll see an example gives us some other
options
get some help from the operating system
we have some specific actions codes for
free or other uses static
Ltd such as a little more so that gives
us additional locations where we may be
able to the data and in some cases even
overflow them so this is an overflow of
these people crammed statically out each
structure and you see here we cannot
overwrite mean weight second and so we
have the 360 and overwriting them
doesn't doesn't also little bit
troubling we can write right into the
heat but in practice it can be hard to
take advantage of that but this is one
of the other vulnerabilities that I just
closed also mentioned we talked about
lightweight IDE having its own memory
manager you look at driver
implementations or three are constantly
way you'll see that rain buffers are
used in all our key when school starts
the sequence of regions of memories
restoring inbound
dreams and these are also falls on
predictable sequence driver specific but
if you look at how these these addresses
tend to be predictable so we can do kind
of very end of spring we just send lots
of traffic to the device and thought
this buffer
and then jumped you a Merry option if
nothing else as possible and other
clients are communicating with the
device then this may not be successful
the time just mentioned it as an option
when nothing else works sorry there were
really have a lot of possibilities over
200 I can't imagine situation where you
wouldn't be able to take advantage of
the attacker the other question here is
what we gonna do when we're done we
don't want to break the target asked his
thread and we need to be able to
continue communicating with the device
in a practice room not only overriding a
return address but were blowing away
register that were preserved for the
caller of the function that has the
vulnerability you can spend a lot of
time on piecing together not only a safe
place to return when you're done with
expedition but also safe values for
those registers that you blew away and
because the systems are simpler that's
probably gonna work out for you but
there is a better solution that is just
to effectively restart the task and in
case of lightweight I P we're talking
about like when I P with callbacks you
can restart the tcp/ip threaten to
return to the entry point for that task
function and this is using a reference
to statically allocated data structure
so it just keeps functioning there's no
disruption in network indications this
this is gonna memory intermediate
functions allocated memory gonna know
where that is not going to be able to
free it and you want to unroll the stack
when you do this as it would be unrolled
when you first started task but this
works in practice
I'll briefly mention other bug classes
we are he saw a static buffer overflow
and the impact you know in a case it's
going to depend on what falls after that
started before and we saw we can right
into the deep so you know why that's
troubling in practice and when I looked
at it really easy to get a job so I
thought still a good place to the deal
it's a really interesting topic but in
the interest of time he joins us in my
case don't know haven't worked out all
looking example and ends in this context
so in terms of our objectives in this
example shows an overflowing call that
country artists on an ARM Cortex and
we're gonna go from executing a small
stature in the original request or
nearby to be able to execute arbitrary
code and our goal here is not to
destabilize the system
target servers and we're going to use
the facilities to see so this allows us
to not write a lot of cool cheap to give
you an outline of the approach will
exploit the vulnerability to get code
execution and we're gonna executed
staging
staging Taylor right second stage alone
somewhere
area memory where we'll start then we
need to hook into the system still a
network of the same ones
and a call back and listen and execute
and I'll turn you for that particular
bond mentioned earlier and that is in
practice registered references are we
look at our 10 bytes in size in its
battle with and the bites a follower
actually so instead of hard coating the
address of trying to reason with or not
that's a reliable waging what we want to
do is used to branch to the address
unfortunately on the ARM Cortex you'll
see today so we're adding horror to walk
past the size and also have to add one
that's because the leasing addresses
names inside for branching always has to
be said and that's actually really
aspect of the cortex and I'm like or
text me or you can simply gadget
branches in stock corner when you're
both their first ever register were
using so it gets a little more
complicated so what we'll do is we're
going to use dropped to 22 are arrested
and then branch and for this particular
vulnerability it also turns out that it
didn't have a lot of space to work with
I only had forty eight bytes to build
this change while the dresses so
constrained in terms of size after we
just rock scene and executed restart
deep breath a little more detail as I
said we want to make our 1428 increment
and then branch to the system image
around campaign so much from you but I'm
surprised there are no god but as always
the way we get there is no
straightforward so far so there wasn't a
simple gadget just a movie I want to
take advantage of these gadgets looking
for the last four gadgets to were using
here that are adding orator 290 which
contains an artist I wanted to get some
of the few gadgets like now that would
actually climb wasn't so the first step
was one in his first three gadgets and
and actually required to register as it
should say so what's the register has
been moved into our two things get
simpler and we can use the the Ghajini
the second section to add more to it and
then were able to branch to branch into
our payload then we perform the rest of
the expectation
so this solve the first problem in a
general way and I were able to execute
our stager but we need to write the code
for a call back that's also part of a
robust somewhere in memory where it's
not going to be disturbed and we can use
mine copy to do this to the OS's makes
it easy and there's there's more than
one place where you can put it on my
trip was to put it past the end of the
systems that before so this is unused
real memory where nothing will touch it
we could allocate memory in the store
there and also would be disturbed
we use lightweight I peacekeepers while
allocating memory there and we can even
put it in the stack of the exploited a
so that's the beginning of the stock in
memory that limit next act if we know
that that has doesn't get close to that
then we also have some space where we
could put in there might be more useful
in cases are you using the MPU and you
can if you need someplace to put it I
should mention on their X 1066 X we have
fewer options that requires that being
executed called instruction RAM so in
that case we need to put this out there
and use rock before we can hook it into
the operating system
so what we've written somewhere in
memory we need to wire it in comics are
the simplest way to do this and it's
ideal because we're not going to
interfere with scheduling of any tasks
we're not gonna starve other cast in the
system we don't need to think about the
problem of starvation so it makes it
really simple in the case of you P it's
really only three calls so we create a
protocol block for UDP we find he's
really what wires all that we see in
this town like we did when we have three
calls function at this allows us to run
and you can also do this is now
connection just chose this particular
example but we do have alternatives
because call ducks aren't always
supported depends on how the the the
firmware for the system has been built
so called on an option we can create a
home task and once again the operating
system makes it simple so we can create
and in a case are payload would have to
do a little more work to you know set up
a worsening socket connection but at
that point we have attached schedule
then run that actually execute the code
in this case starvation is a
consideration the schedules always gonna
run the next available task that has the
highest priority so we need to consider
starvation and in practice that means
making the task block for a while as a
while because you need the particular
system
yeah conceptually this isn't too
different from the calls were using
listen for incoming packets and execute
them so he has are seeing something
small that wires to be able to text you
whenever we don't wanna run just need
traffic that his device so we need to
mark are packaged in some way and the
simple way to do this is just that
indicates to the NBC 8 2012 callback
season has this magic and again on the X
16 because we can execute and certain
region and we have forced
which implement more complicated logic
meet you in the code so we need sequence
numbers or something
execution and and require the subsequent
pack was gonna allow us to larger
islands and implementation can be quite
small so here's the instructions just to
give you an example and I pulled this
off my system so we can see that this is
Ryan passes stock systems technology
which is Jul 01 so real so the first
thing you are magic and we put that into
another package and the instructions of
person that does deserve our three
in-store the return address
and then we access our to that second or
third party which is a pointer to the
packet access deep the payload pointer
there actually and the next step
instructions this is a logical is really
happened so the first thing we do is
read them from from the beginning
regions were reading from 2011 starring
Irwan we then read and we also
increments are zero byte files are ready
to branch to the magic destruction there
is doing a comparison to see those not
otherwise see 20 that's gonna actually
executed and then there's clean up their
stores 5 instructions at the end that
actually before so we get back on
pointer to pee wee construct the address
of people 341 have to do that too big to
do anything or instruction and we
actually very good citizens here and
once you're done freeing the package
then we return and we can go on so what
can we do with this is not leavin system
memory so around after the three cents
but we can write a blast in a permanent
but the fact is gonna resent
news only because there won't be any
evidence of cancer in traffic and go but
conclusions and recommendations
it's hard not to be a little pessimistic
here in 2016 here we are telling
developers that they need to manage
memories safely in C and like I said
there's an astonishing amount of code
for our toss one platform but at least
half a dozen other platforms have
developers actively writing code in C so
we're looking at many more years of
memory corruption for these softer and
because these devices are softer it's
important to isolate them you don't
wanna have them co-existing with more
sensitive systems put them on their own
part of the network security
professionals we need to raise awareness
make sure that people understand the
consequences of bugs like these
catastrophic we need to audit this
technology and and help people fix them
and they get pics and there's an
opportunity for vendors to implement
additional protections for these
embedded systems with three artists we
saw having canaries her integrity checks
taking advantage of executables memory
support it and randomizing Liana memory
these would be fantastic things that
would make an attacker's job harder and
the operating system is open source so
any one of us could do this too
so conclusions I mentioned there is
easily a dozen other platforms out there
more tcp/ip implementations for anyone
who's interested so I encourage people
just to see what's out there and try to
have only scratched the surface of the
one of six and eight years Phu 66 hinted
at it briefly in the talk there's
additional challenges when it comes to
their future is really interesting and
I'm planning a white paper so far in
there and talk to me after the talk if
you're curious people to think of us
from NCC group he suggested area got me
interested in this research Stevan
Ridley and Steven Lawler have an
excellent training found that part of
the talking to check out that training
all the reference research and
definitely anyone and folks who reviewed
the talk with me and give me feedback
and organizers for putting the plan
together and most of all thanks everyone
for coming
and that's actually a few minutes for
questions which questions
so we don't need to I ram it simply
don't have to call ya in the first half
before you actually magic value matches
copy it over and execute
it's hard as you can so so it would be
emulating an ARM platform so so that
handy but in terms of the funding that's
that's one hurdle that you're gonna he
added that if you're looking at software
for MIPS or four the SP 8266 there
really isn't there is an alternative but
for the SBA 266 there's no alternative
and the other thing is that because it's
sensitive to memory layout and so on
you made your investigation in an
unrelated environment and then find the
details are different so there's a
tradeoff there but yet you would be the
way to go
and definitely hit me up if you wanted
him