I am remind you of the contest that are
going on
everyone if you can go actual a quick
wizard one because it's blocking
blindfolded and there's the I think that
their headquarters just started and the
forces capture the flag even for not
participating these are fun to watch and
if you if you have never participated
into a contest before it's a great way
to meet people and to get become part of
a community of your new so I i strongly
recommended
teams are often set up in advance but
they're frequently take new members or
they just want honestly other things are
remember that there's a party tonight
and it will be here and other than that
I'd like to introduce our speaker this
is Balint and he got into radios because
his grandfather was one of the Lancaster
bombers unit in world war two and had an
entire collection of of these radios
which was lucky enough to inherit and
apparently he inherited the gene to work
with them as well and he's going to tell
us about this latest advances so please
welcome speaker
thank you thank you thanks for coming
along
icelandic up along today I wanted to
give you an update on some interesting
things happening in the AM radio LSD I
will maybe give him a lot
give you a bit of inspiration signals
that you can explore or tools and
techniques that you can use to do your
own sort of inquiry because there are
just so many signals out there it's
impossible to cover them all but you
love it so to begin with this anybody
have any ideas what part of the spectrum
of looking at here we gotta hand in the
front row what do you think
900 megahertz I same band is correct
that's absolutely correct and it's an
incredibly crowded and busy part of the
spectrum just like 2.4 gigahertz this is
down 900 megahertz so you get much
better propagation but it's very busy
because some license so today we're
gonna look at the IRA spectrum various
parts of it but an update on aviation
and looking looking above to get signals
relate to that
doing sort of levels of violence using
drones with FDR and signals so I tried
to do some demos as we go through out of
the demagogues with a couple of things
here and the vast majority stuff and get
you can have a show of hands who's
actually used for testing and some sort
of software-defined radio RTL ok so
actually the 2.4 gigahertz I sent that I
like to show this one who can tell me
what sort of signals were actually seen
here you had to turn scholar someone
else I show you know wifi is one of them
was another one that's actually do when
I was out the egg the microwave
microwave in the kitchen when you turn
around actually change frequency
slightly you can see those coastlines
there that's actually the megatrends
side microbes if you're ever in two
point for somebody's operating a
microwave and I should also mention that
those peaks here the narrow ones can
anybody get what that is
bluetooth is out to the correct yes
there are many more channels but they're
all know
and the tool he had run-ins called for
it can be used with you radio and it's a
really slick way of looking at the radio
spectrum and accelerate this computation
using your GPU it's always nice to sort
of look at a pic of public radio
spectrum you're restricted too often
just the bandwidth of your device and
then also the transport that it uses to
connect to the computer audio so for
example let's say you take the USR P B
210 thats usb3 it can do up to just over
fifty megahertz worth of instantaneous
bandwidth your computer then gives you
50 megahertz in this so much for the
spectrum to actually explode wouldn't it
be cool if you can actually visualize a
much larger portion of the spectrum
maybe not quite in real time as you
would expect with say just a single
channel but this here is actually a
continuous sort of plot from fifty
megahertz to 1.25 gigahertz in Kenya
radio and the way that works is that you
can use some trickery of of some
hardware and actually uses
into 10 make next your computer by
Gigabit Ethernet
and what you can actually do then is
asking for some samples that it will
transfer over to you and then you tell
it to switch to another frequency and
you can tell it went to send the samples
and went to the center frequency so you
can do this in lockstep and you can do
it so quickly that will actually running
I don't know how much will actually see
inside here because we know cross have
let me within the space of two minutes
so I can guarantee him a trip she gonna
see here because we're inside I ever got
something so if you have a look this is
actually the current spectrum from 50
megawatts 1.25 regards 50 megawatts in
the bottom left hand corner and then
then that entire range sort of cut up
into three so that you can see them
stacked upon one another so the bottom
left is fifty it goes right to the right
when you go through the middle and then
you end up to 1.25 on the right hand
side of the very top 10 on the various
lower left you'll be able to see you
look really closely the FM band and a
whole bunch of other stuff all the
reactive stuff there is probably the
cellular network all the different
channels that particular in the upper
portion of that band that you can see
the top and some other stuff leaking in
but it's really cool wages to get a
quick sense of a very wide portion of
your fuel spectrum
so we said that 9:15 was really busy we
can actually see that every player
little video this is actually running a
little bit slower than it would this is
being visualized teasing a program
called board line whose board line yet I
highly recommend that you check it out
if you like to analyze signals both in
real time or if you record them and then
analyzed them offline after the fact
it's a really powerful visualization
tool and really allows you to to drill
down and see what's going on so you can
see there's lots of different things
going on
lot of narrowband signals just a couple
of wideband ones and then it's it's
interesting to see things like the mesh
networking of smart meters you
interesting turn signals pop up but also
you and you know rather simple
modulation schemes that you could
potentially decoding and attempt to
figure out what it is we have a
directional antenna you can make my
ground trying to fuck something so this
is sort of assumed that now you can see
there's lots and lots burst all over the
place a very common scheme that's used
to communicate here is called frequency
hopping so one particular radio 1
actually always transmitted on the one
frequency the entire band might be
divided up into say fifty channels
alrighty channels or something like that
and then every radio will know when to
listen at the right time on any
particular frequency within this band
and then you'll see sort of signals
hopping around and I'll come back to
that and show you how can actually be
realized that to see what the same
channel occupancy is moving along I just
recently switched to keynotes I'll I'm
just going to add in a good shooters
transition for texts every Sullivan
so aviation has always been very close
to my heart and testing want to have any
more volume on this so that's actually
the pulses from that right on this is a
primary sponsor on radar in a port and I
talked about this before but just to
recap of your seat sending out pulses
and that will echo off metallic few
slices of airplanes for example in the
contract them so that it doesn't have to
have any active equipment on board was
just a little gonna ready to receive
that what you can do it you can process
that Daddy can take an STR and just hold
it up in me in your radar record it and
then you can process that so that it's
synchronizes to the initial post of the
right out which is down the very left
hand side then and then every single
time as opposed to record for a while
and that makes up one online so the
actual post that comes out on the left
but everything else often left hand side
is actually energy received from the air
from that post reflecting off nearby
environment now remember this is just I
was just using mister Yahoo the weekend
and nothing fancy no directional antenna
nothing like that huge directions and
it's actually wrote any on the radio but
you can actually see that there are
these shapes coming out and if you
unwrap them onto the map this is in the
Bay Area put that on the rate of his
name a few little space you can actually
see that the right point sexually lineup
with structures in the basic but the
bridges you got the power lines that
cross the bay which forms part of these
nice lines and all the stuff is really
close to News
so you can do interesting stuff of
privacy fence right aircraft modern
aircraft had lots of antennas on there
so there are lots of
interesting singles to try to look for
and that are simple 731 rate is lots of
different things and that makes you
really happy and then you know who said
I S and 80 S B flooding that kind of
stuff you can do cool stuff like receive
the broadcast from planes and playing
and then actually put them live on the
map as they come to land in San
Francisco and I'll change color when the
nose get touches the tarmac and so on
just if you like planespotting it's it's
an exciting stuff you've only seen seen
this one thing I did a while back was
actually implement the system through
Google get this virtual cockpit views if
you were sitting in the pilot's seat so
that's actually plane taking off from
SFO and you can imagine what the views
like and then we'll swing around to the
to the north and you can see the city
that I just recently moved up to the
city myself from the South Bay and I got
myself all my equipment again I'm gonna
try to put it back on line and release
it was open source position in seeing
the collecting dust and another
interesting part of that whole aviation
system is a sign from actually tracking
planes they will broadcast obviously
that position in altitude and other
information like that is a car's it's
the eight aircraft communication
reporting system and this operates in
the aviation VHF band and is a digital
essentially text messaging for planes
for you know the control systems or to
talk to ATC pilots to talk to Alan ops 2
rolls-royce engines to report
performance data back to rolls-royce I'm
the planet to delete this global VHF
network and that can be visualized to
use the system originally from Sydney
and I have it set up back there and
every time a balloon pops up that's
actually a cause message being sent or
received to a particular aircraft so
special shows you what's going on with
interesting because you have lots of
messages about the toilets being clubbed
this is my favorite so I added that
little easter egg
that's reported and then also get why
points for the long haul flights and you
can see these ones going to the west
coast of Australia and then those going
into Asia them and that's so good that
uses the Treasurer networking and people
looking at that and you know that's one
part of the aviation mechanic anybody's
guess as to what we're actually looking
at here right
more specifically what this particular
angle this particular perspective it's
an Inmarsat its bleeding into the topic
but this is actually being coverage so
this particular satellite in the defeat
or or the public information that shows
you the coverage area of there being
that satellite's far away in and they
can hit this entire part of the planet
with their coverage so indeed three and
is made up of a fleet actually and there
are they have a whole bunch in
geostationary orbit around the planet to
give you quite considerable coverage of
the planet with different sorts of
beings and services so I was talking
about
VHF but there's also the Inmarsat
iridium consolation and they also
provide services for aircraft so
traditionally whatever land you might
use VHF because you probably have better
data comes in and say hi bandwidth but
if you're out of the ocean for example
you have the option of using second cold
AHS HDL which is pretty cool that's much
lower but
in the spectrum but this is actually
nice because it's using satellites soyuz
the event and you can uplink and
downlink messages and phone calls and so
on and you must like many other birds up
there actually just bent pipe
transponders which means that they will
listen and broadcast on Flickr frequency
with a spot beam to one point on the
earth where they have for example in my
SATs ground stations and they will also
have very wide beings are different
frequency which had the uplink and
downlink or in this case the aircraft
and so you can see that have a system
sort of works there with the different
frequencies that operate what's nice is
that the downlink for the aircraft is
actually in the 1.5 to 1.6 e-hdi hurts
band which is easily received by
defined radios so what do you need just
need to put a dish up in your backyard
it's a little complicated that because
the signal so far away you need to
filter an amplifier best to prevent
other signals from getting in and also
to amplify that weak signal from the
satellite so you can make this homemade
left hand circular polarized helical
feed this is the handiwork of my good
friend in Buckley he just put this
together and it captures for me he's got
this corrects running into a band-pass
filter a low-noise amplifier and then
another on the back side and just woke
up to the STO so why is it nice and
interesting well in mice that allows you
to exchange messages from aircraft and
also set up calls and actually run the
call traffic as well
the Peter actually looking at system
sort of way to open doors to look at the
peak channel their different channels
but we want to talk with a p/e channel
that's where the coordination coming
begins uses TDM and carry signaling in
use at Tata you got the Argentine see
channels for reservation information and
then circuit switch mode or random data
from the aircraft so they're all all
used two different frequencies different
sort of schemes but fundamentally
you start with P channel so this is that
was the flow graph cleaning up a little
bit I don't know if you can tell the
difference
but this is sort of made up two
components one is the sort of basic
signal processing so if you haven't
already before this is an example who
can you ready to flow graph so the raw
signal come in in this case in the top
left which is essentially what you see
on the dish that will go through a whole
bunch of signal processing steps which
all explained in a moment and then it
will go through and plugs into some
other blocks in the bottom right hand
and coach actually do this sort of tacit
pausing and securitisation so the first
step is that yet this you can actually
see the spectrum and you get those
little spike sitting up in the air
actually all the peach channels that you
can see within this frequency range
there are actually a couple and then you
click on Mon and then you get the green
line and so that's cool channel
selection so you pick out the signal of
interest and then you shift your
basement spectrum to that particular
frequency and then you feel too so you
get this very narrow band signal that's
your channel that you want to decode the
next step is to determine the modulation
type so what you can do this thing
called blind steganalysis and I have
spoken about some tools and techniques
that you can use to sort of uncovered a
lands the idea is that if you don't if
you if the signal that you like and you
want to discover what's going on you
don't need to necessarily doing research
on online to begin with thought you have
to have a secret data sheets for it
specification actually just apply some
simple mathematical steps to usually
uncover what sort of modulation scheme
is cuz it's usually a subset of fairly
simple one so in this case it's GMs k
gassing them she came and what you can
do is you can take your signal square it
take to get 50 which is showing here and
then you should get to these peaks
equidistant from the sea and that's the
characteristic signature of MSK so we
know that
MSK the next step is you need to know
how quickly they are actually sending
the information down just called the
symbol rate and the symbol right on the
border right you can determine pretty
easily by taking the signal multiplying
it by Adelaide version of itself and
then you take the entity again and the
first big PQ have actually be the board
rights if you read that off
can anybody tell me what the board right
is what was the biggest peak frequencies
on the x-axis that's right 601 symbols
per second
here so the next step is once you know
what the modulation scheme is once you
know how quickly those symbols of coming
down you then wannabe been tracking them
and then turn them into bits that you
can operate on and then passing two
packets so this status quo clock
recovery is very important and there are
different sort of algorithms and data
rates just a block that you throw in and
Alexei try to track those symbols and
synchronized to it and then sample
that's exactly the right time so you get
a bit out and you can tell if it's
actually working properly because if you
put the samples this kinda looks good
writers Jim ska the way you can tell is
you'll have a whole bunch sort of what
extent a plus one and a whole bunch of
negative one and then you good it was
looking noisy than we probably be of
channels you might be too weak if you
start actually doing clock recovery on
that then it'll look much the same but
what you can do in this is one nice
thing about the visualization tools in
gonna radio you can switch then to dot
view and these samples because
essentially you're showing data points
in between your simple points you have
got all over that spectrum
that range bad choice of words between
negative one of one that once you click
recovery it's only going to peak you're
basically you're you're symbols that
would turn into bits and you see here
you actually have this nice blank space
in between negative 1+1 that means that
you've actually synchronize properly and
you'll sampling bits nicely within we
can do is you can slice through the zero
line here and then determine if this is
a one or two below one gonna be 2012
what you can do then is you can you use
a roster played these are incredibly
handy for determining if their structure
with and articles you want to see
structure so I just put those real ones
and zeros through into the rest of you
can see that there's this interesting
pattern that forms here you can play
around with the width of your plot and
determined that their 1200 wide frames
and this is synchronization signature
here you can see this it's the same
thing on each scan lines that's how your
decodable know when to begin decoding
the next frame so once you actually look
beyond that though it looks pretty
random so generally especially with
satellite links is always going to be a
combination of into leaving their
attraction and scrambling in there are
some very good reasons for that but
that's very extended it makes good sense
when you make in our think especially
space so here I actually had to go out
and such an intern the little bit
because once you get into for direction
and I mean you can try a whole bunch of
stuff but it just takes a lot of time so
you can cheat a little bit and figure
out what the specs are here and the idea
is that you had a signaling units to
come down this rambled become coated
then to leave and then
put into that payload after that
synchronization and remember house to
tell you that this is the coordination
for the rest of the channels when the
frame begins that's actually win the
frame start on all the other channels as
well so they for once you receive the
same crisis to this will be synchronized
to the rest of the channels to the
channels are going to be wider bandwidth
to support higher I write stuff like
voice to into leaving is really nice
because it protects against both areas
way into the works is that you have your
rule bitstream and then imagine the sort
of holding cells memory you write in
your bits from left to right and once it
fills up then you actually read it out
from top to bottom and you go across and
what that happens it it temporarily
disperses those bits over time so that
if you are in fact a burst error and
corruption bits you can use for Tara
correction to fix it up and I want to
thank the entire block it's really quite
quite meet the next step is doing
convolutional encoding that adds
redundancy to your bit stream so it adds
extra bits and then on the receiver side
you can use for example it's called the
Viterbi decoder but we'll figure out
that the maximum power 30 bits and if
your bits have some areas in it will
actually figure out which bits are
incorrect and then attempt to repair
them if the if they're not too bad
also very next game is used all over the
communications well what's nice is that
gonna radio has many of these books
already so it has a convolutional coding
blocking you can just throw that down
interestingly the code that uses is the
same cohen's has been the most popular
code used by the NASA Voyager probe they
use it all the way back then
it still survives to this day has been
superseded by March 11 codes like turbo
codes that are used in LTE nowadays but
this is still a very popular one and
then D scrambling to scrambling what it
does is it disperses the energy in your
signal so it uses up love you spectrum
is using additive scrambler and sort of
an example of how it works and then this
is a block to do that but you can just
push that through as well so once you do
that once you put it through all the
steps on the tobacco decide then you put
it back into the roster and you can see
there's a lot more structuring that
particular plot their compared to the
original one that we have also the CRC
check and then you can validate for
certain whether youre declaring problem
because then you should get the right
CIC so after all that then you can start
decoding messages and it took me a
little while to figure out cos CI CI's
can be a pain depending on which to use
it and usually comes at 20 but certain
CFCs come out to a fixed value here
0 be eight but what happens is you get
these packets coming out they'll start
with the first but it tells you what
sort of package it is the payload in a
CRC on the end zone to look the 71 and
then the way it works is that it signals
that the user data starting and accounts
down the packets
start with a C or indeed until it gets
down to zero and then prints out the the
message so it ends when you get to seize
your so you get some interesting
messages now just to keep this in
context this is why I certainly love
this kind of stuff this is something on
the ground type message in computer it
was probably sent over the Internet to a
relay node on the ground station it was
turned into radio frequency energy it
was sent up 35 30,000 kilometers into
the sky onto a satellite it converted to
different frequency sent it back down to
work
this is a satellite that's just sitting
there with solar panels powerful battery
you know some long lifetime sent back
down to a plane that's hurtling through
the sky over the ocean I mean that's
pretty incredible this wasn't about
clogged toilets mind you but it was
telling people to hurry up cuz like
passengers may not be accepted for
travel when they when they do that this
is only for a short capture so I want to
take this back in right for a long
period of time and see what what sort of
juicy stuff you get you got notices here
this airport I didn't know what it was
but basically all of it taxiways and
runways to be close which is really
helpful you get weather reports there
are different systems as well see PLC
idiocy he can decode that as well and
gain information about where particular
aircraft is heading and these are
aircraft that you wouldn't really have
any other contact from also what's
interesting about in my side is you put
it in the context of tragedies that have
occurred in in the recent history of
aviation you might remember image 370 if
you could listen on the other side of
the link to your own doctor processing
and and figure out do some of the credit
math they did to determine what portion
of the world the last in my set with rum
and then apparently these aircraft are
on time which is pleasant surprise and
then you have these weird human-readable
messages advise you have info no
participating TV I don't know what it is
but I've seen other ones where a plane
has been forced to rewrite and federal
police are gonna be waiting at the
airport so so that's in mice at work in
progress but again it's eliminating
interesting seagulls up there as well so
it runs deep in next next topic
this is actually the tip of you as I
Symbian which is used to send remote
control signals to drugs it's also very
very busy when you go to I can meet up
people flying make it a little article
on this a while back he's actually
played with a drone also seen a drone
flying people with FPV goggles so people
actually now put cameras on the drugs
and then they win these goggles so they
can see from the point of view of the
drawing then they actually writes I
don't know how they do it they are
machines it is incredible to watch them
go in the reflexes that have caused runs
a tiny penis so fast but any ideas what
we're looking at here any ideas anyone
take a guess
correct what kind of video signal do you
think it is not quite enough unless he
was using kind of technology NTSC is
correct you said that very good that's
that's completely correct so we're
looking at a part of the spectrum and
what's weird is it is not just NTSE NTSE
over FM so you can actually see the
vertical sync the frame sync and then it
actually drawing the picture it so
that's actually how bout of systems
operating interference and if people go
on the wrong channel 10 interfere and
then I won't be able to see any more in
the crash the boat to drugs at least so
drunk have fun they sound depending on
the model you get it can sound like
really big loud mosquitoes and I just a
little bit of a test I put a webcam on
there they're hooked up to a year each
310 which is an embedded you SRP going
here went to have a look and actually
has suffered defined radio plus an armed
forces are inside plus a whole bunch of
other goodies so you can look it up with
different peripherals and in this case
because it's more compact you can put on
the underside of a drone and then do
anything you want
up in the end and as I'm sure you will
know the higher altitude you get the
most signals you seen often the stronger
they are so instead of going to the top
of a building can senator nothing so
here this is gonna radio program the
webcams sending images to another
program that sends it down
of RAF and then this is the screen
recording on my laptop can see some
crazy guy jumping up and down there my
friends actually flying the drone
little bit of fun I wouldn't recommend
that for FPV importance re-balancing
that system and it's not terribly robust
but just a bit of fun Proofpoint what's
nice there in kind of scary is that you
can fly and run what you shouldn't but
anywhere has anybody seen that the I
think the FAA put out an exposed to give
you advisories on on if you know you
shouldn't be flying in a particular area
that it determines using geolocation
friend's fiance sure that to me and
apparently everywhere that she turns it
on a conf line
but here you can send them up to quite a
while and you can see into everyone's
backyard it's it's quite incredible so
imagine that for RAF so here again
taking off and this is from the point of
view of the drawing is being recorded on
my laptop so sending the information
down this is it was a different systems
are sometimes the the extreme gets
corrupt a little bit but again very very
quickly go quite high up and just see
the landscape as it unfolds kind of one
thing you know there is one of spectrum
scanners have just want to look at the
activity in the spectrum not do anything
in particular just do the Recon you can
run on there
and as an example this was the sort of
spectrum that was output on the ground
and then I'll shoot those signals were
twenty 20 GB higher so that was pretty
nice and you can just have this run will
collect and then come back down down the
results have a look and then pick
anything that you want to investigate
further
that's just the general STR approach you
can also combine that with other really
need technologies and their USB ports on
this thing you can plug in an iterative
dongle or you can plug in a and Atmel IC
Ravens Ed dongle which i happen to have
plugged in here and I mean that will
actually be cozy between for example
using your radio is everything up bro
nice project GRI Tripoli at 11:54 that
will do and you can run there as well
but if you wanna do other things on
there then you can just like a dongle in
two in the traditional hardware approach
so has a plugin for kismet so is flying
around a little bit and pick up some
Bluetooth packets and this is something
that I've been working on a little bit
if any of you familiar with kismat is
actually if all the correct me if I'm
wrong because they didn't vote on this
but there's an incomplete ZigBee plugin
and I sort of took a look at it and had
quite a lot of nice work done to it and
it would work with this is a raven
mongol bit it wasn't finished so I
finish it and I set up a little bit
because I want to get the nice Google
the signals and so on so it kinda treats
it like wi-fi networks to make that
happen but this is actually now picking
up networks and its kinda nice the other
other thing and hope they're condemning
that to you in a minute I'll come back
to that so essentially now you
you have a stable platform and if there
are other in a modern embedded computers
as well if you want to try something
else but this is seems to be good all in
one package for example and you can do
all of these things with your drawing
and fly them around and hopefully get
into trouble of the batteries run out I
had run fly away once and how to
firmware bug and I just kept line and
then it ran out of battery because this
was a night in this big blinking thing
in the sky and then it just fell out of
the sky so last night at I think 140 I
decided to order a lift and drive around
Dec with the with the kids met with
anything just a test that out and show
some interesting today the pool its
driver had no idea what's going on
very confused because I didn't go
anywhere in the dryer and come back so
he was running they're actually had been
hit on the passage of all these weird
lights and wires all over his car and I
i put the GPS antenna magnet on the roof
he said what what you put out there
you're recording mode which is another
really nice dongle the Raven 800 many
just hanging out the window you know
just catching the brace and and so this
is the result I think I ended up picking
up a 52 54 57 ZigBee networks around and
if you consider everyone has WiFi
Bluetooth ZigBee is one of those
interesting protocols and is taking off
a little bit you know the IOT and what
have you and I was expecting there to be
so much traffic around but there are a
lot of technologies that use it nowadays
and again really been looking there and
interesting now people are taking notice
and analyzing it in terms of security so
you know all the green dots along that
ring part of the network's run this
place I saw some clear text something
was reporting the time you could inject
packets and maybe it might be nice big
sign somewhere you can change the time
on there and then there's this plane
takes coming through there is a
what was that last night but it's nice
to see you at Acton obviously go back
this is the awesome driver he was a
really good sport especially that late
and it was also nice about the setup is
310 you power up the battery plugged
into a USB battery pack so it's really
portable just threw it in my bag they're
doing its thing I thought I will I'm
gonna catch a plane left it running for
on wifi wifi don't like being done it so
far that's at Phoenix I guess the plane
was landing or taking off
picking up in that has wifi networks and
then if you dare nowadays with
everything that's been going on you know
put any sort of intent up to your window
in a window seat and in this case get a
GPS fix you can see that its findings
but again it's portable and compact like
that he can work on a project in flight
just
just be aware that they will probably do
an extra checking a bag you know
interestingly the far more strict about
this in Europe than in america which is
surprising considering everything I got
pulled over like you wouldn't believe so
just briefly then finish up some other
interesting signals z-wave who saw the
z-wave talked yesterday it was it was
really impressive great tool home
automation what's interesting is a
dearth rewrites the Seaway views and
again i just want to see what was out
there so I put together this flow graph
that simultaneously dumont elizalde 3
rights and then just up the road packets
at the bottom and interestingly that
sort of Miss so i thought well if they
doing stuff to do tomorrow I'll take my
kids if I can pick anything up and in
fact I was jumping up other friends
yesterday and I actually had a running
at the beach under many of their last
night in the car and what's interesting
is quite short range but neither may go
to get a bit of extra distance actually
picked up a whole bunches you a driving
around to know geo-tagging a special
tagging but again it's just interesting
to see that you can get that just by
driving around laura is another one who
heard of Laura lawrence continued on the
scene it's part of his hold on power
wide area networking phenomenon that's
happening in the IOT because to Gigi SMG
Paris is going to be some sit and
retired he needs to replace its own
lawyers one of the options
interestingly its troops spread spectrum
which is quite a different sort of
signal and if you look on the left hand
side as you can see I see that ship down
lines that's actually the signal and
think Oh during that so this is a little
off that generates and down convinces
church so that you can see what the
underlying legislation and had a
daughter is encoded there so if you
imagine on the left hand side of these
ones you see the actual church on the
the rule spectrum and on the right hand
side you have the down converted church
so we basically church because this
frequency that increases over time and
it goes back then laura is sort of does
the church goes the opposite direction
so it's going right direction again but
jumps around in
offset so if you make your own signal
basically just a sort of going into a
voltage-controlled oscillator and then
multiply the two signals you can
straighten those dandelions and that's
what's happening on the left and they
claim to have a good coexistence because
the band is so busy and all these other
signals so with this you can still get
your lower rates to go through when you
don't commit the church you see how that
characteristic line of energy that's
actually the lower signal and then at
this point it becomes an FSK
multi-ethnic skate issue of decoding
it's just have these spikes in energy
that appear all over the place and
depending what being a teenager in that
is your data so it's kind of need and
what's really cool his in this one is
actually a BPSK signal going right
through the middle of the church and you
think we'll have two singles are
deferring if that's what it looks like
there if you don't convert the church
that BPSK disappears in your look with
those little bit of energy and I was
really confused as I saw these other
trips and I just thought it was a lawyer
but there are different sorts of chips
singles out there and it's not Laura I
don't know what it is if anybody has any
ideas on wall is but it's kind of cool
mountain again if you'd unconverted
turns out to be the same sort of
scenario so just another interesting
sort of mutant seen me to keep an eye
out like this a new mission it was being
set up in San Francisco and on the east
coast various places just to finish up
then I wanted to show you how you can
sort of going for a long drive some way
you can get a broad overview of the
spectrum and one in one picture of the
quickly so is driving down from
petaluma back to San Francisco these
attract and retain running they're
constantly collecting the 915 megahertz
band would record about half a second
dump it and just keep cycling on that so
if you would please any one of those
individual recordings of half a second
UNC the sort of frequency hopping stuff
that we saw before or interestingly this
one
anyone's guess as to what this was this
is just after I finished crossing the
Golden Gate Bridge going so I know you
know the answer to anyone else
yeah that's right in this case is fast
track this is the fast-track readers I
was going through the toll booth and
what you can do there is you can take
each individual recording individual
recording you basically doing a fifty of
the entire things like a step 2 50 and
then you take the maximum valuable the
bench for that entire recording and they
give you sort of the energy signature of
what happened during that time you take
one of those and then you make that a
scanline horizontal scan line and in
each recording every subsequent
recording that will give you all of the
subsequent scan lines so what you're
seeing here is like the heat map over
time of the 915 megahertz spectrum and
it's actually really begin with so many
down simply you can't quite make out the
detail but it's interesting to see here
on the left hand side there you got this
frequency hopping channelized whatever
it is maybe smart meters but attorneys
in left hand side the band he got a
different sort of frequency hopping
wider band channels there some summer in
San Francisco again you can GPS take
over as well and he had this is actually
the fast track I sort of saw this and
thought oh what's that going to have a
look at the recording and then I saw and
then if your local oscillator you get
drunk on the night and then you get
these really terrible signals he cites
diagonal shouldn't be dying almost put
on hold oscillator warming up that's no
good and then if any of you have used up
to 25 its use by Public Safety added
this new feature where you can enter the
encryption key into the decoder and then
we'll pick the right one for the network
you're using Unity cryptanalysis you can
look at that time spectrum SEO meetup
San Francisco monthly check them out
good fun people do cool stuff like shock
collars for dogs with STR and they had
to thank you very much