are one liners I would like to throw
some of this stuff but I'm gonna throw
it into the audience if you would like
swag so as always we have a lot of stuff
going on there's a lot of really good
training going on if you haven't had a
head over to the lockpick village in a
highly suggested there are some amazing
art being treated for hackers for
charity and they're doing that are live
on the fly some beautiful prints are
also available for sale and all of that
goes directly directorship charity so
user wants some stuff here
trust me it does work you have to take
the little thing off the battery
somebody else that listens but can't
catch
so this is a really big room if you have
questions there is a heckler migrate
middle or come all the way up to the
front these guys will be great for the
to answer your whatever questions you
have no you all got us a ball we r shook
on the only conference with balls those
balls and not stress balls you can
relieve your stress if you're seeing a
presenter but there are other prisoners
are going on if you see a presenter that
you disagree with the reason you have
those balls and so you can take them and
check them at the presenter it's some of
its hard to stand up and and call out
somebody and say I don't believe you I
think what you just said is bullshit
that's why we give you can stand up and
suck that and the fact that you don't
agree I'm sorry but if you receive back
so the last thing I have my last year's
shirt be back actually conduct or if you
have any feedback whether you really
love presenter whether you think that we
are doing something really great if you
think we have we're doing something we
need to change please let us know we
take all of that feedback to heart and
we try and respond to each and every
email that we get and communicate with
each of you because we want to make this
the best conference that we can so
please send emails to feedback its
Macondo door and we will read and
respond to every single one of them are
not automated spam and will try we want
to make this contest best as possible so
without will toss my last sure to
somebody else it wasn't I and then
introduced Sarah and John will be
talking to us about suffered by networks
good morning everybody ok glad you all
made it out after the the crazy crazy
evening of frivolity last night in here
looks like they clean it up pretty well
first off just a disclaimer I just
noticed the screens are are actually in
front of us we are going to be needing
the laser pointer for the demonstration
portion of it and so the cameras are
back there if you do not want to be in a
cameraman be probably standing right
about here so that I can laser point to
the screen so if you do not want your
picture taken you know probably steer
clear of these few seats right here
because because you may end up being in
the background something I know how they
deal with cameras here welcome it's
really good to be here we're talking
about something very near and dear to
our hearts Defined Networking just a
little introduction on on who we are we
are both very very passionate nerds that
focused on the network side of things we
love everything to do with networking
she handles a lot more of the building
and I handle a lot more of the you know
securing breaking securing and so that
that's brings up a really good point so
a lot of people here you know nerves
this and that had no fears about
speaking up here this move all people in
the audience that are definitely way
smarter than me actually my greatest
fear is getting in a fight with her on
stage because while we we've research
together very well we do it emits a
violent disagreement so that's that's my
current that's what I'm scared about
second quick note about the shoe balls
we are both very aware our weaknesses
speaking very quickly so we will expand
the use of small balls to in court
encompass if we're talking too fast you
free to let us know because we both do
that a lot especially if I networking so
just start here how many of you have
heard of software networking before
sweet a lot of people how many of you
have actively worked with it
securing building ok look around your
hands up look around there's there's
there's
a few shot rate up a few tentative 'he's
Defined Networking is huge in she's in
going to a second some of the companies
are using it why is it why is there so
little representation here for something
that is that is increasing as you can
see in billions of dollars every year
there
market research is anticipating twelve
billion dollars by 2019 on the
conservative side you can see things
Weiwei greater than that I usually go on
the conservative side and and that's
what they're saying by 2019 so so what
is the reason behind this why who's
using it first of all and why are we
hearing more about it why we're only a
few hands up and we talked about
security within sorry if I networking
well the answer to that is supported by
networking is actually kind of
complicated it's not like setting up a
traditional network which I love doing
it actually requires a little bit more
you need architects coders you need
security people you need not want folks
like us because software-defined
networking have a lot more pieces as you
can see on the screen there are lots of
large large corporations to include an
essay on there are using Afghan and they
have been for years and years on Google
actually develop their own controller
and drop andromeda all of these
companies are using covered by
networking because it's a very powerful
tool and if able to meet the needs of
their large data centers that
traditional networking is just failing
we're trying to bring to light here is
that those large data centers have been
using a while and it is expanding in
getting lower and lower in the stack is
we're gonna show here and how the
amazing capability that it has even for
smaller businesses smaller companies a
few of the solutions that are out there
right now they're they're commercial
open source it really started as almost
an open source community driven project
with a lot of commercial vendor support
a lot of vendor by and so companies like
HP broken Dell have lent engineers to
the SDN project due to essentially help
develop this capability so you can
actually buy hardware switches that have
Sdn built into a nasty and capabilities
open till capabilities we have a network
secular we're going to be using a little
bit later to show to show you guys a few
things answer some questions
but if you don't have you know a lot of
money to pay brocade or pay Dell or HP
to come into your to your workplace and
set it up for you you're gonna need to
do some research and and studying on
your own and a lot of that can be done
through the open source platforms a lot
of the controllers are built on the open
daylight and floodlight platforms are
the two most common controllers that are
out there there's a few others up there
that we listed that are great for her
recent for different purposes
open visa which is a virtual switch that
handles open close you can actually
completely have an entire virtual Sen
inside a single for your own research
study purposes a great tool and then
VMware has and Cisco kind of break their
own flavor of it as especially Cisco
likes to do so
VMware does it because of their
integration with virtual machine some of
the stuff there they need some specific
functionality and Cisco was not happy
with some of the stuff that OpenFlow
protocol had so they rewrote protocol a
bit to fit their needs so what what
actually is Sen we've been talking about
it a lot what what is it
well I know a lot of hands went up but
we're just gonna review a couple things
when is Sdn really extended abstract in
the function of the control plane and
the data plane from a network device
it's moving those in two separate
separate locations logically ok I do
wanna make the distinction that St and
is not the same as network function
virtualization there's a lot of
confusion around when you're doing that
work function virtualization you're
taking in networking devices which are
rather something in your abstracting the
functions of that provide secure network
from the hardware and your virtualizing
that now they are very complementary to
each other and if we can be used to
virtualize your data forwarding plane
devices your switches that are going to
be operating in your St an environment
but let's get a little bit deeper into
the weeds with FDM so if you look right
here we're gonna stand her center on
this picture on the controller the
controller in STN is your logical point
of control it handles all your control
plane functions right where do I send
traffic what do I do with this traffic
what's going on to control yourself is
generally run as an application on
linux-based platform and then we have
some control channel lines here the
control channel lines are connecting the
controller to the data 14 devices so
like I said the control plane functions
were abstracted and remove those to the
controller we've taken the data 14
devices on the bottom is open flow
switches in their handling all of my
data plan functions so the controller
needs to be able to communicate to these
devices they use the control channel and
will go up a little bit more into the
control channel later the better gonna
be communicating instructions basically
and then at the very bottom we have all
her hosts are hosts are communicating
with their dad affording devices through
the OpenFlow protocol this is what we
call the southbound lane and we're going
to be doing a lot of talking on the
southbound lane and the control channel
specifically the northbound lane which
is where the API is revived basically
communicates to the controller and
augments the ability to produce flows to
security in a lot of flow-based function
that are coming from specialized plugin
API is that are either bender developed
or developing not so much but that's
what's happening at the northbound lane
Dr ste an environment that show but what
is it really so basically this is a
really really lame in way of explaining
it but my controllers gonna be sending
my close to my switches I put on here
think ACL because my flow is a little
bit more than what you would understand
in a routing table or a switching
switching table so your controllers
gonna send this flow information because
it has the control functions down to my
dad affording devices the switches are
going to use these flows in the flow
tables when they're receiving
information they're going to look for an
action there flows and then they're
gonna just do whatever the action is for
that out
drop that traffic whatever's appropriate
now to switch received something from a
host and it doesn't have a flow that
matches it goes through all the flows
and nothing matches now with the
switches gonna do that's gonna take a
packet from that transmission and its
gonna put that up to the controller on
the controller is going to be able to
either send instructions
to the to the switch on what to do with
that type of traffic or it may need to
further send that information up to one
of those APs are plugins I'm to let that
process and and provide instructions so
either I got a flow from the controller
or probably I'm gonna end up dropping
that that traffic now it's not
necessarily a drop action will talk
about that a little bit later you may
have a flood ruled that you didn't take
out of your switch which you should do
and that will cause that traffic to let
out all ports but will hit that a bit
later so at this point you're thinking
okay now I'm stopping a traffic flow and
I'm sending something to the controller
which is gonna process that in software
that seems kind of slow this doesn't
sound like a good idea for a large data
center for this this type of application
isn't call for slow why would you do
this well I would do this because of the
control that I have ultimately that
first packet that goes to the controller
in a packet in message that is going to
take a few milliseconds more ok but
after that all the subsequent packets in
the traffic as long as there was a flow
provided are going to be processed at
line speed controller itself can handle
the controller and the switches themself
can handle logic matching logic layer
one all the way through later for and
any combination that you can imagine
just about all of those those different
layers the API's themselves are able to
handle some functions of looking into
the payload for deep packet inspection
but that's not something that is
currently supported in the OpenFlow side
where the controller and the switch is
resigned yet however those API's do
provide us the ability to really look at
traffic dynamically through every layer
of the OSI and make decisions so that's
a huge powerful tool and by the way this
is all programmatic this does not
require human intervention the same way
a traditional network does talking
so we've been talking about flows so I
wanted to point out kind of two basic
ways that you can imagine how I can
create my flows in a network again
closer what we're using an order 24
traffic so we have a proactive type of
flow and we have a reactive type of flow
the proactive flows think about those as
a as an architect and engineer you're
gonna decide the paths through your
network that you want your traffic to
travel this this means that your
controller needs to have an accurate
idea of the topology and we'll get into
that later on and this type of
formulating your flows in your pads is
more static but for that reason it's a
little bit more secure I'm not going to
have any surprises ok but when
researching static and secure I feel
like we're losing some of the benefits
of the flexibility of the STN provides
us so that's when we can look at
reactive flows reactive flows are
enabled by the controller and these are
gonna be based on those packet in like I
said when the switch get something from
a host and it doesn't have a flood that
matches it sends it to the controller
the controller can either itself or
through the API's provide instructions
in a reactive fashion to that particular
package so this can be resource
intensive if I have a lot of traffic on
my network that I haven't planned for
and all of those packets are getting set
up to the controller so it doesn't
really scale well so the answer really
is
have a good mix of both proactive and
reactive flows and then I'll stop
talking we're gonna talk a little bit
about the anatomy of a flow just for you
guys that may not have you know you may
not have dug in that deep into what
clothes do so this is kind of what a
flow looks like you're gonna have a flow
table in her switch or many float able
to nurse which depending on the hardware
that you're running the rule portion
that's very important that's going to be
your matching field so I can spend on
the bottom you can see there the
switches in the controller able to match
based on any fields layers 1 through 4
and please understand that there are
things that are not depicted here that
we do see special applications that can
match for like DSCP codes for QoS and
things like that actual
fields within the IP header so that's
really amazing so there we have the rule
the next part is 15 match something I've
said ok this traffic matches this
particular flow away do with the traffic
that's going to be my action understand
that action and and instructions are
synonymous I'm gonna use those terms of
both of those terms because the charm
actually change from action to
instructions of the added capabilities
with the Newark limitations of the
OpenFlow protocol for my actions right
here we just have some very generic
actions that can be taken I can forward
the packet either to a port or ports I
can for the packet to a particular
destination based on an IPA have a lot
of our options here I can also send that
package up to the controller that allows
the controller to processing or send it
to an API for further instruction I can
drop the packet obviously and then the
normal 14 pipeline that's something we
will hit again later that means that
basically I can treat this particular
traffic this a way I would in a letter
to learning switch so really what this
is is security and networking did we
just become best friends
security networking though the beauty of
Sen in our opinion is that you can marry
these two things so I talked a lot about
flows and how you can use flows before
we get into the security portion as I
know you guys are all waiting for him to
talk about security I want to point out
the best practice ideas for creating
your network and its secure way ok so
now instead of just writing to get there
I can route to get there the way I want
to get there in a secure way so coarse
and fine grain flows I have the ability
with all these matching options to match
something very coarsely rightly all ipv4
traffic pretty broad or I can have very
fine-grained closed specify specific
host in a city with a specific
destination in mind there's all sorts of
things we can do they're so in a large
Sdn environment think about your course
core switches and routers you want those
processing large amounts of data very
quickly to those who remain large course
generic type closer to be placed in
there around the edges of my network
that's where I'm probably gonna happen
fighter green regular tight clothes and
some of these may be a product of those
reactive flows that you talked about
that we didn't really see when we talked
about the anatomy of the flow is the
priority I mention that you have low
tables within your switches the priority
is something that you're gonna sign to
the flow and think about it like if I
have a higher priority and it matches
that's the flow that's gonna be used for
this lower priority flow even if it also
matches that to think about how that
kind of again gives me the ability to
treat these flows almost like an access
list in a firewall I can also use
multiple tables within my switches these
tables allow me to really separate my
traffic and I can send an action for a
specific match to just refer to another
table so let's just say generic simple
example I have ipv4 and ipv6 and running
dual stack and my network I want all my
ipv4 to do these things that I have this
whole table creative full flows I also
have a very broad match for all ipv6
traffic based on either type that the
action should be sent it to this flow
table is an immediate process through
all these IP v4 flow rules so I'm about
done is really awesome because when
you're networks under attack
we feel that flows can reality retaliate
and we're going to talk about that
security finally 30 there are really
three main avenues attack of an OpenFlow
Sdn network these are very broad very
broad avenues and and generally collect
most of the various types of attacks you
can see on St N one of the control
channel that communication link between
the controller and the switches the
controller itself is also another avenue
attack as well as the flows within the
switches in the flows that are being
sent to the switches were gonna look at
each one of these things and give you a
few a few aspects of each one that you
need to be aware of the control channel
once again this is the communication
between the controller in the switch and
so it's very important that it is secure
the control channel itself can be
managed in or out of band meaning out of
and it's a bit running a completely
separate TCP network
outside of the OpenFlow network and that
is great because it's actually
physically separated from your OpenFlow
network and there's a lot of security
associated with that however
manageability can suffer because now you
have to have places they can route to
that separate network in band makes
management really great because from
within OpenFlow you can now manage your
controller from any any OpenFlow host
really obviously you don't want every
open to host managing your controller so
there are security associations with
that as well as security implications
associated with that as well
control channel can be secured with TLS
or TCP initially testified that it was
required that that control shall be
secure with you less well you start
requiring things like to you less and
people are complaining and so later
editions of the protocol now allow for
both and guess which one
most people are using not be less so
there is an overhead associate Els and
implementation yes you have to actually
load all your certificates on the
switches which can cause problems so a
lot of people are using TCP still to
manage their to manage their control
channel talk a little bit more about
that later
control channel is just a TV network so
it's vulnerable to all the traditional
network attacks that you'll see on any
other network
here's a few of a few the tax we're
actually we're actually able to
successfully leverage against that
control pain control channel remember
ever cap I used it in high school to you
know traffic around my library but you
can still use basic tools like that
later to man-in-the-middle attack on a
control on a controller versus a switch
and now you can see every bit of traffic
that passes between the control and the
switch and inject traffic as you see fit
we'll talk about that a little later as
well this allows you to impersonate the
controller and make the switches think
you're the controller potentially taking
over the entire Sdn so it's very
important that your control channel is
properly secured because in addition to
that the denial of service
behavior the switches have can depend on
how you program so which loses
connection to the controller it
essentially goes into one of two states
and most familiar you could probably use
the field open or feel closed ideologies
so feel secure is that is more feel
close basically the switch behavior if
it loses connection with the controller
is just continue processing traffic
based on the flows it has and when those
lows time out the switch just dropped
traffic that's the more field closed
mind set DVR standalone means the
switches process the process the traffic
as if it was a normal switch so
basically reverted to regular layer 2
switch and switch will process traffic
that way clearly both have security
issues and availability issues and you
need to make a careful choice which one
you which one you choose to implement
right now I'd like to do a quick tip of
the hat to mr. Gregory picket at
hellfire security he's one of the few
other people that is talked at security
conventions about sovereign if I network
if you look for hacker con security
convention talks on SDN it's really him
maybe a couple of folks that are say
there's not a whole lot of discussion
about this and that's what we got
excited about it because we love
networking and there's so much potential
for security within soccer Defined
Networking we felt that it really need
to get come out to a wider audience and
such as this new congress mister picket
developed some great Python based tools
for open till version one that can
incorporate OpenFlow networks can toss
controllers can can impersonate switches
all kinds of great tools that can be
found on its website at hellfire
healthier security obviously the first
stage of any successful attack about an
open network from within an open network
well enough
depending on the way the switches are
programmed your open ports can be
scarily quiet so you plug into an open
support in turn on Wireshark and you may
actually not hear anything your
broadcasts are at the switch between the
switch and controllers your typical our
broadcasts here you know Mtns all that
other stuff that microsoft does not
actually getting broadcast because the
controller can specify exactly what to
do with all that stuff and see you may
actually depending on the configuration
not actually hear anything going into a
port so there's a great secure
implication therefore you're not getting
your unable to just passively sniffle
lot of information about an open network
if it's properly configured occasionally
though you will see LDP and host
identification messages those are away
controller manages the links and looks
at tracks where the hosts are on the
network so OpenFlow uses them LDP
variance to attract hosting link states
within a network another interesting
thing we noticed was meted certain
you're printing the flows and based on
hits and misses once we had once we were
able to listen on the control channel we
could start sending traffic in OpenFlow
ports and see what the switch was
sending to the controller and asking
about this allowed us to fingerprint
exactly what flows were in the switches
based on hey this this which sent this
traffic some plays into the controller
includes the switch clearly had a flow
for that piece of traffic we can now
begin to a numerate the flows within the
switches in addition to that some of the
default flows when you when you open the
box controller plugin the switches it
will install a lot of default flows just
make your network work and some of those
include as you mention the flood flows
you send us you sent a package if the
switch doesn't know what it does it's
legit out all ports essentially either
switching or hub type mentality
depending on the depending on the
controller using this can allow you to
plug one thing into each into to open
ports and listen on one and send random
traffic of this one and see what's
getting flooded over here so you now
know what matches within the switch
lastly you can you can actually conduct
hella sweep of the network and pinpoint
OpenFlow capable devices within the
network because the default behavior for
overflow devices is to respond hello so
you send a TCP based hello and see who
hellos back
controllers and depending on the
implementation some of the other other
devices as well so a lot of times when
you when you start talking to you less
and insecurity specifically with with
suffered if I networking folks they will
hand weighted by saying just pls pls pls
is a great 2010 there is great he last
august 10 2012 that is a great tool and
can provide some great security
but it's definitely not the answer to
everything in there some specific things
we need to be mindful of when
implementing key lesson in STN
unfortunately is not as easy as just
implementing TLS there are some things
we need to think about this is a pillow
packing our issue is this is the exact
specification of hello packet we know
exactly what's inside that tacit the
protocol is predictable so inside hello
packet I know that his nineteen bites
there's no padding there's no random
transmission ideas that are generated
it's a sequential transmission ideas
generated so when I see an encrypted 19
bite or plus the TLS enter nineteen by
packing go by I now know exactly what
that package is as you can see here I
have a Hello packet next to its
encrypted counterpart and it's very
simple and straightforward we know what
every field in a khaki jeans so based on
their side and that's just a Hello
example there's echo request sexual
pleasures and many other packets that we
can identify based on their size so now
we can man in the middle your network
because once again there are you later
to attack you can still man the middle
of TLS connection and we can now packets
we don't want based on their size so I
inject of bad flow into your switch the
switch goes to update or the controller
pulls the switch and switch goes up to
the controller I can just not that
packet out I don't care what's inside
and I know it's an update because I know
what the sizes and I can prevent the
controller from receiving updates from
those switches I can conduct recon of
your network based on traffic statistics
so I can write scripts that will look
for these eyes of packets and generate
information on ok this end of the
network the flows are pretty pretty
course and there's a lot of packing into
the controller I can start getting a lot
of information about your network just
based on the packet sizes that are
coming across the even without knowing
the contents and lastly since we know
exactly what's in that package we can
begin hashing these increasing rainbow
tables that will eventually start
fingerprinting your keys with your
network this is a significant problem as
this tells us a lot and it is not
secured by the encryption encryption is
not defeat
the all the things we can find out about
these packets so we talked a little bit
about the about the control channel and
the implications there the next avenue
of attack is the controller itself and
she's entitled about that one controller
at like I mentioned before in the end
the controller is my central point of
logic ok the controller is going to be
the brain the heart the soul of an ISDN
to the controller really is a single
point of failure and I know a lot of
your thinking that like oh my god if the
controller goes down everything is it's
over right whatever stop you don't just
have one controller and a large network
you have usually overlays of slices on
in those controllers have different
prices of the network and you have a
lover mechanisms and high availability
but we're not going to go into all that
but I do want to point out in terms of
the controller is that this controllers
and application that's running on
usually a linux-based platform so
whatever the ladies are inherent in that
platform you haven't patched it now your
controllers vulnerable so be careful
there's really nothing new there now
controller in API facing this is fine
and there's a lot of people that have
done research on this
you have a very just a myriad of API's
and plugins that have been built to
interfaith on the controller and provide
additional functionality so the ideas
from the data plane if I'm sending in
Pakistan malformed have unexpected
payloads just all sorts of different
variables if I'm sending those in and
thus causing the switch to relate these
to the controller via the packet in
message the controller may get this in
freak out I might pass it up to an API
in freak out the key here is when we
start looking at funding the control an
API that only just takes one packet to
crush me saque to secure coding is very
important and I know that's not maybe
you guys' problem that's the the vendors
but on the open source ID it's something
that we should be cognizant of
controller overload is also a problem
there's a lot of talk out there about
denial of service distributed denial of
service obviously I've talked about
these packing in messages lot
enough posts that have been compromised
if I have the capability to send a very
high rate of packets that I know are
going to get a pack it in generated cos
they're missing those flows there's
nothing in there that matches that's
gonna get sent up to the controller if I
overwhelm the controller with a high
rate of packets a large number of
packets then I consumers resources and
I've basically . your your your network
so the ideas control plane policing can
help there's a function called me during
that absolutely can help however vendors
generally just suggest you meter K
you really need to meter your traffic
and then lastly in terms of the
controller topology changes are very
very near and dear to the controller can
like I said the controller needs to have
a good logical idea of the topology your
network in order to make those decisions
for those reactive flows home again to
determine the best way to get from point
A to point B if i dont know what youre
talking she looks like we have LDP
variants that john mentioned before
you'll often see this particular
function referred to as FTP OpenFlow
controller itself is going to by default
be running a host tracker service as
well as a link tracker service now the
host trackers dermis maybe something
that you look at turning off is what
it's doing is it's looking for all the
individual hosts in a large data center
you may not really need that cake and
you may think about turning that off
because that is something where those
hosts directly talking to through the
SDN on network have the ability to push
those LDP various messages in now if I
can control one of those host if I can
just I can just exploit one of them and
I can start spoofing messages I can
start sending instructions the
controller telling him that meet up one
over there now I'm over there now I'm
over there so that's the problem it's
going to confuse the controller and
that's it's really going to cause issues
I'm you can turn that service off but
again it's something to think about
because those are easy to speak now on
the link tracking side of this those
particular packets the time to live data
and decrement normally so it's easy to
relay from host position really packets
spoofed packets in things around and
making links appear where they really
shouldn't be obviously this again is an
issue because it may cause the
controller to create flows where it
shouldn't be creating posters it doesn't
have an accurate idea of the topology
I'm so one suggestion that I have read
about in terms of securing this
particular issue is at least for the
hosts tracking service to have some sort
of a precondition check of indication
for these messages it's just too heavy
and it's too much so precondition check
would mean that if I send you an update
the says hey I moved over there
my partner and gone down over here in up
over there and that's something that
neon controllers gonna be aware of
because these messages are going to come
from the switches to notify them I'm
status changes within their own within
their configurations like airports other
very important though so the flows I
just keep coming back to the flows the
flows are very important like john
mentioned earlier that blood flow I
kinda wanna back up and talk about that
from it that blood flow that is usually
when implemented out of the box priority
0 meaning that if we didn't match
anything of a higher priority that would
have been reactive or or put in that's
where that comes in so when I send think
about it as if it was an ACL that's an
implicit permit at the end of your ACO
that may not be what we want to do we
may want to think more heavily about
going towards the implicit deny so maybe
have a flow in there with a higher
priority than 0 that dropped your
traffic flow types are generic either
type flows are going to control your lol
DPR ipv4 ipv6 all those things it's very
important to be aware that again many
controllers all these different vendors
had different ways of handling it many
controllers are gonna send very generic
type flows very very coarse type close
to help facilitate this track this
traffic getting to the right place
the flood flows in the normal 40 the
flood flows are gonna happen they're
gonna happen out of the box the
controllers gonna send
the switches and that's gonna say
anything you receive an OpenFlow ports
and that all other ports the normal
authority is treated like treat this
traffic like you were a normal switch
this is something that's gonna be
available on your hybrid type switches
that allow you to do both traditional
pipeline forwarding and reopen flow flow
injection injection that is a real
danger we talked a lot about the
man-in-the-middle attack and being able
to get into that control channel
impersonated controller do things like
that even just spoofing packets and
sending them in when I see TCP so the
idea with injection is if I can somehow
circumvent all of your security and and
i cant man in the middle europe your
network I can inject slows so now that I
control your network goes if I have bad
traffic that I want to get through your
network I can redirect traffic around
your existing firewalls your IPS is your
ideas wherever you happen to have in
that if you an environment to try to
protect your your information so I'm
just going to reiterate close think of
them as not only moving packets but also
a way to secure your network after
really digging into St N we we we really
felt strongly about the fact that Sen in
the capability to make the network more
than just packet transport transport
network topology can be changed in
milliseconds that's something that we're
gonna go through in our demo and this is
something that's done with zero human
intervention you can have code triggers
on a condition that can change the whole
topology of your network based on
providing flows deleting flows
reordering flows and changing where
you're here traffic goes so something to
think about
once we get towards a moving target
defense or often this is something
that's been talked about in STN and
there's a lot of theories and we kind of
have her own spin on moving target
defense are often but the ideas I can
very easily relocate a host I can
redirect traffic very easily with very
thing is in the new implementations of
OpenFlow you're able to not only in
terms of actions for something back and
change all those aspects that I matched
on your source IP of dot line once I get
that right comes in the port of the
switch I can actually change that and
you're no longer 2012 everyone else your
dog too so it's kind of like thinking
that if your network person right that's
how I think of that but it's not it's
far more powerful because that condition
changing you . to can be only when
you're talking over here when you're
talking over here you're still not one
that's fine or maybe you're not three so
there's a lot of power in that just like
with traffic redirection being able to
redirect my traffic based on a defensive
or offensive mechanism very very
powerful so so what's the answer all
this we use Sdn is it secure is insecure
with this as a security community and
help build the security within STN
because once again as it happens so much
this protocol is being built and
security is is you know it's behind
there but it's kind of struggling to
catch up we need to build this protocol
with security in mind pls was a great
solution that's not the only answer as
you can see most of the security
functions of SDN currently are plugins
to the controller that's great and
there's some great ones I have had some
listed up here for example we the HP Net
Protector can actually scrub DNS traffic
so put the flow into into all your
switches that shoots DNS traffic over to
whitelist and blacklist and you can you
can control what traffic it's go through
your network protection there Dr
scrubbers built into St Annes as soon as
it detects a lot of weird stuff matching
your clothes it'll start sending it to a
Dr scrubber there's some really great
plugins for the controller but what we
really need is a holistic solution that
looks at the network as a whole for one
example we can it is it is possible to
inject flows into switches and a
controller not know about them so we
need a solution that can pull the
switches in the controller n determine
that everybody speaking the same
language
cash flows that are in the switches hash
the flows out in the controller compared
against each other make sure that
everybody's on the same page what we can
do now at St Anna will demonstrate in
our in our demo is we can leverage
existing security assets you have your
snorts your trip wires all these sorts
of things into an SDN so that your
networking actually dynamically make
decisions based on alerts from those
things obviously most importantly though
is is do your own research and testing
there is no cookie-cutter solution for
Sdn in in a network every company's
gonna run it differently every company
can have different network requirements
that's why we go back to the it's
complicated thing there are some amazing
control and beauty in STN but it is a
little tricky and it wont unlike a
regular switch routers it kind of semi
one size fits all
St is not like that so let's talk a
little about what we've done here
leading into the demo first of all we
are here because we love this stuff I
finish my masters degree she's been in
networking her whole life we are
passionate about this stuff we both had
happy consulting jobs is something we
we've been researching on our own time
because we've been wanting to get it out
there to the security community how
important this stuff is so what we're
trying to do here is we're trying to
create a vendor agnostic framework so
many of those plugins I spoke about our
vendor specific yesterday and it has a
great plugin and it only works with
Fortinet equipment which hopefully you
all have patches of like last week
vendor agnostic framework is really
important we need to start an
open-source discussion on how we can as
a community build security within our
soft if I networking and leverage the
power of it a lot of the capabilities of
security testing and are still in a
white paper or proprietary phase of
companies go off and do their own thing
build their own proprietary plug ins or
college students are trying to graduate
in writing white papers on it we need a
lot more grassroots support from the
community to do this
the flow logic for for this security
model needs to really can be based on
the type of attack so if it sees a
snorkel or come in for a me know Andy
Dawson
or you know shellcode coming across your
network you can now redirecting traffic
whatever you want and where everyone and
the logic that can support that is is
not that complicated you essentially
just can pick what you want based on
broad categories you all know about tort
categories you can pick it based on
categories of attack and gradually
defined flows based on that so we're
gonna lead into the into the demo here
from here so I can later point here is
what we have built over here and what
we're gonna do is we're going to zoom in
on each one of these and give you an
idea of what it looks like and how we've
created an appliance that can wear a
concept of an appliance that can
redirect traffic dynamically based on
attacks within the network what we have
here is here are three Brocade switches
and we have them right here in running
an HP Canon HP controller managing them
so each each which has a different host
hanging off this which has our tacker
this which has a honeypot this which has
our victim and up here we have our mean
are smart sensor and are and/or log
server as well as this handy-dandy
security plans that we've been working
on now
full disclosure here we try to minimize
the number of Ian's we had running in
here so are taxes kind of dumb and are
victims also sensor so attacker decides
to attack the smart sensor got it we
gotta get a dumb attacker here that's
basically what we built and and so fuel
clicker let's let's look first at what
the controller looks like you know
status quo normal flows in the
controller so what we have here is the
HP SDN controller has it has a lot of
great functionality and again a great
user interface that works really well
and so after this week if you like to
take a look at it we do have a running
up here and you can get a better look at
it so basically what we do here is we're
gonna show the flows in between the
attacker in
and the victim so you can see down there
on the bottom left there's art actor and
we're gonna set him as the source
victim as the destination gonna show the
flows in between them and as you can see
there is a current flow that is built
directing traffic between those two host
controller allows a lot of capability
and showing in illustrating the flows
that are going between them most
humility that little tiny box in a link
between the two switches is actually one
of the packet counters and will show how
many packets are matching outflow you
can actually see the status of network
traffic going across that link so let's
go down to our tax I think they're so
attacker
attackers gonna send an evil king and
will demonstrate here once we get it up
we have a person or triggering on things
and reason we did that is because things
have a really great graphical you can
see things getting dropped you can see
things getting how long they're taking
going and so we're gonna run this script
and have him glad it's not a live demo
will be a lot worse this is planned this
is planned it's a review
there's there will be a don't have
prizes you can just leave with your
dignity
presentation software for those of you
that have not seen him for like three
years on an enemy to presentations
really cool and here we go
not PowerPoint ok so they're sending his
he sending his evil beings and as you
can see look at this thirteen notice how
is taking a little while 13 took 11
milliseconds that is because that
traffic was just redirected
attackers still thinks he's hitting his
victim in reality he's not he's hitting
avian that we stood up inside our
honeymoon and doesn't realize it and it
this is you can do in maps can you can
do anything and they just continuously
scan that hosts him thinking that he's
still the same place when in reality
there's been no change he's actually
just talking to one of our host that we
are now fully monitoring what happened
here is our appliance triggered on this
attack as you can see it connected to
our door sport ever attack and built-in
sense flows to the controller detector
attack kills all the clothes and the
controller and our attackers fully
redirected to the next
let's real quick look at the at the what
happened here so the hosts on the honey
host has the same MAC addresses same IP
address as the as the original hosted
and so the controller thinks there's two
hosts that are coming out of two
different switches the controls little
confused but if we look at the source
and destination it's now no longer
following that original path we plotted
it's now going through the honey switch
into the honey host he's no longer
talking to the same host we've
completely dynamically redirected
traffic to get the isolate that attacker
fully so she can talk anything else on
the network except what we want him to
the implications of this are we can at
now due to those attacks we can now
spawn viens and spawned networks inside
that honey net so he actually thinks
he's pivoting within our network when in
reality he's in a glass box that we're
watching really incredible stuff through
we are able to send you know put up a
Linux names based for example listening
on port 80 he now thinks he's talking to
a web server that sort of thing is is
really easily done with soccer Defined
Networking redirecting that attacker we
love Sen and as we try to lose to USC
and here it's already being used is
being used heavily by large corporations
government entities and it's been used
for years and years being used as it
moves closer and closer to our homes and
and and you know this small small to
medium data centers that you guys might
you know frequent we need to be able to
understand at the end we need to be able
to recognize that security implement
implication that threats that are
inherent with it and we need to find
creative ways around that we need to
innovate and the Open Networking
Foundation there they've kind of been
the lead for development of the OpenFlow
protocol development of the OpenFlow
switch specification and they have a lot
of Brian from all these commercial
vendors but again on the security
community side of it
will require innovation and
collaboration among us to build that
framework STN can be a security
instrument that's the beauty of it
a traditional network moved package and
STN network can move packets smartly so
we can leverage the sensors that we only
have the appliances that we re how all
these things that we already have we can
leverage these interfacing with simple
programming and we can create a more
dynamic defense with internet work so
right now we love STN because it is a
network that can fight back so that's a
broad overview of St and insecurity
there so many rabbit holes that this
goes into so many beautiful aspects
depending on what you're good at so if
you're a coder is a lot of stuff to do
if your networking person there's a lot
of talk to you there
requires a community effort and that's
all we're trying to show here so at this
time that's all we have we're running a
little short on time if you have any
questions we're happy to answer them we
do have the set up over here I don't
know if we're gonna have time to pull it
up all the way but but what were your
questions we explain it really well for
everybody's really confused when we're
gonna be an awesome we got someone got a
heckler