without any further ado I would like to
introduce Karl who we talking about us
about reverse engineering SCADA networks
alright thanks for coming thanks for
coming to the the final talk of the
building track so today I'm going to
talk about reverse engineering wireless
cable networks so I'm sure most of you
are familiar with what that is but just
in case you aren't stands for
supervisory control and data acquisition
which is basically just a bunch of fancy
word for saying it's you know remote
control and monitoring an industrial
systems and these are you send a lot of
critical infrastructure applications
such as the power grid water supply oil
and gas lines things like that and over
the past few years it seems like it's
become the hot new things so you know
DEFCON and RSA you have the SCADA or ICS
village it's even finding its way into
things like the NDC in CCDC competition
where they have like students try to
hack this big SCADA network and there's
there's been so many talk submitted on
state us that even like the DEFCON and
and black hat CFP Board members are
getting pretty tired at that but this
these issues have actually been around
for a while so I was going back through
through the archives found this great
talk from 2006 which is covers all sorts
of fails with connecting the SCADA
systems to the Internet
their their first example is basically
they hopped on the power power
generation
stations wifi in their conference room
and got to Lake basically close to the
generator and then they were asked to
stop back in 2007 DHS did this fun
project Aurora test where they have this
diesel generator I believe that's
connected to this system and by I
believe what they are doing is
connecting and disconnecting it at
various phases such that it gets out of
sync with the rest of the grid and when
you connect it when it's out of phase
things get very bad very quickly and
then it just goes downhill from there
there's another view of that so now he's
just so you know with some packets
connecting and disconnecting a chorus
now there's things like shown in and
since this where you can just search the
internet for these state of facing
systems either through the three
specific set of protocols like the mp3
or Modbus or sometimes you'll see the
ENT interfaces to what they call the H
Meyer human machine interface and this
is a hobby enjoyed by many so I gave
this loves to scan the internet for open
VNC sessions and check out what what's
going on out there and you know you run
across all sorts of crazy things on
connected to the Internet like I think
this is green power system potato
storage farms yes I mean there's I think
he gave a talk in like five crazy things
that are connected to the internet or
something like skating rink think things
like that so there's been a lot of
attention on
SCADA systems connected to the internet
but the SCADA systems are not just on
the internet there lots of legacy
systems that use things like cereal
lines dial-up modems dedicated leased
lines from the phone company and of
course what we're talking about today
our radios and so around where I live we
were seen these interesting and tennis
sitting next to these interesting
working power boxes and we were
interested in what they were and how
they work and what they were doing as an
aside you'll find lots of interesting
things on the IRS spectrum so you have
like mobile data terminals for taxis
police you have a lot of other things
that are a lot of other utilities do all
sorts of things you have transportation
systems so like a train control things
like that so far this talk is sort of a
case study and and how I approach trying
to reverse engineer these types of radio
systems so that if you see something
interesting on on the spectrum that you
want to you to figure out and listen in
on this might give you some some
starting points but back to skater sight
we saw these boxes and we were curious
what they actually were
and as it turns out at least and
california's required by law that the
utility makes certain documents
available that basically describes
exactly what's in there and these these
documents are for developers
subdivisions for example and they'll
tell him hey you need to acquire this
equipment from us and install it this
way and and set up a certain pattern so
what's actually inside here is a patent
counts which which connects for the
neighborhood to the rest of the power
distribution system and that's that box
on the right there
the control signals for that switch and
they're sending signals for like our
current things like that
go back to this other box and inside
that box is what's known as a remote
terminal unit which does the actual
control of the switch and that
interfaces with a radio which does the
actual wireless link over over the
antenna so we were so we now know what's
what's inside the box so we we started
scanning around the spectrum and we
found some some interesting signals and
I don't think I have audio here but
radio and talking about conveniently
enough you can also look up these
frequencies in one of my favorite
websites the SEC website so you can put
in either your service provider or you
could search for particular frequencies
and see who owns that frequency and what
they're using it for things like that so
the first thing that we did is we used
in your radio to start listening to the
signal and plotting it out and trying to
figure out what it actually is so
because we could hear that with just
sort of a narrowband FM
demodulator in the EP suffer defined
radio tool that we were using that
suggested that it was some sort of we
could use some sort of FM demodulator
and get some sort of signal out of it
and so if you just set up a standard FM
demodulator and radio and then plug the
output you would see something like this
and this looks very interesting because
you can sort of see bits there it looks
very digital but there are some issues
here like what's up with with those
points away where they sort of in the
middle there it's it's not like a 10
they're sorta just in between and doing
some weird things and so we weren't
entirely sure how to decode this actual
signal so we went back to those
documents now as it turns out it says
that the radio is India's radio so we
did some searching on what in India s
radio as turns out in des is cancer
microarray data systems they were
acquired by General Electric many years
ago and they make radios for all sorts
of types of SCADA applications and so we
were hunting through the site and we
found what we thought was the radio that
was used in this in this system and so I
went to my other favorite website which
is still the ICC's website but a
different portion of it now as it turns
out in the us- to to sell anything that
transmits a signal you have to get an
FCC I D and get it approved by the FCC
and for that you have to submit a
boatload of documentation to the SEC
including him a text area of operation
internal photos things like that and
some of it you can request from the FCC
is website now unfortunately for us they
can request confidentiality for certain
certain aspects such as you know the
schematics and things like that on on
trade secret ground so usually you'll
see something and these systems
basically saying that we would like
these documents to be permanently
confidential except sometimes they screw
up and don't send that letter and so
turns out that we got the the theory of
operation and and block diagram for this
particular modem but it was really weird
it's so instead of it said let's see
here and use it as a continuous phase
frequency shift keying modulation that
we knew but it uses this crazy do a
binary encoding that we knew nothing
about there's very little information on
the internet about how that's actually
this dual binary thing what it is and
how it works and so this left us even
more confused because we weren't quite
sure what was going on there now as it
turns out this new binary set up
actually explains the little weirdness
here that's going on and so we actually
had to account for that too
to get bits out and so to explain what
what do binary encoding actually is take
a few minutes to talk about digital
modulation so when year when you're
sending a signal a digital signal
basically you're just sending a square
wave of a bit stream and the square
waves modulate a carrier and and some
some way so you could have amplitude
modulation frequency modulation phase
modulation can
do all sorts of fancy things without
that I won't go into much the problem is
if you just modulated carrier with a
square wave it'll take an infinite
amount of bandwidth and you can actually
experiment with this on your own and the
new radio so on the top here we have the
time domain of a signal that I was
generated basically it was sort of an on
off teen of a certain carrier and below
that is actually the FFT or the
frequency domain of the signal that is
coming out and as you can see it takes
up a whole bunch of bandwidth when
you're doing that and as you mess around
with the frequencies you can see
different things happening in the
frequency domain but it's basically just
all over the spectrum and so the reason
for this is that square waves are some
of harmonics and so it effectively
includes an infinite number of
frequencies so the way around this is to
remove some of those frequencies and
usually do that by by filtering
filtering those frequencies out miss
introduces what's known as interest
symbol interference where the individual
bets start smearing overtime and they
start colliding with each other and when
that happens it you can't tell what what
the bets are the symbols are anymore and
22 sort of explain why that happens
look at a wedding filters impulse
responses so imagine if you had just a a
a signal that was completely constant
except for a single lip at an
instantaneous point in time if you
actually look at what happens and you
put that through the filter you actually
get a signal that is spread over time
coming out of that filter this is known
as the impulse response won't go into
much detail about it but basically if
you have just a single instantaneous
blip it can last for a long time and so
the actual way that you get around
intersymbol interference in making
systems is what's known as a raised
cosine filter and so this is the impulse
response for a raised cosine filter and
the interesting thing here is that so
the the symbol . it's T on this graph
and so at a time zero the impulse
response is is one so you have all the
energy there at multiples of the symbol
period the impulse responses 0 which
means that contributes nothing to the
instantaneous time domain signal and so
if you over ladies on top of each other
you get a bunch of these like nice
shaped sort of curse where the the
contribution from all of the other
curves at precisely the right symbol
time you get no contribution from those
those other those other responses there
and so this is how things are normally
done this modem doesn't do that instead
what it does is it uses what's known as
a controlled intersymbol interference
filter the reason they do that is this
basically doubles their their bandwidth
and gets closer to the theoretical
bandwidth limit of the channel
and the issues what is known as a cosine
filter which has intersymbol
interference at precisely one simple
honorable and so this is what that looks
like so you have the the impulse
response for two different bits here the
blue one which doesn't look very blue on
the screen and the pink one there and so
say time negative one
the blue symbols being set at time 0 the
pink ones being sent and in between they
add up together and then at all other
times they are up 20 they don't
contribute anything and so this means
that the actual signal depends on the
previous bet that you received and so
you can add these up in different ways
if you have one symbol of that sort of
going down and one simple going up then
the when you take a sample the actual
signal is at zero and this partially
explains why you were seeing those those
weird things in the signal there and
because this is a controlled filtering
doesn't last forever if you have like
multiple recurring symbols that are the
same of these positive going bumps then
you just get a nice steady steady signal
there so the other half of this is that
that filter that you apply to smooth out
those bit that you are sending it for
for various reasons its optimal to do
half of the filtering on the center side
and happened to fill teen filtering on
the receiver side and so we actually had
to recreate the filter that they were
using to fully get get this controlled
intersymbol interference and so
basically the way that you do that is
you have you know this
co-sign
function and you just take the square
root of of that because why do you take
the square root of that I forgot
whatever alright so so you can read it
and so they basically two to make a
filter you you take the impulse response
you want and in the time domain he take
enough inverse FFT of that and then you
got your your filter coefficients and so
that sort of looks like this if you do
and and and Python so you have your your
squared cosine function and then you
have your impulse response there and
then you're all good to go and so if you
apply this to a if you play this as your
filter coefficients 24 filtering the new
radio it can improve the signal so on
the middle there was our original signal
and on the top of their is is our newly
filtered signal and you you might notice
that the sort of excursions around zero
around the center are far less
pronounced there some other subtle
subtle improvements there but now it's
starting to to make a lot more sense and
so now we got to sort of the easy part
so few if you see a positive blip the
bits of one if it's negative blip
0 if it's AB 0 than the bed is the
opposite of what you last saw and so you
can actually start decoding this by hand
and coming up with a bit stream and then
you can try to reverse engineer that so
teams you know obvious where to sample
either at the peak Cir zeros but I
actually tried to coding this by hand
and got some weird gibberish out that
didn't really make a whole lot of sense
in fact that looked pretty random and so
what's an entirely sure way way that was
happening the FCC documents actually
explain some of that but not a whole lot
of that so for figuring that out we went
to the MDS website turns out you can
download the firmware for these modems
and these modems if you look at the
internal photos there have to process
areas there is an a bit microcontroller
and then there is a a DSP chip that does
the modulation and demodulation but
there's only one firmware image and so
we had to figure out which bites belong
to which processor so we had to reverse
the eight bit microcontroller that
manages the radio to figure out how to
code into the DSP and so we isolated
what the the the DSP code was then we
brought it and I and holy shit that
looks like a mess so like in this
architecture you can have three
operations per instruction and so you
see a lot of this year in like the
middle where it's going you know
whatever Impey are is on on one offer on
some operations and then simultaneously
it's doing the data transfer between
various registers and it is very messy
working and we couldn't get our heads
around it at all turned out it was an
Indian issues so we just swap the bite
orders and then everything looked a lot
cleaner it was still kind of a nightmare
to reverse engineer so we didn't go a
whole lot down that route but I'll talk
about some things we found in a minute
as it turns out you can also once you
account for the Indian issue if you just
plug the firmware as a bunch of 24 bit
floats you get something
looks like this which is very
interesting because you see those those
nice pulses there that we're like the
filter response that we created earlier
so you could actually just avoid doing
all this math and extracting extracted
out from the firmware just by
visualizing that now there is there some
complexity and there you need to know
the sample rate and things like that so
it's not quite straightforward there's
another part of the firmware memory so
it's nice to be july's things but it was
a pain to reverse engineer so we decided
that so early on we were gonna try to do
this completely justifiable observation
and you know not cheat and get our hands
on an actual modem but we broke down and
and realized that was probably the most
sensible thing to do so we went to
another favorite website in mind eBay
turns out you can buy these radios for
about 50 bucks off of ebay now you might
say that's not fair there's no bids on
that yet you can do a Buy It Now 415
they're pretty easy to acquire and so we
got one and weary tune into the ASM band
so we weren't stomping on any anyone's
licensed frequency and then we turned up
our way down so that we weren't stomping
on any GSM systems and then we started
sending bites through the serial port
care now as it turns out that is not a
standard serial port so you have to
figure that out as well and then we
started laughing the signal back in
canoe radio and you can ignore most of
what's on here except for the Deep
Purple Line they're not sure the colors
come through well on these projectors
but basically we were sending various
characters and we would look at
differences between the signal so for
example this is an A
and this is Abby and you go back and
forth thing he tried to try to see
what's different
and what's what's the same and so from
this week could we could establish a few
things first there was a standard
preamble just like repeating ones and
zeros alternating ones and zeros
followed by some other random sequence
that turns out identifies the type of
the modem no sub sequence of bits in the
bits that we decode it actually
translate that's a ski and we were
sending asked me to this radio so it's
still a bit unclear what what was going
on there if you go back and look at this
there's no room that the packets are
shown up so short that there's no room
for length field so we weren't entirely
sure how they were communicating how
long a packet was there is also no room
for say a CRC or anything like that so
it's starting to look pretty simple and
perhaps more interesting is the fact
that if you send like multiple letters
that are the same like a and AAA AAA is
not just UAE's back-to-back it actually
looks completely different and so this
probably indicates that there are some
sort of scrambling going on and this is
not for security but it's used for sort
of whitening the spectrum and sort of
spreading out making it look more random
for various signal integrity reasons
basically you want to make your your
signal sort of look as uniform as
possible and the frequency domain so to
figure out how they were doing the
splits Grambling we went back to we
actually annotated these functions they
weren't given to us
and the easiest way to find but
scrambling stuff and DSP code is just do
a instructions search for X-ers turns
out that X or is not a very common
instruction and DSP code and so when you
see it it's probably either a CRC or a
bit scrambler or something that does
something interesting with a bit strange
and so we we pretty quickly went through
this list we found you know CRC function
and we also found that scrambler which
is a pretty simple function so it
basically operates as a linear feedback
shift register where you shift bits n
and see some of those bets and shift
register are tapped out an XOR together
and then shifted back into this shift
register and so we can easily account
for this in our software and once we did
that we started getting asked you out
and that was very exciting for us
because now we can start potentially
listening and to the SCADA networks we
found some other interesting things from
disassembling this code so it turns out
they say that their bod rates 9600 well
it isn't and that caused us some
synchronization issues which was driving
me and saying turns out they have like
an off by one error in sending their
clock divider and so it actually
transmits at not 9696 18 which is a
little weird the individual characters
that they send are not your standard a
pic characters but they're actually nine
big characters and they use the most
significant bit to indicate whether it's
sort of an in-band
character that you go out the serial
port or its for some sort of out of band
management turns out you can actually
send commands to these radios over the
same channel as well and we discovered
that there's actually a couple of
different types of preamble that would
identify the modem either saying that
it's the sort of master station or the
the slate stations the master stations
just passed out there packets with idle
characters and it's one of those special
out of bands characters that indicates
that there's nothing to be transmitted
well these Playstations will send a
special out of an character saying I'm
turning off my radio stopped listening
to me because all you're gonna hear is
noise and you'll get garbage trying to
decode that so we wrap this all up any
fun package hold your skater and so if
you contest from from github and compile
it then you should be able to use our
our work to also listen in on these
these modems and get a character stream
out so that was about the modem gonna
switch a bit and talk about how the
modem is actually used in relation with
with the SCADA systems so these these
modems themselves are connected to what
are known as remote terminal units which
implement also known as a multiple
address service which basically means
that they are all listening to a single
master station and the master station
will pull these out stations or send
them or send them command by the
individual stations idea and these out
stations will only transmitted back when
they are polled by the master and this
map swell to the old multi drop serial
buses that were used
hardwired SCADA systems using things
like a bus and mp3 speaking of which
there are two major protocols for a
four-state up at least we we mainly
focused on the mp3 because that was what
was being used by the local utility and
what's interesting about these protocols
is that they were they were designed for
these older wired serial bus system so
they don't really take security into
consideration and so if you want to use
these over wireless links wireless link
itself has to implement security well as
it turned out the wireless link says
securities not my problem it's on the
higher level stuff and as you guess no
one implement security here so it's it's
all out there and the clear unencrypted
on authenticated and conveniently enough
these protocols are actually supported
and wire short and so if you either have
our Dr Stata module or if you go out on
eBay and buy one of these modems you can
just pay pretend to like neck at to turn
it into like UDP packets RTCP packets
and Wireshark will actually start
decoding this for you so might be hard
to read but you can't be highlighted
packet here is a response from station
5338 back to i-81 which is the master
saying I've got a response for a request
that you had some some values changed
probably voltage current terms something
like that so no the interesting question
is well how do you know what these
sources source IDs map too well turns
out that utilities like to label things
and that's actually maps up perfectly so
we initially we weren't sure whether the
mapping was was once when like that but
no it is it's it's very convenient
13 DMP actually defines what are known
as different types of objects and so you
can have like an analog value object or
a binary input or binary output things
like that and so these objects are all
addressed by some numerical I D which
are known as points we weren't really
sure what these points map too and that
sort of implementation specific so we
thought we were onto something based on
also more labeling by the utility which
said exactly what kind of pattern on its
which they had installed if you go and
google the manufacture followed by the
phrase DMP point . list you'll get all
sorts of interesting documents online
that will describe the mapping of these
point IDs to various things like point
for is the current for face a on which
one or status point one that these which
is open
status went to says that the switch is
closed they're also control point so
control point to will let you open and
close the switch by saying change
control point to to either open or close
you can do some other things you know
start battery test other weird things
like found this interesting there is a
control point you enable or disable wifi
there's also a control point to clear
the wifi intrusion alarm I have no idea
what the wifi intrusion alarm is but
it's a single bit that gets set that as
yes someone has tripled wifi intrusion
alarm and then you can send another
signal to clear very weird so
unfortunately these are to use that
we're sold by the the switch
manufacturer an integrated into those
switches as it turns out you don't have
to use the manufacturers are to use and
in our case another party you what was
being used so that none of the points
list that we found actually map to
anything so we decided to get creative
and just start listening to everything
and graphing and so we get these
interesting looking graphs hear it
crashed in the middle so we don't have
some data for a few months there but
basically this is graphing the values
are sort of bouncing around between Lake
negative 6600 and negative 7800 and so i
think thats about in the range of like a
single-phase voltage and a three-phase
13 kilovolt distribution system and so
we could sort of infer from this that
this this corresponds to the actual line
voltage and you can see all these you
know cyclic patterns and dive deep into
it and and have a good ol time but
they're the problem with this approach
is that we were only well we were
listening to everything all the all the
outstation have very directional
antennas and so we weren't getting most
of the packets and we were also getting
some corrupt packet so we weren't seen
everything and so one we have incomplete
data to its a pain to go through and try
to annotate this by hand and so what we
ended up doing is assuming that there
was a handful of similar configurations
and basically just using a simple
clustering algorithm to sort of try to
identify the different types of out
sessions are are to use that we're out
there on the network and so it's still
sort of an open question whether we can
actually map out the SCADA systems just
by observing these packet traces or not
but it's something that we've we thought
about at least so obviously if you can
listen you can also send and so before I
going into this big caveat here I am not
a lawyer but I'm pretty sure that mess
around the power grid is Tom dangerous
and very only go so all these attacks
are theoretical we didn't really have a
way to test any of these so take take
these 44 grain of salt because we just
can't try to implement these attacks so
it's simple attack the obvious one is
you know command injection send send a
package to one of these things to turn
the switch on attorney switch off and
because these are using
FM modulation to send to send their
signals it turns out that you only have
to be a few decibels louder than the
legitimate master to get your signal
through in this is due to what's known
as the FM capture effect where basically
if you are you are slightly louder than
someone else the receiver will lock onto
you and completely ignore
the the other senator and so we just
have to be a little bit louder a
slightly more simplistic slightly less
dumb attack is to do command injection
to the broadcast address so it turns out
mp3 has a special idea of like 65535
which means all our to use and so you
could perhaps and a switch off to me and
to this broadcast eighty I have no idea
what will happen I don't suggest that
anyone try this unless you have your own
like Archie you set up in the lab but
I'll be interesting to know that
actually works and of course the problem
with this is CNN to be line of sight
with all the stations that you want to
fact missus probably out the master
station site again you only need to be a
little bit louder again I've not
verified this so there there's still
some open questions that I have that
might be worth looking into for example
how does the master station get its data
it's on top of the mountain
well that's probably another radio link
and
turned out utilities have all sorts of
radio link some these are like 9600 bps
I've seen some on the SEC website that
are 300 megabits per second and so
that's that's pretty easy orders of
magnitude larger not entirely sure what
that is probably like to use
surveillance or something but I don't
actually know interesting thing we might
look at these out of band characters so
these radios you can manage them over a
serial console but you can also manage
them over the air so could we actually
send commands to these radios over the
air to return them and listen and on a
different frequency and then it doesn't
matter if the master station is trying
to fix things they're not listening to
the master station in another thing that
we want to try doing as its mapping out
exactly where various things are you
know basically doing were driving with
some pseudo doppler radio direction
finding thing so that sort of on the
back burner we'll see we'll see what
happens
so this is all about breaking the speed
skater systems how about fixing it well
and it turned out that utilities are
indeed aware of these vulnerabilities
the problem is that there seems to be
little incentive to to fix these issues
in a reasonable time frame so these
systems that are deployed have like a
thirty year lifetime and so if you very
expensive to go out and replace all this
infrastructure in the middle of its life
it's it's purely a cost for the
utilities you know changing it will not
generate them any more revenue I believe
they're required to do sort of a risk
assessment and report that to regulators
but I believe that most just say it's
an acceptable risk and they're also sort
of in a bind because turns out that the
vendors don't actually think that this
is an issue and so it's very hard to
find both or either secure radios or
secure or to use their they're just very
hard to to find it so even if utilities
wanted to fix this and had incentives to
fix this
not sure they could fix this easily
until they band together and start
pressuring the vendors who make this
equipment so stepping back and looking
at the big picture
curious you know how exactly how
pervasive these systems are so they're
all around my neighborhood in other
areas where i've lived I don't see them
at all I've seen some around Baltimore I
believe but not easy so I'm not sure and
you know a lot of there was a lot of
manual analysis that went into trying to
figure out what these signals are and it
would be nice if there is a tool that we
could just point at an unknown R F
signal and say hey tell me what that is
heart rate so one way that might work is
to try to force combinations of like
rates and modulations gain something and
scrambling patterns and things like that
and try to pull out some some
interesting information so it's very
easy to scan the internet now but it's
not very easy to scan the IRS spectrum
especially over a wide geographic area
so I think it would be interesting
someone were to try to tackle that
problem and
basically do see map of PRS spectrum not
entirely sure how that would work but it
might be interesting
a final point is that our security
through obscurity is basically over with
a new radio you can decode pagers you
can decode cheap GSM traffic you can
decode the project 25 radios which are
sort of the federal standard now for
official use you can Dakota area to be
packets which is like aircraft locations
and things like that
recently it has been working on decoding
Inmarsat an Iridium satellite messages
and and so basically any anything out
there that's not encrypted will probably
get listen to sooner rather than later
through the magic of software-defined
radio surtout to wrap up basically
despite major attention on SCADA
security over the years there's still
critical infrastructure that is exposed
over these non-gaap channels when you're
evaluating the security of the system
you sort of have to look at it
holistically don't rely on other layers
to provide security for you don't just
focus on on IP and again
Aref security through obscurity I
believe is is over so that I'd like to
thank you for your attention and I
believe we have few minutes for
questions
any questions
so the question was do you think it
would be possible to perhaps the
firmware on the radio units to bolster
security I believe the answer is yes
however you either need the cooperation
of be bender and they don't seem
interested or you need to try to hack
something together yourself and if
you're running you know the power grid
you might not want to rely on some happy
that you did yourself so I think
theoretically yes practically probably
not without assistance from the vendors
there is some room in the firmware for
letting you know or something