thank you so much I love my targets were
the fissures live or alternatively
collecting fisher's geographical
locations that honey pots so if you are
primed and ready we will jump right in
so first off a little bit about myself
i'm an application security engineer Sen
down in Austin Texas it's my first UConn
thank you and if you're looking for me
you can find me one bit bucket and
smirking at Atlassian for dinner so this
project for started with a trend that I
was noticing on both my personal and
corporate domains and it was quite a bit
of foundering out you can see that India
mark reports as well as mail being
forced from my domains and even in light
of the better defensive frameworks like
Center policy or detail more D Marek it
was still doing out so from your answer
to developing some curiosity is some
fraction of the spam was sitting direct
responses as you may have seen the
trademark example would be Nigerian
prince who wants to transfer his money
over to you in the us- credibility's
curiosity about the identity of these
people and annexed this problem tricky
is that you can look at things like mail
headers from these messages that come in
but that doesn t couple of the identity
of the person
the identity of the person from their
operations from there from their
malicious mail server is sending out
spam so much interest in the agency
these people but in aggregate so their
presidents were people send personalized
responses and get replies back but it's
hard to gather that data in any sizable
sample so when about looking at some
good examples of manual correspondence
between sisters and on the left here is
a recent TED talk it was a comedian who
decided to respond to a fishing message
operate here we have a common idea
supplied by people who are corresponding
does anyone know that is behind the
mustache card Nicolas Cage you got it
and it's kind of a 220 pop culture so
you can see in the bottom right there is
actually a book written about
correspondence between people and
scammers so this is all well and good
but I wanted to go a little deeper and i
thought i think is the most vibrant and
eclectic community that deals with
things like this for 19 yrs so if you
haven't heard of this group they have
damned if I the act of corresponding
with spammers since you asked for it and
I'm not getting to you what it's time to
be alive this is part called scan
bidding and this isn't just something
that you do this is something something
that's been simplified and something
that you can win and the way that you
win is by corresponding with these
people and convincing them to identify
themselves by sending a picture of them
balancing things on their heads
and of course this this is not a
hard-and-fast rule you can see the man
second from the raid they didn't dress
up as some kind of colonial era judge or
something but fear not if you're
unfamiliar with this the community
largely support your entrance into the
sport they have a mentorship program so
check out the website if you don't want
to deal with that they have an ethics
you and they deal with common questions
like What if they want to talk to you on
the phone and the extended community
answer is you tell them that you
suffered an illness and hearing is
damaged so this kind of give me some
some groundwork savings to cover if I
wanted to make this into an automated
systems I really try to distill it down
to a few key points hehe behaviors
automate and any successful instance of
this people
responses were their disbelief that
suspended the first person narrative
always in the appeal to the motivations
of the sender and I'm sure all of your
senior fair share of this damn these
centers will talk about religious
motivations monetary motivations
familial strife really anything that you
see in a soap opera is fair game for
people to initiate these conversations
from these behaviors and I kinda mission
statement for this project became clear
we're looking to appeal to the ways in
this case we're looking to meet his
success is manual correspondents in some
form of system they give some semblance
of the quality that we see in human
responses and from this mission
statement was born so I did get the logo
I didn't splurge too much this is from
Fiverr
$5 and the prompt a diva graphic
designer was any pot this and technology
and this came out within 24 hours so
thank you fiber 44 legitimizing this
it was 550 after I read for the record
so primary use case here what we're
gonna do set up a gmail account and it
will receive messages or anything
forward then see need to print and mail
is pushed into honey fish which will
craft a unique response and an
accompanying and we took some motivation
from the marketing industry here as many
of you know a lot of marketing emails
will contain a one-by-one pixel image
image such that when you open the mail
the market early able to tell when you
read it the reason that we use instead
of an image is because you perform some
rather fingerprinting when we get from
one of our fisher's so if you are a
visual learner let's go to the use case
once more we have a gmail inbox pushing
into honey fish and we have an excited
team of people working in mail but if
you don't have any friends you can set
up the mail to just come straight into
the inbox and that's fine do you go from
there honey fish works its magic and
crafts up a response to our fisher's
messages were sent out and some fraction
of those people in this case the guy
with the mustache will click through an
unofficial record the response thats
completing 100 fish so the actual
technologies Dec itself we use the
Google Ads API to push into honey fish
and fish itself is a doctor compose
system with forming containers we have
an engine X server which accepts the
mail pushes and pushes off to a flask
application and then class and send a
pic server that both takes forever to
smooth from the outgoing mail to whoever
it was that that may land in the first
place and that's record in red is as
soon as someone clicks through it's also
pushed into red is based on
still missing something so I told you we
need something that human responses and
Olivier answer to this is this man does
anyone who this is I told our response
doesn't count
another then Andrei Markov mister Markov
born June 14th 1856 and the Russian
Empire and his team mathematician of the
university of st. Petersburg known
primarily for Markov chains and a couple
of other contributions he changed his
facial here a few times over his
lifetime I tried to capture that you're
on the slide I also titled the images
into a chain that people would notice
and spark up chain over what this is
really quick and markup seen as a
sequence of directed graphs which may
sound boring to you but it's actually
pretty exciting so if you supply some
texts which were going to call an input
cord this it's going to choose the
starting point in that text and then
forum directed edges which carrier
weight and that weight is the
probability that we should transition
from their starting point to any other
words starting point so it's somewhat
randomized it's based only on the
current state but it also generates
pretty coherent and unique responses
because of that we had edged with a
probability so if you don't believe me
here is an example of market seems pop
culture unless we have car cause someone
took every word that Jon Arbuckle is
said and compiled it into a text input
corpus and it will generate Garfield
comic strips so Mark Kotsay network
similarly someone's create wine reviews
from Wine Spectator dot com as a text
input corpus and these markets change
her 81 reviews and I think you'll agree
with me this one looks pretty good like
a person might write and of course this
doesn't apply only to text it also
applies to things like jazz and I found
a couple
master's thesis is people will generate
jazz improvisations with Markov chains
interestingly so this is little doubt
that we're taking here so the next step
would be to find our own input corpus
that sucks all the boxes for us
responses person suspended disbelief and
inhaled a bunch of first if you take
nothing else away the word Corp hora
corpora is the plural of course this
free trade the trip to the Big Lebowski
that did not work it was not in first
person and it didn't appeal to the
motivations of fisher talks about
Germans and driving and the dude we
tried Project Gutenberg books because
those can readily available in text
format but the problem here is the most
of them are from the late 1800's so when
I tried it it was speaking he was
speaking Old English to me let's get
there and then finally there is a
website called the text file directory
Dr the DBS days nothing really funny
happened there but I had to fill the
spot in part of the slight so it was
then that I stumbled upon something
profound the holy grail of input corpora
for this project and that is the
personal finance subreddit
to think for a moment this is this is
really perfect its first person these
people have problems and successes
pretty much anything you see in a soap
opera I'm inheriting money my parents
are taking me out of the house where I
live I receive $3,000 it's it's really
perfect thx all of our boxes strife
financial burdens successes appeals to
the motivation of the center so it's
really great and with that we went onto
crafting a proof of concept we chose
situation five dollar-a-month droplet
block used at XYZ there is a $1 sake I
figure when these fissures read that
nothing
we registered email address under 56
self and then we created a Google
application and then started to the
address and got pushed up our inbox
forest sign up for spam and trial the
first page results there are a lot of
nice looking websites is created with
Twitter Bootstrap so good things like
Mel B and I tried all of them and after
signing up by David a 72 hour incubation
period and nothing really happened it
signed up for some innocuous newsletters
and some others that I got was insulting
responses I wasn't sure the other end so
where do they go from here I went back
to my friends 19 I found a guide
published in 2002 the talks about this
query up here I don't know what that
means people have this guestbook setup
where you can sign them with a nice
message and then from 2002 after signing
up for 45 and giving a high quality
camera through so the 419 heaters are
are as generous as they are eclectic and
they have a surplus 419 scam they also
have an authentic
everything is da crisis pretty easy so
if you want to use this yourself so next
time to install it going to hell but I
did pass over on the right side here
it's going to refresh browser
fingerprinting place we posted ject back
to our appointment here are
fingerprinting
Jacksboro others
here talking about hotel room talking
about $3,400 make some sense of this
when you don't do it too much it's like
staring into the Sun
let's talk about some results but time
will tell
talking about small business people and
it turns out to have an office building
up oil company from Brazil it was
talking about their sites from the
democratic national committee so much
honey fishery played so much that the
democratic national committee behind
very limited might be no responses but I
feel like that's not my fault because
they need so much that he was imposed on
me so if anyone can help do that again
please come and find me one more
honorable mention it in a way to put it
but I got it this morning before hopping
on the plane and it has been so happy
this person's hells bells and they can
cure cancer or AIDS but the interesting
thing is this person isn't the one
performs the smells like a phone book
directory of each spell that you can
purchase a different person for each one
of the things that person can do for you
number five is pretty notable
talk about the next steps right away the
value of responding via my gmail account
versus things like being in compliance
with however the 419
what I like to do they like to you once
I get more click-throughs Mathies onto
coming from those dishes like to have
liked you will be coming up in a couple
of special thinks Romney and Ryan home
in Darfur general inspiration been a
pleasure
are there any questions I can answer yes
question is about the Markov chain could
actually use a third-party library
interesting tidbit it's pretty good in
it was published by someone who works in
the death of BuzzFeed so make of that
what you will but they were truly great
any other questions there
come and say hi everybody