well good morning everyone welcome if
you if you're looking for the Great
Expectations obviously that's not this
presentation I am Molly I'm a threat
hunter we've concepts and I'm gonna be
talking today about kill sue which is
part of the equation groups exploitation
framework from dander spirits my
colleague Lacey who did her research
with me can be here today so I'll be
doing this so so first of all let's
quickly go over what we're gonna be
covering today we're going to break
through that we're gonna break down into
what you'll see is how it works and how
it behaves and the actions that you can
do and then we're going to do the cracks
the research which is what happens when
it's installed how it cysts on on an app
on a host and equally how you can detect
and remediate these infections so
obviously this breaks down to the first
question is what is kill sue so kill sue
is a post exploitation infinity marginal
mechanism it was developed by the
equation group as far back as 2013 it
was then leaked by the shadow brokers in
2017 in the Lost in Translation leaf the
equation group are although it's not
confirmed they're strongly to just be
associated with the MSA this makes this
a state actor exploitation mechanism
which is object makes exceedingly
sophisticated if the association between
the original USA actually does Crennel
that's equally interesting because at
the time back in 2013 the NSA had an
agreement the prism program which was
bring one between the NSA and several
companies within the eating industry
that access to things I can cryptid
emails and communications but a parallel
to this they've developed this
exploitation framework to have
unauthorized access to Windows systems
and also other such framework
kill suit is included as far as we know
if within the dense bits and the United
rate framework the database frame will
be no because that was inside the week
the United rates framework includes it
as the instruction manual that has it
has direct references to kill suit
installations so that's just a basic
overview about what kill suit is but
more interesting is what kills suit does
so kill soup is the post exploitation
paper tea mechanism so a bit of a
mouthful but what that exactly means is
quite important so we we drew a diagram
to try and illustrate what exactly that
means so where the pedal chief agent is
the malware that is deployed by the by
the fuzzy bunch can be used by first
plants to exploit and the dance bricks
framework communicates with the poaching
agents on a infected host to then
install kill suit
so kill suit is installed after the fact
Mosu allows for lots of different
malicious capabilities and equally it
allows for additional modules to be
stored underneath instances so corrosive
breaks down into instance types and
modules items and kills to that some
kills to instance types have particular
messages capabilities whereas module
capabilities tend to be capacitive in
the nature the each of those instance
types one of the instances actually
allows for a penalty
agent to persist through reboots using
the advanced bootloader so time or so T
which we'll cover in a lot more detail
later
so each things in someone your as I said
has a difficulty this is a list of some
of the instance and module names that we
know of as you can see in the top left
there's a publishing instance type which
is specifically for systems on pearl
cheap agent and these all have very
unique functionalities but as I said
these incidences and modules and knowing
how they fit together
is quite important
so instance types like maybes magic
being so it's service slow behave and
brief raff they all have different
malicious capabilities or which I'll go
over in a moment and each instance type
can have multiple modules installed
underneath them these modules tend to
facilitate additional functionalities
for those insolence types one of the
things there's actually worth noting is
that hill suit has the capability for
operators to inject their own customized
modules which aren't necessarily already
within the framework as we found it we
couldn't find a way to actually how
these modules are created but it's
definitely something worth looking into
as I'll see that that wines over to so
many other malicious nasty methods well
what we want to some of the code names
as I said we're going to quickly run
through some of it abilities it wasn't
the focus of research so I'm just into a
basic review of some of the ones that we
know about so as we said about magic
bean magic bean is a wife on in the
middle wife I'm and middle-distance type
basically it allows the infected host
and act as a man and little operator the
instance type installs driver drivers
necessary and injection tools to allow
for the operation to take place and
basically it does this cover do so
highly effective host sunny can redirect
traffic you can inject things it can
capture that sassy set which is quite
cool next one is dark skyline that's
darling is not instant type it's a
module so this can actually installed
under any instance type that Cusick has
and this basically allows for complete
network network packet capture the
interesting about this is that packet
captured his Buddhist of disconnection
quite tailored so you can do for
specific web services or anything like
that once the operator has decided that
you know they want to get their stuff
back it actually formats the capture
package into a pickup file before
transferring it back to the operator
through kill Susan cryptid traffic's
thing to do a killer suit is encrypted
so everything is I the operation is
effective them inside the insta cycle is
encrypted and all the communications are
encrypted using instance type specific
keys so each instance will have its own
different encryption for each
installation next one is so Barnea I
actually really like this one
although it doesn't it's a bit rare to
use so if you have an air gap machine
and you're somehow effective you can
actually this enables the Wi-Fi if
there's a Wi-Fi card installed that's
just disabled it reenable
to allow for exfiltration using their it
groups of channels back to the operator
so effectively bypassing design the
earth net you can then have another
traffic for exfiltration that's what I'm
quickening over is a flew Avenue now
Japanese really cool flew avenue and
doorman calls are the two custom tcp/ip
stacks that the equation group built for
kill soup and basically they avoid
detection by not touching the windsock
api they completely wrote their own
stack so this are on a lot occasions
avoids things like meta analysis or any
logging that would be to do with that
API in practice he also intended to
circumvent a lot of network packet
capture tools during operation we did
have a couple of like Wireshark
instances on there but the traffic
seemed to be very isolated for the
amount of traffic that we knew was going
through so how it actually got around
using that was was really cool it also
has the capacity to do dns redirects and
things like that so it allows you to
basically pivot and create your own sub
network through infected hosts which was
really cool so I said so we've just very
quickly gone over a few of these his
abilities the capabilities were actually
the main research 'fuck bilities was
actually done by God called Francisco
DiNozzo so if I don't really wants to
look more into this do look his work as
his stuff you've really good of this
there's a lot of that list of the
instance types that we have most than we
still don't know what they do so if I
was interested dude so now we're going
to move on to the crux of our research
which is what happens we kill seasons
so our research was to find indicators
of compromise for killed suit on a host
based on active installation legacy
installation and their persistence
mechanism so what exactly happens when
they burrow into a system so to do this
we use these criteria the attack machine
was based on a Windows 10 with the lost
in translation
leak basically deployed and enables each
victim host was when a certain probe
which was freshly installed each time we
used on our message API reg shot you
know the standards statin axis we used
radar to fill both the binaries for the
framework itself and for the memory
dumps of subtly injected into so we can
see what's going on we also actively
adapted scripts inside the framework so
obviously get a specific output for
different variables to see exactly
what's going on we're going to focus on
kill suits so we're not exactly gonna
focus on how you compromised house using
as I fuzzy bunch because that's been
investigated to death we're going to
quickly go over how we did compromise so
we've built this little table so the
attacker we use and one of those punches
exportations eternal blue bandit one
knows who turn a romance and so forth to
get foothold on the victim it will then
use double Polestar to inject the DLL
publicly payload into an active process
standardly this is alpha however the
operator can decide which process they
want to inject into we use calculator
because it was much easier to filter
through on that one once we start
running it runs it then calls back or it
can be listening we got it to be active
after about 93 seconds which allows the
denseness operator things to connect to
the pedal chip instance on the host and
that thing gives an active agent which
gives bi-directional
seater connection then kamala control so
now we know how we've got it was set up
what is the weird stuff that happens
when you kill su is installed by
paratroop on on on a on a victim so one
of the first things that we notice that
so we try to fight some things that
happened repeatedly in each installation
so we could find
I'm consistent four indicators are
compromised the first thing we saw is
that it kept checking the system setup
in progress registry key now this is
used for the Auris running state between
setup and regular running running states
this happened at the beginning and the
end of every installation for kill sue
now this isn't this check isn't exactly
super abnormal I mean this is a bit but
it's not out there we did what we did do
is we try to configure the value to two
is equal to zero one and it made no
difference what the value was which was
quite interesting so we stand by the
speculation one was it looking for all I
customized by the value that wasn't
meant to be where we tried loads of
different variables inside there but we
couldn't actually get it behavior any
differently so we began to speculate
that instead there must be another
component to the framework the once its
installed must inject something in there
if the value is then corresponding to it
acts differently but we tried every tool
that we could find and we can go to
misbehave so although it was consistent
it's not the greatest indicator
compromise on that one so instead we
looked at we look for something a bit a
little more odd to ingest and the Auris
running type and we came across what I
like to call that the James Bond
function system function wi7 which is an
advanced API called the kernel and it's
used for interim our hash generation
using md4 now this was obviously found
in calculator so there's no reason--
calculator should be doing this so
that's two thou anomalous for that
particular process but I said because it
can you typically ingesting into things
like elf ass that depending on the
process can be a typical operation so if
an operator scre up observe the one pin
to calculate so this although anomalous
in some aspects isn't consistently
enormous but what was interesting is
that when it called this the hash that
was generated was then stored in a
registry value now the registry value is
OEM management or earlier MGMT with
these two 32 character randomized
directories when we looked into that
we saw that this on each installation we
inject into a different registry
location there's a taller than the frame
double feature
no double feature is used by the
framework in order to basically build up
a summary of what has already been done
to that victim and you can find down
here locate KS module store root matched
up to the registry that was dictor's
into now keen eyes might notice that the
OEM management and drive management are
actually different that's because
there's quite a few of them this is just
some of the ones that we observed during
our research and our examination of the
tool but what you might notice is that
there's that it seems to be broken up
into two bits so you've got the
capitalist which income left so you've
got drift and then you've got cash and
you'll see that they're repeated and we
found that these would then constantly
be repeated and different for
figurations depending on how many times
we installed it and so we thought we're
onto something here we then had the
hypothesis that this is two separate
lists being concatenated together in a
randomized function in order to make it
as as difficult as possible to print it
so we stayed on that premise and we had
it confirmed when we found the
concatenation operation or two different
string values in order to make this
directory so once we had this and how to
confirm that this is two separate bits
being spliced together we knew if we can
find these lists we can find every
combination but he also used to install
this modular encrypted database into
systems and lofty that would make it
easy for legacies detection so we start
focusing on finding this lesson we're
break it down to three areas we break it
down into whether the list is the
directory was communicated from the
attacker from the operator to the agent
whether the directory was decided when
the payload was first configured and
built before being transferred over or
whether the payload itself would decide
where to put it dependant on variables
to do with that individual system so the
list would be stored in the
payload and then Jesus variables it
would then decide from those lists we
quickly eliminated the idea that it was
a hard-coded into the parachute agent
because reuse of the payload didn't
generate the same results so we knew it
wasn't hard-coded into the pail and so
we then moved on to whether it was
decided from the attacker and to do this
we had to break down how exactly the
dancers framework communicated with a
pail of cheap Cajun when it was doing
TOC operations and that breaks down into
this sort of fly so the dense spritz UI
with trend within translate the user
input through various internal libraries
before handing it off to the core binary
which we've been communicate with
penalty page in which in turn within
acts with the kill zoo instance and The
Associated database so we began looking
at how the user impact interacted with
libraries so the deme library on the
desk or my new library we concludes very
quickly was specific for kill suit
interaction every single functionality
to kill soup goes through this library
and we found that this particular one so
connect is used for dynamically load and
unload different modules within a
corrosive instance
so once we've isolated this we start
breaking down how this how this worked
so it seems to basically configure a
message structure which is then sent to
the mcl tasking an RPC perform call so
we followed that functionality and that
borders to a separately the DFC library
now the DRC library performs action but
it does so by imposing a private library
from elsewhere the underscore DSC
library now this is important because
all interactions with the pedal chief
agent seem to go through this private
library and we could find no reference
to it in any of the library files that
we could find now let's create a problem
because if we wants to understand how
this works how it communicated and
ideally where these this restore we had
to get we thought we had to go access
this private library so we actually
started looking into the the core binary
by analyzing astatically to find any
references to see if we can understand
how this was done analysis of the binary
show there were references to several
functions within the private library but
we found that it was actually a external
cpython module library that was injected
at runtime so doing astatically all the
associated address were empty although
we defined reference is an error
capturing for the functions the actual
commands themselves were not stored in
the binary as it was so we still moved
on to dynamic analysis of the binary but
that in itself had a number of other
issues so the guys who built this the
greater group had obviously put into
mind about people doing this and there
were a lot of countermeasures for
analysis one of most basic was that it
actually detected hooks the debuggers
and would instantly terminate if it's on
so that instant will red flag of they've
done this to avoid analysis we were
actually able to disguise the debugger
and still get it to work but even then
all of the addresses where data was
loaded for this library were loaded and
unloaded as soon as they were acquired
and the index table for different
functionalities had multiple references
to the same function but a lot of them
were dummies and it seemed to move about
which seemed very very difficult and
because of that we were actually unable
to find this hid this private library
within the runtime and debugging of the
runtime binary which was disappointing
to say the least but we concluded that
if we couldn't clarify if it was there
we could at least try and clarify that
it wasn't decided of the payload level
so then we could focus our research even
further so to that we then moved on to
analyzing the penalty payload as it was
run and then when he tried to kill C
operations on a victim but this had a
number of other problems so looking at
the stack of where the Fellowship agent
was injected into we found that the
values and the functionality of the
agent well instead of being
injected into the process as we would
expect it was actually injected into the
kernel and we couldn't exactly figure
out how they've done it so it was
injected in a way that we can actually
retrieve the values that we were looking
for
so although we knew the pochi version
was injected into a specific process we
were unable to actually extract the data
we were looking for so because of this
we actually got to our last resort where
we reverted back to trying to use their
own code against them so inside the
framework there was a pedal cheap
analysis tool PPC crap that you could
use to display internal that values of
the payload and although this provided a
lot of information about how a payload
is meant to behave and was communicating
to you so if you could find one you
could obviously find out a lot of
information about how it was designed to
behave it didn't include the values you
were looking for and through the tables
or valuable values or anything to do
with the registry Varrick ship we were
looking for so again we had conclude
that this is eluded us in this point as
well we weren't exactly happy at this
point because these two lists we knew
they were in here but we were unable to
find them and really exhausted our level
of people to you for a reversal in these
tools basically due to the level of
sophistication that could interface to
prevent us from looking at them if
everyone has an expertise on novice Eve
looking at this or he's interested
please talk to me after because I'd love
to get like other people working on this
because that list is that part is really
annoying there but although we couldn't
find it here we didn't give up so you
know you learned how to fail in your
carry on anyway so we went back to the
installation and we began analyzing in
my new detail all of the different
operations that happen and we decide to
cross-reference all the different
installations to see if there was
anything that promoted a pattern and
eventually we came across this which is
a cryptographic provider type which was
referenced at each fresh kill suit
installation for a fresh pedal cheap
agent but only on the first installation
now the reason this stood out was is
because it occurred each time so we
investigate is type 0 2 3 and the
provider type
the first thing to note is what is a
cryptographic provider type so a
cryptographic provider type is basically
a description on how an encryption
algorithm is TP use and what values
there - to do in order to get the
outputs they require so Microsoft
includes a number of them by default for
RSA a yes so and so forth so that it's
uniform across all the fed machines and
it has types 1 3 5 12 13 18 24 it does
not have a default value provider type
of 23 so this provider type is actually
an abnormality from the default values
of Microsoft provides this is this was
further proven by looking at the
provider type table that Microsoft
provides although the documentation
isn't always full this from all the
instances that we saw nothing seemed to
deviate from this from any system with
that we looked at there's also no
reference to a type 0 TV provider type
any way that we could find historically
speaking there happinesses of type 0 TV
being in systems but this is typically
been because of sort of so bit of
history back when Windows NT 4 was out
it was a commissioner to be used by UK
government but GCHQ mandated that it had
to have a customized cryptographic
system in place so they actually built a
customized version of Windows NT 4 with
a customized provider type inside that
would then be used for their
communications so you could speculate
from that that this tool might be trying
to detect whether this is a custom build
of Windows to try and find specific
targets but that is just speculation so
from this we did find that type 0 to 3
was a consistent installation point
across all instances and from that
there's some success so we had a mixture
of a semi conclusive list of registry
directories that we got through our
experimentation although we didn't have
the list themselves we found that the
registries that we were seeing starts to
repeat each other I don't see if you
then splice them and see that each
section of them was being repeated in
different configurations you can
therefore get every combination
from the list that we have to generate
quite extensive list of places where it
could be stored although unfortunately
we can't say for sure that it was
conclusive
we also found that the type 0 2 3
because it was uniform allowed for a
[Music]
active installation detection by
basically examining registry queries so
from those 2 points we had both a legacy
installation and an active installation
detection point to focus on which is
quite cool but although this is the
active installation what about
persistence so I talked earlier about so
T so it persists using the stoller time
boot kit which is built by the equation
proved now this is an extremely advanced
food clip at the time it works by
basically injecting well into Bukit so
injects into the bootloader of the
system and it allows for all kill two
instances to be rebooted at each boot
and as I said earlier kill sick
incidents can be configured in order to
reboot the penalty view in students
allowing and control a command control
of an infected host this is the only one
that we know to work up to supported
Window System so works up to Windows 7
on legacy vu he doesn't work past
Windows 7 but I'll see where something's
still supported and widely used so this
is something of interest but first of
all how does Windows 7 boot
so to understand how so defects machine
you need to understand how a system
boots itself up so a system works by
obviously powering on initiatives the
BIOS which communicates for Hardware
does Hardware checks
this in turn loads the Master Boot
Record which then loads the active
partitions which in turn knows where the
operators to files are and then loads
the bootloader for that operating system
so to folks so timing focuses on this
error so the transition between the
Master Boot Record and the acts of
partitions hanging off to the bootloader
and in this section the system looks
something like this so the master
pre-record will load the volume Boot
Record into its own memory location
rated over itself in light memory
in turn within start the initial program
loader which does a number at all which
lays the filesystem and the boot manager
location and then hands off the control
to the boot manager which then loads the
operating system so let's get down to
what summertime does how does certain
bug so its first as worth noting that so
the time has been encountered before
under the name of gray fish by our
friends over SK labs and they basically
did an overview about how it acts within
the system and the sequence of events
that happens but they didn't give a lot
of technical detail about what exactly
what changes were made in the system in
order to allow this to happen or how to
remediate or detect it
so that's where our research came into
it the subset that we used for our
research was Windows 7 sp1 using a I Pro
GT debugger and infection was the same
as the previous one so using fuzzy bunch
with a vinden spritz
and the persistence was kill su
persistence you apparently persistence
using kill suit in order to analyze
safety in great detail so let's get
right into the crux of it so what you do
to be back so this is so the first thing
it does is actually it prevents disk
prevents boot harinama
and by changing this this value inside
the MBR so instead of using a whole
command which would then cause a system
arrow and then cause error recording and
instead makes this jump command back to
its own location so we're just loop
indefinitely preventing it from error
reporting so if certain time ever fails
to boot or for whatever reason there are
subjective later but caused it to crash
it will never tell the operator about
why it's happened and will never give
any information which is quite an
elusive method
I don't we thought those people the next
thing is that the initial program mode
our location is typically 7 7 a but son
of Time Machine changes
the reason it does this is that 77a
instead of having the initial program
motor it injects a number of subtle
times specific datasets and it does this
for operations that I'm going to have a
later which is really funky but because
it injects it at this location it has to
move where it and then lose the IPL so
within the IPL it will do these flag
checks which are under which are again
not normal so rather than just loading
the index route before handing off to
the boot manager instead it will do an e
CX register check to see if it's set and
if so it will load a customized index
route which will contain the boot
manager the malicious boot manager
location now although this checks
whether it's set web site I'm using stop
we didn't find any instance or method
shoot unset inside the configuration so
we're not sure why checks this registry
flag or we know is that it does and this
can be seen more clearly here so it
injects this check and if the check is
unsuccessful it still loads the original
uncustomary index route so it has the
capacity to load normally without some
time even though it's injected solar
phone which is a bit on so although
these changes odd where exactly does it
handoff to malicious code so this can be
seen in the IPL where at the bottom here
ad actually injects a jump to his
malicious code 9 3 ie this is basically
this attempt to change the control flow
and allow it to start doing its nasty
work once he jumps to this location
what exactly does solar time do so first
of all it does a BIOS interrupt 15 this
basically gives it a information on how
the signals configured what type of
memory it has what memory length it has
over 1 megabyte and other system
information if the memory type is what
it requires it then enables enables
access to memory over 1 megabyte by X
rating
at the a20 bus line and once it's done
once it's enabled this extra memory it
loads the MFT tape MFT table records in
order to find a object ID file within
the MFT records within this object file
it inserts the index root of that file
for for the location of the hidden boot
back now the object the index root of an
object ID file is not called in decree
it's actually called dollar o now IPL
programs don't typically look for it so
how does solar time know what it's
looking for so earlier I mentioned that
sort of time had to change where it
jumped to for the IPL that's because in
the same location it actually injects
the definition for the index root of an
object ID file so it knows what to
search for but it also injects
decryption and keys and methodologies
and methods for its payload that will be
used later on so it has to move the IPL
reference follow these two bits of key
data so using that that defined dollar 0
is now able to extract the index row of
the object ID file in order to search
for it's malicious food lighter that's
hidden inside one of the references but
how does solar time know which in what
what value is written into and whether
malicious is well to do that we have to
look at how a index entries out is
actually created so these extra entries
formed up of these individual parts but
you might find that between our line 8
and vcn there's no defined length and
that's where so design injects the it's
the offset from the start and class of
the MFT
so it basically installs the offset from
the being of the MIT file to where the
malicious file is stored within the file
system itself now so it can search
through for any value in there and find
the buddy was looking for anybody else
and Jaclyn's at that point and extract
it and then look for the file
we found corresponding to a TrueType
font file which is where it actually
stores it's malicious kernel which is
Michener's kernel driver which is in
uses with which has been used for the
bootloader using the check so T script
within the framework itself once you've
compromised a host you can run this
script to see what service time files
have been injected so in this instance
we found that david p i dot t TF was it
was injected but following that scope
you actually found that list of all of
the TTF files that can be used in order
to store this malicious kernel driver
which was which is pretty cool so once
the boot pack is loaded into memory so
once it's found this malicious kernel
driver what does it do with it well it
loads the mist-covered rabbit into
memory and then using the functionality
that was stored in the IPL location it
then decrypts the packet using the keys
the key that was stored over location
the key that's injected into the
original IP allocation is generated
using crc to hash which is based out of
the malware which is just about a
thousand times I mean it then uses that
hash generated by that to decrypt it it
then calculates the hash of the internal
malware against the hash that's
installed in the decrypted malware to
see if they correspond for an integrity
check if the integrity check passes they
then hands-off controller to the boot
back and after that all of the kills two
instances will be loaded can achieve
instant scan reinitialize and so on so
forth so that's that's how solar time
functions but the crux of matter is how
do we detect an immediate if kill series
on a system so we've gone over how we
can see if he's still what it does when
it's installed
what sort of time does once it gets on
to us how it sits but how do we detect
and remediate these points so for
installation it breaks down into the
type zero to three cryptographic
prototype which is done at each first
installation by paratroop agent this is
some function number seven
conical which although can be
depending on the process is not
conclusive as depending on what the
operators injected into presence of any
of the permutations of the British
characters that we talked about earlier
the lists we have a fullness that
obviously you buyers can access bar can
give references to and you and there's
also this this blank box so at the end
of our when we were coming to the
conclusion we re scanned through the
framework itself and we came across a
driver list
now the driver list couldn't say the mo
drivers that were relate directly to
kill sue their field suit loaded drivers
now the load drivers are used when
instances our first initialized although
we found this journalist we couldn't
find anything instance of these drivers
being loaded during our research however
we speculated that they were installed
and then onion stored as fast as they
were physically possible or they were
used at solar time use this with solar
time in order to create assistance but
we were actually unable to find any
reference of them so although this is a
point of interest we snot are conclusive
methods of detection but it is something
that you could easily plug in
transduction system in order to
speculate if any of these large list of
drivers independent than the present so
this gives a method for legacy
installation and operational
installation so although we know we can
now detect whether it is being a solder
has been installed how do you get rid of
killed soot if it is almost so Kelso
operates in this fashion so the boot
pack the poetry of instance and the
running instances all communicate with
the encrypted database within the
registry so if you remove of the
registry all of those functions ceased
activates so the solar time has no kill
sue data in order to boot the running
instances don't have their module stores
so they don't know how to act and the
penalty Beijing has no index reference
for the registry in order to know where
the kill su modules are installed so it
can't it can't communicate or perform
any actions so moved in the database is
the most effective way of neutering kill
su the location that the database has
I've gone over several times is
obviously within one of those registry
locations and but there are others that
we may have not seen
but if pursuit is installed with so
totemism we put in the system we dope
this is all bunny enacted memory he
doesn't drop the disk unless you
installed so no time so how do you
notice other times installed so earlier
on we quickly grazed over some of the
changes it makes and one of the things
that it does is it changes this section
to use to not jump not operations before
I jump to the IPL control so we focused
on searching for those to knock commands
where they shouldn't be
to do this we actually adapted pi MBR
which is a open source script for
analyzing MBR files and instead injected
this debt and VBR by with a saudi
detection for bytes to six seven and two
six eight for the not operations and
essentially saying if these two values
are found within this Turkish way
they're not meant to be so no time is
installed which on all the instances of
testing we found to be accurate so every
time we installed so the time running
the script identified it correctly so
this was the conclusive method for
detecting it which is super awesome but
although we know we can now see if solar
time is installed using this method by
analyzing the VBR records how do you
stop or remove solar time and that's
more tricky because start a time
installs itself at multiple levels
including the firmware so the firmware
level shows they they had access to
production sort of level access in order
to change the phone my code equally
sometime is heavily encrypted as we said
it uses this well injected a decryption
system in order to actually access the
malware so a bypass there's a lot of AV
systems that look into this sort of data
and basically in order to prevent sort
of function you need to sign
manufactures need to sign that the MPR's
the VBR all of their sort of firmware in
order to prevent alterations now as we
said this works on Windows service
windows over the off the Lexy poo
however UEFI and Windows eight forward
using secure boot
Vence s because the checks are put in
place all the time can note on a
function because the checks detect it
and I'll see prevented from making
alterations in the first place all
preventing the mower from functioning so
yeah big quick any questions okay yeah
the registering of surveys yeah so all
the kills two instances created their
own instance within the register
database so that REM management
reference all those different conquered
configurations each instance would have
its own injection into the into the
registry and under that each module the
32 bit randomized counter after that
would be each module installed under
that so some instances have by default I
think three modules installed where some
of the money have to so depending on the
instance type you can see which modules
are installed an equally if you then
installed a custom module underneath
that instance all say darkstar like for
example for packet capture that we been
injected under that richly location as
well but it's all good
we did look into making custom modules
we couldn't actually figure out how the
hell they built them so we found
references to obviously how it works we
found the scripts that obviously
references the data but we couldn't find
when the bodies themselves are actually
stored so we can figure out how they
were coded or whether they also use they
used to use a custom scripting language
which is specifically the dance scripts
framework so we suspect that because
these original modules were built back
then they may use the same scripting
language but we were unsure at the time
but that wasn't thing we did look into
I'm listening