one of these even start this days was
high New Zealand's Prime Minister to
sender or describe the 15th March 2019 a
government entered they all nor mosque
in recorded during the time of the
Friday prayer I'm the open fire and
Ackroyd of anywhere from 300 to 500
people we're not sure after murdering 51
of them and injuring 49 he proceeded to
the to the limit Islamic centre and
software when they were calling saddened
more and injuring and under no mines
I recently he's just pleaded not guilty
in a court of law offer but so this
clear that the government was a violent
with that's cleared the gun was violent
and since this is a current we've
learned that he was a white supremacist
extremist who announced his plans prior
to leaving the ice on Iran the politics
orientated board of this Ikea champ
which is a popular image board which
people like this 10 congregate he say he
set up a public live stream and
advertised it here and also compared the
mass security I didn't see in the first
line there a real life afferent post
which time he gives the game up this is
like a that's a clear tie between his
behavior on the internet and the actions
which occurred on this day and I just
like to river it like he didn't pick the
gum up by chance and like like let's
talk is essentially exploring how we got
here and hi the system's Richard like
arrogant of functions have enabled this
and potentially what we could do better
to what was so a few spinners obviously
my opinions on my own don't reflect
anyone else's my employer would still
love to take your money even if you
disagree entirely with everything with
what I say
I don't reflect the opinions the
industry and I'm effectiveness in steel
conned so please come back if you're
even if you don't like the talk so like
this is all like this isn't a published
study I'm not an academic in country
violent extremism and I'm trying to be
conscious of my own biases but
and tell you right now that I'm not
trying to mislead you so if you think
something's wrong
have you think that I've taken results
in the context I would appreciate it if
you were to let me know rather than
lighting me up on Twitter for being
whoever so like obviously I've got a lot
to learn but hopefully you guys also
have something around so there's some
way I can help
politics is ubiquitous politics is
everywhere and UK like you can deny this
and say well actually attacking like
tech isn't political and this is a
security conference and just like the
focus and attack but the actions that we
like like the actions we partake in our
daily lives and the things we do for
work day are the political impact on
someone and ignoring them is a political
act in and of itself so again this is
another slide to say if you disagree
with me that's fine
the stuffin of fact and you're certainly
not a bigot for doing so this hope will
also contain references to neo Nazism
white supremacy anti-abortion violence
and radicalism Adam so it's not going to
come around or it's not going to be
mentioned or talked about severely for
another ten minutes so please feel free
gets to pop I did anytime like it's not
a big deal it is being recorded so you
can watch it later skipping that you
want to see and there will be overt
intentional descriptions of political
identities so if that's something
they're not perfectly comfortable with
then you call the diversity minimus so
scissor idea recap of the talk I can't
open internet fight extremism already in
the begin the Internet has always been a
front line in the battle for freedom of
expression when I stand up an Internet
perhaps I better because I'm a better
phrase or a better term of the word
might be open and free which is used to
describe an Internet which is not only
accessible but also permits a dialogue
of some description
so essentially you could work that in
title how do you protect the people who
are victims of violent extremism
while also keeping the internet open to
this end-to-end open the free speech
because we're we grant responsibility we
also grant rights to take action
and that's not always good so before we
go and talk about extremism on the
internet it might be helpful to
understand what extremism is and I've
just noticed that I interchangeably use
the terms extremism and violent
extremism and extremism and of itself
just means a a radical new point like so
like not all extremism is bad and our
society is in many ways extreme so if
you're really passionate about something
please don't think that I'm trying to
get you booted off the internet it's in
that unless it's you know quite nonsense
so the definition that the the
Department of Homeland Security has in
America is the violent extremism refers
to the beliefs and actions of people who
support or use idea ideologically
motivated violence to achieve radical
radical ideological religious or
political views
so we've comfortably broken installing
into two groups who are wealthy about
the Obama administration did so we've
got ITU which refers to international
terrorist organizations and they've got
HV such as homegrown violent extremist I
mean it's it's not that that's not
always accurate description that's not
that clear-cut because there are
international terrorist organizations
which they mainly use wrong room violent
extremism as a way of like reaching
their ideological goals but again we'll
get to that later so now we know what
the extremism is how does someone become
an extremist why do we like get there
because I assume we're not born
experiments obviously I don't know but
the specialists refer to the process in
which we come closer to accepting
violence as a legitimate means to an
ideological religious play goalie okay
and which drive for protectionism as
radicalization
so radicalization tends of two factors
you've got the push factors which tend
to make the the norm shall we say less
attractive for the person I'm with also
the poll factors so the poet the
pressure factors can be a feeling of
like marginalization
so like the things of inequality
discrimination persecution and just
really any ingredients you won't like
there's a lot
like politically violent grips and they
all kind of have their own reasons for
being politically violent it is invalid
this is next so I'm like really anything
and then they'll also make themselves
more attractive as a as a group that you
could join by like being organized and
offering employment in exchange for like
service to the scrip or offering money
or like supporting the community that
sort of thing something we find quite
common with young homegrown extremists
is that they'll act like a sense of
identity there's a there's no purpose in
their life there either
like a common trope for particularly
white nationalists homegrown extremists
are that they're on employees know a lot
of friends to this stuff so like most of
all like there's a really strong sense
of camaraderie in these groups because
they generally don't really have much
else like there's a real sense of
belonging that this causes Michaels and
I'm with my friends and we're fighting
for it so like and this where like if
someone talked with online so whenever
we talk about like I'm extremism online
these generally reasons that they do
this because in the vast majority of
cases and extremists would not be like
on the Internet in ppreciate of their
actual ideal to go in there we generally
be in support of it so for instance
you've got fundraising because like
obviously this stuff costs money and
there's only so much fun reason you can
do in the high scrape for your political
organization so I almost need to take to
the Internet where they can find people
who are more sympathetic to their cause
and naturally hopefully make more money
recruitment
so again similarly just being connected
to so many people it gives more more of
a chance for you to recruit people here
so that you didn't Harrison Belvedere
cause you're radicalization which is the
Dajjal discuss the process of making
your views seem more palatable more
accessible
trilling so like Italy especially stated
to the international terrorist
organizations that use terror cells
where we have the internet used as a
means to distribute training materials
and like YT videos essentially for
everything to do with
like their ideology whether that's in
the case of political Islam like literal
like feel like theology and like
education about it and like then going
to like creating your own poison gas and
like Michael ID you get away with an
arson attack and things is not so and
let's see there's intimidation and where
we building world war even worse
familiar with this would be the first
kind of experience that social media had
with why the like widespread terrorism
on on their platform would be Twitter
and Isis so a huge function of Isis
propaganda campaigns and Mayor Lee and
all these was to simply say like like we
are the Caliphate we are back I'm like
it's like a show of force essentially so
it's useful for all these things but
that's that's enough lesson of terrorism
for one section of the talk we're not
going to talk this is talks broken down
into a section will be about the
technology and ended by the extremism on
technology and will end up we start all
the way back in 1969 and we should end
up with the present-day so as you can
tell us a lot of history so there's
gonna be a lot of stuff on this site
what I would like this today would be a
primer rather than the comprehensive
guide and all of the extremism that's
ever occurred on the internet and holla
visa so a good place is I need to start
would be ARPANET so any and then this
first technology section will be
primarily looking at the
decentralization which occurred in the
design choices off the early internet is
this quite important as so like whenever
we get to the free speech discussion
later on the like the internet and even
it even in this conception if we can
separate what you can't if you can
separate design choices from like a
political ethos essentially the internet
was always set up to be decentralized
and originally there's some debate on
why that is some people say that it's
like this new system so this is the
first diagram drawn with the ARPANET of
the Cova connecting for computers but
that system works well for a number of
reasons there's John Baron says that the
ARPANET was design make this so it was
on things like like a nuclear war that
will destroy you almost among the
control systems other people disagree
and say
four so like so like anyone in the
United States could easily connective
supercomputer anywhere else that sort of
stuff
so essentially survivable networks was
what that dark net and redundancy is in
the game they're the very core concept
about a couple of years later 20 or so
we end up with Usenet which is a
decentralized system for moving content
and sharing content in which essentially
the the indexers as I believe they're
called will propagate content to the
next ended like to teach and actors it's
connected to so if any one of these
servers are compromised to root on the
information we'll still be able to share
through the decentralized grade and this
is in my feeling I'm not sure the date
of it but it is showing the each
individual connection and actually have
one of those connections disappeared
unless it is like a like a load-bearing
connection and like you should see like
you should still be able to share a tree
so again that's another example of very
early decentralization you got DNS which
is naturally given that you delegate
authority to the name server below um I
mean you don't need to understand a
naturalist all this is an example but
again this is a technical decision
rather than a political one I'll admit
because the centralized ledger of all
the DNS names on the internet would be
impossible to maintain by the sifts
another step further and then you end up
with BGP which it doesn't require any
sent any or very well like remember but
um it's it reduces the amount of centric
infrastructure required which enables
kind of a spider web of the spider web
really was the Internet to to propagate
so another one for the techno Rotarians
they're moving on with gods the first
kind of instance or the first public
instance of online states way into place
so and in 1998 there was a hack Bell
Labs I think who designed the early
systems for the net for the 9-1-1 stuff
in america they got hacked and a
blueprint for one of the systems was
leaked on the quad should be the axes
across the country and one of these VBS
is is run in a boardgame store owned by
mr. Steve Jackson and because it here he
had a copy of this on those BBS someone
but there they read they raided his
ready to shop took off his computer
equipment that he was using to make the
game that the studio was selling and
then left for I think three and a half
months so they took him to court they
won the the judge called the prep the
warrant sloppy and advised that the US
Secret Service requires better education
regarding the law around free speech so
I was funny and they had no basis to
hold computers like based on like what
happened so this is quite a federal case
and it also represents the beginning of
the e FF because this is the case in
which the the Electronic Frontier
Foundation set up to to protect so
there's also the case book burn
Steinberg versus the United States which
is also represented by the F F legal
team I mean this is only tangentially
related but again another kind of talk
when it comes to the internet and it
being kind of a frontier for a listen
any conversation where they decided that
you couldn't restrict source food being
released because it was a unless it's Co
pricey because it's a like the way in
which she solve a problem through code
is speech so from there interesting so
the next kind of related on or relevant
statute I could find was the
Communications Decency Act in 1996 so
primarily that was a act to stop
dassault porn being spread on the
internet which obviously did not work
because we know yeah so on the
distinction I find quite interesting
because it's all the television screen
or it's on the radio or it's like um or
it's and like in the physical world it's
like being presented to you but on the
internet you need to take a series of
affirmative steps in order to access is
this some explosive content so content
via spans are unconstitutional so on the
the first amendment essentially splits
that speech up or hi it decides for free
speeches into a time matter place and
content based so for content based on
bans obviously it's like if someone
decides on time other places where and
why
in the context and when she said it and
content based bands are essentially
there IIIi think there are some like
edge cases this is someone going to
orbit this in May but they're very hard
to pass by the US government as you can
imagine listen
so what wait like hey guys read porn
right well we care about obviously is
the freedom of information and so in
section 230 of the CM Act it said no
provider or user of an interactive
computer service shall be treated as the
publisher or speaker of any information
provided by another information content
provided her provider which essentially
means that if I run the service and you
post something which might be bad on my
service I am NOT responsible for like
slightly like simply for holding that
that's like simply for hosting the
equipment and what she posts it because
essentially mmm-hmm I started a business
you know it's it's quite interesting
because it's like simply by hosting the
content itself you know a publisher over
you're simply a distributor and
naturally like it might be think of it
in a more kind of like human context
like holding distributors like liable
for the content of every single thing
that if it would be quite difficult and
also wouldn't make much sense seeing as
there's other people involved with the
actual creation of our content so I'm
early on in the 1990s just after
dialogue started in America there were
two providers that we care about
CompuServe and prodigy and CompuServe
refused as a policy to regulate any of
the content that it's um it's it's
usually posted on anything so if I was
MFIs CompuServe is my ISP and I
connected to something I posted it you
wouldn't be able to actually see complex
a I posted my Bible or something you can
sue them for hosting out information
because they point-blank refused to
moderate it a stole that prodigy on the
other hand did employ a team of
moderators and was active in attempting
to moderate and place the content which
is posted using its service and both of
them were sued for things that are users
posted and
my prodigy lost this because they'd
actually tried to moderate an in
moderation or actually became a
publisher because they were saying yes
no yes no so it's just interesting
because when we get to social media the
open know them I love actually oh really
hey I got a new idea I've had an actual
recent email address opportunity Intel
said who's vanished off the economic
certainty hates to vanish he's not using
they somehow try to connect at its where
because I haven't heard anything about
that on the internet which only further
supports
okay no and I'd and if a deferens tree I
live I apologize for misrepresenting
conversation so no I will discuss attack
all the way up essentially to me
obviously this kind of like technology
and the decentralization behind it was
huge at the time with a certain subset
of people who care very much about their
ability to speak freely and those who
were kind of like had let's say English
interests in which they kindly go out on
the street and say so this kind of
decentralized internet where I can
connect the anyone would be anything
well they appealed to a lot of people
and one of those people was Sir Murphy
who was a Grand Dragon of the clans well
I believe and was essentially according
to reports in Berkshire and the bottom
was a Condon all of his life having
played children's games when he refused
to be anything other than the south what
like when they like when they did
several warrior accidents and stuff and
he went to Vietnam on the pond returned
essentially was better applied the lack
of victory and the weakness of the
government because if you remember the
government eventually pulled out by the
Vietnam War and which is quite weird
because up until this time or up until
around by this time the seventies the
KKK and the government were actually
quite closely linked and well in many
cases is proving to be the same people
so the reason why Louis Baima is quite
significant here and I've picked on him
personally is that his writings reflect
this at the time because the enemies
weren't just like Leone's little
excremental you don't know the click
respond is a like white supremacist
organization in the US which is like
politics can essentially be reduced on
to America for Americans like is very
yeah
I've ever ever
but the difference is in the 1980s and
70s their writings went from anyone who
was in white
she anyone was in white and anyone who
stood against their ideology so that's
like the government that's like whites
who weren't like what like them like
really just any and anything wasn't them
so to reflect this the KKK picked up a
new kind of organization strategy shall
we say called leaderless resistance
which is essentially advocated for
political groups like the KKK to be
organized into two parts so one part
would be the political arm which would
practice no violence whatsoever and will
only attempt to achieve their aims
through the political process and free
drag an entirely non radical peaceful
stuff and the second level of it would
be unaffiliated like Tyra Sal grips who
would carry out violence in the name
Africa and I'm like to the same
ideological lens but just not
affiliating themselves and operating
alone like individually or in small
groups that sort of thing so in 1984
being set up the organization's Liberty
net and I would like to get a photo for
it because I might been told that the
the resistance baby I said were quite
creative in their use of slash strings
to kind of illustrate don't come in here
if although I wasn't able to find a
photo I certainly didn't wanna try
connect so I put an example post one of
the first post BIOS fame was imagine if
you will all agree all the great minds
of the patriotic Christian movement
linked together and joined into one
computer imagine any period in the
country being able to call up and access
these minds we are online with the Aryan
Nations brain trust it is here to serve
the folk the possibilities have only
been touched upon Punta del Este by
giving he was right like the
possibilities of this kind of technology
and highly would enable extremists who
generally wouldn't find out much
consolidated support in their like local
area like that like this kind of stuff
was groundbreaking and this was one of
the and this was quite an early BBS as
well are in mostly called Aria nations
already know yeah so there was also the
white ardian resistance set up by Tom
Metzger
and then George dykes would set up the
Liberty Bell Network and after the fact
so as I'm still reeling from the
illustrate here is that white
supremacist in America Devin that like I
know that this is GX centric so far but
I'm gonna tribute that's to the fact
that the technology was kind of
pioneered in America and we were simply
like after the fact like there is grips
here in the UK like homebody a team and
a few others which did use kind of very
early internet to communicate and like
connect with these guys and a lot
through the stuff Bob like we're
definitely just went into grips you
could talk about them old guy so a lot
of people interested in trying to spread
that message a high-profile case moving
away from my supremacy for a bet was the
urine burg files in which I'm not sure
how many people know this actually the
among young nervous because I certainly
didn't but and the abortion extremism
was spectacularly violent three I mean
like 70s and 80s and 90s having killed I
think in the double digits of doctors
who have practice and bombed multiple
abortion clinics throughout yes so it
definitely changes I think about this
guy marks something I thought I had his
name but some some household set up the
set up the site called the Nuremberg
files were listed the names and
addresses of a whole bunch of doctors
that he knew his the thing a carry load
abortions citing that it was free speech
because he believes that abortion would
eventually be legalized and recognized
the war crime it is and he didn't want
essentially I think he compared it to
the Nuremberg trials as you can see and
said that a whole bunch of people who
committed war crimes in Nazi Germany got
away and he didn't want the same thing
that happened to these but this is
actually an example of high hate speech
is in lights because I mean my guys
we've been clearly seen like this blood
along the top of the webpage like
visualize abortionist on trial that was
marketed and flyer going to extreme
anti-abortion groups with like proven
histories of violence and then he sticks
their name and their kids name and their
address link next to the next day like
it's not
I've likable so yeah the reason why I
want to highlight this is because he was
eventually prosecuted for it and the
site was ordered to be taken down but
it's just like a little firmer for later
the laborious conversation about free
speech where we do talk about Kenneth
this idea I'm absolutely Speights and
they can say anything provided it's not
a credible throughout because the
dissent of not being able to say
anything would be too much right it's
like this isn't the case and never
really husband Riker Steven Lee vine of
Politico I think said in his 1997
article blaming the web that the web is
a powerful extremely low cost
information amplifier but promulgates
the ravings of millennial had hisses as
effectively as it knows speeches by Bill
Gates or ads for liquor so for the price
of it for the price is like a single
website I know not all the Nuremberg
files were there was a poster campaign
but the website got infinitely more
attraction like like for just a design
and the hosting of that like
marginalized extremist groups can easily
reach an audience of thousands and the
new mom who becomes an idea of like
having a limited message like it's very
very I wouldn't say easy but it's
certainly possible to get your message
out there for thousands so when we talk
with you open Internet around the
beginning of the 21st century we moved
away from BBS's and styling kind of
websites to what that is referred to as
web 2.0 actually never going to set up
for is ever again I'm gonna set up the
the participatory web which essentially
enabled websites to scale up with their
user base rather than just like the the
separating essentially rule of content
creator and service provider to enable
users to share content and for that
content to be up to the driving force
behind they like appeal by the site
right
so examples lists are like I died like
I'm not trying to dodge the question but
examples this or literally everywhere
like their I can't think of many sites
which are still a like original web
start like hosting saying except for
like you know more
let me see
so again like going into the next
section it's important to remember that
not yet
this is like the MEC 2000 1000 2003 the
web while it's really like it's really
penetrated like our society in our life
and it's very difficult to be a
participant right now without
interacting with the web this still was
not the case there were plenty of people
who did not use the web their entire
lives going through this period and
they'd find so that's the something
important when we like frank about to
like the speech and like there's got the
right to be on myspace and that sort of
thing and like I just like in the back
you had saying about fire that changes
when we start to rely on these kind of
services more and when they start to
make up more of our lives because like
if and I'll take an example of lengthen
turns out to be an extremist hotbed like
you like it simply does not go on like
them but this this feels kinda goes away
but yeah basically Facebook started 2004
on the scale and Rochester illustrate
the scale free ahead a million users in
under a year oh yeah had a million users
in under a year Google was starving 300
million searches every single day in
2004 and YouTube was created in 2005 I
miss bought a year and a half later I
think my by Google for an extortioner
made the money and then Google also
bought double-click straight after that
which essentially was the beginning of
Google's gonna I don't know say monopoly
with monopoly like web advertising yeah
and then 12 a vision 2006 last panic
where we get to here
so until insects myspace had 100 million
users still quite ahead of Facebook and
this was jest just before it was sold
for however many only like 580 million
and when people were starting to get
weary other sort of the implications
let's tack right because like it's no
longer this the fun project like a mall
long with my friends like people are
actively concerned then there was a
massive outcry by the general attorney
up at Cincinnati to get sex offenders
off of MySpace
given that they liked very like everyone
signed up with a real name and there was
a couple of like suspected previous is
easing the plan
in 2007 after a series of lawsuits they
removed 90,000 saxon hunters from their
platforms with 100 million users sources
for this grouping but notice here that
they're getting removed simply because
of a characteristic of their like
identity like under the my guy that's
like it's probably legal to do this and
it kind of has been done before and it
continues to happen all over the place
but that's not all in 2007 um the
conservative youtuber michelle malkin
was censored by having her body removed
and ben smith wrote the article the
Internet vulnerable to free speech
issues are calling the Mark Zuckerberg
and others Eric Schmidt book illegal The
Chieftains of the Internet and said that
a machine that won't be the government
which is sensing our speech that will be
the owners of these platforms in which
we interact with the world which was
quite prophetic but in 2007 it's worth
noting that their stance on a hateful
content was unlawful of seeing
defamatory libellous threatening
pornographic harassing he had fault or
richly or ethnically offenses or
encourages cons encourages conduct that
will be considered a criminal offence
give rise to civil liability violate any
law or is otherwise inappropriate so
quite wide stretching and I really don't
think that we'd get away with that today
but that's essentially what the crack
was in 2007 something else with YouTube
that happened in 2007 as well it stopped
going from a kind of like blog site in
which content was separated into
searches or profiles so for instance as
an example if I were to YouTube before
was essentially a group of channels in
which you could search yourself but and
so like it essentially if you didn't
want to see content all you had to do is
simply not search for it again we're
talking about those kind of like a sort
of steps to get the content in which you
find offensive or rather awful or etc
right in 2007 they introduced the
centralized feed that
that essentially you could argue you
give up some of your free speech rights
during like three participation right
because but yes I have heard like I have
the right to shout but if I go to your
funeral and sites I'm not going to be
very well received so like the context
in which we say these things and indeed
the sites in which we upload things if
they're going to be like if I have a lot
of years on my blog and then the and
bikes just the sheer volume of the like
participation on my video propels it on
the essential platformer everyone can
see it now there's something to be
considered
in terms of whether we should enable
those on enable lose did you see what I
actually tried to find out which video
that's article is referring to when it
turns out she's been banned by YouTube
so many times I couldn't actually know
if I'm the one so it's like I'm that's
the thing like with this kind of
political discourse where is the option
to join where is the option to opt in
like is it so that if those political
discourses are not interested in I have
the opt I did the entire service to get
away from it like this is just like some
questions so moving on the development
of the web was obviously a gold mine for
white supremacist organizations as we
we'll know annoy given that storm front
which came active in the early noughties
was a public forum which anyone could
rise and anyone could create a client
enjoying so this is again going back to
those kind of uses of external scripts
this is the radicalization and
recruitment aspect right and recently
we've seen the ideally exterminate
successor spare the spiritual successor
to the site release a style guide in
which they require all of their writers
to never be explicitly and only resist
until only like it's like essentially
you can given calyx longline research
daily stormer style guide but it's some
like it errors explicit instructions for
writings on these kind of websites to
not be like too extreme like they're
like they went to the extreme I don't
want on the lives not up but they'd also
want to remain attractive to the people
whose minds chefs quite on there yet so
listen can you know on these Pleasant
folk on the UM on the left on left hand
side there are um forget top vote front
and Hammerstein nation so on the right
we've got an example of the internet
being used for like further idealization
and recruitment and on the Left Volks
front and Commerce Commission were
actually existing neo-nazi groups long
before the internet was a thing and they
used kind of a bulletin like a bulletin
board cell phone and to kind of like
organizer than themselves and distribute
like training materials on top of events
a lot sort of thing so in the end this
is actually the beginning the storm
front was indeed the beginning of this
kind of ironic and what we now refer to
as Krypton fascism where essentially
people well the disingenuous about what
their true intentions are and indeed
like clearly be affiliated with
communities which are violent extremists
about it but men key in that distance
and like it is quite hard to the
beginning guys because obviously I want
them gone but exactly how you go about
doing that with like giving service
providers and indeed the government the
ability to squash any dissent that they
can some I tie in this is some sort of
extremist group so moving away when
supremacist we've got home we've also
about Al Qaeda so this is a bet before
Isis and telling us the reason typical
Qaeda was because Isis has so much on
the internet about them that for me to
condense it into any kind of like fair
representation would be impossible so
I'm al Qaeda is much more simple and
illustrates the points just as well so
so according to research done into the
grips over in the Middle East there was
an initial hesitancy to actually use the
internet because there was debates at
some by some of the clerics like the
internet was actually just a Jewish
conspiracy so when they did that
actually decide use it they used it to
great success and they use it
essentially as a propaganda machine like
they wanted to share them from
information to all of their rumors
everyone familiar with al Qaeda
essentially they were like one of the
first
my radical azimuth grips to have terror
cells all over the world and indeed that
was the purpose of them using the
internet so you kind of I tie these guys
together like with a calls which is
there until I keep the morale high and
to also kind of spread that like
identity like forever
I'm trying accrue more people so
according to Jane's Intelligence Review
2006 ìgee
there was a board on yachts right there
was a board on Yahoo which stayed up for
the entirety of young people's which
al-qaeda used to summon and propaganda
but essentially the orchestration of the
internet and other tools like this was
done I mean by thousands of highly
isolated individuals broadly and I began
by their kind of violent extremism to
excuse me lost my notes again so the
main issue I write I read the entire
genes intelligence we and it's actually
quite good it goes and a lot into the
kind of things which will almost seem
pathetic pathetic when it comes to
talking about extremism later but the
biggest issue that I the first was that
their training they didn't have access
to proper like content creation
mechanisms they had a lot of stuff
around making this stuff I had seen
prettier but in terms of actually making
good training guides that was their
problem so it's interesting by the bumps
the people at under the sink but
obviously the war on terror was a thing
and there was a lot of opposition to al
Qaeda basically every developed country
in the world was working against in
Assam form another so the infrastructure
they had didn't stay up for long so the
so the al Qaeda media machine as it
referred to it's been essentially broken
down into three different by types of
content you've got the like my mother
sites and this is where ful the original
content is created this is where you get
the education from the like to have the
scholars this is where you get the like
the actual nodes of troop movements and
the grind in the Middle East this is
where you get like the actual content
and these obviously go down a lot so
that necessitates the roles and
distributors which are essentially
people who will aggregate the content
from the mother sites and download it
the second they see it up and then they
will hold it there and use things like
mailing lists and things like usual
posted sites like geo cities in the are
keyboards and all that sort of stuff to
I gathered up as soon as possible so
like once a length stick and arm they've
got another link and keeping track of it
and having the vampire to get rid of it
in time is incredibly difficult because
it was costly and AI wasn't so much of a
thing
bokman Yahoo boards was popular so like
assembly the manpower required to take
on this process and effort to keep this
up would have been too much so they
didn't and we got attacked
so another thing like another bit of
this enjoys it up a little bit of our
decentralization there was the use of
email lists and user boards so like
simply from sending an annual can send
them to the mailing list until every
single person who receives it well I
receive a copy of whatever kind of
program mother is so very trusting and
there's a few examples but we are tied
for climate so I'm gonna skip I then I
hope nobody minds so yeah
entry points my unless design aspect
because while social media today like
essentially bombards also the stuff that
wasn't so easy back on the internet that
was required to be hidden because it
wasn't heading then they do die they go
to the actual box and shut it off once
they find out where it was so there was
a fee entry points there were
directories again the distributors are
maintained updated links to the like to
the mother sites ful and plot those
anywhere they kids
mailing lists and message boards as
discussed and also quite interestingly
they non interactive home pages of
sympathizers like things like memorial
pages and things like this unrelated
that's a content al-qaeda would actually
hide lengths to existing websites in
there and then spread through what am i
phone email and other kind of private
communications that these lengths were
like they give you access to Java
content right because once you're in one
website they all linked to each other
you can find all them
yeah again producers so living on phenom
we've got the we're moving towards
centralization and this is where that's
a bit tricky because before this it was
simply a conversation about like when I
can ever talk about free speech and why
do we enable like violent extremists on
the system that we've built this
internet we're suddenly talking about
the individuals right to say what they
want right like a like a we agree that
the second the violence isn't good and a
few other things which I forgot my did
of the restroom but it's fine but we
like it's important to remember that
this far back is maintenance how to be
sex we have had a definition of what
hate speeches so no then nobody enjoys
when the internet centralizes I wonder a
little bit so wer see which flex
advertising revenue are stats has caused
predicted that internet revenue outside
of Facebook and Google is going to be
gone by 5% or not rises Hall in some
cases here we have Amazon Apple Facebook
Microsoft and health for that have made
431 acquisitions worth over a hundred
and fifty five point seven billion
without actually being without having
the proper antitrust investigation
summons them and their as a there was a
streak well I mean there are
investigations but none that actually
meant anything and they did have the
stats for how long the streak of like to
make uninterrupted acquisitions with no
interests monkey trust but will have to
do with like and Amazon noise has 50% of
all e-commerce in the United States so
what began as again going all the way
back to the first section what began as
a collection of decentralized ideas to
make the world more connected with like
relying on anyone Authority is very
quickly going back into the world where
we are relying on those authorities
where we have to choose and service
providers a three a a nimble amount of
reasons have provided services which
people want to stay on like for instance
with social media nobody wants to do in
the social media when no one else is is
the whole point of it right like it's so
like would flow will find it incredibly
hard for
like any competition to come along to
like say spoken and like when Instagram
they put on they bought it so we show a
little sugar it's supposed to do and
then for things like I like other
services so my time and payment
processors and email hosting are lots of
the stuff when indeed Amazon with the
telemetry and just kind of the nature
and watch you interact with these
services it's hard to beat that kind of
market research and when you don't have
access to that because they can cut you
in jail for getting access to it it's
incredibly hard to compete with them so
slowly and slowly I believe we're going
to enter in more and more centralized
internet and not this interesting
implications your free speech Frank
because surely our freedom to say what
we want it matters just as much as the
speech which is inherent in the action
to deny you service my platform because
like it's a sense of speech and of
itself if I decide that I do not want a
certain type of person on my platform so
given the obvious imbalance of power
there and given the obvious like
misaligned incentives right because at
the end of the day these are all
companies and companies are there to
make money and not to stop extraneous
we're not really sure how we're going to
do so essentially I've named this
section plausible deniability and the
absence of action because I think that
really defines how we look at it because
as we felt like and all of the examples
earlier they didn't just go away when so
when I start talking about that they
have an active in every single solution
like I like it and every single aspect
of our internet life and i am i hope
this stuff the way zealots River and I
hope the soft white be the axes is an
awesome thing was illustrating that
point but no there is like because of
this amounts of just mentioning the the
fact that we're no longer working in the
government to stop this some this abuse
of our rights would rather service
providers we're seeing essentially an
action it's like we can't do anything
because we're not allowed to do right so
for those who remember Alex Jones was on
the etheric subcommittee you can think
of for an incredibly large number eight
years while also on publicly like on his
own radio show
Manji which is quite rare but these with
these boys like essentially like
referring to what we call dog whistles
right it's
like it said that's essentially like
violent extremism but they hint that
it's not like they're not saying it
right because all death wrap but they're
definitely at the gamut and then they
for loosing I'm familiar the concept of
white genocide or white replacement is
the conspiracy theory which involves the
demographic changes in the Western world
to be intentional and orchestrated
against the white people so here we have
Alex Jones a incredibly popular talk
show host a was active on Spotify
exactly Facebook he was active on
Twitter essentially everything for a
fusion reviews and despite behavior like
this and people reporting it when it
happened was never removed until I
believe it was his his lost he was sued
by he was Charlie yeah yeah there was
sandy hoping thing I was he sued or
charged anyway it was proven that he was
a piece of so they got mocking in
this is essentially this took so long
and these signs one like the signs
weren't invisible sure there is a debate
to be had between exactly what this
interprets from what I'm asking this
potentially we can start having that the
bit because of the minute there is
there's like none of it right I guess
essentially you're either a violent
extremist or you're not at all a violent
extremist watch running and going I'm
going back to the concept of
radicalization that's not how it works
so something else I think is notable
here is moving away from web 2.0 and
going to the web 3.0 which is a legit
time I said you know you can look around
I said it's essentially where the
services now I use feedback from your
behavior to improve the quality of that
service and we see the example with the
YouTube recommendation algorithm here
you hear has ended up at just a random
video that like this is so weird that he
didn't mean so like you like that - from
like around like you just start watching
something and then you just
automatically just end up at some
weird right - because so
obviously none of this is proven because
YouTube is proprietary and when we don't
know how the each of all of them works
like it would make sense for it to be
optimized on engagement and as we know
violent extremism isn't all that popular
but when the
either they've gone yeah right that's
like it's kind of assaulting something
identity so ideally never ideally sorry
you can imagine that these extremist
videos and the things which would lend
its themselves to extremism would have
on paper quite good engagement stats and
SSI led to a number of fingers like like
setting up to you I'm gonna bet you I'm
super sorry
design it's good thanks essentially did
a piece on the default pasted on the
each of algorithm and then like follow
the basic pattern if just like watching
the news and only particular subjects
and the content got more and more
engaged as you go on suggesting that an
increased engagement can actually lead
the YouTube algorithm to suggest more of
the same and if we accept that some
people are being radicalized I'm not
saying that everyone's being radicalized
I'm not saying that every every YouTube
creator is actually a secret Nazi
hell-bent on inventing any of their ways
not saying any that I don't have to what
I'm saying is if they are being article
eyes it makes sense that algorithms
which are unchecked like this might
amplify the effects of it right because
I gets you know one even needs to send
you right there like you like if you use
your algorithms recommending it yourself
and you're more likely to be referred to
content which is more extreme than the
content you've just watched that
potentially can be a problem when it
comes to addressing country and violent
extremism not tended to send up a person
recently especially with what's
happening Christchurch and with I charm
and once people people's eyes have been
quite open to it recently there's this
concept of the power of the pipeline of
extremism or as it's commonly referred
to the alt-right pipeline which suggests
that there is a transition off ideas and
off discussion which does lend itself to
radicalization
so essentially you start off with fringe
nonviolent views and this can be
anything from all in conservatism to
libertarianism - I know identitarian as
Miniver that means so going back to
those push and pull factors they're
present but not so bad to the point
where he wants to join a violent
extremist group
and the game with or with algorithms
suggesting new content that can I mean
and there's a report that I'll mention
in the next slide which goes into this
more I appreciate this is a bit of a
jump well let's say if there was
extremist content on YouTube and you
were to use YouTube often there is a
chance that this algorithm could suggest
you this extreme but not overtly
extremely content and this is something
that people have talked about and there
are before obviously that the the
research is pointing in so there's no
there's no consensus because there's
always been fences I wouldn't to do talk
about it right so again the and then
with the ease of access to spaces and
yelling radicalization so that's an
refers to the use of services like the
scores in telegram and signal and
whatsapp for the creation of private
groups which we all don't have the
pleasure of seeing what time contains
from quite nasty stuff and because of
like some other externalities that I've
not went into at all like and and
encryption and like one that people's
right to privacy and also the stuff we
can't monitor less stuff right so if
we're ever to tackle radicalization it
has to happen before the fact all right
but there's this is really great report
and it's one of the only ones I read in
this fall is huge it's a long long long
thing but it's called alternative
infants broadcasting the reactionary
right on YouTube um yeah the next
section is white kind of emerging
technologies and so like that's kind of
all I have to say about the this next
centralized services six social media
who's moving onwards what might be a
problem in the future we're like these
guys are very guys and girls are very
good people are very good at helping up
new technologies and seeing how you can
benefit their
let's see how you can benefit their
ideology right so what's next
and we've seen censorship resistant
content listing up on the blockchain
called alveoli stands from my brain it's
a Content file hosting service that uses
the coin but I'm going over the
blockchain but it uses the coin here
like you host it and then when someone
wants to see more want you to serve it
to them you just pay them about a lock
point or they pay you a little point and
it works but the thing is is that once
you've bought it then it actually is
like it shared amongst like it's it's
it's essentially a peer-to-peer network
which stores all the content on the
blockchain so obviously to censor that
or to modify the content on the actual
ledger
I would match everything up right it
might destroy the tops of the whole
thing and it wouldn't work so there's no
way for you to edit or modify anything
on it which is quite worrying when it
comes to this because what if Isis take
a bunch of videos and even the
abominable project right it's like if it
ever gains me an attraction we know that
that's not going to happen so some of
the things right and who here new has
heard a mastodon who here is heard a gab
we hear sort of gab almost at all hey so
essentially gob is the free speech
platform which this guy likes a lot and
this he showed up a Senegal I think I
have same story as the young
Christchurch shooter
same type a guy same type of on central
motivations and again we've got this
time slayer of this i just refers to
this kind of a like again crept in
flashes and right when i KY say it's it
doesn't look good at people of our
movement we're going back in time and
something i just want to go back to you
can see
so screw your optics
I guess so like there's my slide with
lobster we're go so I'm essentially
mastodons is a design choice platform
I'm not gonna go into how it works but
it's like hard to like sensor things on
the inositol network itself and out but
what you say free speech platform which
refuses to censor anything I'm only
leagues like this you can go and look at
all like all those other cycles it's all
archived if you so want and if you do
not believe that it is as insightful as
s decided ban and the other God is bomb
as well once they find out that they
were both gab users after the fact of
course because they can say they've done
something that but essentially this is
wonder if the massive and so yeah but
another of I know a couple of platforms
like this have actually faced opposition
from the services in which they work so
obviously if I want to run the social
network I need hosting a payment
providers any designers I need all this
almost an infrastructure allowing me to
support not mission and guards from
having a few problems specifically we're
finding a domain host I'm finding more
state but on master gone they've almost
right so that's the idea so worth
thinking about for what we do by that so
coming to the end because we're five
minutes left what the do we do what
if Spencer
like seriously because like like like
very like we have to do something and I
hope we can I hope they get again like
if this is not a call for me to say
that's criminalize speech because I like
you're a computer security crawling
you're probably wondering what the house
is that is computer security conferences
censorship this Pro censorship no
instance right but essentially I don't
think it even goes that far like
everywhere at the stage where we were
actively censoring people arm inward
like crushing the same thing opinions
then I would agree that we need to be
cautious but as it sounds they we have
not managed to crush any
what's pharmacist moving like it's still
there just as much as it was in the
early and all these just as much as it
was on BBS if not more
and now we've got content which could
amplify it at quite an alarming pace so
for me I kind of just want us as
technical as technology professionals
here here works in the security industry
like you raise your hand if you want to
work in the studio that's like basically
everyone right so Mike I mean we all
like regardless whether we work for like
runs we're consultants of our own
project things were on something we all
have I stick in the product ring but we
all have a stake in which like in the
business transactions which allow these
guys to keep operating and I think like
for us to have the KFOR could
potentially be like like game-changing
so I would like getting away from this
like that's all you anything just like
please think to yourself how can i Medi
get on like essentially how can I stop
if this beautiful thing I felt from
being used by and if I may never the
next for happier think of it as an
attacker right it's anniversary
simulation one of Nazi uses for like the
likes of accents in your game so also
more research needs to be done to
clarify the link between the internet
and extremism because like for someone
and I believe for many in this room we
can see it and we can see the kind of
like the the speeding along the road
erratically ization that it has but the
the really like the research on it is
obviously quite new in contemporary so
more of that would be often everyone's
looking for a dissertation project and I
guess the question they call to action
well I'm going to take you so I want to
let it go with this what role do we want
the service providers to have like what
do we want Facebook to be able today if
we want them to be able to censor space
you want them you're going to chase
what's in our season one isn't become we
like and do that if we don't want it
from we find directly is going to make
that decision because someone needs to
make the decision and like so far it's
not like us
like like we're not doing a ratings
element so someone needs to and just
reminder that inaction is still a
decision so yeah like that's kind of it
um well I just want to reiterate the
presidency some prayers I do not want
classify speech and you not want to lock
this all up for wrong thing is really
isn't something we should rush I just
think we should have the conversation
and we're in the position to make a real
difference so that's not this up
[Music]