oh yeah okay so this is this is artwork
which had a big abstract so basically
the idea of this talk is that
technologies come on a long way since we
first introduced the current model for
security and I think we can say that
security hasn't really kept up with
changes in development and so although
things are getting a little bit more
secure they're probably not getting
secured at the rate that we would want
them to and this is putting quite a lot
of strain on people who are in charge of
security so in this talk we're going to
discuss how we can use different bubbles
of security and then we're going to also
look at the impact that that's had on
our business because we started
employing
this change within security and it's
what that'll probably mental health to
us okay who are we
so I'm Alistair O'Neill some of you
might not leave March I'm head of
defensive security in that digital
interruption and I've got about ten
years experience in pentesting and I'm
really really into weirded for sex stuff
like forming verified crumbs
I'm not allowed to talk about this topic
so that's that's basically me under the
bridge of a bald cat there so yeah it's
a great I'm I'm sorry for plants and I'm
head of security risk and compliance and
I have about a decade's experience in
information governance and also
standards and the humans are really
weird in basic conspiracy theories that
I'm not allowed to talk about ever it
makes us look really weird if you want
to talk to me later in the pub I shall
tell you
okay so what's information governance
bit of an interesting one to start off
and security talk about and really
information governance is the driver for
security if you didn't have information
governance if you didn't have the need
to secure information you have nothing
to hack and so this is about the
management of information of an
organizing to a level and what we need
to do within information governance is
create and understand the balance of why
was
information so security is basically
saying we need X amount of people to
access this information and useless
information and we need to keep that
information secure so really if I have
my way the internet would be an
impenetrable glass box no one would be
able to get into it but then when I work
with people basement rightly say we
actually need to access this information
and do things with it so we have to find
this compromise and we use quite a lot
of stuff within IG frameworks for
endpoint use to handle data so needs of
protocols that we put in place which is
where we start moving over into the
security area and then we do a lot of
stuff around policy so this is about how
we guide the behaviors of how we deal
with information so I'm one of those
great people who spends a lot of time
writing policies I really enjoy policies
and I absolutely love standards I think
that being clear and concise is
incredibly important we don't tell
people what they need to do they don't
know how to do it so it's not always all
about hacking so let's look at this list
of why the information government
actually encompasses and some of you
might even see things you're familiar
with here right so we have rich men in
privacy
we have audit I mean that's that's
pretty much the standard security stuff
we have for example business
intelligence data science finance all of
this stuff is contained within
information governance and all of it
will be part of any kind of security
work really especially in any kind of
big organization and so that's why you
kind of we're talking about information
governance at the start we're going to
use it as a sort of a framework to
define what security should be for the
purposes of the talk
if you disagree you can talk to me later
but I'm right an information governance
isn't just about securing information
from an organizational level it's
actually about your own personal
information and how you govern your own
personal information so here
things like privacy and we've got stuff
like IT management we've got stuff that
you're gonna look up 500 example you
know you're gonna want to be able to
secure your financial details you don't
really want everyone to see in your bank
account so information governance is
something that is part of our everyday
lives and becoming more so because we
have so much information that we're
giving away and we need to understand
the risks involved in doing that and how
we secure ourselves personally so this
leads us on to what is information
security so information security is
we're gonna say a subset of information
government because it is it's about
trying to secure how data is actually
stored accessed and we're gonna talk
about those see I tried a little bit but
it provides organizations with
appropriate control over the data via
the CIA triad does everyone know what
the CI try it is because you don't
you'll find out soon exciting and it's
not just you know me creating a weird
box where I've stripped out glitzy and I
managed to cut down the kernel or it's a
form of a verified kernel or some kind
of an accessible vault because in the
real world people do need to access
their data people need to develop
solutions for things the business needs
to keep going so basically there needs
to be a sort of a balance struck between
risk and so again it's about this
balance it's about the balance that you
have which is to do with the risk
analysis and for information governance
we do number of things where we can make
a decision based on certain framework so
things like privacy impact assessment so
we can see the impact offer if something
the sleep from a privacy perspective we
can have data breach impact assessments
as well so we can look at the impact of
if there's a data breach and this isn't
just about fines and it's not just about
GDP our this is about the impact on
everyday lives so one of my favorite
examples is the Ashley Madison breach
that was a horrible personal data breach
and because it was about linking people
up to have affairs the impact of that
being released was devastating and four
people committed suicide directly linked
to that so we do need to make a clear
judgement about why why is it that we're
securing this data so
the CIA tried look at our blog is
holding it since it's a normal is the
model that we use a lot for sort of
quantifying the risk security is your
ancestor so anyone done cbss is I can
familiar with CBS s CBS s is a bit janky
but this is part of it and so it's
integrity confidentiality and
availability we're gonna end up I'm
looking for a definition of when are
like an origin of this and apparently
this is a pretty organic term integrity
came from the Bella Padula model in 1976
which is like a formal computing state
machine and confidentiality came from
the bp1 MST that won em in 1980 or and
they were when those were defined and
for some reason we managed to just sort
of check on availability is another
important thing that we want which is
good yeah this is sort of the core of
how we define sort of how secure thing
you should be and how that can be
impacted basically and there's a bug in
the middle because we have books and
everything I thought we were being very
similar in Tate
so what does this mean in practice Ally
so basically this means that information
security is a continuous process there's
no real end to it as long as your
business is growing and developing and
as long as you're storing data or
protocol data you're going to need to
keep doing this information security
it's an ongoing never-ending thing and
Aurora Voris eating its own tail kind of
deal and that means that the really the
need for security isn't constraint it
needs to constantly be going these
ucomfy developing it needs to be there
all the time but one of the problems
with a procession general as partners
talk is that we find the solution state
security are kind of constrained it's a
very sort of reactionary process and
yeah basically there's issues with it
and technology keeps moving and it keeps
changing so think about what we didn't
have five years ago that we have now
thank you
think of your phone you literally carry
a computer around with you as it used to
be a flip phone
I remember the matrix everyone thought
they were so cool because they had a
little blip phone
internet-of-things medical devices there
are all these things that we didn't have
before but the model for security isn't
changing technology is changing but
security isn't changing so not only are
we constrained we do a snapshot a pen
test is a snapshot in time we're
constraining how we respond but we're
also constraining the model and it's not
suspend us right I mean even IO sees
even other and like blue team kind of
stuff is very much a sort of a snapshot
of something at one point in time it's
all very static and it's all very
reactionary in date so this brings me to
talk a little bit about these like
constraint things how we kind of try and
get around them but we don't really do a
great sort of deal so I'm assuming
everyone here has read some kind of
massive threat report where they
attribute it to some government or
whatever else and that's kind of it
happens a lot of needs a second I feel
like it's kind of a cognitive sort of
trick we do to make ourselves feel like
we are actively protecting against these
groups whereas in reality each time
we're just finding them again as a
reaction and then pushing out IFC's
and this is what I call the Jeff
Goldblum theory where it turns out that
really it doesn't matter whether it was
China or Russia or whatever else it
could be Jeff Goldblum hacking your
alien mothership what really matters is
how your data was accessed and how
secure it was and how you can improve on
that and this is how you start to think
about things in a more continuous way
because in reality a constrained
solution to a continuous problem puts a
strain on the mechanisms and people
responsible for it and what it's really
doing is it's putting a strain on the
people who are responsible for it I'm
going to be like this universe so we get
ready
guys things still bad out okay it still
quitting
there we go and quitting needs to skill
shortages as well which is another thing
that we're going to try and brunch in
this because again a constrained
solution to a continuous problem is not
a good thing it puts people under a lot
of pressure and here the state starts
chasing its tail again because when you
have a skills shortage it means there's
not enough people and if there's not
enough people it means that individuals
are given mod to do which puts more
strain on the individuals and round and
round we go like the Magic Roundabout so
we really need to kind of understand the
skills shortage if we're going to
address it so these are some of the job
roles that we've taken out as Mark
Carney and Sabbath skills matrix and
they're doing some really awesome stuff
but this at the moment so if you're
interested to have a word with a bit
afterwards and it's it's it's kind of
roaming and all sorts of really
interesting ways and Ali and I will be
adding some stuff to it and I know that
Jays had other hideth as well and Sharon
has been very involved with this and
sherek very come out sorta the triple-t
asterixis beside them are the ones we've
added for the purpose of the top really
and because because really the matrix is
a life thing and a growing thing so
we've got penetration testers security
researchers writing and listen pious
members insulin sponsor nice intelligent
primal ingenuity architects or team
members privacy and things protection
specialist sweet and risk management and
that's a lot but we see security is a
singular thing but it's not it's an
ecosystem in its enormous how would you
actually look at the skills matrix they
start mucking the skills next to these
as well
and it gets to be very bigger and bigger
yet we still think of security as a
singular thing is singular
responsibility and we still think of it
very much as offensive we don't really
think of the defense side until someone
is planning on blue team and it's skills
focused but yeah so talking about the
skills matrix and the vast amount of
rules we have one of the other issues
that we've got here is that we have a
sort of a thing
like where the skills versus
competencies so I know a lot of people
who ask me how did you get into InfoSec
the answer is I just accidentally did
there are no formal pathways intersect
there are a few universities that are
doing intersects degrees of the moments
of advertise one but that's pretty much
the closest thing I think that there is
to a formal education for a second even
that is in very very early days and it's
kind of unusual because every other
skilled profession that deals with you
know risk or things that could be
damaging will have for example they they
have universal skills they have
scalability in what you're doing
there's assessments when they are
accessible they're regulated and they're
accountable and skills versus
competencies is important because a
skill is a singular learned attribute it
is easy it's anything that you learn in
order to accomplish another thing know a
competence
a competency is a measure it's a measure
of ability it's a measure of
characteristics it's a measure of skills
put together and that means that you can
successfully create a function which is
why when we have things like National
Occupational standards we have skills
and experience and we have knowledge and
understanding because your skills in a
vacuum don't mean anything if you don't
understand why you're doing it or what
you're doing it for so a competency is a
measure of the house as opposed to the
watt and this is what we absolutely do
not have in InfoSec is any coherent
tangible or joined-up standards and
really which we put that side in that
you sent me the other day where can you
explain me the one where it's a standard
and then
and we need to put all the solids
together and then we end up with 15 stop
oh my god yes he is an xkcd comic where
it's there's the there's 14 competing
standards why we just make a new
standard to unify them all and then the
result is there's 15 competing standards
and a lot of that's to do with the fact
that the bodies who were creating the
standards aren't joined up and it's not
on a national level we're basically a
very very infantile sector and by that I
mean we're young rather than we are
behaving in an infantile way I really
what we need is something coherent so
the idea behind something like a
national occupational standards is it
describes the competency that is needed
for the top role but it also explains
that competency to business so
businesses employers and educational
institutions can actually have an
agreement with the people in the
industry about what skills are needed to
build these competences and you don't
even have to have a singular competency
in an individual Ali and I are a joint C
so we are outside CSIS foot for our
company and half of one functional
person I am the other half of that
functional person we go into
organizations and we look at their
security posture we take everything
apart we threat model we do all of these
different things I come in crack the
wave pyrite and blow the standards and
policies and explain what they need to
do and then Ali goes in and actually
configures it yeah I sent a darkroom and
I type a function command senses into
whatever servers is report I have
firewalls you'd like that we'll call
them and we're trusted we're trusted as
individuals but what's our qualification
baseball bats
I provide the standards forever I've
been doing information governance
forever but where's my career pathway
that says that I am the right person to
do this why are you trusting me
people do trust me please I'm very good
at my job but why are you trusting me
how do I evidence this how has it been
assessed right and that's the thing that
we miss in the second thing so one of my
true well one of my mini bugbears I'll
probably show up in this is
in osep for example one of the
requirements one of the parts of the
test is basically has you write a buffer
overflow and don't let me pen testers
here but if there were I asked for a
show of hands about how many people
would use a buffer over like write their
own buffer overflow on a sort of you
know instead normal pen test jobs it's
really really love it's not the kind of
skill that we really require it's a sort
of technical curio that we just have in
there for no real reason it's not it's
you know it's not formally defined it
doesn't fit the role that we're doing in
a day to day business but someone at
some point has decided that this is what
we need to do because really we guided a
lot by B thoughts and influence of
others within InfoSec and let's face it
would you go to a doctor whose only
qualification was being mentored by some
random person they found on Twitter
[Music]
there's a lot of this I mean I'm not to
put major imbalance absolutely the best
we have right now it's a you know it's
better than having no one but we should
definitely be thinking about formalizing
the education structure and emphasize a
little bit better because it's not just
medicine like realistically think of
your lives which you can do to an
unqualified lawyer would you use an
unqualified accountant because the
impact is that being wrong is massive
and the impact of poor security is
massive has anyone seen their massive
enormous fine the VA just got hit with I
mean we're responsible for surprising
amount of that money partly now and
mentoring is useful it's useful at an
organizational level once somebody is
already within a business but actually
there's a number of issues with
mentoring in the wider world which is
white tends not to be used in other
professions in the way that we use it
mentees are inherently vulnerable right
so yeah I mean again there's no way to
really judge who your mentor is their
qualifications could just be someone
who's doing it you know for fun right
and I mean to be really serious about it
there are some concerns I have certainly
I mean if anyone wants to know you can
do captain
crunch and find out about like you know
really unpleasant things in this
industry to be honest with you people
are exposed to things that they
shouldn't be exposed to and in reality
just because my room into info SEC
worked for me and alleys route into my
psyche worked for him trying to
duplicate that is going to be impossible
because unless everybody in this room
wants to go and live in Azerbaijan work
undercover in a baby house right
standards to the government moved to
Kazakhstan then back to divine than
Germany work for a number of NGOs
different organizations the GMC you see
my point
everything is experiential for me I
can't pass that knowledge on that is
particularly personal to my experiences
so without the structure where we have
some kind of formalized way of saying
this is the expectation this is the
minimum we expect this is the core of
what we need you to do we're all going
to be flapping around trying to grab
bits off each other to create a jigsaw
puzzle that kind of looks a bit wonky no
and this is causing a huge amount of
frustration in the in the industry it's
causing frustration for employers
because they're trying to get these
unicorns that don't exist and it's
causing frustration for the people who
were trying to get into the industry
because they're all trying to be
unicorns because no one knows exactly
what it is that they need to do so yeah
this is actually the quote which we have
just because it's great it's a good
quote but yeah I mean essentially it
means that there's a lot of I guess the
industry is very loosely defined what we
do is very loosely defined and that
causes problems which we'll see in a
minute so here is someone what so you
guys might know that's right this is a
meme from the internet I did see a
favorite meme ever I've been alive
informed it's a it's good and again this
is as seen by so on and so forth
and
they're all seniors character through
film TV we're always stuff later
we even see ourselves and starts things
yeah and in a lot of ways this is kind
of how we do perceive ourselves I mean
certainly how our behaviors come across
as well yeah yeah and that's true I mean
like again security so well defined and
we have a lot of weird and sort of
contradictory advice a lot of the time
so for example we haven't gotten
password right our passwords right for
you know ever we've had so many
different kind of contrasting bits of
advice about passwords going back years
and years and years does anyone want to
know what the NIST standards for
passwords I don't even know the new
standard is for passwords not sure
thanks Steve all characters you favorite
member it you can spend on memorizing it
thank you even get it down writing it
down it's not actually bad advice for
those people as long as they leave it
somewhere else can get it button again
password managers better but this is all
this sort of to FA no to FA I hate to
effect yeah why would I want to get my
phone number to Facebook that's just
about it this I have to pay on buy my
iPhone and the fa is a message to my
iPhone I discovered when I hidden my
iPhone in the bottom of the bag yeah all
of this contradictory and even sometimes
maybe not great advice or not great way
not sometimes disclosure for example
could be handled badly - so VLC media
player was recently downloading updates
but they were checking whether they were
signs they weren't using friends for
their security people cost of a lot of
hassle and they didn't we didn't really
ingratiate ourselves as a community to
those guys we don't ingratiate ourselves
of the community through a lot people
and i'll you know i have been on sites
before where testers have been laughing
at def scared and spending the dumps was
a behind them that's fun
that wasn't make this up by ourselves at
all and we scream at vendors every time
i've been to get something wrong we just
absolutely lose a and start
screaming at them but what we don't do
is go in and say well this is what you
could have done this is how you could
have done this but
so we look like bullies yeah it makes us
look hostile and that itself makes it
difficult also to attract people into
the industry as well I think yeah
because people don't want to work in
industries that come across as hostile
and I'm hungry
they don't always feel welcome in
hostile and angry environments this
makes it difficult for us to be able to
connect with the people that we're
trying to protect and it really really
overshadows the really good work that we
do at work
thank God how does this impact consumer
so for the sake of just quickly
consumers here we mean who's put buying
our services right judged I mean again
I've been pen testing for 10 years I
have come on site where people are like
please don't hack us please don't ruin
our day please don't make us miserable
and you know they they maybe they find
it stressful down the pentester route
and again the attack and we are
inconsistent and it happens a lot right
you could get two different pen testing
firms and the reports will be different
people will highlight different issues
people will put things with different
risks ratings and so on and so forth it
it makes people feel attacked right and
they feel like it's inconsistent when we
prevent software going live because the
pen test has been scheduled for two
weeks before it's supposed to go live
and we stopped it because we found a
massive issue it's not good it's we're
the blockers in this scenario and
eventually I think people sort of stop
listening to us and software is released
and securely I mean I want to give an
example but there's just so many yeah I
mean there's not really a hint that's
right it's a climbing ooh yeah yeah yeah
so we were recently on site and a client
of ours didn't want to get a pen test
because he would have cost as much to
pen test this site as you would have
just for them with as much as they paid
to just get the site and everything set
up a small that was this like any cost
five grand okay well yeah yeah yeah
basically it was super expensive they
didn't want anything to do with it
we've got some really great situations
we have one client who just kept
emailing us and saying could you just
change the report give us a clean bill
of health who like no major
vulnerability fix the vulnerability and
while they were retest there are lots of
people you want to do some funding you
just do it we promise we'll fix it like
it's not an MOT it's an ability and you
need to fix the permeability and then
we'll come in and we'll do the retouch
so we just kept going around the circles
and this is just a fundamental
misunderstanding of what we do within
the security and the reality is they
probably didn't know how to fix the
permeability and didn't want to pay
someone else to do it but again this
means that there's pressure on us again
there's pressure on the businesses
pressure from the businesses and stress
leads to burnout burnout leads to
quitting and quitting is again looping
back to the skill shortage I mean I
don't know about you guys but probably
three times a week I think that's it I'm
done with computers I'm going to live in
a cave on the Faroe Islands I heard
goats for the rest of my life no more
technology because this is how we fail
yeah right very literally we start with
our cup of tea in a burning room it's
not like anybody needs a graphic
designer I did all of these I'm very
proud of them can you clap how can we do
things differently Ally well we are
trying a few things differently but
especially we won't be seen as this guy
not Darth Vader we don't to be the guy
who wanders around with choking people
we want to be the guy in sage advice
guys but still gives
constantly productive even when he's
dead
and this is where kind of we can start
maybe taking major trip in a different
way right we can start passing on our
collective knowledge to people within
the businesses and that we're already
working with we can start sort of
empowering the teams that we work with
so for example we go to a lot of QA
testing conferences which are kind of
very different screaming dumb things but
we're kind of we try to make contact we
want to see what sort of tools are there
using and integrating into say you like
a CICE pipeline and yeah that's one of
the starting things that we're going to
talk about I take that food because
that's how popular security is and we've
got some about lovely testers in the
audience because we are starting to pull
the ABS in testers I think a bit more
comparing me in two very basic
competencies as well but we don't mix
around the conference's that we're not
spreading the knowledge and really this
is what it needs to be for us we need to
be sharing the knowledge not holding the
knowledge because for all that holding
the twelve-inch is like yeah nothing
activity changes and without sharing
that and we're basically stopping things
from progressing in a way that could be
secure and really really usable I was
asked at a panel that I was on with Amy
recently what am i excited about for the
future of technology and my response was
absolutely nothing I work in security
I'm terrified fair leads to anger and so
let's talk a little bit about left
shifting security in dev sec ops
is everyone here familiar with dev sec
up or left short expiry yes we have
hands all people that I know influence
and so basically this involves
integrating security into the
development pipeline and we can do this
kind of thing for almost anything that
you can have a self of pipeline for so
for networks or software or hardware
and if you can create a build pipeline
for it you can integrate security and
one of the great things about this is
the responsibility for security is
distributed across an entire team and
across a period of time as well so you
kind of get rid of technical debt right
so for example instead of developing
something for three years then you get a
pen tested and it turns out it has a
million fatal flaws from the very
beginning in the entire basic
architecture and now you've got to start
from scratch you don't have to do that
anymore because you'll have identified
all of those flaws way earlier on the
SPLC it creates a space for like
non-technical people to it's great value
as well so like purely say getting
getting a product owners involved in
working out maybe what could be
potentially issues at the start right
things like threat modeling having the
right security mind that this is that
these are stuff that people with a good
security mindset can add to the security
posture and diverse I got 10 trillion
and it's quite a new idea and it's
something that's growing but I think
even within that it's constrained in
itself because it tends to talk about
developers and how developers do things
more securely the inside teams can be
bought into this and one of the
organizations that we worked for this
whole fight with them for about eight
months
at least about but I can see that I left
with them was bringing in a dev site
hops environment but they've done it
with their can you a testers which makes
perfect sense because you can split QA
testers off into total two fairly broad
groups which is the pretty technical
ones and the less technical ones and the
technical QA testers can pick up a lot
of the stuff that we do a security test
is very very easily and when they do it
means we don't have to do it because
that's based it who wants to take
through the OWASP top 10 I mean it not
the least sometimes but yeah yeah
instead of being seen as dark Vador
sometimes I'd like to be Yoda I'd like
to have my own planet
and talking of VA Wells top ten if we
create the right tools we wouldn't have
to well well that's not strictly true
we'd still incentives but and yeah so I
mean one of the things that I found
since I various yeah with like QA
testers and other people is that our
tools as a security industry are really
really obtuse like I was using the
Metasploit a few days ago and I realized
I never use a tool with this interface
before in my life
it's really sort of weirdly put together
it's like the the set our hosts and
stuff is almost like your sporting
environment variables and Linux it's
it's peculiar and it's not intuitive and
when I've used QA testing tools which I
have been using or leasing and they are
really really intuitive there's this you
don't need to put a lot of thought into
how it runs it just runs in the
background and they also tend to
integrate really nicely into the CI CD
pipeline so they can give you a Contiki
continuous feedback all of the time and
yeah yeah at the moment we're actually
trying to develop a tool that's a
vulnerability scanner for Android apps
that is basically supposed to
integrating with Jenkins and other tools
in the CI CD pipeline and the idea is
that we're taking all of our collective
security knowledge and letting you know
QA testers use it instead and yeah I
mean instead of teaching people how to
hack instead of kind of coming up which
is the way that we're doing it with the
mentorship and the osep which and all
that kind of stuff which hasn't really
managed to fill the skill shortage maybe
we should think about giving people ways
to build securely so that we take again
that technical debt and that pressure
off of us and in this context as well
tools when we're not just talking about
like software maybe also things like
frameworks for for you know how secure
you should be built from the start at
all really at all could be anything in
this context that helps you or enables
you to do something so it could be a
framework it could be a policy it could
be something like threat modeling it
could even be training training people
with the right mindset and one of the
things it's awesome about QA testing
tools as the names they're absolutely
obsessed with vegetables they've also
got really cool names like tor
I mean that's something off so they have
selenium but every time they go out
which really irritates people when I'm
trailing but Rex is the tool that we're
developing because I really like
dinosaurs so it seemed like a good name
at the time and it's in testing stage at
the moment so if anybody is developing
Android applications and wants to test
it get in touch with us and we'll get
you a sign in so this is where we go
back to the skills matrix the skills
matrix is focusing very very much on our
internal skills in our internal industry
and but actually there are a lot of
skills that are quite relevant to what
we do that already exist and a lot of
technical and non-technical people that
are already and within the ecosystem of
putting together software and I need to
think about security and if we start
empowering them with the tools but they
need to think more securely and operate
more securely and we can start spreading
the responsibility for security so that
it's not all sitting on us of security
professionals this doesn't do as out of
a job
but it makes our job more targeted and
it makes our job more useful at the end
but the main thing that it does is it
takes that preventers responsibility
away one of the things about doing a
panel test at the end of development is
it's like a game of Jenga have you ever
tried to put the Jenga rod back into the
pile without knocking it over so we kind
of stuff it with stuff and call it
patching and hope for the best
the product over there is very one of
our patches because people like to be
changes so basically some of the things
that we can put in place this is just a
snapshot it's an idea and there are all
sorts of different things within
security but product owners can create
the right requirements they can do
initial security considerations defining
the risk of a response so things like
and reach and implications is something
that they can define and the
implications that data protection is
something that they can define then we
have the developers creating secure
builds of
technology interpreting vulnerabilities
and solutions learning secure account
doing things in Sprint's and then
testing after each sprint means that you
don't have to necessarily have an
enormous talent test that takes two
weeks at the end which is vitally
important for you to go live only to
find that it's full of holes and Jade
did the test once which was horrifying
where he was able to steal the money out
of every single bank account from an
application because the variability was
so embedded in the code it didn't take
it out they couldn't sell the
application they would have to rebuild
the application then we have the testers
we do fantastic Elton's influence
initial due diligence requirements
technology vulnerabilities these are
people who are already poking around
with this tech probabilities our basic
features bugs and ant software testers
are already looking for bugs we have
some more bugs but not of the software
kind we have design for example again
they can help in building tools with
better UI scalability usability and like
one of my bug bears again when software
tools and security tools not having
great UI as anyone here used PGP I don't
think anyone gasps yes excellent what
any of you say it's a usability is good
yes incredibly it's an incredibly
essential tool I mean we don't really
have anything else pretty good for email
a prefix I pressed mine but people don't
want to use PGP even the creator of PGP
doesn't use fatigue review for 50
minutes that's that's what we've got a
problem and we also the deployment
people so for example these guys can be
involved in configuring the pipeline
correctly they can be involved in
security considerations when it comes to
the pipeline when we do the testing and
so on forth but when we talk about this
and they can also be involved in like to
fight there do I need you diligence even
for like deploying boxes you know
there's a lot of stuff that we do that
could be done by anyone really involved
in the process of setting up the server
and we also have security which is us so
we can be involved in stuff like threat
modeling we can be involved like really
interesting
like I think maybe we could even do
buffer overflows on our day-to-day
business now and we can also help verify
you know issues that have been found by
other people during the testing process
and just generally giving advice and
being Yoda sitting down happily doing
our stuff we have thing and again
insecurity in this context is security
mindset so it could be a technical
person it could be a non-technical
person it might be that you have a
privacy lawyer in your organization you
have to be using that privacy lawyer to
help you understand why you need to be
secure or are you just using them to mop
up the pieces after you breach there are
people like me everywhere I'm just
naturally incredibly suspicion
because nobody I assume everything is
going to be the worst case scenario this
is like I just know that everything is
the worst case scenarios I've tested
things for so many times literally every
time I look at anything the first thing
I'm looking at is a location marker
because I was abducted as a child like
the parental thing but that's actually a
reality so it makes you very suspicious
you think in a certain way so if you
think of worst case scenario then you
can start to say what's the threat and
that's a basically trap modeling yeah
then you can go look on Wikipedia and
get some things that sort of give you an
acronym come out with stride but it's
basically flat modeling it's thinking
about what the facts in the data are so
again we need to drive from why are we
protecting your data so to loop back to
our original fear and doubt no that's
problem and loop back to like stress and
burnout so if the GUI is embedded when
the attachments start it means that our
from input is more interesting is more
welcomed and it's generally more fun for
us and there's nothing fun about doing a
two-week test on something that no one
cares about anymore Horace talked about
in terms of security no one enjoys it I
don't enjoy it they don't enjoy it the
whole process is your pain and it means
our tests can be performed in smaller
bursts as well so we can sort of fit it
around the SPLC
I'm there therefore development
processes and it can be done when it's
required by the deaths as well instead
of simply as a sort of rubber stamp for
PCI DSS or something else that
forcing them to get that stuff they can
be performed in shorter time scales
which we're doing more tests and this
means that we can also hopefully avoid
the my least favorite part of the job
which is the PDF report so we started
doing things like raising issues in JIRA
for example which I'm really enjoying
because I don't need to write it in my
office when he was trying to read this
presentation Versa lariats all the folks
expect it yeah we try and make it make
more collaborative and and again you
know the PDF report is it's a not really
a welcome thing I've gone on so many
sites where they've like can you copy
all of these issues into a CSV because
that's what we'd be doing anyway so you
know just behind you for our stuff and
of course what why don't we just you
know let us know why do we do this from
the start why does everyone get a PDF
report it doesn't make sense no need
arises and again this is something that
we're already doing Jamila was shocked
when he heard that I'd already set up a
0 vm just to start doing this kind of
thing and then so I'm certainly enjoying
it a bit more than a the one hour
are the nine hours of reporting that I
do for like most us sir has Ali says
this is something that digital
interruption is already doing why did we
decide to do this we were knackered
we were absolutely knackered after 10
years of pen testing I have been on site
a lot I have traveled a lot on weekends
and it's a really stressful job when
you're living on site basically and
there's now six people in DI good call
three of us were basically living on
site we have a developer who wasn't
living on site actually brought me as
well for a button yeah and so you when
you live in a Travelodge in Slough you
don't have a home life you don't have a
routine your relationships suffer
and your health suffers that's why
people have what we call the pen test
belly jana is all about that'll burn
your diet suffers because having lived
in the hilton for nine months and you've
eaten the menu 92 times over it all gets
slightly depressing there's a gym there
but you know just watch the telly and
you can't get sick because you can't go
to the doctor because you doctors linkle
and you're not local anymore
and we also find that as consultants we
have to be responsive so if a job comes
in you have to do it so someone has to
take the hit so back to flour you go and
shadow link can be haphazard within a
lot of consultancies so I think even
with the situation where are the
scheduling working certain exercises and
I have people from London coming up to
Manchester and people from Manchester
going down to London make me sense
oh and all of this put something massive
strain on people and it makes people
tired and it makes people burn out and
it's not good for mental health it's not
good for mental well-being and it's not
good for people to be able to have a
happy and conducive life or a family
[Music]
because we are resources but we're also
people and our partners are people so
our partners are the ones that are left
at home with the dogs and the kids and
all of the responsibilities and they're
the ones that are taking up all of this
emotion or housework because we're
absent because when we're not on site
we're thinking about security all the
time which is why you can start it
beyond the abstract who stays up all
night thinking about the next
vulnerability we all do and it's because
there is so much responsibility part on
it's for security that it becomes
absolutely encompassing it sucks
everything out of us absolutely so when
we set up digital interruption we
decided we were going to do things
differently
we were very evangelical about dev
suck-ups because we're sanctimonious we
won't be do contest and then we nearly
run out of money so now we pen test
but what we can do is we can use the
monthly money from the let me confess
that no one wants to do we can use that
to offset the work that we do enjoy
doing so we have a massively discounted
rate for tax for good so if
organizations need to develop secure
tech because they're doing something
awesome like creating software but
because pieces of harassment bullying
sexual assault all the way up to vape
they really need to be secure and I
really want that software to exist so I
give them a massive discount rate and
literally everyone within our
organization at some point has helped
with the piece of work that we're doing
for this software to make it as robust
and scalable as possible we do other
pieces of work that center around
children and stuff around medical stuff
and we absolutely crash the write down
for it but we make them do tub setups
it's not a pen test at the end we're not
interested in sticking stuff back in the
Jenga tower we want them to understand
security we've also got some pledges
that we decided on well this is this is
Jamal Safian is more than me but I'm
gonna take some credit for well
obviously because we're a flat structure
so like your majesty when we decide that
the organization we went for unlimited
personal days no one in our organization
has to call in sick nothing okay why you
can't come in if you're below but I hope
you had a lovely night if you're having
a really hard time you can tell me and I
will listen if you have surgery and you
don't want to tell me what that is
that's fine because you know what if
I've got your sick note I have to deal
with that information and that puts me
in a legal position so I can't really be
bothered with the more interesting
things to do with my time
so it's fine it's also that effect so we
also got no port on site which is good
because basically it means we don't go
on site that much if there's a test
we're doing we will try very hard and
usually succeed and finding a way to do
it remotely or we do at least limit the
amount of like on site going on telstra
halls
booby traps are welcome yes we work with
realistic utility and so a lot of
organizations that we've all worked with
in the past have said that they're 75%
util and the rest is abdomen and and
research time we are literally 75% you
tilt it got it spread out across the
year because we're small and we do have
to be responsive so sometimes we'll have
a couple of months where we absolutely
back to back and then we'll felt about
for a bit when were quiet and give
everybody a nice little rest we shut the
office down for two weeks at Christmas
in our first year and Rob had never had
Christmas off and he was suicided he
tweeted about it
happy people we have flexible working
yeah so I for example work three weeks
on when we got it's amazing I have a
week where I can just sit around at home
doing nothing I'm so happy and it's yeah
it's great we basically well like Rob
for example were completely remote me he
almost never comes into the office
yeah he really likes the MBA so we kind
of do kind of like daylight reversal or
different hours if he wants to some
point I put that is fast up or observing
a Ramadan or the MBA they can move if
they want a little bit of a marketing
type line there but flexible needs to be
flexible you know people do have lives
again with people we're not resources
are most importantly we have no bosses
because no one listens to us anyway but
a flat structure is really important for
people's well-being and it's a case of
being able to say no if you don't have a
situation where you're feeling
if you don't have buses you can't be
forced to do things that you don't want
to do which is bad for your mental
health I just have to resort to
manipulation and they you've got this is
hard for us as brilliant because we've
got office we do gardening and we go and
see our families and we do skateboarding
today and I going to be learning Russian
because we can actually commit to go
into a class every week on a Tuesday
because we can move our work around this
and Rock plays basketball yeah the name
is basketball all the time I don't know
what YouTube I don't want to know what
you did you can do too so those points I
just might not be realistic for everyone
but we do I guess it's just you know you
could potentially look like let's start
with like managerial stuff so don't
promote bad managers is a bit bit I grow
but like anything your managers are
really people ppad people because I
worked in some places where managers
have been stupendously technical and
don't want to deal with the actual like
management side of things and I guess
that kind of ties into enforcing good
policies as well so again you want you
know a business that has policies that
look out for the people that work there
you want to ask your staff you want to
get feedback from your staff about these
things and about your manager and about
everything else trust doctors is it's a
really important one for me I have ADHD
I make no secret of my ADHD and it does
all sorts of interesting things to my
brain but one of the things I
particularly have problems with is noise
I really noise sensitive and I'm the
ADHD kind of person that can't put on
headphones and listen to music if I'm
listening to music I can't think of
anything else nothing gets done
ping-pong really irritates me I can't
stand drains nerf guns are the worst
thing in the world
and I can just hear the tapping of Snuka
so when I'm in an organization that says
we have all these really cool stuff that
might be great but for me it's really
exclusionary and I think for a lot of
people on the spectrum and stuff like
that can be really really illusionary
I'm really what we want to foster it
digital interruption is an environment
where everybody is welcome and part of
that mental health is understanding that
mental health is also about neurotypical
and non very typical and we don't know
what Ali is but he has a specific way of
dealing with things so we basically just
trust our staff we give them the
autonomy to be able to make their own
decisions
finally don't buy my practices yeah so
this is more for like clients as well
what I mean no ask your penetration
tester how he's doing how far he's
traveled if he's been in place a
proportionate yeah yeah if you can
request someone from like nearby or
locally and save someone you know three
hours travel on a Sunday please try and
do that something happens the worst oh
my god I know it's the worst and when
people say you don't have to do Sunday
trouble we've got a policy on it don't
then say you have to get up at half past
three in the morning on Monday yeah yeah
yeah do things like look at class stop
see what these stuff are actually saying
so when you're looking at different
vendors when you're looking at different
companies and if you're paying for
companies to produce things and you're
then consuming that and you're also
paying for them to abuse their stuff if
that's what their business culture is
like so these are things that we as a
community can do we can say enough is
enough we can say we don't want to do
this anymore we can say that we are
tired we can say that we are knackered
and we don't have to set up our own
company in order to have that autonomy
there are so few of us and we are in
such demand that we can actually start
to say we don't want to do it like this
anymore
and we can start to push that change
ourselves it's just about having the
courage to do so
thank you for coming to our turn rent
thank you hon any questions yes everyone
is questions oh god I don't know how we
can we can deliver this up because
people are how this works well you guys
you have to choose who you want to pay
the question so I do mostly saying isn't
Christ already doing some type of work
in terms of actually making this into an
industry I think you're right yeah I
crusts are definitely doing a make
making head wounds in there I think
we're fully there yet but I agree the
questions don't really great details but
yeah Chris isn't unified we've still got
stuff like the CH and CPM stuff and the
Chris actually has integrated other CP
into the CIT now but yes not every quest
is doing good stuff but it's optional
isn't it yes so that's the thing and
something isn't a standard unless
everyone is doing it and that's the
problem so someone who's been putting
standards together forever and that is
the reason that we have an absolute core
minimum standards for things like child
care and medicine because the impact of
not doing that is the bride's mistake
and that's something that we have to
take into consideration through security
as well yeah you didn't get the software
right for a plane and it pulls out the
sky what's the impact of that and and
through all that Quest is doing great
work it's kind of doing it on its own
and it's also quite expensive so if you
take something like national bacon or
standard that's paid for by the
government it's universal everyone has
to have it and you simply cannot
practice unless you meet that standard
and it's regulated it is something that
you haven't imitating so I think that's
the problem that we have at the moment
is security is just so incredibly
expensive in every way and for all that
the frameworks for Cresta brilliant it's
constantly having to be accredit it's
constantly having to reset exams how
many people did we have that we've known
in our in our impersonal community the
who keep trying to resit the crest exams
and then they just run out of time
because they get polling site yeah I
mean and
yeah Indian short Christmas good but
yeah like formal education that you got
to push up who caught you oh so yeah
that is one thing that is worth talking
about then again it comes down to cost I
would rather it all be free somehow and
I think to be honest with you like
security should probably be something
you should be teaching from like in in
primary school why are saying this or
whatever we have computers in school
here because it's a really poor and
useful school that have like justjust
even knowing that you shouldn't put your
bank details under sometimes it's not
using HTTPS so a lot of people don't
know right but also pushing it behind
education is interesting going but this
is not missing it but I definitely have
National Occupational standards it's
having a clear and concise and uniformed
and accepted understanding of what the
competencies are how you reach these
competencies can be in a number of ways
so I worked throughout my a-levels and
went to evening classes so that was
something that it's actually because of
the premise that were in place I was
able to do you can self educate and
medicine exams there are different ways
of doing things the dip that the
National Occupational standards are that
you are able to demonstrate you are able
to have an assessment at the end that
says you are competent to do something
but unless we've got something to assess
against you can't do that so an example
would be the dermal Medical Council you
train seven years to become a doctor you
don't just say right right now I'm gonna
go be a doctor you have an assessment by
the GMC and they license you to practice
and if you fail that assessment chopped
it's it doesn't matter that you've done
seven years of training you you won't be
able to do it it's like saying oh well
I've been learning to drive for ages but
you know driving tasks mean you need to
have that driving test and that constant
assessment there's so much what's the
scoop I can watch it worthless
right you really drive it down there's
also a charted engineering stuff we're
just about there
we just destructive like the competing
all the competing sort of qualitative
yeah I completely agree there's alone
and that's something that again should
be change right because the system is
great it's not good from a technical
point of view for what I want to do but
for like quality writing in for a lot of
security stopping to do an incredibly
useful thing to learn and do yeah yeah I
completely agree that that needs to
change and then we have this piece each
other people moving around the room and
having that level of competition as well
actually holds us back it means that we
don't progress forward because we're not
getting the right people making a
unified decision and that's again unless
I love them but they're done in
consultation we're done every two years
and it's industry leaders that make the
decisions which is why we've changed the
way that we educate but stay like for
education for example we don't teach in
the way that we used to anymore it's not
always just about the kind of medical
adage there's a lot of industries that
have managed to really incorporate new
ways of doing things because they have
this base standard that says ok right
well it didn't work it work then it
doesn't now this is how we move on what
you're saying we're a psych resident
rating on CPS your peers a really good
step towards something like yeah I
notice but I'm happy with it at least
we've had time called so if anybody has
more questions well lighter and you have
come and grab and values on but we need
to let