okay for a Nextag I would like two were
welcomes us who will be talking about ho
to her
taking trade for divers vehicles so
please get me wrong
polls thank you
I can leave this room Flycam addressing
the united nations or something
there extremely exciting including that
the representative
from the country have anonymous see a
over here for the second round with
vehicles
quick so I think about myself on I have
an academic background in autonomous
robots
other perhaps what invest $9.4 is a
cable TV show
they did he is a Google product like
this where we tried to act together
thank all demos
including several that involve the time
vehicles and
wanted the other people on the show with
me was Joe Grande AKA kingpin who is
here
and Franco Nero there and we'll be
talking
tonight after gaining out your afternoon
entertainment
is more info about how the school
projects but he is a tiny preview about
some other ones relevant to this talk we
get a homebrew UAV system
to help protect on God beaches so it
would fly out
into the ocean and drop your life
preserver he got into trouble
and we learned a lot about unmanned
aerial systems
doing this you could say it was an and
punitive
process meant a lot about failure to
them unmanned aerial vehicles
on we also DA
driverless ground vehicles for one other
more pressing technological challenges
in the ground vehicle space which is
maintaining the American read in
high-efficiency pizza delivery
so he is the solution for local
all times pizza delivery sharing routes
in space with pedestrians on the
sidewalk
and the long distance method operating
in a Shi'ite automobile network
this pizza delivery a to Treasure Island
in San Francisco was the first
ever autonomous crossing in the United
States highway bridge in the service of
pizza
I can be hard to convince even a human
driver to make that trip
of those groom you need like with but
the robot do it on
more recently I've been involved in a
lot of people competitions
for a nation and the ADSI condition so
there's a grounded competition
to aerial vehicles to bow competition
summary competition and those I liked
life streamed on the web several them
and you can you can watch them
but the motivation for this talk I
wanted to say quickly
I am a huge fan of autonomous unmanned
systems
I think they %uh the future
transportation and many other industries
and they definitely coming because there
are so many advantages
such as energy efficiency not having to
carry human drive in I'm gonna carry
support for the human driver like food
and water and bathrooms or have to stop
for acquiring those many things on that
with also time savings
nothing to do with fatigue boredom no
time spent with rest stops
operate a changeup is that kind of thing
and then all the new applications that
are enabled when it wasn't practical
are economical before to do that with a
human operating system
so not replacing jobs but actually
enabling
new areas and you places that we can go
and
explore so I say
you can stop the robot revolution even
if you wanted it's coming
but like everything else that you meant
that ever made
in history he's gonna be hacked so I
wanna stop talking about it now
as we're kind of on the cuff this
revolution before the systems that too
entrenched
a for us to go back on certain decisions
that are made
chevron's Rincon think I'm an example
the decision in technology that was made
a long time ago that we're still having
to live with on
this health particular element for
Europe at the moment the american
efforts in this in this
face have been getting a lot of the
press but and Europe
the UK has announced on road trials
driverless vehicles in three cities
starting next year and to go along with
that a $10 million pound Research Fund
Sweden
is giving Volvo commission to invade
Gothenburg with a hundred
driverless vehicles in 2017 that's a few
years of
but surely many other countries in
Europe and not gonna lie get left behind
again. wanna quickly follow suit and
again we know in technology that haste
and playing catch-up often leads to bad
security decisions
on but with all that said
what I don't want to do here is spread
fear uncertainty and doubt
far from it on this isn't going to be
some kinda llamaste
anti robot propaganda sir
a great pleasure for me to come to
Europe and put to Hitler joke on the
same slide
over not too soon on but def
this is not what this is about on it's
not about stopping the robot revolution
it's not about
interfering with the the deployment have
the system it's about getting it right
on and I really got a sense
I love the how unmanned systems in the
future
when I got a chance to grab this video
the five gal helicopter
on a little over a year ago at the
unmanned aerial systems competition so
this is a
US military on and got helicopter and
it's going on
on a mistake of and
and hopper and ask any of life's not
gonna miss Tess and I really got a sense
right at this videos like Wow
yet lets let the robot drive it's really
good at
right really really stable on
I'm not trying to be with them but my
point is
I'm doing for hackers and hacking
I mean in the old school fans 0
discussion
analysis figuring out how things work
and what's wrong with them
and how to improve on so it's about
getting people excited to contributing
to that
and to the eventual acceptance
driverless vehicles so we can talk about
vulnerabilities
and interference with tribal system but
out love type got tough love for
speaking amazing vulnerabilities
this flask out is is very stable as I
mentioned but the operators if you look
closely it's hard to feel that flight
they're hiding
in almost you know seemingly para behind
the stockpot
just in case so that the security
mindset right it's like yeah we made
this robot we know how good is with the
gonna hide behind everything when we
pick it up
so when I talk about exploits and and
countermeasures against robot vehicles
your job as the audience to think about
count account images
and ways that the system can being can
have its robustness increased
that's how we develop corporate systems
the immune system space is really wide
on it doesn't just mean for long robots
just means that there's not a human
driver a pilot on board
you might have %uh of board controller
or supervisor
surface above I thought on any on you
may still have plenty of humans on board
the just not piling I have a safety
pilot well you might have a whole lotta
passengers
and as we know
up until now the field has been largely
dominated by the military
military funding and military
applications and as a lotta reasons for
that which a
need to get into now but
assist a significant now this uptake in
the military space has been a real
system
and
that seems a little counterintuitive at
first because the Aerial systems can
pull out at Sky
crash easily but there's a lot of things
about the air that makes the point
simpler for example the fact that if low
probability running into something as
long as you still up in
so he's one representative system this
is the Global Hawk
and they've published on
and unclassified on the uptake in terms
of lighthouses
Global Hawk and you can see that it
looks pretty much like an
an exponential curve and the government
especially in the United States is
really interested in pushing this
exponential uptake and other demands as
well so twelve years ago congress
insisted that by next year by 2015
one-third of all
military ground vehicles will be on hand
obviously
its okay for the people giving money to
say whatever the hell they want
on than other technologists and they
can't make it happen and it's not going
to happen by 2015 at the wheel with
their
I'm not gonna talk much more about
military vehicles
I because the capabilities classified
largely
on they already have a very keen
interest in
resistance to adversarial engagements am
and as a different cost equation with
respect for example the census high
quality sensors
and once that resistant to you some
technical talk about and also most us
in the civilian space will never really
encounter one on
and my sweet goal snowed in and have
people have a lot of people out there is
hopefully whenever and 21
on so
for example the military space their
drivers ground vehicles with
threats design in mind this is a kinda
century droid for the army and as you
can see it absolutely covered in various
weapons
and a lot of redundant sensors on
it for the fun kinda funny to me I could
as the prototype if they just have to
get close enough to this the press funny
kill switches that are all over the
robot
that's kinda like putting an unshielded
reactor exit exhaust port on the desktop
you know
if you just gotta hope someone remembers
to remove that from the production
version
but is gonna start showing up not just
military space but kinda not back out to
love the place obviously
transportation friends about that
particular tech company which I don't
wanna
single out that will mention them a
little bit on
oceanography Zhuge some submersibles
and and boats dress through mapping
on they're all the rage now in camera
control you can buy
really kickoff a stabilized camera
camera drying on now from from China
like 2015 up fifteen hundred dollars
fully-loaded
operates out to a kilometer really
really nice
Palin inspection is huge is
hundreds of thousands of kilometres a
Aline that need get inspected and
robots and efficient way to do that cost
logistics and delivery
ok and other things like that here's
another European sample
rolls-royce maritime division just
announced that they think that the
future
cargo shipping is completely on man and
actually making a documentary right now
about civil application the time and
both
because they're kinda the least explored
area unmanned systems
but there's starting to be a really
really big push their on and
that's partly because seventy-five
percent of maritime accidents are caused
by human error
and the major technical challenges going
on man bites
is dealing with hardware failure really
long Boyd
obviously this this hacking and security
concerns but the fact is saudis
missions go for weeks or months and
things break I
but if you talk to this the industry
Abbas eg advocacy group for ethical
obligations
unmanned vehicles these are there to
prioritise precision agriculture
comment combine harvesters
a lot of things that perform agriculture
right now practically robots already
a to you GPS guidance and localization
on and infill driving past for their the
big
to lightfoot ability overall countries
which
which to food production and
transportation which is basically all up
on and the roadblocks to fill the main
uptake
I use a shared infrastructure sharing
them with me and because we could take
all the
manned vehicles off the roads right now
then we could deploy the stuff
immediately
but having the robot interoperate with
human makes it difficult
hand in hand with that acceptance
safety and robustness demonstrations but
also the public perception of it making
sure people
believe at this second robust and of
course privacy as well that's being
com written into the FAA guidelines on
on
unmanned aerial system regulations even
though
FAA United States really has nothing to
do with privacy that people are so
concerned about it that it's being
written in
but 15 robustness a
you know and let my we've got that out
the way the fun stuff to talk about
is failure here's a couple classic
failures
festival in the aerospace this is
the Boeing Oct 23 docs to
there's single surviving one in the
smithsonian
using their own space in DC if you ever
be DC is that the sea
you can go and look at it this was
ultimately supposed to cost $10 million
dollars per year
thanks I units 11 to 20 after they
finished all the development work
but the prototypes obviously a lot more
expensive the first prototype the %ah q3
fail catastrophically on its very first
flight %uh
are at second flight its second pic of
actually
and I i've seen personally my eyes the
video this
I was not able to get a copy to show
with the sadist gonna have to
imagine it let me talk during on but
here
is the takeoff run have the %ah q3 on
priority me this is the
a successful take-off run may be the
first flight second flight
imagine that take up front but imagine
it starting to kinda
jump a little bit on the on the runway
as a thought the takeoff
and those of elation getting bigger and
bigger increasing amplitude until
eventually pitches nose up
stole crashes viable millions of dollars
down the drain
so here's the quote
about what happened from the journal and
I'm in systems engineering
I am prophesying oscillations
critical time we infernos hi stolen a
crash what the what happened
well what happened was the designs
who modeled the flight control system
and develop that that the takeoff run
model that on asphalt runway smooth
surface no seams
the actual takeoff promised on on a
prefabricated concrete
family that had small tiny like
quarter-inch seems
between the concrete play both
small in health from the seams
shockingly
across wheels took off daily input the
national census
that landed amped and over-corrected and
we saw our classic positive feedback
loop leading to a crash
catastrophic failure millions of dollars
down so the morrow that story
tomorrow Zach the expectation for the
design is a critical
even a seemingly trivial detail like the
runway composition can be the difference
between success and failure
and exploitation is going to occur
it's likely to happen at those cracks
between the boundaries the people's
expectations
is another failure example this is an
another classic this
is from the top the first up a grand
challenge an autonomous robot race
between
Los Angeles Las Vegas 2004
on this is sandstorm
com which is that vehicle from a
spin-off from Carnegie Mellon University
and it was the favorite to win the first
up a grand challenge
got around seven miles
before it took a turn wrong and ran off
the side ended up in a weird angle
and caught fire
his to you videos sample in action
one lead eventually to the crash for the
the crashes down the bottom com
so what happened sandstone had a huge
teen
working on right that a lot of people
and they had the ability to extensively
map the course beforehand they actually
had people walk
the entire course on once they got the
information from Topher about where was
gonna go
the map was so good that they could
pretty