[Music]
hi this is Rob Sheen from source
conference and I'm here with an
on-screen Eva's who is the CTO and
co-founder of Nyanza and he's gonna be
giving a talk at source Boston next week
on the wild wild west of IOT security in
the enterprise so lots to unpack there
so I know why don't you tell us a little
bit about your talk yeah for sure so it
comes from being part of a company in
the answer that we look at a lot of
client devices in a lot of enterprise
networks and so different verticals you
know there's education so in
universities there's healthcare and
networks there's manufacturing networks
there's distribution warehouse networks
and other retail networks as well and as
we sort of look at all these devices and
we're looking at more than 20 million
client devices most of these devices are
your plain vanilla you know iPhones
Android phones windows you know laptops
and whatever else but a growing number
of these are these sort of RR io T
devices and when we think of IOT devices
a lot of the times we think about the
critical ones and obviously these are
the most important ones so you think
about in healthcare infusion pumps EKG
machines you know vital signs monitors
gluco meters whatever have you
telemedicine robots you know those
robots that kind of move around with the
person's face on them or whatever it is
right all of these things are networked
and all of these things are critical
right if you think about manufacturing
you think about handheld tools like the
torque wrenches that sort of you know
tighten bolts that have to be network
connected you think about the robots
that are on the assembly line you think
about you know the autonomous guided
vehicles that are transporting things
around the area again you know devices
you don't necessarily expect but they
exist in all of these environments and
these are critical again and then you
know other examples in retail for
instance or distribution warehouse you
think of barcode scanners so in all
those really big distribution centers
you know if your your barcode scanners
are critical there in order to be able
to stock the stock
the shelves or get products in and out
of those areas again that were connected
there are Pickers these like vehicles
that sort of run you know back and forth
those are also network connected and
critical and so on and just even in
universities and enterprises you see
more and more smart lights you know
smart HVAC systems and and so on and
these are critical but then you turn
sort of you turn around and you say okay
well wait a minute are those all the IOT
devices that are on you know people's
networks and you come to find that's not
the case at all right there are those
kind of devices and those are super
interesting but there's also things like
photo frames connecting to the network
you know you'd be shocked at the number
of cars that connect to sort of secure
enterprise network like Tesla's or
Honda's or four or whatever have you one
of the most odd devices that I've seen
in both an enterprise as well as a
university or university environments is
a device called a love box so this is a
device that I had to look it up after
the fact but it's a device it's internet
connected I think it came out close to
Valentine's Day and basically you text
someone like a love note or like a love
message or whatever and when you do it
the Box starts spinning and then you
sort of open up the box and you kind of
see the message on the other side and
again I mean everything is getting
connected everything is sort of like on
the network nowadays and this is all
fine and dandy and this is only gonna
get crazier but the thing you gotta
watch out for is what are these properly
secured I think on the right networks
you know they better not be sharing the
same network as my EKG machine for
instance right and just you know what I
want to talk about at source is sort of
the experience of seeing all of these
different devices in the in different
environments and what kind of you know
things that you never would have
expected both in terms of the device
types themselves as well as their
security posture in terms of where they
are what they're doing you know and and
so on
so that's hopefully that gives
it gives you kind of an idea sounds like
you've seen a whole wide variety of all
the different kinds of things that can
be on the network some some very serious
some kind of you know but all like that
you know the love box and things like
that in a world where we're kind of
generally all on the network all the
time you know that is kind of it does
become pretty risky when those things
might be compromised in like pretty sure
the love box probably didn't get a
contest before it went a differentiate
between like the critical thing is it
not but even for the things that
technically aren't how do you maybe
discourage people from either putting
those on there or making sure that
they're on a safer part of the network
yeah I think the good news is for the
most part people have these on guest
networks and sort of guest VLANs and
sort of you know separate it out from
from from everything everything out
there so that's the good news but I
think you know you do see some
surprising instances where they are on
networks or for instance so the way we
kind of look at it is the reason you
should be interested in both critical
and non-critical devices is you don't
want a critical device on an unsecure
Network so we've seen you know like I
don't know Lou manometers or actually
even in one invited see an EKG machine
on a guest network on a non secured
network that's you're super useful to
know because obviously there are things
like the love box that can be on on the
guest network and then by the same token
you don't want to see things like you
know a car or an Xbox or anything like
this which wouldn't be critical
necessarily on sort of a secure network
we're sort of it can be used for
nefarious or not not even used for
nefarious reasons or anything like that
it's just that it's just not good policy
to have sort of non-critical devices on
critical critical networks it's it's
it's best to keep these things segmented
so let's rip off the segmenting for a
second because I
and a lot of cases especially in say
healthcare environments the network
tends to be open and flat at least
inside there's a tendency there to trust
things on the inside even though I know
that that's probably not the smartest
thing because once you're in you're in
and it's not that so shift that mindset
so that things like EKG monitors are
actually on a secured network where do
we start
yeah I mean it starts with you know
VLANs and SS IDs you have your basic
sort of unit of segmentation in in the
network and sort of making sure that
from that basic segmentation perspective
these things you know if you sort of
dive into a specific VLAN where you're
sort of enforcing ACLs at the router
that you have the devices that are on
that VLAN sort of share the right level
of security that you know that that's
sort of desired or you know for wireless
devices a lot of this stuff happens at
the SSID level we're on an SSID an SSID
basis you sort of enforce policy and
just make sure that that's that's proper
then there's kind of the graduate school
level of stuff where you get into
Software Defined Networking and micro
segmentation right where you can now say
well this group of devices regardless
you know I want to create sort of an
overlay Network which kind of has all
the security policy and all those sort
of requirements that I want and I'm
gonna sort of create these grooves and
leave it up to my software-defined
network to do the micro segmentation for
me using overlays as opposed to using
basic things like as societies and VLANs
and definitely that's where it's sort of
the industry is trending in terms of
where where everybody wants to get to
because it's the most you know flexible
and most general way to sort of do this
things or these things but what I've
seen sort of in practice is let's get
the you know the undergrad level of
stuff done first so that kind of covers
the technical aspects of it though yeah
but how do you
management's actually do it because
especially in the healthcare environment
they tend to focus on functionality so
like as it work if they don't work and
that you know the doctors don't
certainly don't care if it's not a
secure Network are not necessarily
unless they have a reason to you know
how do we kind of move that needle so
it's actually getting pushed by
management at the right yeah in the
right times so it's a really good point
I I think the first step there is to
even just shine a light on it so if you
went to a just an arbitrary IT
department or a security department and
you asked them the question tell me
every single IOT device that's on your
neckline right that on the corporate or
the the either the corporate or the
secure or whatever it is and just ask
the question I almost guarantee you that
most departments wouldn't be able to
answer that question or they would have
ideas they would say I think you know
there's these devices or whatever it is
and I think there are this many of them
but I'm not 100% sure right right and so
really the first step and and one of the
most interesting aspects of even going
to a customer environment and sort of
turning on the solution um is just the
aspect of okay let's just look at this
SSID did you know that these things were
on this SSID or did you even know that
these things were on this VLAN and you
know that customer where we saw the EKG
machine on an unsecure Network I mean
when they saw that they fixed it they
got that device sort of off that network
very quickly but you know they just had
no idea they just didn't even know right
and so I think that's clearly the first
step of all of this which is shining a
light on it and sort of exposing the
fact that there are these potential
policy violations part of this is in
certain industries there's also
compliance aspects to this as well right
like in healthcare is to kind of stick
in to that example there's if compliance
well you can't have patient data on an
unsecure network or whatever have you
and you know that that creates other
kinds of problems
um right and so you know so that's
that's I think that's probably the first
step just to shine a light on it and
have that got it so maybe shifting focus
from the the implementers of it to the
manufacturers of it you know a lot of
these things can't even really be
patched or they're running on really old
operating systems and if you upgrade the
operating system you might actually
break the device and you know how do we
maybe shift the mindset of the
manufacturers a little bit to get them
maybe a less little focus on features
and functionality a little bit more
focused on security or is that just kind
of a crazy thing to even ask for I think
that just like your pipe dream because
obviously you know the main the makers
of the Lovebox their use cases to sell
you know Valentine's Day happiness I
guess right I was thinking more in lines
of the EKG manufacturers than love yes
so for the non-critical stuff yeah
exactly that's totally gonna be a pipe
dream for the EKG machines for the
infusion pumps for the barcode scanners
and so on I think even there it's tough
because that's not where they make their
money right you know like Honeywell
selling barcode scanners you know isn't
focused on security and networking or
anything like that they're focused on
okay well how do we be able to scan
these packages and get that data out as
fast as possible and you know how do we
sell as many of these things as possible
right as quickly as possible and you
know do we really need to hire security
engineers sort of that or networking
engineers probably not right do we want
to buy the most you know do we want to
buy a Cisco Networking chipset so that
the networking is all secure do we want
to buy a super secure chipset which
costs you know 20x the amount of let's
say like the the cheapest possible cheap
chip said probably not right I mean
let's just buy the cheapest thing and
make as much profit on what we're trying
to sell as possible so I think you know
what we've seen in general which is
actually we see things both from a
security standpoint and a performance
standpoint and what's being super
interesting is it's not as though these
devices perform very well either on the
network
right these devices have the most quirky
behavior they drop off the network right
they do sort of random things which
affects like other devices as well but
it all stems back to the same problem
which is this that the manufacturers of
these devices they make money by selling
the device to the line of business and
they're trying to solve a very specific
line of business problem they're not you
know selling it because it's the most
secure device and the most net worth the
you know the best networking you know
device right and so it's this sort of
gets us to you know that aspect of with
IOT security it's hard to rely on the
vendors and for that matter it's even
hard to rely on the consumers spending
more money buying products that have
better networking or security chipsets
or software stacks right because even as
a consumer I want to just buy the
cheapest thing right because I you know
that's that's what I need to solve so
you know that that's kind of what flips
IOT security a little on its head which
is that you almost have an expectation
that the security and the networking is
gonna be really bad and so you have to
sort of work around that and kind of
mitigate that a little bit after the
fact by looking at what these things are
actually doing on the network and trying
to sort of adjust to what they're doing
as opposed to sort of being able to rely
on the source no pun intended so it
sounds like we're kind of stuck at that
point where as the enterprise consumers
of this year we're probably better off
just making the assumption that it's
flawed and then building walls around it
I think kind of segmenting it off so
that it can't affect anything else when
it yells not if it's I think so I mean
here's another example of something that
we found recently we found you know what
looks to be lazy Road a vulnerability
with with a certain device in a critical
environment and it's probably what's
probably happening is it's not the
device manufacturer that's necessarily
at fault
it's the supply-chain down the road
right so it's not like they manufacture
everything in their headquarters or
anything like that they have to get
parts from you know wherever you have to
get parts from and those people you get
parts
from they have to get parts from other
places as well and software and drivers
and whatever else and in that supply
chain somewhere there could be a problem
so even if you trust implicitly the
manufacturer maybe down the road in the
supply chain there's some something
going on and so I think it's probably a
safe bet to just always assume that
these things are you know could could be
problematic and sir I'd go over them
yeah yeah sounds like good stuff so all
right well like definitely looking
forward to hearing about your talk and
the talk is the wild wild west of IOT
security the enterprise and it's going
to be next week and you're speaking on
looks like Thursday so looking looking
forward to it man all right cool so
we'll see you there and for those that
want to continue the conversation on our
T with an on definitely stop by the
conference and we'll there thanks Rob
all right thanks a lot