hi this is rob machine with a source
conference and I'm here with Bob Adams
who's the product marketing manager for
security at mime cast so he's going to
be speaking at source Boston on May 9th
and 10th and the title of his talk is
the Nigerian prince has been dethroned
but email remains King which is an
awesome title so I think I know what
you're alluding to there the whole
Nigerian email scam so how is that
Nigerian prince been dethroned so you
know the attack you know you'll still
see it people will probably still fall
for it but it's really evolved what we
really see is that attackers you know
saw that tactic as something that they
could use in the early days of email but
now that people have become smarter more
technologically advanced they've had to
kind of develop their tactics so the
people that still try to pull off that
scam they're you know back in the early
90s whereas we're looking towards you
know the future in terms of what
attackers could actually find and then
using these attacks right so how have
some of these attacks evolved like what
because I'm sure they've gotten a lot
more sophisticated in some cases what
are some examples so the key thing is
you know this is a lot of malware and
viruses and things of that sort but I
look at kind of the the social aspect of
because social engineering is really
what's becoming popular you know it's a
lot of it's a lot easier to manipulate a
conversation and trick people to do
things rather than say code a new virus
to try to break in to say firewall what
have you our network it's much easier to
just spin up different ways to actually
manipulate somebody to send money or get
their pad give their passwords up and
then from that standpoint I don't need
the user anymore I can take control
myself so it's really evolved in terms
of you know it's especially the
multi-pronged attacks you know it's not
just you know one attack it's multiple
different things coming at you at one
say you really need to defend against
hmm interesting so as far as dealing
with this should we be primarily focused
on blocking the issues or detecting them
and you know why don't we start there
I always look at I kind of you know you
obviously want protection but protection
is just part of it it's the training
aspect that you really need to take
advantage of because so many times we
just say stop to a user into a regular
user that that doesn't teach me anything
I'm just being told I can't do it what
you'll have is a user call the admin
saying I've been trying to get here I
clicked on this link six times I'm being
blocked that's that's kind of the idea
so what we need to do is take advantage
of these teachable moments so yeah you
can block it you can detect it but what
you need to do is then translate that
into kind of the next phase in terms oh
okay now I need to cascade this down to
my environment so they can understand
you know what happened why it's
happening and you know if it happens
again maybe bypasses X detection they
could be that last line of defense to
protect you right that makes sense but
just one of the the things I hear from
people and I've asked a few people just
recently say you're just kind of the
latest in the line so I'm just kind of
going down and seeing who everybody's I
want everybody's opinion on this one so
can end users actually be trained for
this stuff because what I hear often is
like some of them can but some of them
can't and because some of them can't you
know you only need one right so is this
whole exercise and training people
futile it's not and I'll tell you
exactly why because you can look at you
know every different organizations you
know you know we're friends with you
know fish me there now rebranded a co
fence and there's other companies like
no before and you know their whole
business is e security awareness
training and it's very important because
when you first deploy those trainings
you'll see a massive amount of failure
rates you'll never get down to a zero
percent failure rate but what you can't
do is drastically reduce that I want to
say it was I want to say 2016 Verizon
data breach report the average you know
failure rate was about thirty percent of
users were opening and clicking on
phishing links which is a high
percentage but if you can drop that down
to 15 or maybe it's hard but under even
10 percent you now no longer at a 30 to
70 percent in failure e what you can see
when you start from so you know it's not
futile it's kind of like you know you
create documentation for your users
that offsets some of your helpdesk
tickets but your users are still gonna
call you does that mean you don't create
documentation absolutely not
it's trying to do your best ahead you
know
solving an uphill battle right yeah I
mean I've always kind of seen it as a
necessary layer just you know you get it
to the degree you can get it and you're
good and then you know the things that
still slip through you find other ways
to deal with those things and just kind
of making the problem a little bit more
manageable that's hi and Masha Sedova
who is on the the podcast recently her
take was that let having some of the
users you know be aware of it allows at
least one person to notice and report it
that way you can help train your
internal systems that that was a really
interesting one that I think is probably
one of the more important reasons
actually now that I heard her say it I
mean it that is true and one of the
things I love that on mine cast has is
user awareness so if I were say a
problem user it learns from each user
and I'm say that use that just
constantly clicks on things I'm not
supposed to what you actually can be
prompted with is information about the
email about the link and then you're
actually given an option which I like
it's you know it's safe it's harmful and
if I'm that user that know it's safe and
I can click it's safe I'm actually
brought to another page it tells me it's
bad tells me why in the back end my
favorite part is logged an admin could
actually see Bob Adams click this link
Bob was given a choice and he made the
wrong choice and now looking
historically he's made that wrong choice
twelve times this month so it also helps
really identify those problem users
right I'm just imagining the Microsoft
Clippy popping up and saying hey I've
noticed that you like to click on email
attachments we actually toyed with doing
a joke campaign about something like
that because everyone remembers Clippy
as as much fun as he was it drove
everyone nuts it was a funny point in
time so overall do you think we've
gotten better or do you think we're kind
of just running on the treadmill here
this stuff you know I live I like to
think we're getting better we have
people that are definitely getting
better we still have the the users that
are still kind of oblivious to a lot of
things
but it's a matter of the technology
that's being used to stop the attacks
cuz you know from my standpoint we look
at a lot of different studies people
don't realize it's well over ninety
percent of attacks start with an email
people are you know inherently trusting
well I got an email you know it's like
someone sent me a package I'm gonna open
this or a Microsoft wants me to reset my
password so we're getting better at
teaching users what to look out for
especially thankfully while we don't
have the nigerian prince as much anymore
we still have the bad Microsoft Tech
Support caller so it's being reported on
a lot more as a lot more visibility so
people are becoming more suspicious so I
definitely say the oh we're getting more
towards in the favor of the users what
attackers are still getting smarter I
mean there's four key pillars I always
look at there are really driving the
success factor its simplicity
credibility psychology and urgency
attackers are sending simple emails
using credible information using
psychological tricks whether it's a
executive to a lower ranking person or a
government authority to just a general
you know citizen and they're always
urgent do it now or there will be
consequences so when you can find those
four elements that's really what's
taking into a perfect storm to make a
user fall for something but or just a
general person but thankfully we still
do have the people that are becoming
more and more suspicious whether
actually stopping before they do it so
it's not as prevalent but we will
continue to have a back-and-forth battle
for sure
actually so in your talk itself I think
I heard you're going to give some
examples and we have really kind of
real-world things people are doing now
yeah without giving too much away
actually give an example of a perfect
spear phishing attack I got it actually
involves social media involves actually
you know different countries different
you know compromised accounts so it was
literally a perfect storm where nothing
actually could have stopped it it was me
being a smart user that actually stopped
it I mean if I had tried to go through
with it you know I would have been
blocked but to me did it for her to
actually get to the point to get to me
was really impressive where I was kind
of like I almost want to respond to find
out who
that was pretty good so I give some
examples like that and then just some of
the general examples and why they're
working but then also I like to
highlight some of the other tactics you
know some things I mentioned but really
some of the other simple things that
actually work like I a real-life example
where the signature was just president
in all caps and someone fell for it so
it's a little bit of simple stuff you
know I like to talk about you know you
know something for people will be
sitting there yeah yeah what else you
gonna tell me you kind of set the stage
and then bring it to the point where
it's like okay bring a full circle and
really just hope people think about you
know these attacks and the way they work
in a different way
awesome well it sounds like you're
really cool cool talk and I look forward
to seeing it on May 9th intent that
source Boston so it's just this next
week so uh you guys are seeing this now
show up next week in Boston and we're
gonna have a cool conference so hope to
see you all there and come on by and
continue the conversation awesome can't
wait yeah thanks Bob see you next week
thank you