hi this is rob machine with a source
conference and I'm here with Hayden
Johnson who's going to be speaking at
the source Phoenix Mesa event coming up
on February 8th and March first so
that's coming up in a few weeks we're
looking forward to that and hidden your
talk is on humane security in a world of
business and you've actually done a
little play of words on human humane so
tell us a little bit about your talk so
my talk is humane or human because
security works in a business which is
with people they try to make profit and
whatnot and I just wanted to build out
the idea that the most efficient way for
us to help security is through human
interactions so the relationships we
have sort of inspired me to work on
those skills to talk from everyone from
the CIO CEO CTO to the juniors and the
team such as a co-op or help desk or
things like that yeah the reason why
your talk Connor jumped out at me was
the the conference itself we've been you
know shifting focus a little bit to
really focus on people in communications
and that's exactly what your talk is
about so now you mentioned relationship
building a lot it's one of you maybe you
could provided some specific examples of
you know times where building a
relationships helped get security done
well back relationships sort of I learnt
that they were really helpful because I
used to be extremely technical and a pen
tester and focus on the exploit code and
then I was doing the pen tests and
handing a report away and sometimes the
client or someone was like so what why
what matters so what I was learning was
that a lot of my skills in not just
handing the report over by talking them
through the actual exploit or the data
that's involved with the reputation of
the business and then having a back and
forth conversation with them really
added a what a value for them and in
return I learnt that you know this
cross-site scripting attack that I think
is all where critical might actually be
minimal with if it's only touching say
someone's date of birth not a credit
card like there is context with what's
actually happening so I get a lot of
examples from my consulting days is
dealing with
and walking through them the pen test
report that's cool yeah that's a good
one I've actually seen that in real life
myself you know it's a lot of times when
we're really deep into technical stuff
we get focused on the technical stuff
and sometimes lose sight of the fact
that context actually does matter and
and that maybe the people you're giving
the report you don't have the context to
understand what it is you just mentioned
to them even so they might not even
understand what the issue is I see a lot
on Twitter or a lot of the podcasts
where they're like oh this super-awesome
exploit code is really great that it's
it's a gimmick work in 1% of 1,000
chances so the relevance or criticalness
is quite lower than the like the exploit
code and what they've done their skill
is really amazing but in the context of
business and all the different
priorities they have to deal with
security it's um not really doesn't
touch scratch the surface of what they
should be focusing on right right now it
sounds like for me too through your
abstract in your notes that you've kind
of done some work around getting in the
mindset of the non-security person so I
was wondering if you could just shed a
little bit light on you know how does
how do non security people think
differently about security than we do
well for example one of our juniors in
the itlp teams is a bit hashtag is or
quote-unquote pessimistic every time I
say oh how cool exploit or or this man
yet report like see what they did there
he's like Oh as if that would happen
here the chance that happening is
nothing hang on a minute no I'm like
totally into security and these things
are amazing and really interesting but I
was starting to get experience where say
this guy is showing me that there are
different mindsets to security and we
can get caught in that bubble so when I
talk to my manager or upper management
or say a girlfriend or boyfriend or
family their view is totally different
and the way differs is that security to
them is seen as a cost Oh like why
should my past would be twenty
characters long what a pain in the a to
have to type that out remember that what
why why are you asking me ten million
questions for my my credit card when I
just want to pay a bill and things like
that so with that in mind it allows me
to think of their position ahead of time
to try to have as much influence as I
can when I speak to them about security
because if I can understand that their
their attention span is one-tenth of
mine for security it gives me a better
way to to talk about security in a more
positive way that might have something
actually be done so sort of like
thinking about explaining security in an
elevator pitch like down five floors
have you spit it out and quickly they
get the important bits and they're like
oh that makes sense without them going
no you're just a mister no you don't let
us do anything and you cost us money or
time and effort right right
it's definitely some interesting points
one of the things I've definitely seen
is a huge problem as this communications
gap between the business folks and the
security folks and the security folks
the technical folks and we all kind of
speak slightly different vocabularies
and I've been telling people recently
when I speak to security people like the
bucks got to stop with us we got to just
get better at this so we got to start
you know it's not just being able to do
it but II able to teach other people in
our field how to do it do you have any
thoughts on like how we can get the
message out wider to more of our peers
well as to what why I was doing this
talk because a lot of my talks have been
more technical focused but I do a lot of
my talks to share knowledge and help
people and think that my experiences
aren't so unique I think other people
can learn so I think talking and
presenting is a great way that the real
problem I find is there are security
conferences like the b-sides or a circle
CD : or no lock on things like that it's
a bit of an echo chamber and a lot of
the culture is that really red team or
defensive team technical aspects so on
the defensive it's like how we detect
PowerShell or on the red team it's you
know how we use PowerShell to get to the
domain controller on credentials so it's
just the nature of the beast of the crew
of info sector little bubble in a bubble
and there's many bubbles in there so I
think growing awareness is just
speaking and blogging and tweeting
because on our Twitter we have a great
community but I think we also have a
small niche community where again we
have the echo chamber that is a lot of
InfoSec drama so if we can expand our
ideas and look at other industries or
look at those that communicate well so
that that is really the way to help
others learn to communicate is just
saying it's important we value your
technical skills very much many hours
you put in and how to learn is helped
but the communication skills even if you
just put one tenth of EF into learning
it you will get much further and you
will feel a lot less frustrated when
dealing with your boss or dealing with
management who think about financials
and the dollars instead of code yeah
that makes a lot of sense I've
definitely seen some of that myself like
as I've become more senior and less
technical and you know I can still be
technical but I you know definitely more
much more in the business side these
days it's given me a new perspective on
the way I probably perceived my boss
back you know 20 years ago and what they
went through I probably just didn't have
any clue what they were actually trying
to manage you know you know I was like
fixated on some technical detail but in
reality it didn't really matter compared
to you know did the business get done so
cool well you mentioned that sorry I was
gonna say you man that security and
struggling with management the
communication breakdown is on us that is
true because if I was really an article
about consultants how they learn and how
people will say that externally they
will blame things so like the client
didn't want us to teach them the client
wasn't open to our new ideas which is
valid but the only thing we can change
is ourselves though we have to actually
look internally and think how can i with
these current restrictions black a pen
tester with these little holes how can I
get the most value in communicating with
the management or with a non security
person and it's all about looking at
yourself and sort of
your skills - the way the field is
because there's a lot of security talks
I've been to and the people like I kept
screaming at them I kept putting it in
front of their faces and they wouldn't
listen to me and and that's fair that's
frustrating but you have to play by
their rules
but which is unfortunate yeah well they
they make the money in the rules yeah
exactly it's I don't see it as fortunate
or unfortunate it's just a thing it's
like you just yet it's like the thing
happens which is unless you're really
compelling they're not gonna listen to
you or even if you are maybe they're not
gonna listen to you because they might
have weighed they have different weight
on different priorities right and if if
ultimately it's their business that's at
risk and they're choosing to sign off on
the risk well that's there right now I
personally think that a lot of them sign
off on things they don't understand
you know so I think it is on us to try
to help better educate what we're
actually getting the sign off on but at
the same you know at the end of the day
it is their risk so it's it's a it's an
interesting balancing point for sure
yeah it definitely is well great well I
definitely look forward to continue this
conversation at the source Phoenix Mesa
conference coming up in a few weeks and
for those of you want to jump in and
join the conversation with us definitely
come on down to the conference and it's
on March febrile seizure thanks thank
you very much yours