[Music]
hi this is rob machine with a source
conference and I'm here with easy art
Aaron - and he is the lead product
security architect at Autodesk
and he's gonna be speaking next week a
source Boston on May 1st through 3rd
he's gonna be speaking on the Wednesday
and his topic is threat model every
story developers or architects - so
these are why don't you tell us a little
bit about your talk and what do you mean
by that when you say that developers are
architects - so this is an evolving talk
it's that the whole thing started
basically when I joined Autodesk about a
year and a half ago and we figured out
that our problem with threat modeling
was scaling was getting threat models
that work had the same speed as
development does and that actually
reflect what what the products are we we
had seen before issues of threat
modeling where it would be either done
at the beginning of the project and then
things would evolve and system would
change and at the end of the day the
tracked model would not match what
actually goes up there and you would
have that scramble just before
deployment
where hey let's figure out what happened
here and with the amount of products
that we have the different teams that we
have different locations different
levels of knowledge of security we we
had to figure out a way to get everybody
being able to do threat modeling that
would respond to those issues and we
came up with this nice methodology
that's been working so far and we wanted
to were to put it out there so that
people could also contribute to it see
if it's something that they can use
themselves and get some discussion going
around and together with that there is a
tool that we've been working on - two
people from Autodesk and two other of
external collaborators that does start
modeling is called and this talk is also
a vehicle to put it out there and show
to people and see if we can get more
people contributing to it and using it
so it's kind of a model for people to
use going forward that's cool yeah one
thing you you pointed out was that
you know the idea that you do the threat
modeling up front and then later it
changes I've definitely seen that myself
a lot I actually teach a threat modeling
class and oftentimes it's funny there
has been a number of times where the
first time they saw an architecture
diagram was when I drew them one and
usually it's not that bad but what
frequently does happen is I'll have
somebody else they all right who's the
best person to draw the picture and
they're up drawing the picture and
somebody in the back goes hey wait no
that's not how it really works and
they're like that's what and then they
argue about it for like 20 minutes
they'll late and I'll just let it happen
I'm like alright just figure it out cuz
we need to know the answer but it's
amazing if they if you don't force them
to have that conversation then it just
doesn't happen sometimes and I noticed
you would point it out in your abstract
that it's kind of gotten worse under
agile in a lot of ways because at least
under the waterfall model you had a
formal structure and time place where
things happen whereas agile you just
have sprints and you're just it's ever
evolving story is like how do you see
that it's that it varies in agile versus
waterfall what are your experiences
there what what you described is what's
usually called the Eureka moment which
is that time when people say yeah we are
secure because we do it this way in that
way and then some developers back of the
room cause it's not exactly like that we
had to take some shortcuts or actually
to to to connect to your point I think
that that discussion when it comes up is
one of the best things ever because one
of the things that I have seen with
threat models is that either you get
that one person that gets designated as
the threat modeler and he's going to
carry the whole thing or you do have
that disconnect between different teams
working on the same system and whatnot
and the systems that we have nowadays
data gets it's a paradox they get more
and more complex even though the pieces
that we use on them get simpler and
simpler so if we can use the threat
model in my opinion to to help the
discussion between the different
developers and different teams and
different parts of the system talking
about and actually having those arica
moments that
a lot of value in the threat model
itself in the process itself so the
whole methodology is built around that
and the tool actually is is in there not
to actually find threats that are of
high value but to enable developers to
have that discussion as the system
develops got it so what are some things
about the methodology that you're
proposing that allows that to happen
like like what in the methodology lets
people kind of get to it early and and
keep it up to date and all that stuff so
I think that if I if I were to order it
I think that one of the big problems
that I have with the way that we've been
doing threat modeling so far is training
we are asking people to figure out
threats basically out of the blue like
think like a hacker come out with what
could possibly go wrong and sometimes
they they lack not only the knowledge of
what is a threat actually but they even
lack the knowledge of the fundamentals
of what is it that there they are
protecting and what could possibly go
wrong so a big part of the the
methodology is focusing on those
specific areas of security interest in a
system pointing out example questions
that you would ask when you were
evaluation evaluating for example
authorization authentication or how do
you defend your secrets or or even how
do you find out what is it in your
system that's that's worth defending so
a big part of it is getting that initial
focus to build the baseline threat model
and then later on it's a checklist based
approach but not really a checklist of
checks that puts the developer in the
mind of okay I have this store in front
of me I'm going to write cold I'm going
to possibly even change the design of
the system what are the things that I
have to have in mind in terms of
security what what could it be that I'm
doing right now without considering the
security point of view that I actually
have to to introduce to a track model or
that I have to route to
other part of the team that somebody has
to pay attention to that or something
for example a developer that has to open
another part for them it's okay I open
the port it's talking David's flowing
fine but perhaps they have to make that
part of the deployment augmentation or
they have to let another part of the
team that deals with the firewalls know
about it so figuring out those security
notable events and making sure that
everybody that has to hear about them
hears about them and addresses them
either as a possible threat or something
that has to be written down somewhere or
part of the tribal knowledge of the
system that's basically we're committed
ology goes right
well that sounds awesome I know a lot of
people struggle with this and you know
there's not nearly enough threat
modeling done up there so the fact that
you guys have a formal methodology that
you're creating that you're using is
great and you're you know it's kind of
battle tested a little bit so definitely
looking forward to seeing the talk and
hearing more about what you guys come up
with looking forward to being there
all right great well if anybody wants to
continue the conversation come on by
source Boston next week these are ours
gonna be speaking on this topic on
Wednesday and we'll see you there thanks
guys there thank you