hi this is Rob Sheen from the source
conference and I'm here with Jason hey
Nick who's the founder and security
awareness expert habituate and he's
gonna be speaking at source Boston on
May 9th and 10th and his talk is titled
shifting a security awareness 2.0 so
Jason you've done a lot of work on
security awareness and that's always a
particularly interesting topic to me
because my last company I built was all
about security awareness and those kinds
of programs so when I see somebody
that's doing 2.0 that sounds really
exciting so what did he do what did we
get wrong in 1.0 and what are we doing
better in 2.0 well well that's a great
question and thanks for having me on I'm
really excited to be to be that there
and I think I think from my mind
employment what we get wrong in 1.0 is I
think just the approach that the end
user is stupid or idiot you know and
that they're always just going no matter
what we do it's always going to be their
fault and in the time that they spent
managing and building programs for some
in my past that's not really what I was
seeing the field right and so I think
for me it's kind of the technical
approach and being familiar with what
works on paper right and what works in
theory and then actually trying to put
that into play in the field and seeing
that what was research and studies show
in a lab on how we learn isn't it goes
out the door once we're at work and we
have all these other distractions and
things like that so I think that's what
I think we get Rona 1.0 and for me 2.0
is really focusing on the user
experience themselves and like creating
interesting content and things like that
so how do we differ the content I know
you know the traditional content was you
know original it was basically slides
with some notes at the bottom and then
we kind of shifted more like animated
things and a little bit more interactive
things but how do we tailor it to
the users actually need and how they
learn yes you're right I think for a
long time what we saw what we were
seeing or using was maybe a PowerPoint
presentation at some point and I think
we can all react this early to even the
term PowerPoint presentation right like
it doesn't doesn't really promote a lot
of excitement and then we moved into
this phase for a few years where there
was some vendors in this phase that were
creating LMS platforms for a training
platform so that we can actually deliver
the training and that was more serving
the purpose of delivering the training
and tracking the metrics and I think it
was a necessary step in the evolution of
security awareness and training but what
we weren't focusing on at all was the
engagement of it and I think we actually
got to a point where engagement became
confusing and by that I mean there was a
two or three year period where a lot of
the training platforms with both said oh
we force engagement like they're
required to interact with our training
modules right and I was i sat on the
other side of those trainings there was
a lot of the strings that ones that I
got the program for the Walt Disney
Company and when I'm trying to assign
training 240,000 users that are reading
the Marvel of galaxy for guardians of
the galaxy and frozen and engineering
theme parks not that there any more
discerning users than the average user
but I didn't even want to put all that
training in front of them and it was
because I found myself when I was just
reviewing the training multitasking and
not really paying attention right and
forcing them to click on something on
the screen or forcing me to click to
learn more I get it on paper it makes
sense right but at work like I'm just
trying to get my work done and I've got
a hundred tasks I have to do today and
you're forcing me the statue is hour
long training and it just didn't work I
didn't see it I didn't want to sit
through it and I'm fine users didn't so
that's when I started exploring a little
more with well what kind of content does
engage my users more
right and you know removing the things
like at Disney was where I really
started doing the original iteration of
the shoe eight videos but just using
funny videos right like it was it was
really it was really awesome because I
Disney I was at a movie studio you know
do I had these resources and they're
like I was pitching these ideas to my
senior leadership and they're like okay
well what do you want to do I like I
just want to try some funny videos I
just want to try some infographics I
want to I want to post event you know I
want to do something outside of just
staring at an LMS training dream so you
know alongside funny videos or whatever
we did some really cool live hacking
demonstrations for like live audiences
and we brought the FBI and the speed gun
you know calm calm and wrists and kind
of flipping it to a more personal
approach to how they can protect
themselves and their family and hope and
assume that they'll bring those
behaviors mm-hmm
yeah I know I definitely when you were
talking about the click to interact type
of trainings like I have to apologize
because I'm part of that problem because
I that was definitely one of the things
we were innovating on at the time
because that was and that was the
necessary next step because where we
were coming from was basically spoken
PowerPoint and it was god-awful and the
at least the interaction was getting
them to kind of do a little bit more and
but it was I always found it interesting
because I would I had at that point when
I started the the training company I had
already been teaching for a while and I
kind of figured out my in-person formula
for how to get an entire roomful of
people to follow along and be like yeah
the security thing is great so I thought
like yeah I got this man this is easy
and then I tried to convert that and
translate that exact basic script into
an e-learning module it's really hard
it's it's it's really challenging to get
that same level of connection that you
would get in an audience so what I kind
of learn from that is you just need a
different approach yeah yeah absolutely
interaction focus you know interactive
module focus
training to allow us to kind of grow
further because we have to learn that
stuff right and you're right and you
just mentioned what is like the core my
approach will be security awareness any
type of a security where's training or
presentation or program is when I'm in
front of 1,500 users on delivering and
training it's a much different
experience right it's like the
difference between a band that you go
see that's really great live and maybe
try and capture that in the studio and
it there's always like an element
missing here is that I think that's kind
of where we're at right now I was trying
to try and capture that live sound in
the studio and said oh I didn't kind of
sort of taking the approach and I think
that moving to 2.0 to kind of circle
back is like thinking differently on how
we're building these things from the
very beginning so if we're if we're
saying okay we need to send something as
simple as a mass communication out on
this fishing risk that's out there right
now the latest fishing right thinking
how that's going to land in your
co-workers inboxes and like what do we
do like at that moment when they read it
and maybe if you decide you mean to do
that communication which I have lots of
opinions on that as well but if you
decide that you need to do that like not
putting five paragraphs worth of
detailed information that they're just
not going to read give it to them so
they can read it 10 seconds and show
them value and get out the door right
right so you've kind of alluded to
expanding beyond the original scope of
training a bit so one of the things we
used to recommend is that you don't just
do this you know one and done training
course once a year and then they never
see anything else again you try to make
it part of an overall program like how
do you see some of this stuff kind of
building out into more of a program and
programmatic approach rather than just
the one and done things yes that's a
great that's a great question and I
think that first part of your statement
is really really defined in my my
opinion like 1.0 it is that okay we need
to do this so we're signing the training
once a year and they take it just like
harassment and
bribery and all those things and if that
doesn't work we know that and so I think
the first couple years of my experience
doing security awareness I didn't even
know I was doing security was first of
all right it was just something I was
doing talking to my co-workers and my
employees explained to them like why did
they get that virus on their computer
and why do I have to clean it off their
computer for them right and then when I
was at Disney what actually when he was
first set of Activision I was at
Activision that are doing awareness and
I mean doing the thing right like we
were gonna start doing the fishing
simulation we were doing the training
you're doing in-person thing but there
was no I didn't have like a method to
the madness and then I carry I kind of
took that with me over into the Disney
when I went there and I'm a much broader
scale I found myself doing similar
things right fishing simulation annual
trading onboarding training things like
that right and I would notice some other
department whether they're ite or
marketing whatever that had these
programs and we're just telling it right
like they were just really well done
they good marketing a good metrics and
everything and so I would reach out to
someone like my co-workers and I would
ask them what how do you like I feel
like my security awareness program is
pretty similar in scope and approach to
what you're doing with core
communications or the marketing like
three or four that's different people I
talk to like oh we should have like a
really great program plan and I was just
like oh how did I not realize that I
need a program plan so I started to
borrow some templates and kind of
Frankenstein the program plan for when I
what I felt was an effective awareness
program and then sharing with my peers
at conferences just in conversation you
know I noticed that a lot of the other
companies and my peers were doing
similar things that are they up so we
just need a program plan and that once I
he initiated that and decided I'm going
to use a plan my security
program just like skyrocketed it grew
and it got respect from senior
leadership you know and it's just about
that approach of treating it like an
actual program and not just a process
that you have to go through and so in
programs I can get into what I think are
part of the programs I don't know the
question yeah definitely definitely
knows yeah we used to definitely tell be
like think of it like a marketing
program and you'll be better off because
it really is a you have an idea you're
trying to communicate to a certain group
of people and you need to make sure they
all get it now how did you how do you
recommend that people measure that it's
working like what kind of metrics do you
collect that is I think I think that
there's common metrics that we gravitate
to because the industry is kind of push
those to us I immediately think of the
fishing click rate right I think that's
probably the first major metric that
pieces or program administrators our
first subject to and I think that's a
decent starting place right that's
usually one of the first initiatives
that you take on is outside of your
compliance training and your annual
training you're doing fishing training I
like to get into ways to when I'm
building out my program I'm trying to
take an end you know six months 12
months 18 months down the road to where
I want to be and thinking okay if I want
to be here my goal is to have a
bachelor's program and I want to be able
to do four events each October during
National Cyber Security Awareness Month
what do I need to start doing now here
and what kind of building to start
collecting data so I can provide metrics
to that's up for me like I was only as a
single resource and so in order to get
budget I had to kind of like prove my
Worth and prove that there was a method
to what I was doing it so it would start
with something as much data as I could
from fishing programs you know the data
and the fishing and you can start
looking through that there's a lot of
really good data there the click rate to
me is kind of junk like I don't think
it's a despair metric to represent your
program with there's there's too many
outliers on that
how many people were on vacation that
month you know is there holidays there
are things like that that can affect the
response rates for me I always like the
report rate which is how many people
reported in email because that actually
should behavior change that you're that
you're working on so I look at things
like that reporter II I would go outside
of just your completion airy for your
annual training which is the most common
probably the second most common one it's
not the first the most common one
because that just kind of I like you're
either ability or inability to annoy
people right and it really comes down to
in a larger company if you want people
to complete a training at some point if
there's a if there's repercussions and
not completing its gonna have to get
transferred to HR at some point right
because security awareness professionals
we shouldn't be in charge it should just
be our job to you know to assign the
training and follow online and so I
think that side it out if you are
obtaining your program you can look at
things like okay I want to have one or
two live trainings a year and events
that they can attend you can start
tracking attendance then and then I one
thing that I really liked was using
hours spent learning each month outside
of training so for instance in October
for national cybersecurity Awareness
Month the last two years we had event
that I did we clean cyber security 101
trainings we're anywhere from 10 to 8
people can show up and talk and learn
about security risk and then we had
speakers come in and we did they
mentioned a life hacking demonstration
where I volunteered to be the target and
I worked with my internal red and blue
teams and basically in the life in the
live audience we have two screens up one
was my computer and one was the red
team's computer you know this computer
is like a mr. robot screen where they're
seeing all the Kali Linux commands going
on and all they did was really go
through my social media accounts find
some information that's readily
available about me just from GRU
and then they send me an email and I
click on it for the sake of the demo
this is in front of like a hundred
people where they literally see them
clicking on the link and then my webcam
is being broadcast on the mr. robot
screen you can like hear people mind
being blown and it was like a ten minute
demo right like you do things like that
and then you can say okay well 100
people attended and it was an hour long
presentation so there's a 100 hours
spent learning that you know voluntary
right and then it gives you like a good
baseline okay well next year if you only
get 200 hours and you won't get $500
there's a game or event so for me you
the strength of your security awareness
program is determined by your ability to
engage people and so how do you do that
how do you show that for me its intended
its surveys you know things like that
yeah that's great those are great
examples I've always found live demos of
a real hacker or simulated hack that
could you know is realistic more
accurately it really gets people's
attention in a way that almost nothing
else does they're like oh that was easy
because in their minds they think it's
like hacking is this like hard super
technical difficult thing that you know
you're gonna be a rocket scientist to do
and it turns out that a lot of the
things people do on a regular basis
aren't really that hard at all they're
just you know they're pretty
straightforward and yeah I've heard of
them to think about it you know yeah
yeah it's great like when they when they
see me talk to and I was easily hacked
in ten minutes right now I'm saying like
look I'm pretty good with my information
like most of my encounter private all
these things like imagine how easy it
was for you and everyone's like so we
did surveys on the you know exiting that
and like 85% of those that attended to
the day were going to change their their
Facebook profile and instagrams the
private and they were going to review
what information they had on LinkedIn
and like that's a win that's a huge win
and they're gonna tell their friends
they're gonna talk to their spouses or
their families like that and that's the
type of engagement it's really you know
you can't you can't buy like that's just
the in person that's a unique experience
for that yep awesome well I feel like we
could talk about this all day so given
our both of our background so um when I
asked you to do the talk I've mentioned
that we were going to do this as the
8-hour new snap talk format so you're
one of our inaugural speakers to do our
18 minute format which is kind of you
know Ted style talk so you you actually
had an interesting response you're like
oh I actually prefer those kinds of talk
so why is that like why do you prefer
the shorter talks versus the longer ones
oh I mean I'm a fan because just it's
the user experience really right like if
I'm sitting in the audience I want to be
told a story as humans we want to be
told stories and I mean that's what a
TED talk does well is it didn't seem in
a journey through a couple different
stories that provide feedback and
knowledge and interesting like pieces of
I like to call it social currency right
like things that are just interesting
and if you are listening to someone who
who isn't reading off the cue cards or
isn't reading off a PowerPoint deck and
engaging you with a story like that's so
powerful and I enjoy that I enjoy doing
that I enjoy kind of violating
expectations unlike if they're sitting
there thinking like okay this is going
to go through like thirty five slides
I'm going to do this I'm gonna start out
with a story of some type and no you're
gonna like wait what how did we even get
here and how did you how did you weave
that information into that story like
that that's so fun so it's a challenge
I'm excited they want in the inaugural
ones we'll see I hear I'm following up a
opening one which talks about why most
what's the title of it I believe it's
why most presentations suck
so I just loved it I loved it you know
awesome well look at definitely looking
forward to seeing this one and looking
forward to seeing at the conference and
for those of you want to check out what
we're doing come by source Boston on May
9th and 10th and you get to continue the
conversation with Jason to myself and
it's gonna be a great time we can have a
lot of good people there it's gonna be a
lot of fun
yeah actually have a few yeah no worries
see you there and I'll talk soon