there are different Andals you can keep
that near you in case you order I keep
it over there I think and this is the
receiver so best thing keep it on your
left
great left side cool can you guys hear
me okay good in the back thumbs up
alright awesome thanks hey so I'm going
to turn this down great all right we'll
talk softly yes there we go okay so this
is a practical old man in the middle and
still testing the mic all right awesome
okay cool so you hopefully are in the
right talk here my name is Jonathan cran
I'm an advisor for the source conference
also CTO Pony Express also like sales
guy Pony Express also like marketing
guide Pony Express also whatever yeah
yes small company it's cool so before
that our QA director at Metasploit and
then before that penetration tester
Robert 7 so what are we gonna talk about
today good to see this well anyway man
in the middle is a huge topic it's
actually one of those things where I
very quickly got overwhelmed with the
amount of stuff that we can talk about
in this talk and what I wanted to do is
focus this a little bit and talk about
you know men in the middle very
specifically on certain types of attacks
you know one of those one of the one of
the things obviously the Pony Express
influence here is you know local man in
the middle on a targeted network and on
a local network as opposed to SSL or or
to like BGP attacks right you know
that's just not that practical for a pen
tester so let's talk about that and then
we'll talk about sort of why why this
stuff matters this year and why this
stuff matters in general and then we'll
get into some practical attacks and some
automation
and then we'll talk about some takeaways
so you know very quickly I also you know
thought well maybe I'll spend some time
doing some automation for this talk and
work on you know making things super
easy to use but it turns out there's
tons and tons of automation out there
there's people in this room Ryan Linden
over here who's put together like some
really awesome automation and and I
didn't want to sort of duplicate some of
the efforts that were already being made
with ettercap and with beef and things
like that so our focus today is going to
be very specifically on the local
network in the wireless network and then
you know more specific than that getting
in the middle and then from there
viewing manipulating traffic and then
automating some of the easy wins what
we're not going to focus on is you know
SSL men in the middle BGP so the more
complex attacks spanning tree protocol
hot hot walk routing protocol or the the
man-in-the-browser
type type man-in-the-middle stuff so we
got it all right cool so you know I've
always been enamored with this idea of
you know how do we attack folks you know
directly around us how we target these
things I was walking past a bank in New
York one time and I was looking in I saw
a machine that was sitting there and
it's running Windows XP and I'm like I
know I can own this machine but how do I
get to that how do I actually access
that box from standing out here or even
you know that specific box you know and
it also you know planes trains and
automobiles how do you how do you sort
of determine what's around you in these
these environments so the question is
you know what why do you care about
local man-in-the-middle has an ARP
spoofing been around for 15 years
you know DNS spoofing these sorts of
things these things aren't really that
new so so why do we really care that
much you know and we go back to this
this sort of idea of how do we you know
sort of utilize what's around us to to
I guess really how what why do we care
about our spoofing why is that a big
deal there's a couple reasons you know
that the trend is sort of toward
Wireless everywhere every devices that
has a smartphone everybody has a
smartphone everybody is wireless every
smartphone on AT&T will automatically
connect to the ATT Wi-Fi network you
know networks are getting more
accessible in a lot of ways you know
think about retail think about
point-of-sale you know just being
available you know that you can access
their network sometimes it is hard to
take control of a particular system
sometimes the network is the easier
target
there's a couple things here how many
people are familiar with our spoofing
pretty much everybody how many people
are familiar with slack the slack attack
get one a couple others okay cool all
right just trying to judge basically how
I spend my time I started talking about
this stuff our our cache poisoning is
still a valid attack you know there's
there are a lot of mitigations in my
testing I've seen you know some networks
more enterprise actually be vulnerable
to it versus you know your sort of
airplanes hotels things like that
there's often mitigations deployed there
slack is stateless Auto configuration
for ipv6 and it was released two years
ago by a by a gentleman at the InfoSec
Institute it's very it operates in a
very similar way but for ipv6 and allows
you to turn a lot over ipv4 so we'll
talk about that here in a second as far
as you know again why you should care
would your users really notice if they
got an invalid sir
probably not and an evil twin attacks
are sort of still pervasive so you know
all of these reasons are sort of
bringing man-in-the-middle back to a
point where it's really relevant
Android I just wanted to talk a little
bit about this there was a study done at
the Leibnitz university of hannover
where the guys analyzed thirteen hundred
thirteen thousand five hundred Android
apps
found about a thousand of those
vulnerable to no verification on the ssl
certificate it's a pretty common
developer bug to basically just specify
ssl no verify i'm sure you've all run
into this at some point where yeah it's
using ssl but the certificate can
actually be swapped out and so you know
realistically it's not not verifying the
communication between the points and you
know it's about the same as not having
ssl okay great
another reason to care arm devices are
getting smaller and smaller you know
kind of started out with the palm plug
gum sticks have been very small the
Odroid devices the SS 808 this is a
little 1.7 gigahertz quad core it's
about the size of you know half dollars
so i'm sorry a half a dollar not a half
dollar and it's ultimately fast enough
to run most most relevant most current
attacks you know similar similar board
here this is a an MK sorry an SS 808 by
saying smart it's 50 bucks on amazon you
can literally go buy this board drop
cali on it and have a full attack
platform for 50 bucks
pretty crazy this so so basically you
know just kind of building building more
credibility for why you should care
about this intel's projecting ubiquitous
computing by 2020 we'll see about that
but but i mean obviously the trend is
toward smaller and smaller devices how
many of you have seen them ipad in a
store recently few of you everybody okay
cool yeah how about this many iPads in
the store
or you know this sort of thing so so I
mean retail and point-of-sale is
interesting just because you can sort of
get access to the network there whether
it's you know wired network or whether
it's a wireless network now I don't know
if these things are securely configured
if there's a VPN connection back to
headquarters with these but somehow I
doubt it in many cases I mean it's
almost easier than doing this anymore
like why steal the cash register if you
could just plug in a device also you
know 4G speeds getting faster how many
people have seen the freedom stick one
person two people three people basically
freedom six a rebranding of clear
Wireless for two bucks a month you can
get 500 Meg's of upload speed on 4G
speeds pretty cool stuff if you get a
chance to check it out so okay that's
all good and well you know the trend is
toward mobile trend is toward network
everywhere but securing layer two is
hard how many folks are actually getting
owned by man-in-the-middle and really
you know is it is it that practical and
you know this talk is meant to be a
practical talk so it's kind of let's go
through some of those attacks so I sort
of picked out a number of different
things that I thought were really really
easy to automate and really really easy
to you know attack and this is the list
that I came up with so we'll go through
each one of these piece by piece you
know the first thing to say sort of
about man-in-the-middle is the easiest
way to prevent this thing is to have a
strong VPN connection if you're not
actually encrypting your traffic from
end to end you know there's there's lots
of ways to sort of get around it even if
you're using SSL how many people have
used a throwing start at one - how many
people have invented a throwing start
tap I see one
these things are they're awesome they're
like 50 15 $20 you can buy them in a
number of different places
Michael Osmond here has created an easy
way to get in line on the network you
know if you want to buy the the
professional kit they're about $40 it's
already built for you you don't have to
actually solder if you can't solder like
myself sometimes it's better to just go
with the pre-built these things are
great what you see on the right if you
can see it in the back is basically
throwing starts half what you see on the
left is a dual comm port spanning device
and so this is a great way to just get
in the middle of a connection if you
have a Dropbox you can basically put it
on the network plug this guy in and
connect to it and so you'll basically
connect your network through the device
and then connect one of your devices off
of it now it's not good if you want to
manipulate traffic but if you just want
to see what's actually going on on the
network it's a great way to do it
now you can do a similar thing with just
the firewall right or sorry just a just
a device if you've got two interfaces
you can set up a bridge with bridge
bridge utils how many folks have used a
Linux bridge before familiar with it
pretty decent number this is basically
all you have to do in order to set up a
bridge on Linux use bridge control type
add bridge and then add the interfaces
you want to it and then at that point
you can basically route traffic through
the device you know a great way to
either manipulate it traffic or just to
get visibility into it you know how you
prevent Hardware attacks you know good
physical security is what it comes down
to ARP cache poisoning so let's talk a
little bit about this sorry for like
bringing up like really old stuff but
it's so relevant that you know it's hard
to avoid when you're talking about
man-in-the-middle basically what's going
on is that you're sending ARP traffic to
the broadcast address and and/or to your
targets and telling them that you are at
a particular IP address they will
forward those traffic to you all send a
lot of timeline you know it's literally
this easy to do there's lots of ways to
do this
so we won't spend a lot of time on it
what I did want to talk about a little
bit though is you know how do you
prevent our cache poisoning it seems you
know a lot of people talk about how to
how to you know exploit it but not a lot
of people talk about sort of how to
prevent it and so I've noticed again in
my testing that did you know in most
hotels most impo wood places I'm not
actually able to ARP spoof and why is
that obviously it's not because of
static art tables right oftentimes I
think what it is actually I think what's
going on is the big disabled gratuitous
ARP if you're sending a lot of our
packets they're not allowing you to to
basically send our packets anymore like
they basically cut you off at that point
interestingly Hawaii has a patented
technique on this that they're not they
published and you can find it it's in
the notes for this slide if you're
interested in it you know typically the
guidance is to just monitor ARP and make
sure that you're not you know you're not
seeing tons of ARB traffic how many
people familiar with DNS cache poisoning
cool I was - I guess I was confused sort
of on DNS cache poisoning about you know
how do you actually exploit this you
know there was there's talk of the
birthday attack which is basically where
you sort of guess the transmit ID from
the DNS server yeah I'll actually give
you a quick diagram I'm sorry for the
the slide here but basically what's
happening is you've got a DNS server
here your authoritative servers here
your users actually making your request
here and this is you know your malicious
user he's going and actually observing
traffic coming from the resolver and
then you know guessing the transmit ID
and that transfer IDs relatively a small
it's a small number so it's relatively
easy to guess and what that allows them
to do is spoof a response back to the
user the user gets either for their
single domain a an a record or they get
you know forth for the domain
an authoritative record allows you to
basically set whatever the NS ever you
want it turns out birthday attack really
isn't that relevant anymore DNS servers
been patched
you know the Kaminski attack has really
been patched in practice and so really
the only way to do DNS cache poisoning
as far as I'm aware is to actually be in
the middle already oh and so you have to
be observing traffic and you know at
that point you can actually see what the
transmit ID is and be able to return the
response back to the host preventing DNS
spoofing DNS SEC is really the way to go
okay so the slack attack this one is
actually you look really really
interesting so provided by the InfoSec
Institute about two years ago I think in
2011 maybe 2012 what they observed was
that most the hosts on network are
already dual stacked so you can actually
provide an ipv6 address to hosts using
router advertisements and they'll pick
it up so this was a typical ipv4
internet typical set up right so you get
your router here you've got hosts with
ipv4 addresses what the slack attack is
going to do is introduce a new router
and give out ipv6 addresses to these
devices XP sp3 will actually pick up an
ipv6 address and anything above that
will pick it up
so let's skip ahead to this slide and
basically I'll walk you through the
steps here so you know this device here
is actually going to get an ipv6 address
the evil routers going to do Matt PT
translation on the device and so you're
gonna have this requesting an ipv4
address this is going to translate it to
an ipv6 address send it out to the
server I'm sorry I go back i pp6 address
comes to this server this translates it
to ipv4 and it sends the response back
the nice thing about this is that your
ipv4 network is still intact and you're
using ipv6 to get out to the Internet
basically it introduces a new path to
the Internet
there's no compromise of the ipv4
network and there's really not a lot of
ways to detect this today so you know in
terms of packets what this looks like
and I know you can't see this in the
back so I'll just translate it for you
on the inside of the network what you're
seeing is ipv6 packets sent to that evil
router and then the evil router then
translating those and sending those out
to the Internet as ipv4 the guidance to
prevent this is simply to disable ipv6
so that's kind of interesting right how
many enterprise networks have ipv6
enabled probably most of them is there
anybody here that's actually disabled
ipv6 inside one network interesting okay
cool
let's skip ahead so Wireless evil twin
this is another man in the middle
technique first one Wireless that we'll
talk about and really what this is is
you know setting up a road network so
they you know devices which can't
discern between which wireless networks
are available to them are automatically
connecting in so let's talk a little bit
about how you might do this this is the
palm pad how many people have heard of
the pump at most people awesome cool
let's do a demo with it so if you
haven't heard of the pump basically what
it is is a nexus 7 with an Android
interface but then also I've been to
Jeru and what it allows you to do is run
security tools on the device from the
Android interface so let me see if I can
get us connected here
so bear with me for just a second while
I get disconnected
you know
okay
all right live demo let's try this
all right you guys see that okay cool so
basically what this is is the palm pad
again this image is freely available
from our website if you have a Nexus 7
you can go download it really let's do
this
so there's evil twin attacks what I'm
gonna do is hit this evil ap right here
it's a little bit slow but we'll go
ahead and give this a shot there we go
oh it's going to ask you which interface
you want to connect on so we'll say the
internal network then it's going to ask
us for an SSID I'm going to allow us to
spoof an SSID if we want it's using air
base on the back end so basically you
can respond to probe requests give it a
second to catch up yeah
come on
back-up plan
so I'm gonna switch it over to a
different wireless network just to make
it a little bit faster sorry about this
there we go
and what
okay
quite
perfect
okay
sorry for this give it a second half
we'll get it connected
seven
there we go all right let's try this
again
okay
so people ap
there we go use the wireless connection
give it an SSID I'm going to turn off
automatic probe request connections
there we go I'm gonna start to get pro
requests everybody has a wireless off
yes all right cool
there we go all right sorry for the
delay on that just want to get this up
and going live demos are always fun so
let's connect with a client
so what you're seeing right now is probe
requests from clients and this thing
listening on ATT Wi-Fi which by default
again
AT&T clients will automatically try and
connect on we've had folks run this
during live demos and actually had
connections from lots of different folks
okay there we go are already connected
and what I'm going to do at this point
is now that I've got the actual
connection listening I'm gonna go ahead
and run strings watch just to see if we
can see anything come across so select
and we don't want to see the log
get met that run and you'll see almost
immediately we start getting traffic
across
they were going actually have a Kindle
this is a Kindle connecting answers most
of the trap it's actually encrypted
which is nice let's go ahead and go to a
web page there you go and you can start
to see some of the certificate strings
again this is I mean you can do a full
TCP dump with this but this is an easy
way to
grab traffic
there we go
and let's do an SSL strip on top of this
is everybody familiar with this is all
strip it's anybody's know so SSL strip
is released by Moxie Marlinspike I think
was 2009 it's interesting I didn't fully
understand it until recently basically
what it's doing is stripping out HTTPS
links in traffic that comes across and
so if you make an initial connection
over HTTP it's gonna it's going to strip
out any HTTP links and it won't it won't
redirect you to HTTPS and so you're
basically stuck on HTTP even when you
enter credentials and things like that
it's two five years
there we go so that's up and running and
we can actually do a
and actually a biblical law or SSL
strips see we can impose nice thank you
so
[Music]
yeah
hangin to bear with me for a second
there we go and right
at work
okay see
[Music]
let me go back here and show you this
okay so we're still getting traffic
coming in let me try to get a facebook
on here
[Music]
awesome
yeah let down
[Music]
like a
and one more time
when I call it here in a second if we
can actually get it going
okay so I'm restarting EVP
I'm running my SSL strip
yeah
it's already running
collect your hand
okay well I'm having trouble connecting
the Kindle into this device so I'm gonna
go ahead and move on if anybody wants a
demo later I'll give them too great
thank you
basically evil twin attack pretty simple
to pull off the PO pad itself uses air
base you can do this on any laptop and
really the benefit of doing something
like this is that mobile phones and
devices with with Wireless are pretty
easy to fool into connecting to you how
do you prevent it you know basically
it's user education there's not a lot of
good ways to prevent this today
there we go again there's not a lot of
ways you can use radius but there's also
ways to to attack radius you can use
easy creds it's probably the easiest way
that I know in order to attack radio
service again if they're using stronger
authentication it's not such an issue
but it's definitely an issue if using
radius with leap does mobile device
management help not really depending on
how you set it up right you can actually
specify that all your devices will
automatically connect to a particular
SSID but again if you don't set up
authentication with that pretty easy to
spoof force to http
is really just SSL strip and so this is
kind of what I was talking about earlier
basic basically it rewrites links as
HTTP and then you know provides you with
what looks like a secure site it's
pretty easy to pull off I mean this is
you know this is the long and short of
running SSL strip you forward traffic
through your device you run the daemon
on the actual system that's gonna strip
traffic and then you forward traffic to
it
how do you prevent SSL strip attacks
really the server itself has to the
server and the browser have to agree
that they're not going to accept you
know traffic over HTTP in the way they
do that is we're gonna H to get HSTs
header Google's rolled this out on all
that all their properties in the last
year you know another way to prevent
this is just you know always browsing to
HTTPS dot whatever you know there's a
series of other attacks we're not gonna
spend any time on these just because
we're short on time as it goes but these
are all sort of semi practical attacks
with the exception of certificate abuse
and BGP attacks so I'll go ahead and
skip three of these you know there's a
lot of tools out there to automate
attacks like this some things you want
to take a look at if you haven't already
it's decent if ettercap beef easy creds
subterfuge is a relatively new one
put an automated easy attack platform
you know I think the takeaways here that
men in the middle is really an
underrated attack vector in general you
know it's it's easier it's a target
people local to you POS systems are
specifically more vulnerable drop boxes
are providing a credible way to actually
get in the middle of networks and the
phones specifically are very vulnerable
there any questions
yep okay after this yeah yeah for sure
any other questions evil twin evil APR
evil twin
right right right basically what we were
demoing here right the automatic
connection into an access point yeah
yeah so you're basically creating a twin
of an access point so if there's you
know what does it here courtyard guest
so you can set it up it's either a
static courtyard guest and run it on a
different channel or you can set it so
that it responds to probe requests and
and when you get a probe request for
whatever your home network is you know
colleague Abe's
g-man puppies network address then you
know this will respond and say you know
this is you know I'm a valid access
point for you
any other questions okay cool thanks
please fill out feedback forms they're
available in the back well thanks guys