hi this is Rob Sheen with the source
conference and I'm here with Justine
Bowen who is the CEO of Med sec and
she's gonna be speaking at the source
Boston event on May 9th and 10th and the
title of the talk is hacking
entrepreneurship lessons from security
starters and she's gonna be one of the
panelists gonna be looking forward to
seeing it so welcome thanks for joining
in so awesome cool so so you've kind of
worked in both small startups as well as
big companies yeah and I think you
started your career and Morgan's
for example you know right right so a
lot of people though when they're kind
of in still in that job and they've not
broken free and you know taking that
step to do that next thing you know
there's this like I I call it the leap
of faith it's kind of like Indiana Jones
you step off the cliff for you and you
[Music]
actually run into lock people they're
like oh I would start a company but I
have kids I'm like are you kidding I
know all kinds of startup founders that
have kids like yeah like that might be a
reason for you but it doesn't have to be
right you just used to make it a reason
or a chance not to make it a reason and
do it anyway so what kind of advice
would you give to other people that are
interested in starting a company but
maybe haven't made that leap of faith
yet
and consciously invested time and
resources into maintaining and extending
my over the years technology have you
found that the risk anymore after a
while fix more on the spreadsheet
already so it continues to grow that's
what's rewarding and one of the things
that I really know about this is
building out my team fostering the
culture being able to create a culture
that I believe works folks that are on
my team might get a lot of personal
satisfaction from that everything from
my you know seasons exist through to the
interns that we're bringing in and I get
really excited and motivated by that as
well
bringing in outsiders as advisors really
paid off in the first two months anyway
right right yeah there's there's a
certain
you can do on your own but there's
definitely an element of team that comes
into play that if you don't have a good
team challenge usually in most
collaborating right yeah I know some
people are kind of it's kind of like the
same people like don't want to buy a
house because they don't want to be a
landlord you know or buy a multi-family
cuz I don't wanna be a landlord you know
in the same way like people like oh I
don't know start a company because you
know I don't know anything about
marketing around I think about sales
it's like well hey you can learn in B
you can hire people and you write I
think I lost your audio a bit can you
hit me up now again okay look you cut
out for just a second here exactly so so
what's the most challenging thing about
starting a company ability strategy and
when you grow someone organically one of
your key to DS is feedback that you get
from your customers and as you get this
feedback you can find yourself opening
in terms of your say your product about
them roadmap and your strategy around
that or even the service
that you might be offering but at the
same time if you've got others involved
when you've laid out a proposal right
yeah I would agree I mean you can only
at any given time you make the best
decision you can with the information
you have at the time but then there has
to be an evaluation loop where you're
like did this actually work because some
people is like nope I made the decision
I'm doing it and then you just gotta you
gotta do it you know you know being
flexible I think is definitely an
attribute of success for sure the most
rewarding thing about starting companies
[Music]
yeah yeah I definitely same thing like
when I can mentor somebody and help them
out and then suddenly they're doing you
know amazing new things it's like wow
that's really cool it's awesome that I
could play some small part in that and
anything that kind of helps encourage
more people to be entrepreneurs I'm a
huge fan of that's why I like doing
things like this at stores even though
it's a little bit
different than the kinds of things you
often see at regular security
conferences debris mr. sauce and I'm
sure it will be from our faces and
sometimes mistakes that are really
excited to share yeah can't wait to see
it alright cool so um so we'll see you
at source Boston on uh you know source
is happening on may 10th 9th and 10th
and you guys want to continue the
conversation with Justine show up to the
conference and we'll be there alright
thanks a lot doctor soon bye