[Music]
hi this is rob machine with a source
conference and I'm here with Lester
God's T and he is the CSO of Mesa the
city of Mesa and we're gonna be having a
source conference in Mesa at the end of
February on February 28th and March
first and I just last was gonna be
speaking there we'd like to talk today
about his talk the welcome Buster
alright thanks so your talk is titled
cybersecurity program we don't need no
stinkin cybersecurity program so can you
tell us a little bit about the title and
what your talks about well unfortunately
I try to relate everything in life to
movies so the latter part of my talk
title I'll leave that to your own
investigation in googling but the
purpose of my presentation is to talk
about regardless of whether you're a
small organization one-man shop or a
very large organization with a dedicated
cybersecurity staff everybody needs some
context and some organization and
planning when it comes to a holistic
approach to cybersecurity ok so the one
thing I really noticed that stood out
from your talk title in your description
was the difference between you know
whether you're a big shop or a little
shop it's still being able to do some of
the same things so what are some of the
commonalities whether you have a big
budget or no budget well first and
foremost the biggest commonality is the
fact that regardless of one's
organization's size everybody still has
the same problems everybody still has
the same challenges and so while we may
not have the same budget the same
resources available to us depending on
our situation there are certain things
we can and I I propose that we should be
focusing on regardless of our size so so
for example not to give too much away
and I'm trying to encourage people to
attend the talk itself is to do things
such as not just focus on prevention for
example and a security program should be
should be focus on the fact
that it's not a matter of if but a
matter when your security is going to be
compromised so if you if you take that
into consideration as you plan for how
your cybersecurity program is going to
be developed for your organization then
you're one step ahead of the game right
so the the knot if it's one thing is an
important point I think that I'd like to
rip off a little bit I see a lot of
organizations that seem to really want
it to be you know adding security equals
we're not gonna have an incident how do
you manage those expectations with folks
throughout the organization either kind
of up or down just that these things
will happen sure and again this you just
touched on some LSAT regardless of size
this is an important conversation to
have and it's important to have this
conversation with the right folks within
your organization so whether you're in a
small business of ten people or you're
working for a city like myself with
4,200 employees and elected officials
and things of that sort the same
conversation needs to occur which is and
the way I handle that is there's too
many variables frankly or anybody or
cybersecurity program to account for to
ensure that there are zero possibility
that you're gonna have a breach from a
security perspective I have also used a
conversation about how these
multibillion-dollar organizations
frankly with all the resources available
to them they have still had a number of
reaches so it's it's not a problem that
you can buy your way out of I guess and
that's a common thread across the board
one thing I would like to emphasize and
conversations I've had and I've worked
for smaller organizations before your
sized or anonymity in regards to the
rest of the environment it's no
guarantee that you're not going to be a
target either so I think it's important
for very small organizations and I would
encourage them to be cognizant of this
that um just because they're not a
target or a large organization doesn't
mean they're
not an attractive no pun intended target
for cybercrime right so how do you
actually get that message out to people
do you run some kind of an awareness
program you know how what you've been
experienced with that it's kind of
especially you know big shot versus a
little shot because I know there's
definitely differences in how they roll
out training and things sure absolutely
we've taken a multi-pronged approach
along those lines we we have done what
you would consider your traditional
security awareness taking advantage of
those opportunities so for the last
couple years every every October which
is National Cyber Security Awareness
Month will host host a booth at our
benefits fair actually for the city of
Mesa where we hand out materials things
to that sort but we also do monthly
phishing exercises I do quarterly
updates with my CIO
our IT department so we provide
quarterly updates to our city manager's
office where cyber security is a very
high priority and we always provide them
data along those lines additionally and
as part of my talk about the
cybersecurity program itself that's also
factored in as well so it's one of those
things where regardless of your size
this needs to be a facet of your program
so it's not just about next-gen
firewalls it's just it's not just about
advanced endpoint software technologies
implemented in your environment but it's
also having a conversation with the
owner of your 10-man business or your
CEO or whatever the case is you need to
find a way to have that conversation and
at the same time ensure that you
demonstrate that you have a program in
place that addresses those concerns not
just from prevention but from
remediation from security education as
well yeah you definitely hit on
something I like there which is that a
big part of the solutions to people not
just the you know the big shiny boxes
those are cool but that only gets you so
far generally so
when you're when you're rolling and
stuff like this out do you are you
mostly hitting the the leaders in the
company or the organization or are you
trying to it the end users as well we
try to do all of the above
so in our instance yeah we definitely
there's something to be said from this
message coming from the top down so
there's definite benefit to that but at
the same time like you alluded to it's a
people person or it's a people issue I
should say in a lot of instances so in
addition to our city management in our
instance we talked to representatives we
have a group that's called IT liaison so
representatives from each department
within the organization where IT
communicates through them and lets them
know what we're doing what's going on I
leverage that group we also have pocket
little education classes 15-20 minutes
where if you're interested in a
particular topic so for example our
single sign-on solution that we use or
the video based training on fishing and
things of that sort so we do anything
and everything in between so upper
management - middle management all the
way to the individual staff that's right
yeah you definitely hit on something
that I have found to be a challenge in
some organizations which is the top-down
element of security because I've been
saying this for years
grassroots is great but if the you know
the people at the top aren't saying the
right things and doing the right things
then people aren't going to do it so
have you found any good ways to educate
that the upper management so that they
are willing to support the organization
and do security correctly sure so this
might be one of the challenges
especially if you're a smaller
organization where you don't have a lot
of resources this could be an issue but
what I have found particularly effective
is having clearly measurable metrics in
terms of security performance and using
that data to drive home the message of
what the security posture is
what the organizations risk is and using
that to frame the story when I have the
conversation with the city manager or
the CIO or whoever the individual might
be council member and so a good example
that is email spam has been a recent
point of conversation within our
organization so I've been able to use
the data that we've collected we're
fairly mature organizational when it
comes to some of the tools and the
metrics to demonstrate even though we
have all these preventative measures in
place we calculate somewhere in the
ballpark of 80% of our threat comes from
email and so we're able to articulate of
those how many emails we receive of
those how many were delivered to our
environment so we can tell how our
third-party provider and I won't mention
names there spam filtering is working
and why we need additional security
along those lines so in a lot of
instances I found a lot of success by
providing data and some anecdotal
information or stories as well too so
that seems to have gone a long way so
much so that just a couple of months ago
our city managers recognized that this
is a cybersecurity should be one of our
top priorities and has mandated
cybersecurity training to all employees
so and again that sends a clear message
from the top down that the city manager
in this instance is very concerned about
cybersecurity and we're taking those
mandatory steps to lessen the likelihood
of having breaches well that's a great
preview of your talk so I'm looking
forward to seeing the full thing so
again you know I was just gonna say I'm
not gonna mention what the latter half
of my title is unless you show up to the
talk and then I'll disclose what movie I
pulled that from pretty sure I know
which movie that came from but I won't
give it away I'm a classic movie fan
myself so yeah so please join us at the
source Mesa Phoenix conference at on
February 28th and March 3rd and I'm
sorry February 28th to March 1st
and the information for the conference
is at source conference calm so
hopefully well I'll see you there soon
great thanks alright that was pretty
painless yeah I'll just chop it off
there add a little you know yeah yeah
beginning an end and then we'll be good
so cool thanks so I assume you've I'll
turn the recording off now
you