[Music]
hi this is Rob Shane from the source
conference and I'm here with Richard
theme from theme works and he's gonna be
discussing strategies for playing
through the pain the impact impact of
dark knowledge on security professionals
in the road to resilience and Richard
actually did an earlier version of this
talk and one of the first times he did
the talk at source Boston back in 2016
and he's gonna be giving the latest
version of the talk at source Austin on
December 5th and 6th coming up soon so
Richard why don't you tell us a little
bit about you're talkin how its evolved
what you started giving it the talk
keeps evolving the basis for it was
listening closely for 25 years which is
as long as I've been doing this speaking
and writing for 25 years to colleagues
and friends who have grown over the time
over that time I into quite an assembly
of extraordinary people and I've
listened to their stories not just about
the technical work which is where I sit
like a child at their feet try to pay
attention but to the impact the work has
had on them and different situations
they find themselves in which have had a
lasting and sometimes negative dramatic
impact which compels a response when I
first did the talk the one we did for
source 2 years ago I wrote to colleagues
and said have you got any stories you
want to share and over 50 people from
CIA and NSA in corporate and military
venues responded with detailed and often
poignant very emotionally narratives of
what they had experienced and so many
people continued to respond to that talk
when I when I did to DEFCON somebody
asked her if I could hear people crying
in the audience now imagine I've spoken
to Def Con this year this 23rd year and
you don't usually look out at a room of
thousand people with standing room or on
the edges and hear people sniffling
crying and in one case one guy said did
you hear me sobbing and back because it
struck such a chord because instead of a
technical talk aimed at the mr. robot
persona with so many hackers
security walks carry in their heads this
was aimed directly at the heart so it
kind of hacked the psyche to go past
that and talk to the human being and how
they were influenced so as this
continued a lot of people asked for
we need strategies for this and that was
my talk this year will be the talk for
source this year much more detailed on
what are the things we can do based on
what people have learned out of their
experience and once again about 20 more
people responded with narratives to that
so this is quite a large collection of
real-life Frank upfront authentic
stories people have shared with me that
I integrate in into a singular narrative
of this is what can happen this is what
we can do about it and just just
recently Rob
ari Shapiro on NPR did a story on the
cleaners who are now charged in the
aftermath of all the hullabaloo about
social media with cleaning up accounts
at Facebook in Google and so on and some
of them once said he has seen so many
beheadings that when he sees one done
with a very sharp edge he thinks it's
kind of a blessing instead of some of
the worst they have seen so much awful
stuff but the result is that one set is
I can't go into public spaces anymore
because I've watched so much video of
terror acts you know that like seeing a
movie over and over again or watching
the news over and over again
it impacts all of us the mind of society
has been terrorized by the media
amplification of events which actually
might be quite rare but which because if
it bleeds it leads they drive home
starting with 9/11 when I said the media
was complicit 100% in terrorism because
it could have reported the acts without
showing them again and again and again
until the entire public was traumatized
it's hard not to believe the
some people behind the scenes really
relish that fact because the billions of
dollars that have grown into the
security industry in that regard since
then have shown that fear and and
terrorizing a population can pay off so
it's not just people who do this work
professionally it's all of us but but
because of where security professionals
often find themselves it can hit home
particularly hard and particularly easy
and the question is are you discussing
it inside our organizations making
available a platform to talk seriously
about this because all that's required
in our humanity is that we acknowledge
what's real for us and then take the
measures or steps that are appropriate
to keeping ourselves as whole as we can
do now that we get rid of these scars to
be a scarred adult is to be an adult we
carry these wounds through life and
their marks of our often maturity but if
we don't attend to them and respond as I
say by traveling their own tours ilion's
they can have a very very negative
impact on other areas of our lives and
that's part of what I've listened to in
the divorce is the alcoholism the
suicides one one colleague at CIA said
he carries in his head
23 suicides and when my friend at NSA
wrote that there were three suicides
that week and I saw a former deputy
director at a conference and asked him
about it he shook his head and he said
no there were six this week last week
and he looked at me knowing my
background as the clergyman which I did
for 16 years and you said doing this
work I have lost my faith well it's to
that abyss that I'm trying to speak and
invite people not to join a tea group at
your conference but to look at seriously
and clearly what they do how it affects
them as people
and how that affects their relationships
and and their health and their lives and
I'd respond in a positive active way too
right yeah cuz what was interesting
Armour from the original talk was that
you know just people doing regular
security work and and being exposed on a
regular basis to things they can't talk
about right or or like in your example
like you know people cleaning up things
and having to look at you know horrible
images but even just doing mundane
things but that you can't talk about and
having to go home and keep that to
yourself like the idea that that
manifests in some of the similar ways is
PTSD was fascinating to me and something
we should really be aware of that's
right and and crosses over I think I say
that in the abstract the distinction
between security work and intelligence
work is really hard to draw these days
because line is very very blurred in
that you are working for a combination a
combine a complex of military and
government and corporate structures
which so intertwined that it's very
difficult to tell where one begins and
the other ends and and habits of NDA's
that require secrecy often compel people
to take some of these hard truths and
bury them and the results as they are in
the intelligence community the RC are
often that you don't know how to have a
normal a fennec relationship with
another human being and and yeah I have
plenty of stories about that what it
does dear family
one friend mentioned that at NSA young
man finally got all his clearances and
he came to the agency for his first day
of work and that's when he discovered
for the first time that both of his
parents worked there well family is
supposed to be a truth-telling kind of
trust trust organization right and you
find out in your 20s that your mother
and your father have been lying to you
your entire life block and proud of it
proud of it one guy told me when its
daughter got clearances I think was
Naval Intelligence and she said it was
hard because she was in a conversation
about some geopolitical
and she was gonna weigh in and she
realized she couldn't talk about it and
her mother who was there said well no or
you can talk to dad about it when you
get home and she said no I can't he's
not read into the program and he's not
cleared to know what I know and he said
he was so proud to hear her say that
well he's proud that his daughter is
keeping secrets the child I guess was
nonplussed but somewhat proud did his
parents had lied to him this whole life
long how do you have genuine
relationship based on forthrightness
honesty integrity and trust when your
whole foundation is to deceive dissemble
cover and manipulate other people which
become so habitual that even a cocktail
parties someone starts a conversation
you're immediately on guard you're
worried sometimes you wonder are they
targeting me did they start a
conversation in order to elicit
information from me so a competitor can
know what we're really up to I mean
every man and woman is a spy these days
for their corporation sometimes
wittingly sometimes not so so we've
created this world hammered literally
we're the nails and it's hammered by
secrecy and the consequences of secrecy
and deception and didn't used to be like
that always there have been lies and
deception but we didn't have an entire
systemic commitment to not telling each
other the truth unless we give away
something of value and as I say the
consequences for us as human beings they
come home in our unfortunately in our
relationships in our our habits and we
often take the wrong way out to try to
self-medicate we just need to tell the
truth to someone we can trust and that's
one of the themes that recurred when I
listen to people telling me again and
again what they did it started with
having one or two or three people they
could absolutely trust often people who
had clearances as well or they could
explore all of what they were
and without that the isolation made them
rigid intensified their fear and shut
them down even more so so we we need
colleagues we need friends we need
allies in truth and truth telling in
order to find our way into a community
that's really kind of countercultural
there's so much of what our corporations
demand from us right the self-medicating
thing is an is an ongoing theme Stacey
Theatre is actually going to be at the
conference in doing a talk on self-care
as well and you know so we were we
actually had the conversation out of
podcast last night
and we were talking about you know
having a drink to relax is fine as long
as that's not the only thing you have to
do to relax so like what do you say is
what do you see is somewhat like some
either maybe warning signs and people
should be kind of self aware of or maybe
things they can do to be more resilient
so that you know they can kind of deal
with these stresses that come up and
work sure good question
a warning signs are you know what are
what are you really hearing that you
don't shut out through denial or or
minimization or rationalizing it I just
found a diary my father wrote when he
went to Europe after World War two and
it included in the diary his statement
that the other people he traveled with
an important group of people allocating
scrap after the war to various allied
governments and he said people were
confronting him about how much he drank
and he laughed he said that was funny
aces they just don't understand how we
drink in Chicago well no that's not true
dad I would have said that's how you
drink in Chicago but there are the
people who drink moderately and I won't
drink at all but he used that to
rationalize what obviously from the rest
of the pages of what I heard my family
was alcoholism so it's really hard
denial is a funny thing I mean a lot of
jokes about denials not just a river in
Europe and all that but when you're in
denial you don't know you're in denial
that's why we call it denial you don't
realize that
Saiki thinks it's protecting you in
order to protect your your ways out of
pain and you've chosen those and so it's
not letting it get through to you until
you have either in so much pain so much
disarray in your life that it overwhelms
your denial and you have what they call
an a a a moment of clarity in which
suddenly everything comes into focus and
you see clearly what you've done now the
truth is that's often a very bad moment
a very painful moment and that's why you
need other people to this way AAA is
based on mutuality community feedback
and support to bear the reality of who
we have let ourselves become sometimes
hard hard to face once we have that
moment of clarity though we find that
alcoholism in this case is what we're
talking about is a symptom called a
disease or whatever but it's a symptom
there requires you to look at all the
other ways you might do more healthy
things that enable you to cope with with
the challenges and painful aspects of
your life and you know they're often so
mundane
when I listen to the things people
advance Steve miles of bioethicists here
in Minneapolis where I live says
gardening he's become a master gardener
I mean you take your obsessions into the
Cure as well as the illness and jazz
listening to jazz and he said he often
had a threat of a meltdown I like when
he came out of Thailand and it's been
days watching trucks loaded with bodies
stacked up past him hour after hour
taking out thousands of dead bodies he
said when you have a threat of a
meltdown like that the public grocery
stores he did first time that hit him he
said you learned you have to go to in
his case he went to a seaside village in
Italy it just been a few days
experiencing the normality of life in
the village going to the market lovely
this of people beauty of the day because
all these things still exist but you
need to consciously play
indignant and so I'll have a long list
of other things that people have said
that help ameliorate the difficulties
and there are things we all know but the
trick is not to know them in our heads
the trick is to implement them in our
lives and to get the support we need to
do that if we find this very difficult
we joked when we first start well my
workout isn't funny what it was once
well if you want it to be more
intentionality is to keep terram you and
I believe you want to be intentional
about that you you may need to build it
in a different way in your life and then
you may need to get support in building
it in a lot of people when they run I
have a running buddy and when they know
that 7 o'clock in the morning the door
goes get a ring and they better be ready
to go out and do 5 miles they have a
different attitude toward being ready to
do that then if they're relying on
themselves only they're in bed where
it's warm still 7 at the morning but
it's chilly out they just say oh the
hell with it
and then you roll over and forget it
so building in truly supportive people
in your life and and building out those
who would try to undermine you I
remembered I mentioned the kind of
healthy eating I try to do people often
make disparaging and mocking hisses
about it is it being a beggar pondered
being 400 pounds and and having your
knees replaced way too soon is normal
and eating healthy food is not and and I
turned out to be defensive about it this
eat the veggies eat the fruits eat the
great mates don't eat too much of the
other stuff you know you know everybody
knows these things right but but it's
the doing of them that can become
difficult it's so easy and an America
you know America we live in American and
bombard us with 24/7 you know it's
impossible to walk through Applebee's
without vomiting quick it's just people
never water you know Megan
with I don't know three four thousand
calories out of the people are eating
that you know that when you're sitting
on a plate and you see one of those
coming down the aisle you you get
religion it's like a fox so you say
please Jesus let him sit in twenty eight
that have not stopped when he said not
the idle had take over half my seat it's
not normal but there are lots of ways
you can make a decision and then act on
it because because you want to live you
want to live and you want to have a
healthy of a body and a mind that
supports your intention in life and
simple truth of that is that most people
do it's just that when you look at their
bodies their intention may not be what
they think it is then your body comes
along got a story about that but I won't
waste your time on a podcast the bottom
line is I'll be talking frankly and
honestly and and with sincerity and out
of my own experience what it's done to
me
they're people about the alerts we
should pay attention to and the kinds of
friends we need because the work has to
be done security is important
telogen work is important we want our
structure to continue more or less as it
is if we evaluate and so just doing
everything we can to enhance the
likelihood that's going to happen this
is incumbent upon all of us let's let's
be the adults in the room
good stuff Richard all right well I
always love having conversations with
you and I'm looking forward to having
you at the conference so we can chat
further weight sources is such a great
conference
not only the fellow presenters who I
love but the people I meet there are
terrific so once you've got a hold of it
animal you are you have been wrestling
it into shape it's kind of like a
knight's quest and you're beating the
dragon so it's a privilege I'm thrilled
to be there again thanks so much no
problem
some days I wonder in my Lancelot or am
i Don Quixote but it's a
it's fun either way exactly
all right Richard well we're looking
forward to seeing you its source Austin
on December 5th and 6th and you want to
come by and hang out and enjoy the
conversations with Richard uh please
stop by thank you thanks so much thanks
Richard talk to you soon take care