[Music]
hi this is rob machine with a source
conference and I'm here with dr. Staci
theatre who is uh has a background in
cyber psychology and behavior and she's
also coincidentally the original founder
of the source conference so we've come
full-circle now we have her on the
podcast as a speaker now so she's going
to be speaking at source Austin on
December 5th and 6th and the title of
her talk is put your oxygen mask on
before assisting others self care and
security now that's a topic that's been
evolving over the years and I'm glad
that we've been doing it because there
are there has been a lot of incidences
of burnout and things like that so what
do you how do you define self-care so
first off thank you for the experience
of being able to have the opportunity to
speak source it's really an honor and
and course very special to me to see how
you've grown it and then to have the
opportunity to be a speaker so I'm
really excited and honored to have the
chance to be have that and have that
speaker experience so when I when I look
at self-care in the way that I defined
in terms of put your oxygen mask on
first just like they say when you're on
the airplane is that when you're working
on anything especially when you're
working with people if you're not ok if
you're not at your best mentally if you
are challenged about yourself and find
yourself frustrated or upset or not
working at your best you need to take
that time and get yourself balanced and
what we're seeing especially in the
security industry is that actually in a
lot of industries that the notion of
taking vacation time you know a lot of
people don't actually take their
allotted vacation time despite it being
a policy they have budded a crew or they
just don't bother using it they would
rather go into work or work from home
and they're not taking that time to say
what's good for my mental health and
people what happens is you're putting
too much of yourself into your job and
and why I think this is interesting to
the security industry is because many
people in the security and
specifically in roles where their job is
to protect and take care of security and
safety of an organization yet what
they're not doing a lot of times is
taking care of the safety and security
of themselves and this is and and I've
been on panels and hunt talks about
about burnout in security industry about
addiction in the secure the industry and
about how is it that in and basically
what's an industry that could be quite a
pressure cooker how are people coping
and so that's why when I when I talk
about self-care its to find a positive
way to release some of the tension that
you experience from the stress of the
job that's not burning out completely
that's not turning to drinking and drugs
and unfortunately there's been a high
rate of suicide in the industry as well
and I think as you were saying that's
why it's been a topic that's been kind
of a hot topic lately because we're
realizing that both as employees and as
managers we're not seeing people who
realize this is what I need to do to
acknowledge my own mental health right
right yeah I mean one of the things I've
been trying to add into source
specifically is this whole people track
specifically for these kinds of reasons
they'd be a way to you know have more
balance and not just always be focused
on you know got to get the job done
because I I have found for myself just
you know I've been an entrepreneur now
since 2007 and running my own stuff and
I totally hear you on the vacation thing
like sometimes I have to like make
myself take a break and I've learned
over the years how to manage that in a
way where I actually like alright if I'm
feeling stressed out it's more
productive for me to do nothing for a
little while and go away and do
something else then idea is to like
sometimes push like I'm the kind of
person that like it's like 3:00 in the
morning I'm like I could just pull off
this all-nighter and I'll be fine and
but you know then I'll be a wreck for
the next three days and that doesn't
help me so you know having that balance
it's definitely it's challenging
sometimes
and especially now I mean putting our
own so I'm the worst person like what
and I was working in an office invited
be like 9 o'clock and I'm like oh now's
a really good time just send out a
series of emails and my own supervisor
who was was really wonderful with me and
she said at the end of the day put the
job down and go home and then pick it up
in the morning and not to get into the
habit of this 24 hour availability
because once you start with that once
and they know oh I can email at any time
you're setting the precedent for not
being able to take time for yourself
because we become a culture of well it's
taken more than an hour for somebody to
reply to my email what's that about I
know it got a bit yeah you're home
having a night just chilling out and not
checking your phone that's that's really
hard to G we don't just connect to numb
and I think what happens though also
when I've seen people just connect it's
done in a way that is I'm gonna
disconnect now and it becomes almost
very dramatic in a way of doing it as
opposed right in develop I'm gonna
disconnect right now and this is about
my mental health and I'm going to kind
of quietly take some time for myself
right it does have to be a big mic drop
every time it's just you know right
right right there's no that doesn't have
to be the big announcement I'm leaving
Facebook for a while right right you see
those from time to time from people like
clearly they've gotten to fry down the
rabbit hole now it's interesting I find
now especially with more people working
from home it's especially challenging to
balance that when there really is no
hard line between work and home anymore
you're just kind of you're on part of
the day you're off part of the day or on
part of the day and it just kind of
feels like all day every day becomes
work if you aren't careful how do you
kind of recommend that people manage
that yeah
again setting time setting times of
scheduling like you would in a day that
to say okay from from 6:00 to 8:00 this
is this is when I'm not going to be
working or this is how I'm going to have
a schedule and
it becomes easy to just let the day be
fluid but it really it takes disciplines
you have that time and and I think what
also happens is we hear kind of also
becomes a stereotypical
take the time breathe whatever and we
all say to do it but then we never end
up doing it and it sounds almost cliche
and it almost sounds like a self-help
guru and we I think I know a lot of
people just you know well I'm not gonna
I mean not gonna meditate if I had the
amount of people that came up to me said
have you tried meditation and I know it
works for a lot of people but I'd always
be like stop telling me to meditate
that's not what I mean like you know and
it's about giving things a chance that
not everything is going to be for
everybody but find out what works for
you in the course of a day even if it's
taking ten minutes to play that put your
video game or go for a walk or play with
your kids or do nothing just sit there
and just veg out for a little while
there's no rules because everybody's
self-care is going to be different yeah
yeah for me like my last company by the
time I was done with that I was so
burned out that I ended up taking a
couple years mostly off just kind of
hanging out and I got I swore to myself
when I started this one that I would you
know no matter what I was gonna clip my
bonsai trees and check out you know and
play around with those and like everyday
I'm gonna go out and check my bonsai
trees and you know that gives me
something I have a lot of them so I'm
just kind of that's just I've gone deep
down that rabbit hole and but it but it
I found I was in my last company I was
kind of neglecting them and ignoring
them and I could tell cuz they would
start to die and not look very nice and
you know so it it was just little things
like that just get like taking a time to
just do something that you care about
that's not work is useful and taking
five minutes out to play a video game or
something is a useful question what else
do I do like if you had to look at your
life and then kind of put it all on
paper and say where's the balance you
say okay here's work what else do I do
besides work and a lot yeah I didn't
always have a great answer for that
question and then it became like
okay I read or I have to think about it
from the other part that's really
important though is also for managers
because as managers being able to
recognize an employee in distress mm-hmm
is an important skill because that's
something that I've seen really
wonderful managers I've been blessed to
have wonderful managers that cared a lot
about my mental health and about making
sure that I was in an okay place and
I've had ones that didn't and one of the
things that I had done some research
almost it was this concept of
organizational citizenship and a
basically employee engagement and how do
you keep your employees invested in
their job and good at what they're doing
and part of that largely has to do with
their mental health and job satisfaction
and so for a manager to be able to to
recognize hey you know what you have
been here working late for the past week
or so why don't you take a day off or
why don't you take some time this is and
in acknowledging you were doing a good
job or maybe this could be better but in
a more constructive way in a more
respectful way and taking just in
general a lot more care for yourself as
a manager so again making sure that if
you are a manager you're in a good place
to then be a better manager for your
people to help them help themselves too
right yeah I think we've all heard the
horror stories of the managers that you
know just don't respect people's time
off and call them at really
inappropriate times and expect things
right now and you know I I've always
been surprised by that because a it's
really hard to find good people and B
isn't it obvious that if you treat
people like that they're gonna
eventually leave like I never understood
that mentality of just like just abusing
your people but yeah hopefully more and
more managers are starting to get that
you know people are part of your team
and you know need to have that balance
in their lives they're just you know
gonna go find someplace else that gives
it to them and people will reach out for
help somewhere in there there
in the security issue and I could I can
name a couple that are just absolutely
wonderful at how they care for other
people and they have a list of people
that they reach out to and call just to
say hey how is it going you know and and
that is because they have recognized
they've reached that level of who I know
when I'm not okay I know what it means
to have that need for self care and you
know even if it's just to say now I know
I
not everybody says I need a hug I know
hugging the thing for some people but
you know just to be able to say I need
somebody to reach out who is somebody
that I can I can call or who is somebody
that I can talk to or send a message to
say you know what and whatever it is
doesn't have to be other people
but what is your safety net what is your
oxygen mask you're gonna put on to take
care of yourself and then of course the
next thing is you know you don't just
sit there with the oxygen mask and then
how do you how do you then pass that
along to other people to help them but
if you're not taking care of yourself it
is very hard to take care of anybody
else or be the best that you can be yep
definitely and just a plug for walks
walks are great like that nothing clears
your head quite like a lock in my
experience and and I will give you a
plus one plug for meditation as as
someone who likes to occasionally
meditate it is a useful thing and it's
one of those things if you've never done
it or been trained in it there's a
learning curve and the learning curves
not off well that part of the being good
at it is just kind of stop trying to be
good at it you know it's just like you
know the whole point is just to sit
there and let things go and not worry
about it a lot of people getting so
fixated I can't stop thinking well why
you need to meditate but every I guess
you know everybody should have something
as long as you have something it doesn't
you know every what do I do to relax
yep you know and and that everybody
should have an answer to that question
and it's a fine line because for a lot
of people it's what do I do to relax oh
I have a beer you
or I smoke or I do you know and I like
to encourage and not not not with
judgment but encourage is it something
that you're doing that's also healthy
for you because it's it's there's been
numerous talks about addiction cycles
and the amount of drinking in the
security industry right for a lot of
different reasons and so what are the
alternatives that could be healthier
behaviors and again as managers and as
either founders or company owners is how
are you basically creating what is a
healthy environment for you for your
people and for the company because it
there they are all tied systematically
together and again you care for one it's
gonna go into the others and you'll just
be better off and a more efficient
company with hopefully more efficient
results - yeah and there's nothing wrong
with having a beer to relax it but if
it's if that's the only way you can
relax then you probably look like you've
crossed some kind of a line somewhere
along the way so right like I mean I
love having a very relaxed but I also
have 16 other things I can do to relax
that don't involve alcohol so yeah it's
it's good to have those things built up
but and I've built that up over time
intentionally that's not like an
accident it's definitely not something
that they teach you really in school and
you know and when you go out with
friends you have a beer you have a glass
of wine or right I mean I get that as
now as a mom I mean the amount of all
right moms were going out for a glass of
wine you know and and no I don't I don't
drink but I enjoy going out with them
and I have my sparkling water and it's
fine and I focus on the fact that well
one I I live in California so despite
when it's not on fire the weather's
quite and and it's just I try and be
mindfulness is actually for me it's not
meditation but mindfulness and awareness
of where I'm holding the tension you
know in just in my body you can just
body awareness or kind of symptoms I'll
scan through my head and go okay where
am I stress this this you know that's
you know almost a list of different
things that
I had and when I hit what's bothering me
I feel the tension and it's I also find
it interesting there's a big stigma
against mental health yet if you were to
say oh I'm going to the gym and I have a
I'm getting a trainer and I'm going to
the gym it runs like hey that that's
great you're gonna have somebody who's
going to teach you how to do your
exercises correctly and and really
seeking therapy or or seeking mental
facility health resources it's the same
thing it's just for your mind right and
whether that is through religion or
through meditation or whatever I mean
here your mind needs as much exercise as
your body does and there can be that
balance too for self-care - mind body
and spirit can all be related to
self-care right yeah absolutely and what
you just said about you know we feel
feeling we can have this conversation
for hours now but um so there's gonna be
a fun conversation at the conference but
you know just a point on what you said
about as you're scanning your mind
looking for you know points of tension
things that you're stressed about like I
do something some very similar types of
things and that absolutely works and
what one thing I can tell you is when
you notice those things they tend to be
little triggers that get you to go right
now here's the cool thing like those
triggers are basically just chemical
reactions within your body like your
organs are just giving you a little
squirts of chemicals that makes you feel
a certain way it there's actually been
studies like any given feeling that
comes up if you just breathe through it
like it dissipates within a few minutes
like if you let it but it's only if you
fixate on it it'll reach or itself over
and over and over again so you can make
yourself that space or you can just kind
of even kind of try to release it once
you get practiced at that you can let
that stuff go really fast and you end up
not even if you're in a very stressful
situation you don't have to own that
stress and kind of hold on to it as much
in relation to the talk my my takeaways
that I hope people will walk away with
it's
my goal is not I think for not to get up
there and say okay just do this just do
that and do this because I know I've
been at the receiving end of that and
I'm like whatever whatever that's not
gonna work what I want people to walk
away with is is realizing that self-care
is a thing and it's a question to ask
yourself you know what am i doing when
am i stressed and how do I know because
everybody should have that scale of at
least being able to know what am i
hitting the red zone what is my green
yellow and red zone look like and where
am i falling on that and so to be able
to recognize that and then to be able to
understand how being able to take care
of that and address that and come at a
place where you're in the green or maybe
in the yellow zone how that really can
result in happier environment both at
home both in the workplace and both and
for the people around you so it's not
only two people who are in the security
industries for managers - and how they
manage people and again I tie it to the
security industry because it does
fascinate me that it is an industry that
does focus a lot on or it bears the
weight of protecting and caring for an
organization and keeping it safe and
keeping it secure and so how can we take
the skills that these people are using
for their job and then almost turn that
around and treat them with the same care
and protection as they do their the job
in the company that they're protecting
right that's great all right well I I
definitely look forward to seeing the
talk and again stace is going to be at
source Austin December 5th and 6th very
quick and thanks for joining us by the
way because Stacey stop dialing in all
the way from New Zealand from a vacation
right now - and you're in your room
service to join us on the college so
thanks for that I appreciate that all
right all right all right so I'll see
you in Austin be in Austin Thaksin hey
thanks