[Music]
hi this is rob machine with a source
conference and today i'm here with
Swapnil Deshmukh and we're gonna be
talking about his talk that he's gonna
be doing at the source Phoenix event on
February 28th and March 1st so uh
Swapnil your talk is pack your Android
everything you needed to know about
Android boxing so could you tell us a
little about your talk sure so there is
a very interesting trend as thousands in
2017 where a lot of malware's were
published in Google Play Store and went
completely unnoticed for longest of the
time in fact there was a report that
came out that stated that one in three
applications that were released in 2017
had some of the other malicious content
on the Android phone which was
collecting a lot of user information
itself without user knowing about it so
that got me thinking about why exactly
are we not able to identify those
threads or the malware's before it's
been released to Play Store and what I
noticed was a lot of Android
applications were packed what that means
is that it's been hardened in some form
either it's been also skated or it's
been protected or it's been part so so
when I started digging through this I
noticed that there are lot many loops
that you have to jump through in order
to understand what that malicious
content is trying to do they have
various protections in place that will
identify if it's running in an emulated
environment or it's running in a rooted
device itself which makes it a little
harder for the Google Play stores or our
trusted app stores itself to identify it
early so I started a github project that
would basically be an abstraction of all
the different malicious contents that
are already out there so it looks for
the signatures of those and what it's
trying to do is it's looking for the
hardened application and trying to
unhardened those applications first and
then looking for a malicious payload
itself so that that's where the talk
comes in play the talk is going to be
focused around how to
identify the hardened application and
what kind of a hardening mechanisms are
they using at the first place and then
once we understand that how can we use
static code analysis to unhardened that
application and understand what
malicious payload is being injected as a
given point so that's that's the gist of
the entire talk oh so uh yeah it's
interesting as I was reading through
your abstract noticing all the different
ways that they make it hard to detect
what they're doing so they you know
they'll obviously the data they pack
everything up so basically the normal
kinds of tools that you would use to
find issues aren't going to work so your
project then basically undoes that
that's right and there are certainly
some research work around this but they
were in 2014 and 2015 so a lot of tools
that they released along with that has
been completely office catered oh sorry
not office catered that's not being used
anymore it's completely obsolete so as a
result of that I'm creating a github
project that would be a live document
where everyone can contribute to it got
it and the the things where you said
it's it's detecting if you're running in
an emulated environment or in a root
environment how does it
what by doing that how is that
preventing the researcher from finding
the issues so if you look at Google
bouncer which is a app that has been
used by Google Playstore itself to
identify malicious content it runs in an
emulated environment so as a malicious
author itself what they try to do is
identify it that's running in a in a
emulated environment and then they will
not inflate their malicious content on
the emulated environment itself as a
result of that when Google bouncer is
evaluating the application or trying to
run it in an emulator environment to see
what the application actually does the
malicious payload itself at no given
point has been inflated which is not run
on the device itself right
so it actually runs so actually runs
differently when they're testing at
versus in the actual real environment
then you got it huh that's really
interesting yeah that makes it tough to
find doesn't it it really does and there
was an application called P Z that was
detected recently in fact in November
last week of November and it was there
for like one and a half years on most of
the trusted app stores that we have for
Android and the reason why we were not
able to detect it is because they were
looking for if it's running in an
emulated environment or is it running in
a real devices it's off since there are
challenges like those there are
certainly ways that malicious authors
have found ways of how they can
circumvent from getting detected right
and that's particularly scary since you
have one in three issue apps that are
malicious and then according to your
abstract they can basically take photos
record calls monitor info about the
Wi-Fi access etc etc excited sounds like
they can basically do all the things the
phone can do you've got it and the scary
part is ransomware is also been on a on
a high this year so we have seen
instances of where they're encrypting
the entire SD card itself or they will
encrypt or lock your device with their
own pin and you ought to pay a certain
bitcoins to them to get the unlock code
so it becomes even more scarier I agree
yeah cuz that's something you could
distribute in mass and hit a lot of
people at once that's crazy
so for your talk who's the target
audience so who would be the best to
hear this information and do something
useful with it
so I'm looking at three different target
audiences at this given point I'm
looking at anyone in everyone who is
using Android applications so I want to
give them an arsenal a tool that they
can scan the application or an apk that
will state out what are the malicious
content in that particular
vacation itself so finding a way of
detecting it and finding a way of how we
can read it to make sure that we are
protecting our devices the second that
I'm looking at is a security personnel
who is evaluating code or evaluating apk
or the Android application itself by
providing them a tool on how they can do
it in the most efficient way so that
says my second target audience and the
third target audiences dev cyclopses
sitting along as well right so any
enthusiasts that we have for dev Cyclops
excel I just want to find a way of how
we can show them how the automated way
of identifying malicious content and
blocking them on the fly sounds good so
is this something that the end-user
could potentially use to define issues
then - so we have a website that has the
live instance of it anyone can upload an
apk or an Android application and scan
it on the fly itself and it will let you
know what are the malicious content in
there or is it harmful to install on
your device at any given point all right
I think that gives a pretty good
overview I love when we have people who
can come on and give to tool releases to
you know solve real-world problems so
this sounds like a good one so we
looking forward to seeing your talk in
Phoenix at our in Phoenix Mesa actually
on at the conference on February 28th to
March 1st I'm happy to be a part of it I
it gives me the perfect platform to
explore further on how we can expand the
initiative that I started so thanks
again for giving me an opportunity to
talk at myself I thought you know it's
huge - thanks thanks again Rob yeah
great no problem looking forward to
seeing you there not like wait okay
thanks a lot
thanks Rob
you