how many what about laser squids so
cartoon sea creatures with with declan
she does like spongebob in Star Wars
[Laughter]
it's been a long time but that is still
my my very feet in and used phone case
it's from laser squid nemesis everybody
introduce yourselves
their mother skip that part I'm Dave
Mattingly we're looking at how we can
use improv comedy that skill set tool
sets process to improve our social
engineering the stats he mentions in the
opening keynote so between 80 and 90
percent of regions starts from some kind
of fishing and this can help us to do
that if you're you're on the red team or
guard against it on the believable war
for the rest of us and I keep hitting
the backwards but instead of forwards
I've done a bunch of things NASA I
worked for Wolfenstein that and and do a
little bit all my security Anabaptist
health these days not attack I was a
regular VJ for a long time I'm gonna
publishing company I preach for the
Christian leaders field at the in
conventions around do a lot of a data
balan tearing music things a lot of
stuff up earlier this year I wrote my
first stage comedy look there was a skip
thing so yeah I had one of the skits I
wrote and it's a lot of fun I try a lot
of things then I've had some minor parts
in minor movies I accidentally played a
bouncer into things so I have you know
real world pretend bouncer experience
what are you doing to watch that improv
copy who is seeking whose lives anyway
or one of the other popular ones who has
been to an improv show in person of some
kind they're a lot of fun I like them I
I know I could not do stand-up that's
way too much pressure and memorizing and
how is this thing gonna be funny for for
everybody when they're all different and
that that is is really really are but
the improv is just a conversation
onstage with stuff that makes up it's
the things you do with the people that
sit around you all the time anyway you
know the the primary rule is yes Han
when you're an improv scene somebody
says oh well the building is on fire
what are we gonna do you can't decide
well no we're we're on a submarine no no
the building is on fire you have to join
what that's already been established yes
it is on fire and it's good thing we
have our more spell firing crossbows or
something yeah add something if you
accept what is there and then build on
it no idea gets shot down nothing is
wrong well they're all kind of wrong you
know but but that's the whole fun you
start by taking what you have at you
accept and that's one is to connect you
need to know who your audience is
if you know doing the improv in front of
a bunch of college students probably the
people might go different places that if
I was performing at a church or you know
at a RPV or something like that yeah I
know who you're talking to
nothing is never going to land with
everybody but you don't want to make
sure that nobody is gonna like it yeah
improv is is a team sport you need to
support your scene partner or partners
your partner comes up an idea wants to
you know help you carry this invisible
dejar app then you need to grab the
other end and help them carry the
invisible did drink having the improv
people split up in their their own
different things it's just been a
interview on the scene we do a lot easy
to use nobody's gonna have any time here
you're all they are doing the same thing
for some reason direct instead of just
I'm here and I'm talking you're sitting
there we're just talking back and forth
it's a lot more fun if we're moving if
we are building or doing or otherwise
making our bodies be parts of the scene
as well project and expect then this is
the the part that scares be follow the
fear as my final improv mentor a
appreciate soundtrack that's wonderful
[Laughter]
Mike improv coach always you say that
awesome is on the other side of fear so
yes it's scary when you think about it
or what you do it's the first time but
what it's done wow that was great
and the more you do it my comfort zone
will go from here to here to here you
get a little more used to it and maybe I
bomb myself that's fine it's all part of
life's respected you know and the sticks
are gifts there's a lot of times we'll
do something wrong well we'll get
somebody's name wrong or I'll forget
that we are in the getaway car and I
decided me to stop for a passenger or
something yeah let me do it wrong that's
just even funny people love it
especially your fellow improv performers
it it does sound scary but there are
lots of ways to get involved there are
many ways to keep yourself keep your
brain fresh I had a stroke fifteen
sixteen years ago I had learned to walk
and talk again and things like this
helps make sure everything keeps firing
he keeps me thinking better which means
I can do all my other things a little
better there are in Louisville 3040
improv groups something like that
most nights of the week you can probably
find a five or ten to pick from click on
one check out
most of them are for general purpose in
problem but there are some that are
specialized though the hysterical x' is
an all-female troop because they're
funny plus the hysterical yep
that came from a biological that but
they're always a lot of fun there are
other ways to keep yourself involved
creatively from a technical perspective
as well the 48 hour film project has
been happening for 20-some odd years
anybody ever worked on it we have a
release Bush we have two days to work on
my get this thing out it's like that
except you're making a film you get your
team together beforehand and you don't
know what you're gonna be doing so you
have to well what if we need a warehouse
why I know this thing out supporting us
we could make it genre film you're
making until you start on Friday you
draw it out of a hat you making a
musical or a silent film or a period
piece or time travel you get that
everybody has 48 hours to turn in a
finished film I've been in a few of
those they're always a huge they will
show all these submissions at village 8
one of the local theaters the doggies
can vote and then the the organizers
help pick various winners things like
that but the other tricky is that
everybody draws different genre all
those teams but you all have three
common ingredients you have to have a
same character you know a name the job
and a line of dialogue usually pretty
simple like what if you're wrong or I
don't know II have something very easy
to work in and a prompt the rubber band
a hose something like that it's a lot of
fun and nerve-wracking you exhausting
all of us Startup Weekend we have two of
those each year here in Louisville you
go on Friday night kitchen I do other
people get involved in yeah I like that
let's work on that you build a thing
there's prizes
some of them turn
actual real businesses and go on there
are several hackathons so you can use
various tech skills to volunteer give
back to the community a lot of games
will help you out while my peers here is
who would win gin if you don't you've
gained a person here it only takes a few
seconds you explain and less than one
minute to play all right I have Horatio
Nelson the British full speed ahead
alright so I have 20 seconds to say why
Horatio would beat Cleopatra Pat Taney
or at poker or I figure skating and then
he'd have 20 seconds to to say well no
the attacker is a lot better Vickers
gave them more dozen laws because of
this and that well that's fun my son
likes this sometimes well some do it in
a car and as we're driving I have to
think I'll live at it
once upon a time as a car game you're
telling a story and you can interrupt a
little amma the card that says drag it
although you're doing this but then the
dragon shows up and you try to get out
of your cards first as you're telling
this common round-robin story word on
the street is say anything apples to
apples
flux movie buffs list off a lot of games
will tilt your mind stayed creativeness
you have to come up with answers a lot
one thing I like about say anything
there are a lot of of games that will
reward people who come with clever
answers in a lot of people a lot of
games will come up with people who are
good acts you know guessing a number or
reading people this is a little of both
I would draw a as judge around I'd say
in my opinion what it is and draw a card
another that's the best hair back or
something everybody would write
something
and I have to draw or I have to choose
among those which my favorite hair
babies it doesn't care what my I think
what I could pick from those than all of
you votes on what I picked so the person
that picked the one I guessed gets a
point and people who pick the one that
they thought I would pick also get so
pit Wars both kinds of players lots of
cool books to stimulate your creative
brain how would you move Mount Fuji this
is a a story interview question book
Microsoft and a lot of companies used to
use it might still use this as weird
interview questions just to see what
your thought processes and how would you
get to an answer how they make M&MS how
would you test a saltshaker counting
base negative to weird things like that
to keep your brain going several others
and I have links up on the site
Oh keep yourself created public speaking
at Toastmasters International I did that
for a very long time anybody ever been
to a Toastmasters meeting or or heard of
it it's a chance to practice public
speaking in front of other people who
are also trying to get better at public
speaking it's a very very friendly room
the nice thing is that you get instant
feedback from it everybody will write on
a little paper or you here's a comment
or note if they get it great so you get
no twenty little cool slips of a
feedback you haven't assigned evaluator
who says the goals of your particular
speech this time were to do this and
this and this
and you have a few paragraphs of written
v value then they also read out so
everybody else hears all of your
specific written feedback and can
improve their own speeches that we did
and they also have a people topic times
they call it the tabletop master will
call on people and ask them a question
you have one to two minutes to respond
that's a my time and it could be as
simple as what was your favorite
vacation or please describe the global
economy there's something like that you
never know what it's gonna be
which is nice play to make sure your
your brain gears are working the track
shut it spilled like pizza Kuja
pronounced muchacha is Japanese for
chitchat
it is a public speaking competition
what's the trick there is that your
slides autumn advance you have 20 slides
that paint on their own every 20 seconds
in Troopa talk to a style you don't even
see them there behind you you have to
know in your head you have to have the
rhythm it's very hard to do but if you
get you to one it is a thrilling
challenge and above all just go places
meet people learn things do stuff I I
dabble in a lot of different things I
still don't know what I want to do when
I grow a lot and there's just way too
much life out there for me to focus on
just one thing or two things
so what's that called
sharpened design that will give you
random questions design a set of
stickers for a camping gear startup
that's on a window final for a Model T
company and make a geometric interesting
things locally here are some of the the
groups that I mentioned a lot of
references and all this is up on my site
check the program it has my Twitter
account go to Big Bang clean net and
download all my various talks and we'll
do a quick demo and I'll skip just the
contact information is also in the
program now let's do the live one have a
bit flood alright I have a white bowl
it's invisible but I have a white ball
it is roughly the size of a softball has
similar properties
they saw all and I am going to look one
of you in the eye and when our eyes meet
none all you're paying attention I'm
gonna say white ball I'll throw it to
you and you'll catch it white ball all
right you got the white ball you throw
up somebody else make eye contact make
sure they're looking at you and throw
Wasat tell them you have the white ball
okay you have the white ball a ball he
has the white ball I also have a red
ball it's a little bigger it's it
wouldn't hurt as much if you already get
hit in the head it's a softball they do
this white ball then this is moral above
a kickball tight little squishy he has a
nice bounce to it basketball is kind of
I have a red ball and I'm going to throw
this as well to somebody
red ball he has a red ball you throw the
white ball I have a white ball you have
a red ball look somebody in the eye
throw them the red ball fine who's gonna
catch it look them in the eye when you
know they're ready for it then you can
throw the ball but it is very very light
is much like a beach
[Music]
because it's common color double our
this is not the kind of ball like that
waiting like like the white ball or
overseas if this one moves slowly in
Cabo on its own but it's also very easy
to catch the ball and I'm gonna throw
the blue ball there we go got it yeah I
got a big blue ball a banana so red and
whites we keep on going this is the
first session of the day all right for
there's everybody hold on so so you know
where they are we able to lose them so
that they're hard to replace another
ball game that will sometimes do is to
get everybody in a circle we're not
gonna do that just now but we'll have
imaginary ball we just pass
person-to-person the trick is the ball
is made of whatever we want to be made
up so the ball might be made of
electricity and I give them that person
then they're carried the electric ball
and then give it to the next person and
we run around when it gets back to when
it gets back to the person before the
one who started they changes so now the
ball is made of tails
this is tickle ball of in this person
who's carrying a tickle ball and then
they give it you a lot of fun it's a
great way to Epsilon your co-workers to
impress your CEO possibly by giving a
tickle ball I don't know
but doing these things and besides the
improv groups who performed publicly
there are a lot of workshops improv jams
very informal
audience you just go and practice these
things with people in front 502 offers
one every week the alley theater used to
do it every week there they closed that
a while back the Bardstown occasionally
will do it like once a month haven't
improv Jam that's a great time if you've
never tried it before just to go and
practice so how does this interact with
social engineering any thoughts from
young as how this might help or Murph's
the ability to talk your way into or out
of something yes
you'll learn to come up with stuff
you're not waiting from a script if if
you're trying to break into a building
legally of course and the guard stops
using a lot I'm here to do this thing
didn't come up with that but he asked me
a question I wasn't prepared for
well obviously I'm here for this if you
have been doing this coming up with
weird answers off and on it is it really
as as scary to do to keep your composure
and it it comes off as a little more
sincere because you're not totally
freaking out in nervous I'm just here to
fix the rubber thing how else
yeah well improv it it's not always
about making somebody laugh it's about
accepting you know the yes and another
reality well yeah yes yes I I am
supposed to have a badge and I will get
my badge because I'm a visitor my friend
is supposed to happen for me it's about
the more you do it the more natural it
all seems and feels it sounds scary but
it actually helps me to de-stress
anybody ever had an emergency at the
office oh no this thing is wrong what
are we gonna do this other thing it's
okay you know yesterday I was I was are
antics on a bicycle it's not a big deal
we'll just change this thing in
now it's alright the the outside
stresses don't seem as mere to me if I
make myself go through very low impacts
you know for for failure exercises it's
kind of a stress practice for me
anything could go wrong at the office or
in life or during travel but if I
practice weird funny terrible things a
lot they don't seem as bad
any other ideas on how this could help
with your social engineering techniques
a lot of ideas have to think on your
feet
mm-hmm yeah a big money to achieve an
answer regardless of what the question
is and it might be a wrong answer or a
stupid or silly answer
but you ever talk to a regular normal
person they got a wrong or stupid or
silly answer yeah happens to us all the
time but by not being freaked out about
being in a situation we're prepared for
it wasn't people help it's it's not as
as strange
let's try another good one for free
crowd that is well I'll give you another
one that we usually do get a circle it's
a great way to get to know people either
first thing that he does maybe you've
got ten people in a circle like Randy
volunteers if I want to come up and is
to be totally safe he's coming we're in
a weightless spot although you're doing
just lurking first names yeah come on up
here and a camera see if you can try to
kind of keep an eye on us here a few
other folks Monaco it works best with
like six or more we get another couple
of volunteers up here
yeah I thought we're gonna try to sell
it to you over something no no no all
right look let's Circle up
so uh some more backs to you I apologize
for all of that we don't know each other
I am going to appoint I'm going to say
my first name and point to one of you
you say your first name I'll keep my
finger pointing so you know that I'm
already gone then you point to another
person they'll say their first name
until all fingers are gone what we're
done put I'm Dave
um beers Nick yeah
I'm Shay all right so now we're gonna do
that again Dave so I would say people
hey there's your totally good scene it's
all about learning and doing it Shay now
we might do the same thing backwards
starting with him and you pointing but
I'm Shay Jeff Nick beers Dave we do this
a little while is if we know each
other's names it's not as weird to
practice doing you know a scene with
each other that's good thanks guys
because then you only really pay
attention the person next to you or
either side sometimes this is it cuts
around weird and then random you can
also use a word association kind of
thing that we're all in a circle I
picked something I picked the color blue
and I point to somebody and they say sky
and they point to somebody else we go
around so we've all picked something do
the same thing again you know blue then
sky work away around then I'll say blue
point person they'll say sky and while
that's happening I'll say Dave and I'll
point for Anthony
we have two different patterns our names
and our word associations going around a
very simple one but a great warm-up
improv exercise so looking at social
engineering and our rules we have yes
and whether you are doing a fishbone of
dish if you want to call out that this
makes a little more natural that aren't
you supposed to have that that code well
you can guess I am supposed to my
computer is rebooting right now and I'll
have it in 20 30 seconds I think we
might be writing an email or texting
back and forth it might be in person
that I'm here to inspect the tapestries
I mean I'm here to look at your data
center to make sure there are no good
sex scrolling cards things like that
connecting you don't want to come up
with something that is weird for the
place that you were going into you or
that you're talking to if I'm trying to
get into a military base I probably
wouldn't come up with something weird
that I mind the new garbage man I'm here
to empty your dumpsters maybe I would do
that but it helps to know who you expect
to talk to and what kind of things they
are used to and they expect support your
partner if you have two people going in
working together you backed each other
up yeah I don't want to call Jim Joe
after I've called him Jim already
because we are obviously using aliases
because we belong here we aren't up
spirt where these people who work here
obviously you don't want to get your
your stories wrong midstream direct
focus on action if you are doing
something with your hands or I drop the
papers picking them up that will put the
focus on the thing that is happening
rather than looking you in the eye and
making you sweat
and wait a minute I thought yeah you're
not on those slips but if there is
something else happening it can act as a
distraction and follow the fear next it
is a scary to talk your way into a place
where you aren't supposed to be most of
us are honest if people but you want to
get you know backstage at a concert you
know it says it isn't say a pen test job
a lot of things you might want to talk
our way into then doing things that are
scary and outside our norm that's when
it gets cool and fun doesn't always work
but that will give you a great story
suddenly you're alive at the end of it
yeah I said I think maybe Chris had me
he tells a story about going to a
military thing and hey once we go at
night and check this thing out and they
end up you know hands behind the head on
the knees guys with guns morning I would
want to be in that way what otherwise
trying to get someplace where you're not
supposed to be do something you're not
supposed to is informative and fun and
then it also works in Reverse
if you've done some of this it's here
you're working the aren't you it comes a
little more obvious that oh you're just
making this up as you go I can tell you
aren't using the same kind of
terminology we usually use you aren't
doing it at the time of day we usually
do these sorts of things as you practice
improv or even just watch and read about
improv it's a good way to make sure that
you're on your guard and you can
recognize improv behavior in the wild
doesn't work there's an improv company
in New York that I love they're called
Improv Everywhere and instead of just
being a must a performing
the guy who founded it couldn't really
get an improv gig so you know I'm just
gonna get a couple friends well let's do
something kind of a flash mob in Perth
the first one they did which became so
popular is now an annual event is the No
Pants subway ride a guy would go to
Subway yeah a suit and tie nice shiny
shoes the underwear for us but but nope
a scary face just no grandpa he's riding
like normal next stop somebody else gets
on without pants feel like five six
stops and then something goes I'm silver
pairs of pants here one dollar you bring
that much people's day just by doing
something weird fine
another one of theirs I like is a random
parade
somebody wearing a majorette that is not
the right you know with the big metal
like fluffy Red Hat and the baton and
all that just font somebody walking on
three hey can you think our parade up
free leaders gone always need somebody
to be a leader if you can take this
going to the ATM okay well just we'll
just don't do the parade and just follow
you here okay you're having that out you
got me like 20 30 people come with their
Touma's and you know you're the whole
parade crying in and then go go -
expertly it's just a fun way to get some
creativity exercise give people story
they'll help remember also these things
like just happen to wear blue char some
khakis and although the best buy it's a
knot or whatever the best my colors
offer you know yeah but what they're a
lot of fun now I always like to watch
them and then see the creativity and
strange things they come up with years
ago I was actually on the The Drew Carey
thing I've got to do a see with some of
his guys it's always a blast I never
expected that but never know what's
gonna happen if you don't try you'll
never get there
who has done we're trying to defend
against some social engineering attacks
in the past just it right before lunch I
got a call about my car work you sounded
pretty important I'll probably get on
that yell back right away get a free
dessert oh that sounds wonderful
alright excellent yeah the war of these
that you are exploited a part of the
easier wedding we all know the nigerian
prince the car war auntie the IRS Mikey
tell when somebody is is tailgating you
into your building no I strike the band
I walk in and it's almost close they'll
come and walk in there and they're busy
doing a thing along maybe they don't
make a monkey somebody you know Matt
might be your boss but maybe maybe you
got fired two hour ago you don't know
maybe he's not your boss anymore
[Music]
yeah you're wearing a uniform you know
or you're carrying a clipboard you're in
a hurry you get anyway that's got a
lighter yeah I've seen women use the
fake pregnancy belly to hide their door
they're like a neon pineapple in or
whatever or you know a lock you go babe
ie just to have it yeah right oh yeah
here I'll get that for you
nobody ever asked for badges you can get
away with what they call pregnancy brain
oh hi can you bring moyen team and
although that's fine I know you might do
the same thing other than they get in
they take off the belly and they get to
work and then hack into the systems and
lots of ways to to get past you know one
obstacle and you get the next obstacle
try to find your way the more practice
you have by want to improv workshops
maybe trying to treat or you just
watching a lot of them product more
practice you have the easier it gets and
focusing on the action the I'm carrying
all the coffee's I just dropped my thing
and it spilled everywhere oh my gosh
hold on let me get this for you my
friend accidentally spills water on me
and I have to get up and go change lots
of ways you can use that to help you to
stretch because it's all smoke and
mirrors misdirection I don't want you to
know what I'm really doing I just want
to somehow get from here to over there
oh well my badge isn't working I don't
know what what's probably business it's
not a badge it's just a piece of paper
the looks like a match but it's not
scanning but you know 20 seconds ago
with the last person waiting I recorded
the badge beep sound so I can impress
some of it
beep it's not working the beat just I'm
not sure okay can I go into the to the
street desk beep and they can fix me up
it must got degassed you know probably
close to my magnet that I keep in my
pocket get that the action the prompts
things to do besides just me and you
make it a lot easier to to get the focus
away from me doing something naughty I
have to do something naughty right now
wouldn't even know and the mistakes are
gifts if you're on a pen test assignment
you want to get caught about you know
sort of you know that's the goal is to
teach
people to catch us it's great if we
could get two or three steps in say if
you are you know a couple things you can
confess but if they are totally on the
wall that is great news we failed
because they're awesome
and that has wonderful news to give a
lot of ways to find out information
about the targets oh if I was like the
the new tech always yes looking at the
bald cap somebody's wearing hey you know
my daughter goes to that college or
something Johnny long does a great one
about just looking at stickers on the
backs of people's car I know how many
kids you have
on our way to school I know how you
folks or looking what you can find
sitting on the dash there was a great
talk at this conference I see you go
about dumpster diving that's how you
make a big splash I'm the security
auditor I'm walking through the building
hey I'm going to be looking at all the
trash things like that and then I
crumpled up a red post-it notes put in
the garbage bag crumpled the red yellow
one over here a green one so I know
where those came from
when I check the garbage tomorrow I know
which desk or which area and well this I
want to look for this specific
department I'll leave my little color
code things now I know our men don't
look at every man what are they
yeah but they they're almost always a
contractor they aren't usually employees
of whatever I'm just guessing just watch
an hour you know go for another game and
see another what's he good to sit down
game like can I get one person at one
volunteer job and do then do anything
or not yeah
Vanya's your hearts I'm going to hurt
myself watch yeah I'm kind of an omni
I'm all the works now yeah yeah I'm in
the intro in extroverts I switch back as
the I reckoned it getting in front of
people it's scary I realized in college
that I was afraid of public speaking but
all things considered was kind of a
silly thing be afraid up so I that's one
of the main reasons I got the job at the
campus radio well I'd love to see the
people I could probably talk to and and
then that was okay you know it worked
out alright and then got a job as a TA
look if I know something they don't know
they're paying to be there to listen to
me I can probably do that and that went
okay then I could talk it's not that bad
baby they don't have maestro years ago I
had to learn how to get it all working
together in and Toastmasters helped me
with that I mean a little over 50
speeches in one year various places
around and that really helped me get my
rhythm my confidence my voice as a
speaker usually prepared speeches are
training sometimes off a cop I want a
citywide humor speaking contest or meet
random questions I think that
twenty-some-odd and Prince the the one
that got me advanced to the next round
was that the banner just put you in
charge of transportation for the city
what do you do so smooth out
Louisville's transportation problems I
knew I had to make it memorable and
interesting for people so they item this
is one of the guys who should advance
people would say you know buses like
radios changed for us no set once we
need septums you bring examples into the
city you know people hang onto bungees
and then you just float around where
they need and went on like that for a
couple minutes
and yeah - we'll let them go the next
round work his way up you know the
ridiculous can be fine
and the stranger you get when you
practice the easier it gets when you
have to do it for real if you want to be
able to make more gestures or get more
body language in public that when you
practice I need to make wild gestures
and weird things just to get my body
okay so I want to do it for real
I'm like this seems a little more
natural a little more confident you know
I've done it's a point where you do key
notes you know an hour long thing on a
couple minutes notice most of my speech
s about like three little points and
kind of make it up from there I have fun
with my preaching because I usually
preach at weirdo events Comic Cons game
cons punk concerts or conventions things
like that so I get to preach about
zombies and pirates and aliens and weird
things which makes it fall I'm not gonna
make this all fit you find a way to be
creative and then do some things and
it's all about The Improv being
accepting the situation here in adding
to it making it stronger or better
improv comedy it's it's a very improv
not as much comedy they aren't trying to
be funny the scene is funny you don't
have to try to be funny because that's
what the environment provides it's all
about working with your scene partner or
partners and if I have to be four people
in the same scene just flip them back
and forth so when I get out into reality
and a happy social engineer my way into
or out of something yeah I've I've
already tried this 20 different ways
it's not as weird or as hard just like
with any muscle our brain is an organ
the more we use it the stronger it will
get as we as we come up with new ideas
and approaches we develop new neural
pathways the more that neurons fire down
that pathway the stronger it gets the
more natural it feels so I keep doing
everything the same way over and over
I've got this really strong mental rut
that's in me but if I try it a little
differently then I have a new way it's
not as strong but it's there I can do it
again
make it stronger how many of us drive to
and from work the same way all the time
I try to at least every couple of weeks
take a back road or some way I've never
been might be faster probably not it's
probably to be slower
I'll see you park the city or that maybe
I'll see very often throw detail yeah
exactly
come change rides yeah you know how
about a taxi yeah you never know who's
followed yet it's probably him it Furby
calm they've always have a happy worker
bee competition either you're buying a
real Derby hat or they'll give you have
achievement
you know $0.10 paisa cap you take this
plus whatever you have on hand and
decorate it some people will get all out
and a have won with mechanical parts you
know the pineapples or you know lighting
help disco things a few years ago I won
by taking police crime-scene tape that I
had my trunk will have please crunchy
favorite drops right and Nikita thought
trying that you know because it's all
about what you have on hand is part of
the competition to make business just a
way so he created with what you have
around couple years ago I took a bunch
of derbies and staple them together in
sign-outs making each
all sighted hats it upside down and now
which I may be a reader be doubly feed
written hat that I could take off a role
with numbers on the inside did know
would work until I had finished stately
theater yes it fits and I can make it
see all I did things like that's making
it to help exercise the creative side of
our brain growing up I was an artist
squished American tech later but I also
minored in psychology and philosophy to
understand how the visual world works
and also how our brains work and also
how the Meno reality works
I still nobody have it but that's the
theory you know I try to use your left
and right half of your brains the skills
you develop in improv are creativity and
communication and those are the two most
sought-after soft skills in this field
in almost any field getting new ideas
new approaches and ways to do things and
understanding and press it back out with
your teammates learning how to talk the
same language as my improv coach would
say improv improves every other area of
your life you might get we're selling a
little but not that much I don't make my
improving my creativity Nicator skills
it's a lot easier to get ahead at the
office it's easier to to trick my kids
into handing easier to go out you can
say easier to have managed my own life
and tendencies easier to manage projects
and goals because I've I've had
experience at looking at things many
different ways the more I do that the
more natural it feels and my coach I
said puffier awesome is on the other
side of here
a lot of things I've never done before
because I've never done this bottle why
not try you know never thought it would
be in a movie I never thought I would
write a play I never thought would write
a book I never thought I would found
several companies never thought I would
do I mean nobody people most of the time
so it's kind of a new surprise every day
but by intentionally doing things odd or
strange or unusual that way I don't have
the same you know ten ruts in my neural
pathways doing the same stuff the same
way all the time my last job I was at
the same company but I had five
different jobs in the five years I was
there from developer to scrum master to
master data manager to QA on the tech
side and I think something else very
different parts of IT while I jump back
and forth between them all because I
have learned to do things a little
differently as I go any thoughts on the
social engineering and how improv might
help as we get ready to close yes I can
see how socially how this would be
important to be able to get outside of
your comfort zone and learning how to do
that to be able to do social engineer is
that the biggest firm unless you think
for first times ocean engineering is
especially on a face to face basis like
trying to get into a building or is it
something else it is feeling comfortable
inside your own skin and a role I think
is the main fit if you look nervous then
you actually nervous you can see if
you're nervous that makes you feel
warmer of us and it feeds on itself
but if it's just hey I'm here to help
Bob with the thing I'll be there 20
minutes how do you here before you know
it
then this is a lot easier to get things
done those having a safe practice area
before you have to take it out and put
yourself on the line it'll help to both
the confidence the the creativity to
come up with something as you need
because you do it all time I think the
distraction works really well in social
engineering seems like the more things
that are going on the less time somebody
has to focus on this same thing you know
portion of it around here on fire it
does have a lot anybody in law
enforcement or rotations a lot of
criminal duo's will I'm trying to rob
the jewelry store my last couple of
questions have reached that thing behind
the counter and turn his back so my park
over here can do this other thing
because they're all busy or I'll
accidentally you know knock over the
speeding rack of things oh no hope you
pick them up and while we're looking
there something else is going on yeah
that they have you know that is their
job is to steal things by distracting
and we can learn from them as well I saw
you two was start where years back and
you have lady there reporter and she's a
social engineer and he told him she
could probably figure out you know where
these bank account was and so you know
the whole scenario he said well you know
I don't think and you know my bags
pretty good and then I first open and
every day when she went in and she
called the bank and claimed to be his
wife and then said you know you she's
got her phone and she gets to say her
phone I've been behind sound you know
baby crying
I'm sorry if she starts getting a little
upset on the phone
my husband told me to do this tonight
you know and I I don't know what I'm I'm
so sad for six years
I'm gonna get in trouble get out what
baby's driving all this stuff is going
on and they literally gave the system
now she has full rise to going Chase's
password you know what that's like what
yeah so I mean you know it all those
tools you know work yeah that's a client
but look up I think voice fish baby
crying or something and you'll find that
one it's like a lot of success long yeah
I was wondering if you practice with the
voice changer software
I don't although I don't tend to focus
on the voice I'm more in person well I
know but you're talking so you have to
pick words that a woman would say Oh to
masquerade as a woman okay yeah I know
on Chris on social engineer dot-org
lots and lots of great information there
he found that women are like 80% more
effective than men on voice calls or
something
so now women do all the things at his
company when it talks when it goes to
fishing and then it's also a good thing
for parts of the country and accents
things like that you want to try to a
New York person in Texas would stand out
the way they talk vice versa Kentucky we
sound like we don't have shoes on matter
where we go you know not that much meat
we can that can help with that
but except travel and experience going
learning doing now that is was that I
help all of us with all eventually any
one last question before we close here
all right well then go for thing and I
mix them up
[Applause]
[Music]