while trying to get the video work I
couldn't tell you all UDP jokes but I
don't know you get yeah I was how that
was a dad joke
Boop Wow what happened here okay there
we go
all right all right thanks mark
[Music]
alright we'll go ahead and get going
here this talk is on as you can see I'll
be talking about zero trust and to kind
of get going through here I wanted to
give a little bit of background on this
talk because it's going to be that's
somewhat relevant this involves the
entire gitlab security team I'm just
kind of a representative of that I've
been doing a lot of blogging on the
topic and whatnot so and I end up doing
I am doing a lot of research on this
subject as well so it's kind of thrown
in there into the mix myself I've been
in the industry for several decades I've
basically been an InfoSec for the past
25 years or so as my exclusive day job I
guess you would call it I have worn a
number of different hat colors over the
years I started out as a black hat
breaking into probably many of your
systems that are here today sorry about
that is a long time ago but I continue
to wear several different hat colors
it's just your coincidence I happen to
have a gray hat on today that doesn't
mean or imply anything but nonetheless I
do wear I do have a pretty varied
background for a long time it was either
IT admin or InfoSec professional by day
hacker by night kind of thing more or
less but I'm doing the InfoSec thing for
I've been doing it for a while and like
I mentioned one of my projects at git
lab as a researcher happens to be zero
trust and we're talking specifically
about getting zero trust in for the to
the company itself for the employees of
get lab I'm not going to include any of
the fancy charts and I agree
people usually show with zero trust
where they got the big particularly the
big diagram that belongs to a Google and
they're beyond core paper I'm not going
to include that in there because that
might imply that I'm trying to get you
to think a certain way so I'm not going
to do that I'm going to be discussing
specifically what we've been doing at
gitlab in that this is the steps that
we've been going through implementing
this stuff so hopefully I can have some
either I can get you to think about
things in your own situation that can
apply to you if you're thinking about
doing any of this kind of stuff so I'm
going to go ahead and define zero trust
but I'm only defining this in the
context of this applies to get lab it
may play out completely differently in
your organization probably the first
thing is user identification being able
to specifically identify a user and I'm
not talking specifically about an
account and a password I'm talking
specifically about identifying that yes
Alice is logging in and Alice's who she
said she is that kind of thing
same thing for device identification
being able to identify when Bob logs in
that that is Bob's you know computer
he's supposed to be logging in with
that's we've identified that it's you
know patched and properly configured and
that kind of saying that would be device
identification data classification this
was kind of weird a lot of people say
there's you know just you should have
like you know public internal and then
there's like the segmented parts and
stuff like that we do it slightly
different we have four tiers I it's
detailed in a blog post and I'll have a
link to all a way to get to all the blog
posts
last slide that you can look at but
basically what it boils down to is we
have green for public and red for the
most critical data and there's also
orange and yellow and there in between
and I'll kind of cover it here in an
example coming up a little bit what we
mean by that it's not specifically about
data in as much as it's about
information okay and there's there is a
distinction to that because a lot of
times the data represents information
and within context even though the data
doesn't change the information could
mean something completely different
access controlled systems this means
that we don't want to implement
something that we don't have some
semblance of control or we can actually
prevent either a person or a process
from accessing it except in a way that
we want and so we need to be able to
have that and have having defined
policies in a way of you know handling
and administering those policies to do
all the other stuff on this slide and
make it to where stuff isn't bad which I
believe is the marching orders of all
security departments make stuff not bad
now some issues that we've kind of
encountered when we started looking for
solutions on this and this predated me
because I've been at gitlab since
February and this predated me before I
got there but there really didn't seem
to be any agreement on what zero trust
was by various vendors and I'm not going
to point any fingers or use any names
but but yeah they're just things they
all have their own vision and version
that they would you know try to push
upon you and everyone kept referring to
beyond Corp and I don't know if your
hopefully if you're into the zero
trusting you or at least vaguely
familiar with this thing
beyond Corp was the Google model that
was a response to a breach that they had
by a nation-state that came after
certain elements of them and took
advantage of their unique architecture
and whatnot so they were able to they
went through and said okay we need to
change things in our model and how we do
security and they came up with this
thing specifically for them and they
went had put a paper out so that
everyone could read it so they could
learn from it and then go do their own
thing as stead vendors just latched on
and said we're doing beyond Corp so you
don't have to worry about it
and no vendor has a complete solution
regardless of what they tell you no
vendor does all right they don't trust
me so basically with these vendors we
had one that isn't Google trying to sell
us an incomplete version of an internal
Google solution to my company which
meant that it wasn't going to work there
was no way it was going to work and that
was kind of a tough realization to deal
with it just like what are we gonna do
we're just maybe we can do a parcel
solution we can just say okay well one
of those elements that we had that we're
trying to implement maybe we can take
just one of those and use that and
implement that so going to these vendors
a lot of them this is traditionally what
they they would make they make
assumptions to a certain degree and they
have to because or you know they've got
to market their their products and
whatnot to sort of companies and
part of it they say okay what you're
doing zero trust you're going to have to
remove your perimeter and maybe there's
a vendor that has features or something
is this a part of it where that works
well for them they can help you as you
remove your perimeter that's a part of
their product or whatever and then
there's what we can help because we can
help you dismantle your VPN because
you're not going to need your VPN
anymore that could be that could be an
interesting thing that they may have as
a part of their offering typically few
remote workers they've got oh we've got
some solutions that while we're putting
this thing in we can actually address
the fact that you have this small
percentage of your organization that has
remote users and we can help you and
that's good all right and they also say
well look you're probably implementing
some cloud stuff we've got a way to help
with on-prem and cloud and they may have
some stuff that has to reside on Prem
and that but it can still talk to the
cloud that kind of thing so there's a
variety of things like that that we're
kind of in play and then they also
assume asset management and I'm gonna
guess pretty much everyone in here does
some level some form of asset management
and I'm not talking just about you know
the servers or containers or cloud
presences but the actual laptops people
have
that's great well the thing is we had a
completely different reality at gitlab
and so that kind of caused some problems
for us dealing with vendors first off we
have no perimeter we never had one ever
no perimeter at all never did we do not
have a VPN no VPN at all no perimeter no
VPN we are a 100% all remote worker
company the CEO the headquarters is the
ceo's apartment out in California and
that is not a job that's real ok you
know it's just there are there isn't
we're all remote we're all cloud we have
been from the beginning and we will
continue to be moving forward there's no
on Prem whatsoever and unfortunately we
have limited asset management and the
area where we have the most problems is
in BYOD we only started buying laptops
for employs a couple of years ago before
that is BYOD get labs started as a fork
of an open-source project okay that's
how get labs started everyone was
working from home that's what they all
just use whatever you have and
contribute we still do that to a large
degree we're what you call open core so
the
the majority of our product is free and
you can get to the source code that's
out there on the on the internet and
anybody anywhere can contribute to that
make changes and whatnot and we've
applied that to unbelievably huge
amounts of our company which is gonna
seem even worse when I get some later
slides it's really not it's actually
kind of fraying in a way but the point
is is just we've got a really good
handle on our infrastructure as far as
what we've got in the cloud and all of
our you know servers and containers and
and and instances and what-have-you we
have a really good at handle on all that
stuff and can scale and do everything
with that that part's great it's just
that you know the asset management thing
is somewhat limited so as you can
imagine we can't rely on a single vendor
for four zero trust to work at all
most of them are selling their solution
is the Indus solves part of a problem
that we've already solved or that does
not apply to us ok so there's a few
other pain points that I didn't want to
cover that will kind of drive home some
of this even more data classification is
fluid and I wanted to give you an
example of this with something that
happens somewhat recently to us we had a
customer just for those of you that
don't know gitlab is say a web based
devops lifecycle management kind of
company ok
so that's what we that's what we do
and we had a customer of ours that
reported a problem and you know this
customer it was for them it was serious
it meant that they could potentially
have their private code breached and
because they were doing all their code
development they were doing it on on get
lab systems and so in our classification
ranking it ended up being orange that
was an you know that's considered orange
data all right now after evaluation it's
like oh this could affect multiple
people multiple customers so now it's
been elevated to read data once we go
through and we can if we figured out a
way to mitigate it and then very quickly
we had this thing patched and that
process
I can't it didn't take a long time to do
this but because we're all about that
whole you know dev SEC ops thing of
rapid development of security a part of
the process and everything like that so
we're very quickly able to Patrick oh
and then get the patch pushed out and do
our notifications and whatnot at that
point the data becomes green data except
for the company that recorded the data
to us they didn't want their name
associated with this they didn't want
anyone to know that they were using us
as a as a resource because they felt
that might put a target because hey our
code is located in this place and so
just to kind of help to help them and
this is just something to you know we do
just you know if you don't want to tell
anybody yourselves here you don't have
to and we'll keep it private for you and
that's exactly what they did and so the
fact that their name is associated with
it that becomes I became yellow data I
think it may have been Orange I can't
remember exactly but nonetheless
during that process at any point if
someone is going to authenticate and you
have a policy that says this person
cannot access read data or if this
person can only access you know green
and yellow data the data classification
could change at some point during the
day after they've done their initial
authentication so we needed to look at
ways to be able to make sure that we can
enforce on a transaction-by-transaction
basis that our data policy and adhere to
that and so that's been kind of we've
we're doing pretty good in that arena
because we have pretty good access
controls on our stuff and there's been
areas where we've had to you know write
some stuff to improve that or implement
something to improve that ends but but
there you have it that's that's a pain
point that we have to deal with so any
solution we have for any part of any of
this stuff that we're talking about that
comes to mind that comes to the
forefront oops
too far there but nonetheless
provisioning and de-provisioning is hard
I'll talk about that one first we had
and this was when I started there if we
had this process in place so you get a
new employee and it's already weird
enough because once you signed your
paperwork they immediately started
creating your accounts and everything
and of course it's digital signature
because we're all remote you're not
going anywhere for onboarding and then
they ship you a laptop and hopefully you
get your laptop before the first day of
work and so they start creating all
these accounts on all these different
systems and I haven't mentioned this but
I say cloud-based were in the middle of
doing some transitioning
and whatnot and there's some things
we're keeping on certain systems for
various reasons but it's complicated but
we're on four different cloud providers
okay
mainly on - but we're still we're on
four different cloud providers and as
far as SAS applications go I think as of
well when I submitted this slides are
submitted to talk you know to you know
just just you know Ferguson for
acceptance for this conference we were
at well over 70 different SAS
applications and I think we've probably
up to that by at least probably ten we
probably got rid of a few and then but
you know there's probably a net gain of
10 and so we do so you can imagine that
provisioning accounts is kind of a
nightmare and yeah when I first started
there it would take two or three weeks
to do that and of course the worst thing
you want to find is that all of a sudden
you have you know Alice is looking at
some system and she sees that here's an
account on some some container some
important you know Lennox server this
running of Bob and it's been and Bob
hasn't been an employee for three months
that's just like oh my gosh why how did
we miss that well the D provisioning is
probably harder and and that was the
thing I was probably when I was hired I
was probably a employee number I don't
know maybe 400 or something and this was
in February and we're now at over a
thousand and we're gonna be at about
maybe
I don't know bye-bye March we're
expecting to be around you know some of
the neighborhood of 1,200 or so maybe
more is so it just were having just all
this dynamic growth that's going on and
we're still trying to do all this stuff
and like I said we barely have asset
management I'm talking specifically
about laptops we're uh were a mac shop
mainly that's what we're buying for all
the employees are Macs
we will purchase a Dell for them that
ships with Ubuntu Linux who they could
use for Linux if they want and they most
people end up just wiping it loading on
their favorite flavor of Linux and as
fine but nonetheless that's the two main
operating systems we support Windows
isn't allowed but I'll be very frank
with all of you we don't have a way to
enforce that yet
we really don't we can see it we can see
the violations that occur but we really
don't have a way to enforce it so we're
we're working on that we're we've got to
fleet Smith in for managing the Mac's
and that's I think yeah we're that's
implemented now and so that's what we're
using for all the Mac's at this point
and so we've got some semblance of some
control over at least a majority of our
of our workstations but we still are
having some problems managing that you
know it still doesn't mean that someone
can't decide to log in from their iPhone
or
from there you know their surface or
whatever it is they're logging in from
so our plan we decided not to focus so
much on zero trust stuff that vendors
were selling we just if they had zero
trust like properties it's like okay
well we'll look at those and see if
that's something that we can that we can
use and it's something that we can
integrate in with what we're what we're
currently doing and we had to reduce
everything down to basics it all had to
come down to just the most basic
components and then solve for those
individual components such as device
management such as you know user
provisioning and things like that we had
just had to reduce everything down to
raw components to see what we see what
we could cobble together from all of
these uh various vendors we have to
solve for each one of those basics we
had to find budget for it which is as
you can imagine would be tricky
particularly if we found something that
was really nice and sweet and it costs a
lot of money we have to figure out well
and right now that's basically it's
coming out of the security the security
budget I mean that's because it's
security related but now fortune we're a
part of engineering and and all that so
that's that's but nonetheless you know
are still it's gonna hit the bottom line
somewhere
and then we have to tie all this stuff
together we have to make every bit of
this stuff actually work where we can
actually kind of make it cohesive if
you're gonna write a policy and that
policy covers more than one of these
basics all this stuff has to actually
work together and we're not still not
quite there so some of the things we
identified where we wanted to have user
authentication with 2fa we wanted to be
able to provision indy provision in
minutes not days or weeks like it was
when I first started there a secure
communications we wanted everything
that's talking to each other you know
between the various subsystems we wanted
it all to be secured encrypted believe
it or not there was some cases where it
might not necessarily be that way we
wanted to make sure it was that way
audit access controls this kind of a
loaded little point on here we wanted to
be able to have a way to go in and audit
all the controls we had available to us
for a particular component api's you
know everything everything associated
with that and we also needed a way to
track their usage we wanted to be able
to say if someone used this API if
someone used this particular sub
component or whatever can we track that
we wanted to be able to do both of those
things and of course manage assets like
I mentioned that was another huge one
like I said we've gotten the
infrastructure part of it down all of
our cloud stuff we can manage that
pretty well and this one it may seem
like a weird one to have in there for
2fa this is one of the ones that I was
really adamant about doing
which was detection and tracking of
anomalies when someone decides to try to
bypass or not use the elements of our
zero trust solution we wanted to be able
to way to see that and see what they're
doing to some extent so he can make some
semblance of a decision on that so let's
talk about some of these individually
what we did or are doing user
authentication with 2fa we went with
octa I don't know anyone here familiar
with octave the price if you people
nodding their heads hands gone up yeah
we're using octa and we gave the users
this is another thing I'll touch on a
little touch on it now I'll just go do
it out we have a very very open company
and we get a lot of feedback from our
user community from the employees and
everything we wanted to make sure if
we're going to implement to factor that
we try to give them a choice so one of
our big conferences where we
occasionally and get together every 9 to
12 months will all fly to some city on
the planet
because we're a global company we're in
60 countries spread out all over the
place when we get together like that we
handed out a whole bunch of yuba keys
every attendant got you the keys and if
someone wants a Yubikey they can just
simply just by one and expense it and
it's you know just practically and
suddenly reimbursed and because this is
just like oh this is a no-brainer if
they want to give you key fine we'll get
they can do
be king if they want to like what I
opted for doing was I have the octave
verify app up my phone because I'm
extraordinarily lazy and I can
authenticate to factor using my Apple
watch because I'm so lazy I can't reach
into my pocket to get my phone but I can
get to my wrist so you know I'll do that
but I mean that's what we ended up doing
for user authentication and that worked
out really well the other thing that it
actually helped with was the
provisioning and de-provisioning I as a
you know a company that's you know
integrated all these different shows
octa integrates with all these different
SAS applications most of these SAS
applications will speak something you
know the del out for SSO a lot of them
talks sam'l and so we kind of pseudo
de-facto standardized on sam'l and now
it's a part of an evaluation process
when we're evaluating a new SAS company
that we're wanting to get a part of it
is like hey can you talk to octa or do
you have sam'l support so we can figure
out a way to make you talk to octave and
what happened with this is that one of
things we have we used bamboo HR Izumo
familiar bamboo HR if you've had our
bolts an HR type SAS application and
very popular with startups and whatnot
when excuse me when HR creates a new
employee in bamboo HR that
auto-populates out to octa and then octa
goes out and creates all of those
accounts and this is based upon the
user's titled and
and the department they're in and even
some groups that they're associated with
and so that gets to be auto-populated we
can do the same thing when we deeper
vision so all of a sudden they leave
their say you know I submit my
resignation
boom someone can go in there and
deactivate their account on everything
and that's that's been a huge thing an
area that we're still working on this is
as you can imagine we do have a we do
have these administrators of our
infrastructure and these are people's
it's an independent of our coders for
example or do all the development but we
have this infrastructure group and for
them they were just like this is
unbelievably painful to create a new
user and now you're telling me I'm you
know Mike you you stupid people you
granted my wish I'm getting 50 new
employees in the next month I'm gonna
have to have a couple of engineers spend
days going to end to all these systems
to create accounts for these particular
people and they came to security and
said look this octave things really cool
can you
is there something along those lines
that'll actually work for us and there
actually was there's octa ASM octave for
a sa I think it's called and it does SSH
and RDP and we use the FIR SSH and so it
will even allow us to provision accounts
and so that's and we're thinking about
well possibly rolling that out to our
developer community as well so that all
the stuff that they have to SSH into to
do their stuff do we have some semblance
of control over that as well so that's
that's kind of that's really kind of
work so we think we've got a pretty good
handle between the two factor and the
provisioning and de-provisioning orage I
should mention all the two-factor
in some instances where we had something
that was basically hosting read data we
went ahead and added a third factor for
some of those Thanks bamboo HR example
you can look you can log in at the
beginning of the day into octave and
then you get the octave dashboard and
you click on the app and if you click on
a bamboo HR it's gonna ask for another
factor it's usually the same two factor
but it's gonna say okay you're gonna
have to prove it again just to make sure
and just kind of a good policy that we
were able to implement that way by the
way I'm not trying to make this I don't
work for octa when I work from it lab it
probably sounds like a commercial for
them but that part that part of what
they were doing work for us it really
did the secure communications thing this
was one of these really weird ones as
you can imagine we have a git lab we
participate with the hacker one bug
bounty program and have been paying out
a lot of money to people to find bugs
and our stuff and I think we were even
trying to you know improve like how
quickly we pay and stuff like that
because we're really trying to encourage
that cuz it's been very very helpful for
us and someone had found a flaw in and I
won't go into details but basically it
had to do with a form of you know pseudo
injection as it as it were when I came
down to it and we were looking around
for solutions and since we're based on
open source is just like Willis or any
type of open source product it's
outdoors or any type of thing that we
can do because we this specifically
could be taking advantage of the fact
that you know you have like one system
is trying to communicate with another
system but it's got to go through a
cluster and so it's just like it's
you've got to specify something and it
is so we needed some way to kind of
manage all of that anyways we're looking
at solutions for this we ended up using
this thing called camo proxy and camo
proxy the thing that was really cool
about it was that by doing you know
security department's looking at it
we're saying this thing is awesome
because by default it makes sure that
you're doing encrypted communications
between nodes and then someone said hey
I got an idea so we don't run into this
problem again while we just implement
this everywhere in the company and then
we're just like sure
turn and so we instantly have not only
did it solve some a current and possibly
future security problems it actually
ended up securing our communications so
it's kind of a nice little side benefit
there is that all of our communications
were taken that and you know taken to
that level on the auditing of access
controls we're still working on that one
there is an effort going on right now -
I mean we can do this manually we're
looking and we're still doing it
manually because we're not done this is
a hard problem and we're looking for
ways to solve this where we can actually
go through and just say oK we've got all
the I mean you think that because a lot
of it's our own code that we we know but
still you it's just like but we don't
have auditing you may not have auditing
turned on to everything we want and then
you've got issues with the data
retention you've got issues with because
I mean we've got employees all over the
planet so you've got like different
jurisdictions or different privacy laws
apply and as a general rule to make
things easier it's just like okay what's
this what's the most strictest policy
out there we're just going to do that
implement
that company-wide because it's just
easier than trying to go region by
region you know so we're having a some
difficulty with that what we're getting
there
managing assets that's again that's
still another kind of a tricky one like
I mentioned having to we got the servers
and instances and all the containers
stuff down pretty good we're still we're
gonna have to figure out something for
mobile devices I don't know I know what
we're gonna do there it was it an
informal poll of our security department
and and and our security departments
pretty big by the way I mean it's
actually because the upper management
was so keen on security the number of
people in the security team is a direct
percentage of the total user population
of the company so as the company grows
we grow and that's kind of nice to have
that kind of built in there but and this
is also the security team is not just
you know researchers like myself but
also there's like you know application
security there's people that are doing
you know sac ops you know the day-to-day
stuff there's a team that handles
nothing but abuse that occurs there's a
team that handles compliance and a red
team and field security which talks to
the rest of the company about what we're
doing security wise and whatnot so
there's a whole big effort there and an
informal survey of just the security
team who should know better there are
violations of our BYOD policy because I
technically you're not supposed to be
accessing anything from phones
technically we all do it though
it's just work we're willing I means the
security and we're willing to accept the
risk that something could happen down
the line and someone might say you know
hey I need to see what's on that phone
not the company but just you know
there's outside forces that could you
know as a part of some whatever it could
happen the chance of that happening is
extraordinarily small and since we're
into risk assessment and security
department we've all done the math in
our head and said well I'm gonna get hit
by lightning twice before that event
happens so I probably will be okay if it
happened once I'm gonna go play the
lottery instantly gonna tell you that
but this ties into the detection and
tracking of anomalies thing this is
something we've started we're in the
process of coming up with a way to
collect all these logs and all this log
data so that we can do some really
interesting things that against logs
that aren't 100% obvious and to give an
example of that it's like let's say that
I have sceptic on Alice and Bob a lot
say that Alice logs in from Seattle
which is where she works
but her authentication is her two-factor
authentication is occurring from a
different time zone or a different
continent okay that's something that's
kind of odd there may be something up
with that
now it could be no and this could happen
that's like just say you know midday
she's logged in from one place and then
in the afternoon all of a sudden she's
logged in
according to her Lobby other planet now
she could be going to coffee house and
logging in from there and using a
personal VPN and the personal VPN is
then you know going through a server
that's located somewhere on the other
side of the planet that kind of makes
sense in some cases that might explain
why on a two-factor saying that it's
coming from different places we want to
be able to track that kind of odd
anomaly now if these things are coming
from different systems we want to be
able to track that there's some
geolocation type stuff that we might
want to be able to do if we're able to
pull something up off the phone that
says one thing or are they you know and
it doesn't match up with you know the
other we want to be able to pull all
those odd things if you have a you know
processes runnings that shouldn't be
running except as a result of someone
logging in and launching a job and then
all of a sudden those processes just
kick off on their own that's an anomaly
that we want to be able to to note does
it could mean that there's something
going on that was not intended so that
ties into that and if we could somehow
then affect access associated with those
actions then we can make that a part of
our are not only with it it's pretty
cool to be able to do that but if we
make that kind of a part of our whole
policy involving access so that's
something we're kind of working on my
advice if you're doing this stuff
obviously you're going to have to get
upper management to support this
we're lucky in that case that security
is way up on the list it's one of the
top is in the top three okay and the the
breaking things down into simple
components is just a must you just have
to do that that's the only way to get
this kind of thing implemented we
couldn't just come in and do these but
the last thing you want to do is to be
adapting whatever a vendor says to do to
your environment you shouldn't have to
change your environment to accommodate a
vendor it should be the other way around
you should be saying I'm going to take
this this this and this from this vendor
and make it work for me it should be the
exact opposite look where you're have
areas where you're winning and then
capitalize on that for us we were
winning with octa and so they ended up
saying what else can this thing do and
that's why we're you know implementing
some of these other features and stuff
that maybe at the beginning if we tried
to sell this entire thing to upper
management it might have been a harder
sell but by doing it piece by piece were
able to say well hey remember when we
you know when we had HR personnel
running around trying to track down
people to create a council you know 70
plus systems you know we don't have to
do that anymore
if this happens in minutes think about
the productivity gain so we got in that
you know in a lot of ways you can start
doing that kind of thing
you know just you're taking all this
tedium out of it and you're saving
people money individual departments and
it ultimately the company then and go
for it and that's what we've done we
tried to capitalize on everywhere we're
running where we can do that and like I
said just ignore the vendor spin just
realize their solutions may not be your
I have a few culture things this
specifically is probably more security
related in general than zero trust
related but the adoption of new ideas it
does work a lot better when you have
end-user input at gitlab if you wanted
to know how we did a certain thing or
what our policies are you can you like
you people out there now can go to our
website and look it up the handbook for
the company is online and it is open to
the public we put almost every single
thing we have up and online and make a
public one is the kind of a part of that
whole open-source thing so you figure
others could probably benefit from this
and - it just it gives us a it kind of
helps hold we are kind of holding
ourselves accountable and so that's why
we do that and we go ahead like some of
the ideas we've had on some of these
things came from unbelievably simple
suggestions from regular employees
saying hey why can't you do this and
just like wow we never thought of that
and so I mean during your onboarding
process that get led you're supposed to
make at least one change to the manual
to improve it to the handbook that's and
the handbook is it that's this every
policy everything it's all written down
so you want to see a lot of our policies
you want to see what our infrastructure
looks like with the goofy map with all
the stuff you can look at it's all
online it's all just very open and so
we've consistently tried to go to the
users and try to see what's going to
make them up make them happy and see it
make their lives easier and if we can
come up with if there's a solution and
it's got two routes one it they're not
going to like it into the
are gonna like it we're gonna go with
the one that they're gonna like present
they'll use it and that's that's a
that's a big deal
we always tried to leave things better
for the users than when we started
that's just and this may sound really
stupid but back when I was a black hat
and I was breaking into computer systems
before I leave I typically would patch
the hole you know I try to clean up
after myself I didn't didn't leave a lot
of junk out there in the logs I I
cleaned all that up and I think I'm
gonna head patch the hole I mean just
you know just I left things a little bit
better than when I got there you know
you know I had ethics when I was
committing felonies so but nonetheless I
mean just doing that for the for the
people you that your work was is makes a
huge difference and we're boils down to
is if you've got something that's
extremely hard which is gonna be
extremely hard to implement or extremely
complex for people to understand and
don't do it it's as simple if it's
really that hard and complex don't do it
do something simple there's got to be a
simpler way to do things we've been
finding them I mean you just got look
that's the only thing you got to look as
that that's part of that whole research
thing in my job and so for applying that
to zero trust you know it should make
things easier and if it doesn't do that
that you need to find another solution
that's it that's the the best part of
this zero trust thing it should make
things quicker easier and faster and
more secure it can be done
all right that's the end of it we've got
a little bit of time so if anybody has
any questions I'm happy to answer them
it could be about any of this or
security in general I don't care all
debts or whatever but nonetheless thank
you very much I do appreciate it thank
you
[Applause]