[Music]
when you give back to the podium I'll
start recording all right you guys ready
all right awesome
all right today we're going to be
talking about moving into info section
you guys may not give the museum for you
but maybe we'll give you a chance
inspire others maybe this field
what we're going to be talking about is
just pivoting into a new career info SEC
if you haven't so if you're not already
there or get a job you really want the
idea is we're very romantic
knowledge is we need the fundamentals
contains incredible knowledge also put
together some gadgets and projects to
sharpen your skills on fun wedding so
who support anyone the needs of your
niche and their feel someone that wants
to explore understand feel they're in
maybe just looking for inspiration I
know when I go to conferences people ask
me how do I get to become a minister how
they go in sorry this is a big field so
this maybe will give you some answers
now Who am I if you guys did I say you
you see me presenting yeah just before
but my name is Eric Jackson
I'm the senior panthous enlist put your
certifications
I've got my prior life was active and
I've appended in language translation so
if you want to have a spear have a party
for you to death I've open source side
github I'll tell you about them here but
as I said isn't normally a web
application security
but let's talk about what we have to do
to actually begin our ways I'm assisting
alright so the first question asked is
security the right fit for you
everyone loves to hang most people want
to talk about hacking when people hear
about fraud it's like I'm interested to
say I wasn't doing oh no was done
non-stop and I used to like Devlin and a
lot but never really pump this really
could be the hacks are funny is true
this is the best part of the job
absolutely but there's a lot of hard
work and stay that goes in prior to that
and the preparations really understand
that
so your first leg of your journey is
determined this is your real passion is
this what you want to spend your hours
of free time in this is something too
much you make your main light you might
commit all your time there's good sizes
Security fits I have here that go how to
surgery creativity and maybe doing tech
outside work but if you like taking
apart things you like to see how things
are prevented one of my friends here is
for those all squinched up when she says
something bad it wants to prevent it
that's a good sign that you should so
time to set a new course
why me by this is is your job sucking
image you need to leave or something you
just need the culture my dad gave me
this book and it's always a bad sign the
dad gives me weird strange books I have
a whole stack of them if you guys want
to reread I could give you one it gave
you this one called or main the giant
hairball is a monetary loan alarming
title because it's like on now this is
no good it's going to be another dad
book by this ornament Kenzie guy he
worked at work at hormone I'm sorry
hallmark he was hired because of use
creative his artistic but like most of
us when we start a job in corporations
they don't really want you to show those
things they want you to kind of have to
admit and incorporation your in so the
things he got been may not be other
things are highlighted when you worked
there his idea was that hairball is a
policy procedure deformity competition
and focus on title they people don't
like orbiting is taking the originality
the nonconformity the creativity and the
innovation
and actually find a way to work it into
that the without extra game piling into
the air hole his idea is you orbit it
you don't fall into that you can't just
do anything you want you just have to
find pants that the company needs you do
but then you want to do without falling
into the tailor politics jealousy
unfairness it was actually a really good
fall
it gets a little bit wild at the end
just recommend this it's like five
dollars on the end zone that being said
the day you decided to go into security
just like quitting smoking you get an
immediate benefits that very first day
there's things that you will know that
other people just won't know you'll have
a wide sort of holistic look at
technology the other people just don't
have so it's you're going to see that
you're valuable just from the day one
when you first open that very first book
you'll have things that your team just
doesn't it what might be boring
beforehand when else would be beneficial
did you know in 1980s if you were a spy
going to the critical skills you have a
know was held pastor a wall I would not
want plaster wall if someone but why
would you need to know it if you can
plant a bomb in the embassy especially
the old embassy you're going to the wall
from where you I have to do you're going
faster or not they have a journeyman
that actually watched agents pester
walls since they didn't do right they
knocked it down program pledging walls
of online learning technologists so if I
when I was a developer if I haven't
talked about another framework again I
thought I was going to lose my mind if I
talk about framework can see there's
mobilities there's things that I can
work around those things that people
need to know well that's that's
something and now I can actually really
enjoy aspects of my training but maybe I
did now are you too late I have a friend
of mine told me it's too late for me I
can't do it you absolutely can it's not
too late they actually started working
this in your job now or to look to you
when you were child hey so how's if ASEC
look in the future this is from Bureau
of Labor Statistics from my farm
I'm Tommy twenty-eight it's looking like
3% rejected job growth which is great
good candidates are always such and
here's the thing attackers just aren't
going away I mean as we sold heard you
know who sings target t.j.maxx Experian
was that the one that cut back the
suddenly the name very much then it
makes people CIOs see so is very nervous
and they are always hard if I could be
job satisfaction talk to my colleagues
here and they will tell their you can
tell you they love their job it's a you
get a player knowledge and you really
make a difference every day so it's
really great have you guys ever been a
job where someone picks your knowledge
yeah like you have some people that
obviously don't know what they're doing
it's hard to do insecurity can't do it
so if you are a professional that can
speak very well that you can show the
multiple skills they're going to be very
very happy in this job in you now when I
talk to people at conferences they
almost always say I want to be a pen
tester or I want to prevent invest those
are just two of the security jobs that
you can use in this field there's a
whole bunch more I got this all from
stance and there they actually went down
several several lines more but there's
things like threat hundred you can
actually assume that your network has
been an end and sort of finding that
people have actually attacked you a
forensics or instead of responder one
recommended your career be that all the
time that you that's a good place to
look at you malware analyst that's a
really great job that if you have any
interest in then people are going to
want to talk to you disaster recovery
and business continuity that was why our
attendance and security is
confidentiality integrity and
availability this is the availability
part people tend to overlook that like
why don't want to do anything with that
well that is a key area security that
people really want do it in Korea they
won't go to Derby con 2017 do you guys
say the keynote for Microsoft or they
talked about imposter effect it's where
you think that other people know a lot
more than you do and I love the fact
that they brought this up they just had
a Don because I think this is the thing
as in this field a lot do you think you
don't know what you're doing or you
can't do what other people do and the
truth is just on that if you've watched
a good Mission Impossible movie there's
all these people that have overlapping
skills that's what you're looking for
the idea here is that you should hit it
head-on by the theory there's just a
lack of confidence in this arena it's
very easy to talk yourself out of
success and say I'm not gonna be able to
do this
it's a present here is a lobster pail
situation if you put a bunch of monsters
in a pail I'd hear a financial
experiment verify this
the monsters would pull it all the
monsters into the bill you don't know if
this group sure hope is there you see ya
all right cool true so that happens all
the time
you're not worth you can't do it when I
was an active particular contract it was
a project of our 12 people ends in
development so if you're in the
development actual amount people on
three right and there's two releases one
person got fired so the other person had
to go to those early songs on fever
leaves that was the person reading it
developing and presenting working late
nights miss my family all the time I was
out like the only person in the office
looking out the window going so this
kind of change it just can't do the
service and and I wrote down three
things like a dune and InfoSec use them
agree like I actually have meteorology
which I have no business yeah as number
two because I just didn't think I could
do it it's very easy to talk yourself a
low success my brother
god bless him was one of really pushed
in this field and kept on saying you can
do this
kept taking projects Cheerilee me all
the way you guys don't have the benefit
my brother but I'm just telling you you
can do it it's worthwhile so been T on
your path for a day or so that's why I
did and they mention your course of
action and then just keep discipline and
record but making you remember is no
matter what this is not wasted time
security will manage
that being said what you choose to go to
security you're sort of artificially a
spy you have to consider operational
security immediately so why I mean by
that is you had to seek out the people
in your field that can help you figure
allies it would be beneficial to you
people that will be realistic and
assessing you they may become be people
outside and they probably should be
people though that were supportive of
your goal they notice Ellsbury Oprah but
just as the positive people are very
realistic they may be a surprising area
some of the people have benefited me or
people I was really not expecting there
are those that will never cease to see
them and they are different reasons I
think there's a bunch of ego in this
field sometimes and there's competition
and some people in your team just may be
afraid of losing so you have to keep it
on the down-low I was surprised to find
the self only took me over 40 years
- out but some people find knowledge
competitive didn't know there was real
surprise so just be aware of that
I do recommend learning someone is
secret not fully I like didn't actively
pull those employees and share with your
allies what you're doing yeah but you
just does this mean what Eric told me
not to say anything so there's this
support call they're talking about
networks I would say a map I barely see
anything
no definitely demonstrated knowledge but
you just don't have to tell everyone
everyone in Stein security guys see you
suckers later he plasters because you
don't know where the semantic you I
don't know if my colleagues know but I
was actually really hope that I want to
be able to look to you which is Pat
hilarious if you know me because I
really don't belong MIT so keep your
options open you don't want to bid to
one pound and that people hold you to
all right so let's talk about how we
start down the path we have to do one of
the hardest things ever we just will
along in i hate humans but is the only
way to do it and you have to determine
your account areas these are things that
if you're in
a job you know how develop if you're a
developer to you know networking do you
know how the internet generally works do
you know any scripting languages like
the pure of Python program have you
worked on that or vice versa if your
windows how much Linux exposure do you
have anything of my spiritual Nautilus
thing you have to learn all these right
away and you don't need know all your
doubts right away but you should at
least be realistic and sesame maturing
what you're missing then you need a
crate repository to be a one music
whatever it is and your first page and
swipe down those kinds what you need and
start being editor them then put your
nose - please buy how do you find those
camps the areas that you're missing well
I talked to several people in empo
psychic about Holly found their their
knowledge there's a different way to do
a list of all of you
okay I'm sort of like my own names but
the college meant a lot of times it
started out and college and recent
liberal arts you don't end up in the
major you think you did
so people go in and say you know I think
I'm gonna be English radio they take the
first etymology classes like that's
that's where I belong so what they're
doing is they're sampling a lot of
information and finding out what is in
those centers in space there's the
exploratory method finding something you
don't know at all and making that full
probably really exploring it in debt you
can ask for official training but it's
kind of hard to go too hard you get this
is usually in people's panic they're
interested in it was sick as for
training they're denied they give up
don't let that be you there's an
official training though and that's
really easy to require and I'll show you
how do you fight so let's talk about
that you have the college method one
thing I did is I'm a big book reader I
know not everyone is there's a whole
bunch of folks that using it and I
recommend she become very familiar with
Mountain Sports Half Price Books has all
the certifications most the people have
gotten rid of and have given up on and
they are great if you wanted to get it
into the security they're there for like
nine dollars I was there
two days ago and there's a bunch of them
out there occasionally you see big-name
books like nmap or menace plate over the
web hacker's handbook all good choices
but syrupy can be familiar with that
hacking expose if you guys see many more
gigantic book about actual hacks how
they were done and help prevent them if
you find yourself forgiveness you'll
find out wow I actually really enjoyed
this this is a great mentioning this was
like is a little bit old but I think it
was $8 at Half Price Books either way at
your library if I dinero eBay is worth
it will give you a very clear idea of
what you're missing also check your
corporate library I'll mention this
again a lot of corporations have
libraries that are free and available
and - of these molds pregnant I'll
mention them morning
podcast I would start podcasts
immediately if you're slightly
interested today start finding out that
you can I like risky biz but everyone
here is opinion security now is a good
choice down the rabbit hole and it's a
really annoying intro but you can really
have some really good stuff in this the
SS Koran you can find some people have
their opinions if you're a video learner
which I try to be crazy that some people
really go well with that think about
weaponize that's Jeremy Durance site I
guess all sorts of things from
application security to encryption
all sorts of things Samy Kamkar gets rid
of them is that a hacker that will talk
about Wired about how things have been
taken for these cars
you know things guy he's a really good
one to kind of follow because you can
pick up about half away says when you
first start out like well some of the
things also it's a really good hack five
there may try to sell you the gadgets
but they have a really good whether or
not women are really sort of program
it's really highly produced but it gives
you some really good ideas of what's out
there
go ahead to buy anything to learning and
what's good about them is they actually
will cover
the main thing is to find something you
can research daily and find resistance
now the exploratory one we're going to
go into like finding a full knowledge
about some particular topic that maybe
you don't know I'm a gadget rippin love
gadgets I'll talk about gadgets all day
always find options that you can build
instead of body so there's a there's a
ton of things out there right now for
you that you can look forward for free a
portable fireball is a great option
Raspberry Pi and there's so many choices
they're open wrt or about tomato if
you're not familiar that with that that
will flush your router and make it into
some new Arduino there's just so many
choices Mulder that you can explore is
there any price will be an interesting
find out there's a gadget you can make
and do it if you have no idea if I'm the
engine with a bunch of these you know
Levi's I don't even know where to start
look at hacker box hacker boxes is good
i subscription service you don't have to
subscribe and there were around 60 or 80
dollars each and they have all these you
need to do some sort of gadget project
and there's utilized six or seven things
in them includes things like physical
pen testing so you can pull box black
base rfid mean so you can make your
alarm system and bypass it I think
there's some wireless one out there and
USB enhances all sorts and the
restrictions are pretty good so there's
really good place to start if you don't
want your gadgets develop if you've
found that you really like in people
have created so many wrong them there's
no reason for you want to do one just so
you dilute it though
the idea is just the best that I'm into
yourself now so you can learn more and
more no I want apologize to you on this
one because there's gonna be a night if
you do this you're really going to hate
me really really sorry because it's like
that you'll have that moment where it's
like I am so frustrated I could not
figure this out why did you send me down
this road now I'm a dad I'm about to say
a damn thing that frustration is a gift
it really does help you because my
portable firewall project I've listed
here I absolutely hated every moment of
it I use everything
today which is crazy that's why it could
never be nil because I wasn't willing to
do this and you have surely obtain real
demonstrable skills let's talk about
working projects so here's a portable
firewall I like this one a lot because
it's a gadget you can get you are here
if you go to a hotel you know the people
can listen in to your traffic you're
certain about people into your devices
especially after when she ran upstairs
the portable firewall I will do is you
can hook it into an Ethernet or into
Wi-Fi for the hotels rather and will
protect a nasty traffic from Union you
also can be can out through it and what
you're doing is you're buying a $30
router flash unit and programming with
all this additional stuff what you
different is networking does anyone
really good at networking you yeah so
good then we're getting if you don't do
it this is a great place for it if
you'll need them learn about VPN and
certifications or certain certificates
for your later working security this is
a great place to learn about Linux if
you've got any exposure this is very
gentle intro any day Ganges business a
dropbox dropbox is uh I really like
they're very James Bondy the use of just
will be device plug into eight and you
can waltz into a target plug it into the
routers with permission and it would
dial back to your home box and send out
all the information you want or maybe
use it as a way to get foothold into an
organization you get even boilies you
get more networking but you also get
exposure to things like encryption a
bunch of the tech tools and you get a
gadget element this is worth the time
and you start collecting edges my whole
or is you know me you're going
to promise eight you're saying buy
everything an egg fine now right no they
make it way too easy
find something right now that makes it
where you actually have to work it out
and then after you do something really
and you feel really good about where you
are on the security world you said
cutting edges to reward yourself
by government security boss about my
payment now official training you can
ask for it but if we were literally
building bosses moved though the budgets
kind of assist your listings chance of
success you may not get the clutch you
want you may sign up for a sim class
find out you're selling in a SQL manager
developers course so be aware you may
not get what you want
you also may be questioning lot or
detoured or pigeonhole you said you were
going to be blue tea here if you blue
team from now on you don't want that you
don't want this to be your only Avenue
I do think other paths are more fruitful
because you get apply things at your own
pace you get to do things that you want
and maybe if you're exploiting Idaho for
is it and you say this isn't for me you
can yourself say I'm done with forensics
I'm moving on you have flexible the
unofficial training and this is
something I really was excited to tell
you this it's often available to you
right now
I bet almost every one of you when you
go back to your job and look on your
internet you're going to see our product
is sold to almost every corporation for
a university or emailed library this is
often free it's often realizing
sometimes it's nearly always rarely news
it really like four points that you can
find including in men men display
Wireshark is all probably there you have
the same product
you'd be surprised what's there a lot of
times of certification courses for free
there are on video courses that won't
prep people for certification if you
want a free option here's your free
option and go ahead and use it as I said
no one even needs to know that you've
done it I'm not that you're trying to be
a little super stealthy about it but you
don't have to answer to anyone you can
use possibilities there are also lots of
free online options have you look like a
ocean for a lot of people Corriere is a
google web application security training
nothing that's one destroy element hiker
box is a good capture the flag but those
are some
signups for a security webinars now like
Hills have a great webinar recently
where they're actually be needed putting
together a card game based on different
security promise did you guys hear about
that World War two thing where they had
silhouettes and planes on the plane
apply planes while we're just playing
really this is the same idea you're
playing a game you saw accidentally
learning about all sorts of security
products really good idea they're going
to make me bill them I think this month
but you wouldn't know about them less
you can sign up for their security of
webinars we start doing to know inside
the frozen Asian yeah there's a whole
bunch out I got me a commercial but join
Issa if you haven't it's a really good
place to connect professionals and you
learn about all sorts of stuff but I
just presented web application security
just students find inner of relay
communities anyone here familiar with
the InfraGard good course your argument
InfraGard is that you guys outreach who
wouldn't want to be part of the FBI's
outreach I love being able to go there
and say sorry boss I gotta go so it's a
really good one you guys do
really recommended in this route but we
have time to tell you something so this
one about now nearing your question
really making it where you really
understand and get marketable skills you
can really apply in did you something
and during the first interview
here's your day at the window where you
just had enough here's your foundation
for about six months give or take for
your exploring in your learning the rest
of the six months is going to be finding
that right fit
finding a way to take what you've
learned really find what suit suit you
even apply those to so you should have a
general idea of what you kinda like
maybe you found compliance right blue
team secure development just we're going
to take that and sharpen to real old
skills six months though seems long
right unless a disease
but you want to know that if you're
making a career change if you're
actually thinking about going into one
of these areas you want to meditate on
to make sure you're making more anything
you don't want to find yourself in it
and then you've gotta go well this is
nobody will expect you want experience a
little bit but your mileage may vary you
may decide the right teacher meeting
jump right in so somebody on your team
chances alarm has something they want to
get rid of right now it is security
related every development
I have been on in every development team
on familiar road I have people that have
these items and they would throw a party
for you if you took any one of those
using greeting there they're all
security related security remediation
most development team teams do not want
anything to do with it this is
continuity operational readiness you
want to see a bunch of people run out of
room screaming just mention operational
readiness firewall in one like firewall
condition not really but it's a great
weight on the security practitioner was
a security practitioner someone's paying
security action of their daily job these
are all security jobs even if you're not
going to be have an official InfoSec job
title you now have experience in it when
I was adaptive I took out all business
continuity and people couldn't give it
to me fast enough and it was great
because I was able to study for my fence
at the same time and good to practice
why I'd learn and I didn't like that it
misses continuity before I went to
security as I said earlier I really
liked it once I was actually able to put
mine parts into place so yes
recommended they'll take you out to
lunch you should have them take you out
to lunch to kiss a male sex with women
if I hesitated presentation
opportunities you know here's the thing
I don't actually want to saying a lot
spider but it's a great way to minister
your students and also learn a lot in
the process and if you're starting out
this a good way to establish yourself as
an expert at least in your team related
to your job fold-in security but that
doesn't have to maybe talk about why
place maybe you could talk about fishing
they're things that they will find
useful the great thing is that everybody
wins
you become the expert those painful
things are taken away the company minds
anyone so it's a win all the way around
really great thing to do keep creating
also while my colleagues propose a
moment later okay
says that the best currency you can
carry it's given that gift back to it in
the innocent so a series a Nemecek nil
find a github project you can contribute
to there's a whole bunch of them they
don't have them on all codes some of our
project plants some of them are ways to
make each engine some just lists so
start giving them make up your own
gadgets and projects and posting a
tribute Arctic article you didn't it
your brave answer own security second
change though I wouldn't man doesn't
mean but you know I'm gonna work for you
oh you can volunteer your time I would
be careful on that isn't this so anyone
heard about what's going on with coal
fire right now hope I'm missing anything
this is a group that does auditing and
fantastic they are real pros because
they really know what they're doing if
you will on it you know you're going to
cross your T's don't you guys and these
guys broke into eight with a good
statement work signed off other
authority we're going to a courthouse as
part of the bendi reserving this broke
into a corner the defendant unlocked it
acted like it wasn't locked in the first
place
Pro can waive for the police when they
self alarm intentionally show the police
alert equals a sheriff who was
responsible for the for house didn't
like that arrested model even though
they had a statement word signed off
correct authority these guys knew what
they were doing I say that only is a
word of money because if you're first
starting out is easy to miss few things
you may want to be careful how you
volunteer your time so don't say hey
guys guess what I'll bring it to your
billing just give me a signature I would
recommend that right up but there are
things you can do if you find the
opportunity
volunteer history I have a estrous here
you'd be surprised how many people do
done don't know so pick it up the very
day you stop it you know you already
have an engine we'll still other people
I talked to several team members and
colleagues to do bug movies this is an
option you can get real money and real
knowledge and real experience I
recommend working for a company gives
you a better shield from liability a lot
of times the issues are found a me and
it's going to be hard for you to be one
of those people find those big issues
might be a bit frustrating I actually
tried to do this myself I really wanted
and Omega watch so I'm like not just for
that weekend read my guns
so this is why I do my daily job send
you reports to companies some of them
have hidden and their terms of service
hey we take bug movies it's usually
woman but stay within their scope and
delivery carefully some good if you
decide this into a company hey I found a
security issue be very careful how you
do that some do not respond well to the
fullest of reports so I'm saying be
careful with this be careful that mature
security you're going to be sometimes a
professional also I really do recommend
gain a basic certification well I've
talked to people in project management
they asked joining the project and
dissertation I usually say well what's
your experience have you done it then
naveen on these days with agile maybe
maybe possibly development I think it's
a certifications needed I don't I do
insecurity Elise's we did for a couple
reasons
no it's probably going to be if you're
in for the center of I'd probably might
be while your gate follower islands but
punky ia offers well the security and
and has plants addled load hops this
with less expensive injury and what's
great is you don't need to take a course
two passes I took my security plus
entirely on at price quotes and modules
and ease is it easy test is not if you
don't know anything about security you
you're first learning is gonna be a
challenge but it's worth it and you it
will prove to yourself that you've done
it and it will show to others you're
serious about this school your creeper
knowledge and you're so sorry you better
money the resultant security plus
insurable Wallace ice party I still have
my Mullen size card because I love
adjustments me so much dude so the
result is you have real work in your job
taking all the good stuff that people
don't want outside contributions at the
bus roll knowledge at gadgets
development maybe you want you may be
certified the other way if you interview
now we'd want to talk to you but with
these kind of things because it really
shows that you're interested Jeremy said
recently I I don't know how any of us we
have found it was like we were fully
qualified exactly so we're trying to
make up you could be a person that shows
a passionate about this field and shows
us your names I'll get you the right way
and also it'll don't very quickly also
on one of my team members
thanks to this so it was a pregnancy
solar pump and she was absolutely right
so let's talk about measuring success is
seen how where you are as a year point
you're probably doing a lot better and
they think you are
but we listen to podcast where you read
books are you completely lost when
people rental horns really don't know
what that's about
or do you like make sure you keep you up
to date I understand what's going on man
do you feel underwater or do you feel
like you're kind of swim you don't have
to be perfect did you feel like you're
still going on them carry a logician
from some of your allies that's why I
think honest good allies are great if
you still tell you you're full of it but
you know have them telling you for you
here's what I'm doing then we'll say I
think you're doing this oh you should do
this next the key is to keep finding
those camps though and continue to
practice the most points fun and non fun
and I say this this is important to
revisit what you felt defusing initially
go back because you might find that
wasn't or isn't nil I didn't Google rare
tree
it was completely must have application
and it's question I revisited after
about the eighth month so that's why
they're dense so definitely your slug
need also need an edge result are you
still in thews or is it just split as I
say that everyone was amused by your
fortune yourself to es5 and really
that's not been you it's okay if
something doesn't fit you you can
actually make it in that you're not
wasting your time everything is
cumulative so even if you learn about
stuff that isn't in your your area
this will main help you later if you
decided that you want to be blue team
insight and I don't really wanna be blue
team okay you're renting well guess
what's going to help you a lot a lot of
knowledge about what the blue team is
also there's this thing where you
suddenly become your job not really just
do your job whether was in app dev I was
a very very good developer I was very
good project manager that was my day job
I did not know if a booked on the
weekend I definitely didn't want to talk
about it later and there's just exhaust
in the TV box I am a InfoSec
practitioner anyone that knows me knows
I really doesn't breathing constantly on
the vacation of the two projects peeler
my Savior wants to do that simply I've
always he thing going on there you end
up doing a lot of it you read about it's
was it interesting to you so if you're
still find this quite exciting today you
should also maintain the super spy
secret agent offset of I mean by that is
you don't want to show up even though
it'll be so tempting the first vlog
that's picked that first exploit the
first web app if you're a ham radio
operator and I know I'm dating myself by
saying if you have a radio operator you
don't tell her when you're in hand
because anytime someone has their TV
goes slightly won't meet they're gonna
blame you I tell people I do now which
I'm still having them struggling the
best way to tell people is if I say I'm
a professional hacker they'll
immediately check their wallet which I
find hilarious is like physical test I
wouldn't be able to do that but some
people just really
so just be careful keeping the family
about what you're doing do take a
picture though your first exploit I took
pictures of mine stolen and you know
this time is probably good kinda share
with your manager my active manager was
shocked to find out why I ended doing
and at that point is like where I'll end
it soon there you go
place it on the resume and it was great
at least at the very minimum for their
reaction so deadly moments of that take
a picture of that - you guys say stuff
of them and as you go on don't rest
we've reached our golden right so you're
in keep movin aboard you have to keep
that continued self investment I've been
in this field for a long time I remember
visual basic one in visual basic one
said your control since you got here a
bunch of toys at toy box wasn't true but
you can make your InfoSec toys really
have you seen you just said to make your
work fun
so wave comes live in your knowledge
forward continuing to continually find
what you don't know
just recently I'm Brady on an Android
phone
they wanted as rid of their Android code
let me know if you live in trouble but
constantly fighting with the Fisher
board and find ways to play at work
I wasn't DMV guy by understand that
there's a magic user right that has to
read a spell book every so often they
keep the spells up is that right the DG
people come on we're in fo sec there's
gotta be someone here Monday what's a
day no the thought was what's the thing
well it's sort of the same wood thing
but you don't have to do absolutely
everything but you do want to do another
skills off your oughta because this
study adventure probably really on post
with you conferences casera bomb going
into a conference maybe on your own
vacation and maybe something you need
for I went to Def Con last year it was
paid for by me and it was definitely
worth it and I guess hit a green cane
which was awesome
and you can serve areas a lot going
things and it looks like you might not
now also you get to connect see what
other people are doing and you get to be
a lot of people are in your also at this
point you have a proven record for a
year you have knowledge in hopeful team
you've taken on operational readiness
this might be the time to take one of
those points in your managers say how
that you pay for that one-day conference
for me to go maybe not maybe not apply
it now but maybe something like D size
also customized look for the right fit
your community like Issa point you in
the right way but you can look inside
your own company when I was on DVD on
another story I was assigned temporarily
to a team that required project
management management person was able I
came in there as someone had understood
the technology so I was assigned to it
for six months then they started looking
for they didn't know the name I think
I'm gonna call it security evangelist
may be a security champion I am not
known to go to classes and bosses pastas
and pastas bosses bosses and saying
you're not going to find anyone else in
your organization if you do like you do
pictures of the experience who's going
to you you need meaning and the I've
never done the kind of before they gave
me my attorney push the other person
aside does they weren't actually very
good security and I decided not that
team bad parts about the team and that
was definitely a good part so I would
definitely I got stood up pain Taylor
Swift on my presentations I just
realized that she has been in every
single presentation I've so sorry about
that you see there were going to be
people that aren't going to tell you
right off you aren't gonna belong here
there's a lot of video and I've said
this on the earlier slide I definitely
experienced it myself
David people told me hilariously if
you're a developer you have no business
insecurity which is funny because we
want people that are developers their
experience in those other areas so is
people have experienced people
so today you're here showing interest in
security you're committed to security in
the future therefore you're grading
security in the extra so keep moving
toward your goal and you're funny to do
that no I know a lot of you guys are
InfoSec people but just in case you're
not today you're deputized fully you can
become ugly call yourself a enthusiasts
and Vangelis champion if you actually
are doing it right now and you don't
actually have the title guess what
you're a security practitioner again the
practitioner someone between security
into place so start moving you or listen
to podcast and they say this is for
security practitioners worldwide that's
for you I want badges for everyone
minded know how many people live
spensive sorry so bad but you know it's
pretend bitch telling people that you
got different eyes 2019 anyone else's
says you don't belong is completely
wrong so just to revisit what we're
talking about it be humble invest in
yourself do the hard work but really the
key thing is finding in Jordan and find
ways to play where you can actually do
security
don't get stuck in the hairball it's
really easy to do that well you I
understand the basketball players be
upset with others because somebody makes
it less familia me look person this case
stick it in your balls that true but
smart phones don't work well big fan of
a hopeless bangle spin that's why I told
people I don't know what so so it works
it's amazing how that works but seek
opportunities that you can apply your
special skills if you aren't enjoying it
we sit yourselves a recharge it's really
important that this is one of those few
investments that you can put time in and
you're an echo through a wave once
you've learned it's not like a visi on a
framework this it's not like the child
learning couch pages showing that maybe
no face will be used maybe one
everything you use the security will
only bump yourself up that much weird
that's right so here's my contact
information you can take a picture of
this like this is my personal address
I'm also reached
st. crossbones at gmail.com I would
explain why Saint cross but some other
time look for my github I have all sorts
of programs out there I'm just posting a
if you want to make your own shark Jack
you can't
I think heck I found it it may put us on
their own pillows as their own can't
believe it so I'm heavy is there any
questions you guys have at all yes
please on the github account do you
suggest it be public or hidden because
if you can think of something that
somebody else hasn't thought of then
everybody will copy it and then you
won't be unique it's a good question so
should you have a github I'll answer two
ways I would possibly do both but I had
before cuz we've seen a github or
someone was paying what they were
learning and they were clearly not
learning anything dangerous for them if
you have your own idea then you probably
don't want to post it the reason my
company owns my penance as I was dumb
enough to open my mouth I'm glad I got
in the Porta so I know I can't pass up
for the things that you think are
beneficial if you didn't Street
neurology definitely even if you are
giving away ideas that's okay this is
good currency for you and it spells out
how much money am I going from this
versus this benefit me show my that's my
sure I don't know if you have internet
connection but in our info guard meeting
they talked about a national membership
that was like $100 or $65 and it
includes benefits if you have time to
pull it up to see free yeah it's like a
national and as opposed to the chapter I
did not bring up my something new
yeah you guys didn't hear that regards
100cc
no at 65 200 I can't remember it there's
three levels
so go out find out how to join the
International Africa chapter well it's a
national
let's go for that any other questions at
all oh I used to have a zombie do enjoy
Gribble's survey certificate from the
FBI so thank you eric jackson for your
participation in Hispanic cultural
heritage month and I know people walk by
zli very spanning what's going on then
it's uh I had an FBI training
[Music]
certifications so for in the DoD world
you're wanting to like just basic level
information security your Karma's gonna
be security at least security plus right
exactly yet I told about the mission of
so glad you said that
right so DoD does required security plus
no pickup and a lot of other government
jobs so the zoo well weren't your
investment right because you already
have it right the demonstrator yes I
just wanted to say and the only problem
I've had with cyber area is Mount emails
that you get to try and elevate your
free membership into a career getting
tons of that that's what we have Outlook
rules right
yes trying to the tarnish learn those
are your opportunity I'll talk to you
have good thoughts of it or the talk for
the DoD I've also heard that they really
prefer what network admins who want to
learn security and get the security plus
because the explanation was you have to
know
what it is you're protecting that's true
but see the thing is like that's why I
really think you need to be well-rounded
because if you're a developer when
focusing on a development
you've never wicked networking most of
the developers I've worked at but never
deserved it
they would never give you I say this
block if you want to see something
really funny as your lead developer what
messages and they'll just look for water
so like um you should seriously be real
fun but you don't have to be just that
in order to get a security you can as
long as you know general areas because
what's one of the best ways to get into
a corporation is through their web and
there might be projects with us that if
you want to be a developer that never
security to work on I shouldn't mention
at once yes any other questions alone I
will offer if you guys