I
it %uh
no idea how long this takes to go
through because I refuse to practice
stuff
so you just Hugo up so my disclaimer
which I decided I had to start doing
because everybody else that I'm but they
didn't because it was like you know
my company doesn't feel the same way in
that's bullshit my company feels the
same way cuz I run it a
I we know my disclaimer is that out
are probably be me and if you don't like
that
or how I talker the words that I use
sorry
there's a door and you can totally use
it and I'm more defender of
I because you guys got me up this
morning
and a and wanna get up
obviously to give some presentations on
where
right so as a base
I am gonna so air probably at some point
and other marketing try and make it
real bad thing in it I'm a drink at
probably throughout the whole thing
are that today but well I'll start
taking just after the exxon a great for
me
I up try to Fuego anybody I
is like the interracial self you live as
I you control me it's all good like it
rolled I think it's fun
I playback so just be prepared for us to
both have a really awesome time and
everybody else left
you um K
so its cool whatever you guys like you
know
I'm doubt so and Chris I
that's me and also it's a different ways
right
my Mike gradual slide that everybody's
seen before
now on a whatever it doesn't matter what
the hell I've done like
who cares and i got really oh you
weren't the discovery
FM only been I mean you might get might
be a better way to do it
up so that's kinda other stuff
about me I guess when you get to have
their lovely slides a
you know all that said they're typing on
shit I didn't put PJs I don't try to put
a
hike either arm and beyond all that I
really like my job
I love it I love it so much that I made
a graphic about how much I love my job
cuz is awesome up
I get to work with some other cause
people like if you're fun conferences
like this and learn shit all the time
and like you know team to a lot of work
officials talking about like I have this
weird
brand new appreciation for my job that I
never had before because I'd
I'd I wasn't ever going out to be famous
on Sunday at one point I thought it was
cool that like
they made a shitty TV show The Fillmore
me know if I can awesome now that you're
a loser you to feel TV show
don't talk about that shit any arm
know but but I just really love it I get
to the display all day long in me
really interesting people and and you
know we're we're like
the the the craziest therapists on the
planet we bring a laptop and we go
through all these all things show movies
but buttons and numbers all its tough
new like yeah he'll feel so said
or like oh you may be so sad I'm happy
arm
this is cool right so I just have to
express how much I love it
okay sources about so I II and also the
weird part 04
side get cited and have some closure my
life and give
some talks about fun things that I
really like to do
that I always just going to get show on
something because
as easy as it may be to get
sequel maybe easy to get
some random box that you know everyone
has 0806 events
out somewhere and some machine they just
couldn't you know a patch for whatever
reason is but
how love people like I love them so much
that I really like get all abilities
stuff
I like looking at their stuff I look at
the stuff other peoples that they look
there
a look at the stuff that they look at
that they don't want people aka I love
it
Lake is really fun to see the things
that someone
interacts with behind a closed door when
they think nobody's watching you'll do
weird shit
I know I do weird shit you to be super
weird stuff as well
and I'm not just saying that cuz I don't
know
I'm sayin its we're and when people do
weird stuff you find out a lot of cool
things about them
like but their passwords are because
they do really really weird something
like no one's gonna know
my password is this the furry 7 in a
home-like
I am the big up get it it
so alright we'll talk about surveilling
people
right in corporate surveillance and and
I want to start this kind at a high
level
I because it's easier and because you
guys may need to do this and get to
you know probably after this first piece
to really scare the shit out of some
executives before they're like
yes so you're not allowed to use the
internet again
and however wanna see your graphs and
maps just get the out
but also pay you because I know you go
of stuff so what do you do when you look
at corporate
companies right you want to break them
down
right boiling the ocean is really hard
to do when I say I wanna do
intelligence-gathering
on XY and suspect
it's gonna take a lot I mean there's a
lot of stuff out there
like I I'm not gonna be utopian industry
logo checkers are right I prince was
buried went there now have all the names
now I know everybody's stuff
know you just know they're stupid like
the name you know anything about
so wanna go break it down to employees
were partners they have
competitors adversaries that they have
adversaries really good to know
by the way because before you start
surveillance
this is like the you're not supposed to
tell people so
do this surveillance on their
adversaries
figure out how the adversaries work and
then when you're doing your surveillance
pic is ever catch you
think them knaves Cal leave you alone
the black bear
damn them our competitors will get them
and then you start the corporate
intelligence weren't feeling both in pay
condom on I'm not saying if you do that
it's cheap a home but you want to get
stuff rights we gotta start thinking
about what what we get Hadley break this
down into little groups
and have we monitor piece a little group
we find things that are fun
and we find that are fun because we're
all a TD in some way shape or form
we go all shiny any play with a shiny
thing to get more than up shiny in
another category
ages drop shiny atop your little buckets
and the other they have a whole bunch
because we need stuff legal
call what my own you look your bucket so
whatever looks funny good things
that this is this is the you know big
boys and soldiers gather
of so I do you find stuff right hoover's
is great for businesses that give you
all sorts of stuff like you know what
the person made the year before
are you know like the people who made
salary cuz you know they're so the vice
chairman is just such a good guy only
takes for their salary but he also had a
seventy thousand about us
know it's that's cool are
a wide you can see also to make stuff
we start mapping out the business see
how this is operates but also give you
all sorts of
meet fun once you get to a point
attacking people cuz you're gonna know
the company
you be able to name drop all sorts of
stuff
I mean hell if you getting to the point
I love
James roars financials I'm sure there's
something shady and some that he is but
somewhere
where you be like look James I know you
mean one point
you know 169 231 million dollars last
year but
the night that you spend forty seven
thousand dollars at Secrets
it's not a secret but so we have to talk
about how
it becomes the stays a secret okay
now I'm kind of a visual person so I
like market visual
which is really good they also do some
interesting analytics around
how people work together on the market
arm
seriously I i have lost hundreds of days
of my life to the stupid grafton I love
exactly comida
combos up in something else or why are
they connected the ponies click click
click click in the Internet has sucked
me in
but try and stay on track it's very hard
and one thing I do you like about that
as you can get mappings all the entities
export them
I'm so then what are the tools we talk
about later you can start in Philly
dated
that I mock
marks really awesome I'm good I'm lucky
that com
it's another really interesting business
and House website
again I'm telling you all these states
only do the same thing
they are different because they have
different data sources up
recently on Tony
arm recently I was doing some fun Intel
stuff in there wasn't enough
about a particular company so
I filed some issuance grievances with
the Better Business Bureau about like me
not being able to do my due diligence
to get the information you needed about
who they were partnered with and how
their business operates all that stuff
so third Better Business Bureau went in
there like okay well we need to get your
records and all they certainly spend no
back to records were
out-of-date thank you for bring us up to
us we've refresh the database
like whatever
where do I find the Refresh Cup oh well
there's this other site
that if you use that we actually have a
tie to called
Corp wiki arm which I think I have
around here somewhere
Corp we keep all state data so what I do
I type in a person's name the next day
all the sudden magically the frog art
char appears all this stuff
now pitted the person did a really good
job at
making their intelligence private
because they paid some people of two
you know forget them in the Refresh but
all you have to do is ask the government
authority to refresh that because it's
their job to protect you and it's your
job to do due diligence
you know the information just falls from
the sky sometimes
um lil sis is awesome because lil sis is
actually
Ron with centralize pieces of data
and then the user community inside a
full-service
starts to attach things to it so what
you start to see that everybody who's
pissed at that company ever
starts dropping docks and better to this
because they want people to be like
they're a bad company and you have all
the pita people all the Intel people
that they paid to Khaleej information
still databases and shit like that
just dump it in Lincoln on here its
awesome
and they do it you know I'm just
anonymously helping the world oh you're
purposely screwing someone but I need
the information so I don't care
hit alright Lake then
have whatever point kidder's arm jigsaws
awesome
you values jigsaw before
aged it's just a huge vicious sales
database
love your name your tight all your email
address your mail stop your phone number
so that the sales people can be like 0
they just got a budget for firewall in
your firewall company pay me 5 grand
I'll give you their phone number and
tell you whether you need to buy
something
they're horrible in your team better
about it is that
Salesforce bottom so now they have
everybody's phone number
and their sales force is doing although
the resource planning everything else so
they know when the new budget comes in
there like ok or other spam these people
who are spammers that's a firewall
have all call I don't think it's a
coincidence that these people who happen
to call you when you need it
hey it its cool
like uses that mean how awesome is that
you get to be like you know I'm a fire
offender I know your budget
why its cuz just I I'm I get much done
with it like I
I'm here for you to protect you buy
stuff
it I idk usually it's a it's an older
microsoft project still does really well
way that they built it they actually
built it so that you can automate
the creation of somebody's bio by
publicly available sources
think how cool that would be if you want
to watch someone
show me all the stuff click yea at
so once we've started to whittle down
the people that leak too much
intelligence
right those are obviously the ones we
have to go over cuz we don't want to
challenge ourselves we just want to do
the easy things get paid
at are so we gotta look at those people
she look at some other things than the
people right who they are
what they do why they do that stuff
how it's pretty simple
yeah you know inside those you have the
WHO and you can find out stuff about
them or talk about who in
and you know who are they so these are
all
again super automated way is to find out
who someone is
you can go to blame checker you could go
to one of those places and you could
take an email address
and partial against 400-plus different
sites
and find out where they also have
accounts even those accounts don't have
the awesome
security settings the Facebook Hosur
baby they do
offer you know maybe there are the
somehow site that doesn't protect
anything about their profile and runs
phpBB that hit single injection
you just happened to go over by accident
are
and why they doing that like what what
what are they doing once they
exist in this internet love hours
is out there arm and ways to find out
the people
like what they're doing and how they're
doing it there's social networks right
that's the whole purpose of social
network is you make some identity and
then you tell people I poop dinner like
your your bootable
do it we're totally the same in lower
different countries are like yeah it's
awesome
like you get out here from
so be aware of looking at their media
landscape
where they talk the most widely talked
the most their
I these things are really important if
you're trying to bag tag somebody
you know if if I'm actively watching in
the day her the day that I wanna go
after the target cider I wanna go plant
bugs in the house and things like that
I need to have heads up display all the
places that they talkin who they are
running real time so that when they're
like oh I forgot my key gotta go back
home that sucks hahaha I'm like yes it
does
ok you know hope
clean up my shit I
so you right I've already talked about
10 terabytes information on someone
right that you're trying to parse err
CF to come get down to little bit
knowing them this is where
in the subject you wanna actually become
the subject to rate you spend your law
you know chill out load Jessup you like
and Jeff Bridges white Tron shit you
just sit there in like
meditate figure out how can you
manipulate this person
who they are right I need to go into who
they are
I know that they went to the school
here's my perceptions about people
the school in what happened I do there
in this fraternity and i know that
I'm similar to them in these in these in
these ways so I can start to come to get
into that character I know that their
this race I know that there's this
religion and I know that
you know they believe in their religion
this with this much this is how their
parents operate this is how they are
this other sisters are
here's the candid nature their
conversation between this person versus
the professional nature here
can I have the professional conversation
going to have a candid conversation
right you get into that because what
that's going to do is it's gonna start
to see you have a see the world
and by looking at how they see the world
which is the most accurate picture the
world of course because it's theirs
you're gonna start being able to figure
out where they drop things that you did
you have on your first search
right you're gonna know that if they use
religious passwords
a bank give them that are most likely
you're gonna know that
if they have superstitions about
something
if all you have to do is you know steel
a black cat out of alleyway and throw
that will bastard industry
in order for them to turn their car
around and go another direction because
they're afraid to cross the road
you get to really control that person
and when they're of their game they're
not doing what they would normally do
they screw up
when they screw up we went
yeah arm
you know how far you from Kevin Bacon
you wanna find people's connections
Google will tell you
if I can type in your name and bacon
number it'll tell you how many
connections that you have
until you get to Kevin Bacon now it
doesn't tell me between me and my target
but something to think about how does
that play a
K everybody wants to see this
everybody wants to know this every
social network in the world wants to
know how close you are to somebody else
because the closer they can get you
together the more value they're
providing you and the more likely you
are to like given money or toys R
credits or corns or
forget artichokes or whatever the hell
they make money on
that mapping the relationships
now we have an idea of who they are we
have an idea
love what they're doing where they're
doing it
who they do it with because may be there
like some hardy go to security companies
all the time super paranoid bubble
bubble bubble bubble bop
but AB their wife doesn't give a shit
about a that stuff
you know like awesome no get her
you'll get close it'll be fine you'll
get it
right so you need to look at these
things need to be able to look at them
like we're standing firm on abilities on
the network
didn't site I'm
wealthy go euros is not a great yeah
awesome
good stuff you'll go to the little
communities an extra page in
good everybody else aside who works on
really dope again serve
you know all there Facebook and that the
plugins all the other neat things
if you haven't visit that page a lot
more than that mean
as its the community's excellent work
um Salesforce aP's use any those
that you people so Salesforce has some
really cool thing right have or chart
is do you guys is that some if you
really got the entire or char
organizations are finding you tell
somebody
Illini like
so the order you like click the company
could or charter
but like me to torture for you that
Google
I inside you is also really need shows
you whose at what position and what
levels in which one of them are willing
to answer questions on things like glass
door and
and other web sites like that arm square
Rio is sales intelligence
so if you can find out the types of
things that you are trying
to look after like like the keywords
that you're searching for
for Twitter that's going to make sure it
hits your feed to know that you wanted
to
do with something their company writer
make sure that
if you were pissed about something that
they would see it of I know what's going
to make
positive that you will click on
something
to see what it's about went I've got
your right they only have
I close my eyes and shoot a bargain I
know it's gonna hate you
is built for you
touch graph any such craft before
showing different types of weighted
relationships by folding in
networks touch grip supports Facebook I
and its kinda half ass supports like
they're not really
but it does um and that it actually
makes
collusion circles to say these people
are very close to each other
these people are close to each other
and my amalgamation of my own is the
you know horrible incestuous security
community and light some
other people I know pic credit
up Facebook's really fun
to do that with because they have
security controls on the security
controls stupid
up have you ever typed someone's name
a question mark and Eagles and somebody
else's name
yeah you know those it brings up a page
completely dedicated how this person
knows this first
that's hot like that's so
like order awesome haha
I have to know how you know this person
no problem just like being
and call look it like really even told
you like when they became friends
has Dexter thank you for securing live
book face I'm
alright lead it has a lead naps to they
make there's always being cool looking
I'm again it auto populates when you
have bigger circles
your information security colleagues in
303 so
again here's why devoted it was like
life is like a random
a hot spring yeah I think some people
from a job I use the word
I but see how these things it as you get
more visuals on these maps
you start to see some really really
interesting stuff
I'm some things that you're looking for
right is your you're looking for
collusion points you looking for who
would be easy target looking for
somebody's outside your target list but
connected to your target they are
looking apt
because they may just legal out more
information is they don't have the same
level back to me and you know that
you know Sally in jester going to a
concert that night but Sally wall post
stuff on Twitter because at one point
she almost got
caught cheating on her husband because
her husband found out things she doesn't
do it anymore
majeste foes all over time and she to
post pictures
up Sally and the dude at concert like
lol its ok look at the making out like
yeah Facebook a home you wanna find
those people right because we need the
track them real time
up so we want to look at how we can
overly and analyze the places that we
felt good information
take that correlate that is something
reasonable arm
I might even go into this consumption
they have now figured out that I'm gonna
give a talk about why adults on these
because it's gonna take five hours but
look up something called low-tech self
and if you've never used it
which how know it is Ray was a really
hurt a bit
that so know XO is a Microsoft thing
and it's all about being able to take
multiple different data points
and create we did pieces of collusion
through importing them all into it so
K so part of this one
was importing them into Excel using a
couple different
data networks being able to now breakout
from those data networks who knew each
other
and then start to whittle down from who
knew each other to
this person know somebody here in know
somebody here but doesn't know someone
here so they go into the circle
this 10 someone here in here but doesn't
know won't hear it here so I don't at
the circle
now I can start seeing alright you know
someone else on five different social
networks but not on this one
so follow official or something like
that obviously I want to use the one
that they're not connected on
and be like yo I just got on this
I know that you know I'm connected to an
every other social networking for your
planet let him just
the no question that with it right right
away
are but also show you some really really
neat things
which you're gonna start seeing about
who they hang out with
way more you're gonna watch the lines
open right
as you're looking at these people in you
analyze these things are visual format
you start to see who they interact with
more
if it's not the one that you thought
then you now know
where to start watching streams
tax rates are coming out like when I did
it at their peak on
and I was checking people that were
connected to Kennedy and
we're taking Twitter in late did a
couple other ones
and I had it mapped the people that were
connected to him
on three out of four social networks
like it instantly pullout
the five or seven targets that work
connected on
on all 54 405 so I can actually some
things
that expense
art such analysis rights now we have all
the stuff that we want to get we know
who's easy to get information from we
know who their best friends are and how
to watch them to or don't have term
now we have to go after because you're
see what the relationship at this
are this is one of my favorite favorite
favorite favorite relationship passive
ever built okay there's the biggest
thing and x-men that this tells you that
no one's ever really willing to tell you
is that Professor X
to find his like or in the middle
somewhere
up sees also you can even find him cuz
he so fuckin irrelevant
it's just it's just so cool so hot
okay at their soap but
like E watery information
if you wanna spread a message to the
x-men about something
you give it to the professor you they
should the beast this is a body of
you give it to over remit everyone now
believes it is truth
he gets to become the bear love your
message so when you swallow start
creating spies in an organization or
leaking intelligence
or saying oh there's this new thing that
you should use because it's really
awesome
go try and directly engage that person
you directly engage the people who are
the head of their spirit
influence which we been able to find
through all the graphic we've been doing
another we have that relationship they
know we only go after that one person
and eventually our target comes to us
me babe or intelligence not
click find copied pasted to report
K you can do that stuff with case file
it's just how you do it
is gonna make sense or not right because
case file in Montego
in all these tools right the over
populate with data so what what
our job is as intel analyst for going
after these things
is the figure out data and cleansing
every single time we do an import
we do import we figure out what we're
using and how we're using it
we scrub everything else around it with
this is mildly important great put it on
my I'll be important folder and get
of your table right now because the more
that you have in front of it
the harder it's going to be for you to
figure out what your targets really are
on you can do that with cell phones also
suffered is anybody play with stockard
that that community made really cool
soho so it starts doing some others
mappings and those types of things for
you
the other cool thing about stalker
stalker I actually plug into some things
like cell phone networks
arm so you can so I figure out who's
talking to who
and then correlating those pieces of
data back to collusion patterns users
have influence
that be convenient to know I don't
associate with you on
any social network whatsoever but I send
you a hundred text messages a day
haha why
how come no one else is both know you
know that for sale what do you do in
arm about dr. sense those guys inside
the same thing
there are a lot more very about it which
I love them for
I me because they're actually using
things like AR drones to create web
access points and use visual target
analysis
in order to fly over the people so they
can continue to be their cell phone
tower and watch them all they all
and then pull that information back in
for Chorley its reports maps
cool you get this stuff I O is James
Bond shit you go by
its awesome get
snake you know you want right so we
gotta go get 'em
you know we are looking right we gotta
get up on that person
know where this remote sending things
that game's done with
ed first we figure out our take out
plans for
John official and a cop rise makes
finally here we can ease on-site attacks
might like
you know start hitting on her best
friend
has had other bets for insist there some
kinda like a path remove my sleep be
around the areas that I need to
up are we gonna go and create other
types of intelligence leaks in the or
find somebody because we did all santo
collection that
is super duper pissed off the company
and then feed them some
evidence because if your intelligence
gathering that gives them what they need
to be
really pissed and then trade them
anger information is an awesome tree
because people are so fired up that they
want to be right
when you confirm that you've listed this
huge weight of their shoulder
and kiss them off so you've got them to
get an excuse to behave
even more poorly but they see it was
like the messiah
truth because you like help you like
like for 10 years I've known this been
going on in finally showed me like
I love you you know like whatever and
you can just get them to do
all sorts of fun stuff for you so maybe
you need to send back the person
get me we've got to the office for Daisy
about other stuff whatever dis
K or you know I yes can read
going through making shell companies
things like that you can actually
attacked the business
something this and arm once you get it
you I have to get in so I put some
things that
and put it all over New updated 18 talks
million I talk about
classes on here I just because if you
get no other info you can copy these two
sides and be like yeah I
when I don't want people home so
you gotta get inside right so you could
do all the you know as the stuff you
like your way and you could dress up
funny
you get kick a door and all that stuff
or you do we usually do which is
electronically get a min ago on that
system and then you're the bad sister
you go and you make yourself a bad turn
you over our bed
they give you a badge right the fact
that
you're in a bad system and like your
pictures and all that shit so white
you're obviously oil company who
accidents
arm and some are going to talk about
those are what you read them
and know how completely ridiculous
opp bag systems are built for security
guards
yeah yeah they're not real complex
if you know I'm sayin the passwords are
not real complex
like the passwords are not real complex
at all K
it how yep this one super awesome
cuz its ERA kinda brings up anyway
little pseudo web interface and you
can't change the database aspect
kitty breaks yeah they told me oh yeah
you
you to change it said I was like I'm all
the manuals them imprinted since like 98
in it that's not true
ok where you have the update manual cuz
you're not a customer Mike
right on dude it your you got it
um even funnier like once you start
looking into one of these are
the two biggest that systems in the
world
they get deployed the most places you
got a 50-50 shot
getting one of these two if you buy the
best up
they have do worse web app all abilities
your ever see
an hour anything about web app so I
can't tell you how to bits with them but
home like to the point of view could
just like slash
write down stuff and get anonymous
access which is valid
but it's a good you access to missus
officers called nonce actors
have a page which I guess they met like
anonymous the crew
like here's how you own it not like
an individual we don't know the lady was
like a gift
of a so when you're doing after you get
that you are also automate finding some
of these things right finding the bad
systems will find
I what port so they're so like you know
go through
take my talk at some point go through
grab all those ports that was talking
about
and look through the network for that
stuff adjust
just touch the box once and you realize
how like old and decrepit
F up is because like the security people
just only type in like
okay no and then they're like you know
chicken scratch nightly reports
up webcams are awesome
and security cameras awesome I mean what
a better place the campout
and watch what their passwords are or
anything else
the wonderful PTZ camera systems where
you can just start learning more and
more and more about the environment it's
not about getting it right now it's
about getting at some point
just archive it watch it hang out like
but consider watching tv watch this is
way more fun
you the interactive it
any so
when you do this just go through script
up really quickly
all the porch or look for got all the
banners there you go take all the Google
dorks from all the cameras
and parse all your banner lot against
the Google dorks so it's like you're
good looking but
its eternal I and your you'll find a bad
system offers like two or three minutes
its its super for arm
alright getting someone's phone
arm so we've all sat there and on like
this under light before
a that makes you look stupid and it
takes time
and then you get it wrong and then your
plants are all over the thing which
kinda extra screws up the whole covert
surveillance
peace so don't do that arm
use wetting agents right that's 14
slippers
do it ch45 is like
four books for a majority you can make
it really even cheaper
arm go to an art store and get the
finest level graphite powder that you
can find
poor dawn Poppe phone just shake the
thing out you'll see this really
distinct pattern
hey if you wanna get the codes of the
alarm system or something like that
don't
hang out the alarm system walk by the
alarm system with a sponge
and putting pied soap on it because
tight has always really cool shit
if it glows if anybody's ever da nasa
because fuhrman
and its just walked by it hang out and
go like this over the keypad
and walk by at some point
because it drives some walk over and
touch the keys in
and then you put a black light up to it
show the work key if they use
easy stuff not reviewed all to you
because you're not touching their crap
K I think take their SD card go to
causes popular help make a freaky
crossover cable
of there's so much stuff that you can do
with it
just kick it when you get physically
next to someone stings
that's when it gets really fun and I
think that's a lot of times the like
pen test the tape community breaks down
because they're like I'm cutting my hair
and likewise it in your hands like
00 does gonna do something with it would
do something like
I can't touch it why could use another
one
just got to shoot me colgo I'm
a ticket like you're allowed to just go
for it
meeting a copy it what you get on there
don't put like
Cherokee let me know if you have to use
minutes late because you like devoted to
you have a tattoo it on your penis or
something
like fine I get it you're sponsored
you know but like in that's nothing to
say that the tool because
that some awesome shit that everyone
should use anyway but
takeover when your key logging like
break
I E so that it kinda does not work
writer mad slow or loads every page nine
times before displays it like this fun
settings for that matter why they exist
arm but then make Firefox fast and super
awesome like do a little
you know faster box or whatever like all
the present weeks and so it kicks ass in
a subtext are used by rocks and then use
like
keylogger editions in Firefox because
then
their AV isn't gonna find it cuz the AV
never looks above
XBIZ of they don't care they just look
at like the browser helper: objects bull
shit like that they don't look at the
fun
cool XBIZ put in their specially finger
right
and now you have a really awesome
keylogger for all the shady bullshit
that they're doing on the Internet like
you know talking in google chat me it's
awesome it's a good thing yes it is
issues it gets past the screen but it's
not good for me
I it's you want to use that stuff let's
just let it sit
Patchett send the ship to your Gmail
want tonight
um if you get impatient you know really
need to do some a buddy is
screen locker is smart water before
it does provide a switch on their just
run smart locker
it lacks the desktop like over my
password timed out
net a backhand you like cool I don't
have to worry about using
any katzer DVD extraction like to all
the crazy hard pinned as the stuff I
just haven't paid it for me
a fairly easy battle a arm don't forget
the obvious stuff
everybody likes to chat with each other
you know digs me is great they got their
password except somebody figured out
exactly how it works and its you know
they've made in the utility to
a cryptic the passwords see you click it
and it goes but
that's worth arm pigeon pigeon is the
best
you got that purple and open in a text
editor that all the fat surgery click
plain text
school good to have
in okie passes is excellent for things
like that
if %uh if you can't get it and they have
some
you know ninja shit running on the
machine don't feel like a free to just
go old school might put a keylogger into
the thing that fine in Windows like
between
askin especially if you look at it and
see dust
you know like weird cookies from the
eighties like other shit back there like
they never go back there anyway just
hide it under the nastiest dirtiest
yucky thing that there is because
wranglers anyway up
enterprises use the hell a key for us
which is awesome
because you know the front end of key
pass
doesn't work really well when you use a
keylogger but everything else is
awesomely gifted
and you know but super duper secure but
key logger who cares yea
i win best passer arm there's also these
other things if anybody starts looking
into them and I
totally and not gonna say anything about
it except for look into them
but these are all the it's like add-ons
the key past so that
you can use KeePass in IE in it
automatically fills your passwords and
for every other website by
taking a master password which in stores
and I for you and
and associating that with the sites and
thus making it like you're single
sign-on
label love thing
and think about that I he has the passer
or being
get a
mmm overlook add-ons right attacking the
third party is almost always the easy
way because the third parties like the
trust thing
and then like it I could be suspicious
upkeep aspin out of this XP I
that it's the Holy Firefox especially if
you find out that the really need that
shit just make one
like and don't let it work and install
soda machine that way
I so yet now it weird
of fun let's also if they always have
probably done in one way shape or form
right
but how are you guys really watch people
because that's the fun part
arm getting geared a lot people's a
blast
you got a first figure out how to hide
now
the the role of hiding anything is
always be in plain sight
the best for all because one you're
gonna get the best information
a2 the last place to work
so like you know hiding a camera
inside have a camera they're not gonna
be like I wonder if there's a camera
that like an ocean there's a camera in
there
it's a camera look and a whole
or I don't know if it's our camera but
it there is definitely a camera right
there
right so I get to be the camera repair
guy for today screen came up gotta put
my shit
a home these are awesome these see
eighties
their made bike Celestron telescopes
their their optical 1000 ohm meter
2000-3000
your lenses that are only this big and
for
40 bucks you can buy it the issue to
hook it up to your camera that also is
10 X 13
you know magnification Julie you reach
way
out touch somebody hike and take full
motion video from
way a four-way
a secretary con this is the perfect way
to make a you know
anonymous Paulo him
hey and United Dropbox
to make it money like always Amateur
Night check this out
so I was 3,000 yards away and I have
POV show enough arm
I I have gotten me
written conversations and highlight
areas said
over 2,000 I
and they can go a lot farther
that's just because i dont have like big
baller money thrift stores shit
if arm and since you're making a porno
you need to have the audio and video
quality be enhanced
right so you want to be able to also
plant video
inside above the area where your target
is because
everybody knows when you know the final
moment happens you won't have that
matrix view
oliver I see you gotta have multiple
different places
order to actually have been the target
out so I put cameras in different areas
arm we also want to make sure that every
opportunity that we have to listen to
somebody we can
Sophie know some other places that they
have their seeger conversation there's a
power strip their
bug even when you're running your bug
super over it the one super freaked out
is powered
you know its power strip and most
peoples have to take those part porn app
arm there's plenty of them there are
deep rebuilt into
you know the walls that you can use MK
awesome
has free power and what else can you do
0 I can take the power
and I can't use that as a way to get the
audio so now I can just go and listen to
the power lines
who all have to do is plug into the
green box outside that easy arm
using GSM and CDMA is a great way
because the higher frequency so it's not
to get your normal RF bugs
giving them poise is really cool giving
their kids toys is even cooler
a home my kids toy isn't listening to me
I'm okay don't be cheap
but if you wanna be cheap it's totally
okay
was in sciences really of is a whatever
that say before
it's a cool it will make stuff site did
a whole series on making like spy gear
right so 3 volt DC power supply
NPN translator a cell from
a nightlight or just a regular like
photocell right
anally and some headphones an amplifier
that now you have
what the FBI calls their ten thousand
dollar interceptor
the Interceptor 10 because interceptor
once a single laser and it's
like a mild a rock they have some other
factors as shit but the
intercept 9 the big one that they used
to catch you talking
arm when you're I do interviews or
something like that is like a hundred
thousand dollars
in this was a little bit better than
receptor-1 arm
because likes 17 bucks but
Italy's are likely to my job really
really easy in principle rate usually
laser at something as long as I can keep
it stable on a tripod
I can make it so that should strictly
back at me I can use my photo sensor
take what comes into the photo sensor
up with that amplifier implicit yeah
a my bordering has glass windows
0 why because here's all your
information tape recorder
right overhears on the information i bug
really technologically cool hears only
information call into the solar cuz I
got the cell phone
it under the table although he's only
information here's me pointless born are
you laughing with headphones on
okay K
making but making FM bugs are still
really practical really useful
the religion science véronique it takes
but two minutes to make this shit arm
in touch %uh is one of the great a NBC
is what a great car tracking companies
they work everywhere
globally three months for 240 bucks and
you can track somebody real time
walk-up social underneath their car
and giggle as you watching driver handle
I get
if you show the CEO a map of like here's
where you've been all day
that's a problem like I guarantee you
that person's got
freak out me like why is this a while he
would be really cool things inside in
touch
you can make zones so I can put a fence
up
and be like any time they leave their
love fenced area you have to let me know
until then I don't really care about it
because they can be shady in the
neighborhood but they got other
neighborhood I wanna know
right now you can build your own
those arm I'm not gonna talk is only
have like two minutes
up cameras in the car
breaking so many stars easy right we all
know that getting cars a super easy
so replaced thirst the rear view mirror
with one that has cameras all over it so
that you can see what's going on in
their car
because they're doing weird shady stuff
in their car you want to know that
insist that the hardware DVR with an SD
card info easy pickup involved
I'm arm attacked the stuff that they
have on them
back to stuff in their pants just not
that way arm
attack everything around them in Fig
over everything is a conduit for your
information
bank
but their cell phones anybody's
mobiStealth rainy those before
our sausages shows you everything that
they're doing every call that they made
every SMS that they sent their GPS
location if it's on the front of the
sent the email to pictures by a while
if you can track it because you get it
on their cell phone make a cellphone
tower
so hard it's gonna cost like $5 Bryant
arm you know use also Common Era probe
in some the THC sniffing stuff its it
simply army
idiot when it comes to the texan I can
bilbies so what you eat easily build she
and you know get it kind of close you
don't really have to mean you get to see
all want other people stuff just
should be quiet a home now my favorite
one in this is under spend my last
second on this
are is I love blackberry good sox's a
phone and everything else but it's just
just it just runs you know it just has
that like old school I still run
functionality to it but I like so you
pull it apart
any shove it in the little area above
where the people speaker is that they
use their Bluetooth connection
and their catch and all the other crap
that they talk to you and
hint all you have to do is just get on
the mic phone maker reed switch
so that you can pair the microphone love
this
and Bridget to the microphone inside the
car which is already have to fight for
you which is
totally convenient and then you put some
software on the phone which you can
easily go get you know these or others
you know get phone super there's other
lot there's lotsa lotsa stuff there's a
lotta Topp
and then you take what are these because
there's so much power up in that area
where the lights are
and you hard wire your USB power supply
into it
and now you have a fully functional Bob
Carr
with GPS in phone in all sorts of other
capabilities that you can dial into
anytime you'd like to see what's going
on in your car
and if you do it the right way which I
learned how to do later
up you can actually attach this to your
DVR
and as the drive around like watch them
real time video
and have the heads up above where
they're going and who they're talking to
in San indexes
to you see them like this you like with
the texting you just log into that you
can see with their texting
employees that have fun display to show
somebody
here's where your ride Wednesday it take
to disperse in nineteen times between
here and here
your face is really funny when you
almost got into an accident because you
rear ended that dude
because you were texting at 14 minutes
and three seconds into the video
why did you say this
um I only had gone so
my my made only hope that this is that
it gives you some ideas on what else we
can do
as far as getting physical and working
within around people to do what we do
not always have it be our meeting click
my fish
and stop it