okay so talk on
member tracing which is a bit loosely
speaking about
singer time component to member
forensics I
this is joint work with David last
Dominic Fisher talk today we begin by I
Dominic myself
so the first like to introduce the idea
of what
member Tracy actually is and to those to
this entry
we have a look at this I'm patriot down
below what you see there is some
execute a below which is on this then it
is run
it is a memory and keeps running their
what's running in memory
feel of course its memory will change
like Thursday that it will be modified
to create it
and sometimes even colder be modified if
you have like a.m.
obfuscated code and sometimes go change
is
but is essentially shown by the call as
you see here so
college mean that memory much of this
process is changing
now the ideals member tracey is actually
quite simple
what you see here are these I am red
bars
and each of these red bar stands for and
memory dump
each time you see a red bar I'll
be rights in Cyprus as memory to disk
and since you seen many red bars here
your CV do that better relatively high
frequency I kinda know
20 30 50 times per second I'll
in all these data all these memory dumps
or snapshots as you call them as well
are written to disk which yields you to
manage data
that they Dyson analyzed offline to
understand what these execute what he
was doing with
so it's kind of a reverse engineering
technique out that the halftime
come up with great
so super probably heard of at this
member friends ex I mean what you see
here to take member snapshot so it's
kind of a member technique
and there are traditional techniques
which are very popular
certainly heard about volatility in all
the tools which are on
widely used to fine motor in memory
it's very good to to find rootkits
and ex-wife you step
the ID there is similar to ours but it
looks a bit simpler
essentially they only take one snapshot
analyze it afterwards on
to concepts look similar taxes are not a
quite different
because in to dismember forensics you
take snapshots of the whole physical
memory
which means I'm kernel memory as well as
process memory
in memory tracing the focusing on
process easy only take snapshot the
process memory
the focus is different as a consequence
in fact this number Sensex
I'm you get lots of information about
system state like
processes that are running I am letter
connections that are open that separates
et cetera
you get information about coding data
overtime much less what system state
also the application areas of 22
approaches are different and the goal
for this member friends is not as I said
finding mother
in memory and also because engineering
whereas our technique is essentially
about
reverse engineering so in summary these
are two techniques and they're not meant
to compete
they're much more a complimentary okay
so
the next question would be why's it
probably good idea
to dismember tracing what's the value
their and I'd like to give you some
increase now issue much more details
later on
doing to talk of course so the intuition
is the first increase in is
you get so much data that must be
something good in their free throws
engineering for finding interesting data
structures
to and disassemble date that kill coat
etcetera
that's the gut feeling lots on for it
lots of information
must be useful but it can be also
be a bit more criticize actually I'm
there's lots of data and coding memory
which is transient transient means
if the piercing memory and disappears
again
right so for instance what you could
have here
I'm you could have a
encrypt the texting memory some
moment in time for the cryptids then the
Buffalo busy road out again and
disappears again
by this of course the hope in memory
tracing
if you take snapshots at high frequency
we will get also trends in data which
can be very valuable
that's the it's certainly a
strength of this technique it but does
not only applied to data
go supply so called because I'm
certainly effort that's many of those
cases
techniques also encrypt go to the crib
that from time et cetera
and relate to see also in this talk we
can do even more
I am you will see that we can automate
some aspects of of reverse engineering
uses traces
and also sink which is quite valuable is
we can guide the Middle East interesting
code and data parts
by automatically analyzing certain
aspects you can say look you
use interesting coat look at this in
more detail
okay it was the basic idea so
you have a brief morphosis you how to
such a system look like
I am it's much like any other a dynamic
analysis system
like mother sandboxes that these as
follows: you have here now this machine
which contain some america's Ishant
module which is colonel
component then you take amal there
already are
any other execute will you want to
analyze
read on the machine executed right
and to keep it running for a no four
five six seven minutes
and during execution it will I'm collect
always member data is never snapshots
right into this
we also collect some meta data go talk
about that with a true
and then the analyst with some
appropriate tools
scripts tools whatever to analyze these
data
understand what mother is doing so the
whole system is about two components
actually
one is is because Asian here and the
other is analysis tools there
and I'm this pretty much kisses
structure for the stalkers well on the
first going to talk about member
acquisition
how it's done some basic eighties then
be going to go over to the house is
tools
however could what they do and we gotta
have a case study in announcing
analyzing a zulus at the banking Trojan
using our tools to be a fairly a long
time
actual
okay some I am more verse about
acquisition
so what's do we actually track which
process that we track
and don't want two of them only certain
processes
and actually be tracked processes which
get started
after the acquisition engine has started
so any new process will be tracked
and also processes that get an injection
for the track process
see that in the picture below so sue me
RAM
opposition model is running and mother
to XE process wills
started later on and does its track
threat
same for drop it off sexy also tracked
and then 4.6 even receive an
eight-member injection from moment one
of these processes
disparate differ also tracked and the
process bardot sexy
probably got started before we started
acquisition it's not being tracked
okay so this is the process is your
tracking
next question is when do we write those
snapshots that this
and to this end we have triggers expand
trigger fires
processes dumped and triggers currently
are a set of system calls
I miss you can be configured to the file
and each time attract process
calls one of the system calls its pro
its members dumps to disk
way and how's it done
I just very quickly essentially the
position engine is a
girl components which I'm will intercept
system calls
and see if comes from processed
distracting
and I'm whether it's a system call
that's the triggers
if so too right scan member invited to
this
the whole system currently is
implemented for being those a
XP soaking
I mention that Sri also record meta-data
not just his memory traces although the
member traces are
and new concept here but we need me the
data
for different reasons so make the data
can be like
system calls me be really I record all
system calls also
those that don't fire I was that
something engine
we also record some events like process
start
exit its load subject injections that's
it for today
and the reason I think if you increase
in why that's important
so issue my arm you have a process that
has some
plain text in memory encrypts thats
plain text and Tristyn cryptids cipher
text
that's great now you wanna searching all
those members snapshots that there were
traces on a search for plane tix because
that's interesting of course
so one search strategy would be of
course to do some entropy analysis
exe it's a good idea which will help we
don't
you gonna get probably lots of hits okay
you see lots of snapshots memory since
the current rupee
now to be I able to refine your search
it would be good to know when actually
al Faisal written to disk for thats
and recording system calls all system
calls is quite useful because then you
only have to search right before right
operations right
which which makes a search much more
efficient and sometimes only
Island feasible actually okay
here's some more details about the
triggering
thats a very simple this is the
configuration file
have used forum analyzing Zeus
and have actually to kind of triggers
before after triggers
so we see you for instance the the
system call in to create key
is a trigger and its before triggers
that means
when that schools before its code is
executed you take steps
and and ask trigger here for anti
allocate virtual memory
I with fire when the system called
returns from its icky
execution Bay sometimes good to have
members before to call
execute some time afterwards that steady
the choice of triggers is crucial of
course if you have
too few triggers you won't get enough
snapshots
you miss probably the interesting
information you're looking for rights
I yourself to choose latest too few
would also have to choose the right ones
and the everything the naive I am
idea would be of course the trigger ever
see so we get everything
but that's not possible for performance
reasons if he would trigger for all
system calls that the system will die
down
so you have to find a good mix not too
few not too many
and the right months and that's better
playing around
K and some properties about this
acquisition component I would like to
point out it's really stable
it's not just them some resort act that
works like every other day
a is tested it with many thousand
samples
must testing and we can really say for X
really I'm
I reliability and also looked briefly
fits Telsey
I mean some whether it's detected by
Malter I mean some other texts
I'm such components and stops working
you had some samples which were packed
with our with a lot to me that said
throughout a popular Packers for
or and analysis its and it looks like
everything's pretty fine so that no
problem there
current it doesn't mean of course that
components not detectable it's real have
a performance on
it's really too performance overhead and
if you do timing attack
you measure a lower price mistake you
will find out that it's
being tracked but that's the same
problem for all these do not think I may
come
now so systems through virtual
performance
Sega pretty happy performance
performances although
although Cooper from this complex on
stands are many
permit this that I'm that guy's the
performance so
crew of course someone is the triggers
having things you have
it's a very few triggers like two or
three I we can even Burke interactively
the machine
so we manage to load Internet Explorer
which is help process
and play around with it of course it's a
bit slow down the group
if you have lots of triggers like anger
site before system will slow down
it's less interactive or almost
non-interactive
but this still get the data we want to
have so in
any cases use this tool it worked
may be very briefly on challenges fights
hard to implement this
on different days has acted on by their
it was not your today's
curtain guru but the
key and challenges valuable like so you
can
remember much fast and compact disc
which make local
the whole process that's cause a problem
and the solution strategy strategy is
I'll ever simple of course
I'm to avoid those problems you try to
minimize they tell you right
this course the first place and in
second place
I'm try to maximize output forms
thats have done so to minimize the
DataView have done
member that duplication which means the
only right pages that change between
snapshots
its you okay that's quite an optimized
implementation because speed mothers
and four II you i'm for the output thing
david has implemented some I'm
I'm specific output component which is
you're talking or something
okay so we move on now to in the house
is parked which will be
sent by Dominique
thanks Andrew for going with those
through the process of getting memory
trace some
traces of specific applications
an in our own analyzes we got memory
traces sized up to 1 pick up 80 for all
day
top and what we can do next how can be
fined into race
interesting code and data and gain
other insights on behavior how can we do
that
and the first answer to that question is
with all the station we sold about that
the human eye can detect
alum anomalies and patterns enough fast
way
so we tried realization we came up with
essentially to graphs the first one is
shown on this lie to you
it shows us nicely to running processes
and the running threats
within this memory trace you can see
here
the work equal line indicating that
there is to start
of the memory trace and again here is
stir
and where we stopped the to record
and those white boxes 3p sense to
processes with the pro society and to
process tittle
title and does process boxes are
connected with
a row with black arose if the
opera process is a par in process softer
lower one an then in does process pokes
you have 20 sparse here
that are threats the red threats are
injected from
all the processes or the origin of those
threat is from an unchecked that process
from injected threat so this threat here
Colts injected from another process
and this right here call started from an
interactive process
essentially we see here to explore
explore
starts our malicious software the bot
right here and this box then starts to
know other processes
one with randomly name a.m. which Tulsa
some
thread injections and then though
leather one
is the Windows comment program here
which God except you
executed some time later
where us the first graph showed us Mar
Morneau love you and help us to navigate
through
this detail view we came up with the
memory view
which shows us X actly when we do
or all recorded snapshots it's for one
process
your its just a an extract of the whole
graph of one process
you see the sna the snapshots the in a
frontal
chronological order from left to right
and each of those snapshots the mean
memory regions or and arranged
accordingly to its work to address
from of two down be used callers to
called so much tributes of the memory
chance for example
Aldrete rectangles here are execute
herbal
memory regions and just to give you an
impression home much data is this
here this small rectangle here often
execute double memory region
is about 100 feel about its large if you
will
converts that binary data into texas
will be about 20
page long so you can imagine how many
page this will be if we will collect it
and text on
text con beyond just understood very
fostered and binary code
so this is a huge amount of data you
so essentially the last graph showed us
that
there is a need for a photo processing
step between the role that though
and still easily sation so we came up
with
a.m. a few relatively simple bot
they have proven to be quite useful
scripts here is a list of a few of them
we will explain them briefly in the
coming slights
and all of those scripts word and used
in hours Houston
and all of those scripts produces
results which we can which allies 10
in one of the previously shows graphs
yes oh one of the scripts is about
finding self belief I coach so
qualifying code
so so funny fine code is a obfuscation
techniques that means croat
change its form during execution
typically
what is he often is some code is encrypt
it before execution
and it started there's a song small the
crips and stop
with the cryptic wrote like the memory
and then jump the code executed
maybe a reason a raise it again or
encrypt again depends on how
sophisticated
if the state Res it's widely used and
I'm
suppose important to get that code if
it's meant to be hidden
and getting the code is important and
then that works very well with
with the member traces favorite me that
is a simple script that finds
says modifying code I was very good
quality
we really able to tech2 also small
small ranges of self modifying code as
you will see in the
in the demo I'm we surely it's very
simple yet fewer
I'm an excerpt from member review here
if he starts a qualifying colleges
market be by a
black bar so you know UT's right
look at it exported et cetera so that
you also see later on so want the idea
of course is if you have found so far
the fine coat
you export thats to either pro December
look at it no details
the next feature I'd like to explain you
is the most you light listing
and its does exactly that with you
expect from a model white Lister
it generates all loaded modules
like Windows dll's in the snapshot
and then compares its original and
data which the data in the memory into
memory trace
so on the left hand side you see an
extract of the male review
and basically you call to mom malicious
called be everywhere
at least at or in the execute double
memory region so you don't know
where to look at and on the right hand
side
you see now the most you'll whitelist
/url a year
enable it in this memory you and you can
see that there is now here
all green that means that
this is all firm
clean loaded de ellos and you don't need
to look at those memory chins
so their Texas only one redline
now here that's one memory chin which
doesn't belong to one then the lol so
if we are looking for malicious Colt
that will be a star
to look a and we see here also now
that here is loaded the main execute
tubal
so each of one of those is a loaded d
lol
you two main and model whitelisting
helps us also do
sport potential malicious modifications
of crude steel else
we see here 3d Los let's also extract of
the memory view
ac3 de los stacked on top of each other
and they August all-star key is clean
and then that's on time all of them
called modified
you you see that here and
the lowest one even got modified three
times
successively and the nice thing here is
also that you see a certain pattern
and we found out in our analyzes that
for example in C you see that popped
into law
in each process but with
will see that later in the team
and its the next feature is threats
grouping
if a call shortly back to the process
you
UCL all the threats threats injected
threat
all attention potential malicious
threats
and you don't know exactly what they are
doing if they are related to each other
or the do they even the same seeing
so we came up with the threat grouping
feature
and it thus you start if the true if the
threat
has the same goat and also the same
entry point in that go it is the same
threat
and you see it see now delay a.m.
up lights to the process few on the top
it's a one threat starting a couple of
other threats you don't know exactly
what they are doing
and with statler you see now exactly
that
there are only three groups yellow
a gray and agree and if you want to
understand
now does threats you only have to look
at one threat
a group and of course only understand
too cold
underlying the group once
okay a.m.
f's a few more features which are easy
to explain so we have a memory Mac sure
that's like I'm with like a text search
in a text editor
you can input some some
source region and search for it through
all snapshots
I the difference though is that three
don't know exact matching because that's
not so useful sometimes
you some kinda fuzzy matching and that
turns out to be quite useful
what to do then be with allies met you
return so you can say okay
USC something I don't know what it is
police search for that
through all the snapshots marked them
black I feel for you
quite helpful as you see very soon it's
actually help for the photo find code:
called injections are common data used
by processes
the other thing is stacked fact races
I'm
when you have a system call the me look
at stack
can figure out which hearts memory
have been executed that's also quite
useful to see
what parts member actor active which
code is active
it's a bit like with the bombing you
always know what's active right that's
kinda very
he'll be fucking like yeah I'm standing
Records Act
and also very important feature although
simple one is the
I the export so as I said before it's
about finding interesting memory tunes
all things about that then once you have
found a new course need to analyze
Manali
but you can but what you can do then
this exported memory to I don't
have a look at it
okay when so we gonna start the
zulus demo I
its actual recording what I can tell you
it's not fake
it's just for for time reasons
essentially and also because its
resolution of these be was here
I like to price high resolution we have
your just a few words about those I mean
sources
see fairly complex as many
functionalities like they to stealing
injection of HTML
and complication its EC et cetera in
this demo we only
I'm focus on the installation behavior
his first thing that happens when you
get in fact
with sows be you can do more than that
you don't show everything and I'm yeah
so we start of here with the process for
you
and then zoom in a bit and what you see
here
is actually both process that's the best
mother had that's what you want to
analyze
you have taken that and run it in a
system right see actually got started by
explored
sexy is quite usual if you double click
on it
and we also see that there's some child
process started by both the pixie
filter now that's that's both the texas
dropper this year's property
so what you gonna do now is actually
have a bit a closer look at these
processes
sitting here you know list and the
speech over now to memory view
right every really have a look at memory
trace
and what you see here is the memory
trace of I am
well-thought sexy what you see roughly
his
as he said I'm xxx is this time wise
what ru
at this pace what you see here if you
notice face a bit
down here are the lever is which loaders
appears mine execute people
and you at the beginning to see some
loading is going on supply was loaded
into memory
you some allocations were happening over
there were
then if you remain fairly stable over
time at this ground
parity
okay visa with in a bit
first I am
now you also see Power Tool Works
it has been speaking about this and now
these features and each of them is a
visual later
your in this too so we can switch on
some
some of these features and they will
have some visual impact on picture
so you see look now for Vice listing
them like this thing
will be switched on the interviewer
that's what you have done actually why
this is now switched on NBC
all these reasons here agree which is
this is good coat
known good coat nothing to worry about
the code up he is unknown
and your receipt is on on code actually
that's not very surprising that sexual
made execute with both which is unknown
wealthy also see piece the whole
patching saying we've been talking about
scroll to the right in the second all we
have also met I'm formation you like
size memory et cetera see
you so this is still the
main image of both zoom out
for the right what you see here three
nights these are these injections
I mean it's little bit more now says but
it turned out these are injections into
the library's
some modifications
okay
you see all psyched about laver is being
injected to weaken look at the name
I wanna move on and I'm
find out what's happening this end we
have now turned on
South Franco detection I mean all the
Zacks a precomputed
right and both be mark you now in the
in the view is all those black thoughts
correspond to sell for the cycle your
phone
there are actually three regions one
small one appear
but the bigger one down there then many
very small ones here
you look at these two in more detail no
a
again the thirty of those regions
so we folks on this one I we've 69 other
layers
what the media to senior I'm you have
some basic information
memory so it's red execute people so
that my cell
somehow sense there's some code that has
appeared and it's excusable so
at most likely really called not the
false-positive
I'm you're not sick
whether this code is actually running
this and be switched on
stock back traces so this this purple
or pink whether it is lines they show
with Regan
which memory sins are really executing
will be very nice to see
up here back the main image of the book
has been yet seen execution here
until this is called he has appeared now
its immediate the active
so that's kind of true /code senior
itself or the fine code is through croat
and it's funny
the next thing is I'm
you want to find out where it's coming
from and have another feature for that
who in a bit and now we have switched on
memory right detection if EC
and is never right system calls the
track from that and where to their
rights
and the senior drew a red bar has been
gotten a bit bigger
you see that means this memory T is a
target of memory rights okay
that's very nice and also see voters
coming from its process 15 44
so this memory thing was written by
process 54.4%
let's see what it is goes back to
process list
see okay
that was explored a taxi so what they
have seen you essentially
is member injection from explore
sexy now we know it's coming from
but we don't know what it is right so
it's time to use our
matching feature that have gone now I am
what you have said please match this
reason here
and surgical old memory you see I V F
for smack to see you
might disappear what's the what we learn
from that up here we have two main image
of both
and apparently the main image of the
book copy down here
the funny thing is it came be explored
sexy
so somehow got there we don't know yet
how but its kind protection it seems
both is injected self
certain processes okay
in
and I think I'm gonna switch over to
yet to drop the process the second
process
child process both the pixie you don't
have a look at that memory
see if you can get generate someone
standing there okay it is again
overview
do some whitelisting I Logan going to
the taste is the simple things like
before
some patching going on one focus on
right now is the black parts you
so we see again image of the BART
also can use in the tight process K
is the main one you love try process so
it seems to be
sent to the same as of both Missy
strange black taxis here that's an
example transient croat
trends in data that means the image
appears
and disappears again several times look
also see
the right that's the same thing as
before same pattern as for the
as for the pot see again MENA region
he talked about the Pew so next on the
look
have a look at the at these dumbasses
because they're quite interesting why
does why does the if they both appear
is appearing appear again to throw for a
sec
you only use actual another feature
I am week and what you gonna realize now
is like him
where the heat is located
okay he resuming now on on one of those
taxes to see more detail it's happening
switch on the base craft and
now we switched on heap location
you see heap is marked in pink so these
memories in this heat and go through the
sea is that them
the image of the both will appear on
keep okay
that's interesting it's not execute the
book he's not excusable
on the rise to be read so the question
is what is it doing he
and then they have switched on the gang
and
memory right tracing and what you see
here now is a
big green bar which means that memories
in
is the source over memory right you see
this memory since written to process 15
and the story though is the following
one
the image of the process is written heap
then that's injected
to process your 15 44 which if you
remember is
explore a sexy now cut somehow the story
make sense
try process of the bought rights
emit index for sexy which in turn then
makes the injection we have seen before
to book a taxi so now we understand the
waste is memories traveling
and you see the same
in all the processes as well actually so
we see
you each of these black cum arse
is an injection into separate process if
you look at you too its time same path
so we see the the drop key processes
is doing it excellent running what's up
in Texas actually
okay this was about
analyzing the first self modifying code
written have seen
so you have a very good understanding
what's happening already
good intuition gonna have a look weak
locus the second round it's a very small
region
it's a bit different it is in the middle
of execute a book called you see that
the threat before and after
so this seems to be nothing injection
but Ruiz L qualifying coat
what is the bottom animation has been
change during execution you see it's
a.m.
the black bars very small region just
one page one-page
a large and what I wanna see what
functions
actually a lot called is there now what
we do is
the export just a snapshot before South
qualifying code has appeared
and the snapshot very has appeared 30s
two snapshots here
which have marked export into I need to
eat a four-month
for further analysis it's happening now
for using
okay
what you have done your we haven't
loaded them into right up but
in the tool which is called been this
been the fees for comparing to bang Rhys
and not on a by them about the
conceptual level like function
basic plot level and a.m.
would be in the show says indeed at the
location
X 40 a et cetera very selfless thank all
those found
we have three functions that appear
that's been it's it's very nice
okay for the three functions that
apparently have been
the cryptid from time and we can have
another
look at it here from one of those
functions
again been dif you see before after
the ICC here before there was no coach
rubbish
after receipt nice clean call you to get
allies now
so in summary
this South modifying code I'm detection
has a that very directly to three
interesting for teens
and if you look at them in detail you
will find out they all have to do
with installation so we have been
directly
guided tour installation routines of
both a sink
you turn right so we have now seen some
details about the book
then its child process some of the
aspect to this we'll see here
calm for and we've seen you you to same
saying in an order you
and it's much more like an over you know
so if you remember to memory rights
from with image very
any to make post if you remember to
memory rights
of in each process from the child
process
you will see you to exact same saying
which the green lights
so the Thai processes injecting goat to
each or too many other processes
so this year is though you of the OC
and of course he does not only rights to
memory
to another process also starts new
threats in it
and this is shown here he does sry
memory rights to each process
and then starts immediately a new threat
the green dots are two memory rights and
the black told is still use threats
which got started
of course you can track down now does
red lines and see
where it is threat is injected to
and
so the next thing would like to know is
what what this disco twitches injected
into all the processes
and for that pur- pose we and able to
threats group you
and you see now that's there is in the
air yellow threat insect it into one of
those processes
it's called the label it this to trade
group I'm
and year it wealth were toolbox
not Eakes XE and for all of those
processes
everywhere is stems threat and it's just
only one threat
except for a few cases for example
here is the Explorer and
in case tote this I'm thread runs in
Explorer
it will start a couple of all the
threats and you see that here on this
picture right now
and if it runs an explorer
it will starts for example here too
these threats there are exactly the same
this one year
and Islam and they got
both another argument
you concede this and meta-data which
display
and the other Singh is in the window
security notify your process
it the book also behaves in all the way
year it starts to New threats
one of two groups che and one of two
groups an and
those threats we also see here in the
Explorer process
and what we can assume now is that the
window security Nov 25
contains the soup set of the threats of
the Explorer
so both of them have house some kind of
similar functionalities
a.m. year is
also shown one threat of the Explorer
does some more interactions
and of course we'd need to know now what
is dis
threat a.m. doing so for dis we go
again in the memory view and see one of
those threats
and and
if we'd know was designed threat this
doing we can
also although we know that for every and
threat
also in the other process of course so
years again the
both image its exactly the same with the
Memory Man
much are we have proven that and
it's also executing used to this
talkback trace again
and what we now have a look at this time
the
and loaded modules and with the might
weightlifter
and we see here a lot of modifications
we go nose
the in to one of them or three of them
am we see here
there is a ago their Easter
anti DLL load it then
there is a memory right a.m.
there is two address given here and you
see also that
there the got written five by its five
bucks that's a charm
to another location difficult track down
this address you will come
into the boat image so this is basically
walking and it talks to create threat
met
of ante de l'eau and you see here to
memory right
which is highlights right now and one
two snapshots later and whitelist to say
that is called modified and you see the
exact same saying for
for the other who Kings on the right
site now
and for example here is still loader los
de lol who
and some other system calls
order or of Beatles and again also for
when
unit so we have now seen
the injections to patching from one
threat
and it appears to be the same in all
other processes
and we have now understood that the M's
threat is basically just
who King some calls and our loaded my
the
into los libros and in case it runs and
Explorer
or in Windows security notify you it
starts
all the threat which are basically there
for stealing on
information or modifying some other
sings
okay so I think we have seen really that
now intend two minutes a good
fairly quickly develop some
understanding of what's going on on you
I'm universal nice way of course
constand all the tissue still have to go
into
some this assembly and look at the
things that scare no one can automate
that
but was really about guiding at least
interesting parts and
having a good increase in what's going
on between of course than helping
detailed analysis so we're
ready to conclude I'm think I've seen
some
we think entirely new technique to tube
and analysis
I'm are you know this I'm member tracey
is
entirely new have also seen the can
automate some things like that I'm so
qualifying code said cronkite Annalise
to impress
regions I was also say that's
absolutely open topic I mean it just
started working on that centrally I
think
what's questions i mean is is really
useful &
is canned can there be new by the
techniques even
more techniques found to make analyses
to gain insights
entirely possible to sync but some clear
I'm
also taken the questions like would be
nice if course if he could break off
snapshots really nice Seok uses natural
that's interesting probably now could
loaded like that the Brotherhood
something
start even from there but that's
technically heart
but that of course very nice I am
he also nice throws a capture go to
memory much as process memory
costing you have much more information
that would really be volatility over
time
great so thank you Mark very much for
you
for your attention seeing you can
take some questions
crack