alright hello everyone
welcome my name is for and urine
interest
same thanks for coming I really
appreciate
you guys have me out this conference and
I spent some time with me today
'em let's do a little bit of a
introductions so up as I said my name is
for I work at Facebook
on in California
and my entire adult life I've been
obsessed with the problem of intrusion
detection
and those view that have have known your
work with me
can contested that's true um
I actually think I've spent more time
thinking about Internet action than any
other
thing in my whole life is actually kinda
sad
but I am I but %uh that's okay
a so I love the problem I'm working on
for a long time
and I i want I wanna talked a little bit
today
about intrusion detection and its its
is one those topics in security that the
you really see you people talking about
a lot
and and frank I haven't seen are people
thinking a lot all about either
arm what I want to do in a stock is
actually spent some time
I talking about how I think about
entering the texan
an I am stepping through some approaches
to it that I thinkers somewhat novel
arm the goal was not so much to impart
some
major new discovery on you but that help
you think about this problem
and hopefully have you come up with
ideas
to help me with this problem so it's a
little bit over
self-serving talk I guess in that way um
but my goal in this is to get you
excited about the subject and get you
to come away with this from the stalk
thinking about new ideas in the field in
ways to contribute
on so that's my goal so this is a
this is talking three acts I the first
act
is is kind of discussing discussing the
the state have
the intrusion detection field and in
order to talk about the state have any
field in security
if the start of the logical place which
is money
um so the security industry
is roughly 3.5 billion dollar industry
a in terms of money spent on on security
products
a and that's according to Gartner
IIT JEE another research firm did some
analysis I try to come up with some
numbers and how much money people are
spending on internet action products
and it turns out it's a little bit hard
to pin down
but a I D G a release some information
about
Sams you guys from our security event
managers and
the whole field of those products on
Sophie people are spending about
1.5 billion dollars a year on those
products arm
sexy couple our money for things that
don't work and do anything useful
so I am I Anna and I'll
and I'll and I'll try to show I think
that's the case over the course in stock
so okay so people spend money on
products
but a how are they working force right
international question ask so who can
return to kinda gays
the date to glean some information about
how all these products are working well
one other ports or so that information
is
is something called the prize indeed a
brief report if you guys ever heard the
saying before
yes and sing some not some not knots
yeah
actually you haven't seen this um you
know I'm not the kind of security guy
that liked love the Magic Quadrant or
something like this:
but some this reports actually really
good Tom
and it's a pretty good summary of the
state of the industry and and so on
so anyway a in the most recent 2012
report
they they have a few different data
points and their I think ur interesting
to eliminate this question of how well
these intrusion detection products are
working
so I'm just gonna walk you through a few
I think salient data points from that
from that document we want well as too
much I see some people like oh my god
another deter
report I was spent too much time on it
but I think it's actually pretty
interesting
and I and II hope you agree in a minute
okay so what does this tell us
seven to 10 targeted attackers are top
target to get attacks against larger
organizations okay this is an all that
like surprising right um but but want
two things I do want to talk about
is intrusion detection in light of the
so-called targeted attacks the so-called
a BTU tax or something like that right I
will these products doing against these
these these targeted attacks that are
happening to become pennies
and so um
the current state of affairs is that
half of intrusions took months or years
to discover that they happened at all
13 years to discover they occurred a
thats seems kinda flake not very good
a okay I seventy-one percent of the time
in the attack surveyed
I the attacker attacks took place in
minutes or less
total time:
about from from to come from Isaac
company
um now over to step back a minute for
those that don't know about the raid
present data breach report it's a it
encompasses actually
almost all the the case studies that our
public
and a bunch of them their private from
comp places like the secret service
and a bunch of other international law
enforcement agencies as well as
Verizon's own
in some response group so everybody 155
cases a factual
a intrusions an actual breaches that
have occurred
so this isn't just a made up numbers
this is actually based on a
actually fairly what the the single
largest study up data breaches that's
ever been done
is this report so anyway okay
so those are kinda bad intrusion
detection systems maybe aren't working
out well
but let's put the nail in the coffin um
so how these things discovered and these
companies in the first place
right when they actually take you months
and years to discover our the discovered
well after them are actually notified by
a third party and not discovered by the
company and/or
right the FBI comes and tells you
something happened or someone forced an
agency
or some other company tells you
something happened I
so that's like half or more than half
the cases
okay what about the rest well a third of
are from somebody noticing hey something
is weird
a system administrator noticing a
processes running on a system that
should be
a somebody thats non-security just you
know
hamster no to something and notifies the
security team
so were actually up to a fairly sizable
percentage of the day above the case
studies
and we haven't even gotten to the
Internet detection system yet
right okay so that they call these
intrusion detection systems fraud
detection systems in that report
5 percent above the time up disk
particular study
again the largest study ever done five
for some the time
these intrusions are are discovered by
an intrusion detection system
a you know the stack of dollar bills on
the previous slide red
this is what it's giving you now 5
percent how bad is that really let's
think about how that stacks up against
other things
well it turns out routine log review
somebody randomly going and looking at
logs is more successful at discovering
intrusions then
the intrusion detection systems okay
what the hell I I these things are
working
right okay say well you know what that's
just a single data source you know there
by Astor whatever some sampling error
rate or whatever
okay let's look at another so there's
another report put out by company called
mandiant
you guys heard a man yet before yeah
okay so they're they're like free famous
for being
like why the big companies that handle
arm Apte
quote-unquote I'm using that I know
people like that term intrusions
so-called and when a company gets
compromised by a nation-state
actor to help them handle the response
figure out what happened in and
remediate
so they actually come up the report as
well they're kinda covers the same topic
um and the report they say sixty so
6 six-percent events intrusions are
detected by an internal process
rate and in fact the numbers that were
detected by ensuring detection system
worse
right because we already know from the
previous slide an internal process can
include
pay something is weird and enter a
process can include random logging
blog browsing right so
this is a state-of-the-art this is where
we're at 20 2012 intrusion detection
right so Lake
we suck and we needed a better
a yeah this is my wii has a problem
slide I
yep it takes a minute
it's actually fun I
okay so some
okay so like maybe these numbers are
wrong maybe these two different ports
are like
you know telling us things are the same
but they're still wrong you know
look I know you guys all the security
are a lot of you guys
arm you you know these numbers are wrong
if you've been doing this for a while
right
so I'm you know there's an Intuit
intuition aspect to this as well and I
see about you guys nodding
so I think the question is um if
if if buying a bunch of boxes and
throwing them out there
and forgive men isn't really cutting it
anymore area arguably if it ever did
or with what can we do and how can we
how can we approach this problem in
and try to try to do something smart so
that's what we're gonna start talking
about now
and that's that we get into our second
actor the story
okay so first of all is to find what the
problem is
art and science a defining actionable
deviations between normal behavior an
attacker behavior is one definition I
came up with for
what you're trying to do when you're
doing intrusion detection
I'm this is kinda complicated so
you know maybe this is a better way to
think about it
rate you're trying to get lucky by
detecting somebody doing something dumb
so how with the freemen trust to think
about this problem
how do we actually Tom who actually
process
alright so here's the first thing this
is a
this is the this is the rookie mistake
the people make with intrusion detection
and ninety-nine percent the world at
large people are doing transaction
art are doing are making this mistake so
the this is that this is example
somebody want to do a true texan
they by Amish appliance or or they buy a
smart sensor
right they put it into the network they
turn on Ubuntu signatures
and then they say holy shit there's a
lot of alerts
what I do and so they go and return of
everything that's making alert
right and they're like okay sweet now
it's working
right if I I mean that you know
you know I'm you know I'm right here and
so like was a problem at this rate
I people love the idea
an intrusion detection system that's
going to
always tell them the truth and never lie
to them
and this is something we call the
false-positive fallacy
of right it's a it's a
it's this idea that that you know
its I'm gonna build a perfect intrusion
detection system that's always going to
tell me the right answer
and it's never gonna tell me something
wrong and that's my goal
right and if I ever get some noise or if
I ever get some spurious alerts or
something then
the whole systems a failure and I'm just
gonna turn often ignore
and I think this is one the fundamental
problems with the field
is that people don't understand that
this is the wrong approach
so this is this is the picture of
somebody
the idea here is that people wanna wanna
have something that wakes them up in the
middle the night
only if it's something that's really bad
and they don't know how to handle this
stuff that's in the middle
right how like it's very easy to
instrument something that every time
this triggers I'm gonna go
alerted I'm gonna get the fire truck and
I'm gonna drive in you know say the day
right but the a the reality is is
unfortunately more subtle than that
so this is something very important to
this discussion
which is called the event pipeline and
this is the process by which
you take a us a an event or a signal
are some signs of suspicious activity
and you use or to put it through the
series OHV
a process he's and out the other income
something useful
and so I'm gonna talk to you about how
you go about that
so the first stage is dealing with noisy
events learning to love noisy events
and that's what we're going to talk
about now so we talked about the example
of the
other thing that wakes you up in the
middle of the night right well
let's talk a little bit more in in
subtle terms about things that
are in the middle so
this is an example I'm gonna show you
some examples from one to 10 I wanna
spend too much time on this but
let's see let's say you have a taxonomy
where you have up
you know one is I want to be woken up in
the middle the night
and 10 is like and everyone to look at
ever right and I want to show you that
there's actually a bunch of stuff
that is in the middle so maybe maybe you
find
you know you've been talking to some
peers and you find hey you know we
reverse this malware we found this now
we're going to this really weird domain
name
and no one's ever gonna go to the domain
name ever but if it so if you look for
that domain name
that's always bad right you get lucky
that's that that's actually for you
pretty good signal okay what about a
a PDF it's got some our innate and and
it do you want to be woken up every time
you have PDF for them our
mmm depends on our depends on the PDF
depends on the user a
so now we start getting grayer and
grayer and grayer rate
different log log into your locations
for same user
right i mean there's ways you can make
this useful maybe they're traveling
may be there you know in a in another
office or or
you know so maybe it's a false positive
like you don't know at the point is I'm
trying to say is like
this is from highest confidence to lost
confidence and number the point on my
my talk is going to be like how do you
use these other things
rate I think what a lot of people do is
they just create an intrusion detection
system and haven't email them
every time something happens well if you
yourself every time
these things on the list happen you
gonna stop paying attention pretty soon
it pretty quickly
right okay so anyway I want well as too
long but not for Best alerts for known
that IP addresses so you get some eye
peas from somebody
but if you've done this before you know
there's some reasons why this can create
some noise
unspecific registry modification so I
could say you're watching a machines
and San you know you know that the run
once key is like an interesting place
where people try to establish
persistence rate
but you obviously don't wanna get a an
email every time a registry key changes
rate that's not gonna work out
so another example any worse alerts
over the years this this keeps going
down the list this used to be up there
now now these are you know kinda down
the list
because they're not all that useful arm
this is an example use rather talk
a snort event for a blink use region
already does not use region sorry hope
maybe a blank use regions interesting
maybe it's not we'll talk about use
regions
um a successful RTP login again not
something you want to email the middle
tonight but it has some poor
part to play in the intrusion detection
story
right I okay
a snot event that you write that that
gives you an alert every time there's a
trip to traffic
so again we're going down the list
noisier noisier noisier noisier
and in the final point is raw data
obviously you don't get woken up in the
middle night because you got a log
you gotta love you rate doesn't make any
sense
but again they're important for the
story so how are the important part a
story or thought about
okay so let's say we went through we
instrumented those but those ten things
we have an alert for every single one of
them
right and we want to do something useful
with these events so
how we gonna do something useful with
them well it's a good example
let's take an example love the other
blank user-agent: one
arm where is it ray here her
yes seven thank you so let's take an
example number seven
alright sorry to disappoint user-agent:
yeah from not something you wanna be
walking about
but there is a way to make those useful
so blacklisting
see you create an event right and you
send it somewhere
they consume those events and then you
wanna go through a process on that
particular event called blacklisting
the blacklisting is a process whereby
you tryin so so the whole goal we're
trying to take
is take those events from as we go
through the list
we're going to take those noisy events
and push them up to big as least noise
as possible
right so that's the first aid for trying
to do so if we can get the number seven
to be a number four
number three like that's actually
awesome and then we get down a
correlation
well actually figure out how to combine
those number three's together into
something worthwhile
so how do we get the 7203 so the first
ever that is called blacklisting
red so blacklisting is about
taking in a vent and call
taking out the the known false positives
red
3 I'm walking out of the zone I
um it's about taking event and removing
the non false positives so we give an
example
have anybody ever brightness not event
for a bike use region before
Yes No well I have cuz I'm lame
and everyone and this was years ago when
user agents are still interesting
and I'm and I
you guys ever heard a Fitbit before that
thing you like walk around with them I
told him he steps
that sound familiar so it turns out
Fitbit like the people that wrote Fitbit
it calls back to some cloud service in
like records your steps or something
and like they don't know how to program
very well so they they actually
for got to including user-agent: and so
10 things you notice as soon as you turn
a signature and if you have any users
that use fits
and also you got a bunch of alerts and
you look at the domain name or the
destination IP
and it turns out it's like some fit that
thing and I okay well that's probably
not a PT year something like
you know it's probably okay so you start
peeling back the layers
to try to wait list those things so
and I admit knows people can be tricky
and hide my I get that
you have to make the call when you're
doing the blacklisting yourself so it
the point is
every single event type whether it's a
no would be Savannah host this event the
user event whatever
you you go through a process whereby you
you you you drop the ones on the floor
that you know are just not worth looking
at
now that's different than the model with
the the smart sensor we talked about
earlier it we just plug in and turn off
everything
we're not turning off the thing we're
just took turning off the ones that we
know about it
and we're loading everything else
through are being fairly permissive here
red
where is going to take the most
egregious cases in turn them off because
this is just one stage in
any event pipeline you guys do with your
this making sense
okay like the look like the fall asleep
but it I think it's like the weird mood
lighting going on so
it's kinda hard to tell so the next step
after you do the blacklisting
so that means you you take off although
although other creatures false positives
the next episode a colleague identity
translation so
this is my Superman changing his
identity um
the point is that a wanna think this
really hard about intrusion detection in
a modern enterprise
is that a lot of the events come in and
they're like
apples and oranges right so you get an
event from a network sensor
like a smart sensor something and has a
at source IP
rate and you get you get similar from
some loggers something
and it's got like a username right and
this is actually like a little
a really hard problem and it's really
subtle but like if you want to start
doing interesting correlations between
these different types of things that are
alerting
you need to be able to do some
translation layer so that you understand
that this source IP
a is actually something to do with this
user so that you can start comparing the
events together
so this is hard and I spent a lot of
time working on this problem before
I but I its its it's necessary
because otherwise you'll never be able
to compare offense from your
infrastructure
to each other up if if you don't know
that they're related
you have to have someone to relate them
right so you know what I would recommend
is to have some sort of system whereby
you can take these events with various
identities
after the time after you've done
blacklisting a to take up all the false
positives
and then you just think of it like
attacked like you tag and then you have
a system that says oh yeah
that I P at this time i've a lookup
table for that you know using DHCP or
something
and that was this user or you know stuff
like that
and if you're if you're interested in
talking more about something like that
works
because it's it's it's a little bit
difficult um I can talk to you after the
talk about it
but but the point is you basically just
the lookup tables that are life
and there's a bunch of different
commercial systems you can use for this
problem as well
arm but it's pretty important okay
so we've covered blacklisting and we've
covered
um identity translation so you think
about that pipeline
and our little event that was really
noisy is hopefully getting a little less
noisy
after going through these various stages
now the next four
other discussion is going to be I gotta
take these noisy events
and compare them together to create a
Metavante
that is views make sense
yeah you guys with me okay so this is
the stage called correlation
so wanna talk a little bit about how to
think about correlation in general
and I'm gonna introduce the concept that
is going to be a specific type of
correlation that you guys can
can't can't think about doing the other
with a coalition to it and I can talk
about those but
let's first talk about a coalition is in
the first place
the idea is to take a bunch low
confidence I'd events like the seven
fours and whatever
right and turn them into high confidence
events right
a combined event that include some
events better more interesting
then individual events that you would
never look at right
that's the key so how we do that
well let's talk about a concept called
the attack plane
this is not an attack fine other at
night in so many things is
um actually what I mean by an attack
plan something else
so what um because of a plane
is in in this case it I mean like a a
two dimensional space
right US familiar with that definition
of plain
just think of it as a as a as a table
that you can stack things on
like Apple's right and a.m.
the purse the point I'm trying to make
is that the perspective you take when
you build that desk
the years plate placing the apples on
arm matters
and so it's let's talk about an example
here's a very simple case
so in this case this is my attack plane
this line here
right and these are these things with
Apple's these are individual events
these are noisy events
that i won a combined together so this
is the trivial case
over wave gripping events that a that
you can do at home kids
I that you can do yourself um
and this is the way of grouping them
it's by IP address
rate seems pretty natural pretty obvious
pretty trivial
rate if there's like four events from a
same IP
over a certain time window maybe that's
more interesting than one event
but I would never look at right for this
is the trivial case
a correlation and in this case the
attack plane
is the IP address based attack plane the
it desk I'm stuck in these things on is
an IP address desk
so let's see what that looks like it
looks like okay 1.2 the three or four
has four offenses over here for to 3.2
that one is over here
and it's got four events break and
depending on the nature of these bubbles
these vents this whole box maybe
something worth looking at
right maybe
now this is a simple case of up grouping
and this is for the state of the art of
correlation as it stands today
but are there different ways of doing
grouping that could perhaps tell you
something more interesting
then simply stacking things by IP
address
and turns out the answer is yes but we
have to take a minor digression
before we get there so please forgive me
for a moment but this is gonna be really
interesting
the killed three those scary
so the kill chain whose articulating
and very awesome is actually a really
important idea in security
I think and I'll it's got a new one
and I think you'll find it interesting
so the idea to kill chain
was started by the US military
and it's a theoretical concept that
breaks what an attack a physical attack
rate like a terrorist attack or a
whatever it breaks those attacks
into a series of stages and it says
an attacker who's gonna attack me has to
go through the stages
no matter what they have to buy a weapon
they have to reload the weapon they have
to like figure out where I'm at
right have to come to me you know I
whatever the states are there's a bunch
of papers on a kill chain
in the military context and in a
military context they use this concept
to figure out how they can do two things
brick the kill chain
when the case have an attacker right so
how can I say they say
you know a detector has to necessarily
go through the stages we're in that
could we actually
a mess them up right and it's actually
pretty useful for that
but it's also useful on the other side
when are trying to kill people
a for trying to figure out the how to
accelerate
coaching so one of the things in the
coaching is like you know I wanna I have
my
my site on the target I you know I got a
college cue and confirm not my orders
rate and you know its cues like well you
know get back to them
so on the problems is like delays in
communication slows down the kill chain
I'm not advocating killing anybody or
anything like that by the way has a
don't get the wrong idea I just think
it's a cool idea from from
from there that we can borrow for
information security context so
Tom anyway so that's the deal so
does that make sense so these two guys
or three guys
at Lockheed Martin actually figured out
how to borrow this concept and bring in
the information security to me
as a copy for you to read it um
but what they've done is a basically go
through with it intrusion attack looks
like from a coaching standpoint
and figure out using that how we can arm
we can stop it how we can prevent so on
so here's my version of their papers
skilled same
I made this up but they're the pier is a
slightly different one this is my
version
I'll a because a I made a little
different optimize for intrusion
detection
so here's one attacker might do
they might do some rekon break try to
figure out what your network is
where your keys are with domain names
you have flick you know do some google
searching
most the stuff is passive they also
might set up um
there see two notes right they might
register the domain names
writes a some familiar over arm
delivery how does delivery normally
happen these days above
exploit spearfishing
SMTP read email spree comment there's
others other vectors rate
that some of common right now yes a
delivery so that's a good
important particle chain right like you
know something as the
go across male a exploitation right
though cut computers compromise
the machine you know usually has a
downloader something in the in the in
the payload
download something answers coming back
to see two I mean obviously there's some
differences in how people go about these
things but this is i think is pretty
good
I'll somebody could takes that takes
over the sea to becomes active
then actively manually compromises that
the a
the machine rate this is the part where
um
they're like dumping hashes right doing
a
a password cracking maybe if any to or
you know doing some other a machine
analysis
and there's internal rekon with a look
around your network try to figure out
what kinda stuff going on
this is where they look at your wiki and
see that the wiki page it says
here's all our admins that have access
to the awesome stuff
and you know here's the passwords so
I that support with that happens I'll
ever movements the login to differ
machines
sorry I'm kinda many going to slow here
but
persist in setting up a way to connect
back in an hour and in staging
exultation
so the state is in these concepts
familiar at least right yeah
so the skill chain the notion that these
things are linked and and and
by and large are necessarily done by an
attacker
is actually an interesting concept for
us right so let's go back to where we
were a minute ago
we're talking about attack points right
and we had this trio case have an IP
address and we're stacking these events
on this table
well what if we had a more a
sophisticated idea
what if we use the kilt same but I just
mentioned that these attackers
necessarily have to go through
what if we use that as the basis for a
correlation
Rep again this is just one idea for
Hadoop more advanced has a coalition you
probably have
other ones but this one's interesting so
what say you have a command control
a its event right maybe it's a low
quality event
but maybe it's a you know a some sort of
maybe it's the the dime que serve the
blank user agent or something
when event comes in maybe it's a seven
out of 10 but you have a label on that
and at the and when the event creates
gets created it's labeled with the kill
chain stays that it belongs to you
okay um exfiltration
rate maybe have something for arm
exultation adjusting for internal rekon
rate info
if you have something if is somebody who
looks at too many wiki pages in two
short amount of time maybe that's an
event
again on the van I want to get woken up
in the middle of the night but an event
you can label
with the internal rekon for the kill
chain and exultation maybe you look at
some
a large amounts over our files going out
with your network
just as an example right so beforehand
maybe the you to these things like a
colour-coded this by how quote the
quality the signal maybe these are kinda
bad
and this ones kinda good right but maybe
they're still below the noise threshold
that your
a response people can handle but now
you've been able to
since you did identity translation these
network-based events
you know they were user Bob right there
may be other users that could have been
tied to we can talk about that after the
after talk to you want to but
was just say for simplicity that's that
you know that's user Bob
you know that this was his are Bob and
you know this was your about
now all the sudden because the fact that
those are tag with cocaine stage
you now have a much more interesting
correlation than just a bag of things
that an IP address did
so anyway that's just one idea I've had
to do correlation
but there's a bunch okay so recapping on
that part
noisy events are an important part of
the story
right if you're not figuring out a way
to use noisy low quality events
intrusion detections that system you're
doing it wrong
right because you're never gonna be able
to come up with the perfect alert was
gonna wake up in the middle the night
and tell you everything bad is happening
doesn't that's not how it works
right so you need to
you need to really figure out a plan for
how to deal with these noisy events
you you reduce the noise as best you can
to prevent basis by blacklisting
and then you figure out some smart ways
a correlation
okay but we're not done we're not done
there's took two stages left
so afterward of correlation we do think
all applying context
now this is something that came out of
context
didn't even know this is from
yes it's on Star Trek the old one
and I have no idea what this episode was
about but it was really weird
I'm up
anyway context is is really really
important
um because it helps you a
speed-up analysis so what am I talking
about here the ideas like
so you've got these events they've gone
through this pipeline they've gotten
blacklisted they've gotten
improved they've gotten better now yes
some things that you think a pretty good
right at some point somebody's gonna
have to look at those with her eyeballs
right now what you want to do is you
want to minimize the amount of time it
takes for somebody look at those things
with your eyeballs
right because you are these things and
you want to be able to you know
look at as many as you can so cut taxes
such a valuable point
and something to holy missed by most
people
the idea is that as soon as you get to
set up a fence that you think are
important
then you can start pre applying
information
about about it from your environment
that's interesting
a lot of people think well how can I
just get all my data sources together
and build intrusion events
yes but how can you also use those same
sources of data
to apply context an example what if your
system
that was that that had a correlation and
had an interesting event
right what if like what if you want to
see what tasks were running on the
system on a Windows machine
at the time in which you looking at the
event now those
tasks the list of tasks wasn't part of
creating the event in the first place
was actually super valuable when you're
looking at it right
the make sense and so there's actually
put it like that right
maybe some data from your logs maybe
some data from your a network forensics
system right much a peek at the
or I don't know you probably a better
ideas but the point is
applying data before the analyst looks
at it
a can actually make the the announces a
bit much more
a palatable
okay I think cover all this
yeah so I could say you buy some fancy
schmancy better plants you can actually
use that to provide context on events
that thing didn't even create the first
place
most people mister point I'm
okay and then of course analysis so
someone to look at these things
actually you know it's funny the time my
career but I wanted to make so it's a no
humans ever had a look at the stuff
and that you know there would never be a
human in the loop
and I I give up on that after a couple
years a trying
because I don't think that's possible so
this is actually a real picture I think
%uh AT&T
knock which is kind of insane
a this is not what the Facebook a sock
looks like
am but a it's pretty cool picture
anyway the point is you know these
things and you know
you want to be able to look at the
minimum up the
the most impactful most useful offense
as possible
with the most context free flights are
you going to do our work extra lazy
okay this is the end so I'm
as well as a couple things so
one of the things that I've I'm from I
first I'm frustrated about and security
is like you go to our conferences
and everybody is always excited about
talking about the lease o'day
and I mean I think that stuff's really
great and cool but I think the problem
is
like how many talks to go to where
somebody's talking about some cool
def defense thing some cool way to stop
attackers rate
like why is there nobody thinking about
that stuff I mean there's some
don't get me wrong but like it seems
like the security community
really focused on on attacking stuff I
think
partially because defense is hard and I
don't know if we even really know how to
do it right
so um anyway that's like my thing
I think people should spend more time on
figure out how to defense rate because
we're in a very bad state
and I showed him the intrusion detection
numbers earlier but that same
presentation could be made about
defense and in general Anna things are
pretty bad
so anyway thanks I'll take questions
if anybody has any