alright I 0 thank you for coming at this
ridiculously early time in the morning
at eleven thirty
I
I am cause a or talking about
physical drive-by downloads and I'll
explain what that means is I
up oh actually I'm not do this before I
put my company slide
arm I'll battery's dead assignment good
I to a whoever was at the club last
night
fuck you is today's gonna suck for me
so if right now
now I can talk about the company thing I
so I name is Kyle Osborne
I'm a pen tester absecon salting I am we
re tiny little wet
knowledge that we we do word i'm open
dancing shopping either no general web
app
and networ got a little bit a physical
om
where the PCI czarist cited stuff I in
the US and
you know we just were time or place we
have fun breaking Shin
it's fun %ah okay
so jump right into it I am Android user
ecosystem
on and I yet so
I basically there's a huge focus
on sucking on it's pretty much like hey
I'm gonna make myself as
in secure as possible let's do it
aren't so this big focus on rooting
phones I mean
everybody wants to have a root on their
phone Drake you can do fun stuff you can
install app so you can customize said
you can
in the US we have our own I
the carriers ISPR nice piece a cellular
carriers don't like
let you to Heather without paying an
extra money which is
ridiculous like a an extra thirty US
dollars just to
tether your phone to and I gotta start
stop excelling
I actually 30 bucks to tether your phone
to your laptop so you can use your
phone's internet like its ridiculous
fees
our but when you get root you just like
but them I can't either all I want no
big deal so
a lot of people together I as a lot of
untested wrong so there are a lot of
people running around and being like a
look
sign in my school like you know summit
but tons of stuff inside edge Mon and
does but she things
ok by the way here Z unofficial poor
assign engine mods you know install
on your random phone that nobody's ever
heard of I
a lot of ATK's being passed around so
it's a case are basically the
Android package files for I for
applications
I so in the again the US we have a
Verizon who sucks and they don't like
Google Wallet which I know you guys I
have the wallets of you guys but
I love you all being in the US are I
so rising basically says you can have
the wallet because of some sort of
yes insecurity thing when Rio and
group when reality they just don't want
you having
specific applications because they know
either one
you know you can tether with them or to
I they have a better product
I'm sorry better product to give you
survey praying you from using it so much
people are like oh yeah here's the
unofficial version of Google Wallet and
a crew a its an official who the hell
knows
you know what's in there %ah and you
know if the cases are signed
by the developer you can you sign him to
install them and then when you install
them it's all like oh yeah by the way
hey this is an
on you actually to go into settings and
allow
arm I set a policy to allow
arm packages to be inside cyber in and
a bit nobody out nobody knows how to
verify
that they are signed by the de ver
developer and it's just had security
events like
for all your about security we all
%ah action again that a little bit with
C and read but I am
your she security efforts I
are I did a little poll I I who will
serve a
only five years is a sound are but
others 500 users and
the services of read it I'm sure some
you guys know read it I
they were about 500 users that and
service on the subreddit
Android a for Android separate and
seventy percent in the morning rooted
cuz everybody loves being routed I 50s
six-person had ATV enable many be is
were basically gonna
rate a TV today on ATB is the
and reading by bridge it's pretty much
are so many you are too cool things and
you know it's also pretty shitty cuz it
makes you super insecure
I seventy six don't discuss disable a
custom ROM so
thats arms are disc custom recovery so
that's a a
clockworkmod or TWRP year that's
anything that you use to review found a
flash
stuff and then I you know 18 almost neck
ninety percent don't use encryption
like who does that how you not use
encryption but
you know handwritten support encryption
till like three point to you and then
for our own
a bunch people are still stuck on 2.3
that
kinda sucks I forty-one percent
you slide on lock so that is a pass for
you just group your phone's open
no big deal I and then %uh those to %uh
vs surveyed twenty to use the gesture
marc
and a you know the judge you think it's
all i care this is an iPhone so in order
for second
there are like a lucky you a swipe your
fingers like this so often do the same
thing now your phones unlocked
I and then its forty-percent
used some sort of security software anti
virus or
remote tracking wiping whatever arm so
it's
conduct our own survey who has every
year
Anza okay is as much better I was in Nam
Miami another conference I won't mention
names
on but only three people in the audience
at the site had Android
and that should give you an idea of what
type of converts was
arm anyway so love those people that
have Android
whose rooted who has root who has are
are in a few view
how unusual route resort area
I am a gate do you guys have a any sort
a custom recovery our custom mom
wrong likes energy mater a ok AP just
what to she's 34 what's wrong with you
all
on iight so now you guys
and some the other guys on who has
eighty be enabled
biking if you installed Sandidge mara
yes engine Mario Katy
and you can't go on in disable it you
start eighty be enabled and
you know I hope by the into the talk you
go through and be like
I should wanted to say all that now
I real quick process I entered security
so you know they're like
browser exploits a application exploits
are there were a few colonel exploits I
member dipper is one the exploits at
have-we affected a lot about phones
applications
on in San awesome like when you've
if your pen tester and you find a server
that has spent my work on version is but
has
a Vaquero version and you're like shit
number different works as its in C
route it's great are ATB exploits so
race conditions or or whatever
else and then of course there exploits
created by vendors I so or a little bit
ago
arm Samsung decided that they were gonna
install kies
which is there phone management want to
watch people's phones or something like
that and
it created a route exploit so was no
useful for users I guess but
and made them super and secure with
kinda sucks yes
didn't Argus I'm a little behind some
russians miss us or our goals
I I'm not nothing years super awesome
the
whatever I'm not releasing like any
crazy exploits or anything
basically just to quench shit and threw
together and call that cool because
it is cool I so we want real quick we
want the sensitive stuff
we want your password you want your
emails about your text messages without
your photos
does you all know I saw the photos on
phone right
and text messages and and anything else
anything else we can get are and then we
wanna
maintain persistence we wanna go alright
site I I saw all your sensitive
information
now I'm gonna pop something on their
side
ever have to worry about it again and
all that stuff did just gets into me
that's what we want I so wanna ru kid or
some sort of
evil AB game and we want to do this
really really fast
we just wanna be we'll use as fast as
possible
and basically we want to get past this
surer you all at least recognize that
screen
I and workin that a little bit
our and I also foobar my eye test
account so we're actually gonna do this
with
my real account which sucks an airy
I okay so of we're going to talk about
it the doc is physical drive-by
downloads or gonna talk a little bit of
physical access to a revised
everybody knows you access a laptop you
guys know what to do
with the a laptop like when you get a
laptop or computer in your physical
access
you booed up something to either crack
the password for Windows or change the
password a Windows you use some sort
love a recovery software you some
forensic stuff you Paul sensor
information of
we're gonna talk a little bit about that
with Android on
yea so a the secure boot loader are so
basically
I'm as you all know your bootloader is
its kinda makes sense
you know it load shit and it starts at
Boone
on the secure Brewers basically on
Android phones
when you have a secure beware that
basically means a oh yeah you can't boot
anything that
isn't signed by whoever
right arm and you have a stock recovery
partition so
the the recovery partition is basically
used and we'll go over this
recovery partition is basically use for
encrypting things are
over the years updates or whatever and
buy stock
it it just if you don't change it it's
pretty secure like there's not a whole
lot of
things you can do with it when it's a
stop to order just
doesn't do anything arms I soccer
coverage doesn't do anything
from have course I'm leader you're a
trip you know encryption prevents
access to the doin its you know call
booted
by Chiara Chiara is basically the
interface that you see when you
you know have your pin number or pin or
password or gesture marc
on and then ATV and a beast on really
got a kind ever
you know kick a little bit because we
like em I
up so all those things work together
encryption and stock partition
bootloader whatever arm you know one of
those failures basically means that
your shits own i7
secular not all devices have a lot
cooler
on real quick I on three problem
guys probably didn't get that you guys
know each be touchpad
Marin HP was all like oh we have a
tablet and we're cool now
in in they saw so they just fire sale
all their talents for really really
cheap
and they discontinue Web OS did any view
grab one of those tablets
the HP TouchPad and XO
arm so I grabbed if like to have them
and I sold one are straight one from
iPad or something arm had 10 for a while
I sit still
kinda play with delivery once in a while
but the HP TouchPad
does not have a secure border that means
that
I can plug into the USB reboot the
device and be like
okay run this in Iran FS
plus this kernel and it's like yeah no
problem all run this
you know who the hell you on I don't
really care there's no authentication
all just go ahead and run this crawl for
you
no problem the its readers but does not
have a secure do our which
means that I will never ever use it as a
regular tablet because I will never
stick my stuff on there because
that shits in securing like our now a
cycle
are so some Googlers commute unlocked
like I the Galaxy Nexus so
the Galaxy Nexus can be unlocked in just
a a a few seconds
on your thing about that is that once a
Galaxy Nexus unlocked it wipes the
by the the partition so writes the data
partition immediately so
even if it is accessed getting me the
way I saw your data when someone tries
on market
however like the HP TouchPad is on
secure an
there are other devices which don't have
you immediate lock
are any immediate wipe and in all those
factors for being called bring whatever
I like I said recovery partition you
know for
encryption and applying over-the-air
updates and whatever system and shit
arm encryption I
again rebooting tax your shit because on
gifted
no big deal on it does however use the
keyguard
pain and pass and
cue card allows for like four-digit pin
no a pen
and you know really small password also
so
you could conceivably track it pretty
easily
you know see me that they have a small
passer
a so this is a key art it's the whole
gesture thing it prevents immediate
access it
you know Face Unlock yes is
anybody here use face unlock on Android
did you guys see in 4.1 or as the co
Samsung whatever introduced at work you
had to blink
they're all like are yet to print
circular access or whatever and
you have to see your point a picture at
it you actually have to bring
a few times so it knows that
you're actually not a static picture a
some guy got smart
and has a like okay well import my photo
to
Microsoft Paint on it take some on my
skin from my face
that i'm gonna put it over my eyes and
then I'm gonna go back and forth between
the pictures so it looks like I'm
looking
and that unlocks face-off harkin it
yet its it's just a novelty doesn't
where
at like I said earlier pattern smudges
CIA
outlook on your alter phone nobody on I
know we password and has allowed
a the so if you do the gesture of their
about 390,000
a possible gestures by you know they're
are nine different points on it I real
quick I came to that because
okay so you can't do you i cant any two
ways are pointers
I C you can't do 123 unless you go
through to first-rate
in less you go to 13 to
it was really easy to get a lot of that
stuff out and you can't repeat numbers
so
basically when is it limited to three in
ninety thousand
and 390,000 seems like a lot but we're
gonna
talk about in the second and it start
the hash in
read-only or route readable file
only arson system user which you can't
generally access
AB of doesn't provide USB debugging te
connecter in forever
physical factors to order on lock code
non stock recovery partition on a reboot
your phone into recovery
and then I'm a star stealing stuff up
there because it's non-stock and it
isn't secure I like I've encryption you
know
whatever he been able you pretty much
win everything
right so it's not all about the phone
you know the phone is great what a day
to
passwords text messages photos emails
whatever on
it's not the best but we really want
your Google account and I mentioned
before we're gonna
still everything I have care of this
unlock the water white phone whatever
may wipe the phone requires a reboot
it slow it takes a few seconds where arm
if it's already unlocked great you know
uses rebooted
you're set arm sitting with custom
recovery if your custom recovery
just rebooted you're set you to start
stealing stuff I love it
video I somewhat I really care about
is being really really fast like I
art I'll I don't know anything about
last night because I remember anything
my last night
however if any have you remember last
name
are and any if you haven't left your bar
sitting at the table or left your bar
sitting at
Arts I les you left your phone sitting
at a bar left your phone sitting in a
bar
I accidentally maneuvering back Michael
shit I should
like secure you know put this in my
pocket so no one
starts looking through my ASI photos or
something
basically I want that like I won't be
sitting at a bar
I want someone to walk away I just wanna
be with
plug something in their phone and be
like who
now I own everything right arm
and that's where this thing comes as so
USB
OG it's a USB on-the-go cable on
and this basically is it turns your
phone into USB host
which is awesome because now I can plug
things into it and its functional
as some sort of post device
but you know this this will cables
awesome
but it requires another cable on it that
sucks so on
have they the guys I have five if you
don't know how five their arm
ago video security hacker podcasting
arm you know they've got a lotta silly
stuff on there but
they were kind enough to make me this a
so this look a beret here is actually a
host motor filth into the cable to USB
on nickerson mentioned that said a stock
yesterday any caller crossover tape
cable
that's actually pretty much what it is
slates v
it's so simple make a this thing cost
about
70 cents on Amazon any in the US is as
cheap as hell like it's less than a
dollar
on this thing same sort of thing like we
ordered them from China
I like 70 cents a cable that they just
easy it's just a few wires crossed over
and the pains are different or something
now with you this is awesome is now
I can just pretty much be like we at one
time at the bar
I want to bring my laptop to the markets
do this right
as by I how it is here but
if you brought your bar arms a few for
your laptop to the bar or a club
people would be a little weirded out by
it probably won't sit next to you not
because they thought you were
are ya gonna hacked them they will
probably just be like
skies fuckin weird I wanna be next to
this guy he's got his laptop at a bar
I'll that's what this cable facilitates
right we want to be able to walk up
to someone at a bar with a mile without
your laptop it would have you
group and driving on their so
that's where up p2p
phone to phone AB comes in %uh some
engine eighty year and that's basically
and ready by bridge and that
allows you a lot of access device I am
and I bill I calling it a framework
both a framework that basically runs on
your phone
it right now senator milan is actually a
queueing I am
where you just plug in someone's phone
you run a few commands you like to look
at that
our steel all your camera photos who no
big deal
or hey I want it honest you all your
Google informations I wanna see all your
offline emails I wanna see all of your
Google Voice data on a steel
whatever and we deal awesome I
so PVB real quick but so you can still
tons a day to
I still camera photos steel the Google
authentication tokens I steel WPA
supplicant
a doc on them in VPN keys and other
stuff and
a bit you know WPA supplicant stores all
over wifi passers in clear text zone
now you can hop on their wifi and
continue their own other things on there
there's device are you can completely
disable key guard
which is really easy in the it the
Android AP I'm super nice
its three lines echoed so like oh yeah
I'm declaring the
keyguard on what class I'm initiating
the class
please unlocked the the screen for me
nobody of three mind the code on and
then you install custom
AB gays and you could do and
actually done this that's a lie a
haven't done that but basically auto
configure proxies are you being on the
phone
someone pp yes it's me iight are
so about the text through on typists
af dissolve I reinstalled some are rude
stuff
I so basically I from my phone
I can ru a few other phones and there's
no
to in the nose or brush and the other
one member dipper
it's all just you know runs on Linux and
they're all just
shell shit are ever so is no reason I
can't cross compile them to my phone or
whatever and
get all working so your walk around with
the phone that roots other phones
so even if they had he been able there's
something or
me you know you in a way before then you
have roots so you have a limited access
you just plug it in to be like a look at
that your phone is rooted now
which means that I have read on your
phone it's awesome our
cracks the gesture pattern so on you
know the gestion pattern like images
only 390,000
options while for and 390,000
lines in a file along with their hash
only twenty make your life I'll
so I just like a sec calculated all the
potential gestures and I just
may be equally ashes on them so you
actually at the crack anything you just
grab the file for those frat hash and
then responds with the
the code I am and then
I would like to make it a I'm organism
crazy as hell om again engine that a
eventual formation sites want you to be
even like you know
before you plug into a phone be like oh
yeah I want you to
steal the Google Data root there for our
worry their phones your Google Data the
the
payload their phones I want your you
know it's all rooted or whatever and
that's good
and then you know when I plug then it'll
be like only look I detected a phone
summer do all these things now with a
knee surgery he's already
interaction down fun %ah
so I made an app called anti guards so
keyguard anti guard right and seculow
name
arm installs basically the
you plug it in and installs and it
unlocks the phone fucking awesome
arm like I said its that
three lines of code which the and Reiki
I is all I
ok this is a good idea have installed so
we can disable the screen
block for you I and it has a few local
on where arm Ste a be enabled
you're fucked like no big deal like if
you
if you ever left your phone if your
phone is ever lost you know
when I have your say while you're eighty
be enabled you should just
change all your passwords and consider
yourself screwed because
potentially this could have happened on
alright I don't really care about this
stuff I just want you to demos
or on way faster now I'm sorry
really what it is I is I'm really
hungover or drunk still size 12
this on way when
II so AB enable is so when a TV enable
EB is enabled and okay so I you know a
lot of I i get some flak from people
going I am you know we won't
no who runs around with eighty be
enabled on their phone right
so good developer thing like most people
that do that well
pre-match anybody that as ever install
the custom ROM has an able
anybody at the developer has enabled
I'll
and a lot of people out in a broad range
%uh and in reality I wanna you
I want to target those people like I
wanna be like okay
you're a tech guy your also the a
tech guy at this company that I wanna
own
summer follow you to the bar and then
I'm gonna own your phone at the bar by
when you're not watching
has so basically grab all the things on
would applications shit so browser
passwords whatever SMS
wifi password system hash whatever
on and then you know it's all good and
oh yeah
sink Google account
II so again EV no root so sometimes you
have a TV in it ATB enable but you don't
have a real
or in some some instances a when you try
to gain root
it all prompt you so for people
have rooted with their Android phones I
you've probably use the application
superuser dodi BK or super soon got a
big game
basically what that does is it prompts
you to grant ru
to the the application is running it so
there is some sort of authentication
there that I am you know prevent ran an
absolute getting root access
so sometimes you're a the phone will be
like oh hey look you tryna request ru
Paul
on a popup this little thinkin you know
you have the proper what the key
the safety car is enabled if if the
phone is locked you can't
you know grant access to Route so thing
in our room you cancel ATK's
and if you can't sleep UK's you can
force unlock the screen
to you for so long the screen and you go
yes fees grant you permission to my
script that I'm alone US
our if you have a rule you can access
Melissa the slash data stuff
in most interesting things at least but
you can go fit grab the
you know photos you can grab some date
on the SD card on you can install a few
days I guess said and a
fun little stuff the install CA
certificate so if you wanna man in the
middle then our install a proxy you can
just are
doing all that I am in you know you
three and re piya
that and weepy eyes great by you know
all the stuff and slash day to slash
data which is where all your application
data stored
mosser that is not reachable why you so
you need to you
either be that I've kitchenette owns
that they don't for you need to be the
root user to access that data and
you know if you not root whiskered
however entered API
gives you access to her tenure so if
if you install your apka that exports
text messages and contacts and
whatever you can just be like oh yeah
hit a button all your text messages are
being backed up through and really
API and I ever text messages if I having
root
and then I V mentioned a few times the
sink
Google account are so
the your account information is stored
in DS system accounts
and its only readable by the system
users only where ru
arm but it has is really really nice
little
tokens in there that are basically
authentication tokens and they are your
Google account
mushy watch say it so they're just a
missile sequel like the base if the
you know queer whatever us on YouTube
that
tough Fortis once you demoss is much
more fun
my bout laptop is mapped Simon for
getting real quick
comment
so I we have wifi access right
on not gonna get on over wifi and why
our
I probably will I know some guy was a
man in the middling at last yesterday
dick
as fuck with you are yourself arm
how are you are gonna see modify some
stuff yes %uh so
what's inside is a few days ago arm and
another conference that
like an engine which I can say this on
video but
anyway on your we're gonna go ahead and
we're going to use my own Google
accounts and is gonna suck for me
400 yes my Google account
alright I at sea
your from yeah
so you you now
HTTPS that's a good now logged in
actually while Laura this I think I yeah
okay cool
is
ask Katie the 12 nor she shit
hmm again I don't usually do this
I usually plugged into on the cellular
network but I don't have that here
band I trust the cellular network more
than I trust
this network so I disable all the stuff
that ignore security
I Tom cipher device are here
right and sphinxes aspect ratio to this
the
the Galaxy Nexus on need are static
couching Nexus caps this is the
I mean at least I figured out before we
started to rain
apparently my camera doesn't work
anymore comment
missiles psychopathy is a front facing
camera tried that once
not fun
area call Recep forget a plus plus
with camera again nah Michael record you
keep
actually at the covers I know is that I
get from picking up my tablet
and in the whole audience spine every
time I picked it up everybody started
laughing and I'm like why you laughing
in
the guys in the front or alike
a as in america such
conference she I mean home can you get
that I love you
they probably won't be back because I'm
awesome skating
mmm alright so you have your little
tablet rare right and we're gonna use
this and you know this as
kinda stuff right there whatever I am
and we have my app
Rania its
ago this is Peter Beeb
an it's just a buncha shell scripts like
at serious its
the only binaries I included arm
are a few things to just make some
people happy because some people then be
the prerequisites so I just
threw in a few binary so I would stop
getting emails from people saying
I can't run this why can't I run this in
and I
%uh so first of all I wanna prerequisite
things was
arm so this you start work against stock
devices because other some stupid BS
with
pp are with ATV prevents you from doing
a few things
so basically I I threw a busy box
onto the device and busybox isn't like a
talk it up just like core utilities
whatever and
I need some that safer on busy boss is
great and since
up my device is rooted it goes I'll
check that out where ru
this awesome like hell yeah is great
so up what you want to do hey on him
again are going to check will recheck
you for ruining sewing
or yet %uh so not natively ru will
continue escalating privileges with the
sioux binary
that's awesome arm and
you know devices don't have real be like
oh yeah you know limited functionally
whatever that sucks
are so our here like fascist
steal all your application data yeah
calculating the sizeof well I expected
operator
think I broke yesterday I calculating
the sizeof
vote share preferences and databases
folder as awesome
all love them I can pull down all of
your application data right now
and that means that I own you very much
hoc in
broke it last night I was on a plane
I think you're any sleep at all on is
decided that I should start
tryna codes and stuff as a bad idea
bomb so again you know K Ag
apnea but you don't want all your apt it
somewhere after he may have some
you know stupid after okay aren't you
you know
I Angry Bird said game saves I just want
your
every you know I want to get stuff so
we're gonna steal your Google
application data and it's like 0
your dog now measure on that more dot
asterisk shared preferences and
databases so this is your
offline EE you're offline he now is your
com doing I know I know it's like not
thing here but do you use Google Voice I
so you might use it just because you can
contact the people on
and whatever okay Google Voice is
awesome
I'm sorry you know %ah
you know I you get all the good Google
stuff like the stuff that like is linked
to your account
are and then a
you know still camera photos because
everybody knows what I'd
typer photos people take with their
phone I am
parents to accounts which were at doing
is a little bit and then on
what's a just can disable
keyguard so here's my love thing now
I know my password arm and i forgot my
password
no are for that shit was gonna be like
on I'll group wrong all that would suck
sorry mistyped
I was just %uh fuckin US thing
yeah
woohoo comfrey
the ignore whatever and the cool thing
is
as all as all AVI stuff like that's
in the documentation like okay by the
way if you want to disable
the interface do this thing and in this
you know he's three logic oh it's
awesome
arm you know from there you can just
feel like I just wanna you know
honoree your text messages now our or
even better
I'm a star you know going installing and
configuring proxies or whatever but
you know if you're installing shit
already your problem you that
and the nice thing about that is ish
running again
and a just lock your screen you can a
you want to uninstall it is
you know is like a few lines in the log
dated that gets
wiped when you re reboot your phone
analyze its
toy you know unnoticeable is awesome
aren't there is a I do have some ru
function on in there so if you're
running like
4.0 240 1.1 or something
and I I like running a Galaxy Nexus
ordered the Nexus ever ever
it can read devices again like I said on
the only thing preventing me from
throwing on
other routes is that on I'm really lazy
cell oh well I am
arriving on lock pattern right now but
if you have an online patter
some member I said there are only three
in ninety thousand
some very small amount in in reality are
so what I do is just go on you you you
Rep
the hash file against a file that I have
and it's all like or yeah by the way
here's your unlock code
so the unlock code I'm sorry user just
about it the
the unlock adjust your parents is
insulted on
the all this stuff you know the the pain
and the password
arse or they have assault so it's you
know it's and it's really big it's like
a
8 eight bytes or something so that makes
it free infeasible
even if they have a a pretty small are
exited the facts
yet pretty infeasible even if they have
a small password arm
to generate you know allister remote a
border and that's why we have salts
arm but the gesture pattern Sherman they
were right now
because shit school hmm
and I got a disabled after want one of
my I'll my own things on my show you
some mitigation tactics and all that is
I always forget to
what encryption Poor's I was have got
from clustering could do this or
something arm
mmm wanna the I am the medication
examine issues
on out like just you know I i forget to
disable a TV all the time
is always doing and Richard uses I it's
like a security
our research platform it for me and its
arm
his water Nuss fun all around are you so
much I do
development on it so I always forget to
disable Abul
again AB's hard to remember disable
right
right so I just enable the gesture
pattern
I don't even what is it however now I
wasn't paying attention when I made it
so we're just gonna be IIIA get the
gesture pattern pwease
I'll look at that gestion patter is
0 0 0
12 4678 how that's a hard question
better
you know you can never cracked back
that's like really long range
now are 0 one to you
for 6 7
a only that issue just better
really easy yeah it's
its I A its its
can a stupid relates I don't know why
they don't solve it like the
a pass or in the pan like it seems like
that would be
a smart thing to do but they just throw
the sha-1
hash into a file without any cell call
good
its I'm not sure why
alright now
now I'm going to screw myself over
so we're gonna go ahead and hit number
five I
steel accounts of sucks is gonna reset
all my passwords across all my devices
are due back in
dear all I am shit you not
actually came do that on that account I
just realized
a yeah I i apologize for doing this
earlier com I hate
everything wanna be that was at the
party last name this I blame you all as
to why I need to
do this I'm on my journey do right now
up
now
who
on or aunt har
Jesus Christ's and
I N
I give up and even yeah I mean do this
cuz otherwise you're gonna get my
secret tokens si quien
in our feel comfortable with that
someone do this for a second
no offense
I am at all but I don't stress
any view had him know why
I a its do my
which one would you mind one you know
has my Twitter account chick
thats conference friendly alright
so that his number the
I'm sorry so its you
organ I
have few you say is love so aren't you
the same
are sings news
nor the are
okay so basically it is the quick script
the notes stupid simple whatever saddam
72 has to be this cuz someone edited and
was all like
your dog i fix it for you so hopefully
this works
good arm we do that's we're gonna grab
and and this is just limited this is
actually more like a
at proof of concept and it is like an
actual attacks you because it basically
is gonna
cool you show call you who
show you cool shit wherever for this
shit on
I'm going home so we want to throw it in
Jerry
of so we think this is the most recent
one
are ok area
I fucked up on some things here I S et
proof of concept file
this is a and right so okay so
what this does is I should be the slide
earlier nom
Brockway oh yah RT I'm Way behind
I'm really drunk still arm took out do
this shit
well you know the shits right there and
you know you make this request
and so you are get this giant fuckin URL
are what this giant euros basically on
a single sign-on token so the single
sign-on token is awesome because
fuckin one single sign scrape ever click
the shit
there are like your dog was what is was
just too
were what is this I don't even up check
that out
just love me know my count out entering
a password that saw some
and so
so that's really like okay but see
really fucking hate the guy that you're
doing this with Ray
and you just wanna be if they see you
had their token and then you just can
kinda browse around their account the
route to him and everything's fuckin out
even
on a sizzling which kept him in sorry I
just love you
%uh you I i cool unlike in an account
somewhere whatever I is great
now I can just access their account over
and over again i gets to everything I
can go to Gmail again
you know do whatever the hell I want not
a big deal yeah it's like them on Gmail
of
you're not carry my emails workers at
Pearson to fuck me over after
up but what if you really wanna just
kinda the case of the guy
I what if you want to if you wanna piss
him off gonna ruin him if you are you
ever
first get I really just want to take
over his account so I'll exchanges
password
of man current password
I don't know what is password is because
I have his token
that's no fun but only check it out
all right now this is my phone or if you
wanna
I smile your phone can't arm
this is this is like a backup accounts I
am in care
are she wrote columns gonna
you know changes phone number so than I
can do that all
you know or I'm gonna chases recovery
address psyche again a setback account
for
you order please don't hack me arm
in some skinnies recovery address or
changes even I just as awesome so that I
could just change it to me into that
or take it security question check that
out
on I can edit his security question
remember that for me are day
actually no don't remember that
anybody has our laptop out like you sir
in the Faroe
I have to ask you to stop what you're
doing
ok your account information has been
for the update its 8 on your I can be a
I'm gonna go to ran open up a new
browser window and we're going to go to
you
email the new browser window up for it
you know whatever don't know your
password
core taxes down I don't count what is my
all are my I don't know your password on
a reset
I can get a text messages
I could change the phone number I can
Changi email address
or up you know what's your security
question mom
that's nice sorry
and show yeah
so based on a token you know you can
pretty much and that's one of the things
that a Tory
like I try to tell people when they're
like oh you know whatever Android phone
%um my phone only has a little bit of
information I now I get your whole
Google account like it
everything you are done with like I take
up the good work out whatever
no big deal right %ah so one he
um fun things out ship my time is up
okay we're gonna roger is for a quick
I'm sorry I said you
fuck you offer last night arm so one of
the fun things is this completely
bypasses
two-factor authentication there's it
doesn't matter you can control you can
make application-specific passwords
because
this issue this is in
application-specific passer this is a
token
she doesn't matter UN I on your shit
agee
getting Google account without ru
basically HTTPS proxy plus doing a few
other things
%uh CA sur you can basically just feel
the same token that's
I mean this request was takin from
opening up the browser and hitting our
login to your Gmail account so
its its dumb simple to grab it if you
have
access or proxy or whatever %ah
see how else %uh if you have a Google
account
and you you know add it to your phone
with the password with a
whatever I it restores all your wifi
passwords from the cloud
in cleartext so you can grab all their
wifi passwords from the cloud and
added to your device which is nice arm
you know a few other
shit thats resort arm I'll mention not
root there
is a root exploit in their own ever on
you there are more that can be added
and it's only in where my retested I did
the demo
occurs on dumb I saw other tack factors
there's a guy named
layer Riverside that do this called use
jacking it the
at Def Con basically they made this
little boo box
were they have charged parts and people
plug in their phone to charge their
phone
event and then it shows their device ID
on the hay
I sounds like a while I just looking for
some logic in there too ownership that's
cool
up another tech sector down the
computers are small nowadays
and they can be run of a batteries so I
just throat and some
a little energizer pack Creighton River
I want to the souls and replace the cell
with the
the the stein your computer that's
awesome because like video games
ok a with this here's a
I X Box controller you here if you put
this into your phone you can play video
games on your phone vs fucking troll
by the way I just I can ever replace the
internals are the Xbox controller
with that hadn't I need computer OSM
how future shit doesn't matter arm this
guy
if you if you guys don't like shell or
whatever but if you ever run your phone
there's a guy name cornholio that I
every loss at the helm why that the
just a native app whatever call you hit
buttons and it does cause a basically to
all my shit through
inside a nap it's awesome check out some
stores art mitigation
but stop fucking things like don't root
your phone it's done
obstruction it's awesome like root your
phone that's great on
disable ADB when you're done whatever
locked bootloader if you can
flash stock recovery image enable
encryption and then %uh
huffing if you recognize this but I who
your phone your hand
if you recognize that it's a reviewed
its a
smaller video where they own an iPhone
with the winners exploits quarry
on mitigation ABT secure which
some guy busybox package manager is open
source basically turn your first of your
screen
and locks the phone when you unlock your
screen are
well ass fucked retarded when you off
the screen it turns off AB when you
on what the screen it turns on AE is
kinda cool thing
rights issues for hot that's over
I'm good thank you all all the code is
up at my get her
k osborn our cause thought I O the cause
on Twitter
my company and shit whatever done thank
you
of
one fun thing I if you use ATB
I'm sorry fuse ppb I XD a developer's
called
PDP a hot second find it see developers
they called PDP ATV a
for shit a malicious toolkit
for did by a TBD secure so they wrote an
article about how an evil hacker
and how ABT's if you wanna be cool a
malicious talk it by me
was founded in the wild by xt800
furs anyway that's all I got goodbye
don't pack my shit for use