so
I like to welcome you to
to los toques of the first day of
hey Stace am I'm going to talk about 50
who reviews
and yesterday when we were and that the
speaker stand her
long-term Khaliq mine told me well your
topic is very
alt very dusty and I want com
to this talk because it might be very
boring and
so I'm very glad that so many people are
using at full
maps and or lost in this room instead of
the other one
am hmm well of course final review sees
is a very traditional topics in in my
opinion am
what I think we have a lot of experience
collected in the last
two decades and I'd like to present you
some of our experience
in this field am after
a quick introduction I'm going to
explained
our approach to do the modeling of I
will rule cents to do the reviews
and then we have fan of time indents we
me ask some questions hmm
the first of all where my my name is
Mark Reuss I'm here from Switzerland
am I'm for the third time
presenting text ace am I E
them and co owner of a
company colts keep in Zurich your
provide consulting services and
you're doing some auditing in forensics
and i have a web sites and
I wrote some books about the topic well
the goal of a final rule review is
you you want to determine in secure
roofs to increase security you want
it to determine the fish into strong
rules and obsolete rules
and if you are able to to identify those
rules
you are going or you will be able to
improve the quality of you finally
so I will show you different approaches
and
our missile vote see how we approach
final reviews
and it's the time allows it I'm going to
present you some thirty possibilities
basic question is so five rules rules
obsolete or or or firewalls elites you
dismay will saw
a quick shorts shitstorm in the
blogosphere and on Twitter
and many people think that fireballs are
obsolete and
and it doesn't make sense to use finals
at all I don't really share this opinion
I think
flywheel this is a good good way to
improve
network security and but of course you
shouldn't
rely on on firewalls only or or
anti-virus encryption whatever
it sits in should be in holistic
approach which
yeah respects all different kinds of
of threats and and possibilities am of
course if you're
the core of your network and Europe
occasions the secure
you wouldn't have to use firewalls
because everything would be perfect but
we don't live in a perfect world so I
will smite
help do to improve security of your
environment the so the steps
that all required it's to do if I will
do so a rule analysis
and weak will go through them first of
all you have to extract
am or to I'm
sorry first full you have to extract if
I will roots
and then you can work but if I wouldn't
suit you can
may be able to parse the 50 who sets by
six different objects and services and
stuff like that
and then you might be able to determine
global settings
which leads to the possibility to
identify weaknesses and to eliminate
them
hmm and they are
different approaches how to to work if I
will sometime
sets we prefer exported files that means
we go we say a customer's TV
has to send us that the configuration
setting rules at the office final
because it's much faster its more
reliable and to you don't have to I'm
use a face abstraction layer from
and I will come to that later but still
screenshots might be a good idea on
on-site analysis where you sit in front
of the
the front end of the 500 you got me said
walk through it
you might be able to enhance your report
this ritual
suspects and it's usually much easier to
do some cross checks
if you want to our stuff I will sex and
you have some implications
it's usually goods to see yes %um flick
simply
cation correct also on the using to fix
and sometimes to lost ok because term
you only can work with the using to face
because
the some firewalls don't allow you to
exports the rule sets properly
or you will get the cookie file formats
which
you you notes able to parse and so it's
to lost hope 22 approached her the sixth
getting the final rule sets is not easy
and it's different
on every different product as you can
see a star has
for example three different ways to
export the file room sets
and the funny thing is a.m. DC three
different race won't
and collects the exact same rule sets
you will get lots of the data will be
the same
but there are some differences since
defense
how to customer was able to export to
sets
what you can do visit and that there are
different formats
whether you to an export this to a
script which use
pretty much on document 232 the the
backup and restore on the
reporting interface am
yeah it's it's a I'm usually to
customers responsible to bring us the
bring us to if I will set and we have to
give him a step-by-step
how to an aunt's sometimes it's not that
easy because
for different reasons he complex s
different services or TCS disabled
services are you hassen
very old product that doesn't support
for example SSH or
or whatever so sometimes it's it's a
pizza hearts to
communicate if the customer to gets the
data that this
important for you written
if you get the final rule set to export
its there's two next
problem approaching it's that the
different
products use different formats for the
final 16
so for example Astaro checkpoint to 40k
test array-based
I'm rule sets which is primarily cool
what's
sometimes hard to read if you don't
parse it
am I personally prefer
command line based who sets because they
are very simple one-line one group
as he's cool into tech sexy the
NetScaler or
very popular and some products you see
any files
a most popular examples or McAfee
and SonicWALL and you know it's very
traditional but
it works am what's very different
or a very exciting kiss that McAfee Web
Gateway
provides a.m. the file in the XML file
as an export what inside XML file
is is in bed with oren encapsulated in
any fine
so we're they say are able to export XML
file spot
basically it's just a container for any
files
and and you have very different a.m.
on the standings for XML files ever look
less excuse the stand total trust my
a.m. all use XML file spot that the
config format this is very different and
to have a very different approach out to
creates the whole whole construct so am
if you are able to put to write the
parser for final rule sets you
usually or you never are able to use the
same person for the from product
so this is an example of this call Sam
as you can see 191 room basically
I like that because it's very simple and
simple this sole risk with
missus a.m. part of an offer to take
foreign cool sets
as you can see it's more like a tree
it's it's I'm
you are able to to to do connections and
to do more complex toughened and it
makes it much harder to understand the
final rule set mint workers
especially if you if you have posted
so the basic attributes of a final rule
for me is is you have to source host
cornett
if the source port destination host
taste nation port
a protocol on the nixon it's a conceit
your
some firewall allow additional a.m.
attributes for rules for example you can
defined time frames are you can define
priorities quality of service
whatever and and that's very very nice
to have a specially if you if you want
to improve the security of your
environment
what if I will rule analysis becomes
much much more complex if you have
attributes which are kind of exotic if
we do a very simplified 50 who
analysis re focus on the the six
basic attributes water if there is a
product which
introduce a certain and additional
functionality
we try to to respect that to rent
sometimes it's not easy because you
don't really understand what
what is important and how the difference
features work so then we try
to to create table based for most of the
final
rule set this a very simplified form as
you can see two
26 basic attributes if I will rue
again we try to find weaknesses in these
rules
cents this or few of the things
on our checklist we are trying to
identify a
the worst thing basically or any rules
which allow any traffic
and there are I'm more complex
weaknesses like him
mashup of of objects for example if you
have for
in one room a high security system
and also some some kind of public
service is defined in one group went and
the same rule is a fight for both
objects
what they aren't very at the same level
of security it's it's it's very
problematic
am and of course we try to identify and
secure rules
if you use burials COO protocols
something Christian or overlapping
objects and
and stuff like that
I'm am
usually do you have to half a lot of
experience in the network for youth and
application security field from the
stands how
a.m. the sweetness this really affect
the final rule set that means
and most of that the the keister do 250
rule analysis at our company our coming
from from the network
and day on the stand the problem staff
integrate its file system so they have
maintain maintain stem so it's its
makes them lot of a better for hats
to understand what the problems might be
then we try to identify beastie said her
insecurities
for example then you are some
here and we try to identify the risk for
the different groups
and then we suggest counties risks might
be mitigated
am of course from the stands that the
talking that work for customer you have
to understand the processes you have to
understand
lay out the quality of the network so
sometimes are subsistence
are a not respecting these details
so it's it's often so that the custom
assessor no we can't implement this
because this product's
has to use telnet because it doesn't
support SSH
and stuff like that but usually that the
primary goal is to
to tighten the the the rule sets as far
as possible
without destructing the the daily Daily
Worker
daily traffic on the network
a simple final rule analysis of an
inline element this is very simple
a.m. what most customers try to remove
redundant 50 environments
and then if you have to do if I will
room analysis you have to respect that
go there are two different file false
and
basically they have to have to the same
rule set
what it's not easy if you have hi writ
redundancy and you have to very fine
cross check if the rules are exactly the
same
it takes quite a lot of work or you have
to do a lot of parsing
am and in most cases when a customer
sese
there for redundant system and 05 also
reinstalled
exactly the same that's that's never
true it's only true if they do it's
automatically if they have scripts which
are murdering that the system and the
rules
but if they try to do it manually it
always face
that's always differences home from an
attacker point through
of you it's usually interesting because
if you have if I will whose established
and 50 a
and notices established in FY will be
New Hope to
gets the traffic to I will be because
there are
you aren't limited just this post
another level of complexity comes this
morty to file a false
no final allows a direct connection
between two points
if you have a single tear 50 its or an
inline element
you have for on a which communicates
through final to point B
and if you have a mole move to TX am
environment yes
multiple firewalls change together and
dis
introduces additional complexity
because you have to consider every tear
and effort grows exponentially Coast you
have to
I'm if you if you put different finals
in line
printing them you have some kind of my
shop both routes
sometimes there is a rumor on the first
five won't it a sin to rule on the
second final
sometime it's what sometimes their room
on the
on both fireballs do have to find out
what what kind of traffic really goes
through all these elements are all the
same
don't this difference i wills
furthermore
the you have to to find out what the
priorities of the final rule set
sometimes
the for example if you have to file who
which
from is combined this intrusion
prevention system
and the next 50 isn't I'm
it sometime really hard to find out what
they're really that that the real world
work that that if I will rue said is
that this really established in the real
world
so because it's really hot from from
from
reviewer point if you to understand the
whole complexity of the system
we always suggest and sits citrus them
towards our customers to do a workshop
to discuss our findings
discuss our approach to discuss what
what ideas we have
and them sometimes the customer can def
very good feedback more information
about the network topology or routing
expects
and then you realize that some bility
sorry kisses
you over referring to aren't 3d
established in in the real world
a firewall aren't that simple anymore
like
let's say 15 twenty years ago
you have a lot of of additional features
I'm antivirus or a graph cashing
HTTP proxy capabilities and
mmm many finals allow global settings
for example you can define okay I wanna
enable anti-virus for all communications
or
I wanna enable out of date for this
antivirus
so 50 through an analysis
also have to to respect these global
settings and
am sometimes they're not part Ulster the
basics I will who
sometimes there are part of an
additional config file and you have to
find out the K
SonicWALL this is them storing the
starter there and if you have
to collect all the data and sometimes
it's really not easy especially
if customer comes to Aus we a product
that the
never have to test it before we usually
have a few days to find out how this
product really works and and how we get
to to date it is important for us
for the global settings we a.m. after
same approach
like for for consideration re reviews
BR identifying all different setting
state or
a provide its then we identified the
current value
the determined the recommended value the
value that the
recommends to increase the level
security and if there's a difference
3 am provides
a risk rating for this potential
weakness
so if you have gone the 50 who'll
analysis
of the of the traditional roots and you
if you have for
done the context review of the global
settings
a.m. gift the recommendations to the
customer
and he's going to implement most of them
hopefully or all
am but there are rules remaining some
rules
can't be talks because they must be like
they are or
or at the new rules to improve truce or
has the best level of security but they
have to be like they are because you're
he wants to provide the service so a.m.
our idea is to two were to
rates the remaining rules or or to rate
the established rules and we have
different approaches in
re aren't really some
didn't really came to a conclusion we
are still experimenting a bit
in this field so a one of the approaches
is to use a CVSS
to rates the difference rules and here
is a
very simple example 4 a.m.
typical connect are typical connections
over 50
a.m. and the scoring should help you
to see okay this kind of communication
is the most severe arista most risky
because
there are very that the system so very
important
or or very insecure services or provided
or
I'm you have to a very whites
attackers attack surface so this live
least would help you to identify rules
reach if you can cooks
you shoot disable them and use
difference
different approach to provide dating you
network
so with its a lot of I will reviews and
Trites to arm collect some statistical
data on
here concede findings the different
thanks you're
looking for this article est am
and disc graphic illustrates that
the two different thinks and there are
problems
reach usually effects most customers I'm
typical pro problems or protector
logging off rule seasoned relating able
to
and any rules is something that you find
everywhere
sometimes sooner or later
and this graphic shows the
most order to the findings that we see
the most
any rules by the exxon Paris again
any rules with the destination
complaints and
am so relieved that than any finding is
always a high signing in
be always report it and think that that
that that's not correct because
that's not the type 50 who set to if you
want to use any real secret to her
go to a simple Lutheran it and this
basically same
when we do if I will analysis for the
first time
a.m. we see or we have
if you stand to pick up a pro Texas at
least see on the truth
we see for the first time analysis
between 20 and 30 percent of the rules
that contain we can assess can be such a
store customers through and anally
analysis and really
especially stiff tool set too so waz
them changed and there are improvements
we cease we still see between seven and
10 percent
weakness a single-sex am
is a test to do a.m. and analysis once a
year
am a full analysis and
a.m. it make sense if you have thirty
changes or
large changes to do in an incremental
analysis of the changes
so why are there so many problems in
finals I mean
the top because old and dusty ascites in
the beginning
am but still we are failing is the same
problems that the
10 twenty years ago there are many
mistakes
a lot of laziness am
and a lot of misinformation and
misunderstanding
especially if you loss environments
corporate environments it's not
on usual that that that the person that
implements a product
doesn't really know which kind of ports
that are required and defender
States okay we Nizza 30,000 ports
to communicate this to different host
its not
unusual and because time missus precious
stay put in any rule or a very vice
definition of ports and
yeah that makes rules much insecure
so that what's my presentation I
like to summary if I will also be
important extraction parsing at the
sectional final who set this is
very interesting thing and that I think
it makes sense
to to work if I wasn't try to improve
them because they are still an important
part in at work
and we always see the same week missus
over and over again
that's not a problem for for us because
it makes
are drop a bit easier but that's a
problem for the customers
term your because it's its seems that's
very hard to
to improve for them a.m.
yeah and and a good firewall rule
analysis respects the ferry for less
pacts
term offer 50 who like room common sense
looking
or any less important assess if you have
for wrote definition of ports or if
you're
use you
there is some documentation how we do
that its
everything is on German sorry for that
and
and I State Park