here we go and today I would like to
share with you and bout some I would say
more like an educational lecture nothing
new probably nothing special for you
because I'm combining information from
different sources about the interesting
expressions of attacks attacks on
Android apps attacks which look more or
less you know effective one of the in
Android apps we have a lot of
vulnerabilities which are sort of like
vulnerabilities of extracting
information and things like that it
sounds pretty boring you can get our
information you can basically extract
any information but here I would like to
share about how applications may affect
other apps I think it's interesting and
if you'd like to begin to get a little
bit more knowledge about mobile apps and
Android apps this would be a good
starting point so here we go I would
like to share a couple words about
myself I am the employee of alarm
company I'm doing pen testing and the
security analysis said these are the
links to my telegram you can write me
you can ask me anything we have our own
chat and generally you can discuss
different things and the guys write in
different questions and of course email
which nobody seems to be using any more
today anyway
the scope of my presentation is the
following I would like everyone who
would like to go back to this
presentation will be able to understand
it all without me and to sort of like
refresh this material in any way you
want all the way to details or just
simply to scan this presentation again
so I will upload this presentation on my
telegram channel maybe somewhere else
you'll be able to get it from the
conference organizers and in
descriptions you will find a detailed
description of what will be delivered
today
in my presentation all the names and
everything else and also while compiling
my presentation I did it in such a way
that if there'll be any questions about
any topic I would give you a detailed
answer now as I will be sharing I will
be sharing I guess two
with the flow but in the future if you
want to get more knowledge about
particular topic you can take the take
the topic and go to the description of
my slides there is a lot of information
hypertext and links and all you name it
and I've given a spoiler we're speaking
about Android Android apps communication
apps intercommunication 2 plus and I
will be assuring about attacks
techniques on this internet
communication process I'll give you
examples so I will show you a video of
how it is all happening shooting running
and doing all sorts of things and in the
same way I would like to give you an
understanding of how these attacks
happens this attacks from app to app
happen but actually I was questioning
myself I was asking many of my experts
and friends what are the models
attackers models was an Android system I
you know I said usually like to it's an
app and human human can get my phone
number do something with it
with an app to extract something or the
app which has been installed in some how
it may affect my operational system and
as a part of this model or violations
described in mobile security project
there is this kind of division looks so
very interesting and here we say not
only like robot versus human but also
the human with what kind of rights and
what can a robot be discrete beat an app
beat text message or is something else
and I think that you can go to it if you
want to work even with documents or you
can go to these kind of slides so you
can go to a mobile security project to
understand to understand who could be
the initiator of this app attacks next
the tools like I said before I would
like to make this presentation as clear
as detailed so that you'll be able to
use it in the future for the future
reference these are the tools for their
checks and their attacks double checks
Android studio would
number one it gives the emulator with
the device with an app and you can play
you can attack and different things
secondly enjoy a debug bridge it's a
it's a tool
fixing tool I there is nothing really to
compare it always because it can do
anything it's very intuitive great
documentation for each ship like
whatever it's tuned you can figure it
out and obviously is a trouser it's a
good app this app is playing as a client
in a mobile device there is it's an
external app that you can do something
you can build this kind of trouser
client and on behalf of the client you
you can play as the threatened app you
have a server part which is like playing
this rosary basically like agent client
and and then the client will be the
choice or agent would be your device
it's a very popular thing quite simple
for the matter and so I split my
presentation into parts number one
explain how it happens why it happens
and how it looks like how you can fix it
and things like that I'm trying to
explain it in a very simple common
language I hope you will not get bored
and the second part is attacks I will
give demos it's a real meat of my
presentation how it works with a video
and why and everything else
what are we speaking about today it's
about activities intense and I'm going
to share with you what activity is all
about I can see my friends and
colleagues they have no idea what
activity intents is all about so I guess
I'm going to address them Android app
has several components which are part of
this application from each to each
application one of these components is
activity this would be the main screen
basically the screen of your app a page
where you have certain operation going
on so basically a directions section of
this activity in the operation and by
activity
I mean execution of certain action you
have the burbank application for example
where you go to the main screen you can
see the main activity which is giving
you chance to authenticate then you go
to activity to look for your amount
your money transfers etc etc these are
the simple operations which can be split
apart usually the app consists of many
activities some any big activity or any
serious application in several
activities not one like I said before
you have the main operation which has
been detected in manifest file then I
want to show you how it looks like and
there are different descriptions of the
activities lifecycle in Android system
and the approach is that there's an
event based system when something
happens we react on it and all the
applications are based on the fact of us
creating a handler that has some code
upon launching an activity or activities
each and every activity it can be a
class in Java or set of classes they can
be used or reused and so on so to
simplify your on this for your
understanding activity can be
represented as Java class with some
functions like on create on launch on
calls whatever so when you announce
initialize system knows about all the
activities of the application you have a
manifest file that regulates everything
that can happen within an application
all it's that the Android needs to see
and the main one is activity and as I
said it's part of the application it's
in the folder with an application
activity has a name only mandatory
parameter which is the name of you can
also add other attributes external
attributes to an activity that help us
simplify the communication between
applications we will consider them a bit
later ok that's more for you to
understand an activity the operations
that you have on the screen of your PC
receive on the sense that you can call
interoperate with them through other
applications it's in the inter process
communication you can call the
activities of other applications here
for example you know he transferred to
you book a car and then you move to your
box drive and where you can you manage
the car rental so you called one
application from an activity or another
application if the activity complies
with some addictions one condition is an
intent filter an option for external
applications to call your activity so
you need to describe that intent filter
as part of your or your manifest file
I'm doing a little bit on abstract
overview but give me a moment and we
will go into detail so this activity can
be called I will describe an exception
but in general it can be called by any
external application so for some
activities you don't need to put this
filter because activity can yes besides
showing you some information also launch
some actions especially if you have an
expert attribute if you want the intent
filter to to work only with your own
application then you set an expert to
false and now nothing else can trigger
this activity if you nonce and false
then any activity can trigger it
if the intents are the same so intent is
the direct mechanism for
inter application interfere bility the
applications in android can send
messages to each other to run something
for example an application can send an
intent to open some other application
like yeah that's Drive opening page or
on a service
another component like music file
download things like that so if this
service is exportable that the other
application can't launch it and it's not
recommended because these are kind of
monitor they're running on the
background and any application will be
able to launch this service downloading
files and so forth and to send broadcast
messages also it's one of the mechanisms
for Android applications is like
broadcast receivers the service that I
label you to subscribe to some events
like battery level the battery is 15% is
sent to the whole system and all the
applications that are subscribed to
those messages and events will receive
it a lot of applications can generate a
lot of all those IPC things may create a
lot of vulnerabilities of course this is
what we will be talking more details
about intense it's not so that's simple
as I said you can trigger this from
other applications but you need to take
into account some things and I will tell
you more details now there are two types
of intents direct intent and indirect
intent the direct ones have
some are triggering some specific class
like in heroes members Burbank
application you have a screen with your
balance and to call it you specify the
class or the Java class of this object
and you address it you can get all the
exported activities of course if the
expert it flag is true then I can put
this part of code and your application
and call the intent sending the download
service to it
you have your right here to it you have
your right here and you start the
service and the most interesting part is
indirect intent it's when you address
not to some specific object or operation
but to some better request to handle
some interaction like open PDF and
everything application that can to this
will be proposed to tirado's you see
this many open PDF so you have all the
applications that you can use to open it
so one application launched an indirect
intent with open PDF action and three
applications are signed up for this and
they say they can process it so they're
shown to you as options if if it's only
one then it's open but the calls like
photo calling the numbers usually open
it through a phone app but if you have
two applications like the Skype you will
have to
of course if you specify the intent
directly then there's only one
application running it and indirect
intent without any data sent and then
you give it an action like actions have
some action for sending a message or
some data some extra parameters it's
another feature of those intents you can
send some parameters send some data and
they can affect the logic of executing
the application and then you start
activity and launch some activity the
same will happen when you want to launch
some service or drop a broadcast
receiver how does enjoy it is react to
direct and indirect intent with a direct
bomb we've explained it with an indirect
not it rolls a request to the system to
process it and what is important here is
that direct intent don't actually save
you protect you from vulnerabilities
here because if you have an object that
runs some malicious activity then you
can launch it with both the direct
intent and the intent filter and it
shows which actions need to be done for
the operating system to process the
intent let me check the right did not
forget to mention everything that's on
the slide
so the activity here is not exported
even if we insert it directly we cannot
launch it because it's not exported and
it cannot be launched by another
application just reminded here for the
developers and experts component access
restrictions through intent we can't
define it for this specific action say
it needs to parameters of data the
category to launch such filters do not
provide for security you can limit the
choice but every time you define that
filter without saying expertise is false
you always provide an option before this
component component to be cold and
here's an example of attack will work
with specific attacks here I hope you
understood the IPC processes some
services that they can attack and give
you some examples of in the buyer and
wild attacks will we saw them first
example is its attacks on exposed
activities with export flag true or
intent filter that allows allows them
using some intent to launch using some
intent on the Left there's an example
of Sakura Bannock be too insecure
Bentley - which is a breach to emulate
and all the militants I don't know
anything that would look like a real
banking application you don't need to
create some specific abstractions to the
vulnerabilities out there you just know
you need to go find them and exploit
them so here we have an activity with
the expert flag true meaning every
application can launch it below is an
explicit intent so you don't have an
intent filter which is used only when
it's in explicit intent here we only
have an application of class we have the
full name of this activity we can
address it using our Android debug
bridge we run shell Android has a tool
service called activity manager I am I
am start the launchers the activity M
means it should be explicitly called
then the name of the class that
processes this activity then - E is an
extra string parameter you name with the
name Jack then we see that the community
was launched
here we have logging we can address the
activities that are responsible the view
statement activity that is responsible
for balance then we close it i launch
the adb shell code it's on the screen
and it works if we have extra privileges
we can read what was there on the screen
if there were some actions then we could
call it and run those actions let me
show you
vivid example such an attack there's a
an article by Adam Gazette of intense
proofing in Android he worked in Google
security team working with Android
applications they took 500 popular
applications filtered them and they saw
pay park application allowing the users
to send money within the system but it
has a vulnerability the activity for
money sending interface was exported
exportable and any application could
trigger it and show the user the screen
with its balance also allowed for the
string parameters to be sent
like from whom to whom how much so an
external application installed on this
device could launch this screen filling
the data they needed do anything
but if we're on this trick on 10,000
devices significant portion of this
users will press the big red button send
it will have a small cancel button on
the left and the same tip will have a
big red cent
so it's social engineering feat it was
and there's a lot of other examples of
activities launching other actions next
time we can drop some intense into the
system but also there are intense that
are responsible for sending the intends
to broadcast receivers so when we would
like to run this intent so that all
broadcast receivers get this information
we need to run broadcast intent in
Android system every application that is
subscribed to this broadcast intent will
receive this information and here
example from insecure bank we - we have
a receiver and broadcast receiver which
is subscribed to the in broadcast event
its exported so it can get some data and
the application will send can send it to
its way send data and there is intent
filter which expects that with this
section the broadcast receiver will
receive it and run some actions on the
right there is a code for application
sending the phone number and the
password to send the user the updated
password information so the application
works updating using broadcast receiver
so how do you run this sniffing attack
it's a great video here the only issues
they need to run it so here I login into
the application enter some data launch
the browser and emulate live for an
application run sniffing module specify
the action I would like to listen to now
I need to launch the password change
activity that changes it I press change
posture and everyone who is subscribed
to this event gets this data well it's
not a very serious example I don't think
everyone changes their passwords through
broadcast but there are in the wild
Gamble's of Showtime's for example when
you use the search the intent to update
the show times applications was
published so you could listen to all of
them and other applications could listen
to what films you are looking for heads
conversion unfortunately even though
those attacks are popular and
interesting there's not many good
examples of those and yeah my next step
would be to maybe create some good
examples but I'm too lazy to to make it
happen anyways worth trying next type of
attacks its intent injection attack we
saw a little bit earlier it's related to
call some
some intent that the applications are
subscribed to so you can generate intent
or choose intense that you can address
from the other applications so here's
the same broad because that we saw
earlier we saw how the application works
with it you know we can make the
application run those actions by
dropping our own intent to change
passwords so to the left you see an
injection and to the right you see a
cold simplified code that runs when you
receive an intent to run this you need
to send a phone number string attribute
and any of us what do you send it it
checks that the phone was sent and then
the password has changed and so let me
show how it's run live example we have
an application I log in I just check
that my password works to the right is a
console let me check if the state is
running I describe the intent here and I
choose change the password and had to
strength parameters run it
and now I see the information received
about the posture changed so I see it as
a message here that launched the
broadcast receiver and changed the
password from of Antonio all those types
of attacks they are quite vivid and you
see that the applications interoperate
and can attack and Android has a lot of
examples of inter inter process
collaboration interoperability and the
way Android does not have any of those
you can also exchange data between
applications a good review of yeah
that's my bail application team has just
provided on their conferences same with
vulnerability is the Droid advantage of
when you protect the external perimeter
not in pic Android fan guru but I'm just
interested in this topic and I'm really
more doing web application protection
and the reason why I went into Android
is because pretty much every service has
no client which client which looks the
same as a web application and developers
are well adapted to web vulnerabilities
they have checks for everything but not
for Android Android had a slogan was
security through alpha station so
Android developers think that it's hard
to reverse engineer Android systems you
can even alpha skate it further and they
built the security based on this and
every time I run some infrastructure
protection I
actually look for an application and we
and this index give quite a big profit I
was studying several projects and I
found some things which are crazy if you
go to your regular web you can see like
okay if you cannot you know it's really
complicated cannot do anything but in it
in Android there like send your your
data choose one with the data fine so if
it says admin falls you know like the
written in the app in story that this
JSON is flying off with all that your
attributes including their attributes
whether you're an admin or not and
you're like okay admin true okay your
admin so things like that are plentiful
was so it's very interesting
I've left on the screen materials that
you can dig into to really dig deep in
this color inter-process say interaction
in Android activity intense you can read
a more of how it's working why and all
that number three is how to test it and
I think this is the only one not even
the only one there are different
materials for testing but it least is
one of the biggest one of the most solid
it's getting old but it's being updated
all the time in number four would be the
description of all these vulnerabilities
and attacks and tax on a project there
is a good description of what kind of
vulnerability it is and how you can get
a login and that's it thank you for your
attention my time is 30 minutes I
believe so basically that's it for me
I'm almost done if you have any
questions I'll be very happy to answer
I'm all be happy to communicate with you
and to share whatever you'll find
interesting on the sidelines of this
conference thank you for staying with me
and listening
you