Regina hi everyone good afternoon my
name is Maxime coriaci my name is Marc
yermolov and today we want to share with
you it's been hard to say what we are
going to share about more likely it's
[Music]
first of all be interesting to those
people who would like to know how it all
works in our case it's a processor in
not only processor but also there's
Southbridge but the point is that
generally speaking when you are looking
at a chip you can you can see it is a
black box in a way because it has some
inputs and outputs and it's quite
difficult sometimes to understand what
this chip is capable of and this whole
assignment could be very very difficult
to be able to reconstruct the internal
functionality of this microchip by
analyzing inputs and output signals
sometimes it's very difficult but today
we want to show you how in a very
interesting way you can look inside chip
without any very expensive equipment
like microscopes and analyzers and
things like that and just to give you a
different perspective and try to think
it can be implemented on one hand and
secondly how can you collect information
not only directly from your observation
but also from all available sources and
I would like to give a disclaimer all we
want to share about may may really kill
your equipment if you'll try to repeat
it it's at your own the warning is you
can do it at your own risk we'll give
you all the links at the end of our
presentation can come in you can ask any
questions we'll be welcomed and another
wafer disclaimer this information
has been obtained not from some kind of
secret knowledge depository it's all
open sources and we in no way guarantee
that our research is an ultimate truth
it's simply a perspective on a problem
it's our own understanding of how it's
supposed to be working and everything we
will be describing in all the demos you
are going to see and they are based on a
vulnerability we have found until s a30
86 and if you will see any mistakes any
errors please do not shy away from
writing to us it will be interesting to
discuss it now what a modern
architecture into architecture in
particular looks like in our perspective
this is the way it may be looking at the
upper part of the tip of the iceberg we
have public technologies and what
students study in universities
commanding system patient segments all
these extensions AVX
AAS instruction which enable you to to
do calculations faster to be more energy
efficient in all your process and any
calculations and also there are certain
defensive protection technologies which
are described well in terms of their
programming model and sometimes you can
only guess how it is implemented on in
lower levels on the level of microchips
but at least the software model is there
virtualization P cheeks and after that
we have the zone of the documentation
although in parts on the trace hub which
will give you some details about and ACH
boot card and and then going down at the
depth of several meters you can see MBA
and EB and pro at this you can find some
information in open public sources in
patents and in book which is written
about an e about Emma SARS reboot you
can
you can look in some other sources it's
like a semi-transparent water where it
thinks make sense but not completely and
dive in deeper in deeper what things
become darker and blacker highlighted in
italics in bold are the things we will
be covering today in our presentation
and we believe that at the very depth
there is a micro code if you understand
how it works and how the forming of a
micro code you can change it you can
patch it on this level you'll be able to
study internal processors internal
architecture very well what's what's
happening inside of it and things like
that and today we are going to speak
about race hub about the internal buses
about the fixing and what into these
it's not really into visa is not about
the payment system and people who have
come here and the thing that I'm going
to share something about finances I am
sorry it's not going to be about
finances at all now what visa enables
you to do it's a low level low level
logical analyzer which intel needs to
verify as we believe to verify things to
make sure that those chips which are
being produced they comply with specs
specification so you can catch all the
box at the stage of many factoring for
example here is a new test chip and the
engineering sample it does not work and
you can understand why what are the
other capabilities you can try to
restore internal architecture of a
bridge of a processor with this
technology you can also try to attempt
of how to work with the humility of
things because this demo we are just
about to show you we can tell you that
we can we can roll the access to the
memory all those addresses which are
physically been put on the addresses bus
if you want to see their spectral for
instance you simply have to catch it
certain entrance for the or cold for
those addresses which nobody should come
to you you are writing your own proof of
concept and almost in an automatic mode
you can try to connect your feedback
line very fine conditions until you can
see in the Machine the data you are
expecting a bit it means that the data
has been read but they should not have
been do that at all
[Music]
technology all I know is quite complex
thing and in the right bottom corner it
will be a road map our our plan for
presentation you will see that at the H
stage throughout our presentation will
be showing about each piece is about the
DCI trace happen visa DCI and we will
also cover the host inside what you have
to install on your machine for it to be
working properly
now let's basically dive into this what
DCI is all about please lift up your
hand if you do not know what DCI is I'm
going to share briefly until 2015 to be
able to debug your internal related
processes you have to have a special
motherboard you had to have a certain
adapter basically there was a whole
evolution of these debugging tools you
can see them on the picture and this
resulted in a situation that those
platforms which had been consumer
platform you could buy them let's say in
a retail outlet with a high degree of
probabilities they required some
modifications sometimes they were not
even suited to connect connect a
debugger to them and you as a result you
couldn't I don't know to fix fix your
system but in 2015
everything has changed DCI came around
and
basically it's a way to to speaking
about the low-level debugging to do it
via USB we have already shared about
that the idea is that you need either
the disconnection fixing cable or a
special box some Intel adapter through
which you can get a JTAG so on a regular
platforms which basically are available
in in regular retail DCI enables you to
double check almost on the full scope of
your internal devices it can check
against your USB device you can see how
it is functioning having access to the
ethics and basically it's the main
technology using which you can debug you
can fix crystals themselves couple words
about trace hub it's when you need let's
say let's say a device which somehow
would be process and not only DCI
because at some point this becomes this
is not enough you need a good a good
buffer which is stacking your events or
logs you're developing something and you
would like to log something in an Intel
since the same 2015 if my memory serves
me right from Scylla like they've
installed a separate device it's an
internal device into PC age enabling to
want to trace events from bias from
India from as far as I remember also
from the port management control and I
would like to give the mic to mark and
he will give us more details about that
to begin with I would like to say that
today we aren't speaking about the
hardware connecting of the modern
chipsets
and their sock chip systems from the
Intel company speaking about the
processor and processors as such as an
integral chip they also have a certain
hardware na means to get the values of
internal signals however they are a
little bit different and they could be
considered to be a little obsolete
because the newer process processors on
the cannonade architecture ice lake
architecture they are also inheriting
these hardware hardware tracking means
which came from the system logic and
this Hardware routing means are now
built into trace Intel trace hub and
they consist of the three main
components visa it's awful and today
we're speaking about visa they also
include illogical analyzer and a logic
analyzer in another component system on
cheap hardware architecture performance
all these components which can be
attributed to the hardware a routing
with a lock Maxim said the trace hub is
called to solve a problem of
accumulating all the diagnostic routine
information in the platform in one
location in Hardware routing when you
get the values and dynamic of hardware
signals is a part of the trace hopper
and all these three components are fully
managed from there from the menu of
managing registers in the trace was in
the trace hub trace hub enables one to
get this routing data to accumulate this
data in certain locations and mota
we can store it into the memory or send
them
the DCI and it also has the dedicated
interfaces for example such as a PTI
parallel transport or any GPIO pins can
can work in this routing data or
tracking data can also be obtained from
trace hub a little bit more about trace
hub Intel implemented some open standard
including on a highest level of the
stack this trace and data are coded in
the software operates protocol format
which is a dedicated trace lab device
you can get an access to that by
different buses or via PCI bus or H
attack or also siphon interface ourself
we are going to touch on that a little
bit later here we're from circuit we've
taken it from a menu on trace up you can
find it in public access let's put it
this way the reversed version of this
manual because there are references from
the Linux kernel from the source code to
this one so you can find it in public
access and this chart describes the
components which are part of the
hardware tracing this controller and
dialogic are and here in some documents
visa is pointed as at this V is in some
as VI si and the Intel company has
developed a quite powerful program
instead to support tracer which includes
a two big libraries create a trace of a
PN trace decode engine each of these
libraries is supplied with a special
utility configuration utility an
executable file with which using the
libraries functionality you can do
certain actions for which they are
designed
unfortunately these libraries are
basically undocumented although we are
part of the package Intel system trace
tool it's a utility quite convenient has
a QE interface read no Java enabling
want to get tracing messages from the
buyers files and for m-e you can also
get messaging but this utility is based
on the trace hub API on the trace decode
engine they are the foundation of all
the trains and on the internal platform
like I said unfortunately we cannot find
an open documentation for these
libraries but we were really helped by
the fact that for certain versions of
these libraries for the Linux platform
they're far binaries and there and
fixing information you can get all the
names of the functions from these
libraries and to understand how the
things are working the the destination
or goal of a trace of API is to
configure based on demand on the users
demand a hardware resources of the trace
hub which may be needed for a certain
tracing and trace the code engine is
basically a factor of decoders of
different the tracing information
collected from different sources now we
want to demonstrate you a video of
tracing of a mask of a message from a
management engine it will be done on the
example of the choice and utility by by
visa
well basically now we are inserting this
debugging our is a tool which enables
you to stop the loading of a platform
not even the CPU but but the platform we
stole it we in then install the visas
settings restore after that the visa is
configured and we are letting the kernel
go and say as you can see the command
interface of the utility this is what it
looks like for the tracing purposes and
you can see that the CM as a protocol
obtain for master is 16 by this channel
how many how many packets and from who I
think 336 this undefined what was it but
possibly this message is simply were not
listed in the registry and as you can
see right now these are real messages
from a me some of them some of these
messages are our select debug and
they're like text messages from within
the kernel
while others have this certain rendering
okay you have certain ID and in
configuration for this ID you have the
line with parameters of what it means
sometimes you can have it both ways
we've shown you this video simply as the
demo of the trace hub operations and has
nothing to do with the hardware signal
tracing can we get our presentation back
please and now briefly about visa itself
visa is an abbreviation stands for
visualization of internal signals
architecture in fact it's simply a
network of the multiplexers which are
called for connecting output signals
from the IP units logical blocks to the
central multiplexer and then either to
the built in logical analyzer on a
crystal or it to an external one you can
actually connect and the external
analyzers with a visa and you do
configuration and you get the same
signal from the internal IP blocks if
you have the high higher precision
higher frequency and so forth within the
visa there is a certain sub device
enabling to manage all of this network
and each multiplexer in visa can be one
of three types cerium central level
multiplexer which is the highest level
multiplexer
which basically connects with a logical
analyzer and also a lot of interim PLM
or multiplexers and for each IP unit
there is also a set of unilevel
multiplexers which get hardware signals
from these units we believe that one big
advantage of visa is that an engineer
working with it they do not have to know
the particulars Raquin C of the signals
they would like to obtain obtain the
values of these signals because the visa
operates with a native signals within a
change you simply have to know the
frequency identifier and all the
frequencies and multiplexers are
numbered and knowing your identifier
within our group of output signal
separates and you can basically get
values of any signals and to digitize
them and also from within visa we know
that there's a templates generators
built-in is simply to understand whether
the network is functioning well it's not
about biological blocks and here at this
slide we are shown it graphically or we
can see IP units and different sorts of
multiplexers the register controller
visa registers controller is the heart
of all the visa management it identifies
such ranges it identifies the address
space for each multiplexer within mmm I
own Rangers which has attributes the
register controller and like I said for
each frequency you set a certain
identifier but also for each groups of
output signals from IP units each you LM
or Union level multiplexer also sense
the identifier in these signals at the
our cluster
to operate more convenient moving
because there are hundreds of thousands
and to make it more convenient for to
operate them they are being clustered in
groups and lands in lanes about eight
signals in each in each group is
assigned with its own identifier also
within the versions you can find very
convenient mechanisms it's a replay ram
that is you can take your whole
configuration for a specific hardware
trace and you can record multiplication
and then with certain inquiry
immediately restore this configuration
by demand so you can switch between
tracing of different sets of signals
from different devices you know about
the file itself our whole research
started from the point when we can we
could see there this an XML file
we really got intrigued by there by its
name by its abbreviation which is very
well known abbreviation and by its size
it was in tens of megabytes of their
text XML information and when we first
opened up this file frankly we were
simply confused by the volume of
information we simply could not
understand what is the purpose of all
this information although we've had
quite a big experience a prior
experience of the reverse engineer we
knew how this piece age is built but
seen all this information from the VESA
xml we could not make out a thing but
time went by will begin to structure
this file and we realized that it
consists of the three back big parts
first is basically a multiplexer in
description the next one would be the
hardware signals descriptor and next
register descriptor here in this light
you can see the three sets which are
needed to do the hardware tracing of
certain signals from the fuse control
controllers of an internal device
and studying these file from XML we
begin to understand that some
information was missing some information
we do see yet another segment of
information is simply not there we begin
to think maybe it's a concise version
and some of the part of information
simply been cut out avail it's not for
just regular users and we were lucky
enough to find in different versions of
their system studio we found two files
visa excel for the same platform for the
same stamping but they were different in
size one of the files were several times
bigger than the other knowing that
knowing that in some versions of the
system studio with the big visa XML
files we've gone through all the Intel
system studio packets beginning with the
version 13 which we could find it in a
public domain and we are confident now
we have all the versions of the system
students ever being published by Intel
and we have gone through all the XML
files from within the studio and here on
the screen you can see the results of
our work it's a set of all the these XML
files we have its size for what platform
for what stepping and if you look into
that it looks like the collection had
been assembled in the following way
we've noticed it's a quite a phantom
file
I mean visa XML sometimes it would show
up or disappear at different builds of
the system studio yet in some versions
it like Mark said it was less in yet in
other versions it was bigger we begin to
you build this collection and as you
could see some of the files they have
the same identical size but as a matter
of fact it's the same file almost the
same file and since there is a different
stepping you can see changes in some
signals yet the new chip provision
inside is different and these changes
are not that many
you can look them up we compared two
panels from the same platform but of
different sizes and we could see that in
a smaller file there is a lack of
description of many circles they are
identical might be described in
multiplexer in register but the number
of the crude Pink's of output signals in
internal devices were really different
and this was the main difference we've
shown you this in two files
highlighted in green what you're seeing
is what was like an in a smaller file
within the XML visa file when when
described in their registration which
are managing visa register controller we
really looked into such an attribute as
standard the standard for some registers
was like a visa control yet for others
like a visa Lane and we immediately
realized that it's a standard defining
layout of registry and its purpose why
this register does exist although there
was no other public documentation but by
reverse engineering out with a trace a
hub API library we were able to
understand this layout and the fields
was in each of the types of the registry
standards and we came to a realization
of how to program the trains hubs
equipment to build certain visa network
multiplexer what it looks like from the
inside basically it's a mechanism are
used in which you can for each outgoing
lane to assign one of the incoming lines
and to set a frequency where these
signals will be digitized a biological
analyzer for several lanes you can set
this same entrance or incoming group
I would like to add from my part the
question is back and why do we need all
of that because okay I want to trace our
signals why do we need to build like
this your instruction JTAG extension to
terrain vendor well let's take the line
out of each signal and somehow we'll be
reading that through some kind of a JTAG
registered but the point is what we've
seen is this very very often the
Alliance have been cut off even to be
able to read the memory you need to use
all different hacks to read all the the
whole line of an address you have to use
different acts because they go through
one multiplexers and multiplexers have
been invented to to make the the the
scheme was envisage easier because you
cannot take out all the lines there are
107 thousands maybe even millions of
lines and to simplify it as a matter of
fact visa probably do not know how to
trace just any signal I mean just any
there are many more signals but visa
shows you the most important signals
they are taken in turn into the
multiplex to cut costs to decrease
number of lines to decrease complexity
of the device and now very briefly about
the logical analyzer itself it only has
16 lanes each actually it can digitize
100 to 80 28 signals at the same time
this is exactly to select only 128 out
of hundreds of so that's max signals
will be digitized to get their values at
any moment in time for PCH the logical
analyzer operates at about 400 men
we haven't yet played with the logical
analyzer built into model CPUs adversely
Kanna like I think they will operate at
higher rates but for PCH it's quite
enough at the same time it can cover up
to 128 signals at this frequency for
each lane arbitration unit that can set
the weight for each lane basically it's
about the frequency of polling so some
lanes can be higher priority some lanes
can be lower priority and so at the end
of the day the logical analyzer will
code those data is private format it's
wrapped its into the open software trace
a protocol standard and sent to the
trace hub this one shows you the output
of the decoder the trace information of
logical analyzer using trail decode
engine we connected it built a network
and then we'll display or display all
the steps Oh show all the steps in a
separate slide that you need to take to
trace hardware signals it's not an easy
thing to do by the way and this slide is
to show an example of an inbuilt
decoder for logical analyzer in
operation what you can see here I'm not
sure what they see - not every moment
where input lanes are being pulled are
marked with a timestamp up to five
picoseconds and each layer 8-bit that's
one bytes for each lane and you can see
state at the moment of polling anyway
you have a high level signal you have
one it's a zero but we found that this
format is very unwieldy for real life
field investigations so we had to write
our own converters
to convert these outputs into
hexadecimal also you can see moments
where frequency disappears in certain
lanes for instance in PCH part of the
blocks start getting disabled because of
the energy saving feature and these
moments are also marked here but as we
said the logical analyzer converts them
in this data in to its own private
format and send it to get trace but it
turns out that trace engine has a
special mode of operation so that's a
very detailed log of this trace data can
be built based on what you get from the
logic analyzer for instance if you are
not happy with the text formats you can
take a look this debug mode outputs in
order to get more details about it
sophisticated cases so this light is a
step by step instruction of what you
need to do to run Hardware tracing its
modern Intel systems the important
moment here is in that apart from these
two files and piqué xml and visa dot xml
that visa supplies in the system studio
it was supposed that they should exist
for every platform well actually they
appear and disappear in different studio
versions but they are supposed to exist
for each platform but enough enough
apart from them you need to have another
file which is interview dot xml in
certain versions of system studio we
found examples of such files and
actually the purpose of this interview
dot XML file is just to connect
the signals coming from logical units
into Hardware events using some logical
operations and signal values and then
these libraries trace hub API they will
operate with a hardware events that they
got from the interview XML file but you
have to write this file yourself
we shall we've shown this it's format
it's very simple you take the complete
path of the signal and its value is
merged with values of other signals and
now about a so chap as I said this
system on chip hardware architecture
performance in actual fact it's quite a
useful component just like the logical
analyzer it's embedded it's connected to
the visa network of digitizing signals
it just takes and based on the current
values of the signals apply certain
rules to enhance make lower the value
and so it just since the counter values
to trace hub it can also measure the
duration of hardware events with a very
hard you know high level of accuracy to
hundreds of events and so instead of
analyzing in the file how long the
signal was up for instance in the right
enable you can just use a search app for
to count to these events let me add
basically what we have is a classic
thing that exists in all Silla scopes
you can work by some trigger and if I
remember you can set this trigger so
additionally as Mark said we have
counters so as a result Intel engineers
have gone and implemented you know real
high speeds logical analyzer on the chip
in order to simplify the debugging on
the
but on the other hand you know people
developing hardware and it may be about
small companies or large companies but
not always
people have equipment good enough well
let's say gigahertz class or so
oscilloscopes to understand okay we've
taken the board's laid out the boards
and if the chip is good but if you've
done it yourselves
there'll be a lot of errors there
because you don't have an experience so
using this technology you can at least
see where the error is some signal is
not arriving or you're sending some
signal at the wrong time or if you want
to dip it with external signals for
instance now when you're laying out some
memory such as DDR it's actually quite
difficult you need to do the memory
training and it's a difficult operation
and you need to somehow debug it and
find errors so just to make this thing
cheaper Intel engineers decided to
implement this kind of assessment as a
logical analyzer on the chip actually
it's quite an exciting idea I think and
we immediately get a question if this
visa technology has practical volume for
researchers IT security hardware for
where management engine whether it has
practical applicability or maybe its
value is limited by the area that it
wasn't in the first place so that's the
validation of chip debugging well it has
a great value for researchers who wants
to understand the internals of an Intel
chip using this technology we managed if
not completely but at least to a
considerable degree to understand how
internal ownership system fab
works a ways it it's so important to
understand its purpose
iOS f this thing brings together all
hardware devices all hardwood components
they're connected among themselves using
this iOS F technology in the past the
PCI Express the bus was used for this
purpose
some other proprietary mechanisms that
were developed or there were applied to
specific chips but then intro decided
that a certain standard needs to be
developed to get these parts
interconnected firstly so that it would
be easier to integrate internal Hardware
logic between different versions and
also to be able to use and integrate
third-party developments into the same
chip and they're using this standard OCS
F for that this specification actually
has arrived from system and ships
systems and chip or mobile platforms
then it migrated through PCH and in the
newest CPUs we have examples of CPUs
based on it as I've already said in
order to integrate third-party IP units
and also to be able to support different
versions of the day so this is the
mission of ourselves why you need to
understand its internal operations I
think it's a key not only to the
understanding but also to a security
audit of the entire platform it's like a
master key to all those like Alexander
tell us yesterday that vendors made
mistakes configuring spi controllers
don't provide access to spi regions
entailing
bad results but if all the regions have
being set correctly the device and the
controller Oh wouldn't it be correct to
suppose that they should understand who
is going to read it so this way to
provide the for the integration of
devices is very important if you
understand it
you're in a good position to offer some
hypotheses to the bar for bugs in
certain places you understand how it
works so using a visa we sorted it out
with this bus and when I stood the phone
thing each device within PCH where it's
an SPI controller or a USB controller or
some other multiple devices that are
integrated there there are dozens of
those so each of these devices has
unique attribute called security
attribute of initiator or s AI so each
transaction of each device is assigned
with this attribute and the other device
that is a receiver for this transaction
transaction it immediately identifies
the one calling it so basically it's
just a number there's no encryption
there it's just a regular bus with
address bus and data bus and it has
special signals that described si I in
order that information flows be
separated as we believe yes and the
specification itself into system of the
chip fabric consists of three buses
iossef primary sidebands and debugging
bus for FX or JTAG when i'm going to
talk about effects today is just JTAG
specification adapted for a hierarchy of
devices whereas for I say primary
sidebands I'm going to talk right now
so the iossef primary bus is intended
and by the way we've got a part of this
information room it's all patterns but
to take a look at it live I can
works in runtime has only become
possible using visa so I can say that
has been designed to control all the
main data flows within the chip within
IPC age with another system on the chip
and modern CPUs actually it's a
broadened PCI Express specification but
it's very much adapted for energy
efficiency and it's based on a special
device special IP unit that's called a
primary scalable fabric it's like a
foundation or the backbone of this bus
actually it's actually a Rooter
where different to which different
devices are connected through different
ports but the most interesting thing is
that the transaction in terms of the PCI
Express standard the transaction is
being routed either based on the address
or BDF so within iossef primary the
routing is done absolutely differently
for each transaction it's methods of
routing is set the so-called destination
idea or dist ID as it's called in some
data sheets or patterns and it's also
important that this destination ID
determines a specific PSF where this
transaction has to arrive at it's much
more flexible way than either address
other than just address based routing I
want to read this address and I don't
know which device it belongs to whereas
here it is clearly indicated which
device and which port this transaction
should belong to and also this routing
modes can be used to
instruct the fabric to define the device
itself also what we found quite curious
was that within PSF there are settings
MTD for each of the route spaces a root
space is basically some abstraction that
when the device has such operates so the
device so this is done so that the
management engine could so the same
device could present different
interfaces to the management to face and
to the CPU so within issues faced in
this piece of unit allows enabling or
disabling vtd I think it's quite
exciting yes let me just add I think a
good example of how it works runs like
this so you have an SPI controller you
have your bias running and the point is
that when a CPU terms of this SPI
control them somewhat with a spec until
it says ok good so I got the CPU coming
to me so I need to take the piece a
controller and collect some data from
the flash drive ok good
but if AC SME Iran's one of the most
curious things there is that modules
them are compressed will have the
Huffman algorithm it looks to be good
but Halfmann tables Hardware implemented
you can't get them so when an object
comes up and says Amica press the
control it says ok your Emmy you can go
use those Oh access those registers of
mine that can support Huffman
algorithm so there's a good example of
how root spaces allow separating the
privileges so who can access what
depending on the functionality so
whether it's a CPU or PC age or
something else maybe PMC controller or
CH so this is another way to distribute
information flow so that you for
instance wouldn't be able to a me code
from the host without going to so okay
if this certain mechanism that allows
initiating these internal transaction
these internal si transaction for the
PCI bus you have an adapter a bridge
so I set primary so if there's a way to
work with these transactions or even
better to fake psychic so I think this
whole idea doesn't make sense so our key
idea is that if you find a device for
which you can set the sae that's it
you're going to get access to such
secrets that no G tag will give you but
you need to know where to put stakes on
but it's not such a big problem because
sae repeating myself is just a number so
running heads I'd like to mention that
we've already found a way to when I say
Eve without going to a specific device
but we're not going to disclose it right
now it's it's a matter for our next
research and the second bus that in
terms of iOS F specification exists is
the sideband bus it's not really needed
for the main stream data or
communications it's a service bus that
allows
setting up some clothes configuration or
get some clothes information about the
device that it protects or maybe some
error messages that are not supposed to
come up very often so it's a low speed
bus but the most exciting information
goes are through this a bus iossef
sideband for instance gateway or
platform gateway information we've found
out that there's a certain set of data
called security fuses which is key to
the entire security system it's like a
root key for the entire cryptography of
the management engine if you get this
key then all technologies or security
technologies that are based on the
management engine such as boot guard or
for instance identity protection TPM or
software based
DRM all these technologies will
certainly go down if you get this root
key and this key is being sent between
the fuse controller and a special device
that management engine is interacting
with over this aside band bus will show
your demo video that'll show how we can
trace the side band bus to get part of
these keys I mean root keys that the
management engine deals with also I'd
like to note that there's a special
appreciation device that's called the
effects the effects aggregator it's a
special device that manages all platform
security basically it controls what JTAG
can do on this platform or what it can't
so perhaps so whether you can debug the
engine or you can you want to get access
to a certain device it's so defined by
the effects aggregator
it's also does it management using this
sideband bus I am sorry
we don't have a lot of time left in the
next presentation so that's basically
how I accept internals look what
interview SF internals look like and if
we can start the video so it's about a
security fuse tracing what we're doing
here is we're setting up the signals
that we want to take a look at we're
setting up in the beginning well there
are there are going to be two a ways to
read fuses through em II and not
intel-based but then the base so core as
they're called we've basically reported
about this at confidence or with our
colleague Demetrius Clara so there are
two ways that we use to count the fuses
firstly we do it via visa and then we'll
show you that they've coincided that
they're match
so these the fuses that we read here em
E as you can see this is a coincidence
they match can we switch to the
presentation back please a couple of
words about a host so don't have the
time for more so we took a look at the
intro system studio that's basically a
platform that's responsible for it all
so we saw some binary files we've
understood that they're encrypted and
within the binaries that sit there to
work with them leave we found the
decryption key we decrypted all our
files in the same way we started to look
around as the asserting to understand if
we have anything valuable in XML and
certain files where there are quite a
lot of data for e for some period of
time and before it and after
there's not a lot of data so you take a
closer look where you can find some
interesting food for instance we found
our secret sauce it's a description of
fuses for the SOC so this by the way is
about quantum quantum it's one of the
obsolete systems also we found the
debugging mode that includes
deterministic modes for the random
number generation a couple of words
about security there are three maybe
four ways of deblocking so read lock for
infill engineers orange for engineers
and providers Green applies to platforms
that you buy in stores they're locked in
some way and also there's white access
level that perhaps only these are needs
we've also discovered that it looks like
there's a fuse that allows disabling
visa on production systems but as you
can will see in the future or have seen
in demos these are not the platforms
where it works so how it can all be
enabled two ways firstly via the
vulnerable you can get our github down
load the upgraded software that we
posted quite recently write it down on
your platform and from then on you can
experiment read the logs observe things
you have full access to visa and a
running platform so bring itself up for
operating systems will be lost you can
trace can I have a mail a a demo please
so what we're going to do here so we're
going to trace addresses
physical memory so on the right we have
read write everything that reads values
based by address we stop Java or we
enable visa after that we download the
data to the computer so this has
happened base gigabytes have flown over
than several seconds between it's just
about the physical address a tracing so
what we see from physical addresses is
what goes so within these two seconds
after we run it we see that we stopped
and uploaded visa so we loaded here and
we're looking for the address we're
seeking so that's basically it 77 see
586 exactly the same address that we
tried everything reads can I switch back
to the presentation so we believe that
it can be enabled through other
vulnerabilities and we're a couple of
times a year
we're getting more and more of them you
can write an exploit that activates at
all we've also found out there's quite a
curious thing if you have fuses that
have that I haven't been programmed so
programmed fuses is bad especially for
mobile platforms because this is where
you can do it you can sign your unlock
token and you can activate orange unlock
and then for some reason orange and lock
will throw JTAG am here at the mobile
platform so nothing like there and
desktops or servers and Bert on mobile
platforms this is the way it works we've
talked with Intel about this but
inter-cell it's a design feature and
we've also found in curious peculiarity
that a special password is embedded in
the bridges that loves you
to do hardware base and look to connect
the adapter so it looks you can see it
from the XML file so does it look so you
have some few stations in a production
that's called for unique ID unique
password from the Intel server then it
birth this value into a chip and as soon
as you need to debug something on the
production platform and I emphasize
production so a special trace person
will connect an adapter to it or just a
USB cable will ask for some special
clothes Intel server and this server
will send it authenticated and send them
the password after that the parcel was
sent to the chip and you have read
unlock you'll be able to trace signals
you'll be able to gain access to
internal CPU States bridge states
whatever you want
we found a presentation well the former
Intel engineer is writing exactly how
about how he uses this thing he analyzed
power consumption the CPU the
presentation has been taken from github
after we publish it there remove the
site and everything has also been
removed from the web archive so once
again I'd like to say we didn't get this
pass without it's hashed its hashes
containing the fuses and it's unique but
we are basically confident and it does a
run like that on the production platform
and basically you can try it with
hardware there's just one command that
needs to be instructions if you skip
this transition you'll also have a real
block on the bridge and that's basically
it
so the main thing briefly the main idea
is that visa is not really about
vulnerability this is more about
research you want to take a look at how
it works
the hood so you do it and you just need
to take you go and take a look and you
can do it on production platforms yes
indeed there's a certain password visa
allows you capturing them at a high
clock frequency he don't need taking
samples so you don't need to have very
expensive equipment
so it looks like there must be a bit in
the fuses that disables that on
production platforms but for an
acceptable reason they don't never
install it because just in case
so unfortunately we've run out of time
so if you have any questions I think we
can take them offline