Ronn brash is a manager in risk advisory
at Deloitte and was the lead in
developing and running the ICS detection
challenge please welcome Ron and Dale to
the s4 main stage to announce the
Challenge results did I get too
passionate when I talked about detection
here so and and and the reason for that
is I actually back in 2004 we had a DHS
contract and way back then we wrote the
first snort signatures to detect Modbus
and dnp3 issues and eventually some free
processors and then for about ten years
nothing really happened they were on
ours were very primitive I'm not aiming
they were works of art but we were
expecting a lot of people to pick up on
that and move forward but it didn't
happen until about ten years later a few
years ago we started to see companies be
created and formed just to service the
ICS detection market with new products
and first it was a couple and then more
and more and eventually it was over 20
companies trying to through passive
means do asset inventory and ICS
detection of attacks so this was very
interesting to me and and I started to
talk to these people and I've written
quite a bit about it and podcast and
videoed and actually just tweeted out a
link right before this of all my
analysis of the market if you you can
see that at digital bond on Twitter but
what kept happening was I get these
demos I talked to the people and I and
it looked good and I'd say well why is
yours better than all these others and
I'd get an answer and that answer was
the same as all the others and I'd say
well that's exactly what I heard from
all your competitors so why is yours
better
and the next response I get was just a
more emphatic ours is better
so last year we created this ICS
detection challenge in an effort to try
to put some technical measures against
this to actually say okay well let's
actually test it and so Ron and a few
others Eric Byers myself we we worked
with an asset owner and we put together
a challenge to test their ability to
create an asset inventory and to detect
events we had inserted in real-world
pcaps
to test them and we had clarity nozomi
security matters who is now four Scout
and as well as grab well there and it
was good I mean I think there was some
real value to it we learned a ton though
and so we were really excited to come
back and do it again here with a much
better process much better data so in
this case I personally this year went
out and collected the peak apps
tremendous peak apps we had about 400
gigs worth of data we had you know a
smelter system that was run with a
Rockwell system we had some Mills that
had a lot of modicon stuff and I fix and
pie there was actually a dcs involved so
a lot of mainstream
things that I thought they'd do good on
acid inventory but we also had packet
captures from the mobile fleet things
like haulers and shovels and slope
integrity systems so we had them some
things that were really gonna challenge
them and then Ron he's gonna he's gonna
tell you what he did but the things they
did to put together the challenge for
detection were really amazing and I
think you'll be blown away it's it it's
by far the most I've seen outside of a
classified arena so had a really good
challenge set up and we got early on
clarity and Drago said hey we'll do it
our our since we're starting to see a
tear of you know a top tier of four
vendors and then kind of the others
struggling to catch up we thought a lot
of those other 20 vendors would want to
compete against them so that they could
prove their technical solution was equal
to it so we contacted all of them I
answered all their questions
and none of them said yes and you can
draw your own conclusion as to why they
chose not to compete there certainly is
some risk in competing if you don't do
well if you're you know if you're not as
good as the others it's gonna hurt you
in the marketplace but for a lot of
these vendors they're already hurt in
the marketplace so we thought this would
be a good opportunity but they said no
so we were in December we were at a
point where we had clarity drago's and
Kaspersky and an open source team
involved and we were still gonna run the
challenge but then clarity made a
decision at the end of the year that the
risk was not worth the reward and they
said they were no longer gonna
participate so we're kind of stuck and
with all this hard work I didn't want to
throw all this hard work away especially
you know Ron and his team I mean it's
one thing to collect pcaps and acid
inventories it's another thing to invent
attacks and insert them so what we
decided to do and this is what you're
going to see here today is we have the
two commercial vendors dragos and
Kaspersky who actually you know we're
committed and willing to do the
challenge up to the end we gave them a
portion of what we were gonna do in the
challenge and we gave that to him on
Friday the packet captures and we gave
them what would have been the score
sheet and we said okay you have up until
Wednesday to use your tool and tell us
what you found so no asset inventory in
this case just the detection phase of
the challenge or what would have been
the challenge and so we're gonna have
Ron describe actually the attack that he
created and then we'll bring Kaspersky
out and they'll walk you through they
actually have videos of how they
analyzed this and what they found and
we'll talk to them a bit we'll do the
same with dragos I will say you know
there's always a concern about
commercialization at these events this
will because they're showing you their
product and their approach this will be
a little more commercial than what we
originally intended but I think it's
useful to actually see this process and
work and we'll ask them some tough
questions don't worry so we'll kind of
even that out so with that I'd like Ron
maybe to go over the attack yes I want
to just do a little
into this so since last year's challenge
we operated the tools and the
methodology for naanum is a ssin it was
one thing to look at three and a half
gigs last year Dale gave me this little
gift flood and I'll put a little hard
drive you know midsummer I would say and
it was four hundred gigs and then later
on I got I got an inventory sheet but I
walked into this you know as kind of a
as just as any competitor and I had tons
more time so but I had to upgrade all my
tools I had to figure out a new
methodology computational resources were
all a challenge we had to greatly expand
our data set I had expanded my knowledge
I've never seen some of the mining
traffic and the attack samples too and
what I realized that of all of this is
that no it has a vulnerability manager
for several companies the there's always
noise there's always challenges and if
I'm a good attacker there's gonna be
there's multiple segments and I want
those rabbit holes and the other thing
out of that is I deliver I work on and
and deliver a lot of different table
tops and this is not just a asset vendor
test this is a way to creatively I push
every team on their IR process push them
on live-fire exercises and this truly
was an advanced threat scenario which
will outline now so why do we do the
challenge so I don't like to sleep I
don't know if many of you do and I know
the teams that participated didn't like
to sleep either this is a version two
community event and it was an attempt
discussed and shared sensitive
information in a way that makes sense it
was a way to share across industry
industry specific technological India
idiosyncrasies assist vendors with with
testing their product but truly
validating some of the claims you know
if I am X company and I have all of
these vendors how do I pick the one
that's right for me when I go choose a
car and I go purchase one I choose what
is my budget my lifestyle what what is
you know kind of what fits my mold and
that's the thing is there's not actually
one is better than the other it's what's
best for my installation or my business
culture and the reality of all this was
is that missiles are provided a moving
benchmark last year was what was one
approach for a live-fire based on a
particular set of data this again was
another it was it was difficult and it
was and I wanted to do in a fun way to
really push and see and take away you
know a lot of you know teams and
products confidence values and they
really had to push themselves and to ask
their products so you couldn't be just
back at jockeying and the other thing is
that this was way
a more complex inversion one way way way
more so I really want to thank everybody
that put this together so Schneider
Electric contributed Rockwell
allen-bradley fire I contributed gravol
contributed I don't know if I believe
Cory is not here unfortunately and from
an independent perspective Deloitte
allowed me to be here and and to do this
why I funded this out of one of my own
projects so absolutely neutral these are
all my independent opinions but thanks
to everyone involved and thank you all
for participating openly and have
allowing us to do these things so this
scenario so it is it is a mine and so I
want to kind of play with the whole
story that I did last year and it's
Quebec core so it's a resource mining
specializing in copper it's situated in
northern Quebec so up north in the
French part of Canada and their
operations consisted of mining
processing and refining and smelting and
based on that the challenge is actually
harder than reality so this is an
unknown environment yes I got an
inventory list I have an IP I have a
device I know a version I know what
cards on it that's all I know I don't
even have a map so part of that I had
some limited time but I also even push
the vendors you know if the challenge
had gone the way it did last year to
have eight hours to handle this
challenge this would have been truly a
hard challenge for many many teams to
handle it in it's a response level
there's a massive amount of traffic this
sample noise cuz that's real life and
this this truly is a nation state style
attack there's not just one attack and
there's not just a few malware detection
it is far far greater than that so as
Dale said there's over 200 million
packets in this sample and this is a
small subset of this so there's 130
gigabytes there's five major five major
different zones and there's actually
about seven zones altogether so here's
the attack scenario as you can kind of
see this doesn't show how many nodes and
how many assets you have but there's an
external kind of a IOT conversion factor
and this is a discussion you know based
on whatever vendor you have you know if
I don't I don't really like the term
maybe ot from from a perspective right
but what everything came in as it came
in through the DMZ and what I wanted to
do as I played with grey energy to start
some of the noisy attacks and I thought
I didn't give a hint I know I delivered
the this was a bang you know if you may
have saw there was a open letter that I
recited out
slight hint and no one actually got it
but there there was so much more than I
wanted to push every single person so
the attack came in through the DMZ to a
vulnerable box and from there what we
did was we did a lot of movement across
with grey zone and was some beaconing on
the DNS server from but in attached to
that DMZ was also the business Network
and so I did a few things in there as
well so I just Justin mislaid because a
lot of people are gonna look at your
business network first for falsities so
inside of the business network for
example there was Stuxnet there was
Havoc's and I did that on purpose to
make sure everyone went down the rock so
from from the DMZ then I managed to get
a box that would then jump into across a
couple routers with some unique
configurations into where all of the
jump stones are in the RDP servers and
in your sessions your terminal servers
now when we think about tournament
servers are usually often resource
limited and so on so what I said really
said you know these are really powerful
privilege boxes and have many ways into
the network but one of these one of
these servers and because of his
privileged access gets to talk to a
VMware machine now this server at Server
2008 r2 it actually is hosting the PI
server it is also do having the SQL data
and it's dumping all of the tabular data
across from from the RTP sessions and
into the DMZ as well so this was really
what I would go for if I was an attacker
this is a privilege box this is you know
where you're tell events are this is
where your pi PI servers are so from
that box it was also there was kind of a
slave situation where inside of the the
qsx zone that box decided the PC n was
actually feeding information back and
forth but also duplicated a really
really privileged HMI and dev box so
that box was talking to a whole bunch of
different PLC's so I has an attacker
wound through there with a bunch of WMI
exploits with lateral movements with
backdoors
there's even a HTTP reverse backdoor we
go downwards and it did a few things
just to test people so I had some
Schneider Electric devices so if we look
at the bottom one or to the qsx which is
on the I guess my bottom left-hand
corner
I pushed an Allen Bradley firmware to a
shiner electric Mac just to see if
people would catch these kind of
challenges you know something snuck
through something there was a PLC
Doswell most PLC's if I do something
called a slow loris attack they're all
the web servers will die very few things
can handle that but what I did something
really really unique is you're looking
for non-standard things and from that
attack what I did was I fed in through a
Schneider Electric PLC
and I did a quantum programming code
with some with some extra bits attached
to it now that was something to simulate
something like with the Tri connects
with some logic that you're not
necessarily gonna see you going across
your network unless you're truly looking
for it and this is where and and this is
the endgame and it was actually there
was a hint inside the challenge you know
you have the power
well that final step there's a
telekinetic device inside of what's
called the power house and that one is
controlling everything and so there was
a bunch of unique attacks and I end up
killing that device and that is the end
game of the challenge given that there's
eight hours and accurately follow this
whole path it is really complex and it's
truly something that is on another level
and so we'll talk a little more about
who who and who and what and how far
everyone got so for the open source team
so who are that there's two individuals
here once an asset owner that you know
wanted to see this from from his
challenge he was a former IT guy really
loved Linux you know it provided tier 3
support for specialized this is but this
is not as mainstream job and we wanted
to see if that you know you could go in
there and jump in there with all the
tools you know if you have the passions
and the hobbies the other team member
was a former acid on our turn vendor and
he had extensive background in OT
operations and he want and he may
provide support for specialized
interests so their approach was to look
at the various open source tools do you
customize scripts to look at the data
and and you know just as I understand
which tools they should use there's so
many out there and this is kind of the
same as a vendor you know or as a client
which vendor do I choose what tools best
for me
well these you know these gentlemen they
really struggle to figure out which
tools work well for them
then they had to make all the data
grapple bowl so they walked into this
with all the research that I managed to
do last year and they had a real hard
time and then they tried to visualize
the data without an inventory list just
like I had to do so do so initially and
then they had to walk through the data
looking for breadcrumbs now from that
they really the things get harder and
harder and truly so these bro and top
everything that was available but as
someone who uses a lot of these tools
and throw me into the whole debate about
why should I have OT tools or IT tools a
lot of these tools have unique flaws and
you shouldn't necessarily trust them and
that's where I let in even more
surprises because I know the limitations
of those devices and those tools so this
group they met so they managed to get in
they saw what happened in the DMZ to a
certain extent they found the signatures
for some of the stuff that was going in
between the the DMZ in the business
network so if you see the grayed out
they didn't see these elements and they
didn't outline them as part of their
kind of their solutions or their results
so they only found a mix in a matchup of
two things and the results actually had
some false positives but also the false
positive for example given the
redundancy what appears to be let's say
ARP spoofing is actually the redundancy
of the DC essence so there was a few
things there and unless you're familiar
with those unique features of these
devices or network layouts you know it's
really a challenge but they did great
so for Kaspersky Lab they're gonna we're
gonna procure a video before we before
we jump this because first yeah I think
I had a chance to talk to the gentleman
one of the two people who worked on the
open source to him and he was he was
kind of surprised how hard it was I
think in in this absolutely I would tell
you this very talented person and and I
think they probably if they had spent
months getting up to speed and learning
their tools and such they would have
been done better but just the idea of
hey I'm gonna take open source tools and
I'm gonna replicate what is available in
some of these commercial tools is not a
short effort is his oh is what I think
he came across absolutely so I kind of
have an also another advantage I've been
was working for Eric you know for many
many years and I had access to all these
tools and I got to experiment on my own
time so I I had a leg up on that on that
whole process you know not not to knock
those individuals but I knew which ones
to play and match as well and where the
limitations were so they walked into
this blind and had a challenge yeah and
I think it would have even been more
difficult if we had the eight hour time
limit if they had come in you know with
tools loaded on a computer so I don't
think it was really a a statement on how
good or bad the open-source tools are it
was more of a statement in their case of
how much work they would need to do in
advance to get value out of the
open-source tools but they did find some
things and it was glad we're glad they
participated so now let's let's bring
out this Kaspersky team we have radomir
distinct oh come on out guys and Alexi
Shulman so thank you for them for
participating I sit down and and so what
we did is we asked we asked each of the
teams to put together a video that kind
of showed how that what they found and
how they found it in their sis
and I think Alexi you're gonna you're
gonna narrate this video so if we could
play the kaspersky video we detected
five major incidents in this traffic
three of them are related to well-known
apts and malware's one of them two weeks
SS vulnerability and the last one to
deny a service on our ability first
incident we called stocks that incident
we detected the attempt of exploitation
vulnerability of code name as 1006 one
here you can see that our asset
detection and successfully recognized
machine on which this attempt initially
was detected and on the event page of
our product security officer can find
additional details about this incident I
mean first of all signature or detection
rules of our IDs systems and information
about all machines which were involved
in this incident information I mean IP
addresses my MAC addresses and for
protocol which was used during this
attack and port numbers all information
is here and on the next screen we will
see two files two samples which you are
extracted from this industrial traffic
so just how it a couple of seconds
please so files which were extracted
from this industrial traffic on the left
side of this screen you can see the
stocks that malware itself and on the
right side of this screen you can see M
o F file which will execute the
malicious one the first malicious sample
when this vulnerability will be
successfully exploited next incident we
called hallux incident it is related to
Horlicks malware probably if you're
something about how its malware it's a
simple malicious downloader or what it
does is just downloads additional
modules in the form of dynamic link
libraries and trance them we detected
suspicious
sexy visa we detected that one infected
machine probably compromised machine in
corporate network sent requests to
comment and control server of hub
extrusion here we can see that our set
detection energy I was able to recognize
with this machine with Windows 7
operating system installed and as in
previous case on the event page security
officer can find additional details
about this attack IP address the source
and destination MAC address the source
and destination ports numbers and so on
we have here one incident with two
events to detection x' well actually
alex is a simple ordinary malicious
downloader it sends yet of course
requests to its own comment and control
server and common Takota server returns
HTML document with long base64 encoded
string like it will be shown on the next
screen hallux tries to find this long
base64 encoded string between two high
rewards and if so then it means that
this HTML document contains malicious
module of hallux malware and after
processing this long base64 string after
the compression it hallux gets its
module extracted the third incident is
related to well known grey energy apt we
detected several requests from internal
network to IP addresses and domains
which are belongs to great energy
infrastructure here you can see this
incident in our products dashboard our
set detection energy again was able to
recognize machines which were involved
in this incident actually only one
machine yeah only one machine with
Windows 7 operating system installed yes
and on events page there are additional
details about this incident
for a security officer I mean again IP
addresses of source and destination MAC
addresses and ports numbers and so on
short incision it's about cross-site
scripting vulnerability and here we can
see a short description of this great
energy incident and information about
machines machine which is involved in
this incident as well also we would like
to show you these two requests on the
next screen the first connect was
successful the first connection was
successful and the correct response was
returned to the probably compromised
machine yeah here you can see it and on
the right side of this screen you can
see another request it wasn't successful
probably the second server is dead now
yeah here you can see it and getting
back to the incident and before incident
which was called a Rockwell cross-site
scripting incident we detect the
suspicious activity in this corporate
traffic just a second yeah
incident number four hmm here you can
see that this incident was displayed in
product dashboard by the way we have a
special correlation energy in our
product kicks for network this energy
can combine different events in one set
and decide if this set of events is
malicious or not so here our set
detection engine recognized that this
PLC is by rockwell and all details as
usual on the event page so let's sort
them in just a second
mmm-hmm
sort them and our incident will be on
top of this list yeah here you can see
at the third place let's expand it and
we can see here that this incident
contains several events for example PLC
unit received get project name comment
and Assurant very weird response we
decided what this response is weird
because it was unusual and typical this
answer lie here like it's shown here
contained weird string actually this is
probably malicious JavaScript and liner
yes and also here are some details about
this attack and a short description yes
we don't know how exactly this PLC was
compromised but probably we assumed as
attacker used vulnerability like it was
shown on this screen and the last
incident in our visual incident amber v
we all see the knife service incident
this is the complex incident it can take
it contains of five events let's make it
a little bit bigger now we can see that
the checker just updated firmware in PLC
unit after that he or she sent receive
comment and finally this PLC has stopped
working we sure that this activity I
mean firmware did this dangerous
activity and we definitely should create
incident in our dashboard about it
that's all for now we have shown five
different incidents in our visual but of
course we found three minor incidents
but we decided not to include them in
our demonstration because they are
actually pretty simple
they are both new credentials network
scanning and so on and so forth thank
you
thank you for your attention
moving ahead so this is actually how
Kaspersky across the start so they did a
great job they found some stuff for that
one team or one vendor didn't find over
the other and they have their own
approach which is which is a
representation of their methodology and
their culture as an organization so
inside of the the DMZ they managed to
get everything fairly accurately and
they also started bridging in between
between the business network
unfortunately they weren't able to link
between the LS or the qsx but that's
where some of the PLC attacks started to
happen and some of those things that
they are mentioned as an attack actually
ot flags
so there's 17 actual attack steps in
this actual data set and there's about
13 actual ot based flags that I added as
well so I did this on purpose to add
noise to see whether or not people you
know that's why you need an operator to
know when things are gone you need to
know when you have a maintenance cycle
you need to know one point people are
pushing things to your devices so the so
in the bottom right hand corner that's
where they started Kaspersky started to
see the PLC era so this is how they did
and how are they able to link a few
things so I just wanted to focus on the
bottom corner and also on the on the
left hand side so for dragos I'd like to
welcome them please so Ron what you you
know your most deep into this and you
created the challenge what what area did
you think they did best in and then of
course I'm gonna ask you the area where
maybe they didn't find as much as you
expected so I think everyone really did
great and particularly Kaspersky they
had a lot of strengths and understanding
so you know some of the firmware changes
some of some of the things that were
we're really noisy events and maybe and
maybe that's what your organization
wants to focus on like from an ir
perspective
you said you guys know you handled
you've understood there was a lot of
assets there I can see that you had
everything listed out I think you guys
are really great there and identifying
what the devices were and also looking
at some of the attacks may be an area of
an improvement would have been
double-checking that that one of those
firmware uploads was - Schneider
Electric oh you so there was little
little gotchas and all of their that and
and I think you guys all you did guys
did great but you know some of those
things are just little tricks for me to
double check your sanity on some of the
results so I think your you know your UI
looks great and I think that you guys
did a good job challenging this and
walking in this blind for your first
so great job let me ask you a question
and Ron please chime in with questions
but so when you when you got this these
pcaps punch of data and you know a few
days to work on it how much of what we
saw in your results was just something
that your product generated
automatically and how much of it did you
have to do you know the analyst activity
I know that's a kind of a broad question
but can you give me some sort of feeling
as to how much of each there was so most
of the events they were detected
automatically by our solution and we had
to double-check couple security alerts
so for example the cross-site scripting
vulnerability so the product detected as
the suspicious activity and we
double-checked it using like human
analysis and then we thought that yes
there is a cross-site scripting and we
decided to analyze so is it like a CVE
and we input it in our results that
there is a possible cv the number of the
cv but in general the product detected
most of the events so it sent sent the
alerts some suspicious activities so
well and one thing so we we also had the
plan for the challenge was if you look
at the score sheet and they all filled
out a squashy but we didn't again since
it's hard to have a competition with -
we didn't actually create scores and
aren't gonna publish scores but there
was a columns that said related to
previous incident related to next
incident and you really didn't tie any
of these you know you showed a lot of I
think I don't know where there were six
or eight of them in the video but they
you didn't really show an attack flow in
your score sheet how would a how would
an analysts deal with that would that be
something that your product would do or
is that something the analyst would have
to do the the attack workflow is usually
done by the analysts but
talking about this particular data set
it's like you know it's super
concentrated super concentrated with
different noisy traffic network traffic
a lot of different attacks and
everything so in the real attacks so it
will be easier to to build the attack
graph and it's very important to mention
that our product can do this activity
too so it can construct attack chain do
you have any questions no I'm waiting
for the open floor so you guys can
battle that with J that's what I'm
waiting for
and again it's what what you guys are
doing it's it's a reflection of your
methodology the Kaspersky you know
process the business culture and that
shows and I think you know you guys are
you're doing great and I hope to see you
around next year for this yes again okay
so well we'll have you both go offstage
will bring drag us out and then flat
Amir you can come back so so thank you
very much guys so let's send out the
dragos team we have dan gunther and
danny boy hello and thanks again guys
for doing this and i think their video
is complete with narrations so if we can
make sure that that shows up and we can
roll the dragos video today we are going
to show the Drago's approach to not only
the s4 challenge but also ICS security
monitoring threat detection and incident
response
we understand that system owners manage
large amounts of assets and identifying
threat behavior can be difficult one way
we make asset management easier is
through zoning and timelines having
context of which zones as well as which
assets and users are communicating over
a certain time is key a Drago's we
believe anomaly detection won't always
allow you to recognize key threats like
an insider or targeted threat actor the
Drago's platform equips a socket analyst
with context and tools to
comprehensively identify
assets effectively detect threats and
efficiently respond incidents our first
step when launching an investigation is
to look at the four types of detection
dashboard where we notice a
configuration detection of saved HMI
display we pivot on the asset ID
information in the alert to the map
Explorer view and filter by server
message block traffic we notice that the
user connects to multiple Rockville
Devices and workstations from a dell
system the drago's platform provides the
analyst with a query focused data set
qfd for Rockwell audit logs QF DS enable
faster investigations and reduced time
spent looking at irrelevant data when
digging into the audit log Q of D we see
an operator refreshing the human machine
interface pages on a Rockwell Factory
talk view studio system the Rockwell HMI
product has vulnerabilities associated
with the system this detail helps
identify when attack occurs and provides
the Sauk analyst with the who what and
when to investigate this user behavior
while this activity may be normal user
interaction with the system the Drago's
platform provides detailed asset
identification and management to aid
your analysts in building experience
strengthen relationships with system
owners and potentially preventing impact
caused by a rogue user configuration
detection coupled with asset
identification is only one component of
fully understanding and protecting your
industrial environment another component
is threat detection and response and the
associated tools provided by the Drago's
platform the Drago's platform detections
dashboard provides contextual
information in a simple view for
analysts to identify potential incidents
the threat behavior pane on the
dashboard helped the Drago's team
identify tactics techniques and
procedures associated with malicious
industrial campaign Havoc's tracks since
havoc steals intellectual property to
support attack development on industrial
control systems
Drago's was made aware of Havoc's from
an intelligence driven analytic
associated with known threat behavior in
this case a successful attempt of
specific communications the Drago's
platform identified another procedure
associated with the start behavior
increasing analysis confidence this
information is presented in the Drago's
detection dashboard
to enable analysts to start the initial
to gather additional information after
multiple Havoc's notifications analysts
are guided to the having slight activity
playbook for triage playbooks provide
triage steps including scoping of the
potential incident as well as its
associated notifications after
identifying the investigation scope the
next steps include identification of
scanning activity and exfiltration of
data indicative of additional Havoc's
tactics techniques and procedures to
continue the s for incident
investigation we pivot back to the
drago's platform detection s dashboard
we immediately see notifications for
grey energy an advanced state-sponsored
malware used by adversaries to target
industrial control systems we create a
case from the notification noting a host
making external connections related to
grey energy behaviors as to work through
the investigation we can also see other
notifications and notes taken by all
analysts working the case using the map
feature we can see connections from the
infected host to external assets related
to grey energy using the Drago's
platform we identified a DNS query an
HTTP GET request a file transfer to the
internal host and an HTTP connect to
tunnel to another external asset all
typical of grey energy behavior the map
feature allows us to quickly verify
whether the suspect host connected to
internal assets or to confirm that this
was the only internal host that
connected to the malicious external
assets in case management we see a
notification that the same suspect host
opened mimicked ATS related files on
another internal host use of mimic ATS
is a common adversary behavior to
harvest credentials to pivot across
networks from the host system where
mimic ATS was located the adversary
pivoted through multiple other hosts
using ntlm and RDP access with
administrative user accounts by pivoting
between several hosts in the draya's
platform we detected a host with many
failed authentication attempts followed
by a single success indicating a
brute-force attack of ntlm accounts to
gain access to ot networks we attached a
diagram from the map feature
showing elements of the overall incident
to the case evidence tab we can see the
gray energy related connections to
external hosts and pivots through
multiple zones including ot networks
this concludes the summary of the trio's
teams findings of some of the major
events from the s4 detection challenge
for any questions or to learn more
contact info at Drago's comm great ok
Ron why don't you show how they did on
the scoreboard here yeah definitely so
as you probably got from the video
dragos I really tried to challenge all
vendors on on valued evaluating their
confidence factor and how they looked at
events as part of their investigation
and so as you saw from the video Drago
is really nailed and understood what was
going on on the left-hand side you know
as you can start to see an in-game what
let's put things into perspective you
had eight hours to look at 130 gigs of
you know me being as devious as I can
possibly be so I tried to demolish
everyone in a fair way just to play with
everyone's tool and to challenge them so
this kind of I was the chaos monkey here
and try girls really got to figure out
they knew the stuff that was happening
inside of the business Network they knew
and they started to cross over inside to
where the terminal servers were without
a doubt they understood how the attacker
got in there and it looks like they're
able and they and truly they were able
to with us with their tool to link the
events there with high degree of
confidence so do you guys think you guys
did great in that regard and that for me
that was really really impressive um you
know I really wanted to challenge
everyone last year on that same premise
and it takes a lot to hide those things
you know I had it in a detection and I
put a pause just like everyone else
would do if I was a real adversary so
dragos was able to link those zones and
able to handle and understand what all
those pcaps were doing so so they I
think they did great there and the tool
really shows that from an automation
perspective right so guys you obviously
had to work hard but you had four days
to do it as opposed to eight hours how
would have I would have this analysis
changed if it was live so alright just
to give you an idea the and I want to
talk more when when Chris first gets
back the collection we did was at most
three hours from all these networks
this amount of traffic of which you got
a subset was at most three hours of
real-world data at one facility in an
organization that has many facilities so
if you were faced with this and it was
happening real-time how would how would
you address this yeah so really our
approach for this how we kind of played
it in so full disclosure of um how we
approach here really the only difference
would have been how far down the map we
would have gotten because on our sites
we had primarily 5 end lists at the
office sock trained analysts working it
and then we had our engineering team
helping with the support side and with
just platform issues with that so really
what you're seeing what you're seeing
with the diagram being built out is
really the first 72 hours of what a
train sock analyst can do or what we can
assess to train sake analysts do with
that if you only did eight hours we
would have probably still started with
the same right because when you I mean
when you're going to a brown site right
and you're starting to do a threat hunt
on a Brown side and you're showing up
it's going to be like okay you know
let's see where the most bleeding is
occurring that we see and we're going to
triage from that so yeah Ron do you have
a question for the team yes so I did a
few things just to challenge your
confidence and I know I did it for
Kaspersky as well so I'm gonna ask that
same question when they come back I
would have just queued my memory how did
you guys handle you know kind of digging
into it I know you had to build a
profile of me and what I was doing for
my devious thing how did how did the
dragos time team which many of them have
never met me kind of get into the
mindset when you started seeing the
attacks how did how did your team's
methodology you know feed back in there
and start to understand what I wanted to
do so a lot of it honestly and it goes
back to the kind of our approach on like
timeline analysis right so one of the
key parts of incident response is
timeline analysis and you know using
like Havoc's as a red herring it doesn't
work because like that's a major
incident if it's in your network if you
see Havoc's or gray energy and so where
we really started on that was what you
would expect any whether you go through
sans or whatever your training is to
start with that timeline analysis and go
I would say with that the biggest
challenge is just noise because it was a
noisy Network to give an idea to on the
data set some of the rock drills and
mining equipment was in the DMZ and so
there was a lot of like really confusing
stuff to an analyst to that it's like
why are these ot assets actually in a
DMZ when you actually put it on the map
so yeah like as we probably know as
customers and I don't like seeing alert
especially with Microsoft gives them to
me really you know those those flags
those things those OT things for example
this pipe there's pipeline data and
there with rights in and some of that's
actually real you know if some solutions
am I see that and say that's wrong and
send up an alert and we may even have
the bodies or the commitment of the
organization level to handle those
things so I'm glad that you guys fed
through and you were facing the
challenges that everybody else would
yeah and I know something we talked
about too and the data like one of the
things there were hundreds of Modbus
rights from the outside of the network
into so the challenges for us as
competitors and especially with time
going back to your question Dale it's
hard when you're both new to the map you
know we had a huge advantage of having
an asset map that we quickly had but
when you're coming into it and like you
don't know what's good or bad right so
we do have to try to find yeah and I'm
gonna get gas this other question you
know what did Kaspersky or what did
dragos learn you know within the water
why don't we why don't we bring
Kaspersky back out here so do Danny
thanks for yeah thank thanks for all
your work maybe can we bring Vladimir
out here thanks a lot thank you no thank
you yeah a hand for the Drago's team for
stepping up to this okay so why I'd
really like to dig into what works and
doesn't work and kind of in line with
what we were talking about and like to
hear your standpoint on this one thing
that is maybe artificial about the
challenge is that you don't have a
history with the system you know so you
I guess there are cases where and we've
seen this many times where people are
not doing
detection they're not don't have
incident response and people like fire I
and others get called in at the last
minute but if you were proactive and you
were building this program using one of
your tools how much
different do you think your results
would have been and maybe we'll start
with you so usually when we do the setup
of our solution to the customer at the
customer facility we know how does the
whole thing works so we work really
closely with the customer
we basically train our solution on the
normal behavior and so we can monitor
likes special parameters so and if you
if you spend some time with the customer
training like the customer and the
solution and put them all together so it
shows like of course better results so
as you mentioned this data set of course
was too noisy and we did not know the
the history of the data set what is what
is behind of the data set what is what
is the technological process behind so
it can be different right so I think
there were 4600 assets in there and so
there was a enormous amount of assets
but I would say coming in coming in with
a bad a bad idea of what your network
really looks like it's pretty common a
lot of the threat hunts we do we're
bringing back a terabyte or two a data
in 24 hours and so you're having the big
data problems and these are in ot
networks and then our advantage there
the difference in the challenge is we
can say hey of this one box out of the
4,600 you know what's the context to
kind of one use that so yeah well what
about a and this is and probably the the
part that I was most involved with is as
I said this was just three hours just
one site you know was I've heard the
word noisy used a lot but that that's
real world I mean we didn't inject reads
and writes and things like that except
for a few that you did in the attack
what is it gonna take if if a large
asset owner with you know 20 of these
sites says we want one of these products
to to be monitoring all the time and
tell us when bad things are happening
and have analysts watching at all how I
how are we gonna scale up to that yeah
and and to that point that's where and
kind of our approach how our approach
might be different is we're very much on
enabling like your stock analysts are
going to know the network better and our
advantage to that is like where some of
the anomalies might it might be tricky
with anomalies like that context is
really hard to capture but that's where
like asset owners kind of also have to
have they have a part in whatever they
choose to use on but are we going to
start to see this this cheering or maybe
you already have it where you're you
know at each site you're you're looking
at the data you're deciding okay this is
what we're gonna send to the sock are
you guys are you guys doing that or
looking at doing that now or does
everything go back we have just a bit
different approach to that so we have
the special thing to monitor all the
solutions let's say the facility is huge
or the customer has like different
factories around the world and the
customer wants to monitor all of them
and what's happening and as Alexi
mentioned we have this special
correlation engine that can collaborate
collaborate okay so this engine works
and it analyzes everything that is
happening like everywhere on different
facilities can combine it combine it and
so to the security officer so our
approach is to monitor like everything
in one place and provide the data to the
security officer and not only from the
kicks but also the Kaspersky Security
Center can monitor from the endpoints
the kicks for notes the special
anti-malware solution for industrial
control system so but from the Drago
side
yeah and that's where sorry can you
rephrase a question why I'm just
wondering if if we're talking about huge
amounts of data coming from multiple
sites here you had three hours from one
site at 25% of it is it all gonna be
sent to one place to be processed or do
you envision distributed processing
being required and or maybe you're
already doing it
I don't know yeah and and that's you
know it's tricky right because first of
all you need the right data and then you
have to correlate the data and it's a
really hard challenge and it's where we
as even the s4 community can help
because um even helping identify like
the Rockwell data for those attacks
right are there white papers like right
having white papers for all those
attacks right we have to know as a
community before we can get it in and
once we know as a community then you can
say hey you know these are the data
sources we need the challenge with
correlating that is at some point you do
have to bring it back to a node to say
okay of site a and site B saw this they
only see part of the picture but
together you know it's a single picture
so there are some real big analytic
challenges that you know both cuz first
QA Ghostface yeah and the circle back on
that right a lot you know there's been
several talks and machine learning in AI
and based on my background I would have
looked at that some of those things to
help challenges using something like a
Markov model with a fingerprint so all
of us are familiar with you know our
phones automatically selecting the best
filter for music right so if I'm
listening electric dance music I'm
listening to country it'll pick and
choose and if you're able to pick let's
say that's the allen-bradley and build a
profile of it and you know that that
should be talking to that you know it's
gonna help a lot with that correlation
effect because you're able to see
behaviors that are far more than just
you know just the attack you'll see the
behavior change and then you'll see the
attack too so you could augment and also
reduce some of the hunting hours and and
maybe kaspersky you know do you have
features there that would really reduce
man-hours for your for your analysts but
also the consumer yes
we're just developed the special machine
learning
you know solution combined together with
the kicks so we can put for the to the
customer facility all together like
kicks for nose and the machine learning
thing and it works pretty good we
already have couple customers and they
help you with that and that type of the
approach can save the men hours in terms
of regarding the analysis and everything
and Ron you very creatively created a
little note at the beginning but and no
one actually got to the end attack right
or discover the clue in the note is that
right or did you guys figure any did you
figure out anything from the note and I
guess no so maybe explain what you were
doing there like a bit on the secret so
like my colleague and I markets in we
were up 6 a.m. and I kind of wanted to
turn this into a bit of a fun you know
joke right
all of a sudden both competitor all
three competitors got this big massive
files and dump of files and I'm laughing
and I'm like you know I would be an any
lost nasty in person and I was like
let's make this even more fun and turn
this into a real world challenge right
if you get it if you get a threat from X
you know organization or X activist or
whatever it is like they're gonna write
something similar to what I did so I
wrote them this row in this note and you
know I sent a note to the team first and
then allow Dale to set share first I
wasn't sure if I was allowed to and
inside their at the very end of it he
says you have the power and no one
picked up on that little note that it
was actually a direct link to the
powerhouse at the end because I didn't
mind if they saw saw that hint and went
after that particular asset because that
was the endgame but they still had to
link everything which was the beautiful
part of the challenge anyway so even if
you went you know I started from from
the beginning and the DMC which is where
most people would start their hunt
because you're usually gonna see your
alerts start from there you could have
also started from the end because you
would add a track catastrophic failure
so you know you would have started from
one or one of the other end and so it
was really unique that no one saw that
beautiful a little feature that I did
can you pull back go back and pull up
the dragos screen there so how close did
they get to the end cuz they you guys
were actually chaining some things
together how close did they get run so
Kaspersky got into the qsx to the del
box there that privilege won and that's
there there are only two steps away from
seeing the the unit in the bottom which
is the powerhouse which is where the
telling mechanic devices which now is a
Schneider Electric product
Drago student was several so you can see
there are several steps away but they're
actually really only two three to three
steps away so you're not they weren't
that few guys were not that far away and
and neither was Kaspersky as well you
guys were way closer if you had maybe
the time or just you know a few other
heuristics or whatever your sampling was
and there were actually the final attack
was what shutting off the power in the
powerhouse yes exactly
so very very little was published both
telling mechanic devices so III kind of
struggled there and I had to improvise a
little bit but I was lucky to have him
on blast it works a simulator with it
with a master and a slave and what we
did is we simulated a whole bunch of set
points with voltage simulations so I set
a bunch of values with my colleague and
you know at last minute we're like hey
how do we do this what would be really
unique and if I were an attacker I would
start doing data shift so I would slowly
start probing if I had real data and
start hopping you know for example I'm
looking at the register so I'm changing
the coil so I would start doing small
little shifts in the data but once I'd
done several packets very slowly I said
you know at this point as an attacker I
would know what it is so okay I can
execute my CV correctly because I've
correctly identified and I know I'm
gonna kill this device so then what I
did was and then I just you know with
the Modbus tool I can stand roughly one
packet every 25 milliseconds so then it
basically I went after a dot but what I
did was it send a whole bunch of apps
with a whole bunch of you know pipeline
traffic and then I had my colleague
killed his server and there's a whole
bunch of resets so it would simulate you
know someone really you know doing it an
end game kind of attack on a device and
then that's what what the final thing
was that everyone missed okay well
that's good and maybe if we circle back
around now to the whole purpose the
original purpose of the challenge and I
always hesitate to ask the vendor this
question is because the probably the
answer is just by our product but how
how is an asset owner I mean the whole
purpose of this is there's 20-some
solutions out there now the field is
narrowing and it will narrow more but
you have all these solutions out there
this something like this takes a lot of
time even if you put it on your own
network you're not going to see a lot of
attack so you could test asset inventory
but how do you actually
how is the community the acetone are
supposed to test these products and
determine which one is the right
solution for them either one you can
jump in on that okay so I think that's
well as I mentioned before if we're
going to the customer facility to asset
owners the best approach is to work
really close
with the asset owner understand what is
happening what is the type of the
technological approaches what are the
critical parameters and if we work
really close together we understand each
other we basically in the same direction
this way we can be sure that most of the
attacks or maybe hundred percent of the
attacks will be detected and send the
information will be sent to us so let me
just push you on that a little bit I
understand how you could test asset
inventory that way you have your
inventory you connect up to my network I
can see how much you find but there
aren't these kind of serious attacks
happening on the network right so the
owner operator is gonna say yes I see
you have this visibility but they're not
really going to be able to know whether
your product one that's really needed is
able to step up so how would they
actually test the ability of your your
product to it detect attacks and we'll
come back I'll maybe give give you a
chance to answer that first and and then
if you have wanted to add anything yeah
and I think like I think that's where
this event was really important in like
a neutral like a vendor neutral event
like s4 right like coming in we didn't
know the pcap we didn't know you before
like challenging vendors to say if this
is what you're going to say like show it
right and asking these hard questions I
think like I think that's part of how
how the community will push forward more
vendors also participating will help
right because watching their demo we
learn things as I'm sure they learn
things from watching ours and so it both
challenges the message but it also
allows us to grow and you know as we
also add rated as we go home and you
know dig back through and be like okay
you know how do we get it in
I feel like it's a win-win having this
type of format Ronna you I really can't
tell you how much work Ron put in
himself and any Americas his teammate at
Deloitte and and some of the other
people you know Corey from grav well and
and some people from Schneider and
Rockwell they really put in a tremendous
amount of hours to create the attack is
there any any kind of final thought you
had on the challenge oh boy I have so
many comments so just iterate on how
much should work personally I put in 400
to 500 hours of my own personal
volunteer time not paid and that's that
is on top of my job that's roughly 70 80
hours a week so figure out the math
there
I didn't sleep and my even you're single
no I saw a relationship but I think I'm
gonna be single soon and my partner I
mean I gotta give her a lot of credit
for allowing me to do these things cuz
you know she doesn't understand what any
of us do I don't know if all of your
guys's partners understand and if you do
if yours does well you're lucky mine
mine is you know she's a great person
but doesn't understand what we do and
this is really hard you know for people
to understand but I want to circle back
to you know how do you choose because
you guys were talking about POCs and
POCs are a commitment thing right it
takes a lot of time and I'm gonna use an
analogy of a car right we can all say
like the Lexus is the best or from one
of McLaren they're all really great cars
but how do I know which car to buy how
do I know do I go for a test drive okay
well you can give me a technical demo
but I'm not gonna give you access to my
facility maybe a test but maybe but
that's not that's another than
commitment
okay well how do I know before I buy the
car or deploy the solution and put the
bodies and the time and the commitment
okay well then I lease the car for six
months or one year but that's just
that's just that's a commitment issue
there's a challenge there for the
industry from both from the vendors
sales side of it right we always say our
car is the best or my products the best
but also there's there's way more
legwork in there and you know even the
dragos team and Kaspersky this was a
training exercise they got access to
verticals that maybe you don't normally
talk to you and I think it was a really
good information sharing thing and I
hope you know last year was a pipeline
this year was a mine I don't know what
deal it's gonna get me next year so I
get to learn so
I'm happy and I really got to give
everyone credit okay well please one
last round of applause for Ron and the
team and our brave competitors thanks
guys
you