[Music]
okay
oh
hey everybody
how's everybody doing
i cannot tell you how good it feels to
be at this conference after how many
years we've been trying to get this
going we're back at cyprecon 5.3
i'm not going to be saying a heck of a
lot up here other than bringing people
up and i'm going to start with your host
michael getzmann
[Applause]
yeah i haven't been doing anything
all right
so we call it uh cyphercon 5.3 cyphercon
service pack 3.
cypricon
uh 5 revision three
i'm just happy to be here at this point
so um
i'm exhausted bear with me
uh
what's amazing about this year's event
is we've had three years of planning now
anybody that's been here previous years
i think we had a riser
i think i was even more exhausted
and came off as a madman
it's true
what i want to talk about is
we're coming into cyphercon 5 with a
different vision than previously we're
going to start building year after year
of puzzles to turn into a monster of
puzzles and paths
so
when you're looking around the event
there's well over
250 puzzles hidden throughout the
conference
and if you earn your way through a lot
of these puzzles you can you can score a
lifetime badge
uh you can see it right there the
peacock
if you earn peacock you get lifetime
entry to the conference
if um
if you're looking to where to begin
the website has a place called cypher
forest
and with insightful forest is a hundred
plus puzzles
um
and lots of mystery and discovery and
creativity made by the community all put
into one area
as you're looking around the conference
i think there's three locations to
discover
the ultimate extreme order form for
cyphercon 6.
so if you discover a place where you can
purchase this badge
highly consider that
let me tell you why
so cyphercon
2016 the first year's conference here's
the program
on the back is a six fingered hand
six figured hand
year two
year three six figured hand so maybe
center count six is a big deal
so um
to be continued
so i was given this key to swallow by
the toy makers
we'll hold that off a little bit
um
thanks
for
patience
and and um
the last few years has been very
difficult on all of us
now is the opportunity to come back and
treat this like a party
look for opportunities to jump in and
contribute to the community
thank you to our sponsors
our speakers our volunteers
and uh
i'm gonna leave it at that because
we're gonna get this show kicked off
so i'm to pass it back to shannon thank
you so much welcome to psychopaths
we're going to go through some of the
lists of villages and um
ctfs that you can do so if trenton from
capture the con is here would you come
on up and tell us a little bit about um
where are you at there you go
all right
as i almost knock over the projector's
time
might have had a slide for uh catch the
con i wasn't going to get that out if
not let's talk through it
maybe um
cool so thank you everybody for being
here i'm so super excited for those of
you that have been here in the past you
know that we handed out everybody a qr
code
you got that when you checked in and we
would use that as a way to encourage
people to go and socialize one of the
things that we wanted to do here that
not a lot of other cons do it from a
catch the five perspective is get people
out and interacting with others
post coping we without like maybe
encouraging everybody to go
exponentially interact with everybody
like face-to-face was not the best thing
to do for revision three so this year
we're backing off on that aspect of it a
little bit we're making it all about
having uh fun so in the ctc room where
they capture the con room we have a
giant puzzle that you'll be able to
interact with as you go throughout the
conference and
play at certain villages
after you complete certain things that
the villages will have you do you can
get a qr code you can then come into the
ctc room and then flip a switch on a
physical puzzle there's four different
teams we have a red blue green and pink
so you can pick a team and play
whichever one you want and the goal is
to flip switches to get your team's
color into the middle it's all for fun
it's just a way to kind of glue several
of the different villages together and
provide
just a fun way to have some competition
against each other but there are no
individual plants this year so it's more
about community and hacking than it is
about trying to beat each other in some
ctf challenge
so that's all i got if you have any
other questions we're right next door so
come on visit us after the
opening ceremonies
thank you so much thank you
and while dave's coming up here i wanna
just quick say thanks to some of our our
diamond sponsors uh secure works they're
over here they wanna they do some pen
testing where are you say hi um we've
got northwestern mutual they're also
hiring they've got a huge list of
positions rsa is also a diamond sponsor
and sentinel one
do you bet you're on stage faster
unexpected here you go
i'm quick
i don't look you but i am
hello cypher john it's great to see all
of you again
have you played the cypher village
before the contest
wow i love the response um
you should try it the pro the game
actually begins in the program
so there is a puzzle in the program and
once you solve it it will give you
instructions on how to actually get into
the rest of the contest and you'll get
one of these boxes that has a ton of
puzzles and more stuff on it
um none of this could be done without
the team i have kryptoman crypto phase
together we work on
we have nate
and we have chris
this is their first time
ever
so let's make it fun for them and they
also need hacker names so if you think
of a really good hacker name for them
let me know and we might um you know
attach it to their body through some
body ink
uh so what else are we doing oh for the
cypher village sorry the cypher forest
if you're working on those puzzles and
you get stuck we have the answers we're
not going to give you the answers but
one of these fine folks will give you a
hint and if you try to social engineer
more stuff out of them that's okay it's
encouraged
get what you can
so we've got our contest that's a
lifetime badge you get a peacock if
you're able to solve that and you solve
that by finding out who the guest of
honor is
so it's a mystery i'm
sorry
okay
um anything else did i forget anything
about it
all right that's it well have fun stop
by and we'll keep you busy
thank you
so we also have platinum sponsors in
addition to the diamond sponsors that so
microsoft is over here in the corner i
happen to know some of the guys over
there if you want to talk about both
bounties and and talk about the security
response center and center con also and
here
hey everybody
uh so in trenton spirit of no points
that's what the wireless capture the
flag is however there is some
cryptocurrency involved if you can do
the master challenge um if you want to
learn how to talk to the international
space station we have an antenna for
that if you want to learn how to hack
shop callers and security systems and
motion sensors we have that then
if you look in your phone right now
uh there's an ssid that is a fox if you
find one of the foxes there's other
prizes to win um if you see somebody and
you think that they are a fox and a fox
is just a wireless access point that is
in their pocket
just ask them what does the fox say
wait what does the fox say
one more the fox says more things than
just that
[Music]
anyways uh so we have a lot of
challenges they're all for fun and we
have surprises if we see people
collaborating um but this year it's
mainly just to get back in the swing of
things let's have fun and let's learn
and hack some stuff
um and then there's also other sponsors
that are the platinum sponsors we got
immediate and meta are you in the room
anyone thank you
oh you're a master
all right hey i'm chris
not chris and chris i'm not
schizophrenic chris is my wife the owner
chris silvers uh we're with cg silvers
consulting we're running the open source
intelligence capture the flag contest
otherwise that was the ocean ctf
uh for details about it just come see
our booth we're down by the merchandise
like kind of right across from the
merchandise booth so come see us we'll
introduce you to it it's very low tech
doesn't take a lot of a lot of
experience or anything especially like
if you've ever stalked an x online then
you're going to do that
okay excellent
yes there are several prizes uh
different books on ocean and different
kind of hacking tools and all kinds of
good stuff
all right thanks so
there you are much up so volley's coming
up i will tell you about our uh our
other sponsors red canaries here they
actually do uh manage detection in
response and they just want to come meet
you so go find them up in the hallway uh
sketches also here synack uh sumpersec
elastic and ie mentor
so come on tell us about the career
hockey village
hi my name is chris and uh the career
village is uh going on down that way and
down the hall
leslie carhart has been running this
type of event at a lot of cons so i'm
very fortunate to be able to do this
with her now
i've heard that because of the pandemic
there's this thing called the great
resignation going on
a lot of new jobs those kinds of things
so what we do down at the career village
is give you the opportunity to
uh review your resume with
uh somebody who's a hiring manager
uh and get some general career coaching
and and things like that so uh it's a
great opportunity if you're interested
we have slots open
uh come on by there'll be somebody at
the table starting
uh i believe about 3 30 um if you search
twitter there's a sign up genius
uh we'd love to have you come out
and uh you know a lot of ctfs give out
prizes but i feel like the prize for
the career village is when you land that
new job so
all right thank you so much
from hacker101 mark are you in here
mark
hacker101 so we'll skip mark then all
right um so the next person we'll bring
up is doug where are you at
doug we're gonna uh have him come up and
talk about um
really fun things uh you also have
obtaining who is our beverage sponsor
anybody like beverages
all right so i run the safe tracking
lockpick village um we were talking
about the lifetime badge earlier we've
got one here
it is going to go into the
same if you open the safe
you win the badge
so this will be in the safe cracking
village
for the entire
duration of the time
come by it did get one last time around
so it is possible
uh come give it a shot
um also we've got uh some points and
stuff like that for the uh capture the
con
contest as well so uh swing by
thank you so much lifetime
so
to close off the opening ceremonies
we're going to talk about these fancy
badges that you all got around your
necks have everybody been to previous
conferences
and have any of these i've got the whole
set anyone else got the whole set it
feels good
hi everyone
you guys might be wondering what this
year's badges are about so we're gonna
actually show a video first
and
you might look at me differently
afterwards
but i hope you guys
[Music]
so
well hey there we'd like to welcome you
the proud parent of a carefully
handcrafted flamingo
each with over 100 hand-placed bits and
bobs they're just now a little over two
years old and their fuzzy pink feathers
are just coming in they're probably
still a little sleepy right now so while
they're still resting let's see what's
going on this morning at flyway camp
it's early morning at fly away camp and
already the camp is alive with activity
today we'll be going on a capture the
con trek at fly away camp and we'll be
going on some of the great trails that
are all around the camp
we're going to be taking some parrot
teachers and campers and taking some
lunch with us
i think we'll be having an excellent
time
well each camper in the pink shrimp
cabin gets their own parrot teacher or
coyote vendor to take care of for the
weekend and their responsibilities are
to greet that parrot or a coyote in the
mornings make sure they're clean and
learn how to care for and listen to a
parrot or coyote it's a big
responsibility but they get into it
[Music]
talking to them brings you closer to
them and listening to them when they
speak is like sharing time together so
you can get to know them better
[Music]
three and a half tracks are devoted to a
wide variety of classes taught by
experienced professionals
flyaway camp also has an exciting
village program with the guidance of
their counselors
campers can choose what villages they
visit with each providing hands-on
workshops and unique experiences
it's really fun learning how to use
vintage computers slaughter projects and
break into safes you can really feel
proud of that when you're done
myself i'm a parent of two flamingos and
camp was an opportunity to bring them
here and work here at the same time
so they can do their thing and i can do
my thing so we can still see each other
our private lake is staffed at all times
with red cross train life savers and
water safety instructors
our sandy bottom and warm temperatures
make for an exciting and comfortable
waterfront
at flyway the staff develop nurturing
and caring relationships with the
campers
sometimes they can get sick if they're
too excitable and meet too many other
flamingos too quickly
over 10 lamingotritions monitor the camp
while directing our complete infirmary
and can provide life-saving measures if
necessary urgent care resources are
located in the badge hall vending
emporium
whenever i'm feeling under the weather
the camp
my mango traditions are really nice and
help me feel alive again
flyaways 450 flamingo campers and 85
coyote parrot and llama staff live in
cabins which have electricity with top
of the line plumbing and bathroom
facilities
campers and staff need never to hold it
in and please don't
we've created special alerts to let all
parents know when their flamingos need
to go
this is my first year here and i don't
feel homesick here at all and there are
great classes to choose from
it's my home away from home
fashion and design is taught in the
badge village by experienced and
talented teachers from the school of
renowned spaku hot couture
campers can find their own sense of self
and proudly show their flair to others
around camp
i can be who i want to be here and there
are some really great designs
there are a lot of classes you can pick
and you don't have to take anything you
don't really want to take
[Music]
with some of the children some have
never talked to a parrot at the end of
two days they have so much confidence in
themselves and they're they're talking
to other campers by themselves doing
things they just never thought they
could do before
a kid was terrified of the coyotes but
he really wanted to see what they were
about and yesterday he said
i've learned an important lesson so i
said okay what's that
and he said
once they know you're not frightened of
them
you can get them to answer just about
any question you want and they give out
free bird seed
ah here at camp flamingos have the
chance to work with each other very
closely and understand what it means to
get along as a group
a special activity we set up this year
is at the badge village vending emporium
by meeting new friends they can get
points through their button communicator
and by solving easy puzzles they can
learn how rewarding cooperation can be
and some prizes will even let your
little flamingos live forever
we have animal care classes and campers
can work with our ostentation of
peacocks and dozens of farm animals
or i've never seen a peacock in my
entire lifetime they're so proud when
they walk around like they've really
accomplished something
if campers acquire an egg they can also
drop them off for incubation at the
badge village vending emporium
they can learn about the miracle of life
and campers can revisit their incubators
to see how their little ones are growing
up
people often ask us what's unique about
fly flyaway camp here at cyphercon and i
i think one of the things we provide is
it's just a lot of different and fun
activities for our flamingos
if it's your little one's first time at
flyaway camp in cyprecon we realize that
it's important for us to work as one big
community almost an extended family to
help ensure you're comfortable in the
villages or within classes
it's a big step and we're so glad you're
here with us
all right how's that
is it ridiculous
was i good was that good
you can tell growing up to use this
program
oh my gosh is it good
could you hear different could you hear
different like personalities
ridiculous
so clearly we take our uh
our badges incredibly seriously
here at cyprecon um
so this badge idea has actually been in
the works for about four years
after year two the cube badge um the
team
we were
slightly burnt out
but we were like
okay forget it next year we're doing a
flamingo badge
and then the year after we did the phone
badge and we said forget it next year
we're doing a flamingo badge
and then the next year we did the paper
tape badge and said forget it next year
the flamingo badge
so it's been going on since year two
and um
you know we've had this sitting in our
basement for three years now
and uh the theme of the conference was
the threat is real
so the threat is real
but of course we can't just do flamingo
badges and
so if you guys
who have badges if you guys feel your
badges
they're a little fuzzy
we flocked all the badges
because we could
um and
it was kind of interesting the
during the um
i guess when we were making these badges
all of the fabs that we normally rely on
in china had closed down for obvious
reasons
and so
all of the badges are made in america
the parts are hand placed so if there's
a bad solder job you can blame me
and
in your in your bags for those who got
badges you'll also have received a pair
of scissors
if you want to
keep them on your lanyard just so you're
aware you have them they go with this
book
and if you look at have looked at this
book there are 25 cut out outfits
that you can dress your badge up with as
you guys saw in the video
so you are welcome to
you know
individualize them if you like
uh and then of course at our badge
village we've got a vending machine with
a lot of different goodies from
different eras of cyprecon defcon
you know flamingo themed swag that
goes anywhere from being super easy to
get to being
difficult to get
and so we welcome all visitors please
come
we
do require masks in our village but once
you step on the mask you're welcome to
come and
cause chaos with us
thank
you thank you so much all right michael
let's come on up and close out this
opening ceremonies and get to your
sessions and villages
all right i didn't swallow the key
don't forget to put your batteries in if
you haven't already
batteries in your badge
[Music]
aim your badge towards me i think i
don't even know what this is going to do
but i was told the squeal
i'm going to squeal
the key is in
is everybody ready
three turn the keys
[Applause]
the rest of the conference and push the
button
bravo
um
[Applause]
all right so i believe the device will
be in with the toy makers so if you
haven't been buzzed
everyone can go outside oh you can buzz
other people
uh
so this concludes opening ceremony
now quickly hack all the things
okay
right here
[Music]
you