[Music]
thank you
good morning
the Titleist talks total life of a
feeling we're not on the VPN anymore and
no my dog is not named Toto if you did
any bit of the osm challenge my dog is
named Kelso long story they're not going
to go into it but it's kind of weird
when you find out a lot of people are
like investigating your life and like
secretly like social engineering it's
weird to know so much about you it is I
feel closer to all of you but in a weird
way
but I appreciate it so I'm John with
atomic
um also known as sake bomb which is
probably what most people here would
know me by my call sign here for my ham
radio licenses K4 ruk in case you needed
that one as well I was I wasn't sure
what time I was going to do this so
hopefully people are gonna sit on the
talk for this osm thing but it all
worked out
um I am a former marine sergeant that
was another one of those puzzles so
you'd have that
um and I basically traveled to I think
about 50 countries around the world and
have done many numerous jobs from now
analysis research Network forensics
cyber crime tracking cyber Espionage
tracking you name it and now basically
that all is kind of Consolidated into
what we call threat intelligence which I
guess it's kind of that but
um I really enjoy it nonetheless I am
also a co-founder and organizer of
Stockholm so if
so after this if you guys don't have
tickets get ready for that because it's
just as fun
and that's where we have the after after
party it's really really worthwhile
okay enough about me on any of that you
guys can ask questions or get to know me
later
so let's dive deep into our fun talk
tonight
follow Gatlinburg Road
as we go into this talk I want everybody
here to realize that I'm going to be
focusing a lot more on the commercial
VPN space well commercial being the ones
that people are going to pay for whether
they're free or just available to use
I'm not going to really focus on the
protocols like openvpn or wireguard but
I'm happy to answer a lot of those
questions afterwards if you're
interested but I just want everybody in
here to be aware of
their surroundings let me put it that
way so to begin
we have what almost a couple thousand
different VPN providers that exist out
there from
Nord Express Etc you can find some
actually let's let's even click on it
how many do we think we have
to see if this loads
Lots can you guys see this great
so
I've analyzed approximately
650 different ones so we have quite a
few for you to choose from if you ever
want to know and they're quite easy to
reverse engineer if you want to learn
I'm happy to teach you that after a
while after this as well but anyway back
to the
oh
so
650 vpns I've looked at including
different proxies Etc and a lot of them
love to offer this these no logging
policies for you yay privacy right
because that's what we're really here
for is we want to feel secure that's why
we have a VPN or at least most people or
bypass censorship or speed boost or
protect me while I'm playing a video
game so I don't get ddosed or just watch
some streaming service like Netflix from
anywhere
and as we've been paying attention to a
lot of the uh if you watch YouTube you
get a lot of really great ads for
expressvpn here on nordvpn there and
they are really packing it in in all the
different uh providers and content
creators are definitely pushing that
whether you watch Twitch or wherever
because they're making a lot of money
off of us because basically everybody
wants a VPN because they feel safe
there are some new kinds of vpns in town
though just other outside the ones that
um you've heard of and some of those are
peer-to-peer based they're called D vpns
and they are cryptocurrency
um
they are offering a new form of privacy
that I guess is effectively the same as
all the other ones but at least they get
to say it
um and then there's also Shadow socks
which is another form of protocol that's
really really getting popular because
it's able to get around certain things
in China
um
so is the Emerald City really made of
emeralds
I don't know
why would anybody go online and just lie
I mean why would these providers do any
of these sorts of things
I was really hoping for that but I'm
very pleased
so
with that oh my gosh lions and tigers
and bears oh my
God so we obviously put a lot of trust
in them mainly because we do pay for
these services and we seem can buy the
things that we know whether or not it's
advertised or not but we hear about it
organically from our friends or other
Affiliates like greats review sites and
other trusted sources
and we see that there's obviously a lot
of competition we have you already saw
there's thousands of different types of
providers and they all offer or try to
offer something unique about them
whether it's a speed boost or the uh
let's see we have additional programs
that'll help you out with password
protect because obviously that's what I
want my VPN to do for me as well
um but in addition to this there are
lots of vpns now that are getting
heavily targeted by Hollywood because
they have servers whether they're here
in the US and Europe wherever it is and
they're getting really heavily sued and
I did include a bunch of links in here
if you're interested in the slides so
you can click on them and read all about
this stuff
and basically how it's all working is
instead of targeting the individual
users that are doing torrenting now the
actual VPN providers are now going after
the people even though they say they're
not logging they still will go after you
so how can you have both a logging and a
non-blogging solution at the same time
it doesn't really work that way
so
with that being said as well this is all
jurisdictional so every country has its
own rules just because Nord might be
based out of Panama doesn't mean they
can't don't have to abide by rules of
the USA because they have servers in the
US they have vpns that might exist in a
data center such as like AWS they might
have a different Data Center
or they might have a residential Network
which is kind of how they're now
starting to bypass a lot of these
security protocol or security measures
that is why certain student providers
cannot block them
but that's slowly coming to an end which
if anybody in here uses a VPN they're
starting to notice why isn't my VPN
working when I try to stream Netflix
this is why there's a huge Crackdown
coming and a lot of it's because of
these lawsuits saying this is how we're
going to go after that problem
um
countries are also doing this so India
is the new one on there which says if
you have a VPN doesn't matter if it's in
a data center we need to know about it
here's the IP address and tell us
everything about it so that's going to
be a big jumble so just be mindful of
some of that
in fact uh even vpns are suing each
other there's
several that I can account for tour
guard sues nor VPN for blackmailing them
you have it's actually really
interesting based upon where they're
located so we have one that's kind of
not going to call it really a VPN or a
pro but it's more of a proxy for
residential proxies but you have
um bright networks formerly Illuminati
and oxy labs are in a lawsuit but one of
them is based out of Lithuanian one's
based out of Israel so why would they
sue themselves in Texas
great question because the U.S laws are
very fantastic and you know what's great
the vpns are using them for residential
proxies so be mindful of everything
you're doing there because
this is it all comes down to the nice
lovely dnca and law but anyway
rambling on again okay
so they also like to give you a lot of
really good applications to use whether
it's for on your mobile device on your
desktop it could be a browser extension
it doesn't really matter but that's what
they're giving us in fact even one of
them now has Quantum resistant VPN Keys
oh my that just came out yesterday
imagine I love this
so now let's get into where it all gets
really juicy
so after investigating and looking into
a bunch of these proxies and don't worry
I'll show you some great examples
a bunch of them
mainly the free ones are really just
proxies in fact they're not even doing
any encryption maybe they're doing a
very little form of encryption which
I'll show you
um they actually don't block webrtc and
what that means in case uh you've never
heard of this basically it's a way that
you can actually find out the IP address
of the person that's going across the
VPN so if I'm visiting a wet bus site
that has web RTC enabled I can actually
figure out who is behind the proxy or
the VPN
Silva what's the point of a VPN
they just don't block it in fact some of
them don't even have a kill switch which
is if I'm surfing the internet and I
have my VPN enabled and it somehow dies
with this a hiccup I still want to be
able to browse but the kill switch is
going to stop you from having that
option
but now you're not private again and in
fact there was uh that's if you're
familiar there was what was that company
uh ubiquity was ransomed for like four
billion dollars a couple months ago and
the person behind it was using surf
shark and surfshark did not have a kill
switch and they figured out this was the
guy behind it because the kill switch
failed and they had his home IP address
so again that'll love how vpns operate
so things to consider
and very very recently within the past
week surf shark turbo VPN Viper and
Atlas
pay attention to some of these names by
the way you're going to see how they all
kind of collaborate
they were caught installing a root CA
certificate so what that allows you to
do if you've ever used a man in the
middle proxy I can create a SSL
certificate that allows me to decrypt
traffic anytime I so choose
they all did it or I can manipulate
traffic however I want to do it why
would they do that
I thought they were for us I love these
kids okay sorry
um some of them also do what's called uh
HTML or browser canvassing which is
where they can see and watch as not only
as you type but as you move your mouse
around and see all the movements which
is kind of a weird little thing right
while they like to take some of that and
clone those actions and sell it for and
for other
[Music]
um in fact even the private relays like
apple private relay somebody uh moment
in an analysis and they basically
because of how Apple's using their
protocols they're using this thing
called quick it's
different than TCP or UB it's a very
special protocol but it basically allows
it allows Apple private relay to bypass
firewall rules so if you had certain
things in place you get to go around
that
and
I think probably the worst part is
instead of spending all the money on
security they spend it all on the ads
they're now they get compromised pretty
frequently and there's been several
instances where all of the keys on the
systems were stolen so they could have
and this happened for I think about a
good month or two watching all the
traffic if you were
just a regular normal hacker not like
an Espionage level of nation state which
imagine that why would they want that
data
been watching traffic so
that's basically that's the start of
this
so let's dive in for a couple little
vpns so you can see exactly what some of
these guys are doing for encryption
levels
if you're not familiar with base six
people or URL including well let's throw
in a little bit of rock 13 in there and
call that some encryption and
do some very basic things right
in fact we'll just give full requests
and have some delicious permissions
that give us full access to how your
browser works not encode it and just do
the bare minimum and
yes this one's a free this is free and
paid as a VPN but I just wanted to show
you and this one I did a bit of this
analysis with CRX I think it's called
I remember it but duo we built this
wonderful tool for you to basically rip
apart all CRX encoding extensions in
Chrome and it makes it really clean so
that's why I'm going to use a couple
examples there but they also gave you
these lovely permissions and rate them
for you
so like me a lot of people use this one
surprisingly
they're right there
I think I don't know why when I looked
at it but I just thought that stood out
a little bit
secret internals do not uh use let's
fire some people but you'd think that
they would try to do a little bit more
with our
actual privacy here
or adding this in here remember I was
talking about how they are doing the
HTML canvassing that they're actually
tracking and monitoring your mouse
movements and your keyboards
because all that data if you're not if
it's free you're the product as we've
heard before however now in this lovely
day and age even if you're paying for
stuff you are also again the product
imagine that but
if uh for my past life of doing ad fraud
work which is pretty boring by the way
but it's also kind of fun because it's
kind of like one of those soft crimes
that nobody really goes after the people
that do at fraud well if you can steal
an actual humans movements with a mice
you can do a lot of really cool things
to bypass ad fraud tricking and the
catches and stuff so that's kind of how
they steal some of this which is why
they have this
or it would be a shame if they showed
you all of their servers and maybe these
names and passwords
and just put it all right here for you
and so you could just see who's using
your networks and anybody can log in and
play around because it's baked into
their code
[Music]
high schoolers gotta make money somehow
somebody's got to make money these
aren't high schoolers I wish they were I
wish they were these are liquid I don't
want to call them legitimate voters but
that's actually a fun thing to look at
as as I'll go into when I get into some
of the Android stuff but
when you submit an app you have to
submit enough information about who
created it and a lot of these times
you're going to find like Joe schmoe
gmail.com and you're like that looks
pretty legit
Okay so
this one's fun zenmate this is actually
a pain
VPN that a lot of people use and said in
fact tied to a different one and I'll
get to that in a moment but
I don't know if you can look right here
blockchain imagine
um
I don't know if this matters anybody
here but if your phone is doing
cryptocurrency uh
mining you probably want to know about
that especially at a low rate why is
your phone
like mining at any given time well the
fun part is even though that's this
part's the probe extension it's doing it
on iOS as well and you can see look at
how detailed they're lovely
updates are every time they do a patch
it looks just a little bit the same
yeah
so there's a fun thing about IOS and
Android that is if you don't update your
app every six months they'll kick it out
the store
so imagine
maybe this is why they do that well a
fun thing here two is some of these apps
actually whether it's on Android or iOS
by the way they will have special things
that they'll download which will then
execute so that's how they bypass a lot
of restrictions in the stores just so
you know or the apps actually won't even
activate until your device is sitting
for long enough about five minutes or so
maybe a little longer and once that is
settled because obviously our phones are
basically like accelerometers all the
fun things it knows it's not moving
there's not a lot of bandwidth that's
when your device actually turns on and
allows them to reverse tunnel and use
your IP address for a IP a residential
IP of that
so let's look at some of the permissions
so I'm just going to go through two
really kind of crud ones and then I'll
give you some good examples of better
ones but why would a GPS need to know
your precise location
I don't know I don't know why that would
matter or why does it need to run at
startup or prevent your device from
sleeping or reading your service
configuration files why does it even
need to know about your phone why does
it have to activate the microphone in
cases
I don't know
for eating your device I forgot to
highlight that one all right well you
probably haven't heard of those but you
have heard of these
Norton expressvpn probably the two most
popular vpns out there right now why do
they need to know about some of your
Wi-Fi connections oh maybe it's because
they want to know which IP address you
are coming from or who's around you what
other networks are out there
why do they need to interact with other
users on your phone why do they also
need to run a startup and be able to
create shortcuts things that people
aren't really paying attention to with a
lot of your actual apps because
everybody has your phone on you at all
times and how often does your phone ever
shut off like your laptop oh wait nobody
really does that ever
expressvpn2 precise location or why does
it need to pair with Bluetooth devices
so fun thing here is just like it's also
doing the Wi-Fi collect connections as
well as the Bluetooth devices it finds
out who's also near you
the way that this data is collected is
as your phone is on it's seeing what's
around you at that given point and with
the precise location as you walk around
it's saying here I am right now here's
this Wi-Fi access point as it keeps
seeing it in in collecting it and
sending it back it's triangulating where
those access points are they're doing
data collection for you or you're doing
it for them rather but you pay for it
boys yeah that's fantastic or just do it
for wiggle for free I mean that's why we
have wiggle right if anybody here
doesn't know what wiggle net is check it
out it's basically Community Driven
modern like tracking um Wi-Fi and
Bluetooth devices around the world
so
why do we pay for these things if we're
really doing all these great things
they're just making money hand over this
okay
so pay no attention to the mega buying
the curtain
so who owns these vpns
well
cape
owns Express cyberghost Zen mate as we
just looked at Pia or also known as
private internet access
they also own several affiliate sites or
reviewing sites if that's probably a
better term such as VPN mentor and whisk
case and I have this information if you
like it I probably had some more of the
links to this to show this out but
I'm not the only one that does this
research to find it out there but I'm
sure that not everybody here is going to
do all this investigation to find out
that hey why is this review site saying
these are the top ten because they own
them
wow
that's why I'm making so much money it's
fantastic well
so what's also really interesting about
Cape very specifically so they had this
thing called cross Rider which is
effectively a framework they've now very
recently shut it down but it basically
enabled uh malicious actors to be
Distributing malware and it also allowed
for ad injection through their vpns
God I love that
so because of enough people calling out
they turn it down they have obviously a
lot of money so they're buying a privacy
trying to figure out how to make
themselves look good but you can't
really clean all the blood off your
hands especially when you have a CIO
that literally worked for the United
Arab Emirates and it's wanted by the doj
which changed
basically he was able to get off and
still keep working there but this dude
think about this for a second if you are
the one that distributed the malware and
you're still working with this company
you work for UAE
still trust this guy
so anyway there's several other people
that work there that probably shouldn't
trust me so stay clear of these four
even though they say they may be
independent they've been buying a lot of
these providers
so
keep purchased expressvpn for the grand
total of
almost a billion dollars
why what VPN is ever worth that amount
of money
well obviously there's a very good
reason they have enough users and you
probably didn't know that all these vpns
are very similar in nature and have a
lot of that stuff
Nord is not an angel either
nor a surf shark oh they merged
so did and who Nord purchased Atlas VPN
not too long ago so now you have three
all kind of tied together
in fact North was also compromised in
2019 not too long been for having pretty
bad
security that's where the other Keys
stolen so that people can see it and
they kind of covered it up saying oh
well they only had access for about a
week and this oh okay I really still
believe you that you've had only an
access for a week it doesn't mean that
they didn't have it before nobody
noticed it for sure man
well
this is a shout out to my friend Yale
who actually inspired me to give this
talk at shmukh Khan because of
she works at consumer reports and said
and had this wonderful post and Nord had
one of the uh they're the they're very
big on privacy they actually say that
and they've had several audits done but
they actually performed the worst in
collecting too much information
imagine that God don't you just love how
they post all this stuff and have the
great external Audits and somehow they
still just
take it off
okay
zif Davis this is actually a really big
organization if you've never heard of it
they own quite a lot of things and they
kind of are like this big conglomerate
they own
soon to be three vpns including Courtney
if you've if you've heard of that strong
VPN IP damage well they also own
PC mag gear locker and Tech saver
another couple review sites that make it
look like
they're the best and they all kind of
work together in a way saying that hey
we know all of these providers but if
you're Consolidated the market that was
really only a couple big players
I'm sure I don't know if anybody here
uses most of these vpns but these are
the big ones and I'm sorry sounds like
phone carriers it's kind of like phone
carries everybody really just is owned
by somebody else is correct
um and so now
um well as I didn't know this until
literally yesterday Opera VPN what that
was owned uh surf easy is basically was
Opera however semantic just bought it
for a couple couple million dollars
so now semantic owns surfaces so now you
can see like everything's kind of like
this little hat
okay
it's no place like home
so I know I'm probably scared a little
bit at least you can now have an
understanding of which providers are
really bad I do have some
recommendations that I'll give you but
I'll probably be offhand but going into
this is rolling your own VPN actually
better there's Services out there like
algo VPN or you could set up openvpn at
your house or whatever it may be but is
it really better is it
open VPN is not the easiest thing in
here for a lot of people it might be if
you have like the PSX firewall that
could be fun you can poke around with it
if anything I'm going to absolutely
recommend wire guard for vast majority
people because it's in my if you're
technical enough it's really simple but
it's also the most secure in my opinion
out there right now but there's a couple
other Simple Solutions for you to check
out but those are going to be my two
favorite ones at this time
um
but what are you really trying to do
like what is what's the actual purpose
of you having it are you like trying to
disguise your location for streaming
is it like are you trying to bypass work
restrictions like is it uh what is the
actual purpose do you have in a VPN
because you know what who cares if
you're going to use express if literally
it's just you trying to disguise your
location even though they might be
snooping on your traffic or whatnot
because it's not like isps or anybody
doesn't do it anyway heck I mean there's
stingrays that'll literally monitor your
phone traffic
Okay so
don't be so paranoid but just also know
what your real use cases
so
I'll also recommend don't Pi don't buy
past work restrictions that stuff just
can get really busy really quickly
coming from like a defensive background
a lot of people are like oh I just don't
want my work to see all my traffic and
stuff well I know a lot of people work
remote work from home Etc but the thing
is
a lot of malicious actors out there love
to use vpns also so you are kind of now
one and the same as somebody that's
doing the bad stuff so maybe work with
your work to say hey this is what I'm
going to do maybe they'll open it up I
don't know how restrictive your policies
are but just throwing it out there a
different case would be maybe set up
your own VPN at home and then you can do
it that way but just be mindful of using
which Services you use
I'm sorry use your own equipment
always use your own equipment learn just
enough but obviously doesn't work for
our parents they're not going to be able
to figure this out and I know there are
solutions and I actually talk to
somebody uh right before the conference
even started that they're trying to work
on some services to make this easier for
people there are a bunch of things out
there that you can use kind of like a
Slingbox for your like a router like go
around the world and look like you're
always at home fantastic but somebody
like I said some of the vpns will try to
track where you're located anyway so
again know the purpose of what you're
going to be doing with you again
um and then like any iot device are you
ever updating your services if you're
going to be using openvpn there are
vulnerabilities all the time or just
constant misconfigurations that people
do thereby defeating why are you even
using the VPN in the first place so be
very mindful so this is why
if you're going to be doing anything
with a VPN by yourself be mindful of
what you're doing and just learn enough
about it and if that's not enough I'm
happy to give you some good resources to
help you figure some of that out but
just throwing that out there so I know I
scared you quite a bit
apologize but in that case
questions
excellent I love no questions this makes
me feel good sorry yes
so for me my recommendations to which is
the question of finding a good VPN
provider there's actually a couple of
good sites and in fact I really do
recommend Consumer Reports there are
they have they've analyzed a bunch of
different ones really in depth they've
they expose all of their techniques on
how to do that there's actually a couple
of sites out there that we'll check to
see if your VPN if you've did a trial
we'll test to see if there's a kill
switch if there's webrtc enabled even
give you a little bit of analysis on the
vpns themselves but in my opinion don't
check a lot of the review sites go to
like trusted and non-profit sort of
places that are really non-biased in my
opinion like that the consumer reports
is really non-biased in that way because
they're half Duty they're really their
feet are held at the fire they're
awesome that way
um
I personally don't trust anybody if
they're going to be trying to sell me an
affiliate thing on uh whether it's
YouTube or twitch that's just me there
are some people out there that will give
they basically bashed other people
saying oh well why isn't tour guard your
number one choice because you didn't
even put it on the list but like because
you're selling them dude
leave it alone
um but
that's that's my number one
um and there are some providers out
there that I will directly recommend
right away because they do expose their
internal audits they open source their
code for audits even down to like how
their keys are generated even though the
keys are always randomly made the whole
configuration and they'll give that so I
can tell that to you offhand I didn't
want it like I want to be very
independent on this I just want to bash
everybody
okay any more questions yes sir
um
it makes me nervous to use my personal
VPN but we use a corporate VPN that's
what I used a few over the years from
Cisco and ATT and like one anniversary
yes
um as far as those go are they pretty
solid or do those get out of date and
have compromises too
well if you've read any bit of the news
um F5 had a major vulnerability that
exposed basically compromise have the
internet because a lot of people use F5
there are some new like zero trust
Solutions out there that are trying to
be really good however it doesn't mean
that
everything is always secure
I mean in the case of F5 they had a
compromise they fixed it but that
doesn't mean actors weren't able to get
in and do whatever
um the problem is stuff the software is
made by humans will always have faults
Etc but there's only so much you could
possibly do have layered security you
could talk all day on the blue stuff uh
blue team stuff but
um
there are there are good Solutions I
mean it's using it is always in my
opinion good like you like there's any
connect out there open VPN but just have
somebody that understands enough about
setting up a VPN and make sure it's
always updated maybe rotate Keys every
so often because there's ways to do that
that's that's going to be your best
that's bad there there are solutions
that are trying to do like be good but
how many times have I found out there
that there's like a Cisco anyconnect at
this school that literally uses the Bare
Bones like
three years old you can think so many
people do that very few people ever like
try to update fast enough because they
don't
I don't know I wish I knew
you never want to change it once it's
working you're like okay great you only
change it when you have to and then
you're then you're terrified and that's
that pattern it's it's exactly it
because for work we're trying to we want
to secure our traffic going into like
all the systems and services and
[Music]
that's why I wanted to go more into the
commercial space and I can definitely
talk about how certain vpns or some of
them are good or some are them bad like
that's that's you know somebody's going
to kill me because I hate saying zero
trust but that's why things aren't going
that way you know that's like the new
term but at the same point that's not
Flawless at all but something's better
than nothing but just always be up to
date that's going to be my best
recommendation there so
any more questions oh yes
um some of these larger like legitimate
VPN providers that are still like very
much not respecting your privacy
um are there privacy policies at least
forthright with this like can they tell
you what they're doing with it or is it
kind of like Pretend We're not stealing
all those things
so are the large VPN providers saying
we're not really stealing your data or
what are we actually doing with it they
put forward a lot of great legal
documentation that says all the things
all these things in fact they put they
have external audits to make it look
really good but when you actually can
try to do some of them you know test it
you're like this isn't no or they at
they try to get additional permissions
over time like hey I need to have access
to this because if not I can't
work with Wi-Fi or whatever May whatever
reason right because our phones are the
worst phones are absolutely the worst
but it doesn't mean that uh
just because they had external audits
doesn't mean they can't lie to you in
those ways because there's certain
things they'll open source it but
um
how do you earn trust
is I think their goal they're trying to
be all privacy Centric trying to do all
this no logging these policies except
that then they say what the things they
do log and I'm like it's not one it's
one or the other it can't have no
logging and then say that you're also
logging like credit cards and stuff I
mean I it's it's a very interesting
practice
but um check out the audience I mean
that's probably the best thing if they
even have that or look at the times that
they were compromised because a lot of
that stuff gets very public and then you
can see like what's exposed or if you're
really interested in reverse engineering
let's poke around because that's
literally what I've been doing with this
and you're just like oh look at this all
right
and then my favorite one is like I was
telling you about how I found out some
of them after just sitting on the table
waiting sleep for x amount of time well
shocking that they like to use your
phone as a pivot point because that's
how they do it reverse proxies are
terrible
so kind of answer your question I guess
it's how do you hold their feet to the
fire well good question how I mean their
jurisdictions are in different countries
all around the world I mean
Nord like I said was out of Panama but
you have some that are based in Canada
you have some that are based in
Switzerland or wherever they may be and
those jurisdictions are very special but
the problem is when you have a VPN it
and then you get to choose where it is
you now have a very different
jurisdiction you're going to deal with
and just because they say oh we have no
logging even though we're a
we're based out of I don't know England
servers are still hijacked I mean
they've had like wingspara have had
their service literally seized by police
what do you do then you now have the
keys the entire infrastructure because
it was all on that box but you might not
know that who's going to be told they're
not going to be like oh yeah we've got
our boxes don't don't worry about it
they just it's such bad like of
visibility in their path so they just
don't want to tell it but if it gets
exposed it's out there I just happen to
read a lot so I know more about it
any more questions
yes sir
is there any place to go to read about
this well
for my news source my aggregator IU
speedly and I just happen to really
enjoy vpns and proxies and things like
that so that's why I read a lot about it
but
um
you if if you're interested in yours I
would just pop it in there or even
sometimes people use like the Google uh
like word thing not that I trust Google
but I know that they have that but you
could put that in there at any time that
a certain company name gets popped up
boom now you've got an alert on it
because it's not like you can read the
news every day but if you get an alert
on it there you go so that's my
recommendation there at least for that
any more questions
oh no this is an ongoing project for me
because it's
like any anybody that's hacking I
thought it was just such a fun project
over the years and I just keep I've just
been working on it so I'm going to keep
doing this for a long time I guess
you can follow you you can follow me
anytime stalk me I mean people you
probably know more about me now after
that OSN challenge then I know that you
know about me that's creepy
are you doing that fantastic
well I want to I wish I could write like
a whole white paper on this stuff I
think it'd be really fantastic but I'm
also really lazy so I'm sorry
but it's a lot of it's in the slides so
with that zygen goodbye matinee
um please if you can I'd love feedback
on this if there's any more I can add to
this I really greatly appreciate it
because I really think I want to make
this a bit bigger I don't know if I hit
an hour or not probably not about 40
minutes so I did exactly the right time
so you guys could all go home
um but I'm really here to help I want to
make this talk better so if there's
something that I can add whether it's um
working on like corporate vpns maybe
I'll work on adding some of that because
that might actually be a fantastic thing
maybe better if I could like come up
with better solutions for you that might
be a good thing too but um you can find
me here uh that's my protonmail by the
way or if you want to tweet me but I
think a lot of people hate Twitter now
I don't care if you want to find you'll
find it or come to thoughtcom do that
but hit me up whatever it is and I'm uh
happy to help out in any way I can so
with that thank you and interesting
thank you
foreign