we're just waiting for you whoever you
are we're waiting for you all right well
without any further ado I'd like to
welcome Vanya who's going to talk about
the subjects actually two subjects very
dear to my heart ship malware and big
data over to you Vanya Thank You Morton
it's great to see you it's such a large
number like you haven't expected such a
turn out on a Friday last session ever
before the keynote but I guess you guys
are keen to listen to what costing has
to say so you might as well hear what we
have to say here as well so my name is
Vanya i work for HP security research
I've been around the industry for some
time that you can see by the number of
gray hair or the rather de by the lack
of it so what are we going to talk about
so before before we kind of deep dig
deeper into what I wanted to present let
me give you a little bit of a concept
first I have to admit something so I'm a
pretty lazy guy right so and I think it
comes from there my old the kind of time
mad when I was a student in school and
in university I usually had basically
two phases of high prepared my exam the
first one was ah there's plenty of time
right the second one is ah he's too late
already so so basically very very
similar very similar to the deadline for
the vb conference when i started working
HP I got this small team of researchers
to to kind of lead let's say and then
when I arrived that we started thinking
about and working on on kind of putting
together some systems and processes and
building this kind of Amalur malva
marvel lab and and then we realized as
we kept receiving some samples from some
of our users that many big like fortune
100 companies and I even the smaller
ones are thinking and considering or
building their own kind of kind of thing
so we I try to connect like a good thing
that the deadline for the vb conference
and the things that we are actually
working on and I thought why don't we
write a paper which will be targeted
more to smaller teams which was our team
rather than like the overall big huge AV
labs like most of the people here in the
room already have but we had some unique
let's say well there were a lot of
challenges and we have also unique
opportunities and I think what our
biggest opportunity is that as you
probably all know HP doesn't really have
a Navy product so instead of being kind
of tied to a particular technology what
you old guys have your own these
different malware detection languages
you're all the infrastructure that you
develop over time we could actually take
a kind of fresh look and try to see what
can we do with relatively small team and
pretty limited budget so essentially we
are at the point or we were at the point
like when many AV companies used to be
so perhaps that the talk is not going to
be as much as the big data is going to
be a little bit more about actually
building a mother lab because by the
time like I said by the time I submitted
the paper i was hoping we'll have all
our systems in place so i can give you
all sorts of ideal for what's going on
and all the stats and how much data we
are collecting but unfortunately by the
time i started writing the paper the
systems were not just yet in place so
and i thought ah there's still plenty of
time right and by the time that the
presentation was looming I thought we'll
have plenty of data obviously we have
three four months to put everything
together install everything we have all
the data right turns out it's too late
now so we are basically at the point of
if you remember give you a little bit of
a history as well some people would
recognize very few people to recognize
this face Graham Cluley may be made
three guys from so forth so this is the
surface labs when I actually joined so
first
lab right so what you have here is they
were like I think four or five of us
working in a very nice building in
Oxford and we essentially had two
machines each running dos and we
processed about 300 samples a month
which meant that we would get the
collection which were exchanged monthly
on the first few days of the month we
would quickly quickly write the
detection and then we would have plenty
of time to enjoy after that to the end
of the month alright so those were the
good old times and you can see some of
the trace where we could use the floppy
disk when we because we had to destroy
them it's a separate the lab is a
physically separated environment it's
isolated from the network at the time no
internet access whatsoever so but it was
actually pretty pretty pretty nice place
to work at now is obviously a little bit
more stressful for for especially people
who have to work but if you think about
those small numbers they kept the Kree
increasing over time so sometimes i
think in 99 I or maybe 2000 I saw this
presentation by by David chess and Steve
white from IBM who were just about to be
acquired by by symantec or some of the
technology about the digital immune
system so the digital immune system is
something which I consider to be like
come on guys this is science fiction
clearly you have some agents on the on
the endpoints you have some
administrator tools running there and
you have information flow in two ways
from the central control like a unit
which basically analyze this malware and
creates new detection and there is the
whole feedback loop between the people
who are using the software and actual
producer of the AV software and so I am
fairly sure that most of the people now
and most of the companies actually have
a pretty similar model of working for
their products instead of the analysis
center we have the cloud we have
automated analysis machines we have all
sorts of scanning rigs and things like
that and so that
in two thousand and I I was thinking and
it will never happen but yes indeed it
actually did happen and if you look at
the kind of obviously we all know every
test stat the number of mother kept
growing over years and it's this year it
kind of stabilized I hope that means we
are doing a better job both the vendors
of the operating system and the vendors
of Av of the kind of developers of the
heavy product so i think it's going to
stabilize around 500 samples a day five
hundred thousand samples a day of course
so this is the kind of number that we I
was pretty ambitious when i joined HP
and and that was my idea is like if
everybody's processing those samples
then if you really want to be serious
about model research you want to be able
to have this capacity and then like we
said people people start coming we have
our internal team that does the kind of
man i say internal there's the internal
IT team inside HP that deals with
malware incidents and so they are very
much a good model customer of or model
of the team that would like to build a
malware research facility such as like
the virus lab so that was that was like
history and contacts now the next few
things i would like to cover our kind of
work love workflow and some of the
components that we need to have in a
kind of successful lab some of the
design principles and kind of
recommendations that we came across
during our kind of Investigation and
kind of finished with the with the
summary hopefully that's it so even if
we when you started looking at the lab I
kind of tried to look like every single
component what we need like servers this
and that various scanner shrieks oh I
put everything on like one Vizio slide
and then I thought I realized this is a
bit complicated so I kind of went bottom
up and then top down so this is I guess
down like big units or what we need to
have like acquisition of course we need
to get our sample somehow we need to be
able to analyze it in some kind of group
then we need to have people who are
actually going to interact with the
system so we need some kind of end user
system facility some kind of portal we
need to have a workflow that will kind
of automate everything from the process
of the acquisition of the samples to the
actual storage and potentially output of
course we need place where to store that
in the storage and then we need some
kind of auxiliary modules which I really
couldn't place in any particular
category category of these kind of
really important part and then I have
like I have partner interfaces and food
producers because one of one of the
things that we do is I think Oleg
mentioned and John we have the like a
sweat intelligence-sharing product
called thread central so that's one of
the things we would like to or we wanted
to incorporate in our design so we'll
kind of drill down slowly butt slide by
slide into like every category so first
one is the sample acquisition if you
really know so you have really two
choices first choices which I thought it
was right choice at the beginning was do
everything yourself and this is what
every mother company and every every
company did create your own spam traps
create your own honey pots crawlers kind
of systems but they all require
development time they'll require
developers and they all require some
stability to a point I I thought that if
we if we ourselves didn't have any
malware samples or URLs that our own
then it would would be no it wouldn't be
nice it wouldn't be fair that we start
and try to join the rest of the AV
industry start exchanging samples in url
so on a kind of daily basis likely or
you all guys too so the other the other
possible ways is
it basically just well pay pay for
access to some of the model repositories
and that was the situation more or less
why not when I joined so and I think I
think it's worth mentioning with those
partner feeds there are also there are
informal or formal mailing lists and
there are various mechanism around those
lists that have frameworks such as
malvel information sharing platform misp
which is used by many certs and
different companies that actually
exchanged informations about malware
samples and mulberry incidents it's
quite an interesting framework that it
is open source I think it's by developed
by Luxembourg third so after the the
acquisition system clearly wife after we
had those samples we need to be able to
analyze them you know we can have
various automated analysis system both
dynamic and Static so we need to make a
decision on or try to make a decision
and store some data in the database so
we need to have a scanning system we
need to have like automated analysis
system for like dynamic analysis URLs
and how we analyze the URL feed as they
come we need to be able to see whether
they actually malicious or not so we
need to be able to confirm and simply
not act on the day on the flow of mother
samples as deka is the coming in so
static analysis workflow it typically
involves anything that is done to the
sample except running the sample it
doesn't involve that so I thought okay
so if you start analyzing the user you
authenticate first you upload your you
get the sample somehow the sample has to
be stored to the storage and it will
just run two things it would be scanned
with anthem Alvers a group of
anti-malarial scanners and done some
static methods such as extracting
strings the usual thing all the checks
sons will be calculated some fuzzy
Texans would be calculated I was hoping
to him
mentor include Jones modification on
Neil themes as well so we had all sorts
of ideas of what we can do and then
after everything is done of course we're
going to save those so we can later use
it for clustering and analytics same
with kind of dynamic analysis we kind of
start we submit the sample there's some
pre-processing happening we restored the
analysis environment we start monitoring
those are the usual thing and and you
guys are pretty much familiar with this
but this is just like for the reference
of the people who already don't have
their own lab so just to understand
what's going on like I said end user
systems our our team is very much we all
like to work from home so we don't work
from a note from an office and so we
need to have like a center of facility
connecting through the VPN where we
would access our research and
intelligence portal and and from that
portal we will be able to access all
this automated systems even the manual
systems running on most likely remember
and so we will be able to to to access
that so those are those are the
important ones you need to have as well
so the big data actually if you think
about just five hundred thousand samples
a day I think I calculated and I wrote
in a paper maybe I miscalculated but
it's only before storing sample I think
you need about 17 terabytes space a year
if the sample average sample size about
500 k let's say so it's it's a pretty
big kind of storage requirement and
that's only for the samples so even if
HP is a hardware vendor we do have to
pay for our internal hardware and so we
kind of have to share it with few other
teams so we have to be pretty pretty
careful how we spend it so in addition
to that if you think about okay so 500k
per sample is not that big but what
about all the other data all this kind
of scanners results rescanning results
dynamic analysis results I think
kind of it if i understand it it gets to
about 100 megabytes per / file / sample
so that's that's quite a large amount of
data to store we had we contacted wanted
like did the guys from because we are
also using coo coo sign books and we
contacted one of the developers and one
of the guys from Mighty our team was
very ambitious and he decided to that we
took he told the developer that we gonna
most likely build a system for 5 million
samples every day and it was like oh
wait a little bit too ambitious there
are some auxiliary resistance we need to
have we need to have a week he where we
can store our kind of documents or
internal documentation we need our tools
repository tools that we build for our
personal analysis needs to be stored
somewhere they need to be controlled in
source control systems we need to have
systems for authentication and access
rights we need to have systems for
requesting analysis from from other
internal and external team so if you
think about there are actually many
boxes and and that was the kind of
eventually I didn't even write or didn't
put in all the links between various
various systems that are required
otherwise it'll be just like a mesh of
system which which we couldn't be able
to see but this was the kind of image
that I came came first and then I had to
change and I c2c and sort various system
and boxes into like high level groups so
and then I was thinking like how do I
approach what what are the faces of of
implementation of something like this
and and came across a tool that's often
and frequently used in some of the kind
of psychological and HR people like to
use this like if you don't know what to
do just put it in a pyramid or something
like that so so I put it in a pyramid of
of am a slow kind of hierarchy and so
you have like
okay that the most common needs needs to
be satisfied first so we first we need
to have an individual research systems
which we did more or less when i joined
then the next level of sophistication is
okay let's have some acquisition love
samples let's hit the storage and then
let's start to share the information and
including those samples then we should
build those automated analysis systems
we ant farms all the work flow around it
because usually you have disparate
systems and you need to be able to
somehow connect those systems so they
can work together and talk to one to
each other so workflow is already pretty
sophisticated I would say and then
blessing now that you have this huge
amounts of data plug in some of the sort
of HP's product we have like a
high-performance big data database
called Vertica and we also have we also
have something called Idol which is like
a search engine equivalent that that
allows you to store unstructured
semi-structured data set such a JSON
blob and then make some prediction based
on on later so there's like a machine
learning tool as well so these are the
top level and then you know once we do
that we can just keep adding new stuff
so that's that's the whole idea so some
of the principles and then when I kind
of realized that I I wanted to kind of
learn more about how we develop what are
the kind of development principles and
develop and then I came across I think a
long time ago I listen to a presentation
from Alistair Coburn who is one of the
kind of father of a child programming
and I thought okay so there's an agile
manifesto for for development well is
there like a 144 in like systems
engineering and indeed somebody from IBM
created an agile manifesto for systems
development and then I kind of look at
it and it's like yeah we really want to
do something along those lines so so
there are some principles such as there
always be changing requirements is like
when I arrived at the requirements for
the labs were
like pretty different than what they are
at the moment we would like to have like
short development cycles because when we
start booting actually start putting
building the lab together we had to
contract somebody so they haven't
reported back to us for some time so we
haven't actually closed the kind of
feedback loop from the developer to us
who are the users of the system and we
just neglected it and it kind of fizzled
out so that's very important researchers
and developers should work together and
in most of our cases researchers and
developers are kind of mixed category
because many people are one and the
other the only measure of success is
something that we can demonstrate so we
can't just play with things because we
can't afford that and look at this is
cool this is nice this is this and no
don't do anything so we need to be able
to push this forward all the time and of
course like i said it goes together with
simplicity which means like being lazy
maximize the work that you don't have to
do and then i also can't came across
this devops terms like what is this
devil sing and and there was somehow i
started reading about it and i came
across an oval an IT novel basically
it's almost like a fairy tale of a
variety manager IT operations manager
Bill who comes to this really badly
organized IT department when you have
developers not talking to guys who are
in the operations and somehow this magic
character called Eric appears right and
the eric is like mr. Miyagi from karate
kid and he kind of starts talking into
this also a cryptic language that the
bill has to find out what it's what it's
all about and basically eric told bill
about three ways of DevOps first way
think about the systems right so that's
very important not do not think about
any individual part of the system think
about system in kind of that the whole
because the system will be as good as
the kind of worse possible part of what
you have so try to find both connects
and
those the second this rule is amplified
feedback amplifier feedback essentially
means that every and every stage of
development you can deliver something
and then you get the feedback from every
next stage of the development process so
the testers essentially give feedback to
to the developers the users give but
that happens in in in frequent loops and
the third way is try to experiment all
the time being researchers that's not
very difficult for us so I like this
principle the most and this is where we
actually were the most successful in
experimentation rather than actually
having a great and big huge lab with all
data behind it so for you for people who
don't have a lab I think you know the
put the important points are you know
start simple with with easy wins so
don't dwell on develop being all this
collection system and stuff because by
not having hardware I realize that over
over five or six months that it's not
necessarily required but some of the
good other things is like if you can if
you start building think about starting
small but then and then building up and
being able to scale I actually
considered also like a fully cloud
deployment of the lab because we work
remotely and it would be kind of very
interesting and as a cloud development
principle is you need to expect failure
so you need to design for failure and
it's most likely that the systems will
fail sooner or later so think about that
harness the power of community so there
are like all sorts of exchanges there
are community projects there are free
tools that we can use as well as groups
that we can join one a good example is a
Yara signature group where there's like
12 and a half thousand community are our
signatures that you we can for example
employ or deploy internally so automate
everything if you can and that
everything is source code basically two
things one is configuration and the
other one is provision so
everything can be done through tools
such as Linux containers and docker or
vagrant or something like that it allows
you to kind of experiment and those
configuration files can always be kept
in the source code repository and you
can also practice kind of continuous
delivery as you as you develop so some
of the tools that we actually ended up
with right first one is virustotal
everybody use it it's a virus total
intelligence it allows you to find
samples it's it's a no it's not free
it's free when you have it but it's a
good kind of you don't have to develop
any additional systems it's allow you to
deploy your own yarra rules based on the
results of scanning you can get all the
new samples and it's really really
powerful especially if we have the kind
of highest level of requests and
privileges so once when you got that we
feel that locally actually Claudia
Guarnere was here and he developed both
of these the next two tools one of them
is Viper which we'll use for local
storing of the of the files and it also
allows you to do like really kind of
great static analysis and create little
projects that you can have kind of
groups of files with for particular
incidents and things like that it's
geared towards individual users but we
are trying to kind of extend it so
everybody can use it as like an in
server it has your it's only our rules
so those are like became de facto
standards in in the kind of non AV
community or modern researchers and and
heavily modified cuckoo you see there's
a HP logo i modified it so so we use
cuckoo sandbox as well for internal
internal development but by the equiv
and fork which basically has some
additional capabilities internal virtual
machine agent is hides the virtual
machine better and works on 64-bit as
well in 32-bit and it has some
plastering capabilities general you see
old all the results which is nice and
the clustering is based on mal here
project which based take static and
dynamic dynamic characteristics of the
file hashes themselves k to normalize
them in Phi the distance between the
too fast so you can actually see which
ones are pretty similar to the one that
you already submitted submitted to the
system so implementation phases i think
we more more or less cover that start
with small and then build to to actually
have be able to get to the cloud
implementation choices we like i said i
wanted to cloud but we ended up with two
wrecks on the right so it's kind of
exciting but I I thought we are going to
come with this kind of great
architecture where everything can be
horizontally scale like this will have
load balancers we could can have many
many many many users but that didn't
really materialize but it's something to
consider if you want to build a lab like
that so in summary it's pretty complex
thing to build a fully functional
malware lab but you know you can start
for something which is pretty small and
it will get you to to a certain point if
you process on the only relevant samples
like for example HP internally our IT
guys are doing anything between three
and five hundred samples a day so not a
lot but it's a three hundred thousand a
big company 300,000 people are employees
in HP so that's a kind of roughly the
size of our number of hours that these
little teams of my other researchers
inside fortune 100 companies are looking
to analyze a day start from small and
then I think you know think in terms of
these devil plays because it's kind of
an interesting approach to to
development so with that I think we are
done I don't think I'm not sure if I
have many more times but I would like to
thank you and then if you have any
questions please do well that was kind
of a blast from the past I haven't
really thought of the immune system for
a while it's been nearly 20 years are
there any questions about on the subject
we only have time for like one or two
see if we really quick
and suggestions I'm fishing for that
slow what to do or not to do I was
actually just going to ask a very very
stupid question I didn't quite catch the
name of the data storage that you said
you're using was really a Viper but
enough oh oh that was Viper yeah oh I
thought you had like a datastore system
or dentist or the other the HP slate for
each museum yeah it's a 33 par yeah it's
a three-part network storage the 33 par
3 part yeah right the verticals over to
catch the database okay but it's a
columnar database that kind of allah hoo
so the exhaust is billions of Records I
mean it's more like four queering rather
than transactional but it's it's kind of
a really really powerful okay so last
chance really quick going going gone in
that case thank thank well help me thank
them for a great presentation thank you
[Applause]