alrighty so the last talk of the session
is by John Young park and it promises to
take us or part of it promises to take
us beyond our senses so I love the title
I'm interested to see how that works
please thank you thank you very much hi
everybody I am very happy to be here
especially it's my first time in prop
beautiful city and delicious beers the
title of this presentation is pale devil
beyond your senses with tax visualizer
let me introduce myself quickly I'm
joonyoung / a security researcher of
unnav in south korea the main focus of
my research is automated male analysis
system in listen ears I enjoy liver sing
and visualizing Android marea so the
agenda of today as follows I will start
the presentation with motivations and
talk about apple life cycle n a life
cycle cycle graph then I will introduce
tab you'll also known as the expedia
lighter many about each construction and
how will show how to realize on a life
cycle graph next we will have a general
idea of live cycling next in case
studies I will walk through five legal
moral samples including downloader and
banking Trojan l80 information stiller
and also the packaging Maria finally I
will conclude with some interesting
points given the leafy growth of Android
more well the number of vandalism
Orioles seen every day has over Helen
domain power available to analyze
classified them the most challenging
task is pig out small unusual patterns
from giant piles of binary codes but the
daily Android morale responses are up to
be repetitive and tedious hunting for a
few suspicious code blocks as those
angles we can see the wood for the trees
rather than investigating a few
suspicious code blocks to see the loot
fortress is to figure out the app life
cycle because every Android F has
essential building blocks known as add
component each component subs are
distinct poppers and has a distinct life
cycle that defines how that component is
create created and destroyed some
interact each other some depend on each
other these relationships between the
add component constructor lifecycle of
app Android & of Android app and the app
lifecycle is the big picture I think but
in order to figure out the app like
cycle better we need to build the
automated analysis system that can
assist our intelligence in addition
visualization in the age of automative
Murray analysis can heighten the senses
of our intelligence researchers as we
know a life cycle can be visualized by
various wellin graph algorithm the
visualization injectibles is one of most
effective ways to identify Maria so
prove Mike conserve mobile app life
cycle and the graph visualization of it
in March last year I began to write some
small scripts in Python and JavaScript
as my pal OH matured i named the devil
as no net also known as the ex
visualizer and nadir the same year devil
was made available to my co-workers as
you can see devil has a simple
client-server architecture the reply is
learning on the wsgi server configured
with flask a user can submit APK file to
the server and then the server sends
Jason responses that contains the intro
objects relationships generated from
text file by static analysis on the
client side Debu jas lenders the app
life site graph using the first directed
layer algorithm of d3.js as mentioned
the relationship between a component of
which there are four components for
different types of ab component you know
at the basis of a life cycle but the
full component alone are not enough to
reveal the behaviors of Android app take
an initial high level view in in the
best case so devil uses uses the app
component only as the seed of the graph
and then generate the relationship
between the components and other
meaningful objects such as intent
permission thread and the more however
it is not easy up to discuss low level
technical details all at once to make
our life simpler I will take a simple
fictitious Morel sample and walk through
the realization of app lifecycle graph
step by step and people I will show the
life learning devil I've suburb
this is Devil's screen devil has
actually so many functions but today I
will show graph visualization mainly but
well this one's so many buttons has many
functions this is the graph of the our
fictitious Maria and retest PN still p n
stands for phone number these samples
gives imei and phone number and send
stolen data to specific email addresses
ok let's start with adding our first
note to empty graph of pn stila
initially kept life cycle graph has only
one f jef not EP entry point you know as
will be seen adel EP note plays a more
important note than any others so it has
quite a large ladies and depicted in
court next the intentional die added to
the graph the intent and related
information can be applied by a two
techniques one is leading from under the
manifest file and the other is analyzing
data byte code objects file dev will
emulate stultified code with the core
being traced the life of objects see the
graph pn steelo has main and launcher
intent filters the main tent note
indicates that this is main entry point
in does not expect any intent data and
launch our intent note indicates these
activities icon should be placed in the
loan system f launcher accordingly the
main and launcher intent on old have the
same color as EP node twitch domain node
is connected next permission nodes are
added to the graph or the permissions
under the epic wires must be declared
and under the manifest file but the
manifest file could declare just a list
of the quiet permission so devil tracks
down all the details of those Commission
you see geez by estetica analysis and
type of propagation algorithm see the
graph p.m. still has internet and leave
your phone state permissions next a
component know that I added to the graph
before the Android system can start a
web component the system also know that
the component exists by leading under
the manifest file however it is not
enough food enough defender manifest
file because singled x files are so me
too submitted as moral samples every day
so devil extracts add component classes
by passing decks header this is done by
simply by inspecting whether a class
extends or implement
android.app.activity class under the
episode is class under the content
content provider class Android content
broadcast receiver class and like cedar
grab PN still has one app component name
main activity class and main activity
class has main and launcher intent
filters and acquires lead phone state
permission
sorry in android you shouldn'ta plop us
wrath if you have operations to perform
not instantaneous you'd make sure you
date they are done in separate thread
this applies to Android more rare as
well this design patterns so vital that
the long-running behaviors of Android
marea must be implemented in Sepphoris
threat hence none other components nodes
are added to the graph devil defines lot
of a component class as a class
extending or implementing jabbering
sweat java rang na noble class android
OS a sink test class and the more so the
main activity class OPN stealer is
connected to send mails read class node
which extends asynctask next import node
editor de Graaff while analyzing any
binary code you know cross reference
information is more useful than one
could imagine to online the
functionality of the ejectors
unfortunately the input important
section like the information is not
located in any specific section of text
file header we must discover importa
classes for our service as mentioned a
component plays a significant role for
the seat of breath therefore devil
defines import class as a class
referenced by a component classes and
and more important class could also have
its own imported import recursively of
PN Stiller the gmail send the class is
imported from both main activity class
and the send mails read class and gmail
sender class requires internet
permission
unless the string notoriety to the reps
wild devil I'm already starving
particles the virtual string object
mimic King java.lang.string string bow
string builder string blah blah etc are
maintained them if the virtual string
object I'll level instead parameter in
the command delay to the either a
component or import table will generate
the relationship between the text and
the class in which the commands issued
pn still has two email addresses note
issued in centimeters with class and one
text node containing the q''-word imei
issue the main activity class so this is
our first and complete a life cycle
graph of Android morale actually it was
the first stable outfit of my
visualization pilot devil and this is
running version of graft ye this is P
and stealer let's throw crap
a little bit different different because
is it is latest version my paper is jump
some or ok so far we have focused on how
to build the graph from now on we'll
discuss how the lifecycle graph can be
applied in detecting Android Maria prior
to seeing the real samples in case
studies we should have a general idea of
a life cycling the app live cycling
could simply be put as traversing or
outgoing note from one node on a
lifecycle graph recursively typically
from entry point yes it's all about
traversing a graph I will show animation
of life cycling of pn stealer
but as we'll see next the app life
cycling is very useful for investigating
the behavior of Android UF and also very
effective identifying distinct behavior
therefore I think app life cycling could
be well suited to detecting suspicious
behavior of Android moral the following
walkthroughs will show some new
perspectives and eventually tell a story
how effectively a well-drawn graph could
be used in finding unusual patterns and
making a lesion assumption about
maliciousness the first case studies
tourjournal it is clear their main
activity class is the main on entry
point as it is connected main and
launcher intent node 1 out Boing edge
from main activity class northpoint the
inter-service class node which means
that main activity class Trott start the
install service class and the install
subscribes no disconnected little locked
Thomason node this means you know
instance of class requires the
permission which are lost on application
to list inaudible system load files also
install sobs class node has one outgoing
edge to application vnd android package
a kite mine time node which means that
instance of class has the functionality
of downloading APK file finally install
service class node has three outgoing
edge to string all labeled exe chmod 347
package manager installed which means
that intercepted classes execute those
commands in a nutshell children not you
guys one unusual permission and if we
start it download and install an APK
file above everything else the eff life
cycle graph of trojan or has the
lead cover ratio of the graph putting
together or of behaviors we've seen we
can say that children are certainly
militias the next case studies caught on
this model has some distinct
characteristics such as accessing SMS
impacts hiding app icons in the launcher
and registering device a demain receiver
or at the beginning see the graph main
activity class has two outgoing edges to
string not label the address beginning
content SMS which explains the behavior
of accessing SMS inbox and the change
componenti enabled state permission is
required by main activity class which
explains hiding of the icon in the
launcher finally device a demain enabled
intent node hassle has an incoming edge
from main activity class node and has
outgoing edge to air sex screen class
node which requires buying the device
admin permission these tells us that
main activity class lived registers as
extreme class as the device admin
receiver as you seen even just a simple
picture with nine nodes and 880 s or
internally or leasable 8 into object
relations could represent over 3
malicious behaviors quite well and also
true turncoat hawk has the main app
class extending application class the
inheritance of classes class is
represented in yellow green color as you
know well as the context of entire
application the application class is the
starting point when executing the
program there are four EP node and the
epi
asian class note are connected to each
other and then the main at class
references Fievel receivers in total
sent to jail deceiver singh naseeba
delivered receiver ting naseebo and
tickly see the class and all at the
beginning even before the main
activities created and you eyes as seen
by the usual georgian hotel calls Fievel
receivers in a stealth way and the fiber
receivers also have both outgoing at two
and incoming edge from their own intent
action node which means that all five
receivers themselves register themselves
as broadcast receiver clearly measures
these behaviors and the grab can make in
tikis story quite simple in a manner
never seen before next case study is
true don't bank on this morale has
interesting characteristics in that one
broadcaster leasable in this case the a
class on the graph has too many intense
actions we could find this unusual
feature by leading Android Memphis file
and of course simply by doing the graph
but the letter can tell the same story
in a less boring and more representative
ways the sky blue colored not represent
the intentional actions in this case
most of intent actions are connected to
a class accordingly the ladies of a
class note has grown to the largest of
all furthermore force layout algorithm
natural expand the range of a class note
and each intent action node to the
largest of all let's see
our resolution is some low too low this
is a class and has too many intent
actions
next case is dangerous when there are
many prevalent variants of a one piece
of model we should dig out the common
characteristics and then contain the
whole Moriya family as best as fast
possible in this case also ab lifecycle
graph could make our lives easier this
graph represents the infamous Troodon
generative family January is a custom
limited access to key for Android the
ticket is being sold for 300 US dollars
to anyone who wants to automate the more
rare distribution process the Creator
promises that mireya can take pictures
like of the audio and video downloaded
recent pictures LaHood calls and the
texts and more so the gender of the
family has so many functions that it
leads to heavy workload for us security
researchers with the graph however it
takes much less time and effort to
determine our sample as a general parent
because every Dan droid variant has a
large Sun flower shaped sub graph in the
center so to speak all the Android
variants have many cross references to
their inner classes in other words
learnable component which he implement
the majority of each malicious behaviors
this capitalistic gives some flower like
shape to the graph ok humans tend to
perceive and remember the world in
images and maria researchers are no
exception they can perceive and remember
more rare in images moreover with a
well-made visualization engine in your
arsenal it becomes much easier to
identify a new more rare in your own
senses for instance if you encounter new
samples having subgraph very seemingly
dead of danger you can assume it is
malicious and predictable we're family
it might belong to
so this one is this one is 10 Troy and
name have drawn service and each variant
this is period of the Android has my
service is my sobs although name is
changes to my service the shape of graph
is all the same of all types of under
the more rail identifying a piece of
lead packaging packaging more rare is
more challenging than any others in this
case also by comparing the graph of
alleged to me to app with the dead of
suspicious ones there maliciousness
could be italy labeled the graph on the
left is that of legitimate heir bounce
ball while the graph of righty is that
overly packaged one back to SMS monitor
take a closer look at to add two graphs
they have the main entry point
burnsville activity class in common in
green box in addition back door SMS
motor has one more graph independent of
the main one in red box on additional
graph the broadcast receiver SMS money
to class plays a role as an another
entry point that deceives SMS received
intent and requires internet lead roles
little phone state a nexus fine location
permissions and performs of a broadcast
and also access these phone numbers and
pictures and never insist the coding
class which requires Lakota audio
permission finally SMS monitor class
widget too suspicious URLs as a scene
the comparison of the two graph easily
Livius the most common functionalities
and additional ones I will conclude some
interesting point every Android app has
essential building blocks known as egg
components the relationships between AB
components construct the app life cycle
which can effectively be visualized in a
graph using force directed to layout
algorithms the app lifecycle graph is
well suited to analyzing how on android
app operates the app life cycling
travels or outgoing node from one model
recursively typically from entry point
and it's useful for analyzing the
behavior and so effective in identifying
a distinct behavior that can it can be
used to detect malicious behavior and by
comparing two graphs we can also
identify the packaging more rare to sum
up the proper visualization of morale as
performed by devil could be a wonderful
tool it can provide insight into wa
beers of immoral and can even heighten
the census of security researchers who
are drowning in ad elegy of life italy
increasing more well as the singles a
picture is worth a thousand words that's
all thank you any questions so thank you
very much i think we do have time for
just one question maybe although we are
sitting right in front of a coffee break
so if anybody has something they
desperately want to ask okay we have one
question right in the middle in the bank
please hello I have was one question
about architecture of your tool as I
understand the very some client-server
architecture yes you use some client for
send samples to serve areas so important
yes you have your tool have some
architectural likely answer various so I
think the question is the architecture
is client and the server architecture
yes okay so why client-server White's
isn't only standalone tools standalone
application why you using client and
server why not only the one tool ah yes
this is the our own automated male
analysis tab part of this is real system
and currently we we implement on the
server side first and verified we deploy
it to the client or one application okay
okay and I think with that this will
conclude our session I think it's up to
us to thank you for an excellent