yeah so finally please welcome Eric you
from no minimum for inside fqdn searches
on the internet thank you can you hear
me good morning sorry for the delay and
recently we have observed some strange
internet traffic especially with a large
increase of unique 40 qualified at only
names and the suddenly increase of those
kind of larger volumes post-series
impact on the interlopers availability
as we as sterility so let's take a look
at some root causes behind the soldiers
before we are going to do that let's
revisit what's going on with ems and
then don't mean any service so can
anyone remember this IP address do you
know what does it stand for actually
this is our conference website so tennis
is very simple internet service provide
translation from pneumatic IP address
which is normally hard to remember to a
more user-friendly and domain name so
the dinners basically consists of number
of the records which basically translate
the dhamma names and IP address and this
is very basic function that required and
used by all the little among internet
apps but at the same time that the US
has been
used more frequently by bad guys in the
past we have seen that Venus has been
used as enable functions to build up
large skill pallets like things to
conduct a PG attack or DDoS attack as
well as Maori distribution of such a
visionary we have seen that deenus has
been used as direct attacking tools
things like Tina's amplification attack
basically you can create a large thing
as a response for short dns queries as
well as so-called a long term sub domain
attacks that can be used to take down yo
Gina's resolvers or the naming service
system for enterprise custom dns e is
also kind of serrated vector for latinas
colony basically you can turner or other
network protocols or data through the
port 53 so the data we have used for
this study is an ad image traffic with
other type of data as well for the
endless traffic basically we have about
three terabytes data connect everything
and the data is coming from all the
major x.x peace global winery and for
the privacy privacy concerns what we
have done is that we are normalize all
the source IP addresses of Venus Queens
basically what the IP address we collect
it will be all the faculty address but
the
RX piece they have a key to to a reverse
translation from the faculty adjust to
the rear IP address so the organization
of the source IP address give us a good
mechanism to preserve the privacy at the
same time we can have very useful data
so this three terabytes is corresponding
about three percent of the global dmoz
resolver traffic which give us pretty
good canal global view so we use this
data set to help us to identify a
malicious activities things like what we
did score and later on so here is the
measurement based on our data about the
number of the unique domain names on the
internet in the past 12 months and you
can see the blue line is a baseline
which is a normal damage traffic that
normally we all represent about three
hundred minion kind of unique domain
names we have seen on the internet but a
whale attack happens with all the kind
of either abuse of the day Athena's
protocol or other kind of activities we
see a lot of kind of high spark of the
unique thumbing names surround the ninja
of this color spark from a one minion
dominance up to 5.2 billion dominance so
this is kind of very difficult kind of
impacts
so let's take a look at some of the kind
of DNS based attacks that behind the
surging of the toning names volume on
the internet couple of things that we
have observed one is the amplification
attacks the non long subdomains northern
South America is quite interesting it
first occurred about three years ago
basically you can attach random strings
as kind of prefixed of a legitimate
dominance and game is tunneling of
course you can use either kind of text
field or subdomain name strings to
convert a useful information past you
file an interesting observation we have
seen that home gateways or homer orders
has been a part of this kind of attack
platform we have SI SE lo or good talks
here in the past two days talking about
the vulnerable home waters that are can
easily infected and upload it with
attacking tools so here is the user case
we have kind of analyzed this is based
law on every Desai's Alex piece data
this is a one-day data you can see the
chart on the Left basically shows a
partition of so-called good Tina's
traffic whisper tienes traffic and that
day we saw about twelve percent of the
DNS queries are associated with
malicious activities the chart on the
right side is further grouping of the
malicious tina's traffic
and the majority of them actually were
involved with random subatomic attacks
that that's about eight percent another
fifteen percent was involved with
amplification attacks why the
traditional Adina's kind of traffic used
for ballot commander control that volume
is a small that was about five percent
but as we know that five percent
actually might have much kind of high
impact because of the nature of the
ballots cnc for the pilot traffic of
that five cent here is a further Dennis
query accounts a solution with different
palates kind of on types for that
particular custom on Saturday and the
majority of the kind of bad at C&C
activities were socialized information
staining activities they are also some
legitimate kind of Lake see ddos parts
like my tools and bullet or is there
since that custom also provides mobile
service we also see some kind of
smartphones parts activities like msn
sander so with the disco love analyze it
give us pretty good visibility of what's
going wrong and throws a tina's traffic
analyze so now let's look at the kind of
dingers and replication attacks how did
it go in the past we have seen that
those kind of amplification attacks may
really enabled by opening as a resolver
like I see that awk but these
we have see that the so-called
purpose-built amplifier startled crow so
this is an atoning named restore club
but are you this is the dawning name set
up exclusively for amplification attack
and this kind of amplifier can produce a
large amount of demons DDoS attack
streams here is the simple formula to
calculate the strength of the DDoS
traffic the borderline basically shows
that if we have four kilobytes kind of
exercise with nine min inquiries we can
produce 300 gigabytes can i tank strings
which is power which is enough to take
down any powerful web sites if the
exercise is up to 40 kilo bytes then we
can only need to have less than one
minute Kremers it's very simple to
construct this so-called purpose beaut
amplifier for this versatile cloth are
you basically the sky just use a set of
text strings and the exercise is close
to four cables there are other classical
method to construct amplifier here is
set of a records that can easily to
produce over 8k bites and since eyes so
it's pretty easy she do this gonna say
and it's rather well here is that
basically the sky just copy the
President Obama's not a neutrality
speech as
way to produce the amplifying so you can
see the answer size is over 3k both well
of the largest cannot amplify we have
see so far is the sky it produce the
answer size of 43 kilobytes so that's
the kind of amplification and attack for
the random subtly it take a different
approach the way they prove a
constructed is kind of queries is use on
random strings like the ones in the
right color and attached to the target
so called a codon which colored in a
young bro with this kind of random sub
donning a traffic which is very
different than our low modulus traffic
for the low modulus traffic we can have
so-called cash heat normally to every
eighty percent which is pretty high so
basically we'd only need to do recursion
for every single game escuela Y if what
is kind of random our sub Atomics
queries each one is unique so we have to
do recursing for each of those kind of
sub queries and which basically increase
the workload for the resolver if it is
eighty percent for the lomo traffic then
we have to pay 5x workload for the
random sampling credits which also means
that if we have say if we have a DNS
resolver designed to solve
to answer 100k queries per second for
this kind of random subdominant where's
the workload we are the 500,000 or cubes
yes yes that's a lot another thing is it
and we have seen many so-called large
powerful website states they provide a
very big data pipe to a pazul absorb and
normal DDoS attack traffic but here in
this case this color at can easily take
it down the lady cinema of that powerful
web site so there's a little way to take
a look on our website down here the
earth ones example how those kind of
random sub timing queries kind of is
composed this is a Chinese gaming site
des chant 28 calm so you can see they
can use a variance of randoms of strings
attached to that King this chantel 8.com
that caused that can easily take down
this kind of website we also see that
the this kind of technique has been
moved from us kind of gaming sites to a
more high ranking website this is attack
against a minecraft power silver it's
similar technique and the table on the
right side basically show within 24
hours the number of unique subtly names
for that
mindcraft silver the the total volume is
very big it cannot reach to 170 million
unique sub toning queries for that
minecraft server and that's pretty easy
to take down on that seller and make
eight legged service unavailable more
reason early we have see that this
technique started being used to attack
some local sighs I for the privacy
concern and I did not show that local
sites can have four names but you can
see and the the way the controls that is
kind of random some tuning strings is
quite Kramer and is it just use time
step plot some randoms of strings and
for that custom actually that website
was also take down quite easy the top
theories actually is not safe as well
last week this is a new type of strings
we have seen that went to tour com so
that post some kind of challenges in the
sense that on some solutions in the past
people have been used to deal with this
kind of naanum subtly armed attacks is
basically disabled all the car
of dingers queries to that target domain
name if it's kind of low profile only
name it's fine you can block all the
traffic because it will have no impact
to you but if it's highlighted and
turning them or the one like coyotes
it's very hard to just use a simple
blocking because that we are also
disable the key demand traffic so we
have to find a better way to deal with
this kind of attacks so let's take a
look at how this kind of traffic can be
generated you know what's the kind of
how many hikes please we need to launch
this gonna attack this is a one-day
attack traffic analyze you can see that
for single IP address and within one
hour that IP address can challenge over
9 million queries and it's it's pretty
powerful and if we look at this
histogram within 15 IP addresses we can
produce over 60 million queries so for
that one for that particular attack for
single XPS and it only need to have 200
IP addresses to generate 83 million
queries within one hour and this is
another way to look at on the number of
IPA and addresses involved with attack
per hour and a notice that most of those
IP addresses are associated with home
Reuters home devices
another thing we have observed with this
kind of thing as a tag is Dennis tunnel
so for this tunnel traffic is very
similar to on random subatomic attack
traffic but it's used for different
purpose you can see here is basically to
open your spot 53 to convert some kind
of informations behind the firewall we
have seen on some talks about vulnerable
home gateways and one thing is that we
have noticed that most of home again
ways either don't have puzzled or have a
very weak kind of puzzled specially for
default here and many customs or
consumers they don't bother to change
the past password at all so if we go to
this website load a password huh if you
kind of put your orders and name it will
give you all the default puzzled as you
can see most of kind of homo ladders
they use admin or public or long as the
puzzled so it's very easy to get into
those home gateways here is already
example is not gear and basically
Medicare is use one two three four as
the default we're just puzzled they
don't bother to use any kind of
sophisticated password at all so that's
very kind of post challenge of us
because those kind of home
home gateway device can be easily access
and can be easily infected and be part
of this kind of attack platform so what
can we do from genocide what we have
found in that it will be important to do
in traffic theatre at increased site
basically to look at what are the kind
of good traffic about traffic and
disable the bad traffic it's important
to have Leo town cannot analyze
capability because as we see is pretty
easy to generate different kind of
attractions and wide arresting is also
important especially for the long term
sub Tommy attacks because most of the
lava truck traffic mixed with the
determine our DNS queries so without a
good wider listing we will not be able
to have effective protection at all so
in summary and we have seen this kind of
huge increase of domain names on the
internet most of them come from that
so-called a dns based attacks and that
is very serious problem so besides what
we need to do is to make cleaners as
infrastructure more stable at the same
time we also need to address the weak
link in the security chain one of the
weakening clear is kind of home a
getaway device and that need to be
secured okay that's the end of my talk I
do I have some time for the QA I think
we have time for one to two questions so
are there any questions from our
audience
so well what do you think a whole can be
routed dilemma be resolved with all the
default passwords yeah this is I guess
suddenly education of the conoco summary
is important so that people can realize
if we don't bother to change the default
passport puzzled not only across the
serious problem another thing is it to
work with a vendor to ensure that they
provide a better kind of protection for
example to provide the requirement that
you have Ching changing your password
when you first install your order yeah
rotors can definitely be a very powerful
bot army right yes sure if you have no
questions and let's say thank you