and i'll pass over the mic all right
thank you
yeah great good morning good afternoon
and even good evening for some of you
um so um i'm really glad and uh
we are glad to present about miss today
and so it's a
double series of workshops so we start
with a workshop of the introduction and
we go
more deeper tomorrow in that senior
workshop
um i'm alexander noah i do work for
circle and
i work in the miss parker team too
so today uh the agenda is the following
uh we will do a quick introduction to to
miss
a kind of of one-hour sessions with
all the detail about myst and then a
more like kind of usage deep dive
of one hour where we do amazons together
um for the logistic aspect um
in the chat room we will share with you
uh
all the details how to access the mist
instance so during the sessions in the
workshop
you can connect to a dedicated michelin
stand that we set up for you
and this one will be used for all the
end and zones that we will
we do as i just mentioned we have a
small short break of 15 minutes
and then we will continue in the end
zone and so on
depending of how far we are today uh
we will maybe talk about the community
building aspect but this is a topic for
tomorrow obviously
but if we have some time remaining we
might uh talk about this and then we
have a
q a sessions uh to discuss about the
different topic and so on
so don't hesitate to to put your
question into and to zoom
uh directly and we will try to answer
her life
all those questions that you are asking
during uh during this session
so first of all welcome all as well from
me so i'm on rashi claudia i'm
also working at circle working on miss
um to just kick things off um i think
it's a good
good moment to start a little bit about
the history of how this whole thing
started how myst came about
so just a quick introduction of where we
came from and where where we are
nowadays uh initially this whole thing
for us with miss
started as part of a of a series of
incidents that we had in
back in 2012 between national and
military certs at the time
where we were basically investigating um
attacks
that were hitting several of the
institutions at the at the time
and one of the interesting things that
we found was that even though we had
something called the malware analysis
working group which was this which is a
group that was regularly meeting and
discussing ongoing incidents
we still had a massive gap in between
those meetings
where everyone was working in their own
silo on basically the same attack and
and doing reverse engineering of the
same attacks without
having the ways the means or the
processes
to directly share with our peers so we
ended up with a lot of duplication of
work which ended
which was obviously frustrating from uh
for many of us
so christoph and the bus at the time he
was working at the belgian
ministry of defense um in his free time
wrote a platform called side of sick
that later on ended up becoming miss so
the initial idea was
really for reverse engineers to share
the output of their work directly with
their peers
in a hosted platform and since then
obviously miss has evolved and changed
the scope of what we were nowadays doing
with misp and what sort of information
we're sharing
but it all started with this and since
then it has been an ongoing effort
basically by
a large community of different
requirements and different needs
and that has been building both the
ideas that go into misp as well as the
software itself
next time please
yeah so what is the background and why
we are doing
we missed it uh i think like on rash
mentioned it started from a with a kind
of
verisco project for a small set of
cesium
circulates is nowadays
the search for the private sector the
community modernities in luxembourg
and we basically deal with the
development of mix not only for our use
case but for many
different users so we are called as
a third we basically operate the
development and we operate
differentiating communities
so a little bit about our involvement
and
why we're doing this in the first place
so we as circle we're funded by the
ministry of economy to basically build
security for the private sector uh and a
lot of what we do involves uh open
source software development so we're
basically
the funding that we get for the uh for
activities also cover our development
forms
we're also uh besides just building the
tools like santa's our dimension we're
also
basically involved in a lot of sharing
activities as well as our day-to-day
operations we're users of the
tool primarily as well we basically host
a bunch of different communities for the
uh national c-certs for the
luxembourgish private sector community
for law enforcement uh organizations
financial institutions and so on and so
forth
so so we're kind of uh
in the game on both sides so to say that
both as a
producer and as a consumer also and the
project was
co-financed by the euro european union
under the sev project
uh so this is also one of the sources of
the income that we got basically to
build the tool and as a first member you
have access to a misping stamp that is
operated
maintained by the first and circle that
you can get access to
so you just need to to use your
traditional credential or
access at first and you get access to
this instance with information
that you can use and so on we will talk
about that later on
so me the main question and i think it's
coming from this story uh
as andresh mentioned from the early days
miss was
focusing from a very specific aspect
which was malware reversing and so on
nowadays it's are sharing platforms we
are basically sharing any kind of
intelligence through uh through miss
um because we had an evolution of the
time for the different things so
and our main goals and that's very
important for us it's an open source
software so that means miss will always
remain an open source project we even
take
some decisions within the project to
keep it as
open source and that's that's really a
key for us so it's really uh
something that you can download yourself
from on your infrastructure and so on
you can really have the full control on
the software stack
when you are using lisp and one of the
goals of the software itself is to
collect information
from other partners from in the analyst
from automatic tools from different
fields and so on
that was really one of the initial goal
of myth is like being able to collect
to get all this information into one uh
one place
and then afterwards what you can do with
it is to normalize
correlate this information extend the
information and reach
information with more information and
then
really benefit from the sharing aspect
of mix and you can allow
teams and community to cover collaborate
and we have
seen miss for example use not only
within different organizations but even
within a single organization you can for
example run multiple myths
to collaborate directly on different
investigations
impedance and casey and obviously when
you have all this information and all
these analysis performance to miss
you are ready to use this information to
for example
feed your automatic protective tools
like intrusion detection systems
firewalls whatever and to feed
automatically those
information to basically make protective
measures
in your in your environment
so start from the starting point that we
already mentioned basically how we
started out with ms
let's have a quick look at how uh the
user user base of mr evolved in terms of
the different types of stakeholders
within our own organizations and other
organizations
the reason for that is obviously that
this drives the development process as
well
so the way miss grows over time really
depends the type of users that are using
the
type of users that are requesting new
features or that are providing pull
requests on the project and providing
code
for the project so i said before
initially
the scope of miss was very limited it
was basically just the output of malware
reversers which meant
raw indicators that we were extracting
during the process and that we're
sharing directly
with our partners this meant very little
analysis was done on each of these
individual indicators there was very
little information in terms of
of why those data points are relevant in
the long term how they are meant to be
used
from detection perspective they were
really just the raw output
from the analysis process or the
reversing process
now one of the side effects of this when
you start building a collection within
your organization of this information
the security analysts are feeding your
various protective tools become
interested in that data set
because obviously whatever is targeting
your organization or your direct peers
are probably the most relevant piece of
information that you can use for
detection
so one of the first steps that we that
we opened
up to was basically involving our own
security analysis our
own organizations so they can hook their
the output of
of the reverse engineering team
up to their seams to their ids's to
their firewalls
and to feed this data directly into
their protective measures
now one of the interesting things when
you start doing that though is that you
generate a new type of output which is
timeliness for the data freshness for
the data as well as feedback on how
useful the data was
so we're very often when you're
extracting information for uh
by sandboxing for example a lot of the
data generated will be nice in the end
and this noise will generate false
positive alerts for example in your id
in your detection tools now feeding this
information back
to data gave it a whole new type of
value
we had freshness so if an older
indicator was reused
over time we saw that that is still
something that is actively to be
monitored
and if we saw that something turned out
to be a cleaned up host
in the meanwhile or something was a
false positive from the get-go
we could feed that information back as
well so
suddenly once you have timeliness as
well as the the raw data itself
you uh you get the intelligence and
lists interested that are tracking the
movements and the
changes of how attackers operate
uh over time so that means that usually
back then
especially in 2012 in most of our
organizations the people that are doing
intelligence and the people that were
doing operations and security for the
operations were usually working in their
own silos
so while there was obviously interaction
between the teams it was not as
ingrained to work together
between those type of rules but this
changed over time and one of the changes
that
that we saw happened was that the output
of what the security analysts
and the reversers and the analysts were
outputting basically from the operation
side
became more and more interesting for the
intelligence analysts that meant that
if they were tracking a certain threat
actor and they could attribute certain
actions that they were seen in the
network of the organization
to the certain threat actor they could
monitor for example how
the given actuary was changing how fast
they were changing infrastructure
whether they were switching up their
methodology and this
gave them a lot of idea of useful data
of improving their libraries of the
threat actors that they were tracking
so suddenly we got this group interest
as well and they were obviously
producing data as well so nowadays if
you look at misp
going from a raw indicator uh sharing
platform that mis was initially
nowadays you have a lot of the high
level threat intel information included
with the data as well so you will see
threat reports
you will see interconnected information
about uh
threat actors modus operandi uh
infrastructure impact and so on so all
these extra layers of information that
we're missing initially
so this was the biggest change that we
had over time within our own
organizations but
obviously it's a c-cert that has
different constituencies
we're also interacting with the security
teams of other organizations and one of
the things we noticed early on was
there's a lot of the issues that other
types of organizations had internally
with information sharing are very
similar to ours
so initially the first use case that we
got that was different and from our
normal security use case
was basically the various financial
organizations reaching out to us saying
that their fraud teams were
running into similar sort of issues with
sharing between their teams
sharing with other partner teams
information about mule accounts and
about other fraud related information
so they reached out to us and they
basically their security teams reached
out to us and said
can't we just try to help them uh also
to share that sort of information
through misdirectly i mean we already
had the tooling in place
it was just a question of changing the
data model so
we we started doing that for uh together
with the financial sector initially
where we expanded the data model of miss
when we allowed for modeling of new
custom data types
and it's even surprising to us at the
time turned into a success
very rapidly so nowadays we're involved
with quite a few different types of
organizations out there
replicating the same scenario where for
example law enforcement where we
initially had
mostly contact with their security teams
and helping them build data sets for
their
for bootstrapping their forensic
investigations nowadays we have all
sorts of information sharing involving
uh for example uh seized good
information sharing from
border control agencies uh law
enforcement agencies uh
sharing information about passenger
information so a lot of the type of data
sharing that was very unusual for us as
a sister initially
now once you get all this data in a
system and you
started building a data set from your
community
you start to see trends in the data set
and this is what gets
for example our risk analysis team
interested in it the moment that you're
seeing how attackers are changing their
trends over time
you can better advise your uh your
constituency your customers and so on
about the different phase
risks that they might be facing and the
different risks that they should be
preparing for
and preparing the organizations for
based on what the same sector is facing
perhaps in the same geographic location
so suddenly you get a lot of knowledge
out of the collected data as long as
data is well contextualized and i think
this will be one of the main topics that
we're going to be talking about quite a
bit today and tomorrow
is contextualizing the information and
making the information actually usable
and turning data really into knowledge
yeah so like andrash mentioned
we have a pretty large set of different
communities using mist
and over the time it became i think more
complicated to handle all those requests
from different organizations
um so we came with a model of governance
even if it's a very lightweight one we
decided to have this kind of models to
still benefit from the open source
community model and then
bring all the experience from a
different community into systems where
it allows us to develop and extend the
software so we decided to
create this kind of models where we
basically
take care of all the features and
requests that we receive from different
organizations
so we use this kind of priority list of
different features
and we get we get that feedback from
different
one of the abusive one i would say is
github so we get the feed from
the different issue that we receive from
github i mean on the if you look at on
github you'll see that we have a
significant number of issues and those
issue are usually for us a way to track
down
all the different requests of features
in myth and that's one way to get it
another way and this one is a quite
common one one
is basically a training or session like
this where people are providing feedback
bug reports future requests and so on
directly during the training and for us
uh i think really practical and we can
get all this information needed for us
to improve the software another thing
that we do and
that's maybe for the audience some
people are interested in that one
we know that there are plenty of
different misuse of groups that we don't
control and that we don't manage that's
great we have for example isaac isao
doing really those kind of things where
you have those kind of user groups
and what we do we participate to on a
regular basis to one of those groups for
example on a quarterly basis on a yearly
basis
and we do a collection of requirements
from those different groups
during during one session and that's
really
i think useful for us because it's a way
to to gather information so for example
on rash mentioned those
financial groups where people are
sharing information about bank account
detail and so on
and that's where we basically gather all
those requirements
so if you are setting up a group
somewhere in u.s or
in the world about sharing information
and so on and you want to
invite us at some point in time it's a
way for us to gather those kind of
requirements
we do a summit which is a yearly event
usually it was physical but nowadays
it's virtual trainings
so it's basically every user or
organizations using mispresenting what
they are doing
it's a way for us to to see the
interactions and see what
can be improved in myths and see or
dynamic in the community behind
and then we have a kind of twenty
percent project around in myth
where we design new functionalities and
we test
them out for example one of those is the
detailing of indicators
which was a request from different
organizations but it was kind of
difficult to design
and with this kind of models where we we
designed first as a kind of prototype
multiple iterations uh we did a multiple
research paper on that and then finally
this become part of the core software
we will show that later on but so we
have a lightweight governance model
but really the goal is to to gather as
much feedback from the user so don't
hesitate if you have any
bug reports idea and so on either open
issue
get in touch with us um we are more than
we
you are more than welcome to basically
share such kind of information
yeah now addressing the elephant in the
room
when you bring so many different
organizations together and build a large
community of sharing with different
needs and requirements
you're obviously going to have to run
into conflicting requirements as well
so one of the most obvious ones that
that we're dealing with very often with
information sharing and something that
that we have we're working on tackling
basically
since we started with miss is dealing
with a different requirement of
of what you count as valuable
information depending on your use case
so this is
different also within the different
analysts different
roles within the same organization as
well so for example for us as a c-cert
in general
uh detection is the most important
matter so we're interested
uh in in using indicators to detect if
our constituency
is affected by something that the
information is being
shared about or whether uh any of the
the infrastructure that we're
responsible for is uh is infected on the
other hand
if you're if you're talking to an isp
one of the large
requirements from an isp basically will
be able to protect their users
from potential harm so that means that
there are
if there are any urls websites and so on
that
they should block for their users they
need to be able to generate a block list
out of the data
that is considered to be malicious
enough now if you compare these two use
cases with each other detection versus
blocking
you will immediately see that the effect
of
of having a false positive in the data
set or data that is no longer fresh
has a completely different impact sure
for us when
that are mostly in the detection game
it's annoying we get a false positive
alert it has to be handled
and it takes time and effort it also
introduces something called alert
fatigue that i'm sure many of you are
familiar with
if you're getting a lot of false
positive alerts you're more likely to
ignore the
next alert that you get but besides that
it has no real
operational impact on us on the other
hand for an isp that ends up blocking
something that is uh
potentially a false positive might have
a catastrophic impact
imagine if someone accidentally for
example shares
facebook.com as an indicator that might
basically cause a riot with their uh
with their users or it might stop one
but it's a different story
but with that in mind you see that these
two use cases are already conflicting
now if you also take the perspective of
intelligence unless that are tracking
strategy movements into account that's
an
even more lacks use case where you care
uh where you care about
uh whether something is a fresh
indicator still or not
even less than the other two groups the
reason for that is you're interested in
the historical movements
of a threat actor for example so even if
something is no longer
an indicator because and an infected
website was cleaned up
since the time when the indicator was
shared they still want to see
how long for example a threat actor was
using that infrastructure
how quickly they changed to something
else and what methods they used
back when they were exploiting it so if
you bring
these different requirements on board on
the same
platform is difficult and there are some
things that we can do to alleviate these
issues for example what we do with
mispis
we have a system called warning list
system that allows us to filter out
obvious false positives
so we maintain these lists of most
most common websites empty hash lists
public dns resolvers and all these
typical things that end up in
the sets while doing automatic
extraction for example
that end up being false positives but
with that said this is just one part of
the story
uh so if you're looking at the different
use cases up there that doesn't solve
our issue of
of having different requirements from
from the data set based on what you do
with it
and this is where contextualization
becomes more important again
if we can supply the information
together with the data why this data is
relevant and what context you're
supposed to be using it
then the consumers of the data can make
those decisions for themselves based on
whatever they want to use
the data for in any of those different
use cases
so so one of our main efforts with misp
has been
to be able to provide these different
structures together with the data and to
be able to label data well enough
back to you yeah so and that's
i think an important regarding the
different kind of use cases and so on
and we try to try to
to support those different use cases and
that's
sometimes challenging for us but luckily
we are at the same time
part of various community so we can see
the different use cases especially
regarding the ending of
of false positive which is a
an ongoing challenge but uh we will show
you or to handle that
and at the same time we basically
operate those different communities um
so for example we operate a pretty large
one for the private sector
um where we have a lot a lot of
organizations more than
1200 organizations are basically uh
connected there um
it's pretty large and we see an active
community sharing information and then
you have plenty of different communities
some that we don't know even about
because you can even run your own
private communities without telling
anyone that's fine
that's part of the system but if you you
want to have
different kind of communities you can
connect those uh
automatically then you have i would say
different kind of model you have those
kind of of
fully island mode communities to kind of
trust in groups so for example for the
intelligence community
it's very common for them to run miss
spin and island mode
so having a gap system and so on
sometimes they are partially connected
with third parties to share partial
information so for example we know some
organizations
or for example border controls or
customs
are using myths but they still need to
share some some small information and
that
partially connected system risk freely
and supports those kind of models
and then you have community that are
more broad and more large
for example in the financial sector and
i think the secret to luxembourg has
some banks
uh we we are involved in various sharing
communities
at european level and worldwide level um
where for example we
we know some isaac that are dedicated to
the financial sector are using it as a
sharing mechanism you have some
organizations that are really
dedicated to a payment processing system
that are using this to share
automatically
information and so on or analysis uh one
of
the i was a pretty large community too
with the military
organization in international
organizations first for example
you have a lot of first number using
myths for sharing their information
but there are plenty of networks
national governmental networks
a military one intelligence one or even
nato for example are using
using myths so maybe some of you are
eligible to access those ones so we have
on the mixed
interface a way to connect to those
community and you can reach out to the
different community by asking an access
for example
then you have very specific communities
that are set up by
security vendors it's not uncommon to
see for example a security vendor
services their own miss
we have seen for example some
traditional agents vendors running a
dedicated miss
or even some operators of specific cloud
services running as municipal instance
to share information amongst
their different customers then you have
communities that are
i would say very specific on the topic
for example you have
about sick information uh forced news
and stuff like that you have
communities doing that uh for example we
cooperate one called the commitment in
mist which is really targeting
um covet 19 as a topic and then you have
10 different subtopics like cybex
security
health related topics and forms so you
can see that this can be really used on
different model of communities
you can bridge those communities you can
interconnect those with together
you can keep it for yourself so it's
really a matter of models um
worldwide there are i would say a lot of
communities that we are not aware of
uh but we as fiscal uh operates
around 20 communities nowadays that you
can basically get access
and that's just sharing the chat uh the
access to the commit 19
list and if you want to get access to
that one you can connect on the
on the main page and self-register and
you can request
access to that community so you see that
misp has
different groups different communities
and it's up to you at the end to decide
which kind of community you want to
visit
so a little bit besides all the
technical things that we talked about
that we do with miss spend when that we
try to solve it
in terms of sharing there are obviously
going to be other hurdles that you have
to overcome whenever it comes to
information sharing
one of the the toughest things to
overcome and this is where no two can
really help you
is to get enough trust in a community to
be able to share your information with
them
so the only way to facilitate this is
really social interactions
so sadly though we're living in times
where social interactions are tougher
than usual
but for example events like first
conferences are great ways to get to
know your community and to
build this trust and build those those
social relationships that you need to be
able to
to really exchange meaningful
information with the community
so i really encourage everyone that that
wants to partake in information sharing
communities to
to be social to reach out and to get to
know your community because that's the
biggest facilitator for sharing in the
first place
other than that there are obviously some
legal restrictions that you have
that might come up in the entire process
we see this very often with
organizations where the the first
questions that they ask us when they
join
in our communities okay how does this
fit into gdpr for example
if my legal team asks me why i'm sharing
any information out what can i
give them as an explanation of why i'm
supposed to or allowed to do this
so if you need any help with that we
have a bunch of compliance documentation
and that we've been working on together
with a bunch of partners
and so we have descriptions for uh how
this fits into the gdpr the nis
directive
and some other frameworks so we just
have a look there and if you have any
questions or if you feel that anything
is not covered let
us know and we keep updating our uh our
documentation
based on on feedback of what's missing
or ideas that we should be incorporating
in there
but generally
what once your legal team is more
familiar with the process and why this
is style
why ensuring security for your
organization and for the data that you
have to secure
is important then it's seen more as a
benefit than a hurdle really
but it it obviously takes time to get
this into your processes to define why
you're
doing what you're doing uh your
retention periods
describing how you're going to handle
data and so on
so this obviously has some ramp up time
but we have
a lot of documentation that will help
you with that there are also some
practical restrictions that we hear from
organizations so very often when
organizations reach out to us
the first thing they say is we don't
really have any information to share
we don't have the capability for example
to build those highly vetted threat
reports that we're so used to from
feed providers and obviously very few
organizations do
with that said information sharing comes
in many different
shapes and sizes for example going back
to the initial use case about
providing feedback from your analysts
about the data that you receive from
your community is already valuable
information sharing so if someone for
example provides sightings
i've also seen this indicator at this
given time
that can already help you tune the data
set
for what goes into your working data
sets for for detection and blocking and
so on
also providing information on false
positives and some information that
provide that you provided
to the community turns out to be false
or something that is no longer relevant
getting information that is valid as
well so pretty much everyone has
information to share by just using the
information and running
into frustration with the data by itself
also besides not having information to
share
there comes also the issue of time
most most of us are overburdened with
the different tasks that we're facing
nowadays
so um taking extra time uh out of the
day to
encode information and to share it out
in the community
is obviously going to be an extra burden
there is no way around it what we try to
do with misper
is to make this process as minimal as
possible but it is going to be a time
investment in the end
after all especially if you want to vet
the data if you want to ensure that you
don't uh
that you the right data reaches right
but
recipients this always has a time
drain on you as well but in return this
is offset by what you gain
by by sharing that information we're
going to talk about this a little bit
more during the community building part
about what effects you're going to see
if you're sharing information and why it
is relevant for you
but to to to basically sum it up in one
sentence
and whatever affects your organization
is probably the most important
information for you and if you get
feedback on that
what what you're seeing in your network
and
and more eyes on it more perspectives
more
perhaps more sophisticated methods of
research from other organizations
then that will probably just improve
your own security posture the best way
it can
now besides timeliness and uh and
basically having information to share
there's also the issue of different
classification models so classification
not just in a sense of
of deciding who we share information
with
but how we classify information really
in terms of
uh contextualizating it we are all used
to naming things
a certain way in our organizations in
our communities and we've probably
been doing it for longer than
information systems
digital information systems exist so
we're probably using a lot of those
vocabularies that we've been using for
decades
and what one of the things that we
wanted to avoid with misp is to
get these communities to switch to a
different way
of describing things so if you already
have your set methods your set processes
how you define things
we don't want to alter that so one of
the things that we do with misplan we're
going to talk a fair bit about that
tomorrow mostly
is that you have ways to describe your
own taxonomies and your own vocabularies
to use those in your community so very
often when you're spinning up the
community and when you're starting out
with the sharing
community a national sharing community
sectorial one whatever
then one of the first tasks is basically
defining those those common vocabularies
that you're going to be using
now apart from the vocabularies
themselves there is also the issue of
of us speaking many different languages
in terms of
of our tools using different formats so
that means even
within our own organization which is
rather small we have a set of different
tools
that will ingest data in different
formats
or will prefer to ingest data in given
format so one of the things we also try
to do with ms
is to act as a hub for all your
different tools
that will get their data translated into
the format that they can best ingest
obviously this is something where we
cannot be completely
100 percent covering all the other
things that exist out there so one of
the things we try to do with mist
is make it as modular as possible and
it's easy to encode your own formats as
possible
we're not going to go deeply into the
into how to do this during the training
but if anyone is interested about that
just
let us know and we'll point you in the
right direction where you can find
documentation on how to modularize and
how to
build import and export my usefulness
so just one side note all the training
materials are available online
like martial mentioned we have a gita
repository with a
pretty extensive rhythmic files with all
the material that we provide
there's a miss book too which includes a
lot of reference
to to miss as as you know misspell it's
pretty large topic coming from from
technical aspect and
you you'll see that in a minute about
the project overview
so don't hesitate to go there on the on
the training
page on github this one is a good
reference because it's really pointing
to the different elements
that we have we have a huge slide deck
of
close to 500 pages of slide deck on the
music book we have close to 500 pages i
would not mention the number of pages
for taxonomies galaxies and front it's
quite large too
but really look at this as a kind of way
to shape what you like
so it's really there to help you and if
you see something missing
uh let us know but we have slides for
example for for
system requirements uh things like uh
for example building community that
we'll talk tomorrow uh that's
part of it uh but for more the
programmatic aspect eti
how to integrate with miss penson uh how
to extend it
to the plenty of slides regarding that
so it's really a good reference
and thanks to martial to share this
information on the on the chat
so to just give a quick overview of this
project and really to show that
the project is quite large nowadays um
we basically have
like four pillars of uh of things in me
one is obviously the open software
itself um
so the initial version in 2012 it was
the small first small block there
the miss core software which is like
just the software
uh mainly for the uh lamb aspect where
you have the backend the web interface
and so on but over the time
the project extended with multiple
things so if you look on the github
repository of mid project we have around
50 repositories so
it's pretty large just to summarize what
are the different one
we have for example the miss modules um
which is an
easy way to extend miss so the behavior
of mist
on the expansion side on the impor
export and so on by just writing
python modules it's super easy to
develop and use
and the idea behind is obviously to
extend myths without knowing
the core details about the system then
we have a library called pymist and this
pie mist library is basically a
python library to expose a new the
mispress api so mispass a large
rest api this one can be quite large but
by misc is really
helping you to to for example jet events
create feet and stuff like that so it's
really important if you want to
extend me to have a look at primis that
is not the only librarian for for
extending uh
mystia some in golang you have some
other in python two you have others in
java and so on
but the parameters one is the one that
is maintained by
the uh author of myth so it's maintained
by us and
you can have a look at this one it's
really the one that's up to date it's
really core and part of the system too
because we use it for our own tests
within me then we have different
repository i will just mention one which
is
dashboard the dashboard is an extension
module
in mist using what we call the mq
feed mix so we have a kind of way to
have kind of a real-time fit
in this pretense between 012 kafka and
so on but we wanted to show an example
application for that and the miss
dashboard is exactly that
is a way to really get all the
information that you're in nisp
uh into a very nice dashboard and so on
this is really to
have a good example of what you can do
with information within misspen or you
can use it
so that's the main pillar you have
plenty of other projects but those one
are the main
main one then on top of that you have um
what we call the intelligent knowledge
database of
misp um and rush mentioned about the
difficulty
sometimes in some organizations to use a
proper classification and so on
and we try to ease this in this
different organization by having a kind
of library of all the taxonomies that
exist
so we started as a very simple one where
it was just including for example a
taxonomy like the traffic light protocol
one first is using it and it's a
commonly used classification but over
the time we have seen that many
organizations have different
classification and so on so we already
in advance we prepare all those
taxonomies in
possible information let's expose lisp
and you can enable the one that you want
so we have around 150 libraries
ranging from classifications uh specific
ones for
intelligence communities uh and some
other activities so this one is our
really useful label and you can just
pick the one that you want and we
maintain those one
so we have some that are coming from
third party some that we are operating
as with projects or creating
it's really usually a good source to see
how other communities are using
classifying and contextualizing the
information there's nevertheless the
taxonomy itself was like
kind of liable those labels were quite
small
so it was not like completely extensive
information so
over the time we maintain a kind of more
extensive one called the galaxy
you will hear the term very often
those galaxies are defining many things
for example one of the most common one
is the trajectory we have a
huge database of selectors but a lot of
times it was extended
for example microsoft is not using
tractors for example here this activity
group is part of the
of the galaxy uh it's really one that we
use for different and you can represent
whatever
galaxy you want so you have a predefined
set of existing one
but you can create your own so if you
have your own product or database
you can create your own from scratch or
you can reuse and fork existing ones so
that's really
those kind of things that we manage in
the project is not only code and
software we manage those kind of
knowledge base
uh for intelligent contextualization um
we have some specific one like the
notice list this one is a
pretty small one that you use for the
gdpr aspect
but this one can be used for anything
you want it's for informing
the analyst or the user of misp when he
touched some specific information in
mist
that could impact for example the legal
framework and so on it's actively using
intelligence community
law enforcement and so on maybe less in
security operation center but it's
coming more and more due to the legal
uh site of information sharing and
especially storing information that
might contain personal information
then we have another one called the
warning list and um andrasali quickly
mentioned this kind of of
recurring problems or false positives
and the one in list are
basically list of existing potential for
politics for example we have lists of
well-known ipr graphs from microsoft for
example we have list of
things like domain names used by google
and so on so
that's already helping users to find out
if something might be a false positive
and we do that automatically and we
maintain those libraries because one
english they're automatically updated
regularly
um i think we have around 50 lists
nowadays
it's it's really useful when you do on a
day-to-day basis and creating events and
so on you can really find
and spot things that might be a false
positive in advance
by having those running lists enabled
and again it's up to the user to select
one money warning list or to enable
everything depending on the
different use case so that's one of
those pillar
knowledge base i mean a lot of
contributions coming from threat parties
are coming from that
aspect so it's not really programmers or
or coders that are contributing there
but it's more analysts
and people doing religious intelligence
or classification and so on is really
something that is useful for everyone
without being your direct contributions
on the code
then over the times we we we became a
kind of de facto standard and
uh nowadays is even more than a de facto
standard is a standard
um we published as an interesting
engineering task force draft
all those documents especially the core
format
and to ease that for the development of
external tools
integration and so on um so if you're
interested you can go to the
standard website where we describe the
different standards that we
published we even co-host standards that
are for people
integrating with with um with mist
and we have specific standards for
example for the object template
and that's something that we will talk
about but that's something that was
really a need for for
us from the early beginning of mist a
lot of organizations want to have their
own structure of information
about objects and so on and we have a
flexible modeling miss to
really create your own data models and
this one is standardized too
and it's really helping sharing
communities to
extend miss us wishes and their models
without breaking the
the standards itself so that's really
interesting for for showing you new
models
and then next to that we will do
everything possible to help community
um and rush mentioned the question of
the
legal aspect and i think maybe some of
you already have this order to
its legal theme about the information
sharing policies and so on
we try to make it easier um so we
publish this kind of compliance document
and so on it's part of this project
everything is open source again so
everything we do is open source and uh
on open access you can reuse it and so
on we have for example a specific
document about building communities
which is something that we do within the
cross size
project and it's containing kind of best
practices
what are kind of agreement that you can
use when doing a setup of
sharing communities up to things about
how to do contextualization and so on
um so that's that's maybe something that
for an organization that wants to boost
up
an isaac or sharing communities they can
look at those documents and so on so
it's again a thing that we try to help
for example we produce kind of osc feeds
of existing reports and so on to
not only have software ready but i have
to have some some some
content and to show what kind of
information can be shared
within uh different communities
so to let some get some of the naming
conventions out of the way
and before we start really hands-on
stuff and just a quick explanation of
the different
uh data points and uh and naming
conventions that we use for them so it's
a bit easier afterwards
this can be a bit overwhelming don't
worry we'll go through everything step
by step also
during the hands-on part so basically
all the data that goes into mist we
separate into two main layers
or one we call data layer which is
really everything it has to do with
individual data points they're
compositioning
and so on so everything that we share in
misp in general in this regard
starts with something that we call an
event these are our general
envelopes for information so that means
that
whenever we're describing an incident
we're describing a threat report we're
describing a watch list that we
recurringly update
and they will all be grouped into
something that we call an event
uh so the name is uh is a little bit
controversial at times we try to pick a
name that
that is at the least amount of a loaded
term that we could find
but obviously even with that there it
can be a bit confusing but just consider
it as a generic
container for data that has some
contextual linking
then each of these events is populated
with lists of attributes so attributes
are more
most basic data points in misp an
attribute can describe for example an ip
address
you can describe describe a file hash or
it can describe
a car plate number for example
there it's basically just an individual
data point with some basic context
around it such as
describing in what context this was seen
in
what type we're using to describe the
attribute for example that
we're using an md5 hash to describe the
hash of a file
would be one of those descriptions
hopefully not used as much these days
but that's just an example and then we
can take these individual attributes and
composite them
into what we call objects that are
describing multifaceted
concepts for example a file object would
be described by a list of attributes
including a file name different file
hashes
maybe file entropy and so on and so
forth
each of these individual objects and
attributes can then be further
interlinked by what we call references
so that means that if we most of the
time when we're describing data in this
we're trying to tell a story so we're
thinking graphs instead of individual
data points
that means that we can for example
describe the entire flow of an attack
from the initial attack vector all the
way to the exploitation
uh using the interconnected graphs using
these references so we could say
initially it all started with an email
that was received
that contained for example a malicious
sample
which then had to send this effect in
our infrastructure so all of these
different steps can be then described
via
different references there then to
aggregate this information
into a and and aggregate the sightings
of this information we have a structure
that basically captures sightings from
our different
information sources that means if you
have an ids that is generating alerts
you can feed information back on when
when individual attributes were seen
uh in your network in your premises or
at your partners and so on
so this is basically it for the data
layer these are
our main building blocks for that now in
order to contextualize this information
we have different tools at our disposal
the most simple one is what we call tags
these are basic text labels that we
attach on individual data points or
entire events
and these can either be created freely
or most commonly they come from what we
call taxonomies
they're basically standardized
vocabularies and that are either shared
by us so the miss project at large
or by individual communities to their
members so
these vocabularies can include anything
from for example something is simple and
and commonly used as tlp to national
classifications
to various different sectoral
classifications and so on
now if you wanted to provide more
high-level information
that that we instead of just simple
labels for the information
we can use what we call galaxy clusters
so galaxy cluster is basically a
knowledge based element that we use as a
label
these can be either coming from standard
libraries
such as the ones that we maintain or you
can create them at hawken mess
that means if you're describing a threat
actor you could create create a threat
actor galaxy cluster
that describes the various metadata
about the threat actor and then use this
to label your data whenever you think
that
whatever you're describing is associated
with a strategy
you can also create for example a galaxy
cluster describing the different
uh uh target sectors and then interlink
using cluster relationships uh the uh
the uh threat actor galaxy clusters
with target sectors
with exploited tdps and so on and so
forth so these are the high level
structures that you can put on top of
your data basically to further
contextualize it
alex
yeah so just to summarize it and that's
always a
lot of people are asking about the or do
you summarize it about
for example in easy way you have to see
really
misprevented as an envelope and then you
have information inside and then
what android describe is basically
different component that you have within
that envelope and then you have
contextual
contextual layers on that envelope and
relationship that are
basically based on on that
so another thing that is very often and
i think
it is good to explain it is about the
terminology between
indicators attributes and so on that is
a different special indicator of
compromise and so on
in misp an attribute is close to an
indicator
and we have this kind of flexible models
where
maybe some of you are familiar with
observables in myth
we call it attributes and those
observables are basically depending on
the type so
we have a specific flag in
in attributes which is basically
defining
if information can be used automatically
for detection and that's
i think one of the most important
aspects when we talk about attribute in
mist
an attribute can become an observable or
a become an indicator of compromise
depending on the
simple flag and this is quite important
because
a lot of analysis and so on will depend
on that and especially or you will use
that afterwards
if you plan for example to use the data
into a protective
systems and so on the ids flags need to
be set so
the thing is if i take an example you
reverse the malware
and this malware is connected to
google.com for testing the connectivity
obviously you will have an attribute for
example www.google.com
and this one is an interesting indicator
for information
for the analyst so like that you can for
example
maybe cluster those kind of malware
together as in this kind of behavior
nevertheless
you are not really interested in that
information as an indicator of
compromise
because it will generate a huge amount
of
false positive but if for example at
some point you have an ideology that is
really dedicated to that malware then
you will set the ids flag
so the thing is when you
uh define in in in missed
these flags and we will show you later
on it's very important because
it will define what you can do with
information later on
if you're going to automate and so on
like
in mix what we try to do too instead of
having just indicators
it's very common and i think many of you
know about it
you might see for example a list of
ashes so like for example md5s without
any context
and sometimes it's difficult to know
exactly what we are talking about um
are we talking about md5 of malicious
sample are we
talking about md5 of legitimate software
are we talking about the md5
value of the x55 are we talking about an
md5 as a mutex in memory we have plenty
of way of seeing those kind of md5 so
we try in myth to have what we call the
kind of
i would not say kill shine but at least
contextualization a category that
help to see in which context this has
been seen
and as for example f1 and d5 you might
have a payload delivery
telling that in which scope this has
been so that's been in mist
we have always and complementary type
so for example for an md5 files you can
say that this one is
from a file or is an md5 of a figure
screen
thing so that means always in miss
try to have as an indicator all those
three information together
so it is giving at least more context
and if you cannot say this context
myth will try to automatically set it so
attributes are equal to indicators but
with a bit more of information which is
useful for
you at least being in a way to
understand what is in a position to
understand
what you have in front of you when you
have to treat those attributes
so this is just a brief
view of what this looks like we're going
to see this more in
practice basically the idea is that that
all the data that we have in misp
uh if it's well defined uh allows us to
draw a graph out of the data and allows
us to tell a story more easily
so here we see a simple example
that basically shows
the bank account that is associated with
the threat actor
uh with all the various different data
points with uh with it
and then we can basically relate these
different data points to each other and
give it give the relationship a term as
well so in this case we see from the
chart immediately there
that that person is the owner of that
bank account with all those different
data points
uh for us as humans it's it's generally
much more
easily understood if we look at a graph
like that and tell the story that way
then if we look at a tabularized view of
the data
so one of the goals and something that
we hope that we get out of
of going through trainings like these is
to really convert also the participants
to uh to see the value of producing data
in that way instead of just
sharing raw indicator lists for example
and that's again what's what we think
that's really important is the
contextualization again
so i mentioned we have the galaxies in
mist
and we have plenty of representation
headaches and so on and obviously one
that is quite important is the mighty
attack one
so might have attack is what only the
galaxy
and we have this flexible mosaic mist
that you can represent those kind of
matrix-like model
which is a case for attack which is a
very convenient way of representing the
different
techniques in a progressive way used by
the attackers and that's exactly what we
can do in mist so you have this
kind of model and we have different
model formats
so again we have an advanced
i would say integration with attack but
you can extend it with multiple
different kinds of galaxies which are
similar to
attacks or complementary for example we
have the individual control system of
attack
it's a separated galaxy you can even
create a custom one
directly in the system and then you can
filter out your data and so on
and that's exactly the thing that we why
we are i would say
in bracket pushing people to do more
contextualization it would be useful for
them at the end
because this kind of information is
really
showing you for example your gap in your
defense
your specific things that the techniques
that are not used by an attacker you
might ask
why maybe because you are missing a
specific detection point that you cannot
detect this kind of attacks
or things like that so it's really
actively using the data
to show something meaningful with it and
i think attack is one of the way
but if you can combine this with
additional information like site links
uh contextualization of the relationship
between different objects and so on
basically everything in hand to improve
your question secure it
yeah perhaps something to add to this as
well some of the
additional advantages is the moment that
you encode all this information along
with the data you can start asking those
those questions from your tool basically
for example show me
uh what sort of threats my my
constituency is facing over the past
year
and overlaid over how what sort of
threats it was facing a year ago what
are the trends that have evolved since
then
the other thing that it really helps
with is it also gives you a high level
overview of in
individual reports that means if i'm
looking at an event in misp
i and it has 800 different attributes
described in there
making any sense out of that quickly is
very difficult but getting a high level
overview using
a micro attack where you say oh okay
this this has to deal with spearfishing
it has to deal with information
exfiltration so these immediately tell
me the story of what i'm dealing with
without having to dig deeper into the
data
itself so it is incredibly useful for an
analyst that is trying to make sense of
the data that you're sharing
also as for the sharing itself i mean
one of the main goals with miss is
obviously to share
information we haven't really talked
about the sharing mechanisms yet
we basically have a bunch of different
uh functionalities and myths that we're
going to see over the next
two days the deal with distributing the
information
one of the most obvious ones to tackle
is basically who
is to be the recipient of information
that we're sharing
so basically miss we we can basically
set the distribution
uh settings for each individual data
point individually
or for entire collections of data in one
shot so that means if we
create an event we can decide who we
share the event with but we can further
restrict
individual attributes or objects further
now
in who we share the information with
gets decided on
using one of two different
means one of them is a simple system
where we tell miss pure allowed to
distribute it to everyone that has
access to this community for example
or to everyone just that is directly
connected to my community
but you can also define more strict
distribution lists what we call sharing
groups
where you individually name the
organizations that are to be the
recipients
now on top of that one of the things
that we often struggle with
is especially if you're in some of those
communities
or you're taking part or assisting some
of the communities
where sharing any information might lead
to reputation or financial loss
for example in the financial sector we
have these worries very often
where if a financial organization were
to share any information out it could be
misconstrued
as a successful attack against them so
instead they choose to
basically even if it was something
completely benign that they caught in
their sandboxes in their honeypots
whatever
and they decide not to share it out of
fear of
of incurring this reputation loss so one
of the things that we have in this
system called delegation where you can
for example appoint your isac your
central
uh authority for a community uh
your a national c cert whatever with the
responsibility of taking over the data
that you produce
and to share it out in their name so
that that way it's basically a semi
anonymized information sharing where you
are completely removed from the data
that is shared out
so the only two parties that will know
who
the originator of the data is are you
and whoever is
is taking over the data and taking over
the responsibility for the data
on top of that one of the things that we
wanted to achieve with this was
basically to build a collaboration with
our different partners so it means that
whenever we're
sharing information we don't want it to
be a one-way communication so we don't
want to have this whole feed provider
and consumers
uh relationship but we want everyone to
be able to chip in with their ideas
so while anything that you produce in
mist will only be tied and editable by
your organization others can make
proposals or counter analysis to it
so proposals are a system where you can
basically flag
information as incorrect and provide
feedback on how to improve it or how you
can add your own perspective to an event
so if you receive an event from a third
party you can say oh i can improve it
and listen this way
please incorporate these changes in the
event and then the original producer can
make the decision whether to incorporate
it or discard your
your changes as for counter analysis
this is what we call extend events
you can basically create an event that
that latches onto an original shared by
a third party
and provide your own perspective of it
and then you keep full control of the
data and you become the owner of
whatever the extension is that you
produce to the original event
this happens very often for us for
example when
when a vendor shares out a report
for example we get a report from say
kaspersky and
we have additional information or we
have a a a
different opinion on something then we
might create an extended event that we
share out to our constituency
which which if they have access to the
original report will latch onto it
and it will show our perspective on top
of the original
now as for the exchange itself every
organization is free to host their own
mispencence and then they can decide who
they want to interconnect with if both
parties agree
a synchronization link is established
between the two mispencences and sharing
can start flowing between them
now this this sharing is still governed
by those distribution lists and by some
other mechanism that we'll get
we'll talk about more tomorrow but
basically and
mispe exchanges information between the
individual nodes in
in kind of a mesh network way we also
have feed system that allows us to
generate feeds and to share those feeds
with larger communities so we as circle
we provide another sim feed for example
that we make freely available in our
infrastructure anyone can just point
their mist to it and adjust the data
and keep it updated using the feed
system this is also great if you have
ever have the need of sharing
information between aircraft systems
you can just generate a feed based on
certain
filter rules um and basically basically
share it through
say a flash drive or something like that
with an internal system
now all of these filtering options are
basically user defined and they rely
heavily also on the contextualization so
very often what we're doing
and especially if you were ever signing
up for the covidiences that i mentioned
before
is you can also make those decisions
based on the context what data you're
interested in what date you're
interested in sharing out
for example if you connect to covet
instance we categorize all of the
information into three categories
health related information so basically
information about the spread of the
pandemic
information about misinformation at
targeting kovid
and also cyber security uh threats that
are targeting
uh that are now basically abusing the
whole kobe situation with
remote work and so on so if you're only
interested in certain
in one or two of these three different
topics then you can set up your filters
to only ingest data coming from
a subset of the data set very often what
we do as well is we have these internal
mis clusters in our own organization as
well
where we collect information from
different sources so we have a dedicated
miss vincents where we purely collect
spam information for example so
for a constituency anyone can forward
their spam to us
and we'll just generate events out of
those in that lisp generally this
information is really not
interesting for a day-to-day detection
use for example
but what we do is we cache this
information and we can cross-correlate
this information with our operational
instance
that means if we start the analysis
process and we we start
an investigation then we immediately see
the moment we start encoding data points
oh this is something that was already
flagged once in our
spam instance this information that that
instance knows about then we can pivot
over to that instance
and fetch the information related to
that same data point that we're also
seeing in our current incident and
perhaps get more information that is
relevant for us from there
so basically very often we have these
multimis internal enclaves that help us
basically to
to separate different concerns and
different collection mechanisms into
their own instances
just just in that scope and i think is
linked to the question that we had
um regarding the military miss pinternal
enclave
someone was asking about synchronizing
with an existing miss penson
you have this kind of local enclave
options where you can synchronize to me
like they behave in the same
organization that's one of the
interesting options
by the way i would just give the mic to
josh that will explain a bit more about
the question and answer in zoom
um to have directly the ability to
answer the question answering
in the market i just want to jump in
real quick uh yeah if you have any
questions
uh please direct them at the q a
board versus the chat room that way we
can kind of keep a monitor
of that and other people can actually
see the questions and the answer
directly in that area so if you have
questions feel free to use the q a board
and that's all thank you josh that's
very useful
um so we can keep track of them and we
can answer live or
directly in the chat okay great um so
you see that the sharing
aspect of risk is like pretty extensive
um
and you have different models of of
usage of me
some people have this pre-consumption
about me being like oh
i need to share with me no it's
depending on what you want to do with
your misconception
and the core functionality of myths is
really to to give i would say the
freedom to each of the
organizations to decide what to do with
the data if they want to share or not
and we uh always design myths that
everyone can be kind of consumers like
basically getting data from different
fields or producer contributors
uh unless mentioned a different way of
contributing like
sightings making proposals things like
that
but it's up to the original contributors
to decide if they want to share
that's really the thing with me speak
and set up a myth for like
just pulling data getting the data and
that's it
and if at one point in time you want to
like push some data
you can just enable it and that's it so
it's really uh
uh it's just a matter of just tuning the
configuration the filtering really on
the synchronization
if you want to share so you don't have
to change anything in your misp instance
it's just a matter of
of what you decide and what you need to
share and then the thing that is really
important in mist
everything can be in flex i mean events
for example that we were mentioning so
those kind of envelope
information might change over time
we have we have seen for example some
past or a scenery point
that has been updated like two years
later because they discover
who was the target or the character
behind and that's the thing that's
really nice that we
really want to be flexible you can
really expand the information
either internally add some some common
and so on and to share this information
in your different mist instances and
share with partners
your teams and so on so really miss the
core functionality of my
distributing information but if you
don't want to use it it's fine
you just not you don't just don't enable
synchronization but if you want to
use partially part of synchronization
and so on you just set up
this kind of parameters
so uh on top of collecting all this
information and synchronizing the
information that we talked about before
we basically do a bunch of different
stuff to improve the uh to handle the
quality management of the information as
well so one of the first things we do
is this is something we mentioned a bit
before is we correlate information so
we're interested in data that we've
already seen before
we also have the feedback loop that we
mentioned before with sightings that
means what we
we really want to get timeliness to the
information as well
so that we can but make better decisions
on what we keep in our working data set
for detection for blocking and so on
the false positive management is a huge
part so warning the willingness system
where we basically exclude those typical
false positives uh
plays a very important role in legal
equation and this is also a community
driven effort so if you want to get
involved with that and build
and include your own infrastructure for
example in the warning list and so on
either do it internally for your misport
just share it with the open source
community as well
so let us know if you want to have that
included as well we haven't talked about
enrichment systems yet
but basically one of the things that we
do with misplaced we we
have connectors to all those different
services that you might already be
subscribed to
so if you have uh domain tools passive
total
or what way or any of the other services
intel 471 and so on
that you already subscribed to then you
can use those
services to enrich the data that you're
working on so if you have an incident
and you're encoding information
you go out to all the services that you
connect that you have access to
and fetch the information on what else
those systems know about the different
data points that you're encoding
so that you basically get a jump start
on your on your investigation
now one of the most important things
that we have to deal with and this is
probably i think about 50
of the code base of misp is basically
the apis and the libraries that deal
with integrating misspelled other tools
so everything that we can do by the ui
miss is also exposed to the api
and one of the most important things for
us is to make sure that that
you can use mis as simply a back end for
another tool as opposed to just directly
using this
itself as for timeliness we haven't
really touched on that yet
besides the sighting aspect you can also
encode information about
time ranges when something was seen and
you can build a full timeline
of the events that uh that occurred
during a set uh set incident for example
so
if you encode this information together
with all your data points
then you get an additional graph out of
it that tells you when what happens
and time-based correlations are really
important as well so so very often
when you're seeing two things happening
at the same time
they might be related with each other
and they might be worth digging into
whether
there is a link between those two things
that happened
so something else that we will touch on
more tomorrow is
we have a full indicator lifecycle
management system in miss
that means you can define your own rules
and tune your own rules on how you're
going to be
scoring and decaying indicators based on
all the contextualization that you have
based on the type of the data that you
have based on
source of the information that you have
and so on and so forth so we're going to
go into much more detail on that
tomorrow alex
yeah so i was just answering a question
and then i will make it public
in a minute that's a question about the
kpi
and using mist there there are different
ways to evolution to evaluate the
quality of the information that you
share
in misp um one of those is obviously to
look at statistics it's a statistics
include paging in myths to see for
example the kind of indicator shared by
organization and so on
in addition to that um base for example
miss dashboard which includes a kind of
gamification of the platforms
and which is giving badges on per
organization depending on the kind of
information that you share
and that's a nice way to to find out if
you are reaching a certain level of
capabilities when using misc
uh where you basically have for example
information like
are you using sightings do you use
objects and and stuff like that for
example
thing that you can really look at if you
want to see if the quality of
information that you create in this
piece
i would just following the standards
what is following the best practices in
the different organization is to compare
with the q and os in feed there are some
some goods even in the usa feed
and for example things that are really a
good indicator is to see
are you just using indicators and using
objects are those objects linked
together by using the relationship to it
are you using galaxies are those
galaxies that are at the even level
absolute levels do you have tags labels
on specific
objects or specific attributes and sort
of different parameters and i think
the question from uh from hong kong is
is pretty good so and if you really want
to
dive into the kpi aspect of myths and
quality of information in addition to
what
andras just said there are some some
other things about the quality of
information shared within the community
and there's some some good examples in
the miss dashboard about the different
budgets
even the models for sharing such kind of
information
so another thing that is i think quite
useful and it was one of the core
functionality of this was the
correlation features this one is
it looks like obvious but it's not
always obvious i mean a lot of tools in
the security field exist
but they don't do automatic correlations
for example at the ces we are using
ticketing system
and sometimes it's very difficult to
find if we have two correlating events
and what we decided in misp which covers
the cost i mean the correlation engine
is maybe one of the costly aspects of
of using missed on a database level but
it's really useful um
for example here we just have an example
of
information about some malware spam that
are used
to share uh information about
target target campaigns for the
financial
malware and what we can see there is
basically correlation
on similar points and those ones are
mainly epic addresses of the
infrastructure
but you can really spot interesting
things there for example
you see that the third bone in germany
share
indicators you have a polish bank
sharing the same kind of indicators we
were sharing such kind of indicators too
and even if they have different names or
different contextualization we can
really spot
similar infrastructure so we can see
okay it's maybe the same
actors using an infrastructure for
different kind of things
or for example we can actually see here
that we have different
names of the similar malware so really
this is important for example another
thing that is
interesting is for example if you have a
simple hyperlapse
set up by a non-civilized company for
example you can directly spot it
i mean if you have i don't know apt-29
and you have like
three different criminals malware going
on that one and so on
obviously it's usually not the same
infrastructures but on the other hand
you can directly spot okay this one is
already take down it's handled by this
antivirus company and you can you can
really handle it
so it's really a way to quickly find if
it's a new thread
or or something that is already known in
the in the infrastructure
so a little bit of the sightings
themselves so we're going to see this
more in practice
uh basically we have a
very simple interfacing list that allows
us to to tell
the community that we've seen an
indicator as well when we've seen it
and perhaps also include information on
what tool we've picked up
what context we've seen so sightings can
have some metadata
on top of just being a sighting we can
also flag
something that we call negative
sightings which is a false positive
sighting
where we indicate that we've seen it but
it produced issues for us so it was a
false positive
we can also indicate that something is
uh is potentially going to be expired at
a certain date
so this is interesting for example if
we're in talks with an
uh with a provider and we know that
there is going to be a takedown
then we can already indicate that okay
this is no longer an indicator after a
certain point in time
apart from that if you are ever dealing
with bulk sightings so if you want to
for example just
capture any ip address
seen in your network or something like
that there is another tool
called citing db and which is developed
by divo it's also an open source tool
uh it's really recommended to use that
it allows you to to capture
massive massive amounts of data so if
you're capturing the entire
network flow of your of your
constituency
and bear your organization and just
dumping all the data
uh somewhere this is a great place to do
it and it's a very fast lookup database
that is integrated with misp
where miss can automatically just query
it for any of the indicators that you're
seeing in expansion whether
it was seen in your network and in which
time range it was seen and the
interesting thing with that is
but it's also for historical values so
if you're just doing bulk collection of
uh of all the observables in your
network
and then even half a year later if it
turns out that
then that you an indicator is being
shared with you that
that correlates with with an observable
that uh inciting db from half a year ago
then you know that you might need to
launch an investigation into something
that happened half a year ago in relugs
and so on
based on the historic uh look up alex
just just complementary notes regarding
sightings and
that's something that is basically maybe
the easiest way of sharing additional
information
it costs nothing and if you are
connected to a misp instance and you can
tell
someone else that you have seen it it's
it's really a
quick thing that can be useful for many
many many organizations so
the sighting itself sounds like a very
small feature
but at the end it's a an easy one for
for contributing and helping the others
to know if an indicator is still
valuable and so on society
is really something that um that can
basically be a kind of of entry-level
things to do
when when sharing information
something else that we have in misspell
this one is i think becoming more and
more important and
we will do a quick demo later on uh
regarding that
it's a timeline i mean when we do
uh analysis and so on it's really i
would say common to have a first-in-last
scene to see the evolution of things
over time
um in the example that you see on the
screen there
uh it's based on specific characters
that center
a significant numbers of
um of specifying and those
perfectionists
uh uh very well known when we collect
those
times time and so on so you can really
see and enter the evolution of a
specific group and so on um this
can be done automatically for example
passive dns records i have
very often the first in-last scene and
automatically you can really
build and create this kind of timeline
because it can be really cumbersome if
you
you have to do it manually um so we have
a nice view like that so that means
every time you set a first in-last scene
on any attribute object and so on it
automatically purposes on the timelines
and it's an easy way to to see evolution
trend and so on for your
analysis
and this is a completely interactive so
you can navigate over that but you can
we can we will show that later
so for life cycle management again this
is something that we show briefly but
we're going to way more depth about that
tomorrow is basically here
we see some examples of some uh
attributes
that have uh scores applied to them
coming from different
uh uh scoring models so we see there an
ids simple decaying model
and then a custom model titled model 5
that are
basically running on each of those
indicators and they generate a score
taking into account for things such as
labels that are attached to them the
timestamp
on when the attribute was created as
well as the timestamp of the different
sightings that came
in so generally if something is still
being actively seen in your network
that is still relevant despite the
indicator itself being perhaps older
and then using the score that gets
generated from these different models
that you define
you can basically then make those
decisions when you're exporting data to
only include
data above a certain threshold when
you're feeding your seam for example
yeah and this one is quite interesting
because you can really
define it so the thing that is really
important with the
decaying of indicators you are not
modifying that
actually you are really just updating
and overlapping
and you can just define those kind of
models so that means for example
even within a team where you don't agree
on a specific model you can have both
models
it's very common for example to have
models for infusion detection systems
and specific models for i don't know
endpoint the air or endpoint protection
device
and it means you have even a models or
kind of simulator
where you can simulate the different
model that you want to apply
and to see what kind of lifetime you
want to apply uh when it decay
when for example you have a specific
threshold where basically say okay you
don't use anymore those kind of data
and you can do the mapping
with specific taxonomies you can
with the different types attributes and
so on directly
directly missed and it is really a quick
queen so
you are not bound for example we know
that some some tips for example have a
kind of
white system-wide decaying models in
this case not like that
everyone has their models we are sharing
some models and you can define what you
want to use
without really altering the data so that
means this kind of
of information there is just an overlay
and and you actually keep your own data
in the systems without having
any modification
so very
so when it comes to starting out one of
the trickiest things obviously is when
you're starting out with mist
is if you're steering as an empty
instance then getting started and
encoding information is really tough
because you don't know what is really
expected from the communities out there
you don't know
it's a new tool you don't really know
what uh how to get started
so in order to ease this a little bit uh
there are a bunch of different feeds
some of those that we we also provide
ourselves
which is obviously operational
information something that you can use
directly so
these are western feeds that we produce
as well from our tlp white data set
and the idea is that this will really
help with bootstrapping your processes
look at the data we consider that
generally well-formed and well
contextualized
it should give you an idea of what data
generally looks like in this so
don't start out with a fresh instance
just go to your feed menu in your miss
when you're installing it
and pull in some of these uh osm feeds
so that you see the information already
also it's a great way to test your
internal tooling
so if you want to test the apis if you
want to test internal synchronization
it's good to have a larger data set
already from the get go
so that you already see that the
movement of the data is working as
expected
uh yeah the other thing that you can do
and where we're going to talk about that
quite a bit tomorrow
uh is basically figuring out which feeds
are worth ingesting
how the feeds compare to each other
running overlap analysis between them
and so on
so this is something that this is quite
a heavy topic
for tomorrow
you're muted alex yeah yeah yeah just
discover music
so as you can see for for me it's the
development of mysteries done
over the years based on the feedback of
users and that's really one of the key
elements for us
uh we we wanted a tool for us that works
and i think it's key and based on that
we wanted something that works for
others too
and i mean the tool is evolving over
time so you see that we have plenty of
functionalities
on those two two days of workshop we'll
try to cover a part of it
we had already some good questions
regarding how to customize this and so
on
uh we might give you some hints how to
do it and and so on
so we won't be able to cover everything
in those two days but
you'll see that you can really um update
myths based on your specific use cases
and so on so
this is there as a tool um what is
really usually matters another what are
the successful
i would say sharing communities depends
on all the practices
um or you you do that and so on and we
really want at least at the end
even if it's a complex tool and so on to
be as easy as possible
for covering different use case and
that's really the thing that we want to
do is for example for a lot of things
that we have in this
and someone just asked the questions
about how can you customize me
a lot of things you missed can be
customized by just modifying some json
files
it's a case for miss objects so if you
want to create a new object
you just update the json files if you
want to for example create a new
taxonomies
or uh creating a new galaxy you just
create those kind of json files
you have other ways to update and and
and change the behavior of mist
it's based for example on this modules
so if you want to change the behavior of
the expansion and so on
you can just play with miss produce and
we will
quickly show you some examples on these
modules um
but that's that's really that's really
simple i mean there's no another thing
so
and that's the thing that you have to to
understand with myth
project is not just a small open source
software somewhere it's really a
a set of of combination of a tool
software packages open standards various
best practices
shared knowledge base and obviously the
community is using it
so that's really the thing that we will
have we love with first for example it
is to have this kind of community
learning together
sharing information and so that's that's
really a key
key for us um we have i think
more than 500 contributors on on the
project
even more nowadays um so if you want to
become one of the contributors it's
really straightforward i mean if you
have something that's a problem that you
want to solve
for example on an object you just do a
pull request and you you it will be
misspelled immediately and you become a
contributor in the project so
really for us it's uh it's really keen
in mispis to have a kind of tool that is
supporting the different
use cases okay so um
before that we do a break i will share
you with you some
practical details on accessing the miss
training instance because there were
some questions regarding that
and after the break we will do um
the hands-on practical session
with an example so we will heal examples
of you you will hear the full event
based on some information that you
receive so first of all i will
give you some details about how to
access the mispinstance
so first of all we have i candy
page which i obviously share at some
point in time
and i will share it again
yes so there's a page
i can do pages you can even edit i will
i will
paste the link again in the chat for
everyone
that's the link so we have a 50 account
on that
training instance pick randomly one
it doesn't matter if you are multiple
one using the same account
but be careful don't change the password
because maybe some people
will complain and then we have a
training first on 2021
uh password so super simple uh not so
secure but that's fine it's
trending um
you just for the reference uh we uh
for the one that doesn't want to use the
training instance sometimes you
for whatever reason you want to use your
own instance we have virtual images
uh visual box and and um vmware images
for
misp so if you want to play with me
locally and so on
if you want to play with synchronization
too you can even connect those two
so and during the sessions we will
connect to that instance so
the instant is igloo.u
and when you connect you will get access
to um to the intense instance so you
enter your training password so you will
enter with my
specific account and we will use that
instance for the enzyme that we will do
just after the break so
what i propose now is to do a 15 minute
break and we start
at 45 if it's fine for everyone
and we will start by with the practical
sessions
with a specific emails
that we will share in the accmd as a as
a practical example
so thank you for the one that join us
now
and we will start again at 45
to do the hands-on session thank you
very much
thank you
okay and shall we get started
sure welcome back everyone
okay so now what we're going to be doing
is we're going to look a little bit
at miss pizza so we've talked plenty
about it but we haven't actually done
anything with it yet
so i really encourage everyone that has
a misfits to also play along
and to create your own events what we're
going to be doing is we're going to go
through as
any fictional little exercise assume
that you
that you receive an email from uh in
this case
luxembourg english telco this is certain
of them describing an incident of a very
simplistic incident
of what happened what we're going to be
trying to do now is to model this a miss
and to explain how you can further
improve it and contextualize this
information
so before we start uh once you're logged
into the
into miss pinsons such as the hosted
training instance
this is what you're going to be seeing
so it's a it's a little bit squeezed on
alex's screen
but the idea is that you have a list of
events that are listed on the main page
so we're in the event index this is our
landing page when we load up misp
and each of these individual lines
represents an event so they're
describing either an attack
or perhaps a report recurring
distribution
or a certain type of of indicator lists
and so on
so what you're seeing here is you have
each of these events having an id
and some metadata around it so these are
this metadata can be either coming from
this galaxy cluster
system that we mentioned for example
describing different
attacker techniques the different types
of
ransomwares in this case or attack
patterns that are leveraged
and then if we scroll a bit further
right so this is a bit lower resolution
there that we see
but uh you should have it visible on the
same page
um you see the information about uh
what this event is trying to describe to
us
it's simple to understand text-based
representation now this instance is used
for trainings in general so it's going
to be filled with a lot of junk
interspersed with real data that is
coming from our tlp wide feed
so you're going to see some obviously
weird events in there
these are just there for testing just
players playing during an exercise and
so on
but also some real events there so what
we're going to be doing now is we're
going to create our own event based on
that email that we received it's also on
the hackamd
page so just have a look at email
exactly
and we need to start encoding with that
event
so before we include anything in misp
the first thing that we need to do
is we need to create a new event so this
is where everything starts
way to do it is to just click on add
event on the left side of the menu
and then you start with a very
simplistic form that where we can
describe the event in a very high level
so here you see it's it's the first step
is very straightforward
the import the things that we have to
watch out for or here is we already
decide
who gets to see the event so this is the
distribution level and that we need to
set and
basically a basic description of it as
for the distribution itself
you have different uh ways of
interacting with the data here already
so one of the decisions that you have to
make even if you're going to share to
the
wider community out there is do i keep
this internal until i'm ready to share
it with the community
or do i already make it visible to
anyone that has access to the data in
the community
now keep in mind that we have a
publishing process in misp so until an
event is published
it is not propagated out to other missed
instances
that means anyone on the current miss
pencils can see the data
but it will not jump to a different
misspen since at this point in any way
but if you if you're creating it on a
hosted instance
for example if you if your isak is
running a miss pinstance and you're
creating it on that one directly
then this already has an impact on who
can see the data
so the option here either go with your
organization only and then
raise the distribution level once it's
ready to be released or you already
involve addressing the process and you
pick something like community only where
others can chip in with their ideas from
the get-go
so this is up to you it's a risk versus
efficiency question
do i want to share the information and
potentially
overshare a bit by including by
accidentally uploading information that
is not yet
confirmed that it can be shared out
versus losing out on perhaps others
immediately jumping on board and saying
okay this is also something we've seen
we've already done the analysis of it
here you go
so you have to balance those two things
out so let's start
no for example for example what
you have is when people are working on a
case by default they say
it's organization and at one point in
time
the team lead for example decide at some
point it's okay no you can share it
to a wider community and then you change
the distribution level
yeah indeed so let's start with the
organization only for now uh
for different reasons that we'll get
back to later on it allows us to show
off another feature afterwards that is
handy
so we start with that then we have to
describe this the threat level so this
is
a very subjective question uh threat
level will depend a lot on what sort of
an organization you are
versus who you're sharing it with so we
all have different interpretations of
what we consider a high threat level
we have some descriptions for each of
these fields uh
predefined if you click on the little
information box
it will tell you that hi is uh
sophisticated apt malware or zero day
attack
please just freely disregard this
because nowadays a lot of information
sharing
happens in completely different domains
so if a fraud team is sharing
information about
fraudster their definition of high
threat level would be very different
from
those in cyber security for example so
generally it's just a subjective
first measure but a lot of organizations
users use this to briefly filter out
what they should tackle first
so still use it with care if you don't
want to use this field
picking undefined is fine too analysis
the next field describes how far along
you've come with the analysis process
so basically uh with this what you're
telling the communities i'm just
starting out with the analysis
these are my initial findings versus for
example saying that my analysis process
is already complete
i'm not going to be digging more for now
i consider this complete if you have
additional information then obviously
uh already start collaborating with us
so just pick whichever is most
appropriate for you let's just go with
initial for now
and then comes the most important part
of this form which is
describing the event info so this is a
brief description for analysts that are
looking at the data that describe
the best described the event that you're
basically uh
sharing now be brief here and be careful
about
including very domain or organization
specific information one of the mistakes
that
that people often make here is for
example uh
typing a ticket number or ticket id in
there
so if you have a ticketing system and
you basically start your investigation
from your ticketing system
sharing out something like what alex has
typed there is not very handy for anyone
else nobody will have a clue what you
mean with that
another mistake that can happen here
very often is especially if you're
starting out small and
in turn initially you're only keeping
the events for yourself
and then perhaps later on you decide
that you want to maybe perhaps
after all share it out to a community
then one of the things that can really
hurt you at that point is if you've
used different language for example to
describe the event info so we've seen
this very often
we instead of describing the things in
english we
choose our own languages
and myself is hungarian we are we're
pretty prone to doing this
in general uh and this is generally
something that will hurt us
in the long term because uh once you
share it out with a more
international community you either have
to go through the effort of translating
it or basically make it illegible for
the recipient
so stick to something simple simple
phrasing
be as concise as possible
but make sure that it's still understood
we know that it's targeting the telco
sector in luxembourg and we know that we
have a malware sample so that's a pretty
nice
short explanation of what the event is
about
so once we click submit we have our
event created and we already see that
that our event suddenly has a lot of
data that we didn't intentionally put in
there yet
so we see a bunch of tags that are
applied to the event we see that
the event already has information about
uh
who created the information who the
local owners and
information and so on so this basically
takes a lot of local settings from uh
from the instance
and it uses the event when it is created
with these basic datasets
a lot of these also involve the
contextualization that we start out with
so it might seem a little bit pointless
to immediately
label something that we have not even
started working on yet
but also keep in mind that very often
what we do internally in our
organizations is we have several missed
instances
that are uh that already are domain
specific so for example we have our spam
collector instance we have our
our sandboxing ignis vincents and so on
these these already are uh define the
scope of the information that go into
them
so we can already decide okay if we if
we are on our spam collector miss
vincent
anything that goes in there will be
related to spam so in this case we can
remove these tags because we don't
we don't actually want to include those
just yet maybe we can keep that one
because it's still
a draft so that means we will do an
evaluation of this famous email accuracy
and then um so we have some defined
taxonomy
misplan on this instance we enabled for
example the workflow one
uh this one is maybe of interest from
different organizations is
a generic one about workflow uh what is
the current state or other thing so
don't forget uh in the initial event
when we created the event we have
information about
uh the state and stuff like that now
with this what we do is recommend to
have taxonomies and you can you can
really
set up whatever you like and in the misp
event to define the current state of
this event
so we keep draft from this case
yeah indeed so we keep it at this and we
scroll further down and we see that miss
warns us about a few things first of all
data is not published
and second of all if we scroll a bit
further down we see that mispo also
tells us that there are no attributes in
here so this is still an empty envelope
that we
are about to share so list tells us
don't share this just yet
fill it up with data first so at this
point
we can start populating the information
so if you if you look at the
initial document that we that we use as
a starting point we see in there that we
have a lot of
information in there described we see
for example that we are dealing with
spearfishing
we see that we have an email that was
received at a certain
point in time and we also see that
we have an attacker that pretends to be
um
working at the ceo's uh uh daughter
and sending the email address from
spoofed uh
the email from a spoofed email address
so we can start by by describing this
information by including this
information
so perhaps one of the things that we can
take here is let's start with the most
basic thing we're describing an email
so let's start with an email object so
we're going to add an object
and we're going to select email
so here we see that this is coming from
the templating system where you can
define uh pre different concepts with
different fields that have to be then
populated using this object templating
system
so we have a bunch of information that
we can fill out here we see the spoofed
address so we see a from address that we
can encode
okay we also have um
a sample that i don't know if you if
i've uploaded anywhere alex if not just
pick any file for now because
i think that's something i forgot to do
yeah i don't know where the sample is
yeah maybe we should add it
yeah just put putty dot x or something
if you have it
oops
or we can do it as a separate object we
can we can just do this separately yeah
we can do a separate objective
yeah indeed indeed okay so what we can
already
describe here is we can we can still add
the name of the
uh attachment that we had in there
um
just to fast track it a bit
good
so we have a timestamp too which is
interesting so um
this one has been received as a specific
so it was a third
of so the first scene is basically
something that you can you can really uh
set up so it was the third of february
we had a specific time if i'm misleading
um so in this one we have uh this one
has been
sent on received on
[Music]
16 so i can
we also see that that basically
the attachment was spoofing
the document uh
about the report about the ceo's
daughter's
progress in school so we can pick the
file name for the
uh attachment and that is under the
attachment section in the object
good i'm just clicking it
yeah it is called report.x attacks i
mean maybe it's not in the text right
now okay it might not be in the text
might be just the original file
about that so yeah report.x dot x
attachment
and then we also know that it was
received
that we have received header ip so we
can include that as well that's also in
the
stated email it's 137.221
and we even have the hostname if you
want to include that that was also
included in
or in the report
perfect so this is as you can see here
we did not fill everything out because
we don't know everything based on the
report but we knew some of the fields we
also see that
each of these objects basically have
some requirements and we satisfy those
in this case
so if you scroll all the way to the top
you will see that that this object had a
requirement
any of those fields have to be filled
we've definitely met that
so we can just click submit and we can
create our object in this case
so here we see mrs telling us if we
create this object that's what it will
look like
so we have in this case created our
object and now it is attached to the
event and
suddenly stuff happened here so we see
that each of these
attributes already start correlating
with existing events
now we read this uh this little exercise
before we didn't correlate with some of
those previous events
but normally uh if this was a real case
if you get a correlation
that is either something very similar
that already happened before or is it
something that simply
might be a coincidence but it's still
close for investigation
to check is this something that might
help me bootstrap my investigation
or is it just noise that is not maybe a
side note because we have often the
questions
um when you create such object in
you see that can be cumbersome to create
it manually
so don't forget that everything that we
do right now can be done through the api
so you can use pymisp automatically do
it and so on so
what we show there um i think if you
think on the api level
it can be done automatically so if you
have two that are extracting emails
automatically from the
pc mailbox whatever you can
automatically do it in mist
we just show the complete process
manually but you can never mix things
for some event
maybe some might be created
automatically and then update it
manually and so on
something else that might be interesting
here at this point is we've encoded this
object and we look at it
and perhaps we we might want to
to change the distribution settings
based on the different data points that
we have in there
so most of these such as the malicious
host that email is sent from
are technical information that we can
share with the broader community
but perhaps the name of the
school that our ceo's daughter attends
is something that we don't need to share
with the entire community
so we could reduce the distribution of
that individual attribute in this object
so that we keep that for example only
for our own organization and for our own
internal records
so one of the things you can do in this
case is you can edit that individual
attribute
so the from address in the object
and you can set a distribution level to
your organization only
in this case once we release the uh the
event to a broader audience
it will keep this individual attribute
for an organization and it will not
share it out with
uh with other constituencies okay
so some other stuff that happened at
this point we see that
several of you are creating events so
that's great the correlation account
really went up all of the sudden
so it's good to see something else that
happened at this point
is uh is the event itself got correlated
to other events as well so if you scroll
up all the way
we see that the attributes that we've
added are also showing us what other
events we're correlating in so this is a
summary of
all the individual attributes
correlations from the event
that means that if you have if this
object is correlating or
these attributes within the object are
correlating to it with a certain event
and certain other objects are
correlating with other events
then this would be a full summary of all
the events that you're correlating with
you can also draw a graph out of that if
you click on the correlation graph you
will see how the events are interlinked
and you can further explore this by
selecting any of the notes
and pressing x on that to further expand
it with
with it with its own correlations
okay let's go back to event
yeah i don't think we have a lot of
correlations
there for the other events they're all
the same
uh okay now going back to a little
example uh
we have now created four attributes all
together out of
uh of the object template but we could
have done this differently as well what
we could have done
is we could also have created those
attributes individually and added those
to the
uh to the um event directly
so one of the things that we can do now
is we can go back to our report and
tackle the next thing that is described
there and let's do it slightly
differently
so we also see that basically uh the
person
uh that this is impersonated is also
described so that is basically
um in this case
john doe the teacher of the student so
let's just create a personal object and
describe that
so what we can do now is instead of
directly describing it as an object we
can first
add those different fields at least a
name
as individual attributes so let's let's
see how adding individual attributes
work so we click on the little plus icon
above the attribute list
and we simply select category person
and from person we select first name
first name is john
and here we can already define is this
an indicator do we want to
set the for intrusion detection system
flag no definitely not this in itself is
not an indicator
in fact we want to also disable
correlation on this as this is a pretty
common
uh name that is definitely not something
to we don't need a comment for enough
but now we're going to convert it into
an object anyway
uh so what we can do is we can also
disable correlation on this we don't
want to correlate on john
okay okay doesn't matter
actually we can do it uh
the same thing for the last name though
and we can basically say that this is
now
last name now we've added these two
things in there now the problem with
this is if we just had
attributes instead of objects is we
don't really see that
john and do in this case are the first
name and last name belong together
so if i were to describe several people
in the same event you would have a list
of first names and a list of
last names with no connection between
the
two things so it's better to use objects
in general whenever you're describing
multiple aspects of the same thing
obviously if you just have a list of
file hashes that you got from a feed and
you just encode those and you don't have
any other information with them you
might as well just create flat
attributes out of them
because there is nothing else to
describe from your perspective
but even in that case it's arguable
whether you don't want to start an
object
from the get go but what we can do in
this case if we did start with this way
or if you receive information in this
format or your tools parse the data out
in this format is
you can select those two attributes by
clicking the little check marks next
there are little
tick boxes next to them and then
clicking on group selected attributes
into an object
and here miss will propose okay these
are the different object templates that
satisfy
the list of attributes that you've
selected there's a person object that we
can use so let's
just pick that one for now
so here we see if we were to combine
these two things they would be merged
into an object
uh that is fine with us we see first
name will become
the the first name of the object last
name the last name
so let's merge it
now we basically have a personality now
we also know that this person that we're
dealing with here is impersonating uh
the teacher of the ceo's or daughter so
the same person impersonated person is a
teacher of the of the ceo's author
so we added the object and we also see
that there is a um
that we can add just another text field
yeah just text field works
where we can describe it i just want to
first disable the correlation because
different means
okay
yeah that works and we just add a text
description of the identity of the
person we can just say
teacher of the ceo's daughter
okay now we're done we have now added
the additional attribute and now now we
know what this object is actually about
without having a description in there
but we still just have an email and a
person described in here but we don't
know anything else we
don't know that this email is proofing
to be that person so we should add a
relationship between the two
now for this we can switch over to the
event graph view
so that is a little bit further up this
one allows us to create
connected graphs out of our individual
data points so we see that we have
two unreferenced objects so we explode
that mode
by pressing x and we can we can draw
an edge between those two nodes by
clicking edit and add reference
and drawing a line between the two from
the
email to the person
when you do that miss will propose a
list of relationship
types between these two two different
nodes
there is also a custom one there so if
you don't want to select anything from
the list that is fine too but for now
we can just use the impersonates
relationship which already exists in the
default library
just click on submit
and now we have a relationship set
between those two so we started telling
our story by basically having a
connected graph between the
these two points now let's further look
at our
original email and see what else we can
get out of the text from there
we also see that the malicious file was
contained in the email as
well as an attachment so let's upload an
attachment now to ms
i hope you have put in the text there or
something because i forgot to clearly
i've
so as an attachment and this is where
things become a little bit tricky
uh there's there's a quick question
there on the chat i'll just quickly
answer that then we can get back to this
where can i create a reference if you go
above the attribute list there is an
event graph button if you click on that
you get the event graph
and on the top left side you click on
edit and then add reference
like i can show it again nowadays oh
yeah that's a bit better here
so have this kind of gray bar there with
even graph
so you can basically collapse or expand
it
uh and then there you can select one of
those
reference objects you press x to expand
all those
reference objects then you can just
select one object that you want
to add and then you can edit add the
references and then you can add specific
references
in case it doesn't make sense to make a
second reference but that's basically
how you do it
then you select your relationship type
and you can add your reference
uh it's not the only way to do it
there's a
i would say current-based representation
where you can do it because we can't
even show it
so you have to go it's it's much more
difficult to understand what happens
yeah so so there the referendum that you
created through the even graph
is represented here so you see that this
object
has a reference so from email to
impersonate
and here's the opposite relationship
that you can describe the reference buy
and you have the reference buy
on this object so another niche mention
is i think
less uh i would say 54 for
and so on but sometimes you just when
you are in the object you just want to
see if you have any reference or
a sign and you can quickly see that
so let's add an attachment now
and upload the sample that was uh
included in the
original uh email so we just click on
add attachment
we select the file that you want to
upload yeah so for the attachment uh in
this you have
really two models you have the model
that an attachment is basically
something completely
uh being safe and you can basically
share it
uh directly so for example you have
attachment like
reports and stuff in our case um
what we want to share here it's a
malicious number um
so and that's i will take i will take
which one
take a sample somewhere
um
press on one what we are interesting
there
uh by the windows executables
and then you have to select if the
sample is malicious if you don't do
anything
what it will be it will be something
like same uh report a pdf report
something that's
like supporting you in contextualization
could be a screenshot for example things
like that
but if you share a sample you have to
select
uh it's a sample because like that mist
will encrypt
and hash a file so that means you have a
zip file encrypted with a default
password
infected but i got to avoid classical
mistake of
clicking on a link executing binaries on
your analysis machines and so on and so
on you don't want to do that so
if it's malicious always click malware
samples
then you have one below which will
advance the extraction
uh mist can do a lot of things behind
the scene when you receive a file in
this case it's a window
of windows portable executable files so
we have particular advanced extraction
for those files and we can
expand completely the files including
resources
code segment and stuff again
so i will upload the files
okay in this case this one was just like
a very simple one
so in this case what do we have we have
an object
with the file names the size invite and
then the hash file so automatically miss
will do the hashing of the different
files
the sample itself is attached so you can
basically
use it and some additional ones like ssd
for example my type are automatically
extracted
just maybe for the sake of it i will
just take maybe another
binary just for showing you what could
happen
with other binaries maybe that's for
later for different events so
okay the objectives because it's easier
to see for the
photograph that's fine too you can show
it afterwards yeah
okay so now we have this again this kind
of object attached and there's a
relationship to create objections
indeed so so in this case the
relationship is to the email itself so
we know that the email contained
this file so what we can do is we can
just create relationship between the
email
and the file and see that email contain
that file
do you see it it's again the same model
so
contains
there we go so now what we can do is if
you look further in the email we see
that there is a bunch of other stuff
still described so what we can do is we
can just
now for exercise sake just take um
at least a next few lines or the next
paragraph
and drop the entire paragraph into
something called the free text importer
what this will do is it will try to
parse this uh
this text blob and it will try to
extract anything that looks like an
indicator out of that so this is another
method of
of basically entering attribute
synthesis so free text import
we just paste it in there and we just
hit submit
so this will tell us in this case it
didn't extract everything actually so we
need to still go back to it and refined
a bit more
but it extracted some of those things
that were in there already so that's
fine we can just already add those
to the event
so how does it work in in behind the
scenes uh we have a bunch of regex
images
automatically extracting information
from from natural text
it's one way to do it there's another
tool for doing it which is part of the
even report
um but it's usually it's a quick way to
automatically extract information and to
see if it's already known for example
so what we see here already is that evil
provider
was basically according to the email
text
and the place that was uh used to
download the secondary payload from
so we can take evil provider and we also
know that
we got an ipv6 address to it so we're
going to add that to it as well and
convert this into an object again
so we're going to to just select that
one convert to object and the object
that we're
going to convert it to is going to be a
url object
yep all the way down there perfect
let's just do the conversion and then we
edit the object afterwards and we add
the additional information that we have
about it
so we have an ipv6 that we can that it
resolves to
we also have a port so once we're done
with that
happy destination perfect
we can also add the port it was
communicating on port 443
and again everything i'm currently doing
there can be done through
api obviously yeah and and finally we
also have a domain evilprovider.com
now let's deal with with referencing the
this to the other objects later on we
can still
still add the additional information
that we have in there and then we do the
linking afterwards again we we have the
same problem here on this one because
you see that the command has a the part
it has a command so that means we can
just convert it as an object again
yeah and the ip belongs to that one as
well by the way okay great
it's even better yeah exactly just my
screen that is a bit
smaller okay
so in this case it's again a url
and the things that we have this time
the port is actually a high port so
while in the other one we do not
correlate on on the port because port
443 is common
this is one of those ports that we might
want to correlate on already
so we want we don't want to disable
correlation for this one
once for the other one we we should
disable the correlation for the other
part
okay now the other thing that we have at
this point is we have a secondary sample
so if you can you have a second one that
you can upload yeah i just just add the
domain so i get it
okay so what do you want
so we still have another file to update
and we have a cv
that was also mentioned in the okay cv
it's an interesting one um
we have we have single attributes for cd
but
sometimes you want to have some more
information so what you could do there
is
to create a simple attribute um so the
cv is much better delivery in this case
we have type which is vulnerability and
usually a venerability is defined by cv
you can you can use other value but
the best practice is the obviously to
use cd
it's very old cv those kind of attackers
are always reusing those kind of old
things but you know it works you know
never people never patch i
know this one is interesting because you
know it was exploited
so i would add the ideas flag because it
may be interesting to look into your
system for
additional ones so in this case what do
we have we have again
a single attribute which is not the nice
thing that you want to have is basically
you want to have as much context as you
want
for such kind of investigation luckily
on
this instance we have one of those
expansion modules
and why the cv advantage is okay
great so and then you have some
additional information in this case we
have some some description
um so what i can do in this in this one
is
so you see that we have either the
overlay uh thing so in these modules uh
someone was asking about extension of
this
is one way you have this overlay things
where you can basically just do
expansions
and see okay contextual information but
sometimes you just want to be
to have a bit more than just contextual
information uh you want to have
[Music]
the uh associated object then so there
you have this this kind of
kind of explosion there and you can add
the enrichment i'll give a try on that
one
okay great so there's something wrong on
this machine that's great
i'll take the other one but this this
it's not an object for that
that's fine we can just like yeah can
summon the attribute in this case
so we have basically the description
then coming from the enrichment
and what we can do is to uh
then make an object called vulnerability
then
id credit in this case is the
descriptions
and make an object of it usually you
should have a full
expansion there but i didn't test it on
the training instance maybe something is
broken on that instance okay so now what
do we have is
it's more contextual information we we
start with a story and there
we see that we have an emails we have a
first url a second one which is a
download and a specific cv so maybe no
we can go back to the uh
we still miss one thing which was a
secondary file that was
downloaded oh okay from the secondary
files yes
yeah so according to story what happens
was
uh the initial sample was uh
when executed was downloading a
secondary
sample and that one was basically then
used to
exfiltrate data from from the system yes
so
this was a new railway download the
interest files okay
then i will add a yeah just another file
and we just
pretend it's the one that we were
supposed to use why is this one it makes
sense it's an emote that's one
downloaded form in your eyes
that makes sense
so now we have all these different
objects in our event and it's time to
build the story out of it as alex has
mentioned so it's time to go back to our
event graph
and basically uh so far the story is
that we got
an email the email was impersonating a
person and we basically got
a primary sample out of the that primary
sample then reaches
out to evilprovider.com
to download a secondary sample so we
have a relationship
between the file
which downloads from
downloads from yeah perfect
from evil provider and then evil
provider downloads
the secondary sample
which is in this case index dot html one
and this one then exfiltrates to the
another evil provider url
now there's one thing we missed in the
story here is that the first one try so
in this case trilogy
was actually abusing the cve that uh
that alex has already expanded so we
have an abuser's
relationship from trilogothexa to
vulnerability
so and once we're done with this we
already see the entire store in this car
so even if you if you have no idea about
what happened in the report and you
don't read the original report
by just looking at this graph you can
clearly read it out
in in in simple sentences we see email
in person later first and john
email contains trilogy exploits
vulnerability
downloads from evoprovider.com
index.html1
which exfiltrates to a url so it's a
very simple story to comprehend without
us
knowing the original data information
and without us having even having to
look
at the individual indicators further
below
so this is when we're talking about
information sharing
we're basically sharing on two layers
one of the layers is sharing with
machines so informing an ids about
things to alert on
and at the same time we're sharing with
analysts that want to really understand
what the introductory was doing in this
case
and what happened during the incident
however at this stage
we have described our event but we're
still missing something at this point
we still haven't actually contextualized
the information with everything else
that we know about it
so we have we have vocabularies at our
disposal
we have at the attack matrix at our
disposal so let's
start going through the individual
attributes and let's start to attach
those different
labels to the data so first of all if we
look at
uh perhaps which one which one should we
start with
let's not do everything let's look at
the original email for example
we know that the original email deals
with fishing now
attack has a pattern that describes
fishing so we can just attach
the galaxy cluster of attack to
and to the attributes in there so
we use cluster yeah and we can just use
the text
magic perfect and we can click on attack
pattern
then we get the attack matrix and here
we can select
uh phishing it should be in
[Music]
you see yeah there it is perfect so we
attach it
we refresh and there we see it is now
attached to the
attribute and if we if we generate a
heat pack now out of the events if we
scroll up
we have an attack matrix view next to
the event graph
if we click on that one now we now see
that
as a first overview already we know
without looking
at any of the details we see that we're
dealing with positioning here so this is
one of the attack patterns that we've
described
let's see what other attack patterns
from attack we can describe you also see
that there is automated
exfiltration happening so if we go to
the secondary url
so another evilprovider.com
we can attach the pattern there as well
now we can choose to do
a single attribute what we're doing or
we can just select all four and attach
the cluster tool for let's just do one
for
now it's it's it's enough
uh watch out it's uh yeah perfect
and just pick automated exfiltration
it's the
first one on the yeah
okay so now we've attached some attack
patterns uh
we we could attach it to the sample as
well what the sample is doing but we're
not going to go through
all that effort let's look at some type
of contextualization
for example maybe this
then it's a matter of test again
regarding the at which level you want to
attach
the galaxy there is the topic is a
matter of fishing
at a global level usually we can add a
galaxy there and then for example
add my tray attack directly there
and select the pattern fishing then
the techniques there directly so you
have different options
usually we recommend to make it as
attribute level
but in some case you don't even know
which attribute level it applies
then you select the even level exactly
so so that's indeed a good point if you
know that the entire chain of what
you're describing
referring to the single uh
contextualization beta label be it a
galaxy cluster then indeed what we
assume is anything that you label on the
event level is inherited by all
uh data contained in unless explicitly
overwritten by
the opposite tag basically so
so indeed that's the case uh in this
case
we're kind of in a weird situation
because we're describing the full chain
of the attack which includes initial
phishing attempt but also includes the
secondary payload and the exfiltration
and so on
and if we if you do this on the
attribute level i suppose the event
level
then you're really really only
describing
which part deals with the fishing which
part deals with the actual exfiltration
and so on
so this is really up to you what we
generally recommend is
don't just do it on the event level so
if you're describing more concepts in a
single event
make sure that you contextualize
individual parts of it
because one of one of the things that we
use these labels for as well is searches
so if i were to search for all
indicators
that relate to phishing i might not want
to get the secondary
payloads effects uh included in that
response because that was just the
initial vector of getting into the
network of the victim
whatever happens afterwards is not
directly related to the phishing
so keep that in mind as well something
else
yeah so some just just something that
you have to keep in mind too it's about
which classification to choose or which
contractualization source you have to
want to
to use um on this instance we have
already
a lot of things enabled and if for
example you go for taxonomy
you have a lot of taxonomy that is
describing fishing
for for example you have even a complete
taxonomy
about the kind of fishing you have and
so on
so when you install your miss pinstance
and you start to make it operational
you really have to decide what kind of
taxonomy you want to use
in this case we have already a lot of
things are available by default
so the fishing taxonomy itself is a
complete one coming from a finger
towards academic paper where we have all
the techniques that are used so
for example you can say that this one is
coming from a
spearfishing which was described there
and you have the different techniques
so in this case it's email spoofing and
you can go deeper there
into the description of what is exactly
the decision
and you can mix match both i mean under
selectively attack
fishing techniques at specific indicator
level
maybe another analyst would want to
classify it
and and maybe the objectives might be
different maybe on one for example
it's more specific for tools but if you
want to run out statistics
at the end of i don't know quite early
meetings and say okay
how many spearfishing that you receive
or many emails proofing
for example if you can control better
emails proofing uh the spf record and so
on you can
just look at the current uh technique
that are used by by the attacker so you
see that
those kind of it's full of taxonomies
that are can be used
and obviously we usually recommend to
not enable everything but just
pick what you really want and some are
very generic
some are more advanced but that's maybe
something that you
we dig into more afterwards but
just be careful of which kind of
taxonomy you want to use because it will
be the language
that you use with the community and your
partners
for sharing this information
maybe something interesting to look into
the email and that's linked to
classifications but there's this comment
there please
please be mindful that this is an
ongoing investigation and we would like
to avoid
informing the attacker or the detection
and can we ask you to
to only use the content information
to to protect your constituents so
this is kind of that you are language
describing to you what kind of
classification it is
um and so no
which one should we use so um if we are
first members if we are using the first
community obviously the classification
that we will use
is not the nato one or the ministry of
defense in whatever
country it's really tlp so then again
based on that we will look into
different taxonomy that we have
we can look for for tlp
and i should not do that like that
i go for the tlp library and then i have
the
specific taxonomy tlp and then you have
the different one
in this case they say you have to share
it with your confusion only so
tlp amber seems to be the most
appropriate
one we say that the lpm bill information
is given to organization
sharing limited within organization to
basically act upon
if we have the extended classifications
from first
it includes the constituent
too so i will just use a tmp but i
mentioned something else that is
interesting
in the email they mentioned that this is
an ongoing
association to avoid
informing the attacker in this case
or would you inform the attacker but if
you do actions
on specific indicators and attributes
you might want to restrict that
so there is a another classification i
don't know if this one is enabled
it's called pap which is exactly that
it's similar to tlp but describing
what you can do with this information if
we don't want to
at least notify the attacker that we are
doing some
further investigations maybe we want to
restrict that
and the prp is really telling you what
are the permissive action that you can
do
in our case for example
non-detectable actions only and that's
really what he wants
because the supporters say okay we have
an ongoing investigation so you don't
want to be here
um other parties are informed so in this
case i will use
red and again this is used at even level
and that's something quite important
because myth will take care of that
um you don't need to set pp rate on
every single attribute
behind it's really at even level so it's
automatically
irritating on all attributes we don't
show it on the interface
because it will be two clamps to you
know overload it with information
but we do it in a way that's on the api
level if you do section of search for
example on even level or attribute level
pip red will be included there if you
have an attribute
containing some information
automatically tags like papers will be
then included into the information so
that's something to keep in mind when we
have information from third party
is to to wonder okay what is a
classification scheme so sometimes they
don't say
a specific classification to use that
you just use natural language or
just a normal sentence to describe all
the information should be shared
so the interesting thing here is that
what we've seen now is we've
contextualized information in many
different aspects and this is just
scraping the uh
the top layer basically we could go much
much further with contextualization
imagine for example describing
how this information is relevant to
whether it's used what sort of
mechanisms they should
have in place to be able to block this
information how can you make this useful
think of different maturity
organizations as well when you're
sharing information
you could also describe information
about who's behind it what the
motivations are
so we did not describe the threat actor
because we we haven't done any analysis
yet this is the initial information we
got from
a cser that just reported an incident to
us but we could go further and we
if we did our analysis we would find
who's behind this we could go for it
for uh for information with threat actor
we could look at target sectors
we could look at a lot of different
information in regards to
to further contextualizing the
information
so in this case we could also for
example say that's in the truth where
because we we know that this is
something that was targeting an
organization luxembourg
we know it was there is also a sector uh
taxonomy
that you can use so that's not a galaxy
but the taxonomy
so we can also add uh for example
information about the financial sector
we know the ceo
is a ceo financial sector organization
so we could also say that it's
it probably has to do with that as well
maybe it's not enabled
sorry about that yeah this is
exactly there if you just search for
sector it should be there
yeah but i'm i'm yeah there's something
that you can do
talk about about later but it's uh
just a sector so we have different one
you did find that so if you there was
one for finance you can just pick that
yeah
something else you can you can do and
this one is important too it's it's
going a bit further than the email so
for example as a source we receive
emails from various people
i mean if i receive an email from i
don't know from an analyst from i don't
know
he set mcafee and found that i'm working
with them for years
my confidence on this information is
quite high
on the other hand if i receive an email
from someone unknown
maybe my confidence will be a bit
different so
in myths you have plenty of taxonomies
to express confidence
for example the one that is actively
used for empowering the military
network is scale or nato scale
where you can basically define the
credibility of the
of the source in this case we can say
that we are we know the source and is
usually really
reliable so that's the source itself and
we can say for this specific information
that is
um probably true
because they send us some evidence now
if i have like three emails taking about
this
talking about the same case maybe my
level of credibility will increase
because we have multiple people that
have seen exactly the same kind of thing
so in this case i will have those kind
of information there again it's it's a
way to
really contextualize information and the
quality of the information
and you have for example
additional one like for example we have
one called estimative language
so this one is more coming from dna and
the cias
it's like the likelihood of probability
that this happen
so we can say that this one has been
almost certain and then we can even
qualify
or own an analytic judgment on this
and i can say that it was like quickly
done and it's
not perfect i will just say low for
example
so then you can have this kind of
information and you can
either use it as an even level again or
a specific review so for example if one
of the emails it was like
not properly collected or it was skirts
or someone modified leather and so on
maybe you can reduce
the summative language of the confidence
level that you have
in the analytic judgment of the specific
evidence or element
by tagging that at attribute level so
again
those kind of information that we are
putting there are factors and so on are
more like
even level but if you have really
specific things that need to be changed
or that are specific to the attribute or
object then you can
change it in the at the absolute level
just some other thing on the user
interface that might be useful too that
we skipped
on the metadata of the event you have
plenty of information there
why that is interesting regarding
organization only and distribution
in this case we just distribute to the
organization but
if you have pretty large even at some
point in time and you want to distribute
you have this kind of overview there
which is helping you to
see at which level you share this
information in this case it's super easy
we just distribute it to the training
organization that's fine
but if you have a pretty large instance
with a lot of organization and so on
it will display you a full graph of
where the information will flow
and will be distributed
okay now going back to our event uh
basically
the reason why we went so deeply into
the contextualization part is looking at
this event
we can already uh use this right away
when feeding our tools when doing our
searches
to basically search for anything
targeting the financial sector for
example
we can search for anything related to
phishing
and find the data contained in this
particular event so this already helps
us with our filtering mechanisms
as for pap and tlp those
tags we can use when we make decisions
on which tools we feed
the data to or which partners we share
the information within the case of tlp
so
we're going to see that more tomorrow
when we're creating synchronization
links with other instances
we can for example set restrictions on
tlp
when we're pushing data to another node
and we can say okay
no matter what distribution setting
don't send anything tlp amber in this
direction for example
yeah as an example as an example there's
a very good open source tool um called
the hive
for serending and they use pap to
know which kind of actions they can do
on the data so if you synchronize them
with the hive instance you can
really be sure that what you set
as pep for example red on the lisp
instance
will not generate issues when you are
starting to expansion within
cortex on the ice to be sure that the
information is not basically flowing
somewhere else so at this point
something that we didn't do so far is we
did not include the
on the initial email so what we're going
to do now is we're going to use another
functionality of this that we haven't
talked much about called the report
the event report we can also include
clear text
information such as a report description
and so on together with the event
so what we're going to do now is
something very simple we're not going to
write our own report we have a report
already available from the original
source
so we're just going to paste that entire
email
okay just submit for now
[Music]
so now if you look at our email
report we just have a simple report
during gear text we're going to see an
example what you can do with this so
this is all in markdown
so you could go into edit mode and
pretty it up add additional information
there
we're not going to do that now because
we're going to just look at an example
that already has that
but before we do that let's get back to
our event and let's assume that we're
done with it with this entire process we
have our
report we have our event we have
contextualized all
our data and let's publish it now to the
community
so when it comes to publishing we have
different uh
uh ways of achieving that ms by default
when we create an event like this at
this stage we have all the data
contained that we want to share out and
that we want to use
however misconsiders this to be
non-final
it is not to be used by automation tools
connected to this
it is not going to be synchronized out
to other instances
and uh and so on
what we can do now is first of all
we need to decide how we shared it out
it is the organization only for now
so even if we were to publish it it
would still only be pushed to our own
tools that connect to our miss but it
would not be made visible to other
organizations but we want to change this
in this case
however let's assume that uh that when
we're an organization
that does not wish to reveal who we uh
that we were involved in
in this entire incident we just want to
entrust the third party with doing it
so as you see there where alex is
hovering we basically have several
options here
we can either publish the event which
means we initiate the entire exchange
with other instances if the
distribution allows it it will it will
alert everyone that we have published
this
or alternatively we can we can delegate
the publishing to third party and stay
anonymous ourselves so let's do that
option for now
so what we're doing now is we're
entrusting a third party to take over
this event for us so let's say that we
would entrust for example circle to take
over this event
and we tell circle that we want to share
this event to be shared with
uh the entire community so we've
collected
yeah you can see this community only for
example or a sharing group whatever you
prefer
okay so this is again a suggestion to
the other organization saying okay we
want you to share this out and we want
you to share this
to this community once we click yes
even though the event was your
organizational and only visible to us
it now becomes visible to two
organizations ourselves
and the other organization that we
entrust in this case circle so circle
would get an email
saying okay there's this delegation
request someone wants you to take over
their event
are you willing to take it over and
publish it under your name this will
look something like this with slightly
different text we're cheating here now
since we're doing a training we're site
administrators and we see both sides of
the story
so we can either accept or discard this
request keep in mind
if you accept such a request the event
becomes your event
a copy of it is created under your name
and basically you are taking
responsibility for the event from down
so also make sure that you're not
pushing junk under your name so in this
case let's just discard it
but we could have accepted it and then
it would have become our event
okay let's go back to the event
okay so now the other alternative is if
you want to publish it under our name
what you would need to do is you would
need to raise the distribution level
first
if you wanted to uh to involve any other
parties
so we need to edit the event in that
case and raise the distribution level to
say this community or connected
communities let's go with connected
communities
connected communities means anyone that
has access to my miss pinsons
and all the directly interconnected
instances including all their members as
well
so in the case for example
of us publishing something like this in
the first instance we as circle have our
instance connected to it
so all the members of the circle
instance will automatically also be
included in the exchange here we see a
graph of that so we see the event would
be also visible to all the directly
connected instances
which we only have one of which is a
loopback
connection to exchange so not that
interesting
and to everyone that has access to this
current instance
okay once we're done we can click
publish
and then the event gets synchronized
so what happens at this stage is first
of all the event will jump
over to directly connected instances
miss will send out a bunch of emails to
everyone that subscribes to
publish alerts that there is a new event
with all the data contained within
it will push the event down various
local channels to other tools
using xeromq kafka and so on and syslog
so if you have any tools that are
subscribed to these
published feeds and they will ingest the
data
and it will also make it available to
the api and to make it available to all
the integration
tools out there so if you have your
your scene connected to miss it will now
be able to fetch the data
contained in this event so this is
basically
the publishing process however there is
uh
if at this point we noticed that okay
we've now shared this event out
but we've actually made a typo in the
title we we wanted to include
uh um i don't know
a trailing period at the end of the
sentence
in the title and we edit the event what
happens now is there is a modification
to the event so even though it was
published it becomes unpublished again
and it needs to be to be republished now
the reason why we do this is
uh whenever there is a change we need to
synchronize it out to
and if you have a publishing process in
place where
so only certain users have access to
publishing rights for example
then anytime your organization is
pushing out information
it can go through the irregular vetting
process so any change will unset the
publishing of the event
now in this case this is a very small
change that we've made so we don't want
to actually send out events to all their
users we don't want to spam them with
data that is pretty relevant for them so
we can publish
do the publishing again but this time
using the publish no email option
so it will also synchronize the data it
will again make it available to all
different
means of ingesting the data but it will
not spam our users with emails
okay so that's basically it for the
publishing
and perhaps one thing that is
interesting and that we didn't talk much
about is
we have now raised the distribution
level of this event to connected
communities
so the event is synchronized out but we
actually had an attribute if you look
further down
that's had a different distribution
level uh so that one is actually going
to be removed from the synchronized
button
uh so we had one that the the
impersonated person's email address
that was set to organization only so
whenever we're talking about
synchronization
that thing will in this case not
synchronize out so that will be redacted
from the event
okay something else that we can do at
this point once we have created our
event is we can also extract it in
different formats so if you click on
download s on the left side
you will see that we can basically
convert this automatically to a bunch of
different formats and extract it in
those formats directly
this is also what we would be accessing
by the api if you were to search for
this event we can also mark whatever
response format we want just very
briefly we won't go very deeply into
this these formats
are coming partially from our predefined
hard-coded list of formats that we
support in miss
but some of these formats also come from
the different exp
export modules that we have so if you
want you can either build your own
native modules for exporting and
converting data
or you can build modules
that are sitting in another tool called
miss modules
side by side with mist that will ingest
the data and then convert it to other
formats
so here's a pdf report that was created
directly out of the event
uh and that you can just
share out directly from the event
something else that you can do
is uh anything that we do in misp so all
the process of adding attributes
all the process of viewing data you can
also do uh
so do that in a machine partial way by
just spending.json at the end of any of
the url
so in that case in this event we're
going to get the json representation of
the
event okay
so that's basically for creating an
event
just maybe one thing that is interesting
we have a very good question from
martin it's a
quite complex one but maybe we can
already partially answer it
so when you create an event and in this
case a creator or
is the training people can contribute on
that one
but if you have an isaac and you want to
distribute back the information and so
on
one of the options that you have is to
try to create extended events for
example out of it
so you can um out of an event you can
create a new one
um which would be for example with
additional information
like validations uh additional things
that you want you
you want to add so you have this kind of
extend even and you will create
automatically a
new event based on that
um thing that is interesting there um
the
the thing is you can really create
something completely new
out of it and then see so for example
for this case i can say that we
uh we did a kind of session with
additional information
um there the distribution is your
organization only
and i would add for example a specific
attribute
which is for example targeting data
and i can say target user uh the son
of the prime minister
so it may be information that you really
don't want to share
with others so this one is basically
a normal event with additional
information there
and it's only shared within your
organization
nevertheless if you go to the original
event
you have this kind of extended view
there and we can have
what we call an extended view and not an
atomic view and the two information
so the is combined and you can see there
that we have one with the information
about the son of the prime minister
which is the extended event there so
just to answer the question of martin
about
the question about
adding information on existing event is
one way of doing it
so using extended event is a way to
qualify or extend even with additional
information and so on
um it's actively used for example for
when you have
two different view of the information
because one is distributed and another
one is like
likely like the private information like
the forensic evidence
that you cannot share for example you
can create this kind of thing
it's one way of doing it it's not
answering companies the question of
martin but we can
even go deeper later on that but it's
it's one way of
because tomorrow we talk about
synchronization there are some specific
options for isaac like
and publishing events if we do
synchronization and so on
that can be used in some some cases for
isaac's
there are many options but that's one
way of of partially solving
this kind of issues of not owning the
data
is to extend the information
so i know you have something you want to
add on rashford
no no that makes sense
again for the collaboration on this one
we can do various things so
in the case of um you have a typo for
example in the specifications and so on
you can make proposal another thing with
uh
on the interface here you see that you
can
basically make either an edit or you see
that you can make
a proposed edit so what is the use case
of that
it's it's not like for fundamental
changes but for i would say minor
challenges on a specific import
imagine that you don't agree on this one
on this idea of season
there's a typo and it's not d5 but e5
in the ipv6 rs so you propose the change
in this case i'm playing both holes here
but
what do i have here it's basically an
attribute
with a proposal of the church and i'm
playing the boss roles for the
contributor roles and
the original creator then i can say okay
i accept the change indeed this this
proposal makes sense
or are basically discounted and this is
a way to get updates from
um from supportive other members other
organizations and so on
it's one way to to update the
information in this case i will
discuss it because it's not correct
we were talking about contributions this
another way of contributing is the site
things itself
so for example for this specifications
if for example we have an expression
detection system and we have seen it
like
three times in a row we can add
on on the interface with the api
through the user interface and so on
that you have seen that um
multiple times and like that you can
share this kind of details about
the sharing aspect
so we what we have seen that at this
specific amount of times we have
the three counts saying this uh this is
a site
and you have seen it and you can do it
per organization
or it could be even anonymously you get
different configuration in the model of
cycling in mist
but it's a way to see that an indicator
has been seen
or not if one specific are generating
for example a
false positive you can see the negative
one negative sightings which
basically tell others that okay this one
is generating a lot of false positives
sometimes not every organization agrees
on the first positive because they have
different views
coming from different networks and so on
that's a way to
provide feedback so one is delegations
proposals or another way is to
basically get affected
okay
i'm just trying to go through the
questions yeah
maybe yes maybe there are some yeah
there are some that are repeating so
perhaps it's good to call them out
uh so there was a bit of confusion about
how to add the
uh the email object so it uh checked it
is a little bit
uh confusing so when you're in an event
and you click on add objects first you
need to select the scope
from which you choose from so it's going
to be climate file and so on just click
on all objects if you're unsure
and then you can search for whatever so
after you click on all objects and you
type email
it's going to show your email object
here the first step is more like finding
out the category of an object
yeah so so some sometimes you just know
the category but you don't know what is
really available there for you
so you you want to see okay what sort of
objects can i use in network contacts
and i would click on network first
and then you get a list of of all
tangently related
objects that will have to do with
network connectivity but
not necessarily describing the same
concept at all
uh but if you don't know or
which the domain you want to pick it
from or if you know
exactly already what you want and you
just want to search by name just click
on all objects first
and then you will find what you're
looking for by just typing it so email
is easy to find that way
okay so just type email and that's it
okay um other questions
that were there okay perfect
and there there were a few other
questions that i answered in the
meanwhile maybe it's
a good idea to read soft about yeah
indeed there was a good one
about correlation graph and and
filtering on it
indeed we don't have a way to filter the
correlation graph but it's something
that we that we've discussed for a while
already and we want to do it at one
point
so that you can add some filter rules in
there yes
the only way to to do it here at least
through the api so that means you you
done the
decorating one and then you have to do a
filtering
priority but it needs something that's
uh
yeah it will be to be added i don't know
if you have an issue on that one
um yeah i think we do yes yes
so maybe you know what sometimes what we
do is
just just to add the one on this one um
if i'm finding his back
so i guess you can see what kind of
issue that we have and so on
a lot of the issue that we have is more
like i mean
around 25 percent 30 percent our basic
installation problem
um that's something that you can discuss
maybe tomorrow about
about recommendation on on on the
systems
we don't need a lot of requirements but
at least um
you need to have a lamp system working
for mariadb
linux systems and ready running
so obviously for example an ubuntu
distribution out of the box is working
without any problems
now if you try to install a missponder
mac os
you might turn into troubles obviously
but
what we recommend is we have install
automatic install script for
for ubuntu for example and this one
works works quite well
i wanted to search the issue for
you just search your correlation for
correlation yeah
creation filtering now that will be a
bit
too specific i think no really not
maybe yes we're filtering by correlation
on feedback
yeah that's easy
oh this one maybe yes yeah yeah okay
this one okay so
so that's how we work so if you see a
component issue that
or a feature that is really interesting
for you don't hesitate to take an
existing issue
about specific requests and add some
comments there
like for example it's really the issue
the feature that you want
uh is it important for you why and so on
and then we use that as a source of
of doing a pd request as an example we
do
a release of miss every three weeks
usually
and there are many new features on each
release
as an example we had a request like that
sami just fixed uh
two days ago about the events oh we
didn't even show it
even timeline and then
we wanted to have something that is easy
to set the number of days and then he
has
the new feature so sometimes it makes a
lot of sense so don't hesitate to create
a
an issue and and propose a new new
feature
which remind me of showing you the even
timeline because we didn't really show
it
so you see that on on this one
we we have nearly everything
same time which is basically the time
when we
create a different object we just set
the time for four for one
so and then i can
basically look at this one and this one
is like the
yeah i don't know why we don't have the
expansion on that one
so for you for example if you have a
specific time we can
expand it and even change it in the
graph so that means if we have for
example this email
a thing with that we can we can expand
it
and change when when this has been seen
and we can even uh
change at which time this specific
specifically
but that's again a good point to do
is to automatically create
a first thing last scene on your element
because every time you do that you will
get an automatic timeline
and actually a quick i would say quick
win when you do analysis
[Music]
so if there are no more questions about
event creation perhaps one of the things
we can do is show the searching
how to search for stuff in your risk
okay so this is something that we're
going to show very briefly now and we're
going to go a bit more detail into this
tomorrow
when we're also going to look at the api
but generally whenever you're searching
in miss
the main question you need to ask
yourself is
what scope am i searching on am i
searching for individual attributes
or am i searching for events the search
filters very often overlapping
or aren't necessarily almost the same
but one of the things you need to keep
in mind is for example if i'm searching
for
bitcoin addresses in my miss vincent's
bitcoin wallets
am i searching for any event that
contains at least one
bitcoin address or am i searching for
just the bitcoin addresses themselves
so this is when we decide between
different scopes so
generally attribute scope will only give
you the individual attributes that match
the criteria
and the event scope will give you
everything that contains
at least one matching value so here what
what alex did he just searched
using the attribute search for all the
bitcoin addresses
in the air in the instance and we see we
get a bunch of them from different
sources we see which events there
they're from which organization has
created that information and so on and
so forth
uh if we're happy with the search
results and we've set up all our
features and we're getting exactly what
we were looking for
maybe even several pages of it like here
we can download the results in any of
these supported formats so we could say
okay now we have all these bitcoin
addresses out there generate the csv out
of it
and it will generate a massive csv
with all the attribute information for
each of these
i hope you're not running my timings
inside of memory
there it is
[Music]
so if you open it just to see the
results quickly
there we go so in this case uh
we now downloaded our search results as
csv
now keep in mind whenever you're dealing
with integration of mis with other tools
or
exports keep in mind that certain
formats don't really cater to exporting
certain types of data so
if you're searching for ransomware
payout
wallets you could for example specify as
a tag
all the different ransomware related
tags that you have
and uh as a type select btc like what
alex has done here and exported
information now when you're deciding
what format to download in
again some don't make any sense so don't
download bitcoin addresses in sticks
format because sticks doesn't have a
way to express bitcoin addresses for
example
so just make sure that you also take
that into consideration and exporting
data so that it's not wasting
uh besides that we can do the same on
the event level we can also do searches
on the event level
if we go back to our event index we have
a little magnifying glass icon where you
can
add additional filter options to the
index
and filter the database on that so let's
just do
simple we're going to just filter on
events coming from circle
and we can also add for example events
that are not published
if you wanted to do some final checks on
whether
uh we need to add the organization again
whether we have any events that need to
be vetted for example for our own
organization then we could use this
filter for it
on the event index all of these search
filters that you apply
generate a specific url and you can
bookmark it
so if you have recurring queries that
you want to monitor
then you can just bookmark the url and
you can go back to it
later on and see if there is anything
that popped up that matches your
search criteria now generally
like i think 90 of our searches do not
actually happen via the ui
they happen via the api so very often
you have tools that you search through
so if you have a
tool that acts as a front-end for your
miss for certain searches that works as
well
we're going to talk more about those
type of searches and how you integrate
with other tools tomorrow more
when we go into the api a bit is a
question about soft delete attribute
search
i just lost the q and a so some martin
asks is there a way to do a global
search for software
attributes yes sorry where is it
there for software attachments yes there
is
uh so not via the ui but via the api uh
which you can also access
by the way we have two we have a
built-in tool we can even show it show
this example there
we didn't show the delete i
and let's start with the question first
and then we go to the delete
so we have this built-in tool called the
rest client that allows us to run
searches directly from the interface so
generally indeed we have a software
delete mechanism in bisp
that allows you to to not fully remove
an attribute but
mark is for it for deletion the reason
why we do this in general is
whenever we're synchronizing information
and we delete an attribute
we want to inform all the leather
instances attribute needs to be removed
it is revoked
so this is why we do the soft delete
when we hide it from the interface
behind it from the exports
but we still keep the data and we inform
the other instances that they need to
also market for deletion
now if the question is how do we do a
global search for all the soft deleted
attributes so first of all what we need
to do
yeah using our little research too
is by the way we have the modern apis
here to create a new api unless you know
yours by heart
so alex because you it's very good
so so just quickly that's so uh so in
the meanwhile what
alex is doing now is uh he's going to
generate a new api key for himself
so that we can actually test the api uh
queries
oh that's one word yeah
yeah you can add enough key from here as
well this will work yeah that works
[Music]
a global action my profile by the way if
you want to find your profile okay
so now we have our api key now we go to
rest client we just paste it in there
now
in the authorization field
here we go and now what we're going to
do is we're going to uh to run a search
for all software attributes so we're
going to
search for attribute rest search so that
is a scope that allows us to search on
the attribute level we'll do we'll see
more of this tomorrow
just a small example for return format
let's pick something like json
and perhaps set a page under limit or
date one limit 100 or something like
that
i don't know how much was deleted here
but it might be a lot and uh
then just uh add another key deleted
there we go
and then deleted september
and we don't need anything else
and this will return the first 100 hits
from the instance
of attributes that are deleted
there we go and now if you if you wanted
to paginate through all these attributes
you would have to just raise the page
number
go back and and get page 2 page 3 page 4
and so on
or if we have enough memory certainly my
training instance definitely doesn't
then we could just say give us
everything in one shot
okay so i hope that answers your
question martin
um there is also a question is there an
official miss docker image
um and there are actually several uh
they're not maintained by us but by
contributors
that are very active and working closely
with us
so i've pasted one example in the zoom
group chat
i don't know if maybe it's not visible
to everyone
i can just drop it as an answer here
yeah it's better
so this one is done by cool acid so why
there are so many docker myths
that's i think the the
speciality of docker not everyone agrees
on a model with docker so there are
at least as far as i know four or five
different dockers there's one managed by
dcso one by cool assist
one by xavier mcpens and one by
harvard security and i'm sure i'm
missing some
um so the thing is um for
for the docker images it's depending of
i would say your test
so have a look at what the different
contributors are doing
and you'll see that you pick the one
that is
matching what you really want to do with
docker
some are really more separated container
wise
some are more like one single container
with everything um
again it's a maker of taste and all you
want to to operate one
we don't maintain one as this project
but there are
some that are under our missed project
guitar position
someone is asking about api key to
invoke cortex analyzer
for the cortex analyzer it's a separate
tool set
of part of of the i've project
and then you have specific api keys
cortex extension is like this module so
it works for the expansion services
uh beaker full cortex analyzer are not
supporting
objects and stuff like that which is the
case for its modules
so you might have expansion on the
interface but if you want full-blown
expansion with relationship and so on
then you can use these modules a lot of
organizations are mixing both so you can
have cortex-enabled and
it's modulus enabled on the same missed
instance
but going back to the question if you
already have the cortex api encoded in
your misspen you want to invoke
a lookup uh through the api through misp
then you can use your misspik to tell
your misp to
run a query against cortex
but with the new api key models usually
it's better to have dedicated api
okay um there is something else easy
you know that we had it already um
[Music]
could you touch on how we could use one
event to add multiple attributes and how
would correlation work here uh configure
event one to fetch all records from a
fishing feed
would this work with correlation show
all instances where any of those
attributes match with other events from
other organization
events well okay if i understand it
correctly indeed
so if you if you do that you create an
event for a fishing feed
and you have those attributes in there
and you have cross you have cached
other instances then within that that
feeds event you will see correlations
both to
other events created locally on your
instance by other organizations
as well as links to other instances that
have the
data as long as you have cached those
events
so we're going to talk more about that
tomorrow about the synchronization but
when you're
interconnecting with another instance
you can do it in two ways
one i want to start exchanging data
pushing data pooling data
or two i can just tell my mist to go
crawl that other instance
uh hash all the values that they have
and if i ever get the correlation
then it flags it for me that it shows me
and then that the
instance already knows about this value
and i can pivot over to previewing the
data
so i hope that answers that yeah and
then the correlation of
for example if you just enable the
caching you just see that it's
correlating with specific values without
providing the full fit sometimes it's
it's quite
handy when you have for example see that
you cannot show the data but you can
show the correlation
there's another one do you recommend
using miss palone or using the hive
miss cortex integration i mean generally
yeah
if you need a case management tool then
then using the hive for that is great
and so it makes absolute sense to you to
use them together
and integration is really smoothly done
so that means that
that no matter where you start your your
process whether you start
by creating an event in misp or whether
you start by creating a
case in the hive you can basically
propagate the data to the other tool and
work on
on both tools and data so so yeah
absolutely
yeah absolutely it's pretty smooth just
just be careful if you use the expansion
on mist and you have miss modules
enabled i would prefer to have
modules enabled because you you
basically have all the features of mixed
like relationship objects and so on
with the cortex integration is basically
just the over with
the vortex yeah but one of the things
that you can do is
if you start for example from the hive
perspective and you push the data
afterwards to misp
you can then go through this process
like what we've done here with enriching
the information
creating objects that affect attributes
so you can do it as a secondary step
before you share it out to community to
refine the data
in mis that you've created in the i for
example and the same thing if you've
used cortex to fetch additional
information in the hive
you can then take that data and further
enrich it with miss modules once it's a
message
yeah this is a good question from
muammar
junaid about when i try to import the
data from six to five it's called
lazy like can you please explain that a
bit and this one is interesting
because it's it's i was saying a long
long long discussion and that
that's even influence or miss people
than the standard behind missed
so sticks is really uh focusing on cyber
security and
cyber studies religion and
the the problem is you might have at
some point in time
data that are basically not defined
anywhere
so it's more for the export of data so
for example if you export in a mixed
event and you have for example an object
with
the person and stuff like that it won't
be in the sticks to export for example
so it means that in misprevent you get
all the information but it's bound to
the limitation of the standards and the
format
where you export and it's exactly the
same for any format i mean if you
um export a person in theory cata format
obviously you don't have any
um field or things like that with person
and so on so
that's why we call it losing because uh
sometimes when you import data
it's bound to a specific set of
fields that are supported and so on
another thing that is
quite important with sticks you might
have a lot of
peculiarities or specialities depending
on the vendor
some vendors are adding some some
specific custom objects
things like that that are not bound to
any existing one
so we are importing them as kind of you
know generic one but
it is basically like uh lucy again so
you have to be careful when you you use
a specific format
to be sure that you properly uh map an
existing
different one so it's more for the
export is quite flexible on that so you
can basically have any object you like
but when we explore for example in 61 we
just
support what is existing in sticks even
if we start we add
some some custom objects too which are
on to the missed object
but some tools will not recognize
obviously the custom object because they
are
just having a profile for a specific set
of known uh updates
yeah i think that's exactly the point uh
that
maybe is different from when we
described the text in those import and
export fields
we say lossy but in reality what we do
is we do try to capture everything and
we do try to map
everything but a lot of it will end up
in custom objects now
now what alex mentioned is the problem
even if we export bitcoin
addresses for example whenever we're
pushing in sticks to format
as custom objects no other two will pick
up on it because
it's if we're just using custom objects
that unless the other two
specifically looks for them they will
just either store it as is
or not know what to do with it yeah and
that
that's why we recommend a feed provider
of
anderson son to actively support the
misformat
then they can they can really impose a
full set of objects and so that already
exists
yeah in some cases however you don't
really care about having the full set
and that's where for example specialized
formats are really cool
so whenever we're feeding for example an
ids for example we don't care about
bitcoin addresses
so in those cases uh so sticks and misp
both
are very expressive uh exchange formats
but whenever you're dealing with feeding
tools for example you don't care about
uh about losing ninety percent even of
the data set
as long as you capture those type of
data points that your tool can
process in the end so this is why
generally what we recommend is if you
have the option for example to export
data from
is for your ideas for your scene and so
on and you have the option between for
example sticks or snort or surikata
go with snorter sturikata because
because those are much more
uh catering to what your two can
actually understand
yeah for example for yards the same you
prefer to have like a good yara who will
say that you can run into another
barista or your endpoint protection
device
and having a generic one that will not
help you to lose the detection
other questions
you already took that one that is there
it is
longer i think we took most of them
unless they missed one
and yeah perhaps we should show the
deletions because we we didn't actually
show it indeed
yeah exactly
okay oh and now we have some more
questions
but we can take those after yeah let's
quickly show the deletions so if we go
to an event
yeah i'll take i'll take a hundred
members so this is a massive
gotcha basic basically missed
uh which we have some protective
measures in place to avoid this but one
of the things that you really need to
watch out for is
when you when you add data to misspen
you notice
oh crap i should not have added a piece
of information that is
either confidential information
information about the victim that i
should share and so on
the attribute that attribute might still
be contained in the event in a
in a soft deleted format you can always
toggle and see the deleted attributes
uh within an event
so i will create i will create an even
from scratch
okay so before i move forward on that so
we have two protective measures in place
to avoid accidental information leakage
violation one is basically that
that by default we do not use the
software method for anything that was
unpublished uh
at first so we're going to show it as an
example so here's some sensitive
information
if alex were to delete this now this
attribute this would get our deleted
so this will not create a soft deletion
uh miss pareto
tells us are you sure you want to hard
delete the attribute so when you read
the text you will see the see the
difference there in the wording
uh the reason for that is the event it
has not been published yet we know that
it has not probably been propagated to
other instances
there is absolutely no reason to inform
anyone that this has been deleted
so we can immediately just hard delete
it so when we do that
it will get hard deleted however if the
event has already been published
this has already been shared out to
other instances potentially
so in this case if we were to delete it
miss will tell us oh
are you sure you want to soft delete
this attribute because this is already a
published event
now it looks like our event is empty but
if you look at the deleted flag you will
see that the sensitive attribute is
still there
and if i were to publish the event now
this sensitive attribute would
it would get propagated along with the
event if you want to avoid this
altogether there is a way to mangle any
attribute that gets self-deleted
what happens in that case is a category
will be set to other
type will be set to other and value will
be set to redacted
this is a server-wide setting so your
administrator or if you are the
administrator and yourself can set this
setting in the server settings
the downside of that is if you are
mangling attributes that you're soft
deleting it will still inform the other
instances they will still
remove the data software the data
because the uid is reserved
however you cannot recover the attribute
anymore so if
so in this case right now we deleted
attribute alex could now click on the
recover button
and the attribute will be recovered as a
normal attribute so if you made a
mistake you can recover it
so there are two different mindsets i
want to make my data recoverable
versus and i want to always inform
others versus i want to always
hard delete data that i delete both of
them have a setting
so just pick and choose which whichever
makes sense for your community
whether you prefer secrecy or prefer
convenience
uh basically so it's basically
yeah that's delete for that review so if
we delete an
event that's another story yeah and this
this one is interesting because now we
have these options where we say
i want to delete this event and
obviously it will be deleted on your
instance
nevertheless this even has been already
synchronized
copy and develop different misc
instances
so that means as the next
synchronizations the event should be
pulled
but to avoid such kind of of issue mist
is automatically generating
a block list of all those elite events
so if you are the administrator you can
see at the block list of events
you can see the the one that i just
deleted
so why we do that it's very simple
we don't want to re-import the event
that has been deleted because luckily we
don't want this event
so it's a it's a block list of all the
cgas
but this this catch there uh sometimes
we have people oh i'm doing some tests
and so on i'm synchronizing with miss
but i can't see my even back
and obviously yes because it's there in
this block list
so if you have some tests and you're
running some tests don't forget to look
at the block list
and maybe you want to just remove
the event for the block keys and then
you can synchronize back the event
there's something to keep in mind it's
there it's done automatically but in
some cases you want to manage the
blockly
so that's something to keep in mind
yep something else
that we perhaps should uh touch on here
is is
for the event deletions besides just a
blockless part
there is one thing that comes up as a
question very often is how do i inform
others that an event needs to be removed
we don't have a mechanism in place for
that so while we can revoke attributes
for events uh we don't have that and
there's a reason for that
in general uh whenever it comes to
events uh
we don't want to give the power to just
outright delete
events uh remotely this way so this
might change in the future
we we're having discussions on that
whether we want to enable that or not
but currently that's not the case yeah
and usually we take as an example
emails i mean you can remove emails from
your personal mailbox but from the
remote mailbox if someone already
receives the emails
you want to have the control over third
parties on the mailbox that
might be one of the drawback i would say
so there are two two new questions one
of them is basically can you demonstrate
the progressive enrichments of events
by the shared communities over time with
correlations
this one is tough i mean i'm not sure
how we could demonstrate that because
we're not dealing with
live instances with live data sets and
act
active sharing
but perhaps for tomorrow we will prepare
an example where we can show it off
when and choose an event that we can
show on one of the operational instances
but i i can't show one on uh you know
what i can't go on
just one thing i'm i'm going on an
instance
okay so so it was
oh we are flexible so it's not super fun
to do it no but
um so it's maybe some some something
interesting there
um so um i'm connecting an instance
where i have
more expansion services uh active and so
on
i'll just keep it for my organization
only so i'm creating
an event there so what happens on
progressively enriching even by shared
communities i mean
it's going back and forth to different
communities but i can i can imitate what
the community is doing usually
so if i'm facing an attribute
for example i will i will say it
hostname with some network activity
so we have specifically a test that we
created with this
kind of thing so what would be your
community and
sharing so it could be for example in
the same organization in my case it's
just clear to the organization so
if i publish event here it will be
shared with
all different instances maybe the
different members of circle
uh and um one of my colleagues
is taking one of the indicators
and then he's going on the far side
database
doing a full-blown expansion so that
means he's basically doing a full-bone
extension
um what do i have here i have a
a complete set of objects for a specific
domain so you see again
i'm going to the event graph
now i enter my domain name and i have
all the
passive dns free curve associated to
that one
and in this one i think i will have the
even timeline i have a completely
different timeline of the different uh
expansion and so on so then i will have
one of my i will it will be published
again
with the uh with the data
[Music]
if it's a collaboration i would say in
the same team
that's a thing so it's sometimes it's
it's
people are working on the same event and
publishing it sometimes they are
sharing it and doing additional
expansion on the uh
on the um things until to reach a
specific point that is like i would say
accessible or at least publishable in a
publishing state that is
acceptable by various people
now we can make proposal too so that
means
if we are again on a different with a
different organization
i don't know if in this example it will
work but i can
take do i have something interesting
there
yeah for example i see an interesting
ipl
this one so what i could do is
i could
add
what's going on here
i will add what
okay just a demo effect
it's a great typical
what's going on here okay
just going back to this one i just want
to add a proposal
yes i cannot just
you wanted but your admin yeah
yeah then i don't you can cheat whether
you
really want you can do it yeah wait fine
it's just like okay so
i i don't know for for hong kong if we
answer your question but i mean
a full-blown step would be like that if
you work on an event it's not a single
person obviously
when you do an investigation you do like
multiple steps but the question is more
like
if you do it within a team usually you
edit the current even the same
organizations
if you do enter team you do proposal
extend it even like we showed before and
then you start to work on this uh
thing so it's here depending on the case
so uh
so i hope you can you can you can see
what are the capabilities there but it's
really uh the progressive approach of
collaboration usually depends of
how people are working together if they
are really external it's more proposal
extended event
if it's within the same team it could be
or within the same event that's usually
the two way of working
if you want to add something no yeah
that's perfect
perhaps another question if you're okay
with
switching yeah when speaking of feeding
tools what would be the automatic
way of doing it so normally when we're
talking about feeding tools there are
two separate ways of doing it and we'll
go way way deeper into this tomorrow
when we talk about integration but
generally tools can either fetch data
from miss
so this is a more common way where a
tool would use rest search api that we
mentioned before where you define yours
your search patterns for example give me
everything that is newer than
30 days everything that uh that contains
at least
that is not coming from say oh since the
sources
or perhaps not something nothing that
comes
uh related to a certain topic for
example i'm not interested in ransomware
when feeding my tools just a stupid
example
so you set up your filter options and
then your tool would fetch
data from misp every 60 minutes for
example
and then replace the data set there you
can also do
sliding time window searches where you
say give me everything from the past 60
minutes that is new
and then you keep concatenating your
data set on the seam side ids side
whatever tool you're
feeding the alternative if you want to
have the data push automatically as it
comes in
you have different channels and mist
that your tools can latch on to
the downside being that you still need
to do the conversion
in those cases so if you were not using
the
the apis to fetch the data from bisp
then mis can push using the miss json
format
data down via different channels serum
queue
or the kafka channel or this blog and so
on
and then your tools automatically feed
on that data so you have these two
different
ways of interacting with it there's also
a third way
where you can basically either build an
export module or an enrichment module
where an analyst can trigger a direct
push of a certain data point
to another tool so that's another option
we'll talk about these different
strategies when to use which
which and how to mix those tomorrow more
so i hope that answers it in a
brief fashion yeah what i'm showing here
is it's just like
on the on the rest uh search client
for example you want to feed your your
storikata and so on uh just
take page um
on a specific limit
so what you can do is if you have a
python script and so on you can pull
directly the data so
the rest client so you see in this case
i have the
shurikata rule set but if you want to
feed your
specific tools and and so on uh
automatically we are generating
uh curl and python card so it could be a
bootstrap to see okay
how should i create my own tool for
feeding my ideas and so on uh for for
study cata for example
a lot of management interface have
already missed connector
so you can even like feed the data
directly from
the from the interface if they have the
ability
splunk for example there's a specific
application
which is an external tools part of the
app store of splunk that you can install
for doing the connection
and some other people are using their
own python script to feed other cm
so again it's a matter of taste
if you are curious about the different
kind of integrations
or you can do it in python for example
in on payments
itself there are plenty of examples
so if you go in the example directory of
palmist
you have a quite significant
set of default scripts
that you can use uh and that's uh
i think usually a good basis if you want
to start to to write your own custom
custom tool set for for feeding your
feeding
systems or existing software in your
infrastructure
yep um
i don't know if it's if we should jump
on a new topic or we just push the
copalos example for tomorrow
yeah i think i think uh we can we can do
it maybe tomorrow i think
if we can i think that would be
stretching it a little bit if we were to
start with that yeah
so um quick quick summary of today so
today we we
show uh how to create an event the basis
of misplay
what is an attribute an object and so on
how to create it so to
make proposal delete uh and and and
stuff like that
so it's really a simple example tomorrow
we want to show you
more the uh even report aspect and the
automatic imports into
into mist with a practical example of an
ocean report
and we will discuss tomorrow about
how to build sharing communities and
especially we will share
our experience of things that worked and
things that didn't work
uh in the past years when creating
sharing communities so if you are
isaac members or creating your own
sharing community even within your
organization
uh it's it's something good to
participate because you we will share
with you some some of the things that
are interesting of building a
bootstrapping such kind of
of community um
i don't know honestly you want to add
something no
and that's basically it thanks for
everyone for sticking through
through this it's a very condensed
session so
we said we didn't make as much progress
as we hoped so we have quite a bit left
for tomorrow
and hope to see you all here tomorrow
thank you very much uh take care and
don't hesitate to ask questions
uh either later on directly contact us
thank you very much
see you tomorrow thank you all see you
tomorrow