I
welcome
alice is doom first
very for sites concise introduction
alright we have had
technical breakthrough so I see the term
I crowd is significantly less than Kevin
Johnson's crown
that's okay lot of people don't don't
overlap much interest
a
us to kinda
putting on my Atlas happy again this is
jarring trying to be Kevin first
oh yeah that's right we're gonna talk
about
sub-crater hurts Wireless New Years ever
use
some radio thing that lives in the sub
bigger trench
those are you were informed
everybody else should have their hands
up your volume no not being a jerk
just is true wat you'll see it's fun
so this started out
back its Yukon with the talk about
some beers radio how it works and how to
play with it
it became a project
that is extensible for your own magic
but is
pretty magical in and of itself thanks
due to
a lot of help from some amazing people
if you
you wanna put a tag line on my grave it
is that I'm very good surrounding myself
with growing folk
um
here's the trick the magical today's
talk
is that we get fast-forward a given
just talkin 3 other venues in different
formats
with different information as the
project's grown as the information's
grown
and I've yet to complete it it really is
about a two-and-a-half-hour talker if
you want to work in exercises
%uh it's a one- or two-day class and I'm
actually putting
putting together a class for black next
year for their proposal
so what we're gonna do is we're going to
fast forward
and I i scan this last night and I
thought I can actually kept
cut this talk in half and give the
second half and not actually lose
anything it's a level of capabilities
difference
the first half is about radio it's about
how it works
how to do things with RF cat by
extending it doing code development
there are slides and videos have that
given three times already
for the first time is really sucky in in
the video cut off is that
so but def Khan and black had both have
that talk we're going to get to complete
the talk
and talk about how to actually play with
RF cat the slides will be available on
going to have
all love the slides available so if you
want to go back and look through the
slides
they're all there too there's value what
place in the sub ita hurts range this is
a slight do not want to skip
everything your cell phones
very likely live in the suburbs hurts
range or
split between 800 900 megahertz
and 1.8 1.9 gigahertz your
cordless phones you probably don't have
a 900 megahertz phone anymore but they
have been a huge
and I like a better because they don't
interfere with WiFi car remotes
you've got a 433
315 they they love these Rangers depends
on where you're at the world
pic I am ease Atta girl texting Tor
that we like to hack I got a firmware
for that that
we're gonna talk about labor medical
devices
medical devices have their own range set
aside for them but they live everywhere
power meters
whoever wanna know about that
all TV broadcast lives under severe
hurts range and much much more
this is the Wild West we all know about
wifi we all know about
I WiMAX somewhat these are standards
that use a particular band for a whole
buncha stuff
some bigger hurts us to have a whole lot
of
standardized communications over there
are standards
and some people claim to adhere to them
but they're wild wild west the
they don't implement anything in
particular so how do we play with that
I my solution is called Orica
it started a few years back I get into
the history just a few slides
bytes
we will be talking largely about RF cat
today to cut 1111 or the 1101 radio
is the generic way of saying RF cat only
without the software peace
why do we care well because I think that
there's probably enough energy can this
ring to
fill an entire classroom love
rocket science geniuses and still win
and now
to the fun part
so are a kak it stands for the radio
frequency
chip conn.-based attack tool I just like
the name
been a net cafe in for years you might
think of this as a
secure its radio redirector if you will
talk a little bit about the background
the goals plans and some other stuff
that we've done
I was
working for some powerful people in the
power industry for about three years
and a the said to me that my task was to
a
hacked the snot out of power equipment
before we stick in the field so that
were not causing what amounts to
basically a compromise the change the
face the Western world
and be scare the shit outta the vendor
so that they get proactive about it
because they were
of so
in my early times with the power work I
went to
power industry a conference called
distributor very common
I I got to speak with some other vendors
that
summer which I was going to be testing
in some which didn't make the cut
even to try testing and some other
vendors I won't tell you which camp they
ended up in
but one of the vendors had a
conversation with me where they said
our frequency hopping spread spectrum
radio
is too fast for hackers to hack I still
stew
on the levels and quantity of stupid in
that statement
2010 that were stupid thing is is
you're right
let's put a challenge out there and then
leave it and
the second stupid is hacking has nothing
to do
well the larger hacking has little to do
with
just taking over your communication but
if you're gonna make it very easy
will rise to that bar problem was
the really wasn't any attack tools at
the time
that made this easy so in my team
actually the
we worked really hard with some various
tools to get to the level where we could
prove their stupidity
just a start the assessment and so when
I put together are afk at the intention
was
something that does not have power
meters out the gate
but certainly can and the idea is
for the people who were in the industry
doing good work
to have a base where they have to
stretch just a little bit
to get something that will allow them to
test the security
I don't wanna lose power I'm very
dependent upon it
but therein lies the rub
so there's a bit over
there how does this work that went into
building RF cat
I'm very interesting radio I've loved it
since I was 5 years old I learned about
it
I but I really didn't do a whole lot
with we did some wifi stuff we did
you know kismet and all that stuff in
the day and you know we've had some
I've had some fun with some radio things
but they're it's always been a
you know if I could do this more a
better could find some stuff to
to break that also
security analysis tools
to let's let's break into it and show to
make better
right you know I love breaking things
and I'm not always the white hat let's
let's publish everything that's that's
working everything but in this regard
the better we can make up our system the
better my life
will be also just satiate my general
love radio frequency
I'm there was a
when the earliest hacking stories
comes from but 1903
when marconi
guys probably heard that name before
still a business today very big in the
in the radio
world but Guiliano
honey marconi was giving a demonstration
of his
we might call a virtual private radio
cuz he was
selling the fact that he could tune
radios
to a certain frequency and only other
radios tuned at that frequency
could be listen or take part in a
conversation
there was a big deal in 1903 the ability
to radios has
jumped huge amount since then but he was
sitting
at the top of a mountain with his
transmitter
and his assistant were sitting in a
crowd not unlike this one
with very intelligent people waiting to
see
Marconi's radio magic five minutes
before the demonstration
a little ticking noise started becoming
quite irritating
and it turned out to be coming from
Marconi's device
some in the audience
here knows Morse code art
this through the audience starts
thinking rate that sounds like marceca
Inc soon it was very apparent that it
was Morse code it was actually Morse
code
saying the most derogatory things about
Marconi and his tool
because this person
was able to break into the
communications and take it over
well the system was in pureed and
publicly outlast
at whoever it was in the newspaper it
within three days
never mass killing a guy whose family
was in the circus
and his interest in radio had to do with
well
circa see things the magic love being
able to guess who people are for example
or information about them
if you're may be in your piece that has
a that has a radio in it you can talk
over
and mescaline took mark on his promise
and said
that's wrong and built a huge
transmitter
that broke into the system he came up
came forward is very happy to
since I get that was me and the
assistant
flames him mercilessly I mean we we're
talkin making the UNIX
list days look really kinda tame
and Devils answer was
abuse is no argument
marconi was far more research says
I refuse to debate with some
with one who would shine cast doubt upon
the technology or something along those
lines
something equally stupid we know that
now
are here this even rodin I will not
demonstrate when a man who throws doubt
upon the system
you what
those of you who saw this you can talk a
couple years ago this is not heavy
attack
but the work in the in the learning that
we did in heavy attack
played into rfk greatly my thought was
so heavy attack helps us determine
hopping frequency frequency hopping
patterns
so then what and my goal was to make a
tool that I could then take those
shopping patterns
put them into and take over in actually
have a network adapter
not just some hacky toy
after it has several different
different faces if your own one is a
interactive tool
I I like to think of it as a Python
interface to the sub your trading
another is that are of cat server if you
guys have ever done anything with
say the Ravens for example there there's
a is a tool called the RZ Raven
and allows you to talk to
ZigBee radios from your Windows machine
well
it's very common and the Raven was no
exception
to plug in the device run a device
driver that
listens on a port and then your
application software just talk so that
network port
to access to hardware so our cat server
attempt to do that
because not everybody wants that don't
wants to rate their toys in Python
I can accept that I and
sometimes standard in is not the
greatest way to type in binary
alright yes
RF cat leverages
the trick on 1101 I already mention that
TI
basically said pretty much everything
you want to do in the sub your trains
let's throw into one configurable radio
instead offering
10 and for the most part
this was the way the new this is the
result
I've almost everything that they wanted
to do there are two exceptions
and one is a sum up the
ZigBee work and some the lower frequency
Bluetooth work
they require a different physical layer
and so they were able to brought that in
but they wrapped in amplitude shift key
thats better known as digital a.m.
thereafter in frequency shift keying FSK
also known as digital FM and
several variations of these things that
we know and love only in the digital
world
and thereafter any frequency range have
upper 900 megahertz down to 300
megahertz for the couple gaps in the
middle
really good stuff a
when I made our of cat the goal was to
make
all of that available in as easy a
fashion as possibly can so
I'm a lover I love I pie from
interactive Python it's my favorite
shell and
I love the fact that I can't debug
processes with that I can disassemble
program so that I I can do everything on
from my little I Python command line
shell
and so the research motive RF cat
which is the most used in most tested
and most stable
drops you to an iPod iPhone shelling
creates
and object for you to interact with your
US
with the USB dongles called the so
you'll see a lot of commands in here
that start with the dot and that just
means in the iPod iPhone environment
that's my object that I used to interact
with that stuff
microphones great by the way if you
never use it it includes
up some nice pretty representation of
information if you want to display it
and it includes for my favorite parts
tab completion
very intelligent way so that
and have to remember the API completely
I just take d dot tab tab
I get the list to the API and you'll see
down here
I've listed several very interesting
things to do with the rfk dont you gotta
set up
archive server can't really see that
very well
basically you start our archive server
and the you connect to it on port
1900 to get interface
to the wireless network you then connect
to our 1899
and you get a command line interface
where you get to configure the radio
outer bands so if you want to tune it to
certain frequency setup embassy
amplitude shift keying modulation
and set the baud rate to thirty eight
for
killer bod 3.4 collide you do that from
that will take effect in the other
window and you will have a connection
with
the network on that configuration were
my favorite parts
love the project actually is in the IM
me firmware that we build
I is called arson F now there are
significant also be used for the don't
know but are Stefan
on IM me is special be cuz
jamie has a keyboard and with a keyboard
were able to set up all the radio
frequency
configuration parameters and change them
at will
and then we can set up
to either just send every packet her
every bit of information that your sense
on the network to the screen at least
the first 30 characters ovett or
filter based on some
think I D which is very common for every
different typeof radio solution every
every product that uses some bigger
hurts they typically will start off with
some 16 or 24 bit sequence
of bits that are just unique to that
device
that way the radio doesn't just send all
sorts of solar noises
and everybody's garage door opener and
whatever
to your insulin pump
the insulin pump sits there is coming to
Mac address it says
okay this this is not meant for me
discard this is not meant for me discard
it sold in hardware very fast and it
doesn't
bygone the system
were able to set up a sink I D in the r
us now from the IM me as well
so that we only focus in on one thing
for example I've got a power meter home
that I'm able to
I know what the sink ideas for it and
I'm able to tune in and catch
every with our with RSF able to catch
every packet on on the particular
channel I'm on it doesn't support
hopping at the moment but
but I'm able to catch a report that I'm
listening and they're certainly 5253
to 82 different channels
in any given shopping system I was the
key bindings here for a
for the RCF ok you wanna take this off
line and go play with it it's also in
every file in the project
but i wanna make it simple and an easily
remember below where at just wrapped in
in the last couple months
I I put in a spectrum analyzer so
we set base frequency and then we set a
channel which
we set the number of channels up to two
and 55 channels
recommending about a hundred and it
scans through the channels very very
fast
and it displays the power output
and each one so
at the top I'm using Python's use a
floating numbers with the you simple but
I could just as easily written
90 1 000 000
comma 5 0.00% 0 0.00%
comma 51 no b51 channels
50 kilohertz
in spacing starting at 901
as you can see I pick something up here
about 90 to
too little limited it's not too it up
production qualities such as you might
find in a two hundred thousand dollar
device
still stop at
I used to have to go I Mike Osman
anybody heard like Mike Awesome
mazing I'm very very cool knowledgeable
and friendly
and I he wrote firmware for the IM me
that does spectrum analysis
and so I used to always have one others
I am you sitting around I said you know
this is silly
I'm gonna probably give a talk and some
and some
and some courses on this is probably
wrap that in just make it happen since I
got the radio
throughout the slide you'll find that
I've got exercises
you leave those to you if you have an RF
can and you're interested please
go use the exercises my email addresses
on the first slide
you have troubles with the exercises let
me know let me know
but this thing these exercises drive
home some
love the keep our components
a far-off cat including what I call the
Obama Road
global mod is where you take you remove
in the configuration your move
all things that would not allow
data to be transmitted to the screen or
to your to your buffer
what this does is effectively puts your
your RF cat into
cause I monitor mode if you will if you
remember the other days have
Jasmine actually the day's still taken
are awesome Christmas stuff
I'm if you wanna print
the client state the state of the
the rfk client print rapper client state
once you have entered low-ball mode
it stores the original configuration in
your Python fine
and then when you want to get out of a
la mode and go back to something more
sane
use low-ball restore and it copies the
old config back into the radio and
everything takes off
and then you end up with be able to do
RF receive everything that you get
that comes in as a packet get stored in
your Python buffer
see a radio isn't really even depend on
at this point or dependency at this
point
your Python buffer stores it for you or
for your application if you're writing
something on top of our Afghan
and you use our for seve to get out that
data
is an exercise would actually cover the
stuff in a few
discover mood or get to that are
better so some other we could call this
a far-off category talk a little bit
about it
we have we have a team are
a debug mode you wanna see what the
client is doing
talking to the radio the Python client
will actually offer up its goods
if you set de tout underscored debug
equal to or greater than 0
shuts up when you said it is zero one
gives you some same messages
like I've sent these bikes to the radio
I perceive these bites the radio use
this
a lot because it's really nice just
when I'm troubleshooting you're working
on something all set debug Eagle One
I will see exactly when i receive data
from the radio
without having to go do RF receive and
printed out
the debug function
sits and spins printing out
client information and the state to the
radio at that point so
if you're if you're running debug for
example it will say
ever see this many packets for this for
this application
be Dongo is still responding units in
the idle motorists in receive mode
things like that discover
discover allows us to set a low ball
mode
default is one 0 mean send everything
even if you don't see any rise in power
in the radio one is the more saying hey
as soon as I see a carrier to send data
I think that's the most helpful which
twice that of all
but it then just sits and prints data as
it is
as it appears in a nicely packaged
format that can make sense to you
in hexadecimal mobile mode is used
by discover and we are to talk about a
little bit and no more store
RF listen is a step above discover
any basically says using this
configuration
if our see packets is printable to the
screen it may seem like a small step up
in maybe I should
it seems confusing but actually when you
get into playing with it
you'll find that they both have their
purposes RF captures basically of listen
but its stores every packet so there
at the end when you hit enter and you
get out of RF listen mode
it will return to you a list up the
packets
so that your program can 21 scanning
mode
allows us to set a particular
base frequency a channel size
and a timeout and it just sits in hops
through all the channels looking for
data
spits out on the screen up to a certain
amount
and then moves on I found this could be
very fun
driving through town a crack what's that
I found that at 9:12 924 megahertz
at my house which is basically an RF
cage I
I still have constant stream of data no
idea why it but
I would have found it if I hadn't earned
standard
spec and notice how you turn on Rd
outspokenness how you turn on the
spectrum analyzer
possible do we so it's a different
window
know when you close the girl you get
your the kremlin-backed Andy dot print
radio configure print out all the
information that You
could possibly want okay most the
information that would be very good to
know about how to reduce configured
modulation with speed were intermediate
frequency you can change the
intermediate frequency for those if you
read your books out there
and I went over this in the exercise
already sorry
oh one thing to note about discover mode
it doesn't just drop you want to lowball
mode the
idea behind the creation discover mode
was identifying
sink words in the area so this is shared
spectrum right
if if you want
if you're in a rare relatively populated
area you'll probably
always have no less than three devices
hitting at once
for a lot of the channels so the idea
here is
kinda like kismet would show
what networks were listening by
listening for traffic and making some
salad and
discover mode
as a primary can turn on called I don't
think word
and it will assume
that all this raw data coming through
has a sink word on the front
and then a carrier will
will carrier will come in which is in
alternating 10 bit up to a certain like
that's how the radio knows that there's
a carrier by the way
this is called a preamble and when the
preamble is done
the sink word normally starts and that's
how it knows that the star the frame is
about to occur
discover mode takes that information
that comes in
does some math shifting around have the
bits
incomes up with possible Cinque Ports
so this this work I use this actually on
discovering my at my power meter sink
word
and actually had some interesting stuff
they're all talk about a minute
but does that make sense everybody
to get 10 10 10 10 that standard
preamble
then your sink word starts after that
but who's to say that you're seeing for
doesn't start with a one or a0
in the same sequences the preamble
so discover mode says this is something
that I'm pretty sure
could be and that it shipped up and it
includes up to
most the preamble and spits out the %ah
the options for
each network that advice
if i'm looking for a list of sync words
i turn on sink word match list hand in a
list a python worst
above the sink words that i'm looking
for. and it looks for
and discovers and prints out when it
when it finds one
not require totally optional %uh power
meter that I was hacking has
16 15 possible
sink word spaced so that they can easily
say
hey this utility is using our stuff in
this utility adjacent to it is using our
stuff it's tweak it
so they don't get each others messages
want to rule them all which that's the
goal
I'm unfortunately it's not totally
the case yet but it ruins the title the
slides and just gonna say
want to rule them all and then throw in
there
maybe a softer defined radio if you're
doing discovery work
but for radio for the attacks I dove
radio
RF cat should do almost all that you
need to do
for leveraging against a bigger trader
so I will have read dogle called Gina
running our of cat
spec an the spectrum analyzer yes any
mcdonnell's
it's a great services it's called it
dawned on naming service
I dogle Paul actually somebody stole
polish mcconnell
missing him right now but Paul will be
running are of cat
proper so that I can tweak everything
right away and and go
finding sniff
I like and I am hearing or a sniff I'm
especially when I'm developing because
there's nothing
worse than making a change and not
knowing okay something brokers at the
transmitter the receiver and having just
a known good sitting around
from the non RF cat part
a salir logic analyzer for my best
friends
and it allows me to tap into bus lines
in communication between
different ships on our afford or on any
better system
and track the the 1's and 0's on the
bits
I just say the ones and zeros on the
bits yes on the wires
the bits on the wire and a fun Q donde
or
for some other STR they're really cheap
a funky dongles like
100 reeboks ok it's not nearly as cheap
as RF cat
I'm if you're only interested in
sniffing which actually I am
I found that summer the high-performance
video USB plug ins
have been turn into St arse and they're
like 20 bucks
so what this allows you to do is get any
better
picture at the lower levels I've what a
waveform
actually looks like in from that it's
easier
to determine modulation scheme
and boundary and it's kind of just a
basic troubleshooting tool
I'm pushing RF cat to be more and more
and more
but it'll never be an STR Justin
so on occasion cranking up in st. are
can make your research that much better
put together an RF attack for so
for example every device that I have all
sit down with the form and I've got a
downloadable from the website this is
just a slight showing some the
information
I'm and of Ilion the
just to make sure I'm answering all the
questions that I have to before i sat
down with the device
and start to play with it base frequency
modulation
broadband with is your modem stuff you
guys remember the modems
you deviation how do I know a a
deviation in the frequency that's a one
or a0
channel hopping how many channels
pattern
an effective sick method because it's
one thing to know a pattern of a system
it's another to figure out how they
discover each other
channel spacing well period this is how
long it stays on every channel
and is it fixed or variable length
very polite packet is well known the
first byte sets the link to the pack
um
does have an address
was just some device that treats every
other buddy is
as able to transmit to it what's the
sink word or sink words if applicable
to use any encoding nurse CRC
Manchester these are all things that the
radio handles for you
very handy to know that right out of the
gate
we've recently added and here's the
the rekon form on the website we've
recently added the ability to
turning use the hardware a yes
in the chip he's always been available
but we've recently made it very easy to
set up
in to use it anybody heard a major
malfunction major malfunction
maze in Guyana the UK I he is well known
for his Bluetooth
and ZigBee hacking he works at a place
called the bunker
its kinda scary a but he's also been
contributing to the rfk project
and he needed recently the yes
compatibility capability and so he's
like
I know you're going to get this is on
your to do list here handed it to me
another exercise so little bit of the
application how we doing on time
Stenton are good morning
mucking around with medical devices
particularly insulin pumps
can be deadly I personally have the
ability to
to push insulin through a
well not push yet but to definitely set
up a pump
to push a lethal injection have against
one
and so be warned wanna my
on my closest friends is a diabetic and
he let me use his pomp
so as I say be careful
we found the PDF
have the manual told us
what frequency the thing operated at and
it's not a standard frequency is not
even in the year
the reins for medical devices with
diabetic cares what frequency the device
runs on
unless of course they're upset because
they can't no
but I thought it was interesting um
the modulation is easily gas just by the
way for my used a spectrum analyzer and
Mike
yeah that's definitely block in on my
god
we use to %uh several other
techniques and tools including US RP
I was working on this last
last January I believe and Mike Osman
was straining give me a hand and he said
wait a minute
you don't have your Sharpie woody while
so he sent me a US are created to help
him help me
the discovery process
probably some of the most fun for
pictures at least we first started out
with a spectrum analyzer between the
radio
module and the mainboard and
a and we hit with the spectrum analyzer
dresses sorry
we hit with a spectrum analyzer first
watch the stuff
and figured out what we could buy by
using a spectrum analyzer
we then moved on to logic analyzer
watching
the day to go over the the data bus
the wires on the board then we captured
basically audio data from the US RP
got a picture of what this way for looks
like an from it
we were able to tell bond rate and
secret given the bond rate the sink word
actually turned out to be pretty easy
I'm we took a packet capture out of the
US RP
cuz the of cat was in a much earlier
statement wasn't able to
to do as much with it I'm and we turn we
put it into a tool called bob line
bloodline did analysis and allowed us to
figure out baud rate and
visually look for data next Mike Osman
in were floundering here just a little
bit we we went in several different
directions I'm telling you the I suck
story
just just so that you know
that when we're when you're doing
research in you go down a road
and you're not sure if you should go
down the road in to try different road
and it turns out that you were able to
cora
triangulate the what you're after out of
all these different things
such as you it happens every researcher
has to do with this
and do with the failure that you have to
run into before success
so my costume then took the
the capture and ran through the new
radio companion you guys heard a radio
K new radio comes with a graphical
tool that allows you to process
maybe D marshall et Tampa 5 whatever
process Rawal radio in turn it into bits
and from that we were able to determine
a all the information we needed we pump
in the framers into our of cat
and we were able to receive directly
from
the center
this is just a little bit of collage
work to show that I'm not
visual artist appears what
the data looks like a bad line just so
that if you ever do it
got something to compare against
this is all the junk that Mike had to go
through to
to work through going to radio companion
2d modulate and get
out the data from
this thing now you're starting to see
the answer
the question why don't you just use a
nasty are for this
cuz that's tough hard in your writing
for more from scratch is hard to you
but I do wants and if I make it flexible
enough
I'm not only got something with it
allows me to do analysis
but also got the attack to when I'm done
and right here you can see
the scope with the preamble right here
the sink worry here and then the data
2013 a hit the configuration into your
our Afghan
we started seeing this is discover mode
we started seeing various forms
don't forget and discover mode you are
either one but a liner to better align
which means that
debates could be all shipped all over
and we
came up with possible sink words that
are not very visible on the slide we
just turn it on
into normal Nick Mon and here's our
packet
turns out medical devices
as well as many the simpler
radio devices they don't have simple
send
and receive a lot of them including your
garage door openers and your
car key fobs and apparently insulin
pumps
you run and they do 100 or 200
attempts and sense now you may think
this is because the transmitters
weaker problematic but it turns out
if you don't even if you have a pristine
packet that you're sure of
the pump doesn't do anything until it
sees like
a hundred so the firmer probably does
some statistical analysis saying
okay river just receive like a hundred
packets errors occur
a lot more than you think from our
normal wireless experience
and so they throw out these aberrations
you know we had five that are
different and you know 195 that are
the same need to reverse the palm
for for actual by directional protocol a
or actually just how to get around it I
know that there's actually a way that
I should be able to issue a command to
the pomp
and just have it drop insulin into
the channel I'm not sure that I actually
wanna publicly present that I'm
I do know of a path to get there and I
haven't had time but I can register
glucose levels a 475
if anybody news glucose levels at
pretty scary
mucking with a power meter is illegal
without permission from the utility
company
and probably their vendor even if it's
on the side of your house
yes you give them the right to manage
this thing as a part of your property
even though you know
now
power meters are just one component be
very large power system
the end the last mile if you will
is called the distribution there's
transmission
on the outside it is the distribution
bubble in this generation the answer
that there's a lot more complexity to it
but think about those stages
meters makeup a large component
love distribution in the modern but also
in distribution
all those meters have wired cables that
connect back to a distribution
substation and distribution substations
have skated equipment and cap banks
and other things that help make your
stuff more reliable
and make their monitoring more accurate
why do I say that
because when i sat down with the guy
originally talking about power meters
I said okay I got these ideas
and he says don't even bother with them
your word about stealing energy
I'm not okay
what bothers you he says
we're working with the system
that is antiquated and
the influence have enough power which
power meters
with the disconnect switch have control
over to literally
change the face the Western world I
stole that phrase from
any went on to detail to me
how controlling enough
have the power through disconnect
switches on power meters
is enough to break things
in the power in the bigger more
expensive side love
transmission and distribution that
can have up to eighteen month lead time
to get a replacement can cost
well over a million dollars he says
I don't want people to gain control
these things shot me neither thanks
many of the existing power meters
use their own proprietary neighborhood
area network man as this call and that
is basically
their meters all mashing together and
talking to some
access point which then has some sorta
back all
sprint may be leased line whatever back
to the utility for control
there been two phases have smart meters
well there in two phases have special
meters if you will
what is called a Mr an early interest in
mr. there's no control there it's just
basically meters broadcasting
their usage so that people can drive
down the road and get the usage
instead of going up in checking a
premier the second type is called
advanced metering infrastructure
and it is intelligent bi directional
communication with power meters that
have some
microcontrollers that do you education
so the check on 11/11
has the same Japan 1101 core that said I
would say 75 percent above the power
meters available today
that's why I'm here as I said before
at the stuff was doo-doo Hurtado
sorry and unavailable to security
researchers other power people or fear
security research
sure typically historically
some people are out there trying to make
it better I'm
but its
become very plain in the last three
years that there are some power vendors
who want to take a proactive approach
engage the people smart enough to break
their stuff
pay them not threaten them and then fix
the problems and push out
get it going to supply chain that
actually can handle security updates
some vendors do not however drink this
kuwait
but rather consider for sticking your
head in the sand
the better way I
typically I have several power meters
and I like to display them
anonymously I cover the face paint stuff
from a vendor who has been very good to
me
and to my Cole scary researchers
and they're only their only request is
that
we respect them to share the
vulnerabilities with them in respect
others
not too sure publicly these guys get
they want to know how the babies are
ugly
I'm II
really gotten a bad attitude about
certain vendors
power meters are in a simple is good
commerce the
typically are covering much larger
distances in the
industrial scientific and medical the
ice ambiance
there are restrictions on how much power
you can use
for anyone given device there's an
exception to the
to the limitation however that allows a
significantly greater in our power to be
used
if the devices hop
over more than fifty channels and not
spend more than a certain amount of time
on any one channel
in a 20 second period these are the FCC
Rules
I to you has rules the cover a lot over
you know the world but the FCC applies
this to us
so what we're finding out is that
instead of just
or what we found out was in center just
grabbing packets
we have to hop along with which means we
have to identify
a frequency hopping patter and
we have to identify a discover mode
not just for one meter vendor but we
have to do it for every meter vendor
because they're all
different there some standardization
that that
looks like it could make this easier
because via at least publicize
everything
but I've actually found that a lot of
the guys
doing cutting-edge work a patented their
stuff
and so their Mac if I is publicly
available in fact the vendor that I
was talking about who still wish to
remain anonymous sadly
has said we've decided
overtly to publish to publish or Mac and
final airs because
we can't allow them to be seen as our
security
got a bad idea so as time permits I
certainly
ok to knock down several more vendors
to you have our cat talking with them
but I will publish
sums are but if you're in the industry I
will talk to you
we won't be sinking with the meter today
the I didn't bring it
but also because I don't want that
Parliament talk
so we start off for the year SPI bus
sniffing using that logic analyzer
as you can see the logic on certain pins
bounces a up and down periodically
on SPI bus we have a clock and that is
this guy down here
and then we get the data in these other
these other wires
SPI has a to and from where
so that instead of just a back-and-forth
we know that this is data coming to the
device in this is
data coming from the device
yes this is actually just video for for
photographic
digital porn because I'm not really
showing you
data
here we go
to retake that day today with 7 through
some II some Python parsing goodness
we end up being able to read what the
data is
sent to the radio including
configuration settings channel hopping
parameters
had to write a special client for this
but it turns out that this particular
900 megahertz radio
the radio set to work at four hundred
megahertz
and it doesn't up
you can understand my confusion turns
out their heterodyne ing their four
hundred megahertz
radio signal to here knows heterodyne K
you guys all have a super heterodyne in
radio very likely or have in the past
had a rating means that you
mixed two singles and you get
to output signals with one base signal
and then plus or minus the other signal
on either side
so what we were seeing was we had a
former mayors radio
and then they were doing their hopping
on a secondary device
which the change channels secondary
device
operates at one point three gir hurts
which Landis right in the 900 megahertz
range
so just reversing this hardware was
rather
odd but you notice the types of things
you can see an embedded space
we hit discover mode
and
we didn't see anything of interest until
I realized
in the process
love the mixing they're flipping the
bits
so that everyone is as your own every 0
is a1
and so as I'm looking for a safe word
10 10 10 10 which is actually a
in the by exodus more a but then
at the end of 5555
which is 0101 0101
the reverse I have this weird thing
that when I invert those bits happens to
be one of the
one of the sink words that i'm looking
for.
the discovery process is painful
sometimes but that's why I'm sharing so
that
if you play you can know you can have a
less painful recently
as I said several vendors have filed
numerous patents
or their FCC filings
are not private there's nothing you can
do when you submit your system to the
FCC we can request that certain parts of
it is confidential
and they won't share publicly I'm one of
the vendors has done this very well
except for one thing that gives away the
american pie still
I'm here are some patents
to Mac and final air that need some
attention if you're interested abuse is
no argument
we r responsible
for ensuring that our world
is secure particularly the stuff that we
depend on
your friend may be the first
insulin related pack to your
power may get turned off by someone
who's played around with the power
equipment it is our job to ensure
that vendor claims are proven true
you very much