yes
sorry
no so obviously we saw that X was
implemented by one
but because there is a more s sex
instruction what will happen is the best
the MS measly
all be favored 111 111 okay
so that doesn't solve that based on the
example between
this thing 128
with more Essex what will happen is in
our example it was implemented by 1 seed
is
ffffff and then 81
okay
so the would be 128 V would be ffffff
81 and that is approximately way to 4
gigabytes
so just imagine what would happen if a
for gigabyte values putting away a
a member of the destination source to my
4 gigabytes that is actually
the total a memory that that would be
too big to
to get a big sellers system would
address so
if the destination is not that big the
destination both but is not that big
it will lead to a buffalo okay and in
the bed was in what will happen is
this thing would be just 0.00% 0 0.00%
81 that is one thing so what is
happening is in the unpatched version
a man copy got me a call is made we're
just trying to go before you go by
myself and you
and in the bachelors in we know that it
has been reduced to just one big inning
by
day so the at this point we have tried
to analyze what the change was enough
what did
what was the chain made by Microsoft in
this bed so how do we explain this thing
thing
depends
night
that's true
but what we know what we want we are not
trying to write an exploit for this this
a proof-of-concept some what we know is
somehow if I put this magic number 128
some that in this and the pediatric ward
there is a high chance that I will be
able to exploit the limited
rate so I'm usually not the
name I'm not an expert with and if we
get a card but this is
sort assemble in the pediatric ward
looks like it's really simple to add and
if we get a good Guardian Windows DNS
server
this is what the simple and if we get a
good looks like you just go with the
name
a fully qualified domain no meaning and
you see that I these
fears away a on Oprah Francis leg string
regular expression replacement to me to
do explain this one then maybe you don't
have to be an expert with any pediatric
are
all you need to know is I have to put
this magic number 128 some that in one
of the speeds
so that the one that he would be
explained
so what they do is I start they're
putting 128 2012 indeed well you know
your your
and i'd regular blend in this look up
but they could never love
Nemo the when the baby was no one
expected ideally
that there should have been a honeymoon
are before to overflow
and it leaves the service should have
guessed but that never happened so can
anyone tell me a better solution what
good I could have done
explain this one that it may be we know
that there's something related to 128
number
and surely that would be a powerful
knows said don't sound it's not that
difficult so what they did this
I I saw there was this that up to the
east
string values the flexed ringside
whistling and regular expressions thing
so what they did is I just rather than
putting the value number 128 what they
did is I
just put a random 128 get a cousin and
then I don't did and this nigga
and then the service kress
because as simple as that any questions
so how this one nobody could be exploded
in the real world scenario
so what would happen if suppose
there's an a what an attacker could do
is
ago said the malicious domain names lol
with the
with the crafted me in this regard and
if we get a car
and a good sis send an email to one of
bill guys in your
at invisible he was adopted the company
makes for easy what he could do is they
would send an email to a guy in this
company
saying people you open this link this
guy would try to resolve that thing
the domain name for this and it would
break the fed's that record and was it
Fed does this accord the DNS solely your
effects have been those being a so when
it tries to bars this eckhardt
at this point the well if you do would
be exploited
and the DNS overturning on this system
Woodcrest
a simple as that
somewhat the important thing what you
want to know where u is
that only the DNS solo service they're
designing on the
machine would press not be in bed
operating system because it's not the
gonna lower than that ability it's just
have a little maybe
in the application more application
there
their DNS server application not be
gonna burn would be
so let's like to do something more
harmful where we would try to bring or
the
being on the end sa1 let's try to
exploit the when the pain goes gonna
any questions on MC dental 58
now so this brings us to another example
next example of MS 11 or 77 MSN 0727 was
released
last year in October 2011 and what they
did is
it fix for 100 is in Windows gonna again
if you look at the advisory
vendors don't give out a lot of big is
it just says that
a ms leno's on this and fixes anymore go
to
exit a and elevation of privilege when
that ability because
of in Senate as imports that is if they
don't give you a lot of new ideas what
bet on the bill was not sanitizer things
like that
so for this stock would be concentrating
on CV 2011 1985
and it was an elevation of privilege
when that if need be and
this is what the desserts from but were
def look-alikes
sick those you did that on many function
that looks suspicious to it
somebody else even a suspicious plus
plus
someone like this teens again and even
then the lake in the previous example
that we saw
only four functions were teens but if
you look at this thing
in this bed them many functions that
were teens any guesses why
the number of changes are so much
sorry
yeah
that's correct so we saw in the puppy vs
one Microsoft only fix to win the peace
but in this bed Microsoft Fix for when
the deputies
so obviously because they've fixed a lot
of things that are high chances that
they need to modify luck do lots of
Gordon this
and hasn't left in December so what I do
know they started looking at e2 one
function one by one
and then I saw that there were three
functions that
all stocked with and the use that FN and
the use that FN
the function starting with Andy's that
FN and all the court in this that will
make the dysfunctions all the scene
so basically whatever team was made to
one function was basically got be based
in all these functions
so far on and this is what we are I did
as I took one of the functioning
NP use that FN I in a box spring can
everyone see this
there okay so
whatever defenses is that for this
function:
there was a poor drafting a cover up in
section was added earlier
and there was this would block of code
that was that was aided by this new
version of the fight
so let's try to analyze it so what we
see is you stock combating
each instruction one by one and there
was this one for additional instruction
that was a big
gone bad EC X ffff
FFF if this movement of efforts and a
call
and another block of cold weather so
let's see what is going on
we know that combat dcx ever fifth was
added
if you see the instructional your mooie
CX
ABB less on goes you know this is
basically the what there was a false
document foster this function
was moved to the CX e6 is then compared
with this one went off efforts this is
nothing but -1
whose those compliments -1 and
if it does not if it is ever effect is
-1
the whole it goes into this block and
calls a function with
said users said record
so let's see what's going on
ECS is compared with my if they CX is my
-1
a function call is made said lost data
and function
said said lasted a bit court
50 578 as and then victim so what is
basically going on in your eyes
and the and bachelors in there was no
comparison leg
compare the fullest argument with -1 or
anything
whatever argument this pasta that
function it happily accepted that
argument
and it continued processing but in the
bed was in what is happening is
the bed was in is explicitly taking the
first argument of the function
it is comparing it with -1 if it is
found to be -1 it does not happy
xx an ETA and ETB is although the
function okay
so I didn't go live but offer research a
ruling on what is this a and that is
what this 57.8%
ages and it is a systematic or for
invalid use a hand I'll
invalid window handle so let's try to
see what's going on
in the bed was in whatever is the
argument
it doesn't get it just accepts it
processes there and goes out
but in the other in the bed wasn't what
it is trying to do is it is taking the
first argument
comparing it with -1 if this bond to be
-1 it does not have peace
xx an ETA and bizarre so how do we
explain this one
everything
so let me go again
in the end vez was in
whatever is the first argument accept
the argument
processes there and it is happy whatever
is the Aug in the bed was and what did
this thing to do is
it begs the first argument but the spot
for this function:
compares it with -1 if it is found to be
-1
does not happy and have sex and had a
and B is out so if you were to expect
this one that would be how would you
sorry
yeah that's correct so we know that
whatever is the
so the bed was is looking for this
argument is not happy when it does -1 if
you like to expect this when they're
ready
just said this argument to be -1 and see
what happens so how do we explain this
argument has to be -1
and there was a little hand when I did a
google search about it
excess it xx and Adam before it bizarre
eg this a the endeavor to sectors
invalid user in relevant to handle so
this gives me a bit of an idea that
possible I have who said this argument
to be -1 and
this explicitly telling you that I'm not
happy because
it is an invalid window and so what you
do is be know that this gives you a
little hand that before us argument
is off by bindle handle so
this is a proof of concept but I miss
Lana sands and
just two lengths of court landed on it
your windows
a.m. machine and it will be abuse going
on that
so yeah and the questions
sorry
yeah
I have a good blog about this I think I
have a link to that goal
so because what happens is if you see
this hour function and data and to use
that ended boxing
this is a good move them to new cannot
does give it a coordinating
so you need to know how to reach that
function how to take that from
so decks I have a blog about their
just google it and it is a pretty much
everything what you need to know
about this thing
any other questions
okay so what we have seen under this
point the point like which I want to
highlight is
that this technique is really very
simple and what
benefits investors could do is they
could use this technique to develop that
own customers place and they are just
not limited to the exploits that data
available from next like backs
they could create their own
proof-of-concept invested and engage
them again
and use them in that engagements sort
done so did this technique is not this
only useful for
I penetration testers but there are
these bunch of guys who are already
using this technique
and can anyone guess while woo
are already using this technique
so yeah my daughter's my daughters they
are the ones who are using this
technique a lot
it is very helpful for them so that they
know what the Fed these but is that
really is what they would do is the
Woodside
doing buying the new defaming and I'll
try to come up with ex-wife's
so that they could use it so a very good
example of this is Ms Leno
9 a.m. est residue 04 it was the lease
in January 2000 and what did it is it
fixed to
when their abilities in Windows when
handling the
all maybe five me defies
even know what the media file is a these
are like really small music by is
so far the stock has been concentrating
on C 2012 003
and it's a remote code execution
vulnerability
then boxing the modified so the nature
of this when they begin which makes it
more
nuclear do for them on that all it does
is first of all it's a remote code
execution vulnerability
and secondly a whenever
if if I send you a link which has a MIDI
file your browser will try to parse it
that in there
so basically if they're not bad as in if
I send you a link to an exploit and you
click on it
basically you are owned by that thing
so let's do a buying any dipping
again you see that they would if they
resist to fix this one and maybe
Microsoft did not deny just changed one
function to fix this when the media
all the functions look identical in
there was only one function that was
teens
let's try to analyze what the function
change was
for the function name as me D out play
next volume
we don't get on the functioning and
if a stock tumbling each in section one
by one you see that there was
this one and business section that was a
and you
and the media comma seven if age so
let's try to analyze what this
and be a comma 7f ages so what is
happening away you know is
so that is this one
BD was that was moved to be in and it is
combat handed
and then logical and was then against us
7f eight so what is happening alia is
vendela that isn't what and logical end
does is
if the value in BN is less than seven if
age it is it it is kept to that value
but fatah if the value of BL is more
than seven if it
it is you use to 07 if age so what's
happening only it is in and bed was in
there was no standardization whatsoever
anything you boss to a it was happily
accepting it but in the bed was in
what is happening is Microsoft is
explicitly taking one video but
and it is not happy then effect if the
vid
if that the the value of that variable
respond to be greater than seven if it's
it is used to seven if age
so this is the only thing that was made
by the function
so what was the change had just taken
for a video but it is
if we it does not want this value to be
greater than seven if it
so how do you expect this one
this rate
so
me know that that is this one really bad
with the bad just trying to take
and it does not and it is setting a
limit to it so if you want to explain
this when they really
just possibility that is bigger than the
slimming make does all this for
on this red a heart goes out this value
which it was trying to check is the Nord
number but I'm leader
for to me to fight now I don't have an
exploit
funded I do have an expert but I can
assure you because
its unmodified so if the NDA's
uninterested to send me an email and it
and be happy to send you a
a proof-of-concept expect for this
so guess what
so this page was the isn't the end of
January 2007
any guesses when was the flushed model
that found in the white trying to
exploit this when the meeting
thing
couldn't sorry denser in for my betta
autos it is not just they don't want to
crash %uh system
they want to get to the level good
execution obviously
if got a good with their different
things you could have a proof of concept
of all this in just one day
like to get reliable court execution it
would take you a lot of them
it would take you some time to develop a
sophisticated expect still do it
it like to do it any guesses all
long would be big okay so the Fostex my
dad was found in the white
trying to expect this one then maybe was
fun on 26th of January 2000
so just a minute next 16 days after the
bet was the least that is already on my
mind
life Frank expect this one on the day
even this is a privately reported
vulnerabilities soul be
before the end of January than one way
there was no exploit our
would just as soon as the fed's israelis
within 16 days
there was a moderate all that was trying
to exploit the system
BR system so back to bed just some files
so what we have seen under this point is
this technique is useful for are
penetration testers
my daughters are already trying to
explain use this technique
but what about security sensors ok
indeed breakthrough
how can they come up with new when the
bees if you guys are trying to do when
they begin the search how could you come
up with new when there it is just based
on
security badges so dun sa be hot but
this bed is I'm not always done right
these badges: I suppose to fix when the
abilities but
the often into his new when the body's
immune system a very good example of
love this this PHP 5.3 playing nine I it
was released in January 2012
and a it fixed a
the ps3 520 19 it was the least to fix
our hair school is in denial of service
when we did does anyone
and you have any idea what they are has
clinton also responded ideas
okay
so
has collision denial of service when
nobody it is it was a very
popular one little bitty and the like it
affected many
are
it affected many web servers love
even Microsoft had a bad for this and
miss if my cuz I fixed it with MC 11:01
100 on also there was a
the badge for don't get fixated
like so what basically a hassle is in
denial of service when the body is
what you do is you have a Feb so
and you just bombarded with lots and
lots of Postmedia but watson also post
here
so venue set do a post the
egress what happens at these labels are
stored on the web server in a form of
untested
for the idea is to send you lots and
lots of I'll post videos
hoping that these videos will cause a
hash collisions on the vessel
and factor being on the web so it was a
very popular when we get affected all
the that sellers
so how did BSB 5131 n fix this one every
day is
then
that
Chris of Chris
you