do it believe it or not is somewhat of a
fee to get my name right
have been I've been called Chris slivers
Chris silver
all my life so thanks for getting it
right
hike or so up some shameless plug that
you'll see later
as well but I throw them out there cuz
my boss
pace for me to be here are the actual
title this talk by the way is called go
with the flow and the subtitle
was is strategies for successful social
engineering
so you'll see why I named it go with the
flow in just a little bit
I for small for those
I have not had the pleasure meeting my
name is Chris overs
my day job is I work for found stone
I do pen testing I'm also the practice
leave for our social engineering
practice
which is kinda led me to a more research
in
and interest in this area I'm aspirate
I'm I love to fish
I I love to speak publicly arm
I consider if i'm talking more than
three people that's public speaking
so he credit for that are also mentor
young people so like tonight at the
after party if you're into that
kinda thing I love yeah I'm trying to
give a claim here
mentoring I used to say messing with it
than that then really a
mentoring young mines
okay people he is wow
okay anyway I didn't realize that was ok
but anywhere
anyway whatever I I'm all about that's
one of the things that
like if you look at some of the I the
the security leaders have today
they you know the Moxie Marlins bites
and the guys are doing like the really
cool research
arm if you if you get an opportunity to
talk to these guys
art in a lotta cases you're fine that
when they were
teenagers they were hacking into stuff
they were you know dollar PBS and and
and all that stuff
and imagine had they gotten caught
interested and you know turn to a life
of crime
and we would never get to benefit from a
lot of the research that they've done
so arm so it's kinda an issue close to
my heart
that I that there are still kids out
there that are that bright
there just waiting for somebody to
mentor them and keep them outta trouble
long enough so that they can get in the
professional world and do great stuff
orange tree so anyway are but moving on
I've been in this industry for a long
time
are before I got into this industry I
actually work in the janitorial business
so it kinda proves that
that I even if you've had a previous
career you can get into security
I it's not too late to to get into the
security industry
are because things are changing so fast
that you know we're still all learning a
lot
so it's kinda cool arm probably what I'm
best known for a to people who know me
I is in the security anyway was
I in 2011 I competed in the I
Def Con 19 social engineering capture
the flag contests
really cool contest lot of fun II came
in second place
so up with which was convenient this
year I compete again but
I decided to go a little different
technique and just have some fun
are s your place for no go figure
right sometimes you get lucky I but
realistically
mmm I'm really just an old country boy
from a little town in North Georgia
called kennesaw II
wonderful and by applause who knows
about 10 assault georgette
go hey okay authorities have one and
that would be
funny but okay so we are like five
people right
so what is known about Kennesaw Georgia
gun ownership
the gun law 1982 i don't realize it been
that long
so so was I like our whatever 1980 I was
16 at the time
do the math right I'll this guy named
Garrett Meyers
is the nickname is wild man as you can
see
and he runs the civil war surplus and
herb shop
in the hounds at kennesaw yeah at
he sponsored this bill that said today
anybody who lives in the city limits
have kennesaw a must own a gun
I how crazy is that right so I'll
so use all before yes I do technical pen
testing also
but we really comes down to it I'm just
an old country boy from Kennesaw Georgia
I have leverage this really to the T and
I highly recommend
leveraging whatever characteristics you
have whatever you were born with
into a career if you can do that and and
you know pair it with what you love in
you're lucky person and you live the
life like I do because I love it
I absolutely love it so
um so this is essentially what we're
going to I
cover today hopefully I was also a run
at a time and I i King
avoid rambling on I
I want to give you a little background
how I can I created this presentation
I and then we're going to dissect a
social engineering phone call
so this is about social engineering but
it's really honed in on
telephone-based fishing I some people
call it visioning
out don't really buy that too much but
its telephone based social engineering
okay away can you guys hear me OK in the
back yeah
okay cool I are we're gonna dissect a
social engineering call
into different phases right arm an
I'm gonna give you an example love a
call now
keep in mind these calls done right and
you'll see
you'll see the the pretext in a second
done right
they take anywhere from 20 to 30 minutes
I'm not gonna play an entire call for
you cuz that would take up all the time
me give you some snippets but arm but I
think you get the point of it
so wat will go through a good call and
then we'll talk about different things
that could go wrong at different phases
of the call
and and play some recorded are examples
are those
up then we'll do something I like to
call quiz time and so
a we'll see how that goes I haven't
tried that yet
and then possibly some some call
bloopers if we still have time
alright so as I said 2011
up displayed in the social engineering
capture the flag so just over a year ago
and after the competition I really had a
good time in
and met Chris had Maggie he's a great
guy you know
if you get up to meet him take it
because he's a great guy
great to talk with and we got to talking
about
the fact that when he does his social
engineering phone calls he records all
the phone calls
well I've always been a long shot about
that you know Georgia
is a one-party state that I i kno nevada
is a two-party stay
so you have to have two-party cassette
Concetta
to record the phone calls but when he
was explaining to me was
well that's true from a person to person
call
from you know if you're calling a
consumer but if you're calling a
business
you you actually only have to have the
permission love the company
that you know the business that owns the
phone other words your client
you don't have to have each person's
individual our permission to record the
call
now I'm not a lawyer and if there's a
lawyer in the audience that wants to
refute that
feel free are but I did talk to the FF
lawyers about it because I didn't
believe him
when he said that and they said yeah
that's right I was like okay well
this work it's worth a shot arm so
every contract since that I have
you know during our little kick off call
our talk to the client
and I tell them that you know we can
record the calls for you
and will give you the recordings so when
you go back to your employees
and you're trying to explain to them how
someone scam to you
you can actually play the recording the
call phone calls
and you know it'll help educate your
place other that's a great idea
well so a couple things started
happening
as I started recording calls and then
arm
going back in listening to the
recordings I started noticing
where my mistakes were right cuz he
you hang up the phone and you think back
to that call you think gosh you know
why didn't I get that person's password
or why did I get that person's password
you use or try to remember and you you
don't really pick things up
short listen to the recording the call
in all the sudden all the little
intonations up the other person's voice
and all the
arms and hers that you said that you
didn't realize you said
come through on the recording when
you're listening to and you realize
with G it's starting to make sense as
how this works in
why I was successful or why was
unsuccessful right
so arm so that started happening in Iran
we started getting unit fails then we
started getting more
social engineering gigs especially
telephone-based
and there were times when I was unable
to
to do the work so we had to have other
consultants do it
and a lot more really not very
comfortable mean is there anybody in
here
who does telephone-based social
engineering
okay so so you know it's a little
stressful
right yet I doing here has ever done
telemarketing
okay a couple that's pretty much what
it's like
you don't still do tell marketing to you
that's why
I hate it stopped but I'm at all right
that's or what this is like it's that
stressful
and and a lot of us most of us in the
room are not all that social
to begin with so you know it stands to
reason
so so anyway so I started using these
recordings to train
other consultants just to give them an
example you know here's
here's a good call on what it sounds
like yours bad calm what it sounds like
right are while the earned time goes on
line
I and recording over a hundred phone
calls in this past year
right arm in I was sittin around 1 day 8
hours
I was you know put I was looking for
some recordings to help another
consultant
and I started actually seeing some
patterns
I'll develop within the calls that I was
making as I was listening to
right and that's kinda where I came up
with
these sections of the call the greeting
portion the building up the trust the
identifying the problem
and in the going for the gold in its
basically built of
this particular pre-tax now
this is a pretty common pre-tax it it's
very effective
I noticed it in the social engineering
caption fly contest
and essentially it's basically you
pretend to be a help desk person
you call a typical user you describe
something
in their environment that has changed
okay whether its specific or general
whatever you describe something that has
changed and that's why you're calling
and that hopefully builds up your
authority and you know your knowledge
your trust
and then at some point during the
conversation you
you're asking the the user to check on
something and there's a problem
there's something that that they tell
you
are is X and you say oh that should be
why
it doesn't really matter what arm you
know
is different theories on on how
technical should be
but at some point there will be a
problem right
and so then you move to the the truth
the troubleshooting stage where you
you're trying to determine why it is
that their system is not configured
correctly
right and that's where it really starts
getting as technical as you can
and at some point now whether you force
this
or or it's prompted by the user which is
my
my preference up at some point
somebody's going to get impatient and
you're gonna offer
a better solution how you can fix their
problem
because now that you convince them that
they have a problem that you're here to
fix
right you're the nice guy coming in and
fix it
then then you're going to use some
you know portal the you know support
portal you'll hear that a lot
in the call holes up to remotely fix
their problem
so that you don't have to you not
wasting any more their time
right and once they start feeling like
a I'm get tires phone call that's when
you're ready to
to to go in for that and then of course
whatever portal you're going into
a you can't log into it because the
there some kinda password issue where
they need to change the password
right are we do have consultants who
actually ask people
arm for their password
I'm just not a big fan of that because I
just don't think it's realistic
I think if I were an attacker and I
could just get the user to change their
password to a value that I give them
what that's going to work so much easier
and more consistently than asking them
for their password
then I might as well just do that right
are
and you'll see sometimes it you end up
in the past for anyway
so arm and if you go through all this
trouble shooting pretext
and you don't get to the point where you
feel comfortable even asking them to
change the password or whatever
you still get autumn information Adam is
well
that you can use on the next call to to
make it sound like you know a whole lot
right so it's kinda over a another way
to do
kinda reconnaissance extra
reconnaissance on right
okay so putting it visually and
this is why the talk was called go with
the flow
up because I created a little flow chart
as you can see it's a very simple
flow chart are which I'm sure could be
expanded and
you know feel free if you if you have
ideas I love to hear
but essentially go see these four phases
UHV you know the greeting
and you know did I get a good response
did the person for example did the
person when they answered
did they say their name because some
people just say hello and in some people
say hi this is Jamie
right are you know when I when I
introduced myself
did they pause when I said hi this is
Chris with the help desk
did they go a K
you nor the acting suspicious just right
from the get-go right
are and of course you know if you get a
bad response you you exit the call
now if you notice it's got one box
appear to exit the call
but that doesn't mean that you use the
same technique to exit the call
if it's during the greeting for example
you might say
I'm sorry I was trying to get in touch
with Jamie for when tears
this is Jamey Johnson I've must have the
wrong number or call somebody else
right if your way down here in ready to
go for the gold
and they say well I'm not comfortable
doing whatever it is you're asked me to
do
and you make up some other exit but the
key here is to develop
army at least one exit art
technique for each one of these phases
so that you don't get caught off guard
you know you can to it it's kinda little
give-and-take in your
you're listening for their for the
response in trying to
judge whether it positive or negative it
is negative
you go in your exit script if it's
positive you move on to the next phase
right make perfect sense right sounds
easy okay
so let's hear an example hopefully
love when it goes well yeah exactly I B
economic nafta calling okay I this is
Chris with the help desk
government disability a bolivia
I have to be a 100 hi serbian
morning getting carried on sorry I think
you got on that
elvis but on I was warning the reason
for my college years
on are you where the accounting
accounting system upgrade
I am aware at the time not going okay
good good
sir hmmm I was calling to make sure the
everything happened over over the last
few weeks about the
about the upgrade got here that and we
pushed an update last night I want to
make sure it
everything was working okay some even
temper the new bookings but
issues me you mean in terms of the new
bookings but
year routines I am the only problem that
I've run into is that after I
after I to permit them like complete and
submit them my copy haven't been popping
up
print out for my record okay
yeah me get a gift he's given me
stuff split
I don't even have to continue doing with
switch interfaces reason for that is
that the web-based interface with
yeah that would be the Internet Explorer
no okay
I know that I called and I'm had
somebody help me one time per
retrieve it just because I like to print
a copy for my own record
but what had happened was I admitted it
and I think the pop-up blocker block it
from popping up
to allow me to protect yeah that's what
i was thinkin
was probably is at what's been happening
with a bunch of people
public like that for it thanks anyway
week in phnom we can take a look at that
begin with version
the Internet is were using for me I
think it's just the thing that everybody
else is using
am this is one of my favorites sorry I
don't know exactly what version it would
be
am NOT super computer savvy I'm
by alright for items and that's what
we're here for
I'm a I were here for me I'm yeah
beaches the Internet Explorer right now
I year
on okay if you just look in the media
I'm
here me p.m. let me bring it up as well
you hear all the hype in about right I
was typing renner
yeah strenuous steel question mark
so just under their you should see
something that says
the enhanced servers McKay
okay so I've skinny a lot of space %uh
Mitchell numbers are there
K we're now getting we're digging you
know it has 10 period one period 11
okay and then there's another one right
below it because 10 period one period
here okay 22 yeah
a home in DC one is 11
you need it impunity pueden
governor has no I do not space 11 it out
2.2 that be the problem yeah that may be
part of the problem here
limits DOD I believe that a problem i
really appreciate your
your help yes sir scheme no complicated
when all I thought it would require is
like a
no more pop up blocker from way if you
think that this is helping men
okay you remember the calls been going
for like 20 okay
with your YouTube run this command on
it's our basically it's just its two
words
jam together it's system in for
upload me yeah already a cup all your
within appreciate
do in there I'm wanting can do
is is look at this
on we have this support portal
from to so just for system management
home and its kind in a pilot phase
so what I can do is just log into your
computer remotely
in pull all the rest the information in
the intro should
mom okay set whatever you need to do I
my only thing was that I just didn't
want anyone a guy didn't want the pop-up
blocker to run anymore but whatever you
think you need to do.
I yeah yeah okay so let me
let me login to the portal Broadway okay
eat your pussy your host the
scheme
and by the way I'm
unlike sit in my pajamas at home doing
this right so
yet that's what the typing noises make
it sound like aunts
the lipid no
some trouble logging in there is some
left and you
having to change a password I'm
pretty recently yeah
cuz I with this new system is if your
password expires switches
it doesn't really tell you okay if your
passport expires you end up having to
change it
before you can actually login so I say
what do you know how to change a
password
I you can i just give you my password
are sure
by ready for it
if it would be me
are so
I I think up like that alas address and
password you but you get the point
racket yeah of
I you know we make fun we lap
its it's pretty common okay it's that
you know once and really this particular
call
was was a particularly good wanna and by
the way that's one reason I put that
you know that I feel recognize that
picture from
I was a pillow talk the movie pillow
talk with the worst day in
rocket anybody old enough for that yeah
okay
of anyway yeah here
well i i wasn't there at the screening
of the movie
they here I anyway so so why did that
call work so well
okay from the from the very get-go she
she asked me how I was doing right and
it gave me the opportunity
to say well things are kinda crazy
so I get garnered a little sympathy
there you know sympathy goes so far
in social engineering to Macy's to me
it's more powerful than the whole
you know a fake authoritative kinda hey
this is the CAFO
Bob Loblaw to me said that the is more
powerful and mostly because I think it
it it gives people a good feeling when
they help you
instead of being afraid to not help you
they feel they want to help me so it
makes them feel good about it right
arm you know she with when we started
talking about the application
I knew a little bit about their
accounting system
course I didn't know about the booking
slips which worked really well
and of course you know she's been me the
information and I'm just kinda
confirming in confirming it
for her to make her feel yeah yeah
that's exactly what I'm talking about
right a lot of times people just give
you the answers are you have to do is
agree with them
right if you give them an opportunity
arm the the problem here yet
she gave me a freebie that because there
was an actual problem
but it's amazing how many times you call
a Windows
user and you ask them if they're having
a problem
many times they yeah yeah have I've had
I mean have either been meaning to call
the helpdesk or I call the helpdesk
we're all here a I i'm well
no actually I'm not playing this but I'm
another call I was on
arm one lady said I'm not having a
problem but this other ladies have a
problem
she actually transfer me to the other
lady and she gave me the help this
ticket number
and told me who she talked to at a gay
actually I just talked to him
and that's why I'm calling you know us
yep
sometimes you just get gets like that
right arm
you know making the user feel good about
about
not knowing about computers alright
avoiding making a field arm is good
right
you know I'm sure she this lady was very
knowledgeable and something
right for the business you know a lot
about computers that's okay
I probably don't know jack about what
she does so
if I make her feel okay about that
although I'm just a computer geek and
you know that's all I really know
she'll feel good about giving me all
this information if you feel okay that
she's not for me
with right arm in a course you have to
be ready to explain
anything in plain English are win
you know when you get prompted so if a
user says well what is a homie
what is dns well be able to explain to
him you know it's like a phone book
right that that your computer looks up
when you type
Google dot com in it translates these
things called IP address
be all good inpatient because the whole
point here
is is for her to get impatient not me to
get impatient
it's almost like a negotiation the first
person who gets impatient loses
right cuz I got all day you know this is
my job
right there's no big deal I got nothing
better to do it and it's kind of fun
arm and then of course and then of
course being you know
gracious win when the the victim does
give you information and
gracious that they're spending the time
with you right
making feel bad it's not definitely I
help okay
so that's a good call II so let's see
what happens when some things go
goal or I this is Amanda
I am and it is very good the IT Helpdesk
are you this morning okay hurry up
okay K yeah mainly the reason for my
call
I years are you aware the upgrade it
we're doing outlook
net no out we just recently
push down upgrade outlook and I some
other users are headed to issues with it
like Outlook crashing
on have you have you had any issues this
morning er
you I'm here this is Vernon
yes burning good okay
has your system in I'm sorry
somehow my burning year
okay my my system okay
okay I will act like I said no just
calling
I just making sure that everybody
sitting was okay
we had some users that dear outlook was
crashing a couple times
yesterday not not mine
okay we have any issues please do call
the help desk in medicine it
okay thank you okay thank you I
so that was about as eloquent and non
threatening an exit I could think about
the top right
I'm sure when you hear the recording you
think maybe that maybe I should just
hung up the phone
just click right I hate to do that I've
done it before and I hate to do that
because it kinda
makes the user little even more
suspicious right
I mean obviously a bust and I go through
this
this process if you noticed the first
call that
that I played for you I used my name
Chris
now she never asked my last name I'm
pretty sure on that engagement
I didn't know a person named Kristen I T
so I probably would have said silvers
and she asked me my last name
arm but you know it's always kinda
a balancing act whether to spoof an
actual
employees or not right are you'll see
some these calls
at if you do it right and you've done
another reconnaissance arm to know
to can get an idea of who knows who in
the organization
then spoofing a name is perfect but
like in that case if he didn't do enough
then you didn't realize that the person
you're calling
might be sitting right next to the
person you're faking to be
I've had that happen the let the lady
said no this is not johnnie
I'm sitting next to Johnny and he's not
on the phone you
yeah a yep
yeah I think that was battles the one
time when I just click I got nothin
you know F so I I'll
but the thing is I've had actually work
really well for me one time
and that's why I put down here professor
corn blossom
because I I was doing reconnaissance and
this was obviously a a university that I
was calling on
and arm now the this scenario was a low
flipped
I was pretending to be a user and I was
calling the helpdesk
and I was basically trying to get them
to go out to our website you know
credential harvesting can I think arm
and
I wanted to pretend to be one of the
professors
well when I look at the the faculty list
and I wish I was going down through it
all sink in we'll you know who cannot
spoof
well this university was up North
and obviously I have a bit of trouble
talking like come from anywhere but
Atlanta Georgia so are I had to find
professor who maybe was from the south
took a little digging I found this guy
arm Hughes his last name was cornball
awesome
believe it up so I call and I get the
gala phone
and he's like yet can I help you not see
the this is professor corn blossom I'm
having some trouble blah blah blah
and the gap ozzie where really
and I thought how this is going to be
sweet I said
really work he said your name is really
professor corn lost
a pause a little bit I said look it up
also not here attacked at that I'm sorry
professor how can I help you
in
come play theory
don't try to scam a scammer Friday yeah
give me a little credit alright so yet
so they're calling it is going great
I mean I got all kinda shit in fact he
was the guy that
that but once he logged into the site I
had him
taking his his phone going over to other
people and having them log into the site
as well
right so yeah it was like a three for it
was also yet
goodnight straight up taking off early
today yet
iight so let's here another example here
ok he can you tell me your name again
my name yeah yeah wat
late that
and lead okay who do you work for
or let it. future must
I'm sorry say that again
hoosier who's your boss my boss is Gary
lead you can hear my stall looking I
okay remind people named in a recognized
well
i mean i i work up here and I don't
think Paul
%uh euthanasia or your word
I were just dance and poker six months
as well to joy
I know some folks up there okay so
you probably know gary has been there
forever right not donna@here
okay I'm gonna pick up to
for preview course you have about David
I left brain and today she
okay area the headline here
there well I mean data manager
I'm not sure who is like to use them as
a director or something
share only sure this is also serve a
phishing attempt or anything like that
okay well you know I'm just like AIG
growing me and I you know they don't the
me relate they don't down
you know I don't get invited to like the
board meetings or anything
help a neither do I its
yes yeah he's got tough
hit yeah
serving out there's from run let you
know you know
he'd like the security at is painful and
I am somewhere you okay good
I at a it was painful when I did it
it's painful listening to it right
because I'm just trying to backpedal on
the sly I
somehow I gotta get out this call right
so
arm you know in in actually with my
stall techniques
I had an org chart alright Lisa hedda
unemployed list
and I was feverishly trying to find it
interest right have fun and games in
crap amis like to easily
so arm so so this goes to building trust
I mean you know
when the guy answered the phone he was
nice enough but when I started telling
what I needed all the sudden he just
turned into this
you know interrogator right are as far
as who I knew in who I was and
you know like like you heard you know is
this a fishing attempt to write
so arm so sometimes
you know there's just no shortcut for
thorough
reconnaissance right you you really have
to know what you doing so
by the way just a quick side note arm
for the parent company
Mac for ya know ya know doug is talking
it Focusrite
here okay it was really really
let's just ask me how can I help you I
certainly how are you
get every new I'm good thanks they are
Stephanie are you 00 where
SuccessFactors upgrade that we've been
pushing out this is Brad from it. in the
Inglewood offer
on so our users are reporting problems
and i was just wondering if you're
having any
I am for which system
are for 6 SuccessFactors
are you SuccessFactors user you know
what I don't
think K we r I
marine let me transfer your virtual
feels like you believe that
system which i think actually are sure
yet great president of
just a moment so so in most situations
getting transfers bad thing
by the way sometimes it works out okay
especially if there's
a if you prompted if you say oh
everything's fine with you
could you transfer me or if they say oh
well somebody else has a problem
those companies in most cases though
transfers are not good because you're
not ready
for that new target you've done your
econ on the target your calling
you know about them you have no clue
about who you're about to talk to so
the the lesson here really is in the
building trust pays when you're
talking about the their application they
got upgraded Bob Loblaw
you need to know that environment and if
you catch one
that it's just not applicability down to
them
then you're stuck and there again use or
to get into that balancing act between
talking about some general peace love
application that they use light out
worker Internet Explorer
versus something specific like you know
maybe they call something cop net
or something like that right in the more
specific
usually works out better but you never
you never can tell
I so the last one the last kinda one
that let me know if you have a few
minutes
with are let's check your
your service pack while so this is like
a minute I'm about to go into a meeting
here at nine o'clock
is there a way we can do this different
time home
actually backing track to on going to
our
new remote portal on me
let me see here would you know how you
have no your workstation name:
no I don't okay with me having fun with
your
login ID the in
yeah I'm getting access denied at in the
last time you change your password
it has been long yep yet okay
that's probably the problem so actually
work real quick
we walking through on change a password
required Indian
hacking getting remotely and you can get
your meeting
so you just doing what we need I I'm a
little leery of all this at this point
still there when a if you're here on
site you can come to my office and we
can work through it
on it yeah I think I can probably come
by later today
ok I are you available maybe a
late this afternoon three four o'clock
sure
so fortunately she gave me an exit right
I'll be there sometime you this way
I out but you can a tell-all which she
was already starting ill suspicious
right and a and a lot of it is just I
got impatient
right I am patient whether what I should
have done at some point which is kinda
cut my losses
right when I started syncing her getting
all suspicious assisted okay well
I understand you gotta go to a meeting
out you know all you to give you a call
back or
you know we'll work it out right and
just kinda left it there
that you know be in me ass I have a
tendency to
push sometimes gets me in trouble
okay so arm
I so here's a little experiment and arm
I'm not sure how exactly this is gonna
go but I
if everyone's been awaken paying
attention will we'll see how this
happened so what I want to do is I wanna
play
a clip love up kinda
early in a social engineering call and
then we're gonna see
by by applause whether you think the
call ended up going well
are not so well from the perspective of
the tester
okay right so another word that you know
did I come out I'll I don't remember
what the first one is but anyway
up was I successful or without
unsuccessful
yeah was highly or did I get married if
cocaine in a click on it running in that
brings up a little window
I the has like this little white area
near
in the white area I can these three
letters
the am d I Charlie Mary day
char name marion was David
like PG&E okay right
and then click on OK
okay I think they know that my darling
the info when she normally
no get access to my computer to do this
do I do well actually I can careless
home well actually %um let me see if I
can do that with the
for remote for real quick
yeah out your I don't wanna wasting your
time me on
on just a sec here here
you know he
you
okay I think that's it so I
was it successful I clap no a while
okay obviously I was not successful was
that
go ahead clapping think I was not
successful wonderful
yes it was a bit maybe because you're
your password scale
I'll tell you what if you don't mind
this plan to change a password will play
yeah I'm gonna pass on this time I yet
yeah this if not a wet a lot of it was
that if our cast
hi Monica this is Chris the helpdesk
Karimi
good how are you a K I'm missus I'm
assuming
you're aware of all the accounting
system upgrade that we get rid
your fam okay good were you aware that
some users were having some issues with
the
the web-based interface on the looking
for
are no while you're talking about like
that
a new accounting system yes yeah I think
he sent an email
okay yeah yeah we did in and
I don't know if you got the notice that
we did some system upgrades last night
began it a cure that problem okay now
fight rescue yeah I'm
I was just a calling to kind of follow
up on a system upgrade
I'm how's your workstation running
today's so far so good I haven't had any
issues
aka
okay and down like I said I'm just
calling to kinda Checa
I do you know but just a can check to
make sure the upgrade work right
how I CI you know I haven't really
noticed anything different everything
was working fine so I
him at all fuck he
well let's hope so on enough if you have
a second I just wanted to check a couple
things on your system
just sure that everything went smoothly
okay
but that they are
okay I think that's it what do you think
K
yeah you think a successful okay yaa
got her got a pretty good Scott
I'm
Monica win one thing we notice about
this is this new support for all
is some if the user has changed your
password in 10
first time you change your password tall
grass in a week now because we just
upgraded many told me that he made me
change my password
and scam script someone was there before
me nervous system maybe a little
I'm okay would you know it well
obviously know how to change a password
yeah idea yet humana list lessen your
temporary password okay so I can get in
there
on going go to the screen you know the
control
early hmm the password change Anna
and putting your password Indian
arm change your password to Monday
2011 okay
okay make sure that matches and then
click OK
aka okay me yeah
only takes a minute to synchronize out
her and
now when you still Monday you you did
all lower and lower K
yeah Lee and just you know they're kinda
picky re
know I know I am yeah all our cases
hold on just a second let me there from
missing
here okay
yes yes okay good year that came ACA
you didn't notice a thing right now okay
good
okay good I'll take a look at that
monica in
fuckin if I can upgrade the drivers on
that on its can turn off target with
Jason
and catch up with him okay well already
are cool okay thanks a lot Monica and no
problem you have good afternoon
you do you think already okay to back
that that particular call are a few
pick up on this I said something about
loading drivers for the printer
and get in touch with Jason she had
dropped
issued said that she talked to Jason the
week before in the header
reset your password or whatever are a
and when I asked her if she was having
some problems she said I'm not having
problems with this but I'm have some
other problems
with my printer right I've had actually
had the occasion to actually fix the
person's printer before
during these calls are it
in this case I could because she was
missing a driver a home
you know and and yeah I didn't want to
walk all the way through
going out the HP and downloading the
drivers anything but arm
but yes so you'd run into these kinda
things Ryan
in she was thanking me at the into the
car was like yeah everybody wins right
ever I feels good yet so good call their
alright so for him to come and go the No
here
what is your friend been is I'm
in it. down your debt Chris just wanna
make sure who s talking to
thank you people had to look you up on
are aware of this stuff sore service
part of yet
the on it's the its at Port all-time ATP
dot com
haha I've used it
okay why he is it recently I don't think
so
alright I think that's about it hero or
zero is yelling air
yea right
are she puts me on hold
I'm sorry my home I have to define and
get out what I'm doing can I call you
right back
no that's okay I like I said we've got a
whole list for people to call
on Alka if you don't have time I can I
think awesome idea
okay thank you now no doubt there's
technical ways
you know to do all the phone looping and
all that stuff for the call back but
that's a big hassle I usually don't get
that so it's really not worth it but
that's one defense by the way when
you're talking your users
just ask the person asked to call the
person back right
and then hang up look up there for
if they give your phone number ignore it
look at the real extension
or call the help desk and say hey I was
just talking to so-and-so
can you transfer me to or whatever right
nine times are 10 that's gonna for
most phone phishing attempts
really if you just year well first I'll
put on hold
while you look up stuff because that
makes them nervous I know it makes me
nervous
because I have no clue what they're too
and while I'm on all
way I think this is the last quiz here
you guys are spot on if it plays
okay maybe some technical difficulty
yep apparently yes
it was good alright will call so we have
a little bit I'm here
yeah at waterfall go israeli we carved
out some extra time good
for some bloopers I hate a home
and by the way that outta I think later
they got
a house on the in the Hamptons or
something II
up for doing it so what is
saying now kid the
too long miss it he says is password
supplied does not meet them
on minimum complexity requirements place
like another pass for that meet or the
following criteria:
nearly seven characters has not been
used in the previous 12 months Talk
password
must have been changed within last 30
days lol maybe it was a state is a
changed it
a that's what it is okay their policy
was getting in the way
me check surpassed okay
so in in usage occurred asterisk the
might make a run
yes CA SS
I E 22
20 aswell I Mitchell artist
I'll to scrub shown here okay okay okay
so on I'm just going to use the remote
a main portal and are gathered the rest
the information
and and get that 60
so you know the wrenches you're in pain
yet
the same ol crap here's another good one
only
he said the two you just change your
password on Friday right
yes yeah okay
it's on just had for knit cap like p
and a and now the LRT
05 taking fair here
so if crappy password and 0 for
yessir okay for yeah let me try their
it up yeah the because my mayor faces
using your old password that's what was
the problem
only yeah I was the yeah yeah
that out there always reminds me that
old Seinfeld episode where
when Kramer was people get confused
between him and the movie theater in
any and and he was trying to act like an
automated attendant and then finally
goes
why don't you just tell me what movie
cool 14 at
here if no I don't you just tell me your
okay
cool yet iight so that's all I got
here
are ob obvious shameless plugs appears
if I have any questions why we got
five minutes or I don't week from the
fountain account but
I want to the found some guys does and
sometimes he the reach weeks what r
to or sometimes I email him and he tweet
stuff
yes here the front you think
yep I'm just more successful with I
don't know what it is
out of its a a guy/girl thing I
yeah I think the southern voice
yes a definitely physical when I do bud
yeah I'll leave it at that yeah your
question
welfare toma de absolutely makes a
difference in this is from those have
you done telemarketing
when's the best time to call I mean okay
at home
it's dinner but if you were calling
professional people
you call in the morning morning local
time people in much better mood
you know they're ready to talking give
you all can information yes
from the back out day in the week
arm I don't outta I'm not really found a
lot a difference
are I mean I would probably do
Tuesday through Thursday just because
your
you'll be able to contact people a lot
of times like customers all say
I want you to call 10 people and always
have to clarify that
you want me to make ten phone calls are
you want me to actually talk to 10
people
because if I'm gonna talk to 10 people
you need it or I need to come up with a
list
up at least 40 people because it
typically takes
for phone calls to get in touch with one
person
you know normal business environment
right okay I think we had one other
question over here
up I'm sorry success rate overall
arm I haven't really done the hard
statistics but
and and there's a question UHV you know
if I make it halfway through the call
and I get all this great information but
they don't
reset your password is that considered
success or failure
so but I would say it's gotta be
it's got to be in the nineties year I i
mean
year pretty easily here yes
yes force have people react to the
southern thing arm
its single enough I used to be a little
intimidated when I would call somebody
in New York thinking you know they're
just gonna
but actually actually I think it works
better
when I call people who were in the north
versus the south
and in fact they had one play D who I
just got back from Derby Conn
when I was making this call and she
she was somewhere Midwest and she
and I was pretending to be somebody in
California right
and she picked up on it she said wait a
minute you said you
your cone from the California Office you
don't sound californian
acid really what do I sound like she
said well you sound like you're from the
south
acid that's uncanny yeah I'm actually in
from the south I just moved out here
she say she said I'm really good with
accents acid
are really where do you think I'm France
he said Kentucky
you I said we'll all be
from Kentucky specifically local
cuz I was just a little as we a so she
starsight she said well I'm from
Louisville real out really have you been
to so-and-so
whatever Bart was we you know we're at
night you know
and we start on outlaw and from that
point on she just she was just totally
use mine I'm making yet we we were yeah
we we were we were buddies
yet are so well
yeah
arm yes sums I me we have consulted to
will say I feel bad cuz I felt like I
just scanned my grandmother right
arm n enya sometimes
but but the point of the exercise is to
make the organization
you know more secure and hopefully
I can't I can't I mean I don't know the
100 calls and I made I don't know if
those people
got reprimanded or fired or whatever I
mean I don't hang around but
I do consult with the client that to
explain to them this is an education
process it's not this is not something
for disciplinary action right especially
if it's like the first
time this person has been tested you
know if they just really yr
bad okay maybe or or you know whatever
but
the purpose of this is educational us
are we at a time I'm
yeah I don't I'm sorry thank thank you
all appreciate here