alright everybody we're gonna get
started here I'm
welcomed for serial killer this is
packed the clout I'll Adam UAE
in the you take away and okay
I sure hands who's actually awake this
morning okay that's all
that's way more than I expected as me
not so much unlike
three hours ahead in my local time zone:
two hours sleep last night
day and for an interesting ride this
morning sales does
okay so we're in this year or killer
track which
is just awesome to me right a hack the
clout as a return to look loud security
today
and I was going to smoke warning intro
is your killer sandwich hack the planet
replace a cloud in sight I'm not that
creative I can figure that one out so
was gonna skip that whole part and kinda
jump into it so
how many people for some work again idea
of who's in the room cuz I liked it a
lot things going
really of the coffin of my presentation
so how many people here or
you know enterprises are you know some
kinda company and you're struggling with
securing cloud resources and services
okay couple how many view
here are penned testers whatever in your
job is to go
assess cloud services a couple more
wire the rest if you hear seriously I
was like two percent of all love you
up so feedback on the cover during the
presentation
yell our questions insult me Tamron
yogurt
it's all fine okay was make this very
interactive specially this early in the
morning can you hear me
that's better I C that's what we need
lotsa feedback alright
I so quick disclaimer so when I first
I was asking this presentation I was the
CISO
of parochial Salesforce I was a CISO all
a cloud service provider tenneco's
really a caso
although report up to me but that was my
title so
when I first were are was scheduled come
get this presentation
I was a hundred and biased right I was
gonna come %uh took the company line
cloud is safe we love the cloud all of
that
since then I've left Salesforce I can
say whatever the hell I want now
so you ask me I will to hell you I have
no problems with it
so yet that is great for you guys here
is my shameless plug this is the only
say most part I think in the entire
presentation
i've a new company box security we are
hiring
those positions on hiring if you you
know what a job if you wanna talk it be
known about the job referral fee
that's what I'm looking for right now
really we're hiring
me just make sure this is very clear
we're still hiring there's a lot of the
perks right that we have its
really cool stuff okay I so now Wireless
enemy
this is basically the hey look at me
this is why I am up your own states like
right
and so this is why I'm qualified to talk
about clout in security and whatever
had been in this game really really long
time how many people were around for
these
me you know all these acronyms yes I
thought government if your heart
so back in 99 I started my career well
size fits all civil government before
that 99 it for my corporate career
at for coming up TRX we launched on
that travel management systems city we
lost Expedia we lost orbits are part of
orbits
we were a SASE before existed right but
back then we call it ASP
application %uh solution provider and
then
well that was bad nobody like that so
we're OST were outsource
also also sounds better some reason
right are crap and that was about a
couple years later so we are hosted
solution provider right
is all markings the same technology same
terms everything
sass on as does the ass
yeah an impasse okay much much later
sorry
been it's about ninety nine unbeaten
security companies in dealing with
clout right I sino la tobacconist have a
lot of acronyms
is unfortunate Sunday's depend on the
conversations you follow on Twitter
but it is what it I so first before we
really getting
let's talk about clout what is clout how
we define clout
if you read articles about cloudy
talking about clout such a character
nobody knows what it means is like a
cloud is indigo
our easy to where your client Salesforce
o'clock go
you know what is a so we'll talk a
little more clout first and then we'll
start dive in and and see where we go
so first have a car we have the lowest
level right is
Infrastructure as a Service
infrastructure services you're bringing
hardware
or rainy instances a run on hardware so
this is like Iraq spaces
easy to use stuff like that how many
people employ some kind of a system like
this
in there I enterprise right now sick
not many surprising usually you wanna
talk to people that much much higher
they're all kinda moving to augmenting
their
their infrastructure was some kind of
all are rented hardware
then if you move up the stack one level
you have Platform as a Service
prices were her Roku rain right so when
I was a sales force
division Iran was a Roku and so this is
where we're at. so we basically
ran the on you allocate a little down
so our application services right so the
web services databases whatever
you are you go to our platform granite
hopefully it will hurt
sometimes it didn't but completed and
you know we took everything else
and then if you go up a level you have a
most people will call clout right so
sassy
when moved to clout mostly thinks that's
right this is a
it's a service as an application out
there I'm gonna go use it and
hopefully everything's gonna be good
where is this is your workdays your
Salesforce is your
you know whatever's right so how many
people are using some sort of sacks
in their environment okay almost there
right how many people are using
something like a pass
a Roku I Google a
App Engine whatever's calls it like that
okay
like two or three okay balance still
very interesting not he was moved out
model yet K that's the really dangerous
mark as you can see for yourself
alright so then white really happens is
what you look at all these you realize
that this is really work loudest
cloud is always really combination of
services I it's a stacking up services
so community assessment or somebody uses
right now
really any right always your answer use
aspin there's no way as an example
type box box
okay so her summers a box I think I
don't have on thoughts go with that
you a month so if you look at box right
in your call to your website you look at
you know where their porn images from
where they're storing things
you realize boxes accommodation services
go to Salesforce
your workday go to any these guys you
realize their combination services
their stories stuff on easy to other
store stuff on Amazon's s3
using Rackspace's occupy using all these
other services to come together to bring
one big service that they didn't give
you
such companies and services so cloud is
really a service effects
right it's a bunch of things and the
sting stack up
to be the clout that you think that the
service for and that you don't have to
audit
and deal with right very simple right
and so the Wii
once we understand that there's a a
stack of things right there's a
as all the things that go into it and we
understand the types the cloud services
they're out there
we can start on what a reserve risk I
see you have the infrastructure stuff
if researchers the lowest level they
don't build an application for you
there are running a website right it's
your application is offenders
application whomever
in so what you really concerned at this
level is was the security of the
hardware the fertilizers are given the
other people are there internal security
policies
and that's what you have to deal with
when you talk to these guys now if you
go up the stack to somebody like
I have a Roku and you look at the pass
now they provide you an OS
they're providing you the II you know
web server configurations
the Friday the database now you have to
worry about that level security and yet
to start
auditing now I so as you go up the stack
gets more complicated
then you two sacks and sass now is where
most people are used to auditing
most who are used to thinking about
clout
so they're like oh the process for teens
in the second actions in the whatever's
in the world this is where they start to
think
right it so as you move up the stack
have to worry about different security
levels
but in the day really to think about all
a bit because
its just you know a service of things
so how many people right now our
auditing cloud vendors
as it is my number people same wanna
love you okay shame
so arm let me ask somebody if he doesn't
mind sane
and we'll try to actually come for the
real thing but this time %uh someone
who's not
auditing their clout our staff and urs
can't we shout out why they're not doing
that right now
axle love that answer somebody else is
doing it that's the best kind of work
right there was somebody else does okay
anybody who's just is not getting done
it all on a shout out why
general I think if I was gonna go for
answer that question okay in
alright so I when we start talking about
cloud security and we start our audience
and you know what the security problems
are and how we're gonna break in the
clouds
you know we there's a couple things we
have to think about first in the first
thing is we have to think differently
right we on a cloud we gotta look at a
cloud service
the technology is the same stuff we've
always say
car is not new it's not unique spin
around for a very long time that's why I
started this presentation my story out
back in 1999 I was doing clap
right it's been around a long time all
the technology stack has been around to
go look at parochial
Salesforce I'm when its sovereign
systems
post press database run for Nash are run
Apache
but always different you know services
all stuff that you've seen everywhere
else
but that differences that somebody else
managing its bottle differently
its integrated with the budget other
services is to think differently about
it when you look at it in your approach
it
right but the technology is all the same
so the first thing i would tell people
here's my go out or a mistake if you
should ever second
is accept the transfer risk whenever
you're looking at a car servicing like
oh I want to use this call service but
you know the security and a concern in
in all this
you have to let go either we can be
control freak if to step back a bit and
say
oh well somebody else's managing this
campaign them to manage this
I have to realize that I'm gonna give up
something I might give us some control
just like if you're a vendor any kind
event if you're selling a product
service on a service whatever
to another company they're giving up
control for you how eager consultants
okay smallmouth okay so consoles know
that's right consoles coming to an
organization and they say oh we need to
do this when you do that whatever
and the internal IT guy insurance
carriers info
like this is my thing is what I do you
know why why mess in my playground right
and the songs like one here to help
right and there's always love or not
always but many times is little friction
right
same happens in clout got a step back in
africa is OK
was not the you know vendor manager
security and do what they did
and it always work out a little bit
better and then
the next thing to think about is that
once we get over that we have to say oh
not all vendors are the same how many
have you have security audit checklist
that you send your vendors
I wanna was more than than that I know
because I've been on the other
I've been on this idea too many times I
know that at least 75 percent of you in
your
have some questionnaire that you sent to
vendors there's like 300 questions
in Excel has absolutely nothing to do
with what your auditing but that's what
you're gonna send them to piss them off
anyway
you all know that alright have been on
the site way too many times
so don't be that guy I so the big not
parse
to him think ever is when when I work
for these vendors
and I get this questionnaire Scott 11
tabs in Excel's way too damn big
got 11 tabs three hundred questions per
tab in the light answer all these
questions on my
n/an/an/an/a and then i get some email
back from a risk analyst don't
you are not allowed to answer these and
a well
they're not help but to me tell you I
course make sure all day long whatever
care finance if you are whatever right
it don't be that guy I think about it
before you do this right
I'm getting you to walk through it when
you when you order the services you need
to think about it
in rationalize the rest musical with the
risk each services so that when you go
in there you say okay
on a threat model the shower quick are
and say okay
here's the restore it to my business and
we go enormous asset from heart this
urge you know
on asylum tempor nec checklist whatever
is
but it needs to be relevant so you know
to come in and ask a thousand questions
%uh PCI for something had nothing to do
with that
don't ask a thousand things out windows
on is all an action or whatever
this is the biggest thing that holds
many organizations backing clough
is that they send these ridiculous check
with something all the field checklist
well the problem was that the security
defender the promise that im checklist
in the first place
okay you know that much less RAM II have
to get out ahead
checklist paid and and I'm response for
bill have the same thing so
I it I think full
I so next thing is we move into know
thyself right so now that we understand
that we must think differently
and we must approach differently we have
to kinda start to think about ourselves
what we trying to get
out of our security program what
actually matters to us what do we have
to dress in the cloud right
and so with to develop our security
baseline we have to say
you know these are things that we care
about these are things that we're trying
to achieve these are things that we're
gonna make our vendors achieving this is
how we're gonna
approach it now if you go look at like
our class security alliance in
Co other random organizations out there
trying to do stuff trying to help with
this from a bill that based on a bridge
that gap between
traditional okay here's our new standard
in whatever reason enterprising
hearsay kinda Taylor the wording on the
presentation and everything to the cloud
services
is too young right Werner infancia that
by it
you know we're making strides their
again technology has a change Weezy
change our mindset how we approach it
and so as we figure that part out then
we understand the different kinds of
services what we just talked about
it's only going to assess something we
go okay what kind of service so we
actually assessing
why do worse assess that's why was it
Roku we're platform as a service right
so platforms as service we ran the stack
you going to put your code
numerous organizations daily would call
me and say
hey we got to a single injection Marco
moderate damn thing was going to echo
what do you do it
they were so surprised the streets like
whoa whoa whoa whoa what up her office
clout
you know protection from suggestion now
you protect yourself
probably not scheduling for me to do it
I write the code was in my coat a
manager was there code right but they
had no concept of what they were looking
at night
I had 18 come in and do a are secure
right came and they did the are in the
paper star from whatever rise doctors
find a row
the broader Ely and testers and the
Pentastar stop ago
out ya to write the code you ownership
to write the code work
far as a Service as great monies film
and cater for the client right
so understand the service that you guys
are looking at before you get there are
ways we sponsor money in
one feels timing you know I know if I
can remain but well you would have known
works are not there but
you would've are in so you know this is
still like the largest ball that I see
right here
understanding really is at rest and who
owns what
it seems to be very confusing for many
companies these days and we as in
diffusing get better
communication around that I think on and
then I again we talk about the
acceptance transfer rest I put on here
twice because still a really really big
thing
we are for we're are control freaks by
nature in this industry right which
hey we need to be I'm been as
interesting fifteen years and
I'm different control freak an essay but
works for me
a home but we have to step back we're
talking about cloud how certain vendors
and partners
to step back a little bit which is hard
to do rikers our security is our baby
and that's what we do and we love it as
a job in
of it goes upside down with plenty of
iron out the details so
but we have to learn to do that I so now
we move into this doesn't faze
ones were us are talking about how on
the security I love it my goal of
coughing presentation here
and this is where I want your feedback
this is where I want to go to store
shelves now thanks ago
hey i'm looking at vendor XYZ and what
should I look for or
hey I have this concern are hey what's
the biggest
insecure thing you know about me cloud
services whatever as we've got social
things out
and let's awake the recipe was mike is
this guy was your sleep in
its leader either arm %um Cisco the
assessment phase that area as he woke up
welcome hey I know this morning I could
I
okay so the first thing on assessments I
am DXR
um so first thing on assessments you not
getting everything for eight dollars a
month
I so there's a CEO of this cloud
provider
and when I used to write for
InformationWeek part-time
do interview with them and I'm like a
what if I wanna come in I wanna says
your service
he owes sure because I get these
documents or send you whatever you're on
a pen task whatever
have fun I don't care okay we focus your
data center with a touching staffer
phone look two-year
you know everybody's against do him
eight dollars a month
yes of as lovely what he said to me it
was like I personally got balls
second all you're right I think that was
a month how much security to every
dollars a month
not very much for me now very much so
quick
so yeah I you know it Eagles Michael
expect everything
right so look at the kind of service and
if it's like eight dollars a month don't
expect that likes me super badass
security
unless the company is very progressive
and you know
whatever it is I'm awesome security in
like like the guys a box like another
secure got a box like they're really
awesome there's a lot of shit to do for
you
for the 15 or so dollars a month they
charge per user
there's a limit right sort of remember
that accidents things work with the
provider
how many have you have ever truly try to
work where
I an external provider like us ass your
cloud vendor whatever
on their security to truly understand
you know what they have
and give them feedback as well every
okay and every given a feedback to be
like hey this is what I would like to
see the light
non-confrontational like hey I wanna
talk to you
it was gonna cells was a X says I went
off a nose for
well cells or cells was also on of
now so those guys ago so with so this is
a great case
most people I talk to most people that
came to me we're like
oh my god I'm big enterprise and here's
why security checklist and we're gonna
run up on a bill to suspend or gonna
tell you how your security is knowledge
might
go whatever as they come back in like we
should do this business on right now
might but they never want to have a
conversation or dictate to me
my do my service I run service your
customers you can talk of tumors or your
customer customers they
they want the service kinda Trump you
here
I can provide me with what they want
like SB ensemble I'm the business
they want this so dictating to me
probably not really gonna work so much
but
having a conversation with me and saying
hey how about this or could we do this
are
help us to understand this I had any
tire guy on my team
senior principal engineer dedicated
to go talk to customers just for cool
shit just it was the senior
where r senior principal security
engineer caution i think is what we are
surprised his car
you would literally just go out and talk
to customers and cuss words like
yeah we'll really lights up your back
all over locks
cool what does that look like you want
to syslog what you want you know this
cuz
one cuz was a no really what we want is
wanna be able to run
agent on our side to subscribe to a
queue on your side parts at all so we
get real time we don't open the firewall
all this
right call for five days later is in
production
right had eight senior principal
security engineer cool shit like it was
an awesome job I wanted it cuz
he had your paperwork that I had to do
those quiet nights so ima
work with your vendors like most will
never try to actually really work with
the vendor so these guys they went out
the door to Salesforce were hit by nine
know what they told you
I know the exact story exacted on the
other side that comes in
as ellsworth so I know exactly what they
said their kinda exxon I want on
but now and plan to sell source spy now
on
so who is to work with your vendor most
is cloud vendors
a really open if you approach them in a
like
collaborative manner and don't try to
position as
hey I'm big enterprise ihe on the
customer if you
his work with us to hear some quality
shit I want most the security teams
will talk to you and it's very very easy
a smaller vendors to more defensive
because marketplace second sucks and
when you have those conversations
community intent not implementation when
somebody would come to me a climb come
to me and say
hey you have to implement this you have
to use have been what I'm gonna say
you have to implement these firewalls
and here's our standard was lighted
I mean the clout how you gon ASA in the
cloud warheit
he do that that's an amazing feat Cisco
I there from you
from like think it doesn't work and they
could not grasp is like what you have to
stop essays
Mike when you're white missed holiday
this
a sure whatever me the cut if the
context pick it up I will go by serving
as a system a days and I can't do
anything but
whatever out do that whatever you want
it
the problem was they were trying to tell
me the actual implementation how they
did it not be in 10 what they want if
you talk in 10
you realize Rd added right I really was
doing all that
so I had another customer call me and
talking about web application security
and he tried to tell me about to go into
action bodies were about that as I can
and I was explained what we do and how
we're not vulnerable and and all this
kind of thing
and he could not grasp it because we
didn't do things the quote-unquote
traditional way
and what what he did tell me that I did
not understand sequence action
fast forward right now the guy who
discovers ago injection
heads up my research team at my new
company I
understands you go into action inside an
hour it's not a new concept like
I get this but go back for months and
there's a guy tell me that I have no
cost for this because my
implementation was different than hits
right that is so damn annoying
so work with your vendor and communicate
that intent
as you're going through it cuz it'll
help you tell your assessment as well
to understand how did they implement
things what are they doing
where you really need a threat model
their business and how do you really
focus on are the true security there II
you know hour from architecture
everything else so
where to start art so as we want to hear
from you guys cum targets of rights
early only got it now
I get so as you guys use in talking as
well so if you're already being
you know are going to do contest
security whatever other cloud service be
at Sasa whatever
where do you start really
that's a key on me this morning now
remedial him in you Voice sup
always read the damn annual everything
doesn't matter what you assess this
dollars rule
I'm if you can't ask for help and just
background okay thanks a lot when we got
our
okay so when I see you can testing right
ISO is that a
other presentations at some work on if
we're going to some work on
now okay RORO tell him it was like is my
first trip in the west by the way I'm
enjoying it quite
quite quite a bit I discover the thing
last nickel Bob Evans
its can also
I was like who the fuck is Bob Evans
once they have so many places might
whatever this is awesome so on I'm
enjoying my trip to the Midwest as for
so it %uh summer Khan is a drunken
conference right
some con- 2002 didn't happen because
everybody was so hungover
the entire conference got cancelled the
next day true story
I was there a Foxworth conference O'Shea
okay
everybody's holler it technically
started around 6:30
the I day there's a start in the bar and
just uses continuation treatment I for
is really bad
it us for a couple years later I'm at
this conference in watching this guy's
some work on maybe
RT on seven Atlanta and he's on stage
any is literally drinking at a four
beers at one time
and people are throwing shoes I don't
know
I don't understand why I was there the
entire day it was not like
on the agenda throw shoes now I like I
don't know shoes to start off line
what guy said it was really interesting
to me right
he was talking about whether application
security he's got a huge bag I know if
you guys know well guess you're the
the speakers Billy of it and so Billy is
a thirties talkin and he saying okay
where do you start menu assess whether
occasion people are like
oh you scan it you spider you do all
these things just
now you read the fucking manual first
he's like you forget what this offer is
what it does the mangled normally tell
you the most
love what you need right off the bat so
do you understand the application to
find all the weak points
clough services in the same thing they
have about pages there FAQ's
Health Bureau kubrick wasn't hired
developer section on the website
that he talks about the code however
ron's all this
you either get her page there's all
kinds open source projects that actually
run
in production it's like your road map
for hacking them right there
the most awesome thing ever now course
from my role when I was it was not lost
on
because I have this platform that
anybody can write ha style code:
uploaded to apply for execute a platform
like me
thank you just attacking from within my
platform also
about but two weeks into that job of
held I take this job okay so it's the
reader may not but not only do you read
the manual you read the menu of all the
things
right so if your gonna go when you gonna
track when the services are you gonna
try to pen testing to audit you okay
only to look at the whole ok apply for
what is Oracle user group uses
a.w.s services members on ec2 s3 all
these things 00 uses ready to go
all use the same grid is always our
services I so now I'm gonna start a
manpower and say
oath here's all the touch points here is
everything it uses
utilizes Michael read all the manuals on
Nos to fully understand what they do how
they integrate and start to find my
weaknesses
this is the week is the cloud services
cloud services almost like really code
for saw any redevelopment here
actually revolver sock I
so the problem for developers are
they don't write anything new and okay I
voy a team Ruby developers and I given
this shit all the time
because I supporting a Java developers
as I love the subtle Java really works
quite interesting for me to watch in the
day my skype chat so it's fine
for me so much for them but it if you
look at the review world right
in the rupee world nobody really writes
new stuff everybody built upon other
people stuff
so I what you talkin to me is coated a
and i'm looking at this
are so Klein right to make a calls to
the south so papi
yeah when I actually got down to the bar
which is noblest cellblock
I'd go through three a TCP
implementations to get there it was so
quiet
on supplement ACP client what up in a
steep decline on top of the native Ruby
issue because i dont have open SSL
that's a cloud services or crap like
Rubicon on swype
so but that's ok cause services or their
hot spot in the stack up a budget thanks
so if you wanna find the weaknesses and
you wanna know where to attack
you just figure out what in this month's
service is comprised of
and you start picking off pieces my same
as if you're auditing
you try to find the rest of the class
service June with the biggest risk
is not the vendor your actually talking
to if the vendors willing to sell to you
is an enterprise
they thought about security it was up 12
in the back room the keychain to the
task to answer security questions as
least that guy right
but what your real risk is is what
services they use a solicitor class
service
and they're using messaging system a
queuing system recovery because these
days
maybe these are ready to go really
really common
a lot because services offload there are
two systems to register your
so maybe these neurons to go of you ever
noticed
rest ago doesn't sell to the enterprise
there's a reason they don't sell today
at a price
readies itself is not secure res is self
doesn't support kept a transmission boom
there you go their dad is a weaker point
and say
perot-gore Salesforce I want the front
doors that you're probably already so
if you if we go back now I understand
why spend so much time on this
i've seen hey call services are stack up
thanks
understand what's in there think
differently on your approach don't think
it is like assessing this one box is one
application
it's a hodgepodge up some good some crap
that's in there so you have to start
thinking about that %uh same goes with
by all the email
sending providers email sending
solutions in the cloud
that's a that's my favorite want to
attack those he's
really fun okay now if you wanna know
where to really look
like to dive into it actual disc one
single provider
this is allissa starts with so we talk
about the things right a look at all the
things that make it up
and I still think that's the most
support says we're gonna find your
weakest links
and that's where you're gonna be able to
attack one thing and then out through
to get back to the more secure service
or more secure service
that they're trying to sell you but the
others things start to look at
is were data stored how is stored house
transmit this is a big one in the cloud
crime
on in the enterprise for a very long
time we've had a methodology of
I if you had a website as a CPS we're
gonna terminate SLR load balancers are
front and
and they're gonna go play nice to be
back to back in right now there's a
start to change a bit as
are it's less expensive you for us all
to rewrite the code does not it is
expensive anymore
are to do but this is still is pretty
like a scene in stays in place in many
organizations
well the problem is that same like the
design carried over the cloud many times
so then when you start looking to cloud
providers and you realize oh well they
one on top infrastructure providers like
easy to
with your data is flowing in on purpose
on a public network
which is a sense is a problem ever right
BC to now easy to my body is a easy to
secure tell you oh we tag packets we do
all this and secure whatever
somebody's gonna screw up right it's
gonna happen
arm was about least six months ago
easy to screwed up the load balancing
fixed and responses were coming back in
the wrong pages from different customers
so there is a perfect example right
there right isn't is no longer a what if
it's no longer theoretical
it actually happened so any by that was
that was transferred ATP
stuff its comeback you get the wrong
response is it was crazy was
chaos right but the people that were
flowing for ACPs all the way through
their stack
didn't have this problem because it was
a possible for to happen and that's an
area
so no which took a theoretical made it
real so understanding
incise a I love where your date is is a
calming old
are with other customers of one customer
laws on application exploit that they
get your data
II network configuration same thing I a
is your day to suffice I was somebody
else
the Wii you know in that move back into
the increase aside and not just from the
trans aside
of the backups where the backups in the
cloud are they stored in the cloud
off-site all this car stuff are they you
know cryptid all that kind of thing
same with the data storage at the stone
often things like rights rescue system
hugely popular in the cloud services
it's amazing and other guys it get hard
when other guys work day and all these
companies
in they all use cut the same technology
stacks which is really really
interesting so if you listen to very
specific things I talk about
that your road map for attacking anyone
of these harm
but I the you know they all kinda have
the same somewhere weaknesses which is
always funny and the next thing is you
get down to the architecture right we
all know architecture reviews we are we
we all go through there we talk about
okay how's the setup or whatever
but one interesting thing is I love to
point this one out again like my story
is was the true rest Cove the various
things based on architecture
so frances if there's a single injection
in a fun and
are application process provider
is a possible for that attacker to get
to your day right
I see some heavy ass season had snow is
like me
I don't know the question is you don't
know what to do the architects review
because it may be multi-tenant
environment it may not be
it they may use ever database accounts
to access data per customer
they may not you don't know sequin
Jackson in itself is not always
dangerous to you you just don't know yet
don't know more about it
so I was taught her body make sure that
as you go through their you start
looking at
the actual architecture how these things
stack and
are how the risk actually affect you
now anybody wanna anything
what was the number one thing you look
at you if you are in a cloud service
heard some are some from down the side
earlier
now nothing location okay
so like physical location worst restore
as a great one right
so physical he's a physical location of
where your data store right
so you have residency issues you have oh
my god is my data being stored higher on
what are they doing with it yet safe
harbor issues with you
all these great things right I me
personally me I
use cloud surprise that North Korea feel
secure the gonna clear weapons and stop
I get it up
whether I so um and the last thing to
assess is does the vendor to assess
it defended as assassins get their
assessments from will save you a lot of
work to make sure you look at the scope
%uh those assessments too many vendors
say hey we're PCI compliant and they
walk away
you have to work for the environment PCI
compliant those controls carry over to
the other
party environment generally no PCI
toll environment PCI all environment so
whatever that it's all
marketing shit example no punches
carpenters I love these guys
height so I want to start talking about
that then we get in the car the
protection side of things
so on you know how to protect yourself
in Harry you know
properly utilize cloud services so
arms to skip the first one talents
pretty obvious you guys get that
I but the next one is that the audit so
this is a really interesting one to me
so
most cloud providers don't provide a lot
of audit logs for you
they don't lie to pack all the some that
are so sales for princess
they're working on our be much more
transparent a Roku are they
send along a three-tier by today to de
Justin logging data
I you can explore all your data there
get real-time streams it's easy
but the XOR is a newer more progressive
thoughts are most providers don't allow
this
and segal creative sometimes but you
can't really do things with the
API's I monitoring different
transactions change of state a setting
means you're crawling
but it's usually very close to my
solutions I but they're there are
something resources are to come on the
market to help with this thank goodness
but this is very important and then
continues on how do you guys to continue
sorting right now
how many people understand the concept
continues on it
okay was from spin cycle now in it okay
so continues on it
so I wrote a framework a bow as the two
years ago when I was a CISO it either
or former his cock cock cock kept it was
are continuous continuous up
continues automated auditing now
continuous audit controls
automation that's what Scott so cock and
the concept behind Kaka
its rates a name for market approval
because it was the shit
thank you on a you guys were getting
their songs like i
lead the horse to water make you drink
you're okay and %um
so arm the Casa behind this was I was
tired of my staff spending so much time
on auditing every six months when some
random ass order came in my office
and I was tired of finding are on
discrepancies my controls
analyst hired are spending so much time
on responding to
trivial attacks week's been already from
work to do all this force
ago our as much sex as a monitoring
system it go out to check control
test control so very support Active
Directory our policy
go out had a test account you try to
change the password that s account took
our password that didn't meet the
complex requirements if you're
successful control fail
if it was not successful control was
intact and they're going to hope for our
law call this right
is great insisting that we wrote in shit
was in ruins
whatever on but if it worked out well
home
I got a mild of lower for a second a
problem anyway so the cause behind
continues on what we did is on all the
time
we could find when the state or control
changed and we knew about it Inc
pretty much near real time right and so
take this is our pilots a cloud provider
where you no longer manage the security
controls and you can't run a contest
every day and you can't run source code
are you tools on ever release you just
don't have this visibility
to shift a lot of your actions and your
time
to the audit function well as we know
our it is time consuming
can be boring sorry auditors but it can
be on
and so we need to move to using the API
is an automated tool sets
too costly test the security these
platforms kasich's has to make sure that
our signs are preferences and everything
are in place
and you know basically just give us that
real-time knowledge
similar to what we would have if we only
application in the infrastructure
K so the Casa behind continuous auditing
or yeah
Kaka because the shit you know so I and
then we talking about the %uh
communicate
intent not a plantation I can I put this
one on here is a big one
if you work with the vendors talk to the
vendors a say
hey here's the intent is what I'm
looking for
Julie work so much much better the
companies and hey install some Cisco ASA
is for the hell of it
you know cuz many vendors will do
whatever you want and it doesn't really
actually give you what you need
you know I to secure enterprise which is
quite unfortunate
so on so I hurts me so hip for
we talked about data residency so we
have some
country lies there on what are some the
other big concerns that people have with
our cloud services
and providers at
if they have a season security expert on
the team okay that's a great one
so arm
truck the counting is that without an
interview people
a home okay
so that companies that will truly cell
into the enterprise
actually thought more about security and
would really
have better security people the people
there or has its own the press are not
target the enterprise secure consumer
based applications and services
they're the ones its government to watch
for but
disc falling 10 usually find who the
security people are any organization
and then you'll be able to rate them out
and look across different organizations
and see how they
who they know you know all that stuff
but the biggest thing I say is
is go back to communication have the
discussion with the guys
you know in five minutes if you think
their season of are but the big big
thing to look at is not how seasoned or
knowledgeable security Siemens but how
influential they are
in the organization are you have the
smartest security people on the planet
but they can't get things done either
because their own inability orders
because the organization doesn't want to
then it doesn't matter it's all for
naught are worse than the other big
problems or concerns you guys have
you were
gone something action here SDLC okay so
is
what he says if they fall in SLC right
so are the democratic code out there
on the SS Marco you know is a care you
know what they're doing arm
yeah I'm not going to say most a
mostar cloud providers toll most of us a
lesser
let the really really big ones like
Salesforce so sales were stuck on proper
right if very structure program all they
have to write at JP Morgan on their list
and she turned down from there
clout is like the wild wild west the
selects offer developers who were
are like white over to ship code awesome
I was gonna for protein production
reporters have made a caveat is working
again it goes back to host if it will be
shipped about people for developers on
order don't
on but now it's just the cloud services
are
so like a blue box we we have to set the
code we have on device
our security code but we have our
security I for I
two different kinds developers my guys
are on platform like
it supports for we just no doubt over
who
no we can't say we can't do that that's
a really good one to watch for
because the security controls I around
who was putting code in production
how fast do nothing if it's been audited
is a big one in the
in the CAF providers because you don't
have the luxury of being behind the
corporate firewall and
lose practices are okay sometimes and
all that it's out there is public
you in your you know best friends in ire
on North Korea Syria
whoever's attack yesterday arm can all
attacking play with it all day long
I so want more our way in the back
I guess we both you with some first
support
and what can they see yeah I can see
everything
no contest arm so this is an interesting
one to me so
I just had this is from my team ranks
weeks at best buy for we do see a lot of
data for our customers
and you know one of my guys is arm
misbehave
his fucking hit me I am and he's like
bathroom
hello hi to see if the user man we can't
see their data
we are protecting me
how was mister protected if we can't see
it I don't know me
we have figured out how Mike to who
and the Knights in that conversation cuz
that's like my Big Lebowski not done
right that's all I got
so anyway %uh in the cloud providers
it's very interesting right
so if you go back to enterprise you
think about it who can see your data
inside in a price on your host your own
application right
your network admin your sysadmin your
day be sad man who ever write these
arsenals the essay
the same applies to the our cloud
providers
they have people who can see your data
right unless you're doing corruption on
your side
and then stuff in the car today to them
they don't the keys on a they can see
your data
now they may have policies never look at
your data and let me tell you they do
those policies many probably do follow
that but you run the inherent risk out
somebody can see your data
and this is whether their ethical about
it honest about it
anfal so how to best practices in
Spanish safety guidelines
oscalus corroborate our disclosure they
don't look at it but they can also your
data
what's the same respect you had when
your hose inside the enterprise
it's shifted outside if you're in a
prize right so after to back the risk
and actually slightly different
based on their controls but it's the
same problem essentially okay
there's another on the back right
availability
tell billy's not security question who
cares if its up
what is down a secure nobody can hack it
be honest does my fair I like when I
when like a plan for a good hour ago
ship our jobs number today I'm going to
come out
wants you I'll knows availability
I so I I think I saw talk about it so
fell below the cloud services
on most closer visit you look at don't
have as a lace
on purpose when you go out a look at it
does say
we achieve four we strive for
these are awesome intense but are not
guarantees to be very very careful that
most your cloud services other
know how solid as always unless they are
highly focused on the enterprise
or you're a big ass customer in the
giving us away the rest of them
the key piece of the sounds fancy but
then when you like calculate the actual
number of 9th they just gave you your
allies is like
and a month a year they can actually be
down like a shit like
math always wins so talk to move off the
market in on that
I but our many the services are getting
better on availability
aspects in the cloud where they can be
read on it we can actually you know
architect properly because we'll have
the restraints a physical hardware in
space
I but like I said most of it is intent
okay are one more
rights so are so questions reliability
you know if the car
Firefox 7 possible stops the f-bomb this
early in the mornings like me
on his car if the lockout provider folks
out you know where the liability right
if it's a regulatory thank efforts I
want their customers and whatever it is
wears a liability on yet this is an
interesting one
so I know vaclav I was just talking to
our intercompany
our last week on the hook la provider
and this they want to do business with
huge like they were like all and we love
you guys gonna do it
this is exactly what stop the contract
unfortunately on
the cloud provider would not agree to
the liability terms that the
interest company wanted and they weren't
even putting claims data or
you know in like that this was further
internal operations you know whatever
stuff right I
in the cover would not accept liability
they were too afraid of the liability
hamanaka me
this is a big one this has been a
problem for a long time with posted now
source providers
arm you see a little bit with my
consultants but not as my life kinda got
over that got standard terms on
a club fires are still scared to say yes
gonna take this liability I'm gonna you
know go to these limits whatever
some will do it but many of my word
about it and with good reason I will
defend them a bit on this one so many
star fighters
they don't know what data you're really
gonna shove in there you say
00 I want to use it for my internal
request tracking right and there's some
do show some customer data client data
patient data whatever their
Dennis compromise and now the customer
has a
in a regulatory phone line and they want
a cloud provider to pay for it and deal
with it
when in reality like hey the terms of
engagement with slightly different they
didn't know about that they didn't know
that was going to be used for
so large providers had very heavily so
we total sales wasn't happening ago
so disclaimer low sales force the fam
right but they have at it right
Salesforce is not want to deal with help
the regulations the liability is too
much for
they pushed back everywhere they can't
when I was at a Roku
we would not sell to somebody else
health care so we came to us and said
it would have to go later I want money
they
I mean i libri pay me because I'm a
greedy capitalists right and a pain me
be on a call be like sorry I want a
business like that is
kill part my heart right there every
time I say that right I
but the in today we did not want to help
their cause I don't want a liability
because it's too big a liability
for me cuz I don't know what they were
going to have their risk group we risk
but whatever
so this is a really really good one yes
answered a few big liability
requirements
make sure you're on top kept so
we're going to start to finish up link
it to some Q&A I
but you know this is kinda want to know
I would work with providers as a
kind of an overview some other stuff
that we talked about their I
you know everything from the transfer
risk management to
a you know how to say that all the
private different and working with the
virus
picking the providers around that up
that work with the risk levels you need
which tied it perfectly here to this
liability question that we just had
right so have the open dialogue really
work with them understand their stack of
things to find those witnesses want to
attacking to go after
and is going to make your life much much
easier but understand eight dollars a
month
you like in the vesicular in the world
it just did
economically doesn't make sense right
not gonna happen so if you want like
I was gonna say government great
security but we or kinda know the
government scorecard security so
yeah I don't know where SAE you with a
little security
my organization has hope on you know it
was a month public market you there
but ideal scenario that you're looking
for cloud providers
these are couple or points are kinda
some the ideal things
day when you talk to cloud providers you
talked about you say hey do you have
these things
kind of helping others in these are some
progressive Concepts
in security asked that in the cloud is
very
easy to put in place so Francis the
first one disposable systems
right so what my platform that we run
are and a Roku in
I think a the box as well are
we treat systems parva version release
so when I was at Roku we never had an
operating system like a server is a
server to assess
in production longer 32 days 32 days was
the oldest
that any instance was ever production
mean it can ever be vulnerable to
anything
or in 32 days because everything every
time we boudin instance it was auto
patch
everything tom our pastor right and so
we treat is systems as they were
disposable their part of the release of
we were in a row code
wrote for instance is I didn't hand path
we roll
appease the code we're all for instance
this is a great causing a cloud
providers can do this or talk to them
about that if they're doing it
it's a big win because patching bowman's
been all this stuff
becomes less meaningful arm is still me
for what much less me it was our primary
control it's a secondary control at this
point right
traffic management been automated again
because control systems have API's
everything fertilize this is really
really easy to do and this is where you
want to copy writers to be
I and then I security events as per
operational monitoring
this is something that I season
enterprises doing but interesting enough
consumer cloud providers move to this
before anybody else and I'm not sure why
i cant one thing I saw a class specific
thing
I just happen to see this trend is that
they're treating the security alerts
and they're missing patches pacification
zone list as per their
operational monitoring as announce
coming up in in the dashboard from the
idea of guys on our core whatever
and now if a patch is messy like soon is
that if I Z comes out hoop it's right
there they're all the incense and
they're good 20 minutes right
so it a Roku we store all our entire
fleet
in the flea fluctuated based on load by
an average profit 21 to 2200 servers
in an emergency we can rule the entire
fleet and some forty five minutes
I did twice in one week there was no
purcell verbally came out
the vendor pass it two days later busy
airports that has actually was not
complete here's another one
we roll the entire fleet twice in one
week no doubt on the customer's
are and no faults in the environment by
and we were able to do this because
we had pacification and operational
monitoring so it came up we saw you up
that script was gonna handle that we had
can automated configuration management
so when is this came up won't it was
already bill
air got built or need to be I and
because we treat every as disposable
there was no persist or done anything
everything was easy ways
for the switch everything was gone and
we're up and running
so these are things that are progressive
in the claus pace
when you start talking your vendors
these are things you think about also if
you to assess if your pen to serve our
ability
are due for release as these are things
you think about think about how all the
systems are gonna be
how the configuration man has done and
realizing a lot like operators removing
its systems like this
so a be on top at the boulder testing
and and
make sure doesn't the new stuff first
lie all stuff gets probably won't really
be there
alright so that's our about all my
ramblings that I have for this morning
at
I like 9:30 or something in the morning
on well
I guess was like 6:30 my time when I
started this hostile
thanks to our schedule me first project
our harm
so I any questions and we go any with
drugs and you guys wanna go doesn't
matter much to me
by any questions around assessing the
risk of Clough
specific are providers how she revolvers
are whatever our care
I could
I guess the question is whether arm
providers allow you to click Mark so
what's the user is on the platform
doing their thing a blue nightie company
secrets mix it with their porn whatever
it is that they do
you're completely blind all this right
yes I love you this much about porn
year the ones doing it okay so right
um as requested his arrest question
right its
how much risk you wanna taken and how
willing are you to be polite to that
situation
I what you can do in many cases is
arm if it is the if it's aka sasser
describes the web a service
I you can log the I traffic coming off
your network to their network
and then inspect that traffic and try to
make you know
on guesses based on that now so complete
you don't get what's outside if you're
in price but give you some visibility
less
at least on other thing you can do is a
lot of these providers have
API's such you can are due to predation
expert and spectator this area crawled
it is there that I think and so
on automating be able to go out there is
back with the date is look at the
actions
and doing state change detection so look
at going in for instance is an okay
here's the admin settings and I expect
to see
or in the PI check the settings are they
still intact Yes No
okay who was last login: it's not great
this is not complete this is all custom
but this is one thing some organizations
to come over the real answer is
talk to the provider and just put on
them and if you have
if you know other companies usually
local groups like give local groups are
businesses that get together talk
security thing you guys are always the
same vendors
leverage that lean on a lot these bigger
organizations start to move to this
it's just me look at their featureless
in the priorities is down a little bit
because behind the other
10 things the business users one who was
pain but I could say that are
leaning on with your group helps a lot
as hell Salesforce's
I do log importation actually our times
is about 15
I CIS those in the Bay Area kinda got
together and leaned on
patrick who's the chief just over
Salesforce naturally ok
rap is like 15 like be companies and/or
base has a yes to prioritize
so work with them there's a question
here yes
Microsoft sucks fine not like
are yes oh wow what our customers
accuses of 365
I we have test accounts on a platform of
integrations that we do
um it's no worse than a better than any
other
services out there on from the assassins
that I dunno and
are the ones I've seen for my customers
I action no
a couple guys to run security on that
side over there
on the great thing is that its Microsoft
a very visible
in so they have to deal with that
visibility in the market
a big security breach affects their
stock price
so on they're much more responsive and
proactive then
a lotta secure your love the service
providers in that same space
I you know the some others that are very
security minded but
I they're one of the better ones in that
space because I who they are mostly
yeah
you know that's a great question
somebody really address arm so
a as to its response the cloud
coordination with the
customers on you know when I some
happened about a clout
on SLE poor most was really really poor
right now
on and its kinda how the spaces grown-up
on
that they become about sunlight we
manage it we take care of it that's
their big business proposition cell
so that kinda carries over his response
the security as well
on so it's very important we're starting
to see someone is provided below it more
progressive
little more open because they're getting
burned and flogged when they're not
are but for most part more so the best
thing to do is when you negotiate
contracts with providers
have a contract are have a stipulation
in there
the basis as a turn or if I with an ex
upon a time have any security fence
this is what your sweet old and here's
the regular checkpoints
et cetera if you bring contractually
their legal teams of all
the picture
yeah and that's because back to the
immaturity and the others know as a lace
is our best effort right
are so you're bigger ones you guys are
selling to the enterprise so your box
you work day
here DocuSign your sales forces you can
ask the negotiators terms not permit
without problem your smaller guys
dollars a month
there public not really looking so it's
okay I X O
our question you but I get caught
I'll be around for most the day so if
you want to chat about the sq providers
or whatever
I give me a shout and we'll talk thanks
here