can and brought your kids
I so this is the one morning you're
gonna get
the the only y/n I am
now would be a you know and I know I
know little Johnny
want an iPad but I'm going see our prize
for an hour
or you will have what can only be
described
as the most awkward ride home with your
kid today
so this is this is me and my nicest
get out
all right amount okay
so um right this is
the official gun control thank you all
for coming out again
um well it so who the fuck am i right
I am Duncan Minot's exchange student
from Deutschland of course
really nothing yeah I hear I'm
radio to my my
okay I'm going with not again okay so
I'm the returning your kind champion
um I have come to defend the crown
except I've been attending a month to
the talks and
I've really liked a lot of what i've
heard there's been some great technical
contact: this year
a.m.
but have already decided that I've won
because the one thing that is still
messing
from the discourse in the dialogue and
year just for granting and fuckin crazy
as a raving
which is that's what that that's this
home
as a level of accountability for
industry were still patting ourselves on
the back trying to solve the world's
problems
but spending like no time looking
internally
as to you why it is that maybe we're not
solving some of those problems as fast
as we could
so a.m. so anyway
by gay and taken off the ground and the
reason that I'm taking off the crown is
cuz
I don't want to be the only person I
don't want to be the only voice
thats out here talkin shit about what's
wrong with
this business that we're all in so but
that's not gonna stop me
hair I just leaving the crown up there
for somebody to come pick up
and it's your job to come back next year
or go to another can
go back to your office make a positive
change in what it is we do for an
industry
I I have her head and I have more I T
cedar
certifications than you the sister
mommy let me prove it UK
so I am I am certified
to work at Best Buy their
start but I
okay those %uh view that the that manage
to catch my talk last year
you know that I I set out to piss off
wonderful people and then in like
inadvertently piss off another group of
people
so I got get certified to remove my own
fuckin routers
you now don't worry don't worry
leg if you're not offended yet I am so
not done
okay I am certified a clicking Next
I am certified it changing passwords
I am certified
running nasa's I am certified
at working at Ernst & Young I'm
certified it working at Deloitte to
and I am certified
at working at the Department of Defense
don't clap for that shit what the fuck
is frank with you
seriously okay so so there's a point why
why am i showing off all my
certifications I wanna make a point like
obviously this is fine
um I do hold a good number I've the
search I just showed you some
you know you where you can guess um and
I got a whole
ass load more than eight and show off
and that's not cuz
arm it's not cuz I think sorter on their
high
but well let me ask you a question
rate Chris I mean do. that's what search
do so multiple choice
mother fuckers so
all the certs whether they make me do
they make me the most awesome fog and am
I am I the man in my the next guy you
need to hire into your
IT department to handle security for
your company
which but
so so rid CC the gases see
the air I'll the answers all of the
above mother fuckers
the truth of the matter is I'm not half
bad
what I do for a living doesn't have shit
to do with the pilot plaques on my desk
I'm by I'm also not half bad at taking
multiple choice exams but I can't
remember the last time I was at work and
somebody said
quick your honed do you a or do you be
or do you see right and I can't remember
the last time
as ash from the start but I had to fire
a Photoshop so
so there you go so
our day book what's what what the fuck
is my point
right whitewater so let's talk about
certification
as an industry body cuz because let's
admit it this industry
I T in general completely culpable
InfoSec
maybe a little bit worse I mean I so the
DOD
doesn't require that you have your MCSE
to work on their servers like they'll
take
dude I'll take a they'll take a grime
leg right out a basic
and if he says yeah I like computers the
full image from the the store on nt4
this through the commitment from the
Windows Server they don't care that he
doesn't have an MCSE
but if you want to go do Lake you know
cyber
security for the DOD you have to have a
sis be so
so what's the value right i mean if
we're ever so obsessed with these things
why what we what are we really getting
out a bit
so
their tool for your HR department right
the idea is that this makes it possible
for human resources to do hiring and
recruiting around the particular skill
sets that they need to this is hard
security is hard I'm not gonna lie to
you
without how I'm probably preaching to
the choir you now
right so if I wanna be a Windows guy how
much do I have to now
about be GrpN HSRP
exactly jack shit right and that's a
maybe I do know some stuff but I don't
have to
if I'm a UNIX guy how much do I have to
know
about you know registry hives
not a damn thing if I were to insecurity
have to know all that shit on I at least
all the shit to my employer as
so it's hard for HR so what about you
well you'd like that job the end of the
day you'd like to
move ahead you like to do some new stuff
you want your career
to progress so you don't get those certs
in hopes of getting better job
get a raise at your current job get a
new job go to Washington
centered ass watch logs
make six figures packed do you seriously
we do that Tammy T
okay and then after the certification
body a fight at this is america
let me go cash private enterprise 3
market right if we have
the certification program that everybody
wants then
everybody's gonna come to us and we'll
make money it's a quality product this
is a free market right we are
we are adding value it's it's it's all
good
I think we're gonna spend a little time
examining you to these and I
bad a bad all the people certifications
in the room they're really good a
multiple choice questions have already
figured out the answer
because there is only one right answer
so raise your hand if you're I TPG
certified
as a room full love you here you don't
even know it
in 2001 I S E to choose the certificate
the the certification body by NCIS is BS
SEP in
like four other search for you can
become like a
developer Eunos saw for security life
cycle all back up in Dr
nearly business continuity you do all
that stuff go get a search
that I see two years earlier company
called I TPG does it
I TPG generates the courseware for all
the exams so the camera body of
knowledge like the whole thing
everything that goes into the exams as
report together by this company
they do all the pre review courses race
for those people that show up with the
isc2 pains at the classes for any of you
who've done that
don't even work try to see to work for a
company called ATPG
and they're not really supposed to tell
you that although I mean let's be honest
I got this
with you awesome open sources ATPG dot
com
I'm the world it. BG's really freakin
Pradesh
I don't think I don't I didn't find it
and I see two dark side though
is now we're so I don't think it's like
a big secret but
they do all other marketing to so right
for the market the stuff
the market HR departments the market it
into the industry they did a fantastic
job in marketing it to the federal
government
they run all the classes that people pay
for they put all
all the books that people pay for they
run all the tests that people pay for
so what but the fact is she do
do but what what do they do
alright this non-profit collects 23
million dollars in revenue
from I TPG each year believes this is
the last year I think it at one point it
was as low as $6 million dollars
for for running 0 a website and mailing
you pieces of paper
so hot I am in the wrong we are all in
the wrong business are we
so by the way
pay attention to the titles on my slide
so
the CISSP common body of knowledge
currently has 10 domains
to pass that exam you're supposed to be
proficient in all those domains
and each exam soon a 50 question six
hours one sitting
a I know there's like a there's like a
lite version is this where Lake you know
if 250 in six hours is too hard it's
like a hundred and three hours
really
I'm but anyway so that's what the test
consists serve and that's all it takes
to get certified is to go through the
process
and take the exam and then you and then
you get somebody laid out for you and
say that you know in some a copy of your
resume which they don't validate
and somebody puts a a number on the
thing and signs it like there that
person but they're not really
the other just checking the name and the
number validation
the so anyway so I'm I'm not saying
you could lie and kisses P
but you could art tho
I decided that that the O evidence-based
arguments are the most effective so
here's a graph
this graph is um a frequency very calm
and it looks like button on the screen
doesn't matter yeah
alright so I will walk you through this
because it was so bad
right so this piece of the pie a
right here is 50 questions in the 250
and they tell you this going in
are for a.m. yet for the next to love
tests
right so 50 on don't count only 200 mm
do they don't tell you which ones
a but if you've taken the exam in the
last four years you can clearly tell
because they're not even for this SB
anymore
they clearly on some other subject
matter so now they got 47 exams in
rotation
across the entire day event they refresh
a handful the questions every year but
they're spending almost no money
developing messer
and instead you're paying 600 bucks for
the privileged cuing the new product
that they're gonna sell you
next month so that's the green pie
the rest to this legal regulations
governance and risk management
right security architecture and design
make up the rest that the majority of
the questions on the tests that I
sampled
and those are you in the room that have
taken it going how are you
you sample past how many times did you
take fucking
easy just want my past and one but I
will show you my secret
so and then I broke it down and
and do you notice anything about the top
where the slivers get really really thin
right like so what appear in these three
ten little slivers rate
fi sack OPSEC crypto
and then over here BCP and network
security
so guess what you can pass without
knowing any of the technical domains for
she acted
you can I don't I don't know how one
question
in operational security or physical
security qualifies you as
is his profession how high is that
France posed to be
move six min triggered relation to an
expert white
I wish I was kidding
but those have you have done it know
it's true
sorry because you spend a lot of time
and money
but you know it's true so I'm
where they get itself I'm there some
web-sites
on this internet thing where you can
just download
reso so in addition to Lake you don't
even have to be technically proficient
in the thing that they can they're gonna
certified as being proficient and even
pass the exam
but this dudes so you're gonna take the
CISSP next week I take it
get a good picture so
well good luck II I
so so there's the other safe for you to
download the questions
right and I and and answers and
and practice on real questions on the
test now admittedly
the one thing that that that I TPG has
going for this SB is that there are 47
versions the exam at two under 50
questions apiece
so I can't quite do the math all in my
head but that something like ten
thousand questions you'd have to
memorize
and at that point like you you don't
really need it she
if you can memorize 10,000 questions you
ought to be able to pretty much kick ass
at every
multiple choice test you take over the
course your career
so but actually the best part the reason
I included this is an act as I wanted to
like bragging I second tired at the
CISSP questioned
who cares I i mean this is me on Google
and you can do it too
but the best part the best part is so
the bottom and these are the raw folks
sure on this part say registered for
like some you some account anonymously
and they put all the stuff on there any
comment on in like most it's like
yeah I totally like download this study
for like two weeks impasse then lakes
sweet it really works right oh and by
the way you're supposed to pay a 149
bucks for these
but I figure if Lake you're in this
industry the fact that entail 149 bucks
to download from your site could you say
such as your problem not mine
so
am but the best part is this the fuckin
to comment on this
fresh so I i did. if you can't see it
this guy just click
so this guy who is totally okay
with cheating to get the certification
cuz he's registered for citing is paying
for these things to download them
and pad his resume without actually
learning any this stuff
is backing on the CISSP is worthless
I'm gonna span 750 bucks to get a CISSP
in a week
and and by the way it's still fucking
sucks don't do it
but I mean is 0
first ask yourself in a CISSP is worth
it league only cost you 150 bucks should
he do you think it is
so sorry I couldn't not put that up
there
that the lake morally bankrupt awake
resume pirate
downloading the stuff right not the guy
who's trying to elevate this
the right not to another guy who's
trying to be at the happy oh that the
high-minded guy in the industry saying
like
CISSP isn't enough it is a really sorry
finally the technical you wouldn't want
to put a person in front of like
anything
you know important the old maybe it's a
good for
you know general knowledge base but you
know you're alright let whatever their
arguments that is that's not this guy
this cash this guys like disguised
you this case apart I mean you know
pirate and whatever you are but but he
took time out from his day
in which he clearly doesn't give a fuck
to look back on the CIA as as be on this
site where like
you're just downloading it to cheat some
awesome
so awesome
okay so I am so there's there's been
this thing going on lately
around the CISSP and I be loath to not
talk about it
just because the the reality of the
situation is that there are people that
are still invested right there people
who have not divorce themselves from the
SIS be exam yet
okay and and smart people people that
like are good at what they do
so there's a there's the the the four
horsemen to the cyst pakalert II added
this is popular because I more clever
but they came up with the four horsemen
shit
so do anyway these are these are for
guys that are you know this is like the
Def Con crowd rates early Dave Lewis
from liquid matrix Chris nickerson from
layers
I'm Scott turbine who some grumpy
podcaster
and boris who's a sir or market these
guys on a podcast by the way
but the so they all came up with the
idea that they were going to run for
the isc2 border directors to try and you
know
shake it up make a little change try and
steer the organization in the right
direction
well we're not very far along this
process
but truman didn't make it because they
had a whole bunch of their
tf2 get like enough sponsors head-to-toe
review petition to get
in the running for the border directors
name get enough it so they got enough
signatures but then a bunch of a more
like to run out as they were phony
because like you know hey i'd
I trolled Twitter for a buncha people to
sign my petition
like no shipping on all CIS espy's but
so so been a little bit about the two
guys that didn't make it in
because I know I'm talking to a roomful
of people who who
some %uh view a good number love you
have this yr or are thinking about the
server might have some other I see to
search
whatever the case may be so Dave Lewis
from likud major Exxon I'm gonna fuck
with day/date a badass
if you if you don't check out the good
natured start like these like the one
guy
i think is and he's Canadian to a I am
cases is kinda tryna pushing things in a
positive direction and then there's
chris Nickerson who is my fucking hero
so this is this isn't like my total Lake
rabbit hole sidebar thing like
so the if you don't know who Chris
nickerson as
Chris niggaz n and a and a guy named
Ryan other guy named Luke
a.m.
start on this TV show starting quote on
his TV show called Tiger Team
bigger team anybody fuckin clap for
Tiger Team that's right
so they start on this show called Tiger
team that was it if you haven't seen it
you gotta go find this shit on you to be
the show
fuckin awesome it is this reality show
about Penn testers
they do like mixed vector
a physical pain tax rates are like like
they'll hack your
the hack your learn cistern the hack
your phone says the the social your
people and then a break in your shit
and like you knows all intended to be
this league really awesome expose
but so there's two episodes and in the
pilot episode they break into this high
and Beverly Hills car dealership and
they drop necklace chaise docks and they
get a any shooting the show gets fucking
cancelled
but this is how much of a badass Chris
nickerson fucking is and why is my
fucking hero
so like to show totally gets cancelled
eastward flaky a it did they they all
change our jobs they'll go different
ways now
and and try again and and they make a
sitcom
about this that you might have heard ov
called breaking in
Chris nickerson got my complete bikes
christian slater in a sitcom how awesome
is this guy seriously
like I got my employer sued for duck for
dropping docks on cable TV and they make
a show about me starring Christian
Slater
box the so awesome so
alright so like there's my leg weird man
crush interest nickerson
any and somebody's gonna email the like
a link to this video to a mic for months
from now
should be who the fuck is this creepy
guy I'll
and I'm just I'm just a fan at the art
man that's all it is
solace alright so that can all I have to
say about CISSP other than just to say
that
if if you give a shit if you wanna see
change
we might have a moment I'm not highly
optimistic because
that's not my job as a whole lot funnier
to get up here and back
shit that's gone wrong and celebrate
stuff that goes right
was it easy so but at the same time
you know if if you're if you're going to
vote for board of directors or even if
you were going to maybe especially if
you were going to
and you think maybe you'd like to see if
we can do something
about making the icy to search not total
garbage
like the next sir I'm about to talk
about oh yeah
a give you one guess anyway I'm
but the the year so maybe
maybe consider voting for these guys I
and the border directorship
writer who is a
who had the gas for life was up next hmm
fish you guys are experts but yet as
course it's
courses the CE H+ the Certified Ethical
Hacker or as I like to call it how to
get rich by rewriting the and Matt man
page in question form its diseases like
it some
that some guy that I got fired from
jeopardy
from the writings that was just let you
know what I'm going to do I'm gonna go
take the technical docs
and reword them in the form of a
question ants
you britt exactly what is dash
H
what is Google dot com okay so so and
the ec-council
I if you if you don't follow attrition
in the air at a project
I'm they've got caught selling material
with play dress content like their books
on like how to be a Certified Ethical
Hacker
I'm at let me say that again their book
on how to be a certified
for call hacker contain plagiarize
content that they ripped off the
internet
so I'm
what their yes sounds legit
shoot up so you i jus there so bad
they've got their own charlton page on
attrition dark and if you go well
okay so what the fuck does that mean
that they are petition that are down the
child into page
right dude along with the shady fucker
to give it up for my man Greg Evans from
work at the only man to ever be
threatened with having is CISSP revoked
lucky for him he was lying about it
so
he is in fact reasonably decent with
Photoshop
okay so the statistical analysis wins
all arguments
I i went ahead and took a summer the
overrode not some of the questions that
from the ch
is just the one I'll balls so
you the one question set for the current
reading CH
and I and their work domain since I
kinda had to make my own
but I figured certified that means I
pass the test
ethical I know something about at 6
hacker I know something about hacking
and I filled out the question what I
quickly discovered as they relate to
other categories
right security networking and
definitions what does the Fed flag do it
easy P
we're legitimate technical question
you can google the answer to or open
security tools
how do I perform a Christmas can with an
app the answer to both those questions
by the way is
Google mother fucker and then there were
a handful the questions on affects
and exactly zero questions on hacking
and you go okay we'll wait wait bullet
bullet
I mean maybe you're just being a dick
might you duh
baby but maybe you're being a dick and
maybe they really are questions about
hacking
okay but so here's what I would expect
to see in a certification that was going
to pick demonstrate that you had some
ability to hack
because let's call hacking exploitation
especially if it's offense if security
which is that the cEAT supposed to be
right this is the
I'm a baby penthouse tercer so
you have not trying to be a dick but
really honestly if you're just getting
the CDH like not a pro
right anyway I'm so Jojo
this is the this would be the cert where
I would expect us to show
right like oh here's an array into a
char pointer with no bounds checking
I am which of these answers would
successfully exploit this we're just
tell me what kinda vulnerability is in
this code
okay so I just gave it to you somebody
shouted out what what kinda
vulnerability I just described
fuck yeah overflow right
valid easy wasn't it do that ninety nine
more times and you could be certified in
something better
the Certified Ethical Hacker we could do
this right now
right self right if I put
you no question mark equals script alert
dot fuck you
in an earl in a box pops on your screen
what's that called
that's right me
there you go okay see this isn't hard
this is easy but
but that's my point to rate is is that
that there was none
there's none of that it's like this is
this this is that
the army so these definitions right they
would ask you to
to define certain security terms and you
know but
I can't believe how much of that is
really about like password hashes
Mike I
again John
dash %eh okay so when this is this is a
course
grade the site where I downloaded the
same stuff from ec-council and just to
prove my earlier point
I'm red I passed on September 14 like
fuckin two weeks ago
who's got past with 86 rate me get this
guy oh there's like five questions that
are changed
and there's another guy hears three and
by the way here the questions and
answers
so like like a really honestly go
download this go pay to take the test
you will pass
mush pasa so so
let's check back in on the case for
certifications
so how do we do great HR hiring and
recruiting
our certs a good way to validate that
people actually have the skills that
they say they have
crickets
who yep so course for you
our course if you're in a jar and your
job is to read resumes and you're not a
technical person
and your job is to find somebody who is
technically qualified to do a job and
you're using search your fact
sorry used the word is going to do your
job and get paid I suspect but
at the end of the day you're you your
mission to leverage certifications to
get skilled technical people
daughter is clearly being undermined
actively
right there's a market for not learning
the shit to get the search
and oh by the way just because I passed
the exam even if I didn't she
this still doesn't mean have been tax
burden the K
so your professional advancement
you just dropped three grand to go spend
a week in Chicago
studying in cramming for your CISSP you
worked in the industry for four years
you read all eight have shot harris's
books and if you ever meter you're gonna
choke her out
you been buying practice exam so long
boatswain has breached your credit card
twice
and you are frayed and frazzled and you
said through a fucking scantron test
like it was
1988 fares Bueller
just to then go awkwardly ask somebody
at an Issa meeting to sponsor you so she
could desertification and you finally
get it and you go to your boss and you
realize that some
dickhead spent 150 bucks to do the exact
same thing you've been doing six months
time
and your boss knows it now
to somebody send a link to my video will
be on for months
right like you so what does it do to you
what does it do to your bottom line
how do the people that are aware that
this game is going on tell the
difference between this and the person
who like grounded out really knows what
the hell they're doing in the person
that has cheated
they don't
so you've been ripped off
or use Oct cheater you
so-and-so how to search benefit you
if you're and an ethical douchebag
anybody disagree okay so
so who's our winner of course
of course right I see two is raking in
the dough they do. dear crimes fucking
call so gold butts are all these others
because it's an industry everybody wants
to get into you come at a college in
already got experience is really hurt
real above a bar get a certain its you
know
why because it's in the job posting days
to come
you know it Haulover so they're raking
in the money
and ultimately eventually you the stuff
is going to stop being
of high-value both to employers into the
people pursuing certifications
trying to get a career in this field
sucks really sucks so
there any search that don't suck
I'm interlude let's do this is an
audience Paul
break first white oh I see p
GSP
she Chiesi the is that that that some
sand share
alright like like that I get to take it
online
with with Google who
right hey wait remember when I told you
that I have more certs the new
pulitzer
oh okay wait I'm in our time you get
back to you in a minute
Saints so here's the thing I'm gonna
talk about fans in a second but if
you're trying to tell me that
a sans like a any the G Akshay at Silver
level is any better than any other stuff
I just going back and I call bullshit
I do it's bullshit now I'm not saying
that the material in the in the courses
in there
isn't good but do you think if I went to
another part of the site may be able to
find the stamps q's and a's
I will I will give you I will give you a
hint the answer is fuck yeah I did
I mean could so
but I'm gonna skip around and go back to
your point but CNN's gold
break so this is instructor-led stuff
but then you have the right
a practical write a paper get a
peer-reviewed have somebody that has
some cried
look over what you had to do and say hey
this guy actually knows some what he's
talking about
one of the problems that they're still
having in golden it's not it's not
rampant but if I can could become that
they've gold becomes the sand gold
search
become like a thing is is the plagiarism
issue
right plagiarism is a is a is actually
for whatever reason a horrible problem I
know what it is right is because
security still trying to figure out how
the fuck you do this as a as a job
rate we're like if you're a Microsoft
engineer Microsoft listen to the book
right like I mean I'm gonna I'm not say
and that doesn't require talent and
skill and knowledge base and experience
to know that but at the end to the day
there's kinda once or so truth for how
to work with and products that are made
by a vendor
with security it's a it's a whole broad
field so
but getting some peer review ray getting
some be ok demonstrating that you can
actually
put together and collate some parts
around what it is that
that that you wanna the the you want to
put out there as positive
I am you security research well they
demonstrate something more then
I guess D enough times correctly by
Cisco CCIE
not only is this probably the hardest to
cheat at because you have to fly out for
the fuckin lab practical
this is the hardest sir to fake did you
know that they don't print a paper
search for the CCAA I know I try to try
to get one for the for the deck
and what they actually do is they
engrave a plaque it's like a glass like
laser etched plaque is a real bitch to
get one
to end it in it Anna and the guy at the
the trophy store couldn't get it to be
quick enough
for today should I mean every nobody can
get those they're totally affordable
so and then offense if security I am
you're there a I haven't seen anybody
tryin
and I mean I looked around and I
couldn't find anybody cheatin' on the
on a awee year they w/e I'm
I think the backtrack certs a little
cheesy
by you know it is what it is um but it
for
for those of you that don't know when
you actually go to take the AW
recertification
like you get actual binaries and you
have a 72 hour clock that there I'm
to do whatever you can to come up with
an exploit an acute right thing that you
can't research
so the only way to achieve is to get
somebody leaked opponent for you
I mean so I guess you could
you the really I mean if it is that that
point you're smart enough to her hackers
could get to see a españa become a
manager
ago and hey that will make you at least
top 50 percent as you knew where to find
a real hacker
so
okay so how do we change this at the end
of the day the employers a key
right i mean this is this is simple
trickle-down economics right
the employers are leveraging search to
find people hired to pay their
those people that would like to get that
money or that have that money and want
more of that money
are the ones paying to take the
certifications and then that money goes
in large volumes into the hands
the certifying bodies the companies that
do this stuff
so the end of the day employers have got
to get out
love the paper have it and actually
start asking people to demonstrate
skills
now I want to tell you a sad little
story
but its it's sad because it's a sad
commentary on the world
I did in fact get hired at that job
at Speedway back in college and Speedway
is the only company to have ever
required me
to test on skills I had to pass a bad
past
I had to pass I shit you not that maybe
put the smack on the right way like the
the cheesy I think they're polos now
it's Peter and I don't go inside hit the
power brake but
the you but but back then you had to
wear a smock
and you had to put it on right and and
then they made me
I and then they may be count make change
that was the last time I spoke in
eighteen years old is the last time
somebody asked me to prove that I knew
how to do the job they were hiring me
for and in just taken off my resume
a guy is a nice guy and he's like not
totally socially retarded so
will bring him in they didn't know I'd
just land halfway decent social engineer
ever I I read the the are the deception
that I got a good
today
but by the way shout out to to kevin
Mitnick for agreed to be my opening act
today that was so
so nice for them to fly out for their
cell
alright so focus on skills test for them
in interviews
there is nothing I was sitting across
the table from somebody that you're
trying to hire making them do something
really hard on the spot this is security
after a
we was going to do clues to make
somebody do that would under pressure
thirteeners
fuck you have you ever had a bad day in
security like do you have any idea how
horrible it can be issued by
you should be good under pressure if you
crumble under pressure even if you know
the technical should get out
go teach I hear it. PD is hiring
alright so yes stop relying on certs
and at the very least here's the other
thing for all the times that I've ever
applied to a job in Lake
send them a copy like just a photocopy
love
love certifications that I have to
qualify for you for the job you know how
many times they verify their
exactly zero right I mean is so if you
back up like those
you know I don't know many people caught
it early totally would like but with all
the numbers on those certain stuff
fairly
midsummer me easy summer here a little
harder you can
you know asking about later but anyway
the
bill 0.08 is so that you can validate
the that's a real certification right
except for the fact that like you know
if you're lucky enough to have a pretty
common name you may just
you'll be able to go search the registry
for your own name in the pot on there
any Photoshop shit
but it doesn't matter cuz they will look
anyway they just won't work they don't
look
HR doesn't care they're not interested
in spending any time
doing anymore research they like poets
on their can I get a copy copy be
something that has the same Mike four
letters hun it is the
thing re probably never even seen one
before so
so it starts with the employer and
realistically I think for the IT
management and the roommate is not fair
to ask HR
to get on board with this I mean it you
know just say to them like I don't care
so much about certs are not spend so
much time on certain looking for certain
keywords or whatever
but admit hiring people is just gonna be
hard
and it's worth doing even though it's
gonna be hard rates were
it's worth it's worth taking the time to
get the right people on your team
rather than ending up with you
government
there so
for the rest have you in the room though
that are going to do any hiring illegal
voting this was always to 40 minutes
thanks a lot asshole
so but that
but no you you have something to do this
to ride
I don't hire people I don't wanna be
hired then lead by example
right step up be be an example %uh what
you want the industry to be like instead
of
because everybody's running around
getting the search even the people like
me
baguette I could totally get that like
I'm a fucking hypocrite
I own that I'm really good at it
but those but the reality is it raises
were all just chasing cert
we're all just running around like
trying to put alphabet soup on our
resumes
because we think that's how people will
judge our skill and our ability to your
job
then we as legitimate security
practitioners
just for their the myth that that really
is what matters
right so the next time somebody sends me
a resume
with their name comma some certification
I like I am so tempted to use tear it up
at yet no thank you I email them back
and say no thank you
thanks but no thank you how next year
you to come up here do this you're
bigger dick than me that's awesome
so
um you you throw like a sis p
I America in
back at her so
anyway so talk about your
accomplishments ray if you've been in
this industry for years long enough to
go get your CISSP
if that's the coolest thing you can put
on your resume 5 back
right do something interesting right
even if your job sucks cuz
cuz admittedly some part of everybody's
job sucks and some other people in this
room have jobs that
only suck right I'm day but you know
what
I way so is the custodian from the last
place in here
okay right so i've seen what you freaks
have done in the bathroom this in the
past two days
that guy's job is worse than yours to
point that out
I'm so even if you don't have anything
called put on your resume because you
did something cool at work do something
cool on the side
right I would so much rather hear from
somebody
who's like and and I can I can think I
have at least a half dozen people in
this room right now
were in this situation who've done
something really fuckin sweet
on the side like an open source project
or a
your research paper rate that got
involved and it's gotten
maybe something to do with what they do
at work maybe not by
they do something awesome and it's
actually kinda become a key piece of
who they are as a professional talking
rock on good for you
put something out there like don't just
doin even if even if you're like hmm not
I'm not awesome enough to like hold a
whole thing
on everybody in the room to like cheer
for the
a for the forensic challenge if you did
it who did the DFI our challenge this
year
clap fire great so
volatility Lake kick your ass today to
Denair
had Jack your tag attacks the man well
that was brutal
so anyway um fun challenge that's that's
all written in Python you can tear all a
ballot ility apart write your own plugin
like tomorrow
and just a minute to the Google Code
site right I mean that's a that's a
project you can get involved in today
that is the hotness
right and that's just the that's just
one example I get to get a bunch others
that are represented in this room here
today even know this is kinda
yo small local time right so great
opportunities to get involved
may even if you're not going to do that
do a professional organization speak get
back
goal earned a network go further the
dialogue over you know go for them
and and make merry whatever I'm
but do something other than just you
know sat on your ass and and study for
for a test
or even even if you're you feel like
isolated like from
you know I can't get out a group I've
got like this this
ya horrible boss who makes me work like
60 hours a week
or arm you know there's no money for
training I live in the sticks whatever
the deal is
right session on mailing lists we all
have internet access I mean
how the house would you hear about this
car I mean
you i lub
I love you and know I love you guys but
come on it's not like it's not like I
got a flyer in my mailbox nom time
series right though like
are you what hahaha will be clear this
up because this is not intended to be a
troll on pink a nag
for a so fuckin are the first things
first the whole fucking room right now
fucking clap for pink and agen captain
in the rescue yellow shirts
that made this happen fuck
Park yeah far yeah alright self
at my point though was right you guys
don't make any money on this i mean
9 right so they don't have a massive
budget to reach out outside this is all
this on internet girlish a guess what
the internet matters
if you're in this review better fucking
hope so right
so so get out there get involved in an
online community even if you can get a
local community even if you don't know
how to code
you know thing one you probably know
something and if you don't go learn and
then
share what you learned with others it's
that simple
I would so much rather name Google the
next candidate that comes across my desk
ago
well look at this guy out there
answering questions correctly
on the Internet on things like you know
already out so
so here's one here's at your homework
assignment for anybody
who think you are getting the CISSP to
go get some good karma
go study how I can IC camp work
and then go correct every CISSP ever
on how I P sec phase one works cuz they
all get it wrong it's wrong the CBK it's
wrong everywhere
thank God for them check point made it
next button
so so there you go
record does hard for tomor crypto be
good so
anyway if you do things like that be put
yourself out there
then you won't need to set for a test
you don't need a piece a paper to tell
you that your valuable
and at the end of the day somebody like
me
might get it might sit across the table
from you and say
you're hired
I'm fucking out
you
hurry the fuck up
a another big hammer Duncan
so um
you're still here so anybody is coming
to the
after party you know the wristband I was
he just this you coming to the
after after party we have your bracelet
be a GP sports 8 o'clock
rusher have other arrangements right
you know to do
Service here. the one when some shit man
what a crappy giveaway
so you're here but the little money you
paid to be here actually got you
something I guess
besides beer and watching people vomit
outsiders and shit
right I'm
a the the UK guy so here the outside
pass out
again vinik's
now now the mean drunk by the way picked
a fight with the bartender last night
you did
no Iraq
so bear with us I'm fat and slow and
tired it. physique
therein
I so we call on a man I hear they're
gonna give after losing to the prize up
to a random person
which may differ so
where this payout
Justin cock pic village your prize or
give it out
where you my peer become
my sack in Justin's run a lockpick
village he actually rains his own
sponsor
night that's fucking awesome those but
the two was a little busy
alright
see a lot of people here the axis of the
village so did you at least learn
something
got everybody else wants gay
all first off thank you
Chris Jamie for asking me to do this cuz
I don't work in this industry and I
don't know stuff
but I'm up here and also thank you do
Ryan are husak for
all the help lot to help are with all
the organization keeping an eye on
things cuz pics have a 10 seed grow legs
and walk
so anyways are
bloody guys competed in the challenge
today
we allow to cool prizes given way to you
first place with the time of 50 seconds
Alex savaria monitored
the grand prize
24-piece professional lock pick set from
storm lock picks 150 dollar value
nice job you slow
I
second place with the time a fifty-five
seconds
Nathan Blevins and he gets his choice to
either
the storm Raider or bogota set and
ring pack
show up
overtime
job
and last but certainly not least
third-place
the time of 1 minute lamar benjamin
it's a
you the fuck out here
hurry up your past hour earlier reston
up
lazy
act so the a.m capture the flag contest
recalls but for it Asian
but Roos to server no wonder around a
ship that
by kept dropping those welts OS-two
really
I know where you work intern
so
third-place with a bag a random shit we
got for free
is I'm gonna put your name dude sorry
Adam mmm ago low
I wanna fuck are you
that you are going up an awesome t-shirt
on
it even comes in is really
awesome back yes there's also
donated by our sponsors 30 you forgot
her
alright second place is Sean Nicol in
where I got here
all that mother fucker really well use
least get actual like money set school
you do we take donations by the way
fuck you I can hear you
next a Mac to get all the flags and our
winner is
really corrodes
and I cheated
he sits the next to me in my day job
you know where my boss is he here
but no i did some the fact that maria
are very is here
alright where they were when the floppy
disks challenge
is a lazy fuck didn't come get the prize
so your dq sorry though pointed as maker
and walk around all day
with a fucking trophy I give to somebody
else they want it
who had mister mitnick signing and
standout was the attractor trophy I
that a boy three innings
I never forensics challenge now
Robin might you both turn in the same
question the same time
so you as you fight or the rain and shit
in a bag at their place come up here
next end up fuckin sheet of each other
I dad screen you guys you can be
make out later figured out
night you know welcome appear
Joico me fat ass the Brit I'm I
do resemble that yes alright
shut up nobody cares I say Moses ran the
arkin necks your day there you go sorry
buddy very sorry but
yet you also get money
bags in the VIP area badly get him
alright
first places i know im but your name
dude I'm sorry
Peter Piot are
like
I'm up here iraq ready to eat much next
time
well we should all have a hard time
member who gets the lifetime bash next
year
does know if has your fuckin name I
here any that and that was a pretty hard
challenge
again thanks to check written je vreme
together for Susie here
bisbee you drunk already matthau alright
well
value right now my fair contest
a pic Joe
i winner is John hack to get one to end
it in it Anna and the guy at the
the trophy store could get it to be
quick enough first to dash
I mean I mean nobody can get those
they're totally affordable so
and then offense if security I am you're
there
a I haven't seen anybody tryin and I
mean I looked around and I couldn't find
anybody cheatin'
I'm not gonna awee year they w/e I'm
I think the backtrack certs a little
cheesy
by you know it is what it is um but it
for
for those of you that don't know when
you actually go to take the AW
recertification
like you get actual binaries and you
have a 72 hour clock that there I'm
to do whatever you can to come up with
an exploit in a contrived thing that you
can't research
so the only way to achieve is to get
somebody lied to pony up for you
I mean so I guess you could
you the really I mean if it is that that
point you're smart enough to her hackers
could get to see a españa become a
manager
bigger and hey that will make you at
least top 50 percent cuz you knew where
to find a real hacker
so
okay so how do we change this at the end
of the day the employers a key
right i mean this is this is simple
trickle-down economics right
the employers are leveraging search to
find people hired to pay their
those people that would like to get that
money or that have that money and want
more of that money
are the ones paying you to take the
certifications and then that money goes
in large volumes into the hands
the certifying bodies the companies that
do this stuff
so the end in today employers have got
to get out above the paper habit
and actually start asking people to
demonstrate skills now I want to tell
you a sad little story
but its it's sad because it's a sad
commentary on the world I did in fact
get hired at that job at Speedway
back in college and Speedway is the
only company to have ever required me
to test our skills I had to pass up back
past
I had to pass I shit you not that maybe
put the smack on the right way like the
the cheesy I think they're polos now
it's Peter and I don't go inside pip
operate but
the you but but back then you had to
wear a smock
and you had to put it on right and and
then they made me
I and then they may be count make change
that was the last time I spoke in
eighteen years old as the last time
somebody asked me to prove that I knew
how to do the job they were hiring me
for and in just taken off my resume
a guy he's a nice guy and he's like not
totally socially retarded so
will bring him in they didn't know I
understand halfway decent social
engineer
their I I read the the are the
dissection that I got a good
today
but by the way shout out to to kevin
Mitnick for agreed to be my opening act
today that was so
so nice for them to fly out for their
cell
alright so focus on skills test for them
in interviews
there's nothing I was sitting across the
table from somebody that you're trying
to hire making them do something really
hard on the spot this is security after
a
we was going to do clues to make
somebody do that would under pressure
thirteeners
fuck you have you ever had a bad day in
security like do you have any idea how
horrible it can be issued by
you should be good under pressure if you
crumble under pressure even if you know
the technical should get out
go teach I hear it. PD is hiring
alright so yes stop relying on certs
and at the very least here's the other
thing for all the times that I've ever
applied to a job in like
send them a copy like just a photocopy
love
love certifications that I have to
qualify for you for the job you know how
many times they verify their
exactly zero right I mean is so if you
back up like those
you know I don't know many people caught
it early totally would like for to have
all the numbers on those certain stuff
fairly
midsummer me easy summer here a little
harder you can
you know asking about later but anyway
the
bill 0.08 rate is so that you can
validate
the that's a real certification right
except for the fact that like you know
if you're lucky enough to have a pretty
common name you may just
you'll be able to go search the registry
for your own name in the pot on there
any Photoshop church but it doesn't
matter cuz they will look anyway they
just won't work
they don't look HR doesn't care they're
not interested
in spending any time doing anymore
research village poets on their
can I get a copy copy be something that
has the same make four letters honey
this the
thing re probably never even seen one
before so
so it starts with the employer and
realistically I think
for the IT management and the roommate
is not fair to ask HR
to get on board with this I mean it you
know just say to them like I don't care
so much about certs
not spend so much time on certain
looking for certain keywords or whatever
but admit hiring people is just gonna be
hard
and it's worth doing even though it's
gonna be hard right it's worth it's
worth
it's worth taking the time to get the
right people on your team
rather than ending up with you
government
there so
for the rest the view in the room though
that are going to do any hiring illegal
fighting this was always to 40 minutes
thanks a lot asshole
so but that
but no you you have something to do this
to write but I don't hire people i jus
wanna be hired
then lead by example right step up BB an
example %uh
what you want the industry to be like
instead of
because everybody's running around
getting the search even the people like
me
baguette I could totally get that like
I'm a fucking hypocrite
I own that I'm really good at it
but those but the reality is it raises
were all just chasing cert
we're all just running around like
trying to put alphabet soup on our
resumes
because we think that's how people judge
or skill and our ability to your job
then we as legitimate security
practitioners
just for their the myth that that really
is what matters
right so the next time somebody send me
your resume
with their name comma some certification
I like I am so tempted to use tear it up
at yet no thank you right back email
them back and say no thank you
thanks but no thank you how next year
you to come up here do this you're
bigger dick than me that's awesome
so
um you throw like a sis p
I alright in
back atcha so
anyway so talk about your
accomplishments ray if you've been in
this industry for years long enough to
go get your CISSP
if that's the coolest thing you can put
on your resume 5 back
right do something interesting may even
if your job sucks cuz
cuz admittedly some part of everybody's
job sucks and some other people in this
room have jobs that
only suck right I'm day but you know
what
I way so is the custodian from the last
place in here
okay right so i've seen what you freaks
have done in the bathroom this year the
past two days
that guy's job is worse than yours to
point that out
i'd so even if you don't have anything
called put on your resume because you
did something cool at work do something
cool on the side
but I would so much rather hear from
somebody
who's like and and I can I can think I
have at least a half dozen people in
this room right now
were in this situation who've done
something really fuckin sweet on the
side like an open source project or
a your research paper rate that got
involved and it's gotten
maybe something to do with what they do
at work maybe not by
they do something awesome and it's
actually kinda become a key piece of
who they are as a professional talking
rock on good for you
put something out there like don't just
doin even if even if you're like hmm not
I'm not awesome enough to Lake hold a
whole thing
on everybody in the room to like cheer
for the
a for the forensic challenge if you did
it who did the DFI our challenge this
year
clap fire great so
volatility Lake kick your ass today to
Denair
had Jack your tag attacks the man on
those bruno
so anyway um fun challenge that's that's
all written in Python you can tear all a
ballot ility apart write your own plugin
like tomorrow
and just a minute to the Google Code
site right i mean that's a that's a
project you can get involved in today
that is the hotness
right and that's just the that's just
one example I can to get a bunch others
that are represented in this room here
today even know this is kinda
yo small local time right so
great opportunities to get involved may
even if you're not going to do that do a
professional organization speak get back
goal earned a network go further the
dialogue over you know go for them
and and make merry whatever um
but do something other than just you
know sit on your ass and and study for
for a test
or even even if you're you feel like
isolated like from
you know I can get out a group I've got
like this this
yo horrible boss who makes me work like
60 hours a week
or arm you know there's no money for
training I live in the sticks whatever
the deal is
right say shit on mailing lists we all
have internet access I mean
how the house would you hear about this
car I mean
you I love I love you and know I love
you guys but come on it's not like
it's not like I got a flyer in my
mailbox number I'm series right oleg
are you what hahaha will be clear this
up because this is not intended to be a
troll on pink a nag
for a so fuckin are the first things
first the whole fucking room right now
fucking clap for pink a nagging captain
in the rescue yellow shirts
that made this happen fuck
bark yeah far yeah alright self
at my point though was right you guys
don't make any money on this i mean
9 right so they don't have a massive
budget to reach out outside this is all
this on internet girlish a guess what
the internet matters
if you're in this review better fucking
hope so right
so so get out there get involved in an
online community even if you can get a
local community even if you don't know
how to code
you know thing one you probably know
something and if you don't go learn and
then
share what you learned with others it's
that simple
I would so much rather name Google the
next candidate that comes across my desk
ago
well look at this guy out there
answering questions correctly
on the Internet on things like you know
already out so
so here's one here's that your homework
assignment for anybody
who think you are getting the CISSP to
go get some good karma
go study how I can IC camp work
and then go correct every CISSP ever
on how I P sex phase one works cuz they
all get it wrong it's wrong the CBK it's
wrong everywhere
thank God for them check point made it
next button
so so there you go
record does hardcore gamer crypto be
good so
anyway if you do things like that you
put yourself out there
then you won't need to set for a test
you don't need a piece a paper to tell
you that your valuable
and at the end of the day somebody like
me
might get it might sit across the table
from you and say
you're hired
I'm fucking out