so good morning everybody I'm Johnny
I'm just a quick review of being on from
Israel
income that's the farthest that anyone
has ever come
to and this place um
in my training I am in army officer
intelligence officer for its third for
about eight years
and the Israeli intelligence core then
I became a consultant for the Ministry
of Defence the Israeli minister defense
transferred for a few months for the
Department of Defense your Department of
Defense
and the than now
which is my current position I'm a
manager at
the hectic said Van Security Center
which is
accompany acquired by Ernst & Young I
think that everybody heard of earnest in
young nobody really thinks I'm Ernst &
Young in this capacity
so what they did is you know the
american way that the
just bought someone so um
where I a former military on
intelligence outfit though we're about
thirty five guys
think were forty now um
acquired like a year ago we have all
sorts of analysts
geyser do Chinese Arabic Farsi Russian
and Turkish
is urs allow out there and you probably
are wondering why do you need all these
guys doing all these
languages because some when we do
an assessment security assessment we
take it one step further and that's
actually gathering intelligence I and on
intelligence that
you might have heard of you know like
one ability intelligence there's a new
her ability that intelligence
that's not intelligence what we do is
we assess and we gaffer and we'll talk a
bit
about what the tools that we use I will
give you
I a proof-of-concept for you to think I
love
on how to gather intelligence on what so
just a small %ah up primer on on
intelligence some
before we we actually go into this we
need to understand that are several
field intelligence
are we actually this talk is a bit about
sigan which is signal intelligence and a
bit about
human jus human intelligence now seconds
um is what you know as the guy in the
middle love the wire
you know like man in the middle but and
a for more capacity oven nation or state
somebody listening into the conversation
it includes I want to go into the
details in close mass in alan was
measurement intelligence
comin radar intelligence all the
boringest that most boring
a types of intelligence we're not
talking about these guys
awesome which is open source
intelligence
now which is actually reading and
sifting through media
open media and understanding what's out
there um
there are there's a lot of good stuff
and the open-source
I'm not open source computer style open
source
very different and there's web in which
is
arm a a sub practice
I've of sandwiches is talking on forms
but not exactly participating it's a
very complex
way to to say that it's different from
%ah cents but
down we talked intelligence officer they
have to make this difference
humint is the one that we all know James
Bond thats humint
working your magic around people so
let's go to our subject which is social
networking specifically Facebook but
let's talk about the most common
perceptions that if you work in an
in a corporation or everywhere else at
people
believe of social networks mostly
mass destruction right um
well we don't actually look at it like
this it is more of
our dream you know we would like to
be in the room the first day that
somebody wanted the director of the CIA
agents that will there's this Scott this
thing called Facebook
people actually put their content online
you'd only to find it they update it and
I love the American Way is the fact that
the CIA if it really like someone is
actually funds it
and one of the initial funding was by
up the venture capital I
guys from the CIA queuing to remember
name
I'm the funding Facebook they give it
five million 10 million I remember
the initial funding so fifty they're
really like that
no wonder so
they really liked it because you got 845
million
monthly active users and
when the Facebook got its on stock
altogether
arm they had to actually show all the
statistics that they're actually rights
and
how much are fake profile home under
real profile
I love interesting stuff now not exactly
the property of the US but
for the rest of the world or everyone
who wishes to buy Facebook stock
arm and you can see the state ominous
just amazing
the amount of users you were talking
about active users not someone that
opened an account then just forgot about
it or unused I R fake profile and stuff
like that
actual users so
their lineup good and bad things that
could
come from Facebook um a very well-known
are example is oh what's it called that
the Arab Spring
and all sorts have a venues that it
happened
afterwards which is the Syrian
Revolution and which
using social networks a lot of
basis that they are ruled by Dec 30 ship
I
were able to assemble and rebels were
able to communicate
using social networks and actually one
voice can be heard over
thousands and millions I you guys from
me know this
I want the American now wave using it
an Invisible Children the a coney 2012
um which is also the way
I've using Facebook but of course
we're gonna hop over to China because we
need to talk about bad thanks
and some we have a very malicious and
won't see very malicious to a malicious
uses Juve Facebook a very well-known 10
K
that China suspected have actually
setting up a fake profile love one of
the head there operatives
and nato and actually friending
all sorts of nato officials and you know
your boss wants a friend you on facebook
you gonna say no
I and they said yes an affordable the
fake profile they did not suspected that
the beginning and they got a lot of open
source intelligence on the specific
nato officials and funny thing is was
it these was that got the word the guys
from nato that are in charge
love cyber there's a yeah
and and now in Estonia in Tolland they
have fun
they have this the CDO we r remember a
lot of initials
I it's about cyber okay it was after
that the DoS attack the alleged Russian
the DoS attack on on talent
they open the center there and well
everybody could fall for it um
one of the major things is the
transition towards facebook when it
comes to
I jihadists jihadist activists
arm jihadist activists or jihadist
terrorists are
um of terrorists that to do their
activities in the name of God
we're not gonna say that specific name
of God because it has given rise to a
lot of problems during these last days
um so some we can see a transition
towards a
sure social networking arm the gaffer
here and they actually tell you
what is the specific targets that there
are after
arm its most common for de dos attacks
as much as it's not you know our a very
fretful
well attack vector it's still something
that causes destruction
I love business
so the real question is does anyone care
i mean
this is a growing field then you have a
lot of ability to do good
or bad so what does does anyone
think of this I mean besides the CIA
so apparently the FBI I are very
interested in and social media
as you might think and died actually
wanted to our
to ask someone to develop a tool for
them
so from actually went and our
that a tender online tender and they
asked for people to
give them you know where r an RFID and
ask them
could we develop this tool and I it's
all about social media
I'm force well economist that because
they have kinda high hopes
for distal um the actually want to be
able to have a worldwide terror data
and a US domestic terror data and the US
embassies & Company consulates & mission
what this is not exactly what you wanna
the Facebook
that's very nice but it's like getting
world domination by Facebook
it doesn't happen by day and now by a
tool
so the funny thing you know with open
source intelligence is a good data
examples that
someone actually asked them on their
site arm
do you have a to you mean Rd trying to
bring up their capability or so
something that no well this is a new
requirement for the FBI we've known
its not something we do that's good to
know
um we can see a goal over into
got the legal system now we had a case
not that tough are going August are
where
are the court ruled that information
into a that was gathered
using I am a profile from
someone that actually was a rat so now
that you know
are wanted to the to bring out his
friend and he wanted to say all sorts of
stuff
and the the judge actually allow didn't
say that Facebook users may actually
this site to keep their profile
completely private shared them only with
friends
or more explicitly with friends or
friends which means you
it doesn't really matter if it's private
that's you know
everybody can see it and we could use it
as Intel we could use and legal system
we can use it
wherever we'd like to so not only
intelligence
also the legal system so
what about the private sector what have
they done about
so um if you guys have heard the have
arm Anco else one of the
largest are oil manufacturers and Saudi
Arabia
I think it's the largest in the world
well also the world is there
I and they actually I reported
a breach a data breach on their network
and they actually went online with it
and they did under Facebook page
very bluntly they said well that's what
happened and down
or not you know very vaguely the later
later discussed the
more a details but very vaguely but
it was online see a lot of people liking
in this
this is this is a really funny hit so up
once once they've publish it I mean it's
out there on Facebook
you know what happens their employees
are commenting
and you get also serve weird stuff that
I mean is that why my email doesn't work
and it's kind of a funny way to get to
know you know get your acknowledgement
on the attack
did it work are their mail system
doesn't work okay
so it's related and we have all sorts
OVA are comments and people giving IP is
within the network because
the guide to publish that was the
network administrator
so it was that there was a way to to
convict him instead of you know just
Eileen
they went online and it was private
I'm well as private data that we went on
to the public
go so we have a lot of things that
people say about their corporations
and people don't really understand that
this is private data
and they don't really understand I the
problems that
they actually a a cause once they you
know give out
private information of an organization
and really helps an attacker understand
what
is it that you have within your
organization I mean we have Lotus Notes
as well
okay I don't know publishing it
so basically all comes to the the basic
assumption
I mean you do not have a bad for him
stability
is a Russian guys area
I have I have in israel week I'll about
a million
russian immigrants and there's a huge
are Russian community
and and I'm the guy that I have a good
friend
russian of course and he said while
these are Russian guys I so well how do
you how do you respond to see the beer
right next to that one this is this is
keen net
this is a good beers's said only
russians friend get this is really
shitty beer
I and of course
this this is only a Russian contraction
so a bit about hype I we're talking
about BBT
I hate using the words we have about to
a slight so maybe which is advanced
persistent threat
um also it's a buzz on what it does and
the fact that they have used all sorts
of advanced gathering on intelligence
math Phys
yeah you know but have above crap um
but let us understand exactly I
what is it that there after I mean
before we're talking about the Y let's
talk about
how do I find my target because this is
something that
people just dismiss sake yeah they one
out then they just
single them out is that johnnie
okay and his coworkers okay let's find
johnnie
it's not an easy thing to do I mean
johnnie's not within the management of
Ernst & Young
you don't have them online and connected
directly to all his friends
ordered the saying goes to if assumable
the
Rs they would have been attacked with an
advanced
persistent fret that is a big if
um they would have done scoping far less
intelligence so let's just understand I
mean we're trying to fish someone
outright
use spearfishing like everybody likes to
say
so how do we how do fish
I mean just like a set we have johnny is
1 percent you have the advance
securities under which is like 45 guys
and girls and up he why is like 250,000
that's huge even the israeli practices
like
I 1700 that's a lotta love
other people so
assist star of the basic assumption I
mean my attacker
I'll would actually know me he knows
that i works for you why
and that's a well we tried to willey
Google hack as well
well there could be an option but we're
talking about Facebook here and there is
a slight problem you know if he'd
actually use Google hacking
there's a small indexing more than
actually prevents it I
Yahweh they don't if if you know that
that
once you go to to the facebook when you
wanna translate something when you wanna
use map resources you always get
most amazing guy search engine in the
world big
just good for searching google um so
soda this is this is a small issue and
you can really do it using Google will
so
cool having is out Anderson nice tool
called the harvester
on which actually helps you get all
sorts of names and phone numbers and
being research I don't know why being um
anne gets a lot of data a lot of data
but it's not really
it doesn't really help us here because
it doesn't have facebook aunt
remember most people have facebook not a
lot of people have linked and then you
know
it's really it's not something globally
I mean I i talked
virtually all over the world and and
only in Israel and the US I saw a lot of
people using Arlington
jus ideal for gathering in 30
information intelligence but
are a case sup what's a basic answer
so let's think it over
ever heard above about that touch ref
maybe it's a basic hyperbolic tree
which means yeah I know that that that
doesn't really
look all that useful looks like an
angioplasty or something like that
but and actually as a good
representation at
when it does the an analysis it looks
like this
which for intelligence officer is a
dream
um what it actually maps out as the
group
within your Facebook profile it maps out
the connection
and in here you have hectic sedan
Security Center
I ran it on my profile which is great
I mean you have my officer school here
you got one of the units that serve you
got
now University stuff like that which is
ideal
but its kinda cheating because I ran
from my profile with my permissions and
I know
johnnie because I am johnnie and it is
cheating
so a if we look at how touch craft does
that
it goes through Facebook's API it's
called graph
um you need to have a 20 can access
token to get there
actually wrote it down there is the
access token and every act as though he
gets you
grants you a permission for every
operation
so its kind and not the way to go
because we don't have permissions
so let's go back to our assumption
if we know your friends I know you
everybody knows you at a friends tell me
your friends and I'll tell you who you
are
let's see if it works so
others my profile page and my
for places listed right so
basically it's the same assumption for
all my colleagues
mean you could see it here as the
younger here see on
over place so
if we want and do it ourselves we could
actually achieve it
even that is a bold statement
as I set I mean we have this we have
that which is the friends list and
within the friends list we can see other
people that have the Y in it
but it's likely different all the time
so it's not really that much of an easy
search
arm you can go through every one of my
friends in a friend's friend in
this is done through a profile which is
not a friend if anyone
this is not linked to anyone
so it's kind of a simple solution isn't
it
I mean you just need to aggregate it you
need to search it
all by yourself mean it is simple is a
I found X so
but if we work out we need to actually
be
profitable me to make its and real time
and I have 400 friends and above in my
next and the next guy has than the next
guy has that
it takes a long time a long long time
about 1300 hours and just that's just
looking over to profile and marking it
so it's not really the solution
but let's think of it this is me very
good depiction
and I have a friend called along any as
a friend although for
I know along a long nose over
of a Muslim now for anyone that has
study mathematics it's called The Clique
okay it's it's a close group we all know
everybody
click could be these free could be 6
could be a lot of people
but the main issue is the fact that
everybody knows
everyone so it's a closed group
so here promising what was that help
so we have up we have a tool that we've
developed
I in a nutshell what does it starts with
a profile a targeted profile for example
me
and then it goes to my friends an
automated tool
it crawls through Facebook it performs a
recursion
that it goes through my friends my
friends friends and my friends friends
depends on the level that I actually
asking to go to
and a great an XML evolve these
individuals
and then analyzes the connections
so said i've watching the video we're
gonna wash into
so this is you know this is not a
masterpiece over to was just %uh for
proof of concept um
this is a profile this the two was this
one it looks like a browser because it's
based on a browser
course on because you remember what we
said that if we use
Facebook API Facebook will shut us down
after free trials free crawling able
mom Ivor give us a captcha up or Justin
I have
than I S axis but this is a me or
the fake me Leah the film on Pacific
profile
a woman no doubt um
she has no friends only two friends
there are not really related to me
I'm and specifically what I do
is I go when try to find me
what you need internet connection for a
it's a major issue
as we're waiting
up
that that has to happen of course
so let us see why doesn't
it
we don't so we're gonna watch a video
year
always have second plan
so we go through we at the at has a no
friends we
go in search through yawning which is me
johnny's yawning you can see that
if you were his friend so it means that
you're not his friend she's not my
friend
so she does start or get
friends a friend's get full of I goes in
crawl through my friends as you can see
and on PR right you can see it starting
on me I'm specific be
the target and that navigates onto
facebook and goes on to all my friends
and you can see here that scrolls down
because we're
imitating a browser any the scroll down
option
it involved that you found on friends
and then you manually go through all the
france
now I don't care because this is a tool
so it doesn't cost me money I just but
decided
works its magic right so
at the end while it is has crawled
through all my friends
I then take all the data
onto a different tool Facebook research
it loads all the data that was achieved
was a
aggregated and then what it does
actually as this definition
a finding groups a group of three
as alone of Phil and me as you see
an what does it actually compares the
connection
between the people has it found the
connection at
works its magic works his magic and then
once you once that they actually are
recognizes Rupert says bingo found a
group
arm and this Pacifica a
example you don't have it but we'll see
what happens because we do have the
process data
at the end we have a graph that looks
like this you're probably wondering I
mean that's not
that's not you know such graph of course
that's not that graph
but this is information achieved from
someone which is not your friend
but as a friend of a friend okay and not
even
not a friend I mean I just someone to
crawl through Facebook
an on/off arris profile that his
indexed all your friends cuz it started
from
from Yani you can see that has all my
friends take the graph to load a bit
and then
if I drill down an icy and I just click
on any one of my friends I could see
a different connection between his
friends but
we are interested in these graphs that
we could see the connections
we're specifically going after each
enough for connection between
johnnie and his friend from tactics
from advance Security Center why is that
so important
well the most important thing is that
before both through the examples
it's useless arm if I'll go n
search on one of the profiles once I see
there's a connection
to me even if I'm not tagged their I
have one
profile on one photo on my profile its
easily
recognizable if an analyst gets the data
gets the list above all the group that
johnny is listed in
which is not an open
it's not open data I mean you don't go
out to the world and say
this this this is this are my friend
from high school
these are my friends from college these
are my colleagues he's on my colleagues
from this place
and so forth what a noun list with do
is one say he has this this type of data
it he knows that course that that step
he knows that specifically
it has to do it specifically you can see
group
likes tennis live yanni shy hand all
when they all fail
and the other we can actually the deuce
at these people are connected together
because what happens is that in every
graph
we have a different part of that group
why is that because not everybody knows
everybody on Facebook me for example you
have a good example that
my boss which is tile Moses doesn't
necessarily
no this guy who create on doesn't know
or is not friends %uh these people but
we can have stance in all groups
so there is a connection probably work
related
shy friend also in all the groups when
you look back specifically if you go
when asked I'll
which is a very good question on now
20 most employers he says well I don't
ask
my employees to to friend me on Facebook
if de friend me I
approved but so this is what happens
here you can see it on the graph
this is that the beauty of seeing at
with three graphs because
if you have to graph you have permission
to rip off route you have all
permissions
that's ideal but this gives you
everyone people there are not directly
connected
but are connected because tile
specifically
is the employer of these guys but he's
just not their friend on Facebook
so what an analyst will do is go and
sift through the profiles I mean
Johnny and tile could have the most
hardened profile
you couldn't see a single photo on the
you know the profile photo and stuff
like that
and if you can see the profile for just
puttin
isn't his mail on Facebook and click
enter and log and it will give you are
you johnnie and
you'll see the picture um and
I you could see and then an analyst
knowing who is Johnny how does it look
like
could go from the specific group he
doesn't need to go through
400 by the power 400 he has these groups
he
that they're closed group um this is
only a demonstration
I've close number but we can get
up to 10 individuals in a single group
so if you have this you could see thirty
people almost thirty people
on this specific I graph arm all
depending on
the actual connections between these
these individuals
and this is all opens opened and to the
public
coming I don't think that to be a friend
of someone there are
to all the tools that you know if your
friend of a friend
then you could do something the Act is
not my friend
nor is it nor is she a friend of any of
my friends
um but she was able to sift through and
crawl through all the specific profiles
and get all this specific data we did
not get
a single capture from Facebook told to
just two to run it to crawl through it
takes about a week okay a whole week
have just running in crawling
just aggregating the data and Facebook
did not do anything about it
the yacht is the most irregular or
anomalous profile in the world she has
two friends
which are free other fake profile and
she then crawls through have a facebook
and nothing
pops out nobody gives that you know the
funny thing is
if the app will start asking friendship
then
were a facebook will work their magic
and say of this is anomalous
but if you just watches profile
I mean that's okay you know so back to
our
to our discussion
I'm not saying at the end I'm not saying
not
use Facebook okay is
this is the a blunt statement butts
when I first II started with this
I had a lot of people from the
intelligence community that
that used Facebook and there may now
their main argument was you know
I mean I've heard my profile you know we
could do anything
and and they said well you know let's
see if there's something else that
people could
you know aggregate on us because we're
all hard
and there are a lot of people on similar
positions army intelligence is just a
close community but
core corporate management or
finance finances your main target as an
actor
and not because I'm Ernst & Young but
it is and the best targets I
a lot of people hold positions that they
don't understand how much
open source data could be aggregated on
them and what Rd consequences ovett
and just like these little piggies cons
going on
ever not their products you know are
actually it's given free but you know
if if if it's not that one then
your to product and yeah you are being
sold
so you can make your chili your choice I
mean
you could stay n or you can opt up you
can't really opt out but you know
you get my drift that's it guys
hope you enjoyed it here
any questions