yeah so where do it up Python talk to be
a open source intelligence gathering
talk and exactly whom I
so I am really I'm a student at Eastern
Michigan University studying I
yeah I'm on the
extended stay plan which means I'll be
done
in sometime are I but
a I am at thirty 7.2 on Twitter feel
free to spam me with whatever
I don't care up I'm also a analyst at a
company in novae
do in social media customer relations
are management and yet so
soon at Easter so what are we talking
about
it's the OSA gathering methods are we've
research with implications
specifically in social engineering for
this talk but it extends far into
marketing staff
ants I your intelligence world so we're
gonna play with Twitter
is what we're gonna do today we use
Python to do it where he's a model call
tweet by
but before we dive into the actual API
stuff in the
code we're just take a quick I'll look
at some
key to our concept I'm sure all familiar
but was go over a quick so tweet
140 characters this is awesome cuz
people
tweet out everything really short
they've really don't think about what
they're signing
and they just send it it's also really
concise
so there's a lot of information in a
small space we also have the school
thing a Twitter the laws you follow
people this is I think they're
their main business model loves you to
determine who you wanna see
whose information is coming to you and a
lot of people say
I wanna follow you and see your
information so what will go over how the
other friends and followers actually
work here
so france we're look from is perspective
here
a followed be so ace friend
is be a friend is someone that you
choose to follow
moving on to followers so this
I love their terminology here cuz
following friends followers
followers from sees perspective
be followed see see did not choose to
have be followed them so
the person you don't choose as your
follower so we put it all together
from bees perspective these from the sea
these followers a
and this gets to be really cool because
if your trip out
graphene out are groups and
organizations and you're going to see
who's connected to who
and whose thinks they're who are who
thinks that they're connected to certain
people
they define that for you it's just out
there is public data so you can take a
look at any sort group an organization
see who's talking to each other who
follows who and you can map out the
whole organization
really quickly so
how do we do this we use Twitter's API
it's really cool to have that woulda com
and we now have to do this authenticated
about a month ago Twitter chains are API
used to build to do this all
unauthenticated you to send the right
you're ok West and information comes
back
now you need of tokens so how hard is
that to get
you go out to have that we're a calm you
say
you login with your your Twitter account
you say I wanna make an app and you name
it whatever you want
and you say okay cool generate of tokens
boom
done and if thats if that's still too
difficult
for you to actually work make a fuss you
can say League of the O of generator
tool
for the specific and point request I
wanna make and it will generate
the Coral Springs for you the the
command line for curl
you copy paste that in your machines run
it here comes information back
so were authenticated now great this is
an authenticated tho
stop you from doing something this is
authenticated so Twitter can actually
see what you're doing and who's doing it
that's all I really want to say is they
want to say yeah this user request this
information so we can
market never ties directly to that user
better based on what they're doing they
have to API's they have the REST API
which is what we're gonna be using
and they have a streaming API stream in
school you can play with that you can
say I have the search term and i wanna
see everything in real time
coming at me on this term and actually
returns 1 percent of them
because you just that's a lot of
information but it's one percent
love all the tweets in real time dealing
with whatever search from you put in
you know the committee but specifically
the REST API
well the right we buy we were actually
were about the API directly the
endpoints
sweep I as awesome Python wrapper for
Twitter's API
so you're right and you're a Python
interpreter import we fight and to start
rocking path
the of tokens and you're good to go up I
get home
dot com slash tweet by it's written by a
guy Josh the coder
is actually went pretty active on the
project in the last few months
our point in new features an updated for
the new API changes
stuff so it's it's really start to pick
up speed in this really powerful
anything that I want to do
its in there already are door I've not
actually had extended at all
if I go and look up the ape actual API
docs and say what is
how do I actually do this water there's
a method in tweet by that does that
so the API and points for using
if you go to %uh Twitter API to
twitter.com
slash status less use our time line this
gives you information specific to
users and what they actually tweeted so
takes the user ID or screen name so
screen name would be thirty 7.2
and the user ID would be each user has
a are 64-bit integer value associated
with them
that's how Twitter actually tracks you
across the stuff so if you to go on
there and you were to have an account
you like I no longer like this name
I want change it versus okay you change
it but you still have all your followers
and you still have all your friends
because they're tracking based on that
64 bit I D so it doesn't really matter
if you change your name to get away from
someone if they have that I D
they've they've got you you can change
that I D into account is
basically what it is there's a pram
inner sense ID
which so every user has this ID every
tweet
has this idea as well to every tweet is
as atomic units
its sick 64-bit I D so that's the sense
I D you can say
give me every tweet sense this
particular tweet so if you're building
up a database and you say this last week
I have my database
I wanna see everything this person has
done some Sun user time-line
with the option sense idea but last I D
and here comes everything back at you
but you don't have %ah count
this is this is exactly what you think
returns account number of tweets
to return in the request you can do up
to two hundred at a time
and if that's not enough tweets you can
actually at page in there
with that you can page up to 16 so you
get 3200 tweets
at a time basically in in one request
3200 tweets
that's the max Twitter will let you get
for one person
you want for the back on that I don't
know how you do that
it's not it doesn't exist in the API if
there's a way back machine for Twitter
let me know really interested in that
but I haven't found it yet
%uh exclude should say include but
exclude replies
know it's excluding replies in this one
so
if I don't really care about the
conversations that you're having with
other people i just want to see what
information you put out
specifically I can exclude all your
replies so if someone tweeted to you
haha I went to the
ice cream store and they were out of ice
cream and you you to be back haha
well it's not really that interesting
your flight back that we don't want that
further away was it to get just the
information you post as yourself:
include RTS that stance furry tweets
so if you re tweeted someone by default
that doesn't actually come in the stream
from here but include read tweets
Eagles true home you get all the REIT
which the person that
which as we go further into some other
stuff all point out why that's ok really
good idea to do that
but basically down at the bottom tweet
by that API to get status
and then just the user name that's going
to return back 100 tweets
for whatever user done
next and point well back
that standpoint user show if you want to
get specific information on specific
user
again takes ID your screen name are
really cool thing here's include an 80's
so you get back tweets in their 140
characters
and inside the tweets are user names and
there's URL's and there's hash tags and
everything
and you can write some really cool Raj
axes and you can't parse all that stuff
out and grab it all
or you can just say include entities and
Twitter will parse it for you
comes back in the chase an object in
it's awesome
they'll give you 30 that Co your older
shortened version will give you what the
user actually typed in or give you the
HTTP request that their
actually gonna send out and sometimes I
even are on shortened URL so they bought
a bit lien
sometimes election resolve it for you so
you don't have to go do it yourself
our list of all the hash tags
individually will stop all the users
that were mentioned in the tweet
individually
so you just don't have to really do any
work its already done for you
and again it's we piled up API that get
user
and returns back all the information on
the user
and this is what returns back for
a user this is the Jason object for
myself
and there's actually an interesting
piece of information in here
if you want to figure out what sort of
operating system I was using when I put
my status
are just shouted out
give you heads and description
okay so we've got we lookin description
we have two characters slash
R slash and if I was on a UNIX or Linux
box
you would just see slash and because I
was on a windows box
it appended the carriage return
character so
you could see just by looking just at my
information
that I use Windows machines arm
again you have your also apparently I
still have my LinkedIn up there
great connect to make awesome arm number
followers France
how many times listed when the account
was created sets in UTC SATs
actually close to gonna do the math
right now but you guys can
its were five hours of the give you the
offset what time zone and stuff like
that
is the count you enabled so should you
be looking for
GPS court in its potential along with
the cow arm
how many times persons tweeted is the
cover fights thats
if you had someone like a a sports
figure some like that they could have a
verified account
that its actually them using that
account well Twitter's not verified me
I'm not big enough yet they don't care
so this last half a bit it actually
returns the last status
and the I redacted that information cuz
I didn't ask the person if I could put
it up there who was talking to so
it's not up there but you can see it
watch list of
the background images and colors and
stuff an interesting point with the
background image
so if you have a protected account and I
can see your tweets
I can still see your background image
score at your Twitter page
and its gonna show up it's God's sake
house protected right in the middle but
you still see the background image so if
you were to put personally identifiable
information there
and I won't know what the account was
and I could see the actual content
you're posing
you've still given me that information
so
there's lot of things in there follow
request that so like if you were
actually can automate your process a
sunny now follow request to people and
stuff like that
this would come back if you grab the
status had you actually sounds of it
this is a quick Python code this is how
how hard it is to get set up and that
this the first half a bit
is all because I'm grabbing API keys
from a different location
so importing my consumer key consumer
seeker
access token access token secret setting
up an of
so off the coast we pie of himmler with
the consumer key
super-secret offset access token and
then
I now have a Tapio
our Twitter API Eagles tweet by the API
passing and
passing my of tokens and I could use a
tap eat dog get user 30 some point too
and it's a user dots rename it starts
popping out information we've now made a
request to Twitter we've were
authenticated
anything we want to do this rock n roll
350 request an hour
we're good to go so its
really starts get really easy and you
can just play with my phone and
that's as far XD is we're gonna go into
the Python code with here
we're actually start looking at our some
%uh the actual things that you can do
this so the method to the madness that
we're gonna go through
met talk about the information that was
gathered
what you do need to develop the model
that I was I'm a show
we'll talk about the specific tools that
are used if I didn't use
if I use something other than Python
explain it how I use that
we'll take a look at the visualization I
created and then
do a little bit analysis on and try to
understand what it is that we're
actually looking at
so the first one I wanted to take a look
at what is my echo chamber
on Twitter work for anyone you can
target this you can say I wanna grab bar
JW gorelick and look to see what has
echo chamber is what sort of
yeah I'm sorry call you off are what
sort of information would be coming up
back at this person what would they be
seen just by sitting there just using
the service
gives you an idea of what sort of our
perspective or bias they might have what
sort of information that they choose to
C
so I grab the last 1000 tweets I've
everyone
the user followed in that case that's me
and
just a basic workout and all the tweets
straight up workout
found a list of our 5,000 common English
words
on Google and is excluded those so
here's my
my list of words and I threw it in the
world dot net
so if you not play with that site its
really cool allows you to take
are adult a text document it will count
all the words on it
adults make a visualization a look
something
like this you can if you want to do all
the work at a time do the work out
there's an advanced feature and you can
say word colon and then a number
and that's the waiting the the word gets
so when I ran this against myself
grabbing all the tweets are the people I
followed security
internet seance so I mean that's the
stuff that people were saying and
speaking about that I was seen
so that was my echo chamber was coming
back at me what what perspective do I
haven't stopped and this can be very
telling are depending on who you look at
very telling us to
what they're interested in and
I mean if you try to market to them what
products might they be interesting what
are you talking about what might they be
using sup
even from a social engineering
standpoint on that if i'm talking Cisco
ASA all the time all day
then there's a fair chance that I'm
using Cisco essays
so if there's a new father Billy Cup are
new export for ASA comes out
or maybe they're using it %uh IronKey
ass is a jerk without telnet or
something then there's a new father
Billy the drops and everything's
gonna be out where you can see if if it
was up there
that I talk about that a lot so
potentially work wherever I'm working or
in my own environment I may be volatile
something
looking the little bit I love a chart
that doesn't require as much
kinda just diving around and trying to
just makes sense the data
tweets per day what does it look what
does the person look like when they
tweet over just a week period you take
all their tweets
so grab the last 30 to 100 with two
that's all you can get and the pot those
just over a week
what are the most active what are they
not active
arm and I actually do this for
individual
and then for a community as well om
individuals last 32 art with the
community
it's actually interesting as playing
with the streaming API see what I could
do
and I tracked InfoSec over weekend so if
you've
tweeted with hash tag InfoSec between
May 18th
and 21st the three-day weekend and I
happen to catch the 1 percent of tweets
and you were in that
you're sitting in my database now what
you up and
fun stuff here but basically all due in
part the tweets over weekdays
and here's one individual looks like so
we have
actually pretty big bop this is Sunday
through Saturday
so Wednesday Thursday Friday Saturday
lot more traffic for this individual
that it's been a week and maybe
maybe this individual works a job with a
really focus that begin in the next
kinda
not folks at the end the week maybe
there's some to their job where they're
traveling a lot then a week
I don't know but I do know this
individual
is partly InfoSec community so if we
look at the community
to the that are they not wire in the
community or do they fit right within
the community
if we look at this this is community for
InfoSec
and here's how we tweaked and I thought
this was pretty interesting we have
pretty much flat
and then Wednesday Thursday Friday
there's a BOP
in traffic and source that they're
trying to figure this out
and I racked my brain like the movies
come on a Tuesday night so I like
what are we doing just its Patch Tuesday
it's not past Thursday I mean like
what what is going on why would we have
Obama traffic there and
Sokol yet again Wolfgang because you had
the brilliant idea conferences
where we're at right now and what day is
it
were not at work were at a conference
it's a Thursday
I bet you there's a lot more tweeting
going out today than if you were sitting
at your desk actually worked out
something at least
that your bosses would hope so but the
in so I think that's what this is
it's the InfoSec community we have a lot
to conferences we have a lot travel at
the end the week going to a new location
for the next week or so
like that I think that describes a and
and since you actually
I you you have the tweet data itself you
could dive into
individual tweets you could say
conferences and you could dive in a look
at the actual conferences and say
okay that makes sense there is a rise in
conference traffic there and it kinda
describes that or does describe that are
no it doesn't let's dive in deeper and
find out why
next thing
what does the person talk about and hash
tags are interesting
is a user-defined don't have tax they
say whatever they want
its way of saying my tweet fits into
this book it this little category this
is what I think the South
or I'm trying to be ironic by using this
hash tag or something but it's a way of
classification
in the user's doing it for you so if you
look at hash tags
you have a pretty good idea of what the
person actually
is talking about so again last 32 under
tweets
include entities begin where us that
Twitter will parse all this for you
this is just awesome the parse it all
you poured out the Jason object
you're good to go you have a list gin
its hash tag lazy hacker
not going to do the work if I don't have
to arm include read tweets
and what actually I have a a slide where
I didn't include the retreat and there's
not a lot of information there as a
person actually didn't with a lot
himself it with a lot himself every
tweet a lot of information
so if you include read tweets this gets
a lot more interesting and here playing
with
are Google our visualization API if you
do a Google search for code
are visualization playground on Google
there's a nice
Ajax environment that you can just start
throwing information into into running
it arm
so this guy that I was looking at are
you could probably guess who it is
if you wanted to but here is his topics
here's what he tweeted about himself so
hash tag and a Samsung network security
monitoring
bro WS 2011 so it's a conference APT
security aryan this guy's probably the
network monitoring he's
probably doing some
yeah Seth APT that's an interesting one
I think
probably isn't so the government related
sectors some sort incident response
like that but this is just just his work
his tweets we look at what it looks like
with three tweets
so we have a little bit different
pitcher he's tween more about security
on in when you include for tweets
and now we're starting to get stuff in
force akin sick world and
DFI our stuff so we're starting a good
idea
on the community this guy has placed
himself in just by his is hash tags
moving on to read tweets replies this
gets
again weird last 32 our tweets to be a
same old story include entities include
three tweets
if you're looking for read tweets and
you don't include the re tweets
you're not gonna get read tweets so it's
it's something you run the code say I
have nothing
and then you look back in Houston define
so here we look at three different
charts we look at
are read tweets replies the best time
for spots
so this is actually my information so
who do I retrieve and says for better
people up there
arm I don't actually I was surprised by
the state I don't treat with a lot
in comparison the number two it's
actually signed up who are reply to
this gets interesting we start seeing
people that I reply to a lot but didn't
show up in the recruits
so I communicate with these people but I
don't send their message on
gets to be kind of interesting if you
take both are side by side you say who
but as a person retreating hutu the
reply to
now you've found the important people
they're spreading the message the person
agrees with
and they're also communicating with on
if you were to try to get
from a social engineering standpoint
these were the re tweets
and the replies would be a good spot to
look at if you want to send a message to
get to the person that you're targeting
who might come from if you had if you
had the ability to come from someone or
spoof someone's account
arm maybe you take the a lot of
something to make a 20 something it
looks like it came from the right person
it really didn't but
chances are if you pick someone up high
of the person's gonna see if they're
gonna respond to it and then
applies broken down over time this gets
interesting from AR
if anyone's ever done any source sales
done easily cold call stuff in years
like
people are answer the phones are not the
dusts would be really cool see when this
person just be most likely just reply to
me
when he does not waste anyone's time
just call on than or
when you are you back at my desk sets
when they gonna reply there to call me
back
so I took a look at %uh someone else's
information
and replies per hour broke it down we
actually have a BOP
at about noon so kinda makes sense guy
goes on break goes on launch
biggest a reply to people then again the
the
and other day 3 for 5 o'clock ok
arm another reply at at seven o'clock
and then one right before he goes to bed
so big spikes
so if you were to target individual and
you want a response from them
maybe you would send it the hour before
the most active
so when they they walk on their Twitter
account and they look at all the
messages that they have the right there
you're right near the top so that
there's a good chance they actually see
your content combined with the social
engineering stuff I'll try to get them
to click on something
then maybe you would take from one of
those
are individuals and target a certain
time slot to get the
the most bang for your buck so just if
you sent this
a message this guy at eleven o'clock at
night
the earliest he's gonna reply looks like
67 8 a.m. in the morning
he's probably seen it on a messages come
across through their and your stuff is
to be lost the noise
so there would be a really cool
that's the way I would actually said
let's replies people so here we get to
something
kinda interesting can we take influence
can we measure that and yeah this would
be the time to further con- balls
worries clout to do this I
don't like Klout they change their
algorithm daily it doesn't make any
sense
and they give you they don't tell you
what the album is based on
and if you give them a Twitter account
you have so much clout
if you give them a Facebook account you
have so much more clout
so Facebook is more valuable than
Twitter I don't understand why
but they just want information that's
what the company does they market
information
and are the company's and the more you
give them
the more clout people have but if we
take that just as
this is a guideline we say we don't
really care that you're over there is a
perfect
and that is probably not someone out
there doing better and we don't want to
take the time to actually write our own
you can interface with the API and grab
any user
and see are what sort of Klout score
they have
and another cool thing that they don't
really they don't talk about I think
it's there
their biggest selling point is topics
they take a look at what our users
tween about or what other people think
the influential about
and show topics and you can grab that to
the API
so you could say if you pull up bar
Wolfgang K
hey I didn't mention that you brought it
up so since you did caps
right now Wolfgang stop topic is cats
you go look it up
I've might've bomb that database over
few months and
poisoned at but its cats otherwise it
would've been something more sensible
like business our cloud computing
security but if we take a look at all
the stuff import all together
we can do something with with all over
last 30 to 100 tweets
including all the things and Klout score
in topics
and using a formula
because if if I had a close score 50 as
on her clothes were 55
I just multiply that by the number of
times I interacted with someone
really doesn't show a big difference so
i squared the clock score
so if we have fifty versus sixty now
it's
2500 versus 3600 clock normalize the
data set in everyone's kinda grouped in
towards the middle it's all compact in
so I would rather see a more spread out
value simple squaring
makes those values explode now
we get to come out to the the actual
video six
quotes
so what i did. here's I took my last
tweets
with the interactions with people
ok the real
so from when I was active in
to on to the present which was actually
August legendary the star
and this is using Google's visualization
API if you look up motion chart
it's a nice interface you to schedule
data in and it generates it's all for
you
so you can change the time scales and
you can change what your axis is our
and the cool thing with topics on
I wish I had a live so we can actually
show you and of show it in the video but
it
be better just feel the arm click on
stuff but if we mouse over individual
here a little bubble
it actually shows the topic associate
with that person so
the people that are higher up a new one
is no what topic it was like interacting
with at that point I'm
you can just hover over the personal of
but and so the talk about it
it's actually see what happens
so we have some movements I think up
father here a second show the the topics
om yeah so you can click on people
see their names and on the right hand
side show back in a second so as you
mouse over someone the topic would pop
up
on the right hand side and clicking on
names allow you to track individuals
so I was interacting with ire de Cannes
Miko are from a secure
and if we see on the right hand side
we've got full box
where we can't select individuals we can
click on that and you could say I want
to track these individuals
throughout the whole thing is to be
really kind any
and you can track individual people so
is reticent his influential the podcasts
up but have to sweep through
so Wolfgang but ima be sized Troy so at
that time period
he exploded when traffic and and we can
see stuff like that
if you to correlate this with actual
events so what where was the person at
correlated with the interactions not the
frequency that higher
interactions with different individuals
you actually a lot of information
so on visualization will go back into
the
presentation clients
so every tweet you sent out has a source
tag attached to it and that's what
client used
could be web it could be TweetDeck it
could be Twitter for iPhone
doesn't really matter what it is but by
knowing that information you play
you glean more information from the
person as to how they're actually a
regular stuff
so here i'm taking a look at an
individual grab the last 32 or tweets
and took a look at the total counts for
the client usage just snapshot boom I
have less 3200 watts account look like
and then visualize that again over time
to see if there's a reason to even play
with stuff over time
or if it doesn't matter so looking at
this individual it just a snapshot in
time Twitter for iPhone
the gate with a lot from his iPhone so
now we know he has and I lost device
Vegas is even more information if we
were to target him our web
soco everyone uses Web Worsley
we're looking at a client it no longer
exists now but
it used to be a application on I was
devised a large eat-in multiple social
media sites on one thing so
cool Twitter for iPad arm
watch list of Cam'ron I owe us
%uh court we all information that points
to Apple devices for this individual
just by looking at their place usage
now if we go back up to a year
visualization here
client breakdown wanna take a look at
inning
so I take a look at select all the
different clients I only grabbed
the top three here customer us towards
kinda not really use
so we don't really care about them again
visualize them over time
I want to watch Bruce Lee and
so right now his overall usage is
dropping down
and we see a huge spike up in looks like
a
June July of last year gets even bigger
cities get more active
coming back down web dropped off so he's
not he's he was using mobile for a while
almost exclusively bruce Lee goes up
comes back down
and here in a second
or gone
in order user
so if we looked at his chart as a point
in time just last 32 her tweets
bruce Lee was third analyst but now
it's no longer relevant to he doesn't
use it
hasn't used it for the last three months
and
spas
but the interesting thing there is as I
mentioned the client no longer exist
it was the developers for a well as the
messenger
they made this client and a law wanted
them to go back to work a name again
I don't know why but they did so the
client disappear
so if you were to target this individual
for social engineering engagement maybe
you have this really cool application
you just built for I owe us
that blows it him to integrate all of
its social media sites and
again together in one app and since he
was such a power user for your client
before Bruce Lee
is your developer from that team you
gonna give him
early access to this information this
client and now he installs
your application on his phone
potentially pain
I think that's kinda game over that
point but
we're not done yet we thank you
interactions with topics
so I want to go back and play with not
take a little bit
and some summer student I don't pay for
multi go
so I have community addition so it
doesn't allow me to grab a last-32 under
tweets someone I grab the last 12 I
think
that's no good so in this case file was
made import Excel spreadsheets
or CSV files so I could do that with
Python
take Python we can go grab all the last
32 our tweets
including entities again and we can and
I didn't mention it were using cloud
again for the topics
and we can set up a document that is be
the person I interacted with and then
the topic for that all the case file
and whatnot Eagle visualize it for us
this
this demonstration actually took me
about five minutes the code up
it was literally just boom boom boom
done grab the information
grab the cloud information for Taylor
CSV import mail to: and visualize
like 30 seconds and this is what looked
like
and so I get that you probably can't
read the icons
right now swung to give you a full
overview of what it is
before resumed in the stuff know if we
can actually read this or not up for
can we read the source is too small okay
so
one person the front can see it people
the back and we will
over here and we will pull this off
same chart and we can zoom in and we can
see
different topics
so we have a big no dove information
security so the people that I'm
interacting with
most on Twitter are all tied to
information security
we have stuff like music so I'm I play
bass
the band cool we can start moving around
and see the different entities on the
chart and who are interacting with and
what their
influential about arm hacking technology
stuff and
to grab this information after the
script written is like thirty-seconds
and third multi-goal and boom you have a
really good idea
of yes
so actually this is this is actual user
names so if we so if we look at the
the yellow images and pulling also this
is a good one we have HD Moore
at some point I interacted with HD Moore
so
I pulled out the user names using
entities and put a parse that all for me
and so that we can see and we can
actually follow
the line coming of age the more and we
can see that
clout thinks AC Moore is influential
about packing so
pretty accurate network arm know it's
actually the clock topic
so if you were to go on the club's
website which yeah
so its it's a site that allows you to
define
influence of individuals and that maps
out the different topics that they would
be influential
yeah which is really cool cuz and I
don't actually have to calculate that
myself
so if I were to pull out all their
tweets
and look at all the information do some
sort of Calton calculation
I could figure this out and you could do
it yourself if you want to if you don't
use clout
but since they have it there it's
already done just leverage it
and so that's
played with that
will leave will scale
yes I lied but
worse
fairly close
up there was
so
if my son isn't your cup of tea and you
still wanna play with this information
is a really cool website week steps
acecomm if it's of
which is a crapshoot it gives you a
tremendous amount of information
but someone I'm not going to actually
showing it but it gives you all the
start breakdowns and pretty much
everything that I've done
isn't weeks thats Art Walk charts
if tweets that is enough you can make do
with what charts
it's not as friendly all the information
is displayed one thing you have to
say I want this specific thing click on
it give the user name in it generates
that specific thing are
again clout what I was playing with
there's another site
competitor clout arc red run by I think
people soft
arm it actually it's a cool site if you
just want a footprint someone
are they give you a lot more information
about the actual things that they
tweeted the actual messages they posted
and who they interacted with its it's a
lot more friendly in that regard but I
think they're scoring mechanism is
crap in comparison to clout arm
sorry if you like crap but its its
it's not as great art social much in so
it's an interesting site you can
go to it and you can type in whatever
you want and it will show you all the
social media stuff that's talking about
that topic
so if you put in the username for you
put in a name there's
the potential you have some really
interesting stuff come back work role
YouTube it called Facebook called
Twitter and stuff grabs a whole bunch
information brings it back to you
there's a potential I put at the bottom
because
it's not very accurate are you really
have to sort through it but maybe
there's another gold in there
%ah fear not a fan of
well to go for your visualization stuff
network attacks
plane back in the Python stuff you can
define your own graphs
based on notes and your edges and
really cool thing with that is multi go
classes all your addys in together to
make that chart
it didn't take into account interactions
so if we look at the number for Twitter
replies that I had
we've seen walking was huge but if we go
back to the
the multi coach R will things actually
be the same size as everyone else
as he doesn't have that many things
coming into a links the only had me
and then a topic so is the same weight
as everyone else so if you to play with
network axe
you would define the way to the node
where the way the edge and you could
actually show
interactions with topics and so music
look like a big topic for me
I really don't interact on Twitter with
that at all that's
apparently some the people I do interact
with do talk about that their
influential bout that there's enough of
them
but I really don't do anything with that
so it's kind of a misnomer on that chart
but if you were to do a waiting up the
interactions
then with the topics you would have a
lot more information
pertinent information about the
individual so
thats
pretty much it that is my contact
information
student Eastern email me with
any questions or do you have afterwards
otherwise I'll take questions now about
anything
go ahead for I
art
yes
no how I if
so I haven't played with anything else
but every other social media site on the
internet
has API's you can pull into I know
Facebook is pretty wide open
if you want to grab Facebook data for
people in their interactions
thats and lets the users have locked
down in this is the case here to with
Twitter
lets the users have locked it down it's
out there it's public information you
could grab all that
and you could add that into have a a
bigger fuller picture
so where's this going what's the
implications
so the started out as a project I've
just what is out there what can I find
but from AR
an audit standpoint are you want you
want to know what your users are talking
about
maybe your your you
you think maybe years you users are
leaking your your IP out there
you wanna know are they talking on
Twitter about your different things on
the designs and stuff that what you're
doing
you could really easily you something
like to reply and you could grab that
information this a give you a good idea
if they're talking about a lot with pop
right up
arm it's really a it becomes very
domain-specific
as to how you'd actually utilize this
but it's really
at this point it's a data mining data
exploration thing
and figure out from there what's
also the Python module art we pie
no
for
maybe
i havent I haven't decided on that yet I
realizing it's all public information
yes it probably should just be open cuz
you grab this information yourself
but have open source in all that stuff
and making the tools that make stuff
like this possible raises the bar for
everyone
whether they want to or not so
we can talk afterwards but to
right now it's not I get help and if I
do decide to
it'll be 30 7.2 don't give up
there actually the the clout one
interaction with clout in
interactions that is actually about get
help that specific one are
butts otherwise most or not
that's the one that if I get help so
follow Fridays on Twitter
hash tag FF if you're not familiar with
that its you go out I every Friday and
you can go on there you can say these
are the core people I follow and I think
you should follow them to
so I got tired of picking and choosing
it felt like I was picking favorites
so I said if I enter a grab the last 32
or tweets myself
look at just the last month's worth the
data and then if I interacted with you a
lot
then you're on for Friday if if you can
fit in the top two tweets are if I was
not to tweets
if you fit in there the great based on
your interactions were alone
so if you don't interact with me a lot
or I don't interact with you then you're
not going to fall Friday
but if we interact it on well then
you're gonna be right up there
so it's automated this is a script that
this runs
and i no longer have to worry about that
what people whining complaining like a
it's not my fault it's your fault so
work I think we're good to go