stuck in here now carole we're gonna be
alright thanks for being here is like
the second-to-last talking all of their
be gone so it's it's pretty great to see
that there's actually know some people
here I was kind of a concern records got
my time slot that would be basically
myself and my wife which is why I made a
drug test here she also had me on the
project so I figured she had to make an
appearance today we're talking about a
project I'm falling stretching the
sandbox with our feature vectors and I'm
explain what those mean essentially a
project that's been on my mind for a
while and then you can kind of gave me
the motivation to go out there and put
some stuff out and now we're talking
about it so I know about half the room
knows who I am because I I drug you hear
the other half the room number to me
like that I am actually kind of local
originally from Lexington Kentucky
currently living in Cincinnati where I
work for a fortune 1000 company who I
did not give permission to use these
slides that's why the name is not here
in any way shape or form and insert you
know legal disclaimer there but my day
job is Angeli instant response and
analysis yet our stuff
analysis engineering that kind of stuff
in a previous life was active duty Air
Force where I did four years working in
the power lab at the National Air and
Space Intelligence dinner
yes thank you just said things that I am
this is kinda nice part to my disclaimer
you know I consider myself a haggard
specifically you know I R version Jerry
malware that kind of stuff
engineer you know tray error by
education I like to build things like to
put stuff together that's sort of what I
do I am NOT a professional developer so
it's kind of scary is actually one of
the first products that released now
they're open source so I fully expect
you guys to terror that completely up
and they welcome it I'm also but please
do it I'm also not a mathematician in
any way shape or form so we're going to
be talking about the feature vectors and
doing some statistical analysis on this
feature vectors I I had a
undergraduate statistics couple times
and so have like a very elementary grasp
of what I'm even talking about so I have
no idea what I'm doing right but I got
this weird talk about anyways I had to
bring it up my wife jessie is actually a
mechanical engineer she's just taking
all kinds of higher level classes right
now and she makes sure that airplanes
don't fall skies are run by anything I
did before her by her I put it up on a
slide she told me it was completely
stupid but I did it he was sweating over
I guess the road man talking to be
talking about the agenda
reduce the product you know what it is
what the motivation is behind it may
give a little bit of thoughts on
sandboxing in general I know that most
people you probably are very familiar
sandboxing which is probably why you
came to talk to to begin with but just
in case
missing people gonna talk about a couple
points feeding the beast our collection
so how do you actually populate your or
your body of knowledge I'm not going to
make this like an Intel collection
talking any way shape or form but
there's a couple basic things that you
went into populating those populating
the initial until the real briefly that
is believed that is basically what I
used for various reasons to support the
back end of the analysis here and talk
about what our feature vectors actually
are
I made them up and you know what my
thought process for making them up was
then they go over some of the code and
some of the plots that were able to to
use to talk about all the things I
didn't finish so what we talk about when
we hear so many analysts gets a piece of
malware the first thing they ask
themselves is what the hell am i working
at I got this I got the sample maybe I
got it from a host that wasn't directed
at you working operations you're pulling
things are going to legends you know
from here
guys every day I get a sample you might
know immediately what it is because it
has a particularly no be getting bad you
might know immediately what it is
because the registry keys that creates
because the new texts that it creates
because of the positive rights the
things that drops however a lot of that
to be mean or process we're moving more
towards you know at an age where we're
getting a lot of power in you know from
automated sources and not all the time
because somebody's looking eyes on these
things and so on those cases your
processing thousands of malware samples
are your processing mount thousands of
you know binaries maybe they're not even
malicious having that you know
assessment of what is this how can I
classify the sky cluster these together
and I do that sort of grouping and
correlation
it becomes important kind of interesting
especially on the scale that we know
that we work on today of course there's
lots of projects to do this there's lots
of times and I'm not even doing like a
prior art page I hear mostly because I'm
lazy but also because I assume that you
guys have Google you go out there you
can view our clustering there's a ton of
great things that you out there a lot of
its static one of my good friends who is
not here can actually did our DNA
project which is exactly
the same type of goals but using your
static analysis so the second part of
the objectives here the motivation is
we've got a ton of data from marcia
boxes right i mean everything very same
box I don't know about you and your
organizations and how you guys operate a
sample of the sandbox and we can we do
this sometimes for a virus hunting will
be doubling down hundreds or thousands
samples through analysis engine and a
lot of times a day to just kind of sit
here nobody ever looks at again right i
mean these things generate hundreds of
megabytes per the data and it's just
gonna sit there we have it put you in a
couple of projects to correlate some of
the stuff together one of them at work
has been my baby the past year I'm not
presenting of that today but this one is
something that they did we can share and
and and look at would like to have some
other guys so here's here's the talk a
little bit about Sandboxie again i'm
looking like nobody does down too hard
like bigger than most people are pretty
familiar it was a boxing is the concept
behind it right you do it you know
traditionally you have your static and
dynamic analysis tools that people been
using for years and the whole idea of
ice and boxing is that we want to
automate we went to great you know and
isolated environment for automating you
know system observation and sandbox has
really exploded over the past five years
and never prior to five years ago they
really weren't a whole lot of first one
there wasn't a whole lot of open source
anything I think the project started
about that time but there may be one or
two vendors and they're charging a whole
bunch of the sand boxes and then a lot
of people kind of rolling their own that
time but over the past five years is
kind of a kind of taking off to discover
thoughts on rolling your own vs fender
vs open sores I don't want to start like
any sort of like war here by talking
about this but just my $0.02 on your
kind of the pros and cons sandbox you
have control over everything you can do
very custom custom anti anti sandbox I
guess that's a word in science I say
boxing technique so you can really know
have full control over or what that
looks like a lot of times if you really
are the guys that right now where they
have the inside you know inside baseball
knowledge of what you're doing to try to
evade than 6 I'm kinda thing with a
vendor exactly don't have any control
over it
the vendor has all the control over it
they also charge a lot of money so there
is that they consider whether there's
open source and there's two major major
major major disadvantage major
advantages you got this great community
to support its constantly being updated
the features that something like who's
offered over the past couple years it's
absolutely exploded major disadvantages
yes a lot of our does that out there has
been no somebody I don't you hate it
absolutely that's absolutely true so we
gotta know what you're dealing with you
know you know it's definitely possible
that members of aiding your open source
and blogs and you need to take that with
a grain of salt
so basically where we operate in our
requirements we do everything for you
and we get back of course we can kind of
tell a distinct exit immediately didn't
do a whole lot but even the way that it
exits sometimes can be very useful
especially when you get into this
product is still gonna generate feature
vectors which obviously talked about
that are depending on you it's inside of
you and I you know Sam boxing techniques
as well and if you didn't know I am
using Google beating the beat again I
don't want to blame for this point but
so the whole idea behind this project is
going to take unknown samples were
trying to classify them well you have to
start with something right you have to
start with your known knowns so it
starts no known you have to have to have
some sort of our collection of some sort
into a program of some sort of process
it doesn't have to be elaborate maybe
its elaborate that's going to be
your organization I'm not gonna tell you
how to run your your organization's
Miller collection or insult program I'm
just gonna say that for the purpose of
this project is a couple pieces
information that I collected collected
hashes I collected the source that I got
the samples prom I collect the source
that supposed to say day not dad I
collected the file type of our family so
for the purpose of this project I
basically went out to open source
research where you know somebody like
SecureWorks or hire somebody released a
report on some some our taxes said hey
these samples belonged to the same
family and I said I hope this report on
this report date these hashes belong to
this this is the file types they were
because the when you actually do
analysis file types very very important
is apparently a deal expiry very
differently than an exe as far as when
you actually executed as a box of course
I do I do this I create an awesome
spreadsheet as I'm just going through
these reports demonstrated UCSB and
actually created a tool that is part of
the project I tangentially had text up
high and it will basically take all that
trades data to CSV and it's a very
simple table this tables were super
simple and the purpose behind it is just
to get all the information in a
relational format so that you can easily
tacit and associated with the analysis
of course let's take a look when they
see could do they look at this they get
a pretty web interface and show them
what they need
I think most analysts that I know don't
really go further than this
they they see the things that you see
they make it a determination whether or
not they think it's militias they might
copy some of the c2 down into some sort
of
repository we use creates a familiar
that project and then life
well there is a lot behind this name
there are these also like 500 megabytes
are up to 50 megabytes JSON or is this
just nothing but raw data and that's
really what we're looking at right now
our feature vectors what are we talking
about so I started using the word
feature vector I wasn't even exactly
sure I was using the right word but the
definition from Wikipedia makes me think
that maybe I am i dont know so we can
video says that feature vector is an in
dimensional vector of numerical features
that represents some object in the
example that they actually use they said
well usually you're gonna see this like
image processing and signal processing
that kind of stuff but you can also
think about it conceptually like well if
you want to create a feature vector of
all the fruit that's on the table you
can say that you for Apple's
9 bananas and you have 10 players and
then your victory that one would be 49
10 and that's just a very easy way to
just sign some numbers to feature set so
when we're talking about an hour
whatever side is that what if we try to
sign numerical values to the artifacts
that we see in this you know dynamic
reports so things like number of API
calls registry keys you Texas network
connections Dennis call outs all those
you can count them up and you Adam Jones
who
better basically now of course you run
into some issues that we have to deal
with like well maybe you're going to
count the number of strings and that's
kind of important for a particular our
family they usually have you know ten
thousand dreams or something but they
only make to DNS queries well maybe
there's two DNS queries are just as
important
well obviously you're gonna need to some
sort of normalization in that case you
can also do things like you know the
bite of a buffer copied or network sites
of networked generated and then last
book there is no normalization and
uniformity in comparison so created a
script basically is titled great feature
vector case you know it wasn't so
painfully obvious from the title what it
does it's basically turns Jason reports
from bukavu into into these feature
vectors that we can then stored in
database so the process has been pretty
several not go through all this but
essentially what it does and this is
kind of a first pass like i just want to
see get some numbers down to see you
know what I'm dealing with here goes to
reach the major sections of the cougar
porn so you can see down there the
bottom you networking items and says
board if network is in today's report
count all the things and headed to a
feature called network underscore the
key items and so what that does is it
allows a little flexibility because not
all reports contain all the things so
you are going to get a little bit
different results every time you say
they are static items drop files
behavior summary so I'm actually created
this from the newest version of Google's
excellent diversion where they actually
changed up the report format quite
substantially so this actually at this
point does not work for 1.2 it only
works for the 2.0 death anybody want to
go out and make this backwards
compatible they could I probably will
because we're gonna have to for
operational environment so that is
forthcoming but essentially this is very
very simple just goes in accounts all
the different types of data the Cougars
recording calls that a feature
then puts it in a bit in a dictionary so
that they're always associated with each
other because we just put a ministry to
rate it won't line up and stuff so the
behind the scenes stuff that happens is
once you've selected a substantially
large number of these in fact I i kind
of front-loaded all the samples I think
a lot about 300 samples
different different actual 25 and 40
different families into your gonna wanna
you're gonna want to do that whole
normalization process and so the weather
normalization process works is
essentially the max values for all of
the features you collect your gonna want
to calculate the mean values or you can
just cheating assume the minimum value
is 0 then you're gonna obviously wanted
to bide for each of the beach for each
vector gonna want to buy by the max
value and so you get a number of its
between 0 and and one for each and that
can only be done after you have a
substantially large number of features
calculated because who knows what is
going to be the only have like two and I
wrote functions in this project that
will he time you wanna like recalculate
renormalized you run it a little run for
a few minutes and it'll be normalized
vector's vectors are actually stored in
a table they're stored in a RAW format
are not stored normalize for that exact
reason and it but it does store the does
store the max values so that you can
quickly users quickly reference those as
your calculating the normalized vector's
vector's tables kind of like this
Associated the hash the machine is very
important to one thing that I didn't
mention one thing I did not mention when
I talk about the case and box set up the
biggest thing in the AM acknowledges
uniformity so you don't really want to
be comparing at 32 bit Windows XP
machine to a 64 bit Windows 7 machine
it's very important that those are
treated as a separate groupings task IDs
so you can get back to the computer
bored
the type of vector or type of victory is
the value so better type would be like
network connection
value would be like eight alright so the
bus so this presentation I'm gonna go
over with you know what
presented and in some of the results in
kind of walk through it so the main part
of Project is a mess beat up high school
of the core resource the product to find
you know that the vector classes and
lets you interact with the database is
going to do any piano roll see anything
like that unless you want to find you
know your basic functions are going to
be late the vectors for some statistical
analysis and display pots so I created a
examples direct examples directory
within the project that basically has
right now for different scripts that
form
give you some plots and we're going
through those to kind of walk through a
lot of family stuff on the whole purpose
behind this group is to group the
vectors based on those tax family
biotype source and the normalized them
and then create something called so the
first part of this is is is very
important and it's it's where you take
those samples are so the stacks that we
are being put into the tax table in the
new kind of break those up into unique
what I call labels and essentially what
those are as you know the family that
you said that longs to the file type it
is the story that you got through text
as the source data as well but it put it
up there and it pulls out it takes all
the features that are associated with
each of those and then it normalizes
them as part of that group and the
second thing it does is it creates an
archetype and essentially what it an
archetype is very key to this entire
project
so what is an architect I found is that
you know directly comparing all features
for every picture showed a very low
correlations wasn't very good results
honestly you're talking about you have a
lot of different factors that do very
very different things so and to think
about this conceptually it's pretty easy
to think about you know particularly our
samples you know they have kind of their
own calling card so particular sample my
create new texts of a particular nature
and that's very important to define that
sample another sample my trade a whole
bunch of domains as part of the domain
generating algorithm that uses and
that's a very important facet of that in
our family and so comparing those things
directly to each other
don't really make a whole lot of sense
because one sample might not even know a
great domain names in the notion of my
so what the archetype
this was actually compare only the
things that matter for sample for family
so I created a function that that tries
to figure out what is most statistically
significant for a particular group or
family tries to figure out which of
those tags which of those features
really makes the biggest difference and
so the way that the archetypes are
created is essentially you give it your
subset you're interested in which is
basically all the samples that match
your particular label that we just
talked about and then you also give it
the superset which is all the samples in
your universe I guess and then what you
do is you say which features have the
lowest amount of variance in the
lowest amount of variance want to still
lived in the subset but the greatest
amount of variance in the superset so
it's a simple as simple as taking a
variant of each of the vectors and
subtracting them and figuring out
essentially you know what are your top
30 samples are sorry what are your top
30 features that really defined you know
that sample and so just kind of walking
through the code a little bit first
thing we do is we have a prune the
better because if you care about you
really don't care about a lot of zero
values for the most part I mean there
might be some weird cases where where
the fact that there are 0 new network
connection for something really define a
sample but for the most part you don't
care about 20 there's a lot of zeros
that's what I've features total from the
drina samples that I looked at and I
think most samples only actually had
about a hundred non-zero values so first
thing you do is for the subset
get rid of all the zeros gonna find the
standard deviations for both sets like I
just talked about using your gonna do
that your bases and then you're gonna
find the difference between the subset
in the superset
deviations and then you want to take
basically the top 30
the lowest it's gonna be as good a large
negative number so all that and get down
to the bottom basically is going to
return a very proven set of features so
instead of having 255 features were a
lot of them are like 0 you're going to
get like 30 features and they're all
going to be a distinctly significant for
the subset you provided as compared to
December set so then the next to the
idea behind using archetype is then you
can compare unknown samples to that
archetype to see hey does this fit the
curves is you know how how close are
these doctors what is the distance
between these doctors at this point but
you're going to want to actually
calculate
the same feature sets from that
archetype for each for each archetype of
you want to compare samples to make
sense of the words they're so and then
when you can play these archetypes you
wanna be able to quickly retrieve them
you don't want to have to do this every
single time so so its doors in the table
and just like the max values that you
used to normalize their songs in there
that you can pre-order type redo also
it's nice because you can actually going
here in manually edit some of the
features and once I start selling some
plots will make sense when you're going
to want to do that so then
families is it kind of gives you some
stats on each of the labels labels look
like something like this he got plug
attacks p32 from SecureWorks on you know
2015 08053 windows 7 x64 and so that's
kind of what is it that's kinda like the
unique identifier for this family and
then it tells you some stats about that
family that he created as you know each
sample is the meeting distances point 26
the units on that don't matter because
completely normal eyes so its point 26
somethings their deviations 2.07 and
then it kind of compares that to the
rest of the samples in your universe
there so you talking about having you
know I mean just all samples as point
six that's roughly three times longer
and the standard deviation is much
higher
it is so the next thing it does is kinda
give you a little bit of sanity check it
tells you that there are 48 you know
vectors that belongs that family they
can basically be defined by that label
and the number of all sectors within one
standard deviations 40 the number of all
vectors between one standard deviation
to see you a shitty one and within three
standard deviations is a hundred
thirteen so what you can see you there
somewhere between one and two standard
deviations way you actually get all
those doctors and you can drill down to
make sure those are actually catching
the ones you think they're getting in
and and they are for those partners
couple outliers and we're going to
that last thing it does actually plus
the entire the entire family and
slightly you guys ever used properly
before but it is interesting I basically
shows us for this project as I wanted to
use it I know that it's probably work
for a lot of large organizations that
have restrictions on white putting their
data in the cloud but essentially
apparently described as I hope for plots
so it's pretty cool its allows you to
get very interactive but essentially all
your data belongs to them so I it's
totally not something that is going to
be feasible for a lot of corporations
but you can you can easily adjust this
so this is like what when the family
buses gonna look like here so you got
all your samples over on the on the key
and then on the x-axis there you have
those features thats were defined as
being stood at least on the bottom
so you can see that the the main line
there which is basically the orkut and
he's probably read Saturday's in the
front row there but it has the different
values that make that archetype up there
on the x-axis and you can see where each
sample sample goes so you can see over
on the far left-hand side of the graph
there that there are some some samples
for ATI stats inti duplicate objects
that are so even though one standard
deviation so what that tells me is that
something that I might want immediately
treat this feature vector for maybe I
don't want that guy in there because
it's just too far out of the average
something around here is another example
with even more this is a family group
here that I got from security blog post
Monday hashes they will pull down and
you can see there are pretty tightly
grouped but I really like to see those
outliers I really like to see it like
there are two random samples and if you
go and you kind of fall them through in
the back to unify zoom in and the bottom
there you can see that there's that
sample for ninety this kind of just kind
of outlying so what does that mean that
means there's a really good chance or
something up with that do that do doing
something really different obviously the
graphs I can't tell you why but it's
gonna tell you that of the hundred
samples and i dont down maybe that one
is doing something you can go look at
home here on the shape of these plots so
I ordered these again the the actual
numbers themselves aren't really all
that important in the order
themselves aren't that important these
are really more these could be more like
bar graphs but bar graphs are really
really difficult to put like a hundred
home on this created times that's why
they're more like a plot and I order
from least to greatest so those on the
on the far left they're actually really
important and they're just as important
as the ones on the far right even though
they are physically smaller cool thing
about me is you can let you go home and
you can see them but that's just kind of
a comment on on the shape of the graphs
here's another one where the family is
pretty tightly grouped together so this
is an example of a of a family group and
i think is pretty pretty solid hear
those samples that I recently pulled
down and ran through the system so
example script we have
archetype stuff so this is actually very
similar to the previous one but it is
you less noise essentially so it uses
the databases that are creating the
archetype so the first one takes couple
minutes to run but the sample size I had
I think about 1,300 at Alice's at 300
samples about 1,300 analyses it takes
maybe I don't tell four minutes to run
the script this grip over I'm pretty
much instantly because it pulls the
archetype straight out of database and I
just bought the only place that means
their deviation so this just really
gives you a good deal of the overall
distribution of Tiger standard
deviations
so this is kind of this what this gives
you it just gives you a good overall
feel you can see it as was pretty tight
you can see that there's a couple couple
pictures here you know the behavior API
said resource resource API calls kind of
all over the place something that maybe
you and one immediately removes this is
again it's another good visual way of
saying hey these bitches are really
tight they're really the standard
deviations are really close to the mean
we really want to use those and the ones
that aren't you can say hey what if we
just meet in the next time that we
define this function here is the one
that's not fair and honest and again
this could be good as the dad you put
into the right so what I found is that a
lot of the automated like threats dreams
sometimes they don't tell the truth when
they just give you a hash dumping right
is like 200 hashes and they say all
these belong to projects are always
going to go to store all these belong to
do it right exercise thing and turns out
that they i mean like not a hundred
percent there and so if you're just
dumping and stuff from particular
threats feeds you might find they have a
much wider variance and their beecher
set standard deviations and that's a
very good way of your kind of getting
here in 20 sources
absolutely yes so that's why that's why
I always include the date of the report
that guy got it from again like I said I
got these pretty much all from from open
source reporting was my pretty much my
only source for you has jazz and whatnot
and and I always made sure that the date
was something very very important to
distinguish it is separate but
absolutely mean you're gonna get
completely different results from the
wall from this year than you got two
years ago
alright so best guest up high so this is
this is the script that kind of does the
hey I have a known sample I want to
figure out which architect is most
closely fit to obviously doesn't fit any
of them and still gonna give you an
answer but gonna give you the answer
this you know where that works great so
compared to test back to each of the
story archetypes it normalizes improves
the sample to fit the target I but they
are kind of explained that process
earlier but the whole idea is to take
the sample you take the analysis you get
from you know the sandbox and you only
look at the features that are relevant
to that archetype when you're doing your
comparisons that defines Euclidean
distance from not warm front aspect to
the archetype to end it also and
distance between the archetypes vectors
to the archetypes mean to find standard
deviation it figures out how many
standard deviations away you're seeing
is based on the average standard
deviation that the internal did the
internal families doctors were from the
internal mean that didn't make any sense
why the talk later it's kinda hard to
explain but
essentially what you get is you get a
standard you get a how many standard
deviations is your feature set away from
the archetypes feature set and based on
that rack and stack them and say how
close they are in this through my
samples again
relatively low number of samples bout
308 showed that number one guest was 75
percent correct basically had no
knowledge of who it was or what it was
and then after that I was able to go
back and say yeah yeah you told me
correctly 75 percent of time the first
top our top three it that number jumped
in ninety-eight percent so we take
something I think we can absolutely get
better numbers than this I think the way
that you get better numbers in this
process is you prune the feature sets
even more you go back and look at those
rash said hey this is as too much
thinner deviations let's remove that
line or hey you know i happened to me I
happen to know that was one in here that
needs to be the snow and then you kind
of shape those little better in other
ways you populate it with you more data
you give it more samples you give it
more you give the more you know and tell
you make sure the samples that you
actually say what you say samples no
particular thing it it it really is but
your top 3 98 percent of things are good
here that looks like it's gonna tell you
first thing is going to take the
distance from your your your vector to
the archetype how many standard
deviation is this going to rack and
stack them and and and pretty much tell
you your best guess so there at the
bottom it says this goes for this guy's
whatever 32 C so
what happens if the sake verify how can
you have been verified what you truly
don't know obviously I cheated because I
you samples from itself so I knew what
they were headed time will listen to it
now but I know so what would you have
done that well you can look at it
graphically so compared to our sights
high as the final example here in
essentially what it does is it improves
the sample in the same in the same
regard as as the previous trip but then
it plots against all the archives and
what it does is a very visually easy way
you can even say hey you know this
really doesn't occur at all and its
graphical way to verify this guess so
here we go here is a here's a quiz so
what these what these samples are you
hear what these parts are right here is
you have a sample in our tests and read
the blue is the archetype that's being
compared to the yellow and green are the
standard deviations away from the blue
myself I'm just looking at my polygraphs
which one does the red most of all I
mean you can see this just came across
those you can see that that's one that
if it's pretty much almost exactly as
you can see if all of her right there
between the two upper and lower limits
so here's an example of where it was
wrong so best guest told me that this
should have been the number one guy so
it's not clear this not you can see red
dots that are clearly outside of the are
clearly outside of the the standard
deviations all across the board so the
second guess was actually this did and
so if you choose between the first guess
the second guess the second is right on
so again it's a pretty it's a very nice
way to graphically verify your best
guess
was correct or if your best guess gives
you like you know five basically I've
determine if you go look at the grass
you can pretty much tell that that the
first guess was completely wrong for
whatever reason that the second guess
was right so that's what I have right
now I do for long products I wanna me
nobody ever does right so what are the
next steps that I currently have to this
guy I went to operationalize this is a
couple things that I didn't do that I
would like for 12 creating cooper
reporting model so this is like
automatically generated every time you
run it and that's that's like literally
next on the list I didn't actually get
that finished I have a stand-alone
Python scripts that will basically
interact with the API right now so if
you have a Google service running the
API you run the script will just get
into these databases so you can run the
rest of the scripts but it would be
really really just kind of built into
Google from the get-go and additional
features right now it was very very
simple stuff writes all we did was count
as count the number of essentially tags
that Google created for these samples I
would like to do some more sophisticated
stuff like look at the number of bytes
their pastor buffers look at the number
of bytes the past 30 caps look at some
of the more things they're more
intrinsic than just counting to create
some sort of like front end so that you
could easily get your archetypes without
having to be a sequel person to go in
and manually edit them sequel and
cluster grass so the one that he didn't
see didn't see any cost of gasoline see
where you could take a whole group of
samples and put them on a single plot
and see how close they were relationally
the challenge there is that when you
have it in dimensional vector in you
want to block them on a two-dimensional
space is gonna lose your gonna lose data
and there's all kinds of theories out
there like you know what the best way to
to do that is but some point you're
gonna like you're gonna lose data and
the way you lose data is kind of
important so I'm in the process of China
event out a couple different solutions
to put these on to put you know all
these on a cluster graph correctly he
has any suggestions I love to hear your
thoughts on that but that's about it so
petition you can't explain these things
to me know see there's probably a much
more intelligent way to do that
of the presentation coming up tell me
how stupid I am NOT using bounded
distributions and let me know you think
the product there's the obvious but
thanks guys