imma go ahead and get started so
absolutely kinda in June beyond a major
put and beyond in there because I
definitely don't want to harbor
misconception that you can do everything
Anderson it's not sure 100% silver boy
it was meant to definitely accelerate
the process and automate a lot of the
things that you used to have to do
manually but there are some things that
we do above and beyond recon and g2 to
really build our open source
intelligence products and so that's why
that's why the and beyond is there and
of course I'm talking about applies to
application security so who am I on the
Managing Consultant over to visit so I
run all of our commercial services out
of envision we are software security
company that means mobile applications
web applications declined applications
all I kinda stuff so you're in need of
that type of service we certainly
appreciate if you would consider us to
be our consultants are looking up for
users by train
sometimes developers sometimes you guys
and then anybody that I listen to me I
love to talk and I like when people as
in other words a compartment near a lot
right tone I love Jesus and as you can
see also love my church shout out to new
spring in South Carolina pastor P Drive
mass and always recall I can never get
away with I'm that guy that I came off
last military the shares on the back
never get a warning I'm always walking
away with it to get so caught on live
demos ahead not as many as I wanted to
do simply because if I did I'd be about
four hours so as always my do you live
demonstrations with with those an
offensive it's early as possible and
while I don't condone it can prevent it
if I did I would be doing any demos that
would be fun so talk to know that I
don't look at recon angie is being a
children by one person managing the
color the framework but there are a lot
of people involved in contributing
modules and code and things of that sort
and this talk as an element of me
talking about these folks were involved
in that Brian fuhrman's actually here
sitting in the back Michael Hoffman's to
be clear I'm not sure he's been at the
Derby Conn this year but all these
gentlemen here including in the whole
offensive security group I'll talk more
about why a little while yet these boats
here in Mahalakshmi shot out because it
wasn't for them a lot of material that
would exist there you're talking about
US Attorney John on the last day changed
a lot and I've always talked about how
all these new technologies new resources
become available for us to harvest
information from and also my kind of
trajectory meant for years changed I
used to do a lot and that's where a lot
of this lawsuit was was geared towards
have since moved on to envision we're
now into an application security 100%
and so most of what i've talked
previously about a dozen has been kinda
related to net second I figured you know
I've had to come up with a whole new
methodology about how I approach open
source intelligence gathering now that I
am now that I'm not gonna share my
methodology and show people how I do
talk a lot of apps that are like you
know I'm source code or more fun doing
application scared I just don't see the
need for spending much time on a source
intelligence is ever going to answer
that question for you so what good is
the second set of the source code now
that's not always relevant but it is a
division because most of time probably
89 percent of our engagements we have
sourced we are a company that's bug
focus not looking for every similar
ability in the application not just the
ones that led us penetrate the
environment or penetrate to a specific
goal has been outlined for us in a
penetration test that's a legitimate
question
and often sent one thing are consumed
one thing right up front and at the
darker the assessment is the drain of
the need for more open source
intelligence know what I mean by dark
black box versus white box testing and
so the closer you get the black box them
more useful office open source
intelligence is going to be a but it's
not a zero-sum game because even even if
you're doing white boxer engine source
code analysis you can still use our
products to help show risk in the bottom
line is whether you doing a penetration
tester of our abilities whether you're
doing a dynamic test or source code
analysis the goal is the same ultimately
we want our client to fix problems in
coat but want to fix problems in their
applications so how do we do that when
we do that by showing risk the risk are
undergoing impact right impact is the
key to making intelligent risk decisions
on static analysis to change how we show
empower I we can still use those same
products along with vulnerabilities that
we find in code to show attack patterns
and say well as doctor can do this with
information they got here this
particular vulnerabilities of doesn't
necessarily show change our show impact
it just gives us more information right
actionable recommendations to now we
have coatings up a pass to fix your
problem with the idea is the same we
want people to fix bad code as a seminar
in the morning
somebody I'm super glad I have you seen
my peace talks you know that you know
our quite often approach as soon as part
of a float like I take over one piece of
information first and then moved on to
the next night transformed into
something else goes in a flow thing that
I've seen with when I'm collecting
information perhaps it's not so much a
flow of information
different categories of information that
I after and so there's not a specific
law you have to go in that were chasing
and so I've done here this particular
talk today talk about the different
categories of nation will talk about
what I'm looking for
why i'm looking for that specific
information and then we'll talk a little
bit about how I go get that information
and hopefully get some good image
missions in the first category of
information will talk about her contacts
so what am I looking for when talking
about contacts well usernames and e-mail
joyous and sometimes email addresses are
used and why am I looking at stuff well
they open up certain attack patterns
with an application security that I see
all the time
coming across in reports done by
Invision and reports done by other
consulting firms and those attack
patterns are as follows a user
flawed I've got college username well in
most cases are seen there's no there's
people do a collimation very very poorly
attitude typical problem solve and
policies we see that rampant everywhere
right and how many people many people
here do consulting engagements regularly
where where they they report we found
her policy every application and almost
need to be a template that started
building the report is back on its a
ballot problem or user to user names
opens at a top I guess a username and
they're not doing anything automation
properly
well there's a good chance we can guess
their password we do this quite
frequently to gain access authentication
access the application also what about
account lockout this is also another
difficult problem solving its rarely
done right
always it's typically done wrong if it's
not done right
users and you have an account lockouts
poorly
quite often I can result in what we call
a user-level denial of service
vulnerability righteous systematically
lockout accounts as a penetration always
do that the purpose of this is a way
that we can show your risk to the
organization
information well for those of you that
I've gotta some search functionality
built in there I'm actually gonna bounce
out we'll show you this walking through
briefly I just lost my place tonight
activist and 2 I'm going to Lotus not
sure data shows you that didn't stop
just stop shots your database enabling
time during the process to about 200 you
mess it up on a later when you're
running later module or something like
that when any case and you do like a
show modules you'll see that every
module has within its path
something along these lines what that
means is is the data that goes into the
module and the data that we're trying to
get out of the model so say you got a
new project or you're connecting against
a target and all you have is a domain
when you add the domain to the database
do it surged domain stats show you all
the models that take the domain as input
and then you can kind of see what you
gonna get out of it so say I want to do
have a domain so I do a search domains
that those are all the Recon modules
that start with domains a result
something else wellness contact right to
search desk contacts in letters dashes
before this time because we're trying to
get contacts and these are all the
models recon injury that results in
contacts so what couple that I'm
particularly interested in right now
well first sailed maple so what is sales
mobile homes before my previous talks
one of the original founders of boneless
read less to tell me in the past year
and what he did was he had this goal in
mind that you want to create a new
jigsaw for those you that didn't know it
was it was an online CRM that was
awesome for harvesting contact
information about people they were
converted over today 2.com under think
it was sales floors and then it's been a
game of cat and mouse on the transcript
or data indication wall and
just not been very broadly by sharing
data can't necessarily blame but we want
that data right well on this guy was
like that data should be free so he's
made it his goal to create a new jigsaw
for all that information is accessible
now including the email address so we no
longer have to try to build email
addresses office first names lasting
whatever email addresses are freely
available for sales maple sub let me out
of domain and I'm gonna go ahead and use
my church is a good target and they've
done a decent job of things up to know
when we embarrassed by me using them so
I can see you got one in their run it
seldom able to lay down you can see I
get first names like that last things
and then I get email addresses rights
not to build gmail.com nice so seldom
able something that I've added recently
it's definitely worth taking a look into
these things also like specifically said
I was security use this I'm not going to
build it up and it also put up a wall or
something that's going to be accessible
to the security community so I feel
pretty freely about about marketing he's
tough as nails tester tester is a module
that will call the email addresses for
you now that we have email addresses in
the system load male tester ronit you
actually go out using SMTP protocol and
DNS to make sure there's a mail server
there and talk to the mail server to
validate the email address actually
exist then it'll remove it from the
database if it doesn't so it's not a
perfect science did you can lock down
your mail servers to not respond tonight
give that information through SMTP but
in most cases it's been successful use
bring prevents this and so demoing it
will actually do us any good
scraping metadata from files in here is
overused is it
medical cell bill and a couple bucks you
basically what it does is it was like a
Google search and tries to enumerate all
the public-facing XLS xml-based and
totally based documents and PDFs that
are associated with the domain
edited out of them well the whole bunch
of dependencies romantic movie if you
are using polly's and it takes to set up
a built-in redundancy so let's load
medical aller and i doing them using a
smart alert feature that is awesome
videos lol medical all are in a good
show options here we see the source of
its use the same domain extraction set
to true will be set
extract to all and run it and rock
wickets extract a false to come back and
say these are all the documents found on
websites that are associated with a
particular domain pretty cool
information we can get from that lets
set extract to Drew and now I said
extracted shoreline now bridging the gap
from passive reconnaissance to active so
I wanna make that very clear
going to reach out to those web service
and pull down those files so now we're
actively touching the environment's an
important distinction to make by default
this module set the ball so that you
just see the vials I mean you can make
it to you can go out and grab them
yourself or you can use this model move
forward
make sure just remember it's not passive
a longer this point so run down the
files are distracting me to do
information you get from that quite
often user names actually used on the
internal systems quite often you'll just
get the names of the people so they
can't name versus the username you get
to computer name quite often on the
network that made the the software like
creating an idea what software the
running and inside so a lot of need
information that you get anywhere else
you can extract metadata with them files
and so basically yeah this is this is
what medical looks like I don't have it
storing anywhere into the database at
the moment simply because the three
different file types tho lax animal and
PDF file types on parsing they're not
consistent terms of the names of the
data fields and so right now I just
gotta bring out to the screen keyboard I
just put this together yesterday so yeah
I'm working out it's a work in progress
I was like you guys were enjoying the
party I was up in the room waiting for
the next information profiles and what
am I looking for here will social media
profiles public or private I'm doing
everything to social media something
like eBay site where you have a
public-facing profile just call it
social media and the public profile and
private still relevant because we can't
find them doesn't mean we can't connect
with them and then on privatized at
information access so prob public and
private social media profiles why well
some of those it opens up some other
time I like our our contacts did you
know a collimation done wrong or white
doesn't exist at all any type of reset
system often this type of folks here
running to invent a process is fairly
early I do what I mean by that is like
answer these questions and I'll send you
an email as quite often
case in point recently I was doing
assessment of a fortune 500 company just
operate under the porch of popular right
and they had a single sign-on portal for
everything everything they used in band
password security question and they also
had user numeration in the login page so
I was able to users go out on the
internet harvest some people just like a
done in previous previous demonstrations
and harvest invalidates users user
enumeration but when you validate user
obviously it's going to show you the
security the security questions they're
using like five or six random security
questions we found was that if you just
kept on asking for the same person
eventually get all their security
questions so I did after five or ten
people look at the security questions
that will be pretty easy to get high
school that I go to the name of my dog
workable
56 keep requesting Angela asked me just
those two questions so down the basement
profile this person's profile went out
there started doing some harvesting sure
enough there is a better this elegant
doll's name what highschool did I go too
well
Facebook tells the mascot right and so I
just look at the high school band at the
mascot went back to the authentication
page a few times varying capitalization
eventually change the password right now
got access to she wasn't an admin to
once I got inside the system they have a
user lookup function we could look up
everybody else in the company guess
which was their username so then I can
see you with this guy is its name let's
go back to the password reset system and
do the same thing eventually I have you
got stuff happens you know this is Chris
gates or or robbery give talks before
that slowed up on absolute style right
that's what it is is most times you see
the ability to low not high high impact
would guess what theres back to change
together a profile gives us the ability
to do that so how we do this well a
couple of ways a LinkedIn com module and
that's all it was
I think somebody here mentioned it
earlier today he would use being
profiles and it would go to the profile
and it would go to others profiles
LinkedIn on the right hand side
others that you would call that we just
heard forty employer personal company
and then once it was done it would add
all those people to the contacts table
was like that's the one that wrote this
road original model as a hebron 1232
thinks now we can 2222 popular profile
stable let me take the profiles table
you choose crawling can get more
profiles and then just have a separate
models to call these profiles Herman
cossacks he's done all that work and I'm
tell me it is the most effective contact
harvesting method which in reality is
amazing views encourage it takes a
little while Tehran
more contacts than any other than any
other module shuttle model and framework
profiler named jack which you're like
user name of your handle whatever no
good like $136 resources and tell you
whether or not you're there
well alright we can go and say hey where
is this I got this particular target
where does this person have a profile on
the Internet
enumerate all the places ever profile go
their harvest information or profiler
does that for over 200 different sites
on his expand my web preacher expanded
the targets beyond just social media to
things like previously Madison and some
of the more unmentionable places that
are you certainly wouldn't want your
people have accounts at but he did that
because he's a threat intelligence
guides is really good resource to go
find information about where people have
profiles
talking about the guy in my class so we
show this to you really what is
obviously yeah you just like person's
name and you just drill down until you
have a list of everybody with that name
right and then you have a better profile
about this John hole in a guy that works
for me a bit of it is a division was
like
is awesome I start writing module around
this time it's still pretty buggy I
think one reason why the maybe they
haven't publicize it all that much as
cuz it's got some bugs in it but I'm in
the process of writing a module horrors
that you can just takes people's names
were whittled down as i hear all the
profiles associated with that name
pretty handy stuff ok here we go next
talking about look at pornex category
look at boris bridges and what about
china like breached data right but not
what I'm looking forward looking for you
rentals rock we all look for nationals
are using upon less damage it's amazing
the kind of information get out of that
details details important well their
important because we defined areas week
right if we know that a breach of the
company occurred because they had ramped
acetyl injection application developers
might have problems understanding the
how to code injection we can definitely
hone in on that and other applications
on the same domain or owned by the same
company and increases will wear those
important well uses rapid and also
pattern analysis of something came
across recently so you know you do
publicity see somebody last October
right had a password
capital Aug 14 like a month ago in July
what would you have guessed the password
anybody capital S U and 15 right and you
would have login as i'm ok so happens
all the time so you can use that
information and get in so how do we find
well searched all the modules that
assist you in those areas you will find
the full suite of phone the stock which
obviously acosta money will talk more
about that here in a little bit this
module right here is the one that just
kind of the guests know it doesn't cost
anything it's just a yes no it's been
it's been breached or has been seen in a
bridge loan stuff and from Troy hot
probably exposed this by now you can
search his briefs data and his face so
he's cataloging pay so much to replace
websites and allows you to search for
usernames email addresses in all of
these places well pretty handy tools
once again these things say yes or no
and then the baseball actually give you
a link to the pace another place you go
to see a little bit about breach details
privacy rights dot org
haven't seen as critical resource is
where I go to look at details about
breaches regularly updated on this a
little bit year as you can see the most
recent one that logs September 17 wasn't
all that long ago with the Kardash
website god help us all because look how
many people got hacked 660,000 people
have a balance on the Kardashian website
man we are going down the tubes be able
to end of humanity is near but charts
which uncle just say and you can get
information about that particular thing
about it is they get regular updates and
stuff like that so you can stay on topic
today with it and i also like to the
Krypton security are a good place to
harvest information about this and you
can actually go here in to search for
the organization
the company name on it it'll come back
and tell you that companies been seen in
a bridge somewhere so pretty handy
resource there another one is the one
company hacks interface that many cells
are built on his website basically just
goes out in such as Twitter or the name
of the company and then reached are
happy that is sometimes results are
unpredictable but but it's another
resource and of course are searching out
there using your search engines for
something else i'm looking for
technology I want to know about
technologies and why specifically for
specific service I technologies on a
framework for being use wanna know I
wanna know the server architectures
anything I can get from a third-party
resource about the underlying technology
is being used
outdated software so while his wife
technologies and port facilities other
doctors know once I have to manage
operations into an injection or once a
single injections really nice to know
what system actually inject into a so
that I can just meet with that payload
needs to be some end up with a false
negative situation and talking about
direct quotations if you see what
version are using you got to see details
and go to exploit the TV Live exploit
code for it and then you may be able to
get access to that particular machine
without ever seen application without
ever having to go through the
application nothing is your server
server and client side trainers have all
of their own like vulnerabilities and
associated only the dotnet got a certain
set of antibodies that are only
associated with them
angularjs has an ability that are all
associated with angular and so he knew
the framework for dealing with you can
go specifically look for the abilities
how do I do this one start with bill
without com dot com the internet
constantly looking at heathers analyzing
survey responses in all kinds of
different stuff fingerprinting
fingerprinting server-side and
client-side technologies obviously the
code so it's really easy fingerprint
client-side stuff was being burned all
that stuff you just go there you search
for domain or search for specific cosell
tell you the information i've seen about
that particular about that particular
host of the place you look at job of its
ok used on the homepage of the website
as you can see here we have job openings
and envision so cheap kamagra quick look
for a job application security please
send us your resume we will have to talk
to you
party job sites savings I got resume
posting sites up like that obviously it
company access looking for elite PHP
developer well the problem running
Israel no least is busy bees like plane
of existence ok so what our bellies next
category information i'm looking for
what exactly am I looking for well live
exploitable vulnerabilities would not be
exploitable vulnerabilities without ever
send a package to the environment
source code leagues in things like use
troops in forum stuff like that and then
straight up searchable bugs are talking
expand want searchable bugs in a moment
but why is all this results in really
low or no effort level discovery so we
also don't work for us
somebody else's head scan the code
somebody else's and the dynamic public
facing website and maybe they discovered
some vulnerabilities and made them
search will just go out there and spoke
information and then BAM we've got we've
got seats available is a really quick
wins how do I go about doing that well
I'm full-body scanners right stuff like
most of you probably heard about this
point I'm their scan the internet for
web applications and on that basis for
his think they assert themselves a
certain field he's not doing too much in
terms of terms of DA Govs
to have in the past maybe now you can
just go there and i charge my domain
search facebook.com and you'll see our
values its tracking facebook.com last
time it's candid partisan false-positive
sure there's positives there it's an
application
the riddle positive right but you know
how to do things can somebody else
babysat the scanner somebody else I did
the works after weighted towards finish
durability
another train home project basically
what it does is it looks at dot net apps
from a 3rd party perspective just go
look at your sent a series of tests to
determine whether the applications
global to any of those dotnet specific
configuration also really useful tool
their 3rd party perspective of
vulnerability disclosure sites XSS was
around for a long time it has been taken
over by excess says those not really
sure why of all the data is also been
migrated over so if you see is access
access poses now the the resource for
that show their search for the domain
search for the hosts and see if
anybody's reported across as scripting
vulnerabilities that application domain
and of course there's donate kind of the
the hub for debasement you can always go
there and search as well
to see if anything on with your target
domain has been device
which definitely means whether there's
been some level of exploitation on that
particular server and so did you go
hunting or so how do we do this well
earthly concerns desperate buildings and
I see all the modules that you this
morning recon engine shutdown modules
will go out to the punch tighter and
extend exercise post searches for you
the other stuff
manually gonna be public place right in
its target I got it marked out that's
because we're testing testing any Uhde
or staging test environment maybe not
publicly but if there is a publicly
accessible version of the application
well then it can be seen by the status
ok that information may still be useful
and it still within scope because you're
not the one that's right the dangerous
out there you're going to get the data
about it so just because you're testing
in a restricted environment doesn't mean
that there's no information out there
you can use about the production version
of the applications of you that my so
what about dynamic portability so about
static or abilities goes back to that
searchable boxing out talking about how
much I find steady source code analysis
type of our abilities on the internet be
open source intelligence was some of the
papers of yourself up into a result is
really talk later called get Rob to get
up and basically what it does is it will
call you an organization's name it will
go to get all the repositories that
bloggers organization and a list of
filenames not gonna put out a list of
filenames and then it will look at all
the filename to see if there's any known
vulnerabilities associated files such as
underscore token Datar be right so
things like that really really cool idea
got me thinking we can take this further
is actually a modular framework only per
module that exists is the one that
analyzes file name but its extensible so
if you want to get involved in a project
something like this is maybe a good
project for you to contribute to another
really good place to look for bugs and
codes budged in code is a website called
search code and I've got it all up here
it's a fairly new project think it's
been maybe a little over a year now
there's filled with your search go but
you can it's doing is harvesting source
code from a budget of repositories you
see the list their get up big bucket
Google Code complex are supposed to Dora
and you can just go in and searched
right you search strings that are
associated unknown source code abilities
and framework your testing an app that
positive words public-facing well we can
begin to do source code analysis ever
having to pull down the codes most
people would say well I just put on the
code and analyser well what if your
target organizations got $250 I'd rather
just use a search engine that started on
all the indexing and have a search of
warming up so so these are these are
real real real approaches to how we can
do this kind of a funny thing I was
going through the get robbed code as you
can see down there what's he looking for
a particular snippet that particular
signature was very kind and she is
looking for a is looking for your API
keys file so that you pushed out like a
four of a kind you and your API keys and
find it using around I've done that
before you can go find it bizarre
rebasing higher-paid actually whited out
completely but I've done that before I
made that mistake we are all human we
make mistakes so that's another way to
do this is a man searching using either
give your Google or both
guy so we're talking right now God or
king is Google to working with an
accusing the Advanced search engine and
and so there's two different approaches
that we can switch W someone anyone
talking to nightlights so the other
student approaches to Dorking one we can
use advanced search or use Google's
Advanced search which this with the site
colon get hot dot com Advanced search
operator on there some advantages and
disadvantages to both have searched for
work so you can you file name you could
say I want to look for a pass are not
following the path you
as a sage / Idrus a which is as you say
public he's right I can search for that
if I just put that and hit enter
anything you need to strengthen their so
you have to restrain that will that will
be predictable show up in a particular
file every single time
more searchable abilities as a string
involved right so that's not really that
much of a headache but it is a
restriction
makes it a little bit hard to focus on
our targets were already using in
cycling yahoo.com only way to really
focus in on a targeted by knowing the
organization and by knowing the
repository name is in using the Euro
thing you see on the bottom line of the
slide there to focus on his superb
repository makes it a little more
cumbersome to find those vulnerabilities
are using Google doors on my call to get
when I get home through Google I just
kinda get dorks I'm not trying to
actually create a new word independent
dorks out there but they are more than
just right I mean we can do it for sight
but the dot com site source words dog
whatever is now it's been around forever
probably news there's no code blacks
there's a budget of resources there so
we're not just restricted to get the
results non-users reliable obviously
Google indexed upright so after changing
fairly regular in fairly quickly perhaps
Google has an index that yet so I have
found that the results of surging code
bar bilities through give up through
Google is less effective than just doing
it straight through the Advanced Search
Engine ok so while we do this well
search within the framework will show
you a couple new models we got minor
repose and again towards modules with
those do is get home I will go out the
organization names within the database
it'll blow down all the repositories and
all the developer profiles for that
organization that's absolutely key
places I start doing reconnaissance for
the sort of information is out wanna
know where the developer for files are
as a reminder that information what you
know when you go to say new spring that
Cece even though
they have a private organization
organizational access controls a
privatized lot of the repos you can
still see all the developers at her so
she knew that organization pulled out
all the profile because it will be
useful here in a bit then take all of
the profiles of profound the profiles
table and it will go down all the
repositories under this profiles which
includes both the ones associated with
the organization and also the ones not
associate with just the wall the ones I
belong to that particular person once
again we're starting to expand our
footprint here and they get hot dogs
will take all of the repository
harvested and run those search strings
against them
ok right now got a small file and
therefore forgive forget the sky like
six or seven different searches in there
but something that is a community we can
start to build I just I went I just come
through Google on the internet trying to
find all the ones that people have been
tweeting and talking about hunting
articles about over the past few years
just collected those but obviously
there's room for expansion there so very
very powerful year the next thing I'm
after is a master sensitive information
we haven't completely left the the gift
of stuff yet after debugging information
any type of device information that
developers left somewhere
development notes made it doesn't
development let's note somewhere out
there on the internet and configuration
so probably saying internet and well you
explain why you're just a minute but how
here in just a minute because they do it
completely on accident actually pretty
funny I'm so why
well obviously we can learn about the
private repositories information we see
in public areas of theirs debugging at
this dividing notes about them debugging
and internal or an application that's
hosted an internal positive or we can
begin to learn about that particular
application and then of course you
configure and the whole reason for doing
out of an configuration storage because
they don't want to push her tonsils to
the code repository and so obviously
within that we have possibly secret keys
possible API keys of our party API's
things of that sort system pretty darn
sensitive information
how do I look behind in peace and that's
really hard for those of you that dude
that used to try to search space as a
part of your OC methodology you know
that those things are like the actual
search capability built in place
websites is like a flicker in time as I
searched the past three hundred and that
was about 90 seconds were so hot and
you're continually scraping apologized
catalog all the space darn near
impossible to search Q late that's
really hard to used to search based upon
information but we have just under
people here use just one guy she
probably you probably know about what
I'm talking about when I get to this
others liked it so let's treat them like
paced by developers are operating within
the context of get home and give it has
this really neat feature I can put
debugging information there I can put
configuration information information
there and share with the other
developers why would I use that
third-party waste paysite well I don't
blame you for using it all but the key
is the gift doesn't allow for
organizational just right so your
organizational accounts cannot create
adjusters don't just associated with it
was mean which means all of the athletes
controls that come with having
organizational cow don't protect any
just saw the just and injured by the
fall so in that developer dozing creates
Egypt based on sensitive information
about application that just goes there
public-facing account and by god I found
so many sensor credentials sensitive
information all the stuff debugging API
keys and stuff in June just simply by
harvesting all those developer profiles
going to each one of them clicking on
just seeing what's there and developers
don't realize that when they're
operating within the private access
control restricted repository say
created just about this just goes to
their public profile
by the whole again so that's definitely
something you want to start looking out
and what do we do able to just down
there we just are searching for key
words and words are you want to search
for here our stuff like anything that
you would search for say if you don't
post exploitation on a machine right
we're looking for passwords were looking
for
on database connection strange looking
for maybe just demands actual commands
on a fan on things that sort
a lot of time you look for you just go
strolling through the look at them but I
like when I use with Recology
modularized down in their research that
will take all of the just so when you
actually do the repo marginal
profiles impulse allergists to this will
go through this module go through in
search of those just a solid keywords
that you give it very very powerful
definitely check it out
ago lacking database we've all heard of
this before right
watching Google Dorking do for us as you
that a mess with this new public had to
do it manually because the tools that do
it in a fashion no longer exists a
leadoff double stuffing it's really neat
error messages double whole bunch need
information contacts live
vulnerabilities that they're running
something that's that's searchable a
credentials files as we saw in the
medical or marginal all kinds of neat
stuff and the whole on sources for dorks
right i mean you've got a database which
is hosted by the office of security guys
used to be hosted over John along
website
anonymous they published their supply
list a couple years ago trust actually
going on download that thing it's out
there you can grab it that's an
interesting set of dorks to look for
single injection of the Google dorks all
the different doors that are out there
that you get leverage Google and then of
course custom lists right on I've got my
own custom list of application security
focused towards that I use when I go out
I search for them but not limited to
just google right we use in being Yahoo
in a lot of different places
ominous also being hacking database
available from the bishop Fox folks that
do the research degrees but guess what
mastered own Google I got the Google
hacking working within recond something
I've wanted to do since I started
building this out three years ago
whatever as anybody's ever tried to
scrape who knows it's hard like they do
a lot to prevent third parties from
scraping their content but I found a way
to do it
ok I'm not gonna go in all 12 details
about how I do it because out there who
want to take a look when I got drunk and
searched ok gotta do a got a model that
at the base model and it will go out and
it will take all these Google dorsal
situated with the domain so that you're
targeting you're actually targeting your
scope and will respond with all of the
different hit again you probably asking
by the box and you get by the caches
well but we demonstrate so going on here
let's load the Google database and right
off the bat is on a good show you the
options for the better I mean bumping up
to the top two people back in sea ice on
media Italy you'll see that they got a
whole list a different kind of course
here so what it does is an and God bless
the folks they managed to maintain it
they put in all the overhead you take
the submissions and they provided to
provide access to that to me as an open
source project as some of the other
products that I can build this thing so
deftly huge shout out to the offensive
security guys in months and particularly
what I do is I entire database upgrade
all of the different doors into
categories and so on a search for all
like $3,700 reach them and take you may
want to focus on one particular area I'm
so let's say I want to just search for
error messages so I can see each day
today
error messages to truces to set up like
an hour surgery just those things up at
the top if you want to use your own
custom lest you just set dorks to the
path of the file and you'll ignore all
the Google database stuff and you
shirtless guys here
her messages and it'll do it for the
demands by go-ahead run longer so
connected to the Internet
let it go and google like okay not a
human lie I give them a little while ago
a couple weeks ago and liked it took
like three runs for Google highly say ok
you're about so long as I'm basically
what you're going to see eventually
you're going to see my just top flip
over an image pop up on the screen and I
will be the capture and what recon and
she gives you the ability to do is enter
the CAPTCHA within the framework it will
communicate with Google to receive your
emeritus so there you see you capture
any takers for this isn't working
probably be completely ruined it by
talking about it but that looks like he
s ILS and her actually gets faster so I
get the cookie I guess I am human from
Google not pass that could be ok so I go
gangbusters on this a lot faster when
you're not over like two bars of
eighties but you can see his right mind
cannot modify header information one of
these things we do to the website or
something to possible vulnerabilities so
this stuff works on one thing I notice
is to be able to do this forever to come
back and noticed that the more difficult
to capture the longer the Camorra
question again
like this one right here on this now
because I think you should see how it
works pretty cool stuff I'm super
excited about this it's been an awesome
capabilities trying to build into this
for a long time and finally here so some
final thoughts on this long time since I
last talked to all the cool stuff then I
guess what is well guess what this is
done today free right in fact the only
thing you need to do is get an API key
produced nothing everything I do it for
40 cents application security obviously
pulled down 10 JAL's gonna cost money
but everything else done today hun Sen
free doesn't cost you and that's that's
really cool internet for these advanced
search that searches and stuff like that
you've got stuff that you use on a daily
basis are things you used in the past
please tell me expand the list you can
e-mail them to me or you can send them
to us pull request out of the framework
either one works however you get it
seems fine air once again ciao ragazze
offensive security for maintaining
providing access to the database also
allow me to make a regular request for
to keep it updated so every time you
shop new updates refine gee you're
getting updated version of the Google
database and also what I now something
new and I just got permission to
announce this of the past 24 hours of
service and it said look I can't afford
as a boutique individual that has
clients I can't afford to get all of the
API access required to do a lot of
things that you do and so as a private
contractor I'm gonna start providing
that as a service to folks so and you
want somebody to do all the Reconquista
for you
contract with me and as a consultant
also go through couple hours to all the
OC are you filled out the work space
station from their kind of making some
of that more expensive stuff accessible
to everyone doing in a way that I feel
is
is ethical without without reaching any
other founders so come up to me
afterward get a car give me a card I
love to I'd love to work with you on
that and also if you don't already know
if you like what you see here you want
to get more in November up in Charlotte
North Carolina I'm gonna be teaching my
class you're never going anywhere right
for those you that here probably four
times as much that's ok is there becomes
also minutes so lured the other seven
are 50 bucks or whatever it was but yes
so i mean the black hat cost you like 45
grand you go
application security training so
encouraged to come out
abstract on rocks my training page also
I got so wet that I am done with the
presentation just in time are there any
questions and if you want about me
Twitter Follow me on so on and so forth
talk anybody still down otherwise a log