afternoon
attacks and smarter defending
fingerprinting nominee for the award the
least funny type of Derby Conn ever the
other equally on funny but true title is
zero mouth almost zero crypto TLS talk
if you are after some kind of DJB town
of elliptic curves with calculus and
stock you're probably going to be
disappointed I don't do the pic map
thing but if you want protocol analysis
and that sort of thing then hopefully
this is more for you
the genders really to do a quickie Las
primer for people that are not they are
multilateral years if you are doesn't
matter is pretty quick delivery beyond
finger taylor's fingerprinting as a
whole to handle section on attacker and
defender scenarios and then he wasn't
all so that people can go and play with
the stuff themselves before we start to
mention I use https along as an example
when I'm working through these things
but it's not HTTPS talk advice equally
to other tlass enable protocols this is
really just because everyone understands
browsers pretty well so he's example for
most people to grasp the other thing is
when I talk about various signatures and
what you can do with them
none of these hypotheticals are all been
done so if I say you could be at X I
have already fingerprinted aspects it is
possible is not just a lab type scenario
so why not said a quick deal as Prime
trilogy is what we really mean when
everyone says Asus out and if you really
mean necessarily should not be in this
talk we should be at your office getting
a sellout of your environment moving to
tell us and you can watch the recording
and then catch up on this but people use
TLS encryption is a phrase if it's an
algorithm and its not an encryption
algorithm its approach called used to
determine which cryptographic algorithm
amongst other things are going to use
its great for fingerprints because it
doesn't get mangled by now
proxies files or anything is completely
payload based it doesn't use TCP header
right the headers so it doesn't matter
what your networking equipment does it
stays intact and this is being managed
so the most common uses HTTPS he got a
browser on a web server and they want to
talk to each other and that would be
fine if you just had one browser in the
world and one web server in the world
they could have a predefined set of
crypto algorithms that use and use them
but that's not the case
the web server has to interact with more
than one type of browser and so they
need to find a common ground in what the
capabilities are and they certainly will
tell us they exchanged their
capabilities and turning the best one
that they can both use similarly there
are other web service in the world so
the client's need to be able to adapt to
what certainly talking to when you visit
a website you don't know in advance what
web service at on so they constantly
have to negotiate for each connection
and of course there's plenty of other
browsers to make this more complex and
you start seeing from diagrammed it gets
a mess of different possibilities and
different options even just using the
mainstream browsers there's no all
browsers in here there's no old versions
of these browsers there's no command
line stuff so you can imagine the number
of permutations that must be so how does
it work well you quickly used here last
books crypto ferries appear be sprinkled
magical crypto dust everything becomes
secure government surveillance go dark
dystopian future is avoided and we can
all go home have a nice drink and chill
out unfortunately the reality slightly
more mundane and what actually happens
is you have an exchange of hello packets
whereby the client's explained to each
other better word what their
capabilities are what cipher suites they
support compression they support that
kind of thing as key exchange which is
shockingly exchanging keys cryptographic
key material and there's options to
change the cipher spec halfway through
so they can renegotiate different
different settings and then you got the
encrypted data so what from this is
useful to us well we're looking at
Taylors clients so really suffering the
service kind of points we don't want
anything encrypted cause like I
mentioned I'm not the JB and I can't do
anything clever with encrypted data on
that and we don't want to try and key
exchange because the key is done
properly is going to be unique to
sessions so it's points the finger
which only releases decline hello packet
which is really convenient to because
that's the first back you ever getting a
teller transaction see the earliest
possible opportunity in the session so
this is our primary the way let's talk
about fingerprints so first of all why
clients as opposed to service
well service you can actively
fingerprint you can connect to a server
and drove it and determine what is you
can't with a client caused by default
it's a client it's not listening you
can't product you have to wait for it to
be putting something else before you can
determine what it is certainly a server
announces what it is anyway if anyone's
ever connected to an SMTP server web
server anything like that but just
screamed the software that's being used
across the banner there's no real meet
several ways to say
books and the next time you connect to
it it's still an Apache books you don't
really need to determine things on a per
connection basis if you're attacking the
client uses going to open IE or Firefox
or Chrome so you don't know one TCP
connection to another what it is even if
you profile them once that doesn't
matter two seconds later and finally
because of this service a much more
configurable one finds with regards to
tell us if the server is been modified
and it no longer matches our
fingerprints the much more difficult to
fingerprint from retailers expect
clients however don't get modified is
often how many people have logged into
their browser and and she removed
supported sites we actually probably are
some but there are not many people
generally sleep tight street from the
browser so let's get to where we started
and hopefully that will illustrate where
I'm going to do this
back at the year end of last year then
over bundled superfish
got busted again today but they busted a
bundle superfish
in with a bunch of their lap and rooftop
is out there that was meant to be
helping with us to sell books actually
man enabling SSL and there's been a
bunch of the tools that will discovered
around the same time and everyone was
worrying about them
and we have headlines like this we're
just talking about how the certificate
dropped onto the machines in various
ways and have been installed as a stiff
thority allowing the average to go and
re-signed connections as their own and
then people when crack growth and could
sign whatever they liked and that's a
typical fourteen attackers clients that
the certificate was only part of it you
could see other things that the
application was doing with my hardcore
lecturing to love netstat
you can look at the processes you can
see that there were two processes the
talk to each other
entirely on localhost and then one of
those processes goes and talks to the
internet now if you look at what those
are
its process number 408 pool and 3388 so
using my other league hacks going to
love task man you can look at 338 thats
Internet Explorer that's the one talking
on localhost the one hitting all the
websites is quiet that's because what's
happened is in in these cases are
talking genius box same sort of thing as
the others is the kind of sexy has
through one means or another
cooking connections to browse proxy
settings or whatever was told it to
connect to it and then it connects out
to the internet you can also take a hint
when you look at its installed directory
that it might be doing something with
Telus is got things for making stickers
so we know he's doing something with TLS
and we know the Browns connecting to it
and the browsers and getting errors
because likes to fish it has addresses
in the CIA store and that means that it
can re-sign anything it wants but that
also means is that no traffic from IE is
hitting the Internet it stops there the
fine is not boarded and the client makes
its own connection out that means that
whatever occurs on the network from his
perspective is purely about the client
and actually nothing to do with so if we
take a packet them unaffected Lenovo
laptop and inflicted one and put them
side by side
we can see that they're not the same
even a cursory glance they support a
completely different number of cipher
suites restart preferential site this
week is a completely different one
they're not even using the same version
of tail acts so they're pretty distinct
from each other when you look at them
side by side like that and that's on the
same machine that means that you can
drive fingerprint these are in a bunch
of assets in the in the Taylor's header
and I can go and look for which I did I
really just not rule looking to take
their stuff on the wire is useful for
system admins because as system
administrator doesn't necessarily have
access to the point where in a world
where people can bring their own devices
in and the enterprise doesn't
necessarily have access to look at the
price you might not have access to the
server so really you don't have an idea
as to whether someone is super efficient
elected for example or any of the others
without having access to be employed by
slipping on the network and alerting
them this way
detected using your existing
infrastructure even this guy whoever he
is seen to be quite impressed with it so
let's expand a little bit because it
works so far the ruling made only worked
on the surface of the problem is that if
you look at site for sweets chrome
version 45 and Firefox version 37 look
the same as each other and they both the
same as Thunderbird version 38 so you
start to get collisions impact of the
first hundred and fifty signatures are
collected I would have only had seventy
five unique ones about stuff like this
week's like I started so we need to look
a little bit more of what we can do we
decline hello packet
so this is a standard header from a
client doesn't represent the the sizes
of the book seize don't represent the
size of the fields but it is the
ordering so this blog here is fixed
location you can find it really easily
with no computation there at standard
offsets from the beginning of the paler
this section is mostly fixed ish because
it depends on the size of the show
SessionID but once you can't relate to
the session IV then it's an easy offset
the and extensions you actually have to
pass properly because extensions each
have a link to their own and you have to
find the length of an extension of up to
the next extension to find the length
that thought to the next and so on so
that's a slightly more CPU intensive but
it's still not that so what's useful in
here we don't use any of these links as
because we know the length we've got the
date already
those are just there to navigate with
packing when you're grabbing it do the
SessionID because the SessionID is
shockingly unique to the session and we
really don't care and Brandon is well
it's random so again I don't care really
useful extensions add a load of
extensibility on top of what's already
inside Taylor for example there's a
server header to put the hosts in the
clear conclusion that was secret when
you're browsing the web site and that's
to allow the hosting of multiple
websites on a single IP address each
with their own a cell so he can return
the serb before you get to the crypto
resent the rights and that way you can
do the equivalent of the jump TTP 12 1.1
the V hosting but we are also being able
to check the order of things is
incredibly important so we look those in
the fingerprints to extensional slowed
in a different order but different
browsers there is no r/c defining the
ordeal of them in similarly the
cryptographic algorithms listed in a
preferential order the compression
algorithms are listed in a preferential
order so by looking to the order not
just the capabilities we get another
level of crime
clarity on the fingerprint let's
actually talk about creating a
fingerprint well I need to get some
sample data so I sniffed a few of my own
clients and they think but I needed to
get a bit more days in there so I
realized there are websites out there
who are dedicated to doing regression
testing for web developers you might
peace or CSS and you know it works in
the last 30 versions of Firefox and 20
versions or chrome or whatever but you
don't know what's going on over there
are services that will go and buy a 30
40 50 browse the web site they will take
us a little jpg screenshot and email
them to you conceive you wrote some
horrible CSS the broke life to the great
thing about that is they have completely
honest user agent strings so I can put
them on my web server that sniffing
absolutely everything and correlate the
fingerprints are generated against
fingerprints against there use ratings
provided and I instantly feel like a
whole bunch of fingerprints like a news
story like this this is Dropbox there's
nothing particularly special about
dropouts in this case and it's the
shortest fingerprints I can get it on a
slide easily story in JSON it's fairly
human-readable there are a bunch of
liberia's deposit things like 590 please
so it's it's really useful for people to
use and transform into other forms and
the server names in not because we use
it for fingerprinting because that would
just get us back to a situation that's
why blacklisting which will come to in a
minute but the finger pointing toward I
wrote named Julie because when you
generated a ton of fingerprints and
you're trying to work out which goes
with which client this helps you back
together also I'm worried about the
application I don't know all the Taylor
said they will protocols like HTTP and
I'm a pessimist and DPS or whatever but
there are there are plenty of Google's
out there I don't know so I want to be
able to spot a lesson at the ports also
if anybody has ever worked in a large
corporate environment you'll notice
cannot on the one that uses the
universal filed by passport to get your
personal book so you can do what you
want on the internet instead of going
through company proxy
and this demonstrates my point that
people are not looking for a cessation
port 443 in a largely ignoring 443 cuz
it's just encrypted
hackers don't listen to Aiyana's
guidance on board members either so your
actual training data but not necessarily
dropping it straight on the poor you
think it is blocking it may not be
enough so my goals are to detect
taylor's traffic and fingerprint on any
port to do it completely state loosely
because tracking TCP sessions and and
that sort of thing can be quite
intensive computation asymmetric as we
talk about large networks these days so
I don't want to have to see both halves
of the conversation and wanted to be
fairly low cost in terms of CPU memory
and storage and I'll come to the storage
thing in a minute to be keeping all this
low we should get high detection rates
more accurate detection rates and not
need quite such the harbor to drive it
so the detective Taylor something we
can't meet the fingerprint tell us as a
whole before we move into acts so this
these RBP air filter anyone who uses TCP
double steal or something we'll know
these two checks on two bites and the
first one checks that it is a packet
that identifies itself as a TLS
handshake packet and the second check
checks that it's a client hello within
that like it's a pretty high rate of
detection on its own but we can get a
bit that we take this one by here and
it's the first of a two by value for the
TLS solution if the first point is that
23 that will get you all TLS because the
various versions at a less
11 going to use the second bite to
differentiate so this one gets you will
tell us a bit in blue is if you're a
masochist that gets us there will be
three and that's just horrible I would
rather recommend alert on his cell b3
being in your environment
panic about that and don't put that in
this and we do the same again the TLS
record version
by just checking for bites with no
horrible offsets the past some no CPU
computation legacy right down to pretty
much detecting tell us as a whole
on every port your new real CPU
bottleneck is gonna be being able to
drive the network on fast enough for the
over-all packet filtering to to apply
the filter you can also shrink you'll
throughput down by adding a fifth check
because there is a bite for these
SessionID like if the SessionID length
30 I either is no SessionID then that
means it's the first packet in a TCP
stream so you only get capture one
packet per stream as opposed to the
subsequent negotiations and that way you
can you contribute stories right down
just get one packet to examine forestry
is removed blue because we don't want a
cell b3 that's the filter you want to
apply and it's pretty low CPU cores to
talk about storage of attention
the reason I mention storage is that if
you want to get use of this this is one
of those things where you probably want
to harvest data all the time and then go
back and analyze sort of signals
intelligence style if you can because if
you have an event happen you might want
to look at what happened yesterday
phyllis was so I did some analysis to
see id take a mixed traffic and tactical
command for help around my home network
so it's mixed traffic is still less
traffic its iPads it's you know whatever
things and cannot determine it because
actually downing downloading binary from
http is one of the biggest ways to
trigger false positive so well I'm
tilted 99.6% of packets were useless so
implementing the first check it down to
just under three percent being useless
the third check as you can see 100 5%
and I had a hundred percent success rate
with no false positives when I
implemented all four of those checks
that's not to say that I'm planned but
in that eight gigs of data
I didn't have anything and in subsequent
tests too I haven't been false positives
additionally it saves on the storage
tank exact data when saved to pick out
with that filter went under 20 megs
which compared to eight gigs is not much
data if you implement that fistfight
checked when you look back it becomes
five point four MECs does look like full
floppy disks regular update to the
printing which I don't think he's
particularly bad going so moving on
there are a couple of floors that are
worth discussing before we get into a
year before they actually looking at it
and one of these that obviously people
are going to think what if I'm moving to
evade this is a sensible and obviously
is possible because the client controls
its own Klein Klein hello packet there
are a couple of gotchas however to
modify your fingerprint you have to
modify the Hello packet and modify the
Hello packet means that you are
announcing a different set of
capabilities to the world if you're
announcing new capabilities you have to
be prepared to the server on the other
end is going to call on those see you
need to actually have those capabilities
similarly if you're removing some to
make sure they're not in the fingerprint
that could cause you problems because
you may be lowering save a cipher suites
that you use to a week 11 additionally
if you're using a library as opposed to
coding your own DLs interactions in May
abstract a lot of this from you you can
choose cyber sweets most of the time
with libraries but I don't see many to
choose the order the closure extensions
in for example the other thing
fingerprint clearance so if to clients
look exactly the same from a fingerprint
perspective they cannot look they cannot
be differentiated when you're analyzing
them because you can't tell which it is
because it has the same fingerprint and
the definitive answer on whether this
happens in this is sort of ish maybe
kind of because what happens is I think
it multiple fingerprint collisions where
I can differentiate declines from each
other but then I noticed that although
very with the same fingerprint in
different acts under the hood they were
the same thing so if you look at Absa
particularly on cellular devices you
have multiple routes that we have the
same fingerprint but then you'll find
out what's really happening is they have
embedded Way bit in each one so it's
actually from a technology perspective
it is the same client and that's
important because they are the same
client in terms of what they're
vulnerable to what they're not
vulnerable to come to a second but if
the vulnerable to the same things them
from an attacker's perspective I don't
have a different lines from a defensive
perspective you may be a little more but
you can still differentiate them from IP
addresses and things like that little
bit more easily so there's good examples
'cause that's way more fun to me what
about this let's talk defender stuff any
woman's defense in a network has
probably seen lists like this it's been
forever exporting flows down its
firewall logs proxy logs in a prepared
addresses the talking to each other
you probably have an idea about the
connections and you may even be
monitoring some critics protocols but a
lot of the time you don't really know
these connections are one of them might
be suspicious
see my current ECB dumping on the packet
sniffer you can see the full 443 and you
can see that it's a garbled mess inside
so the only possible conclusion is that
it's probably your users web browsing
and command in the middle ear or
something like that trying to determine
the content but most people are not
doing that you could do with key
material derived from the client or the
server to secretly package but again we
don't have access to those you could
check against IP blacklist
this is Alex Pinto provided and if you
want more data and more same review of
this what she's talked also this is the
rate of change of data in black lists
each of these buses a day you can see
the blacklists do not remain static they
change every day if your blacklist is
not updated as often as the published
blacklist you're probably out of date
this also includes they to being removed
from blacklist so you might be
incorrectly flagging thing similarly you
don't know how long before things appear
on a blacklist so what they are useful
you can't guarantee that you're catching
everything this way the thing I like
about the Taylors fingerprinting is that
people don't tend to update how the
character is set up that regularly even
the big browsers with their regular
releases have the same crypto between
versions or other time and when I looked
at malware it never really changed its
critics acknowledges and black list
includes internal traffic of course
either they only look at things like but
net control and command control but
service was looking at least again you
probably do a few things looking who is
look at the intense records and you can
determine what a bunch of these are some
of them might scream bad the unknown
connection to an SSH d the IOC session
but what about this host 10:54 10 399
you can see it has what appears to be an
HTTPS sessions SharePoint and an HTTPS
sessions at Amazon Web Services which
says nothing because the entire internet
on Amazon Web Services retailers
fingerprinted and see that it's icy MITM
proxies connecting SharePoint maybe
there's someone attacking another client
on your network man in the middle of the
connection and grabbing the documents
all the credentials as they go past what
about the Amazon Web Services well if
you think a print as a torrent link to
the Tor network may be late to be
natural straight export traded that the
just pulling up SharePoint with some
context this makes things a slightly
different view on this anomaly detection
in the people have a really controlled
environment you can work with the other
way just detect things that you think
might be troublesome
if you have a corporate image and
everyone uses one version of one browser
all the time or just a couple of
browsers you can have fingerprints for
your known corporate tool that everyone
uses anything else
presumably back you don't even need to
think about what it is
use language like you should be going to
look at and have a look
defenders point of view it's not just
about all the hacking you don't need to
be looking at hacking tools and picking
them out there are a couple of other
things on your network you probably
don't want to see like that
Java for example has a fingerprint when
it goes to update itself from the web
server on the Internet
also any after road has compiled in job
will have the job fingerprint secret
spot someone using Java if you have an
environment where you about that because
you might have tools that are against
corporate policy despite being fined in
their own right
you may not want them in your
environment depending on what it is you
may have tools that you just don't want
to talk to the Internet directly there
is a really nice security tools that are
great in the hands of your scrutiny but
when they come from the finance
department and appointing a box you're
probably less pleased about them you
probably also have things do you expect
humans to interact with so when you
start seeing scripts interacting with
them then that's probably a sign you got
some kind of issue you need to address
and all these signatures are in the
database and I'm gonna give you the end
so attacked her attackers a lonely man
in the middle when it comes to Taylor's
because possibly doing something with
Taylor's doesn't have a whole bunch of
ways to get in the middle and it depends
on who the person is so it depends where
they are how well they are technical
capabilities that kind of thing you'll
notice peas in a very different place to
man in the middle you as opposed to
someone who's on your network during UPS
moving for example then you can do the
whole oh my god nation states BGP
hijacking and all that stuff there are
two ways but either way
beginning in the middle and actively
interested in traffic modifying traffic
blocking traffic
this list is not exhaustive but it does
give you a flavour of the different ways
so what i'll be attacks on Taylor's
lawyer claimed the three groups you
can't a client that's known to have
weaknesses so the client doesn't check
certificates as certificate training
issues it supports weak ciphers crack
whatever their attacks against Hitler
slobodan frameworks they have coding
issues they have before overflows
whatever they they they do not check
things properly things like are pleased
with his bounds checking issues I know
that's a service but these example and
then the other one is CIA issues you
climb spine everything works fine in the
technology level but it trusts the CIA
thats wrobel been hacked and so robust
it would still be effective against
climb the enemy the attacker is of
course the perfectly functioning client
flags a big error saying someone's
attacking me and raises the alarm this
is what we're trying to avoid especially
in many of those man in the middle of
situations where a single person has
been targeted this wholesale man in the
middle against entire network if your
pen testing a distal a new man in the
middle of the oldest of land you gonna
get a mix of clients you don't want that
coming up and setting the alarm I miss
you defended you do what so let's look
at standard Windows host and see what we
can do sorry no that's not a standard
Windows a look at a standard Windows
host and see what we can do so what does
he do well we can see this user has a
few browsers I don't know one URL to the
next which browser is going to be
connecting if I have a chrome
vulnerability and I drop it on Firefox
I'm gonna get no that's not very
stealthy so I mean to drop it on the
browser that I want they will have a
bunch of the tools on this book these
tools to create the US Naval sessions
and that's you know they could be things
that I want to avoid the things I want
to attack and this is just from a random
screenshot found on Google Images
there's a bunch more on most people's
boxes
so very well this in mind is the example
Google reported that there was a CIA
there had gone rogue I want guests on a
better word issues too because they
cannot be trusted
they shoot the morning and so they
pulled it from Chrome as you would do to
get the advantage over other people so
in this situation I i'm knowledgeable of
this attack and I want to attack people
when I don't want to attack chrome
because Google has just announced to me
that they're going to set up alerts when
I do so have the client on man in the
middle ring through whatever DNS
spoofing off spoofing or something
the client doesn't TCP handshake with me
great I don't have to do anything
without just maintain the handshake and
they said decline hello back it to me I
run my finger printing its Safari Safari
Zone mine own bad database so I just
would like a port forward i doing TCP
handshake of my own for the client hello
packet onto the evil server and then
just passed package backwards and ports
and that can be what everyone can be an
existing to like MITM proxy Metasploit
or whatever else I'm using to attack it
and it can be on local who's the next
connection comes in and has grown so I
bought it to wherever it was connecting
to originally because I have the
destination IP address cuz that's in the
IP header from any connected to me this
way I can still use the Chrome user
never hits my exploit and never played
it up I never see this instead I think
this is a little before I wrote all it
does is it listens for connections and
boards to a different location dependent
on fingerprint it's or chrome and send
it to the real Google it's all so Safari
and it sent it to the real Google they
look at the next defender example you
can do fingerprint to find routing
that's pretty much the same as well as
described just now but from a defensive
point of view
same again I place something in front of
my servers much like a reverse proxy
gives the handshake
and then I see my server is expecting
humans to come look at it it's a
connection from Goa lang so I can gather
whatever internet once about what this
person is doing and my real server
doesn't get touched by them when I get a
crime connection however that get sent
to my real Server Pages get served and
everything works soviet next attack a
level and the forensics the scenario is
overly looked at my targets are prepared
on my exploits I'm ready I know who
might who I'm attacking in the network
and I may even a drop the first-stage
malware and phishing link but
essentially would have done these are
set myself up so that the bypass the
firewall and waiting for the day to
connect out from the network to meet and
I'm listening
meanwhile back in inside the
organization
these new key security defender guy has
spotted the euro and then using the
standard tactic of using W get with the
modified user agent to appear to be I E
72 come grab the sample more aware of my
books which is works all over the time
because generally can't tell but if you
hosting malware on an HTTPS books tell
us enabled you can Fordow get signature
to a seemingly innocuous server and you
can send I seventy or attack server and
therefore the defense personal our
analysts doesn't have this sample and
doesn't know you drop that stuff and
then on the defense side you can do
fingerprint canaries we have margins
platforms these days people in Netflix
and applications like FaceTime and
blackberry messenger manage their entire
infrastructure so that they are in the
service they own all the API endpoints
and they write the application it may
not be on their infrastructure but is
there around they don't have third party
apps so if you run a network like this
you could have been as you know when
it's going to change and you know is you
don't necessarily have to do anything
about it when you see a different thing
to bring come in it could be someone man
in the middle of it could be someone
attacking you deliberately manning the
man in the middle of cells using
something like the sweet for example
or it could be a customer being man in
the middle either way you could detect
and you can react to it and deal with it
and of course no talk about man in the
middle in attacking would be complete
without the oh my god nation state
attackers are coming up and some of that
might be useful to them in a phenom
animal in things as usual if they see me
your Skype user use a particular IRC
client or something they make you do
something useful to go in for further
information
some apps are only available when OS so
that signature tell them what OSU's or
some other attack if they see that you
are using a particular gambling out they
might have a gambling problem that they
could blackmail you for and in fact
today in the press there was common
police came out where the UK GCHQ
analyzing people's porn habits amongst
other things
by looking at this you get a lot more
information if you're doing wholesale
interception like that you could
essentially done a lot of information
about people and an honorable mention
goes to honey honey pots crucial doing
but I don't use the web threat
intelligence if you put your passing
stool on https instead of HTTP you don't
just know what one bility someone is
exploiting you know what they're
exploiting it with you if you were
looking at groups and attribution being
able to say that this group not only is
this exploit but they did it from some
movie script releases a lot more than
they just you see these whatever and
even unknown fingerprints are good
because the same unknown fingerprint
would mean reused codebase most likely
and if you look at any of the
attribution stuff that's going on with
malware reason code is a pretty common
thing he could do a set amount of
attribution just from the fingerprint
without actually looking at what they
did on the books so let's move to tools
calls it the funds that doesn't fit in a
lab and is great for me to talk about it
but it doesn't really help you guys do
anything so
I'm releasing couple of tools people to
use this one is fingerprinted us it's a
packet sniffer / pcap file reader if you
don't trust my tools running on that
work you can capture them your own way
for you to pick up for it at this it
does that cross party lines the Texans
though it will match signatures like you
can see on the screen
got a bunch of things saying there's a
torrent link there's much there's
thunder bird whatever talking to these
house they all look at server name and
play out the Taylor said Apple you and
tell you what it was connecting to not
just from DNS but from the actual
hostname which gives you a lot more idea
about what it it's so that's hopefully
useful the other one is a fingerprint
apt which is just a pipe on script but
it takes that Jason file and it would
sit in a number of different ways this
is a C struct so if you write C code and
is probably changeable to other
languages that I don't know you can use
it to put fingerprints in yourself so
apps can sell fingerprint incoming
connections this was a fingerprint
showdown who counties can buy books all
those packets nothing but it worked out
quite nicely because now I know all the
notes are when they keep reconnecting
the next one is an IDS output its Sarah
Carter and snore output this is probably
most useful to people because if you
have existing ideas infrastructure you
can use this to push signatures hour and
you don't even need to run any code of
mine you can have your ideas alert you
when you see specific things you don't
like the look of its a bit funny looking
because most ideas don't have support
for the various fields inside the SSL
stream so I had to drive them myself so
you've got all these distance and bike
jump rings to manage audio cassettes and
get there this is actually pretty short
signature
some of them are a little bit long and
if anyone tries it has issues before
using slaw take a look at your main
config alike supreme and Alexis lol so
it doesn't look like it did by the time
against the rules which is so little
pool
and the final output from this 110
second-to-last is there anyone from
single intelligence here that submitting
it know if you were to admit to being in
signals in its again I did excuse core
output so that you can go and attack
everyone on the network to it's actually
the least reliable of the signatures I
don't know what to do with it was too
late standardization because when you do
you think you print it stores some of
your personal data in there like the
service connecting to show you what the
street that out before you go and
publish it to someone else rather than
it being in your sample your cooking it
does indeed you and that's kind of the
way back machine bought archive my
machine it matched the same as Jabba
through I kind of had a raging flip out
like a moment because I thought I was
getting bad fingerprint collisions were
coming my way and I got down like a bad
run a whole but it turns out thanks to
the mothers have given in Java and I
completely corrected fingerprints after
all so this brings it when I saw the
little point that you can use this to
determine the lineage about compiled
outs less scripted star and certain
things like going in Java sort of nine
between area have very specific
signatures I was just for PHP Python
movie it's very useful for being able to
determine when someone's attacking you
know just what they're doing but what
they're using to do it finally I'm
releasing the fingerprint database
itself it's far from comprehensive but
it does have a lot of things probably
got about a hundred and fifty signatures
in the main file which includes browsers
email clients web of connections IRC
clients a gambling at Java duty less and
bunch of other stuff
there is a little while with Matt 250
ish signatures long delay separated out
if you've ever used the SSL labs
difficult checker it throws some
ridiculous number of tests and generates
two hundred and fifty unique signatures
are you may want to exclude that as well
as separated it but if you're interested
in people scanning you that might be of
use so we get to the demo but inevitably
fails because it's a demo so I was going
to attack them I was going to show you
the googles and then I thought well this
is the Fixit track its defensive more
than offensive so you don't know that
the sides watching to Google's not error
is not really a very exciting done so
well as you do this for the duration of
this talk I had a listener running on
this machine 443 and have been running
my fingerprints on it in the hope that
some malicious person is scanning the
network and I can fingerprint scanning
me and that can be my really exciting
dominant so let me just break out of
this recession and find so so
so will you be my laptop in the
background going connecting out and
doing a bunch of things as well as
people fingerprinting me that that would
show really things in there because it's
got to take some for things like this
point just to show you how it works out
creates and data so far as to curl the
HTTPS interface of Google then here it
matched girl pretty quickly and did most
of it aligns let me just put this back
no not now I am okay so that's what
failed them
predicted that with a 10 screen so
what's next
I'd like to hear back from the community
on stuff I would love if people wanted
to contribute signatures check things
out of gas hob fix my awful code to make
it better for get into a cool thing
whatever help write new tools I would
love to see this is like an Apache or
nginx module or something like that to
treat clients typically negatively
instead of having to use slippers so if
you want to be involved this is where is
the Taurus SHO drool on
repository hope I foresee this Twitter
accounts if anyone wants to interact
with me the slides Rome slideshow and
the blog post on the bottom is like a
mini white paper outlines the technical
details of this without me willingly
giving silly examples and we think some
random observations wrapping up
OpenSSL Swiss assumed to be to have some
reason which I can see horrible the most
popular extensions being used or
elliptic curves and signature algorithms
for the elliptic curves which is why the
extensions that I do with differently
which are neglected to mention
I do a load of policy on extensions to
you'll see that the technical writer
sorry and the other thing is everyone
when Snowden released a list of what he
did said about never trusting missed
again mister P 256 and this to be 571
curbs account for 98% of the
preferential kurds senior clients i've
seen
so all these don't trust this stuff
doesn't seem to have filtered down to
the client is still seems to be fully
trusted and that is what I had if anyone
wants to ask any questions that would be
great on hero comes to feel free to stop
me otherwise likes