hello
the title my cock be today is Cyber
Security office I'm scheduled for my
caucus date is I'm going to introduce
myself then I'm going to talk about
seven security off that's an idea then
I'll be short demonstration and finally
concluded some closing thoughts
hello my name is Ruben Abhishek call you
my friend rock star by personal twitter
handles at char that you can used about
the stock
nine years old and i cant high school
science by John into the world of cyber
security began at I gave you talk at
last year when I was eight years old I
talked into sex and then my travels have
taken me to be square scared that I want
to he said calm then I went to where
we're standing ovation to ground zero
for sex D rice book on new kits that
features heavy security then I went to
bsides Austin
scared eng sub security you generation
then I was unveiled from server box as a
real next-generation seven scary in our
say I can really say however in a box
packing box conference and I just wanna
say I really appreciate it thanks to
Dave Canadian team for giving me my very
first opportunity to speak at a
conference show thanks thanks very calm
I want to see all of Derby Conn could
you make us feel loved inception and her
family so here's some other fun facts
about me when I was changing America's
most beautiful baby
wow sounds old else america america has
shown no conflict in 2014 15 I was deep
disco contest one how did you start on
contest the company kid who who
recognizes that recognizes the candy
making and truly I must go before I
sleep these are video biography species
have any time I was to you
USA Gymnastics state champion for the
rings out my main topic
office what I get out of it
RBC building blocks that kids use a
separate nation to make words ok
kathleen was gonna say you're welcome
320 okay and tony has talked
that's our basic building blocks that
could use at their foundation and are
speaking art stands for address
resolution protocol ARP happy IP address
to the MAC address so that he can accept
and communication that the correct
device on the network
spoofing is one he has cables
information to change the IP address to
point he is back at it so that he can
intercept other question our
communications from different devices on
the network a simple way to understand
this is by using simple mailboxes and
all the mailboxes in my neighborhood
located in common area inside my mailbox
mailbox is our families with our house
is 1337 backgrounds bobby is 1057 so I
get home I will need to find a way to be
home at her I wanted to find a way to
change parties home address 2.2 my name
change his name to point to my address
which is basically what are keeping
those about the overflow attack which
the hacker inputs more than what the
memory buffer can hold if the code is
not check how long the input is popping
it to the memory but there are trying a
case of instruction pointer will get
over it and the hacker can put it this
way to understand this is by example of
a birthday party invite you to my
friends to a birthday party gave them my
house actors at that guy and put the
sign over my house actress that the
party has moved to his house so on my
credit going to his house to get rock
free clinics explain cross-site request
forgery is the usual log into his bank
account he gets a second shift he gets
an email with a link on it clicks on the
link and you realize that money from his
bank account gets talked so how did this
happen to have emotions he crafted
length transfer money from his bank out
by using the previously established
damage is saying you're invited to a
birthday party candy shop you possess
invitation card to get into the shop
securing entry pass and he wants candy
too but he does not have an entry or
invitation so he tricks the other kid
with E and she got to go in and get
candy for him it's time to party now
this entry pathways are in use before I
dunno service which the hacker system
software system data unavailable someone
who needs it
hacker c.k by closing a pore over the
website too many times or even do a
document a location that extra
site
your understanding how serious his
family and then had the service
picture for exploit frameworks and
exploit exploit a simple way to
understand this is how I go to my shower
and Ocampo class I can boast 09 shucks
and sword and a comfy back
exploit remarks is kinda like this it's
basically a 20 bag basically at all that
in it to win it to test the system is
exploitable are not just as any of these
tools can be used for purposes but just
as any of these weapons just as any of
the weapons can be used for good or bad
purposes he said were close to be a good
purposes i cant testing purposes
hacking here are some of the well-known
actually about exploitation former army
chief Metasploit Framework
MSF so Sean Garrett ok or is he talking
about
the OIC ok explain Armitage and tell her
body
charity testing the test the system is
exploitable not injecting random input a
real-world example this is our drug
testing if you're looking to something
you don't know what the doctor will
inject different types of our genes we
enter your personal and she tried to
tell you she is fine she attacks TV
attack inside computer graphics card
that is responsible for processing and
displaying images text and videos and
GPU the GPS dedicated memory as well I
said ship the GPU graphics processing
unit GPU is put to keep you attack GPO
tax on families for power cracking
attacks too young to keep you to do it
at the meeting process then he CPU is
much faster a pirate tool is better than
hash cat so chances by the all that's
wrong but it could take five he's super
fast super managed to keep you feel
which employers and employees into an
algorithm which converting output
numbers and letters to have to accept
that you can never get rich off value
back a good example of this is
your strawberries are like the input the
album and you can never get the original
robberies back this will be his friend
section and sections track which Dr
backend database except when the user
supplies without any allegation
introduced its handle right in our
concentration 39 concentration over what
it can handle that have you ever
wondered what the meaning is highly
concentrated protein so when a snake
bite you inject it into your body and
your body candy body as commander
shutdown which can include some serious
damage so jane is for Java applet Java
applet attack attack which he hacker v2
malicious Java applet in the sixties and
buy some social engineers have a full
tank of missions and can completely
exploit the system so simple and uses of
a real kid get in the video game arcade
get that kind of like the shop up you
will get the idea is to keep and which
to keystrokes and and dogged
need a simple changes its talk a lot
when their school lockers
kidding want to find out about what
somebody was talking about but hindsight
a locker a logic bomb a piece of code
that runs want to spend time are
conditions met simple went on Shannon
example of a cook over a cuckoo bird
eggs and other birds nest because it is
truly heroic stopped so I think about
hatch's it is all of the other edge off
the net and takes over the next time and
go home and they don't impersonates
gateway around her and tells him that
he's the client and at the same time at
his to get where outer called
communication goes to the house in this
picture you see that they're trying to
get the ball game and the monkey is like
the hacker
mediation appt international thing but
not tonight at all I'll say is just got
half in the system
recorded all the interactions and
transactions between all the
interactions transactions CNN com city
dogs have you actually moving
Incredibles what you guys for watching
kids
he's called to the principal's office of
putting tacked onto your chair at Fresh
dash tries to repeat itself but the
highlight video camera and catches dash
to his machine now application cannot
deny 2004 obfuscation applications
defensive technique in which her she
sleep schedule according to data so that
will be hard for each year and find out
what coordinated else so what happens a
venir have found out that my family and
data they can invade into our objection
is making me and being it's not easy to
begin should be as EDS then when it
served as trips with eggs it'll be
easier for someone to pick out but that
they can chopped up into pieces
stated then it'll be hard for somebody
to pick out and almost like undetected
he is fishing fishing is to lure and
bait feeling personal information about
themselves is a part of so far have you
all to you
in the movie there's an angler fish to
be more efficient capture that is for
Corey's
otherwise known as target not talking
about a happy to find numerous countries
chase card companies country's children
know these countries but even her
children educated et cetera brain
coercion
dangers how many of yall know what what
what in the movie expert are sure who
shot his any target just as a hacker
will go after his or her targets are
from you are ok so what is a real
computer program a program that allows
hope control system that is installed on
my meeting asking operating system
forgot about purposes mostly used for
bad purposes like spying on me for good
purposes like running tech support and
picture I give the example of the
enormous in da shower used operating
system with other various programs like
these make a fish and soft wire is
basically software that by some people
information i buy where he's at or
otherwise known as I am with protection
network traffic
lets you browse by keeping our
application for for kids that it allowed
without provocation Shelby Harper
somebody truck that he that man haven't
stopped checking again so location back
in the senate hardly shoe store you talk
to you about Aug 10 attack I cannot
guarantee that you'll get it get it
AUD people attack but do keep packets
into the network so that the network is
congested example of this is where I in
a traffic jam packed to continue to keep
our like these from iris a barrage of
our our that Hutchison show to homes and
it's hard for example of this is from a
living parasite has to cut health care
system holds much wow I want our that
tragedy and network network systems and
that work is harmful IT skills
information it can and shop owners and
it can affect 3 information security
integrity and availability so I don't
have very much
samples for that extra cross-site
scripting XSS shipping is when you
inject code into a input field as a
script example of this is steal a nice
turn pro
body interest we shall be it causes some
serious harm to you can lead to
infection disease or death can you
assure so what is it quotes be harmful
body with some company maker
out of it comes a hot girl the
application is the one bodies script or
anger is like why is for you people are
the weakest link
they have people than it is to have
system because they implicitly trust
others without any foundation and she
seemed like nobody really thank you
bode bode is otherwise known as OJ or
negative day and in fact are usually
unaware of what the hackers hackers had
the advantage usually is launched today
that the soccer comes out my dad and mom
taught me 20 here you know has no value
but when it rains do something but when
I was raised to the power of something
called a 10 inch care software
oh so now my gosh Asian sure we'll ever
watch my video that I get a Java applet
talk where you have to click on the line
and well when do you have to click on a
link for them they don't get these are
the things they don't get back on track
to let them with cash and without
permission
so it'd be cool if we get redirected
user to a pic website that we control
and they just got that even doing
anything or even knowing that they get
so am I gonna be doing so i right
when his Fox
I have my
I'm going to need to create a website
and I want you so far
going to do a website attack and I want
to do just actually the website and if
I'm going to go site Connor address so
obviously credentials so that is they
don't want to I dot com
including the website we wanted to do so
I am trying to find a candy but yes and
control panel and now I'm going to
inject the beef hooked into a website
Cole said that shareholder so I'm going
to go here just to see you so we haven't
left open that
no outta here before
now capped start your caps can be in a
spoof it so that the usual think that
the IP addresses so I need to change so
hard to change my spouse right now and
continue no see so you have to put the
mask your IP address so we're going and
then I put that now I'm gonna do the
gusto network interface 0
which one you want to add a gateway to
the condoms and I managed to punish and
I'm going to an art poisoning actions
and I'm going to start so I'm going to
go to 12 so it's actually giving you my
IP address so how do I go to the website
and he's you want to go to England
ok so now I should look into for I knew
I wanna go to persistence and at home
why they call me call me with the steps
to ensure that the beef pork or manually
changing it so now that doesn't work
forever until they close the browser
then I'm going to go to
so actually it made a fake website and
look like Google so anybody want to
shoot anyone want to hospital after all
research purposes
greatly appreciate it I can't even have
a dream I can't even have a group of 30
years old so since nobody took the risk
to go back and I'm going to you to
harvest and like I said so do I mean you
all that and at the same time so you can
I set her up she didn't block
now for sure you want to go ahead and
open it up and get our house in
Wonderland and yes it is after all those
who are all of those he just laughed
probably go change as my gallery today
and I don't know
he fuck get the official tak I used
either kept going absolutely intact and
you have to show you that most people
use department and anyone anything or
even realizing that they got hacked now
in conclusion I started a website called
an adult started a right to me ask me
how he could have they could be like me
and I wrote it can show videos about the
dangers of factors of job security
it's a non-profit organization so please
if you can get involved here so this is
over the years over the past haha I talk
to you two things are my second degree
from cuba out and making video lessons
from you to see Sharon spread the word
so please spread the word and get out
there
so in closing I don't think my God Jesus
Christ gives him without him I'll be
nowhere here I wanna thank my family for
all the support they have given me and
helping my dad get a lot my mom helped
me and even my little brother had so
many teachers ninety several kids R kids
and they help them is probably the first
time you heard that happened she can
staff so by contacting patients
dot com handles a crap talk show
thank you and I hope you enjoy and talk