I think we're getting started here a few
minutes early so I got a lot to go over
in a short amount of time so so today to
talk about honey pots reactor defense
and so jump right into it
first little bit about me boss the head
of security operations along also a
senior security researcher with the
rides so a lot of fun stuff so that fun
stuff
pots so take a look at traditional
defensive concepts for these are the
things that most people are currently
doing within their organizations right
now to actively protect that right
first and foremost maintain a tough
perimeter and you want to have a hard
outside make it hard for attackers to
get it right and then implement layered
security controls you want it to be
tricky for them to get in get further
give it about stocking of your ideas
wow you know elected stuff in place
right and you want to block all the
stuff you know about the known virus
signatures on the known IDs signatures
all the stuff the actually attacked the
you actually know you're probably get
hit with rape and then we ought to
reinforce Paul C so that our users
you know we actually protect their user
to keep them from accessing things they
shouldn't stuff like that right and then
we hope that all of this stuff actually
works right we pretend it does but
really doesn't matter so they get most
people are here pen tester you can you
know this is there's always a way in
you know it's not likely given working
for a vendor or not gonna come and tell
you like a good buy any security product
and it's going to magically protect your
right there's always going to be this is
Gary here's klingon stuff away into an
organization you have to have you know
not just the right tools that people
trained and ready to respond to the
stuff people willing and able to
actually help defender downward and it's
not just the apt is right it's not just
the attackers from the outside the worry
about because you're inside employees
can be bought like people can always be
paid enough to sell your trade secrets
you know people can get fish then all of
a sudden there's someone on your their
system their Rd insider environment like
most environments we go into and help
people and we find out you know there's
already someone inside their network
they've already been breached in some
way that's why this will talk was
created was looking more inward looking
at like what's going on inside your
network and trying to find some way is
to dynamically catch some of these
attackers rate that's why I like active
defense oh yeah so so what is active
defense great so it's exactly what it is
right there so what they mean by active
defense is simply no tipping the odds in
your favor making it harder for
attackers to penetrate your networks to
do this by creating false systems
creating false services stuff like that
this can adjust actively dissuade them
from the real targets right and then
trapped them get them caught in your
little fishnets essentially in learn
from them figure out what they're doing
what they're after where they're coming
from where they're going on at all that
good stuff and then that's how we gather
data on and actually learn more about
who these people are and what they're
after and then using that information we
can better defend them and last phase is
actually attacking back and I don't like
popping shows on attackers and stuff
like that you know you can cross the
line there but within reason their life
things you can do
back to the attackers essentially
essentially all this comes down to
reducing your meantime to detect attacks
and then meantime response you want to
minimize that as much as possible and so
here I am Sam Quigley is just the glass
in security engineering is not to make
compromise impossible
the goal is to make it expensive
difficult and noisy that's essentially
what we're doing here so why internal
honey products why why do we want to use
internal honey pots for this one nice
thing with honey pots as there's tons of
them out there and they're really easy
to configure and deploy and maintain
essentially these are just fly traps in
your organization they sit there and
wait for weird stuff to hit and the cool
thing about internal honey pots like
external research focused on me pots as
internal ones the most you're looking
for is for someone to raise a flag
essentially you want to trigger an alarm
when they do something so you can
respond and this maybe you know
something that if they did this to a
normal system you probably would even
notice it but since they're interacting
with your honey pots are using only
token or something like that is
something very on and it gives you kind
of a something to follow up on a nice
thing about this is your to learn a ton
about your attackers once you start
deploying internal honey pots and
actively watching what's going on in
these systems the key though with honey
pots kind of something to focus on after
you already have the basics and place
like after you know standard baseline
security control stuff like that that's
when you can start looking to implement
honey pots so what are some use cases
for honey pots primary research this is
how a lot of the Threadless are
generated so how a lot of the companies
out there are generating data to help
better generate rules and stuff like
that for their products and things like
that but defense is primarily were gonna
focus today that's that's using honey
pots in a way that not a lot of
companies are doing right now so defense
so tell about that there's actually
quite a few virtual machines out there
you can deploy for free within your
environment to mess with tony Potts and
start figuring this stuff out the first
ones honey drive three buddhist pretty
cool project I would recommend this for
like an actual enterprise defensive
deployment though because this isn't the
system's not very well guarded at all
it's more open and like a test bed for
playing with various honey pots so you
can go in there and figure out like what
honey pots you want to use on other
systems in a real way on this one you
know someone start poking out it's a
dead giveaway right away that it's a
honeypot says hi everywhere like the web
interfaces and stuff like that have to
be careful but it is something good to
learn from now I do like using an actual
defensive scenarios is ADHD the active
defense harbinger distribution and this
is my black girls information security
insecure ideas all those companies are
here and like a lot of the people that
actually helped create this are actually
at the conference right now so if you
find them you should definitely ask him
about ADHD because it's a very powerful
tool and it's actually you know honey
pots but also has acted defense Tulsi
can attack back at the attackers well so
very cool project highly recommend you
check it out but first things first
before you start deploying any of the
stuff we start tracking attackers and
watching what they're doing and you know
launching client-side code on their
systems and stuff like that you want to
deploy warning banners for all the
systems in your environment this gives
Ely way so that when people who are
logging into these systems you know
legitimate or illegitimate leader having
to go through warning banner that
essentially says hey you agree to these
terms because whether you like it or not
attackers actually have rights even
though they're inside your company so if
you like poppers show on now but you
didn't like having to go through an
approval this is like you can do
something like that you can actually get
in a little bit of trouble for that so
it's just something to keep in mind so
what are some types of high Potts you
know this is kind of my breakdown of
honey pots there's a lot of different
varied viewpoints on honey pots out
there says my and my interpretations so
no interaction these are essentially
honey ports just basic services the city
up there and either log or block based
on interactions with with those ports
and then lo interaction is it a very
basic basic flat web page or something
like that you know not a whole lot going
on there
medium interaction are kind of the most
popular honey pot season was actually
simulate real services you know I guess
the Sager sepia tone out something like
that and then hire action these are more
like actual real systems or systems that
are set up to imitate real system so
essentially trying to imitate every
aspect of the operating system and then
my favorite ones are honey tokens and
honey drives and strings and stuff like
that these are the ones that you can
actually get a ton of traction for our
and also you in a little bit we're so no
interaction honey pots first so these
are essentially just funny ports these
are very easy to build and deploy its
been like this
Linux example here this is actually from
the ADHD CD is also in the hands of
countermeasures are about to defense
book so I highly recommend that book as
well
parade here you know just a couple lines
of bad effectively created honey port
and what this does
all right here in assimilating FTP and
that whenever someone next to this it
just blocks them from the host to
seizing local iptables
very simple you can also do the same
thing on Windows I just using that
candidacy which I just a few lines of
code as well so really easy to build out
and then you can simply push these out
to other systems with a new environment
but then when you really want to get
into some more you know little bit more
in-depth reports there's actually Python
in PowerShell tools as well to do this
so our show there's still called Windows
PowerShell honey ports this is actually
on ADHD as well
scripts script by by Jon Voight and
carlos perez essentially what this does
is it's just the same as the neck at
estate auction was PowerShell so you
know a lot easier to deploy you can
actually deploy this remotely on systems
be like W my stuff like that really
easily
so same sort of calm separate here we're
just simulating 421 and then we're going
to connect to rate we're going to
connect using netcat over to this host
answer first connection succeeded as
expected right and then right after that
were blocked so simple as that right
mostly long as all the activity that
happens seek an injustice and do
whatever log management system using
sorry here you'll generate you start to
generate a list of these hoes and you
can choose to not like him too and just
start generating a list and you can use
this list later on to correlate back in
time to see like what else these people
have been up to acquire they poking
around at the systems stuff like that
and Linux there's an awesome tool called
artillery by someone you might know Mr
Dave Kennedy so they can run on Linux
actually has a Windows binaries well
with the really nice thing with with
artillery it does kind of the same sort
of thing it just you know logs and
blocks based on people connecting to a
report you decide to imitate
but also shoots back a bunch of junk
here which is kind of funny because
sometimes I see people trying like
actually figure out what this is so you
can waste their time we'll have a really
nice thing with artillery is there's
lots of really great way is to pull logs
from this so by default it just on the
logs into the Linux syslog so you're
probably already pulling these logs you
can just add additional searches for
artillery and then he can you know
essentially is set up alarms and stuff
like that off of that activity so in
addition to local syslog you can also
just create its own flat files you can
have Justin artillery flat file logged
essentially doubled his lungs into or
you can push to a remote syslog server a
lot of ways to pull this data and push
everything off to another host rape and
same sort of thing
IP's are added to ban list and block
locally now a bonus feature with an
artillery is actually does a full system
security check once you once you run
this social life running your web
server's root or something like that
I'll tell you it'll give you a bunch of
key indicators like haters you don't
have your system configured
so that's a nice features were all but
one of my favorite parts that comes with
free built-in file integrity monitoring
here we're just simulating basically
creating a web show was uploaded our
little shell . php files is what all
attackers do you know that we have the
final there and we can tell within the
artillery logs that this new file is
generated and the final census alert
this file is added so you know just a
nice additional feature on top of the
honey port activity itself saying here
run public facing honey pots yeah this
is probably not be anything new to you
guys right here I just like showing
people how to really run honey pots just
like how often your systems are hit when
they're just directly open on the
internet this is like some random ec2
instance here and has just blown up this
is just less than a day of running just
a honey port on this post so it's like
people to see that so they get the point
across of like don't put RTP open the
internet or like don't put SSH over the
internet without SSH keys and stuff like
that you're getting hit all the time so
it's kind of like reinforcing that point
move on to new interaction on any pots
so actually getting in like sum the web
applications and stuff like that is a
pretty hot
this one is very old so so fair warning
if you're going to deploy this you do
want to customize a bit like if you just
spend this up and throw it out there
people are gonna look at the readme page
and it's gonna say like oh this is one
from like this is a wordpress site from
the nineties so it would be a little
careful there but it's a just a little
small python script you can deploy very
easily and it logs to flat files so very
easy to ingest into whatever whatever
you're logging solution as well
PHP my admin know they're good service
to fake just because like how often do
you check your logs and see PHP my admin
sweeps against your environment so if
you're running like a fake PHP my admin
interface the you let them gain access
to it doesn't actually have a back-end
database you can actually gather a lot
of data from them just by you know like
full packet capture on this hostess
well so you gonna see everything that
they're they're hitting your house with
sometimes you can actually get the full
exploits as well as carve out of the
pcap this is a great way to do that and
this you know same sort of thing
blogs to a flat file and it's very easy
to deploy on existing applications by
admin something that is very popular lot
of people use it cuz they don't really
know how to admin their back-end
databases that well so it's a very
popular air and popularly misconfigured
there now you can do this with any fake
application you can basically gotten
clone whatever you want and weaponize it
and turn it into a fake application
sorry here we're doing is we're
simulating a fake VPN service day when I
take a guess why we're simulating bpm
well first and foremost you want to
learn what user names attacker has to
say like if they have really user names
passwords that but the real reason they
decided to simulate a VPN so we could
run client-side code on them this is
here so we can run Java on their on
their points like once they're accessing
this thing you can do like reverse
fishing to trick them into logging into
this thing or whatever like see if
they're on a certain host once you get
them to run client-side code you can do
stuff like this so honey badger badger I
think Tim Tim tones he's the developer
of that i think is actually here
actually does it uses your wireless card
to scan for all the other wireless
networks around you and then it uses the
Google Location API to essentially
pinpoint your location it's very
accurate actually is so so here's an
example of how this works because
attackers were never gonna attack
directly from their own systems justice
a bad idea rate so here we're going
through Switzerland some proxy in
Switzerland but then we open this
document that we bond and we do use
honey badger to gather some additional
data on and actually shows were in
Westminster so pretty cool it's funny
how accurate the thing is I was playing
with them how
house and actually pinpoint my location
exactly in my office where I was sitting
so many crazy media interaction
up the chain here so there's tons of
these this is by far the most popular
type of honey pot so I'm just gonna
focus on line because it's my favorite
one and one that I've gotten a lot of
really good traction from netscape oh
and so is very simple just simulates a
sage so basically fake a Linux host or
network just little Python scripts that
you can heavily customized to acquire
all of the other Linux hosts with Inter
Milan which exactly like whatever you
want it to look like and you can further
customize the command output and all
sorts of other stuff so little tool to
push out to multiple devices within your
within your environment on the really
cool part about this keeps Standard Flat
File logs but also stars the full ttyl
session now it's nice about that is you
can replay when the attacker did and
what they saw and everything like that
in real time so you can see like all the
commands they ran you can see the output
that they receive Cece like the whole
picture it also helps differentiate
between like a bot and real person as
you can tell by the speed they're doing
things they have typos stuff like that
the problem with this is a very popular
honey pot so this is one that's been out
for years now and a lot of people have
used this researchers of studies up all
over the internet so attackers now know
about this and there's a lot of easy
ways to quickly check that their they've
logged into a honey pot and terminate
their session so you just have to be
careful that like this isn't what I
would deploy facing the internet this is
more when I would stand up inside and
just see if someone actually was into it
another risk with exposing these
externally is that if someone actually
connects this thing a lot of bots
earlier about networks while she just
log into these clinics house and noticed
stay logged in
they do and this can incur a lot of
additional cost free if you're like
Amazon or something like that
have to be cautious of that and also go
and I'll try and attack other systems
from this box it won't work because
there is no honey pot but you can still
incur additional charges you can also
use could pose a pen test tool sort of
fun thing to do is keep up whatever
doing like an internal pen test just
like your shared server that you guys
are all logging into and stuff like that
movie legitimate service and then just
dan kept her up and just wait let it sit
there for like a day or two and
guaranteed something's gonna lie in that
box whether it's like a vulnerability
scanner or configuration management
system or something like that
jets or something along again and then
you can steal the credentials really
easily so here's an example of capo if
if no one's really played with it so we
did here is a desayunar iptables script
which essentially all this does is it
forwards any requests destined for port
22 to port 2222 which is where actually
spending up the honeypot so now we're
gonna change perimeter good changed her
kibble user man well this is a good time
I'm just glad this demo play is awful
there's a Smirnoff Ice I think there's
more if you like one so what happened
back here as are using the honey pot and
essentially tried some some bad
passwords and stuff like that and that's
essentially what I was showing in the
back in here is the logs now this is the
reason not a lot of people actually run
honey pots and because they don't want
to go through this massive amount of
data that's what if your gonna do this
you should pull him into some sort of
like management system so that you can
go through and actually make use of this
data rate down here with the attackers
done as they just essentially got on the
host did some you know basically
figuring out where they are some
operational kinda you know intelligence
on the host they've gained access to and
then they pulled down a file the cool
thing with hippo is that once they
pulled down any power to the house
actually does story in this DL directory
so you can go grab it later a shit
compared it stuff like that sort of
showing here is an alert that was
generated based on the hippo honeypot
being breached
so whenever they reach you want to know
about it and so what I did here as I
just replayed the ttyl session and sent
over as an attachment to the email
funny part when I did this damage this
is actually a real attacker like hitting
her honeypot slightly open their online
this is ours this is the one we actually
just generated says unexpected so I
didn't have it formatted rate at the
time either but since we pay seen here
we can see like this is everything the
attacker did and saw you know presented
to us neatly and in the form of alert
essentially now
if you want to check this out of cloned
the capo repo so if you wanna check out
my guess I have a bunch of other scripts
to you that I've done like for their
argument the capo client like added some
monitoring scripts and stuff like that
as well so if you wanna check this out
there's my my get up there and higher
action on any pots high interaction
honey pots are essentially real systems
and the way we deploy amount longer them
is in the sense of their real systems
put real systems on the internet but we
have dedicated monitoring of highly
instrumental these systems so he can see
for command-line access we can see
everything that's happening on the hosts
essentially so some just a few of the
tools that we used to do this for free
tools are these aren't so much free but
but so in addition to whatever logging
system you have is good to always be
watching this data but Sir Cana is a
really cool idea solution and not just
for you know the traditional idea sense
we actually is circled for his Wii
sinkhole the traffic so whenever the
members trying to call out with sinkhole
it and we send it says her kata kata
allows us to actually interact with them
our actually it creates a really cool
ability to interact with some with some
of the weird malware out there is the
one we do use more in line like as an
actual ideas where we actually try and
block some of the traffic and try and
see what she was going on right and then
congress and boxes and see where we
lower our exploded and gather some of
that that analysis room right now this
is a fun project Roman hunter this is
the router Manhunter so you don't have
to just use real real systems to create
any pots this one's essentially turning
your router into a honeypot so this is
you set up a real access prime and all
it does waits for someone to connect to
it successfully so the fun thing here is
it considered either as security and
security want and depending on how you
want to gauge the attackers that are are
breaching it like you said it with
weapons someone pops it you know
probably whatever but he said like it w
it
wpa2 or something
and someone gets and that's something
like you might want to look into what
this does it takes their MAC address and
just adds it to list and see can take
this Mac and you can correlate this back
against your real environment see like
an employee or is not an employee r you
know what is this
that's like one of the it's just a fun
little honey possibly can deploy on on
the router now we did lots warnings with
high interaction honey pots because
you're essentially using real systems is
dangerous to have dedicated to honoring
someone watching this all the time
because there's a huge risk if you don't
have someone watching this ready to
respond already take the system offline
if they start attacking other hosts are
things like that cuz I could come back
to your company you also don't want to
please even in your own IP space if you
are you know trying to do stuff like
that on the internet right to never use
your goal your organization's gold
standard image when you're deploying a
higher action on a pot of a story about
this there's company who decided to
deploy some honey pots and what they did
was actually put out real systems out in
a DMZ that was under their control and
of course in RTP open to the internet
with a weak password as I think it was
the day they put it up it got buried and
so what happened is they've gotten to
this hostname dump the local admin ashes
and like the company has disabled so
they'd like we're not ready for honey
pots and and they actually use that to
pivot into the organization so like
deploying a honeypot cause illegitimate
breach for this company so we have to be
very careful and like you know make sure
you really take precautions if your
gonna try some of this stuff and part of
this is segment doing so and proper
segmenting so put something out
folks and unfortunately throws up again
and we have no audio and video to speak
of moving until about the 32nd minute
mark so you voted there but we do have a
slide in the meantime
you can see there on a windows box
labeled as a tablet PC right there is an
office to get some good data on this
just right from here now of course
there's been IP address go course right
why would it go anywhere else right well
there is some more to the story but
that's actually the wire transfer he did
send this to a banking and EUS in
california is actually reached out to
this bank we let them know I K look for
this coming through the wire transfer
like a like you know this person and
stuff like that and actually from the
job we can tell a lot more of this
person who turns out of the whole
Nigeria LinkedIn is not really was all a
ruse which is pretty genius when you
think about it they're using that to say
like Nigerians gathered in a stop right
there pretty it pretty genius if I say
so myself so what are some more things
you can do to just screw with people
rights groups attackers and stuff like
that
my favorites is just the bonds are so
funny can plant the is like somewhere
people might be trying to steal stuff or
whatever the thing with this is a bomb
unforgettable that DK is this file
called 42 does it it's like it's like a
four point to like byte file that once
they expanding its like it's like 30
different zips compressed in another zip
like it's it's ridiculous
expands to like four point to petabytes
deploy this is still take out of
supercomputer basically
beef beef is another fun one so if
you're overdoing it like testers he
probably is be four you know exercised
validation stuff like that but like when
you own the environment in your own like
where these attackers are are in
essentially you can just inject your own
be folks from do like dynamic wrinkles
on and stuff like that or like pop shows
are you know whenever you really want to
do is an awesome if you had a chance to
play with it and you have to be another
fun one actually haven't built one of
these cuz I'm afraid to have someone
like Fri my computer that's what it does
it's essentially you take the USPS
actually turns into basically a battery
like all the details are here definitely
check it out if you wanna mess with this
thing but it's like it be the equivalent
of you like plug-in USB directly into
the wall and Mike into your computer and
then click he is always fun this
actually I'm yes he is the past and the
cool things you can do this with any
images really it's just a PHP IDs
features actually but I can dynamically
screw with people and people office
mostly funny I think it one of my
favorites this is like the dumbest thing
ever but it's so funny just cat
different him overnight cats have never
seen this is what it looks like people
in there for a long time trying to
figure out what this is
so that there's no sit there like what
is this we needed decipher this you know
it's funny just waste their time for a
long time now to take it to the next
level you can do full on ASCII art like
this is fine I'd definitely check out
the script down here with them see what
this does lousy to play for movies
through like telnet sessions and stuff
like that and then we get record in
asking so let's get back to you know
kind of the meat of everything we're
talking about the key to all of this can
we bring everything back together is
actually monitoring the stuff so bring
into some central management interface
you can actually watch what's happening
and dynamically respond to what's going
on you're within your honey pots and
your real network so you want to bring
in all your security tools you want to
have like at least a single pane glass
Regency kinda everything that's going on
you might be able to monitor your honey
pots and you want to be able to
dynamically correlate that back with the
real environments like they've been
doing this over here in the honey pots
was a Caesar been doing against real
systems for like the past 30 days and
that's just the stuff you wanna try and
tie the pieces together using honey pots
kind of as well as the glue in between
all this and once you have a very good
network of kind of all the stuff setup
you can actually start to create your
own essentially enterprise threat
intelligence and sore throat until like
totally just way over use and stuff like
that but but when talking about here is
context aware credit else this is like
stuff this directly affecting you and
your unique industry has like it here
and retailer of different stuff and say
hospitals hospitals can be hit by
different stuff and say the government
to like you know getting these giant
threat list of IP is i mean that doesn't
do a whole lot of good but if you
generate your own like IOC's based off
of what you're actually seeing in your
environment
and then you share with them similar
industries you can actually gained a lot
of traction on the dog comes down to
shun very now the next aspect is you
actually want to automate your response
to these threats so one of my favorite
ways of doing this is actually just
dynamic honey products like taking a
system that's probably compromised or
are you suspect something weird going on
and dynamically turn that into a
honeypot there's a couple ways to do
this very easily just by implementing
command my logging to detailed their
sentry gun registry value up to set for
the command prompt and you can create a
profile that ps1 file to get power show
now there's a really good down here so
Michael girl he actually presented
earlier today are yes some awesome
information on Lake detailed verbose
command-line auditing so I highly
recommend checking that out if you want
to implement some of the stuff you know
there's also a lot of tools out there
that will help you with automating
response so first time Google rapid
response pretty pretty neat tool makes
it very easy to respond to threats and
work as a team to share intelligence you
gather already netflix has their own
project phyto Khan says a really cool
PowerShell framework for a response and
empower forensics is an awesome project
actually everything at invoke I R is
actually really cool air attack in Sinai
think of his name
really sharp guy behind like the whole
invoke I R project so I highly recommend
checking this out but so I wanted to
jump into the mix too with the whole
breast cancer response can think to say
I wrote this little tool called up
yesterday and just short for power show
recon essentially what this is
script that we've we've integrated with
with our Sam essentially to go out like
say we see something weird like a like a
crypto were outbreak on a network we
want to do is go pull friends of data
from this home
and then knocked offline really quick so
doesn't know spread to share something
like that
century the goal of up yes recon you can
also run as a standalone script and I
think it does pretty well you guys
should check it out and let me now where
you like and don't like about it but one
of the aspects we added into the tool is
that when it does go pull data from the
host you can set up to send out email
reports to you know the entire scared
operations team to let them know i ka
like this hostage-taking offline here's
a bunch of forensics data from that
hosts we just pulled and so just sent
out this email and read here actually
gives you a report of all the data on
the host nice thing about the the report
is everything self-contained has images
base 64 encoded directly into the page
and stuff like that so you don't have to
reach out to another server too poor to
pull anything down so makes it makes a
nice for you know quick and simple
answer response essentially so how do
you bring together and everything we
kinda we kinda just talked about
well one of the main things is honey pot
dashboards so actually being able to
track everything is going on in your
honey pots in one easy to use way dr 3
nice things about it has a ton of
different dashboards in there basically
just about every honey pot that it has
installed it has a corresponding
dashboard on something you can go check
out and like figure out what dashboards
want to use if you're if you're going
like full open source you want to do
something with a commercial solution
it's a good resource to start with so
you can figure out why honey pots
forward for your your situations and
then keep a graph is one of these
sources we talked about keeping I
definitely want to mention kipah graph
is this basically pulls all of the data
they were talking about out and shows an
easy-to-understand way so we're looking
at the wall of text earlier
well this actually helps make some sense
of that
of modern highly networked this one we
didn't really have time to talk about
details but this is a really cool
project in that you can dynamically
deploy honey pots and monitor them from
one interface as long as you have extra
IP space you can just keep pushing out
more honey pots and he's actually use
some of the more advanced forms like
Diana glass top and some of the like the
really high interaction honey pots so
pretty cool project that you should
definitely check it out and then of
course you know the best 148 no I'm like
that ok well just jump right into the
data should be collecting them so so
down a lot of the most important data
that like to collect in the dashboards
that I use top attacking IP address
wanna see who's hitting these honey pots
and then the trending want to look at
the trending of honeypot attacks verse
the trending the entire environments
wanna correlate the two and see like
where the spikes happen and if they if
they really talk usernames find out if
people have really isn't that they're
using fake ones suffer top passwords
they think it looks like real passers
you want to figure out your dive into
that and see like those as someone who
actually had their credential store
stuff like that and then honey took in
file access so this is finals but
tracking honey token access is something
you definitely want to have great
friends centers so say someone's door
document moved it you know they did
something else with it you want to know
about that and so having that the
dashboards a good way to do that and
then user agent strings so user agent
strings are kind of the one of the more
undervalued aspects that they were
looking out here to talk about the
attackers because most people don't
bother to change the user agent strings
when they're attacking websites and
stuff like that so you can learn you
know if they're using tools to scan you
are there you know if they're just using
their browser they're using like a
foreign browser something like that like
it will give you a lot of intel on just
what what's hitting your environment and
then payloads any malware that's cool
down to the hosts want to track and
directionality
to figure out where they're coming from
where they're going
going all that good stuff then so from
there you end up with a you know decent
dashboard covering here honey pots honey
pots and your real environments
essentially so that is when I jump into
some work cited recommended reading so
most of what I what I talked about it is
actually based off of some of the work
that John strand and Paul a story and
have done so I highly recommend their
book offensive countermeasures the art
of active defense it's a great read and
it's like it's a very short book but
like every page is actually has really
good content on it so highly recommend
that book and if you're ever gonna do I
R
the blue team handbook is is a great
resource is very short and simple as
precise to like here's what you need to
know for like performing this sort of
engagement or something like that so
very kind of straight to the point now
if you wanna get really deep into our
game and like management check out
logging in log management by Anton
shrunken and Kevin Smith you know the
logging it could be hard to get through
but it's it's a good read
actually has some really good stuff like
build out of stock in the right way and
stuff like that and then this last one
reverse deception cyberthreat counter
exploitation it's exactly like the name
sounds it's a counter Intel book and it
talks about how the deist deceive
attackers and some of the tricks that
like CI folks used to deceive and trick
people into divulging information and
all sorts of other good stuff so so if
you wanna do any of this stuff anymore
check out some of these resources for
that thanks
around