I guess he probably go and get started I
think thirty seconds earlier is ok maybe
there are you planning on seeing me I
don't feel comfortable standing on a
chair but maybe if I do this you can see
my hands feel up here so they start
sticking around my talk packing web apps
this is mostly suck out of an
introduction so if you haven't started
hacking web apps or something you want
to get into this talk is designed to
sort of point you in the right path and
kind of show you what what I do as a pen
tester client kickoff call the way to
record delivery so quick disclaimer
composite video and kick off so kick off
call there's a few things that happen
initially when the project starts so
once all the legal stuff has happened
with the client you know they've signed
the paperwork and everything what we do
is we go to our rules of engagement or
that basically clarifies what the scope
is pages that they might not want us to
touch that are sensitive testing window
is a 24 by seven or is it only business
hours Monday through Friday information
like that
also the point of contacts do you have a
question or if you happened to set the
building on fire by some magical mystery
than you know who to call something to
remember at the end of every assessment
a report is expected just keep this in
mind as you go through you and I want to
make sure to document as much as
possible
distrust me this does make your life
much easier at the end instead of
thinking shoot I didn't save a
screenshot for that cross site scripting
or whatever it is keep that in mind
ok so how do I keep notes well keep know
it's convenient name for the application
it's built into Cali Linux that's also
available for Windows and Mac OS and
it's pretty cool way to store
screenshots or code or anything else you
can make different pages and a cool
thing about it is that when you're done
with it you can actually exported always
HTML and get right to the client if they
want your on its so they don't have to
install any sort of special software for
themselves
couple of ways that I keep things
organized so after you have several
items if you have several websites or
IDs and scope you can grab it by IP or
if you're working on just a couple is
all grouped by vulnerability as you can
see the darker red or maroon colored
that would be my chronicles the red
would be a serious and then the orange
or yellow is low and blue informational
that's just a personal preference
however you wanna do it but for me
that's just a quick visual way as I'm
keeping track of what I found evidence
gathering citizens you as a few
prototypes of what to document as you're
going through and doing these these
assessments any HTTP request and
response that you get make sure document
those so for example I have found a
cross-site scripting vulnerability not
only going to document that the GET
request that shows what I said I'm also
going to document the response code and
I also do a screenshot to show where the
code executed so make sure to document
those things anyone scheduled downtime
or issues so if for whatever reason they
didn't properly whitelist you on their
firewall their IDs IPs and those were
times that you couldn't access the
website this make a quick note on that
that way if they have any issues going
over there
you can say hey I can access your site
during this time any money to monetary
transactions listed bank website or
e-commerce or something
log that information that way if you do
happen use personal car company card you
can get your money back again don't
share any screenshots of any cool hacks
if you happen to get rude on a box or
something don't share that online
disclosure agreement so you know don't
you it's not a good thing to do
make sure you get relevant legible
screenshots for example I know that's
kind of hard to say back there but if
you if you find a really good you get
like sequel injection or something
make sure to take screenshots of legible
parts of the uprights 04
map for example sometimes it can be a
whole lot of output depending on the
tables and things like that if you need
to copy and paste something that's more
legible who dis your terminal do that
but just make sure that it's something
the client can read so they can actually
understand what it is they're looking
for a way that I like to call out my
HTTP requests and responses as I like to
highlight it you can't put it as a code
snippet and for example you can see
where it says username equals and then
just a basic check for seeking injection
you can see I have that if you wanna
call the payload is highlighted that way
as the client is looking at the report
they can see exactly what caused the
issue
guys sorry having to go through this
really really quick so you have any
questions or anything after talk please
come see you if you do find a single
injection for example make sure you
check every parameter that's in the
application for all the same things
peres
if you find one parameter thats
vulnerable to seek an injection there
could be seven or eight more that are
vulnerable as well she want to make sure
to check those and document all those
parameters under that finding something
that I go by because there's so many
things to look at and do so many of
these assessments as a methodology our
checklist you don't want to be
necessarily confined to these this check
list because they can change so much but
basically just something to kind of help
keep you in order to make sure you're
not forgetting to look at some big
obvious glaring thing discovery open
source intelligence these are things
that we include in our methodology and
so basically we were doing this is my
client gives us a website would go look
at not only the IP to see what other IP
is that they have or we also want to
check and see if there's any domain
squatting or someone thats copying their
site for phishing site and so learning
to use tools like Facebook and Google
and all these things for open source
intelligence is a great way to check to
see not only if someone is trying to
copy the site or do something malicious
but it's also a good way to see if this
company has been compromised before so
you might be able to find
credentials or information that's that's
already exposed to the internet from a
previous half so that that's that's a
good thing that you want to make sure to
do for every assessment through this I
found data base types without having to
do any enumeration I found entire
database schemas or credentials
current credentials and several things
through developer forums through
archived emails several things so it's
it's very time consuming but it's
definitely worth it and you
payoff for sure so discovery a tad more
to discover eosin discover is a great
tool that like to use their squad at
their several out there but one of the
ones I go to first was discovered by Lee
Baird because it covers so many things
so quick so make sure you check that out
automated scanning yes we automated
scanning well you're supposed to be a
real hacker way to use on its can tell
you I again we do so many of these
assessments so quick that they cover a
lot of ground and look for a lot of
low-hanging fruits we don't ever just
give them in their results
straight from the automated scanner
because an automated scanner is not a
pen test a boner ability scan is not a
pen test so we just kind of use that to
see ok
are there any big glaring holes or we
could look at and of course we go
through and we do false-positive
analysis and sit there something we need
to dig deeper so it's just kind of a
little added to help us cover a lot of
ground really quick
the big time saver and again a bone scan
is not meant to those who say that it is
I would beg to differ so even those
scanners help again we have to validate
their findings see you know is that
there was just a scanner that totally
misread something don't rely on those
make sure you test it
you automated scanners that we use our
analysis and IBM apps can skate pro at
the highest grade automated scanning and
add-ons that you can put in there with
it to help make it even more valuable
and then you have
things like Nick too and then if it's a
framework like WordPress or Joomla
Drupal or something like that there are
also tools UWP scan that's for WordPress
sites are things that go through and
look for just some major glaring holes
things that help you save time and no
Oscar buster some people argue that this
is a huge waste of time sometimes it is
sometimes have actually gotten some
really valuable results for running this
basically if you're not familiar with it
when it does it will actually you can be
a huge directory names of directories
things that were doing search for or it
will do it at rude reports or start from
901 and always liked all the Alpha bad
and it will try all these different
combinations it can take a long time but
it's a good way to find some hidden
directories as more options and Kali
that you can check your not familiar to
check this actually tells you exactly
where to go in the menu
a few pro chips for automated scanning
verify the settings don't just put in
the URL and click Go
you want to check how many threads are
you going to flood their system do you
have safe checks on you know you have
certain denial of service things turned
off just go through and look and make
sure that you understand the tour before
you go otherwise you could potentially
cause a lot of problems it do they have
any certain pages like a contact page or
sign-up page or something that they
wanted to avoid otherwise this can
really just their data base with a lot
of junk which could potentially cause
analysis or actual or chrome dads get
sometimes you do test and production
environment and not a development
environment so those are all things that
you want to check in when you're ready
got everything set up you know then
click Go
now the good stuff
manual testing hasn't talked about you
wanna take some of that you want to go
through and look at what the automated
scanners have found that they fine
sequel injection for example if they did
take that throw it in something like
burp suite pro or something where you
can replay that attack and you really
dig into it to see if it's a false
positive or not
manual or automated scanners can only go
so far they they can only do so much
there's a human element the interaction
just isn't there so that's why you have
to do manual testing to make it with
gentleman again like we proceeded and he
talked about that a lot because it's
it's kind of a regular go to tools for
many things there are also other tools
out there for manual testing as far as
proxy tools like zap
familiar with bad and several other
tools that you can do some research on
talk about some of the stuff I'm trying
to get a train to go through it as quick
as I can hear parameters are not
familiar with program is being if you're
not familiar with what parameters are an
application there are several resources
on the internet for free that will help
you explain and understand that once you
get a better understanding of what that
is
start diving into the application more
see sometimes the parameters will be in
the URL or sometimes they're only
imposed requests so just make sure to
sort of looking at the coding and
digging in and really trying to break
the application in as many ways as
possible I'm just going to click through
to view the slides because there's so
much information
basic things you want to look or again
cross-site scripting
cross-site request forgery sequel on
LDAP injections
local and remote file inclusions so
again use Google or become familiar with
those terms and exactly what they are
you can you can really leverage some
Italian really leverage those
vulnerabilities for some really good
attacks several times we've been able to
completely compromised and even further
into networks Thurs something simple
like sequel injection so just make sure
you just become as familiar with that
can there are also several diem diem
that you can download practice I'm
trying to think of the name a few
yeah yeah damn horrible there there are
so many out there right now they have
some have specific scenarios for you to
follow almost like capture the flag type
so just really practice those in your
home lab to become familiar with the
towards other things you want to look
for as their sensitive information being
passed through a get requests just
remember that those get requests can be
cash on the local user browser so if
something happens and I machines
compromise and there's credentials are
something that are stored in the history
from the gate request the attacker could
potentially get those and then leverage
with that information so that's the
stuff that you want to check now to
prevent death by PowerPoint happy dog
hot dog for a second
other things you want to check this
makes them more notes
authentication how are you up indicating
to the application is using SSL TLS can
you access certain pages as an
unauthenticated user or maybe if you're
just a regular level use her and you see
URLs in the code admin
can you access the admin pages as a non
admin user so
privilege escalation things like that
those are all things that you want to
check for authentication for sure don't
just look at the web app also want to
look at the host of the rapids on or do
they have certain services open that
they that shouldn't be there sometimes
even externally we've seen a remote
desktop and desktop unable to the
Internet
don't ask him as a silly thing but check
those things because you know there
could be other ways to compromise to
host of other than through the web app
so make sure what the host is a running
an outdated install sir yes something
like that can you that you could see you
know a good photo HTTP methods do they
have good copy delete trace or other
methods enabled sometimes we found that
is enabled so what do we do we put a
shell script up there and we have
automatically compromise that hosts just
because we could put information up
their name overdone delete was enabled
so deleted it so sounds really simple
one kind of stupid but those things are
in there so we always want to make sure
to check there is to see if that's
something you can leverage again
director commercial shell-shocked heart
bleed so these are all things you want
to look at for the hosts as well so
there are several things that you can
again as I mentioned using several
things you can find out about all the
things we've talked about so far
different methodologies I highly
recommend
the methodology from a loss and
basically what that's going to do is
give you an outline of things to look at
help keep you on track during your
assessment to make sure you're trying to
cover all the grounds of the application
sure you set up a practice lap don't
ever try a new tour something you're not
familiar with on a client site for the
first time cuz be disastrous and then
when they say well what did you do and
you say I don't know that's never a
never a good day so always make sure you
know what you're told you're doing and
practice them before you do it and wants
you get everything set up and you've
practiced go ahead some websites
actually got through this fast enough
like I was hoping to to leave time for
Q&A if anyone has any questions for me
please on you know you have any
questions about time we tell the client
say like Monday and Tuesday will be the
heaviest day for traffic ok so Monday
and Tuesday will run IBM abscam will do
it unauthenticated and then we'll use
credentials for authenticated scan to
see what it gets and then later in the
week what we do is we will look at the
output and see if there's something
worth going
after and we'll start validating that
through burps we are on our own I know I
would I wouldn't proxy that will be a
lot of garbage
yeah yeah and that would be a gigantic
file too because of how much stuff yeah
yeah so whenever we do an automated
scanning like Nexus or IBM abscam
something that's off by its side
course it logs self so we'll do that and
then what we do is look at those results
and replay the things that look
interesting
manually through birds we grow so that
the answer question for ya for web
applications not so much mostly just to
look at the host just to see what the
host is running and it does a quick scan
of you know SSL TLS ciphers they have
enabled at their certificates ballot is
it out today in all the basic checks
yeah but as far as the actual web web
app itself now that I know you can throw
and potentials and things like that but
i just i don't know that I would
necessarily trust and as much not saying
anything bad about this because it's
great tool but I don't think as far as
like specifically for a web out so it's
a good question by else
yeah it since Tennessee like it looks
super serious when you see it but you
know as well as a pen tester all the
applications I looked at think maybe two
or three that I actually classified that
as a serious or critical and it's kind
of a kind of depends on the application
what's going on now they're there are
ways to leverage that but then you have
to look at you know what's the
likelihood versus the risk as well so
really it's one of those things where
you have to look at it you know is that
possible what can you do with it and
then the likelihood person's risk so it
kinda just depends on the application
and and what the applications so
unfortunately like a lot of these things
is not absolutely 100% answer yes that's
critical show if you have suspicions
that ability is there just keep doing
research keep beating away that because
they like the most common way to do it
or like the proof of concept that works
we probe might give you it's like well
what does that matter but say you really
really dig in and start looking
obfuscation techniques encoding thing
certain ways that by Pastor Web
Application Firewall are certain things
that you could you maybe get something
in there that you couldn't just by a
high-level example so I encourage you to
really dig into that and just just beat
it up as much as you can
that's that's a great point and some
will say well why do we need to turn
that off you know your hackers around
that there are ways that we can but when
you look at the contract we usually only
have one or two weeks to do this and it
takes quite a while to fill that out and
see like how you need to get things in
and out of application for awhile before
you're being blocked it so we say look
just whitelist us let us go through
there let's get past that as if we're an
attacker that's already figured out that
way we know what's behind it so you
always want to have them whitelist you
on application firewall and any ideas
IPS that they might have as well so you
want to make sure that you're properly
whitelisted so you get accurate results
so
alright anymore questions thank you guys
SO SO much are ready for the question
you've asked well thank you guys so much
if you have any more questions come see
me I'll be happy to answer