Francisco be a tools demonstration
discussion but I have a new tool I'm
gonna release instead today and that's
going to go over the concept of creating
an auto auto brothel you know the places
unsavory people go to to get diseases
that's we're gonna go over so over a
little bit hardware the beginning so
when things are recommended as cheap can
bust ups but we're getting started at
the top one is can't act that's by air
kevin is a sales last name its doubts
that the box open source hardware or
just call was pretty well another one's
kind of equipment 9042 can do you make
this better
ok we'll have the tracks
where'd ya chair so ok so we had a USB
can that's about 60 bucks concern
anyways he is available for shipping I
like it a lot on Linux simply because it
shows up as a trial can when you start
messing with these one seriously when
can I prefer I can but they're about
equivalent when things were going to
talk about his scandals is a big boat
dealership in normal ones this one's
when you get from Mike Autozone or you
know arrived here in this kind of places
ABC plugs into your car they tell you
what your engine lights on reporting but
a DTC diagnostic trouble code and you
can clear that's pretty much what they
do
normal person has and they have a
dealership tall and he's a lot more
expensive the last month's pay like $100
for these games 2000 but they go up from
there and so this particular picture is
a tech to by Jim yeah and they all
connections because they work on cars
more features the do a lot of stuff
that's kinda own proprietary protocol
so the generic protocol to get dynastic
stuff and there's an unpublished one and
most dealerships use the non published
12 at their their cars to get things
done numbers and that kind of stuff or
to work on actuators like in a row
window down or a card or those kinds of
things he's also can be used for
reprogramming some of the ECU engine
control units from where
so they're nice and the nice tools I
guess to get your hands on you can also
probably argue for software side we have
psychic and this is my preferred method
Linux kernel have some tools there
that's the can packets up there so you
can see him God you can see that all
right door but that's really really
simple so can packets have an idea they
don't have a source or destination just
a simple I D
up to eight bytes for the data packet
the payload and that's pretty much so it
becomes a look at them three persons not
too hard it's mainly just a matter of
seeing them out of a noise of a bunch of
other packets going by your screen that
kind of stuff
the reason I can is because once I catch
and it it you let you use all your hard
work the same tools
countries like a network interface you
know so no matter which never occurred
to have you in New Lenox wth 0 same here
this is can 00 but a break and then work
no matter what hardware the person
pictured used so the way this neutral
him about his kind of an extension of
the other two are icy some open source
on github if you search for zombie Craig
and I see you find it it's basically
pieces you have a instrument cluster the
top which has your speedometer turns
saying nose and a picture for your door
locks
there's another screen comes up that's
your controls the reason why looks like
game controllers and game controllers
playstation xbox whatever the controls a
pretty much the same as grand theft auto
and as you
driver allan that it controls your
inspectors from the top and it does it
but not not by using a programming
methods such as any for anything like
that but doesn't by using can packets
just having a real car so the window you
see on the left
can't rap it's going by and so we can do
is you can practice your looking at can
traffic identifying different things
like what controls the throttle what
does door locks and then you can send
packets just like you would on a real
car and see if it actually has an effect
doesn't unlock the car doors those kinds
of things and there's a lot of
background traffic that comes from real
car traffic should my car so that's
balanced so get used to looking at can
do I can stop you can change the
difficulty levels so once again I kind
of stuff
one thing and doing training classes is
the certain tools that work against
components such as engine control units
are body control modules those don't
work of ICC it's mainly can traffic so I
want to make another tool that allows
you to do queries for diagnostic trouble
codes and those kinds of things in a
virtualized environment and ICIC
simulation your car to do it so I create
the Cinco de UDS server so also free get
upset because they can't read it but
it's
and so that allows you to run that you
can run other tools like caring caribou
universal I system actual results in
Metro cars can do like him but forcing
and that kind of stuff so you can
practice with those but one doing this
kind of came to this realization that
old likud said during a virtualized
simulation environment for training I
can also use this attack dealership
tools dealership tools are using out of
scope for security development they have
all the keys all the cars he's the
firmware of those kinds of things you
really need is an extra piece of
hardware so the ODB gateway comes from
OBD is the normal course you plug into
and I tend to hoist a dirty bastards who
d be instead so I wouldn't have made a
tool so now I'm not wrong I say no debe
it's just different all in all it really
is is you have to be ports attached to
it but you have to do is this is kind of
minimum install you would run the ground
wires to each other
12 volt power and then the green one so
they can hike and that's the minimum you
will have to put a 200 or 250 ohm
resistor on the can lines for it to work
and what are you trying to mimic the
other one still so if you're going like
an American car though typically have
more can so that's a high-speed cameras
may have a middle seat can or low-speed
can and in those cases wanna run those
two but sometimes a line or something
else your thing will vary but if you
keep it to just can't high power and
ground it's fairly universal so here is
one thing you can do you can be any
vehicle you take a scan tool which is
like da
here so that's the scandal here
Bosch it does everything make all the
decisions based on your then one thing
you can do is use in a ban from another
car are you in similar cases showing a
2006 Dodge Charger and then when you're
through his assumptions based on that
you can also make up your own vents on
the command line options and so this one
is a believer not a valid then says
permit open garages thence have a
checksum in bytes in this case is free
and open so this tool if it didn't
couldn't do proper calculations on your
been bashful where it won't get some
signs this one is fine
is concerned it will try to process this
one no problem you can work from
anywhere this picture was taken out of
our laptop had a scan tool doing much
testing allows for fussing so many
things you can also send a bunch of
closing packets I think this means ample
that is well you can do it for no
controls so I mentioned we need to go
dealership to like you know controlling
door unlocked that kind of stuff if you
look at the debug log which is on the
left side and you can read it but it'll
basically an English what's going on
you're plugged in this way you have you
know a deal at all like an MDI here for
the tech to go and you say I liked the
card or it will show you on the left and
English no se ok were spying to test her
present we've gotten a request for
sending data and then you'll see the
highlighted section there which is
saying that was unhandled device control
from gym and that's the other
highlighted packet so it's the package
began a are those controls and so we all
know
the reasons I'm handles because there's
nothing to do from the simulation
perspective not gonna simulated door
unlocking with this because just
software only basis output so that's
what you see as a unhandled but you know
right away when you could do a lot
that's attacking you can send a lot that
card or you need the car there to do it
and so if you're in icing as opposed to
getting a rental car and then figuring
things out you can just tell this the
car you're interested in the national
press the buttons here's what it would
be for this cars such a lot of times you
not looking through all of that can
traffic
here's another example of the buzzer so
DC's were trouble codes normally get
like my worst 205 trouble codes in a car
although no car really would have
something like that this week in July
comes on this case when i dun jim has a
a different way of sending packet data
so you can speak much much higher number
of the EBC a model there at like 1030 or
98 trouble codes body control module 676
I mean so fake stuff but like what's
happening here is you can have it trying
to display these things so one thousand
and see how the devices handle that the
goal is get to crash when you get these
the crash
you can then work on getting for their
exploits to it is again they have the
keys to all the other ones doing some
relatively squishy
they have very low security they don't
use even have a internal I T Department
these tools like I said I trusted their
tools that you know aren't like security
review kind of stuff so you can make a
malicious car that drives into a
dealership and it's there to attack the
dealership has you playing the
diagnostic tools see where engine light
is on again take care of that tool and
then when she had on that to you don't
any other car that comes in handy on a
brothel
and now we see what this is about you
know like that picture in case me
nothing you should go and do this as a
security audit tests are adding 10
testing tool to bring contesting two
types of a lot so it's kind of getting
another big area just hasn't been looked
at as a lot of interesting stuff there
the UDS tool just like I said we got
pushed this morning so there'll be
something certain tools it doesn't work
terribly well but there's a lot of
involvement with getting a lot more
generic man the father better that kind
of stuff some ruling for technique
contributions to us if you have problems
to do something better let me know so
the very early stages so any questions
about this store your car hacking tools
in general that I didn't cover exciting
give you the original talk would be ok
ok so that the password piece that's
kinda referring to that has the keys to
her car or the security access to it and
so typically when you're going to modify
firmware likes a change in number but
you can do you may 16 challenge response
you make every class to 24 bytes use a
comeback and you have to give it an
equivalent to a place that's at that it
like a rolling he typically or something
of that nature and so on the dealership
poolside and password will side it will
go through and kick it with a number
should be it passes back to the ECU
nieces alright cool now willing to take
take changes so with this tool what you
could do if you wanted to as you could
smoosh the request so the seed initial
seed part toward to give you a bunch of
keys assume you have a lot of times this
past rituals do I have a kind of like
license so maybe only get the push like
10 keys or something like that before
you have to pay again so it may not be
that great for you to unlimited unlock
stow yeah you could run through the kind
of the entropy out of it determine how
hard is just the guests to hear these
keys that when I would recommend 0 for
breaking those as a couple days to do it
but for a tool perspective caring care
bill is a has gone away and map like
things but also can be the framework I
have a model had released but you can
make 12 that does the same thing for one
of the vehicles that requests that's the
key the seed and then I just are
proportionate and will happen is she
like you out after like three to be like
oh you know teammate rises with your
area code is and so then you send a
packet that tells you to reboot and then
what does that your you can do it again
just the tour does that they wait for an
area and then we continue where you left
off and it's not too hard ratings front
lines that's that's one way to get the
key another one
so their thing you can do is when you
see like one side so here you can see
where it was like oh I sent a door
unlocked and here's the packet loss of
course there's other things we say like
oh gets information like the VIN for
things like that the way dealership
tools work they don't do the standard
mode nine to get to them which is the
generic yes pls scan tool from Bosch at
work
the request data based on a memory
address off the see your body control
model those memory addresses like 30
then would be simply should go to change
it so when you make a request to go read
it you can change that packet to go
right as well so you can also kind of
brute force that memory space undersea
well as in there one thing to look for
for these keys as you can make a request
for the CT scan the memory space as you
can see that sweet shop in memory if you
do a lot of times these these embedded
systems also pre generate the response
is supposed to be restored right next to
the seed so you can request the
Mauritian
the memory check the base next witness
in that as your answer and your right
amount time to do it can be pretty
smooth I went on like that happen to you
of any of the testing of the keys are
and human nature and science questions
came down from where I'm not a few yes
I'm glad you're you're the component in
this case you can make it would make it
it was a request from where you can get
fake firmware but I think a lot of your
ship tools don't down the former
modifying uploaded on the way they do as
directed
parameters little spots in the memory
you wanna go out the other way he'd want
you like hearing caribou something like
that some other tool to download the
firmware you absolutely can download ECU
from where
do most likely to come from their
dealership if you bought it for party at
the UC don't always can either princess
I have 2009 Honda and that was on key
line so it's a different type of bus
they are using Kinect your car and
getting into them as always through can
you know sometimes you can smooth things
to the entertainment that kind of stuff
you get into your entertainment you know
that when you gonna do it differently
you gonna do it through you know you see
like updates offer that kind of stuff so
I could have a web app loading Delos our
new firmware version that's a good place
to start
you can also take their radio unit out
and look for like 80 lines into it and
some have either not now the newer
vehicles which street that like you
would a dust-up
embedded systems another good sign for
most things in the newer stuff there's
planning for doing a lot that I mean the
PKI infrastructure for doing over there
updates at the have them it's not just a
nice to have the PKI infrastructure for
it and there is a lesson handful of
people I know they're doing a PCI
further updates and when they do it
there could be an issue as well
weather entertainment unit itself may
check the key information in may not
check this pushing out to other devices
are in venice is something that is
insulting check the PKI just have an
understanding of it so that's you
sometimes that each component
entertainment center does all the
checking and then and then passes it
using using just a standard password
things that you can circumvent the whole
peek at you want I just jumping on the
bus and acting like an entertainment
center
school so it might take this it takes
from where
and I mention this but you get my
participate in and just hacking and
general short talk feel free to jump on
open ground just at work as a mailing
list there we can shoot me an email
directly at Craig at they'll as I am i
think im here I don't but it's a lab SCI
com
this website also has the crackers
handbook for free download that look at
things
yeah I think that should be questioned
URL yeah