agents and I'll be talking about
bypassing two factor authentication with
Android remote access churches little
bit about myself I'm a researcher at
Fish me and one of my passions dealing
with our research is taking a look at
those command-and-control infrastructure
for malware especially ones that are
utilized PHP panels like finding
vulnerabilities in those arms my hobbies
include drumming in music
feel free to hit me up on Twitter or my
work email to go over our agenda for
today so we'll talk about why miscreants
are utilizing mobile rats after account
takeover introduced three families
talked about how they're spreading in
the Wild Arms in previous campaign info
the different command control
infrastructure types also talk about
some medications that organization's
commitment to combat these threats and
finally of course what I like to talk
about is the vulnerabilities our
families first little disclaimer though
since we are talking about exploitation
of concepts definitely going to try at
home unless you wanna by men in dark
suits and you know there might be some
hostile URLs my presentation so
definitely don't want to visit those on
your mobile device so I miscreants are
using mobile remote access Trojans well
as financial institution start to
implement two-factor no longer is
account takeover solely relying on user
names and passwords so they now need a
one-time SMS pin so by infecting the
device can also do conducting a phishing
campaign the mystery now has every piece
of that pie for account takeover one
other issue that I've seen is that you
know some of these fi they don't have
any official Android application in the
market
so you already have a user base that's
used to you know going to third-party
application stores looking for
unofficial applications for their
financial data is also a low entry point
compared to you know modern PC men in
the browser Mauer and the reason why
they're so successful that there's a
lack of Mobile Antivirus adoption and
Kaspersky put out her recent report
believe that actually was like early
2015 saying that one in five Android
users encounter encountered a mobile
threat at least once in 2014 really
interesting thread really seen that
Android malware ecosystem take you
through the steps of normal to factor
accounts take over there are even miss
create here starts with a mouse pam
campaign you know fish are victim clicks
on that looks like you know the FI login
that he's you soon to voters his
username and password and of course the
setbacks them as gramm steps to see
factor account takeover so that phishing
site has some sort of verbiage saying
will you need to download our latest
mobile application in order to be more
secure so that victims you know
downloads and installs it on his mobile
then as a financial institution sends
SMS one-time pen and a mobile device
says there's compromise that the
miscreant and gets a copy of that he has
every piece of the pie for counter so
one way that miscreants are duping users
into installing these moderates is a
process called binding its most of these
are baked into the crime where families
that all talk about here in a minute
socially you can use a binder to wrap a
legitimate application with you know any
type of Android malware so definitely
seen that in the wall street side of
another binder here
they're essentially two types of command
control infrastructure for mobile Mauer
pretty much the same that you see on the
PC side for rats I like to categorize
season 22 different avenues one being
jabbed Java c2 and the other being PHP
panels for the first family will talk
about it
Andrew rad Java cease to also known as
sander rather droid jack and the second
family as I banking which speech P panel
and then finally done early so the job
is he to you know most of these are
going to be run off of residential
high-speed connections so a lot of the
the seats you domains that you see will
use utilize some sort of dynamic dns
account such as nineteen hours no ip
dougans so on these are generally run on
PC which begs the question you know most
of these crime where kids they've been
released free online some sort of leak
and you know sometimes by doing that the
person it's releasing her three might in
bed some sort of back doors kid which
are you know completes our SEC issues
for a mystery and these are also highly
flood susceptible PHP commanding control
also known as panels in the underground
a color and one of the huge issues with
this is that there's a lack of input
validation in the PHP code itself which
leads you know rise to PHP shall upload
vulnerabilities remote code execution
sequence action are permanent permanent
cross-site scripting so on so forth
these are also very susceptible to layer
7 flood attacks cheerleaders are hosted
on compromised websites or toss away VPS
accounts for the first family get into
an example of a job seats you family
first known as injury and changed its
name to save your ad now it's available
as droid Jack in August of 2014 there
was a active campaign as you can see
pictured right here pretending to be
from Kaspersky saying that she needed to
install this mobile security application
so this was spam doubt as an attachment
to Melissa's apk targeted polish
financial institutions and also Germany
via SMS or someshit attacks on so as
minded as Kaspersky anti-virus and and
for the German AFI's it was actually
targeted as a Google service framework
update and there has been attribution
for the authors leading back to India
you can still buy now on hacker forums
dotnet or the official site which is a
Droid Droid Jack dotnet some of its
features has full fine File Manager
remote file manager capability SMS
interception of course for its affected
by passing contacts grabbing GPS
tracking record calls and audio tapes to
imagine that remote ambient bug device
for someone's cell phone in the same
thing with video spy cam screenshot here
the actual crime where kid again
Jabu Jabu based seats to not only would
this be able to generate they became
itself but also access the server in
which infected device check back in
after the last time package price of
$210
whenever I take a look at this
been following his family's for a while
so I was like to see you know how many
fresh samples are hitting virustotal so
utilizing virustotal intelligence last
Monday so several fresh samples still
hitting virustotal so still seen in
awhile so as I mentioned earlier you
know these are extremely susceptible so
in a lab situation set up there one of
these servers and just with a simple
soon flood within a matter of a couple
six seconds was able to really just
crushed this CPU so yeah maybe just
completely unresponsive for the second
family that will get into his car died
thinking this is a PHP pain already has
targeted financial institutions in 2013
and is still used today this was
famously used by the never cracked part
I'm sorry never quest also known as of
track crime aircrew bought track being a
man in the browser crimeware for PC
initially sold this was between for game
5 k use dollars so pretty high entry
point more oriented towards the crime
aircrews that she see realizing that
type of software so the source code for
this particular family was leaked in
2014 intercourse with any type of crime
where kid that's leaked that of course
no spawns variants of that as a good
example say you know Zeus browser
exploit are now browser exploit but the
actual crime family at cease same issue
on several variants that
some of its features include capturing
SMS of course and Collis premium rates
cans incoming call redirect so in the
event that you know I'm conducting a
campaign without thinking and do a
couple of fraudulent transactions if I
had the bank calling that individual to
verify that I can just call me to verify
the transaction
seen that a couple times and campaigns
are record calls and Mike again so one
unique feature getting two more like the
crime we're into things as they dance I
forensic capability so this family has
the ability to wipe all device data to
prevent you know forensics later on
pictured right here is actually inject
from abroad track configuration that
prompted the user to install a facebook
one-time password OTP this was actually
a high banking inject was involved track
about three months ago systems utilize
so very prevalent in looking at the
fresh samples that had virustotal
intelligence that's monday so with that
source code lead enemies in February of
2014 researcher pull down the panel
named xylitol and founding in
unrestricted file upload vulnerability
picture down at the bottom here is the
national admin screenshot so let's do we
offer this one you could see that this
wasn't really marketed towards your your
average rad dude user this was more set
up solely with primary intent not only
with the features but with no the back
and coach with the crazy thing about it
even though that this has been publicly
disclosed people still uses our family
with the vulnerable panel going over the
proof of concept here so the sin filed a
PHP file included in the crime market in
the panel source code itself what does
was intended for was in the Indian you
know audio samples were being uploaded
to the them our seats you from a
compromise device was being accepted
from the sin falta PHP in a drops into
the sound directory so there's virtually
no upload restrictions at all so you can
upload PHP back to our show as i've done
here in this example in a lab and then
you know accessing the show within the
sound directory / shelter PHP the last
family with tocqueville's another PHP
panel family this is called Android
March of 2014 cert India published
several warnings targeting the financial
institutions and the government sector
over there originally sold for $300 on
forms and US still being sought today
you may have heard about this recently
in the news in that the dark OD heck
informed bust the particular author was
busted within this roundup and turns out
he wasn't internal fire i working on
none other than our other was pretty
interesting
does the guy pictured right there so
some of the features for this is
probably the most feature rich were at
that i've seen
definitely geared towards more of you
know your your new this actor record
calls and Mike intercept text messages
course access call logs call phone
numbers
open web pages you can probably think of
some sort of you know social engineering
campaign that you might be able to get
that remote support scans perhaps comes
my ex felon upload files one unique
feature is actually has a built in
denial of service so you know any
are compromised mobile device you can
have that senate services to people when
other unique features the crowd
harvesters so I believe those like
whatsapp and Skype some of those other
well-known I am tools being able to
scrape the credentials out in that back
to the seats are still very prevalent
probably the most prevalent out of all
the three families so highly utilized in
the world today
screen side of the seats use this was
actually a screenshot within their
marketing material but very feature-rich
as you can see indefinitely geared
towards more of a noobish actor reason
beings in a very flashy GUI google map
overlay of you know your compromise
devices so you can check in real time in
GPS really cool features but the amount
of time that they worked on their front
in HTML JSP completely didn't even
bother with the back in PHP code and I'm
still has pain was actually source leaks
so not only the panel but also the
National apk generation August 2014
still available on github
so merely put on that panel that weekend
discovered a remote code execution
vulnerability among others including
seek injection and cross-site so
essentially how it works the apply
settings that PHP file it writes code to
configure PHP so by sending our
specially crafted post a request to
apply settings that PHP that has been
written to the config php file so his
subsequent request to configure PHP you
have a remote code execution so one
other issue with that is that a
completely zeros out to config php file
and is very noisy but it also completely
renders that panel interoperable with
other you know can take to appease
people files like a CMS like WordPress
or something and no longer has
credentials to check in with the data
base in doesn't know how users so
completely denied service the panel's
well so by injecting peas beans you can
take that p2p file in the previous
example I just passed you get premiere
of Season 2 system function and we have
remote command execution by passing that
in I'm having that you know I go out the
user name that Apache is running
little bit about the mitigation of this
under wrap up here a little bit when you
leave some time for questions as an
organization that we want to monitor the
official and unofficial application
repositories for your brand especially
any type of spam or D Mark fields that
you might be able to get realize too
that by implementing two factors your
organization's thinking about moving
that area that increases your mobile
attacks one thing that I have seen that
some organizations are doing instead of
relying on SMS for that once I'm pen
they actually have their own
authenticator app that's pretty cool
idea I'm so not relying on SMS elisa
makes it a little bit harder and that
the event in the event that devices
compromise its able to receive SMS
messages he sets out of band within its
own application so that's pretty cool
idea I think definitely time to educate
our user base more special with the
dangers of utilizing third-party
application stores and so what I've seen
sooo is that not so so much of a problem
here in the states mainly overseas in
that some devices most of them actually
they're actually ship without the
official Google player app store there
are used to use utilizing third-party
application stores so that is that
something that they're already doing
which was which is an issue if we want
to have them a report suspicious
activity and of course one cannot fail
to mention earlier is that all of these
Trojans that I recently went over is
that there it does not require any type
of rude or jailbroken permissions these
are all once the the user's duped into
installing this whenever that's going
through the installation process this
request for the installation is pretty
much every developer API requests under
the Sun so it's pretty big red flag that
you'll see whenever installing these
Trojans sent a request
mission so with that I believe that
written no remote access Trojans require
a very high level of social engineering
that's pretty much it for my
presentation for now you have any
questions concerns
peaches grapes misplace it would be the
initial download I believe you know for
that apk so they would have to have that
the device configured
what I have seen is that you know there
are strict instructions that you have to
allow third-party apps gently with
within the the fishing campaign itself
will have you know instructions you have
to allow application has been installed
outside of the App Store a third-party
install so that's step one to download
the game and then from there during the
installation yet to approve all of the
permissions that that rat request so
doesn't utilize any type of you know OS
level exploit anything's all what's
available to the developer API good
question of any others
yeah ok then I'm actively engaged in
looking at every panel but I would say
most of them are rarely see Windows you
know utilizing a LAMP stack lamps I
guess
yeah most of the web least from what
I've seen PHP runs on what like 80% of
websites like that so I believe most of
them would be utilizing some type of web
stack had another hand simply one way to
mitigate the threat of think so yeah
what what I have seen was some financial
institutions lol don't have their own
banking application that a subset
one-time authenticator is that where
you're going with that ur ok so yes some
other type of out-of-band authentication
other than are utilizing some other type
of messaging medium other than SMS via
at some I think that's the way to go
question back not currently I know
there's recently some stuff that came
out so apparently overseas in china is
really hard to download Xcode IDE for
iOS and apparently some people at church
and eyes that and there has been some
rumors are some research that came out
this said that had some ties to
financial you know account takeover for
those but I haven't had a chance to play
with
for Windows no I'm sorry a Windows
Phones pretty securing loans targeting
then maybe you can still get 0067 any
other questions