so we're talking about building a better
honey pot network one that gives you
some intelligence something more than
what I'm seeing so far and stuff I
played with I have been doing this for
like I guess last month and a half and
new to certain things like flask which
is used to display stuff and I thought
stuff so it's taking me a bit longer
than some people might and it's a little
bit rough but I have it out there and
get help so I'll just walk through so my
name is Josh I'm a security analyst with
OpenDNS and Cisco now been acquired I
was previously a threat analyst at nasa
and helped build the security operation
center there and threat analyst at
minutes so I'm dealing with currently
with four actually I have a few more
honey pots but I haven't been processing
the data but their counterparts in
dealing with in my instance are
necessary pot a malware honey pot one
that involves gas tanks which is awesome
and scared a lot not go into more detail
that so the amusing calorie it's a fork
hippo which is a sshit potting medium
interaction and empower people attackers
can connect in that think they're SSH
into a system in which to log files
kipah writes this one log file calories
JSON log files and log
. log JSON formatted for certain
databases for easier to work with a
little bit easier they both have a
little bit different information so I
process both when I'm looking through
the border with them create session
files just like hippo
if someone connected and it will record
whatever the type and which is great cuz
you can replay it but the session files
are treatable and beatable but it's a
mess there's actually a Python script
it's included with capo or calorie or
other parks that place for you so I i
read a script that takes that and saves
about to text files saved ttyl and then
session replay file file date final game
of some sort
carries great because hippo I remember
it only allows about to I think two
accounts to log in and if you want you
can set up more passwords which is a
pain to get to watch for a lot of
connections and then look at the office
login and you can add those passwords
and to a file of the most people are
allowed those accounts are allowed to
log in but Calgary has only two or three
that would allow the root root and root
password I think everything else is
allowed so I just wanted as many
connections as possible some people want
to specify I do a couples rule to send
all port 22 traffic honey pots to to the
port that carries listening on and then
I changed by admin access so I can still
get into the system do what I need to do
to a different port usually it's 2222 I
feel like that becoming pretty well
known I went up 10 seizing diarrhea it's
malware its goal is to get get a copy of
the power that and it's listens on a
whole bunch of ports kind of weird
Italian time I managed to figure out
install it kind of pain it reached a
sequel a database which is also kind of
annoying some some tiny parts right to
log files some right to databases they
all
different different projects they are in
a single single organization even though
that project i think is trying to bring
us all together
saves malware to a folder called
business dreams as always kind of
strange maybe there's a reason for it
anyway I'm just pointing out that
they'll save different places all season
cohn pot which is a state a honeypot
it's awesome
imitates industrial control systems so
that rights to fly a lot of that text
files which is great and i'm looking
aghast just cause its so cool and laid
sensors and gas tanks so people who
connects to them can misrepresent the
temperature of the gas tank and other
such things this article here
Trend Micro details the whole process
and great know it's a PDF document but
those are fun to play with
there's only if you download the
specifications for the gas tank sensors
you can buy all the commands you were
type
play with it these are the open ports on
just the honey pot then using for this I
had to honey pots running they're both
on Amazon and I was going to speed up a
whole bunch last night they do that so
but this is was running just a quick and
not scan of this specific honey pot so
there are some obstacles its lesson is a
pain because they're all different every
anybody's different diet doesn't like
Ubuntu after 1200 for for some reason
I'm using Ubuntu found that out the hard
way there was a dependency and need it
so I just amusing 1204 I didn't want to
limit to limit people with what I with
the code I wrote and put on github
but you and I intend to use data or you
can try to figure it out it's a shell
script which I get into too honey pot
networks that are interesting I actually
have one here which is the modern
hunting network and its really popular
and I love it was what really got me
interested in the guy Jason who wrote it
he's done a great job of bringing
together a whole bunch of different
spots and installer for a server it's
it's like basically a quick shell script
it actually he prefers to 1204 as well
for many pots and server and when you
install it provides a script that you
can put up honey pots and adjust
automatically uses HP feeds which is an
interesting it's a way to transmit data
securely to the server or to other
servers the result of it is as map you
can it's not it's not persistence at the
bottom there are connections you can see
as they happen
states and countries and states just one
big huge country to country is just
light up and little dots appear when
things happen but if you navigate away
and come back all that goes away that's
kind of what I can do stuff which is I
guess cool there's another threat map
that might seem to be the main goal of
honeypot servers and hopefully you know
the North's 11 looks great
it's awesome actually that but having
been a threat analysts
Napoli is useless to me it's it doesn't
do anything I don't know so I men's
gloves look at it though they love to
have a big screen with about that but
internet hacking attack a tribute
attribution map is actually the best mad
you can get it makes you sound like you
and you can actually get that that's
available for free though the pew pew
attack map which is I was gonna install
it on my server
maybe later so we want more
we want to be like that guy like rats
but we want to look we learn Russian but
wait and infiltrate carding forums and
get death threats over be like this guy
he's an actor but you know the character
you want to know what the attackers are
thinking or want to know what these
people are thinking these two are wanted
by the FBI won't bother with china but
we are we deal with reports that are
basically in the past reports with
government and a lot of these ones that
I've dealt with in the past they all get
list of demands thousands of domains
things that are associated with some
kind of pot that is something that all
go through these debates and I'll see
legitimate demands like microsoft.com so
you have to do a lot of busy work to get
through all this crap that stain and
it's sometimes it's really outdated they
give you they being whatever agency or
department gives you what they give you
a mess we deal with reports and company
is this is a good report but a lot of
times there this cued towards the
company there a marketing vehicle and
you can get some good intelligence but
often out there are a lot of a lot of
work on their part and time has passed
another company report we could do some
feed so probably all if you're
interested in this car thing subscribe
to blog all sorts of stuff of course
this hacker Google Google Alert doesn't
get everything correct i rly I really
get anything from this except news but a
lot of great blogs but it's still all
the past we want to be like one of the
ppl releasing the blog post the release
of the new information so we want
actionable intelligence I want to
predict the future a little bit that's
always what I thought I have my goal has
been
as a threat analysis to predict the
future and get to it before the before
they can get my organization so I goals
with his project are an easy
installation
actually covers that pretty well I was
very influential I just didn't like but
now has the goal to have statistics to
but statistics don't tell me either and
I'm doing threat analyst secure
communication I just wanted to make sure
everything was traveling in the clear
the stuff I'm using doesn't you driving
safely the stuff I'm using I'm using be
elk stack plastic surg lock / day it's
not secure naturally as do some things
on top of it
embrace new technologies like alcohol so
I wanna get useful information so the
management issues with all these honey
pot so you have forty honey pots out
there are a hundred honey pots all your
stuff is out there you have all these
different kinds of honey pots
everything's in different folders
databases should be easy to get to
but it's not so this is my initial
diagram I haven't changed it there's
that whole blog move I i dont know that
I just want some scripts that I don't
have a whole lot group and I move logs I
i many parts of the bottom final rules
I'm not sure about that either but I
have on the honey pots lock stock picks
up the blogs and does various things
with them based on filters are written
as total to secure connections basically
transparent to the system so it's the
applications that use it and then over
to the server which is wearing red is as
a law blog broker broker lock / again
runs and it's picking things up with
filters and then goes into elasticsearch
and then come on at this place also have
some scripts that which I have actually
about to get into that use other cool
stuff so it's pretty easy installation I
have this one script down here and this
these two folders right there
shell script you can see everything that
since that it does not modify it as
indeed it is great it's really easy to
configure
listen to local port and send off to
another IP to a port and keeps the
collection encrypted using Redis is a
day to broker I don't know much about it
except that it burgers data pretty well
so then lock / mix it up
iconoclastic search and this is this is
a screenshot of just the dashboard that
had built for
wanna get access the elasticsearch
database you can see in this one has got
a lot of its assets loggins I think I
chose to view 40 41 months you know I
put a server online last week in Sao
Paulo Brazil and within seconds ahead
connections is critical
got a lot of gas population some of
these are testing got Khambhat
connections I it's still actively in
progress I have filters and lodged a
shit look for certain things and then
that stuff gets pushed into
elasticsearch so that you see a proper
account of things but I of course had
the threat map map has to be there so
it's not as amazing as Norris but I'm
sure you can work with that the client
installations just as easy after you
install the server it actually writes a
client shell scripts down at the bottom
there and this client folder heads up
stop and saves in the folder and you get
instructions in your terminal how to get
that and go install any honey pots so
the scripts that have running these are
the client I have two scripts I try to
keep it minimal
I didn't want too much processing done
on the client systems have getting our
info dot tie this gets the hash right
now it's not before functionality that i
won
but the hash and information to file for
lock / to process send over to the other
system for actual processing then I have
read ttyl which as I explained earlier
to such as this ttyl files from the
hundai SSH any pot that saves it to
normal text reprocessing letter O three
ttyl just see this is what it looks like
it's just this is actually just opened a
text file this is a screenshot of that
so you can see it's the downloading
something it's a messy text file so but
it's easy to parse through that with
Python and get interesting information
that that well redundant but there's a
piece of the lock stock filter it's just
it's just text it's pretty simple their
work through some else commands what's
this green oh yeah this is my these are
those files on the server they bypassed
with lock / through a star to sit in
this folder copy files and coming and
then my python script to read these
files and processed through them so any
analysis folder I have a bunch of
different things I've got some these API
key subtext those asshole by API keys
for two things I'm using for the moment
gonna be adding more than a second so
the IRA Stoll API this reads hashes from
that file that was sent over from any
pots and sensitive IRA Stoll getting
back to results that's useful it'll be
better when I can
set up to actually send files that have
been seen yet I'm also working on
integrating malware dot com or if you
want your own could be sent box inside
your own
is that your own environment compound
reader this reads the JSON and the
laptop log files and formats for
database calorie compound reader I get
mixed up because I miss him so much and
I just read the one log file our reader
reads JSON to end the log files and
formats for debates then gasped
operators same thing using special
things like the virustotal API which you
can you can use that for free but you
have a limit of four calls per hour
which is kind of annoying so I'm using
the paid one thanks to the company also
using OpenDNS investigate which is
basically a Google search for domains
and IP addresses which is a paid thing
or you could work there and analysis
that's coming actually so this is kind
of a quick view but just looking
investigated i this is a screenshot from
Intel portion of the thing which you'll
see more of a moment it's just it this
is a SSH connection they collected and
called out to these IP is right here
over on the left side and I got some
information just who is data from
investigate who is data is this one part
of what you get from investigate I'm
looking at that I P that in some doubt
to this is the web interface of you got
to the same informations who is this
information
another view of another IP this is a
connection in and the password they
typed and
and the username I got some information
and then you can get more stuff with the
API it's all documented online its
public you could see all the demands
associated with the various network
prefixes are in progress and doing and I
a narrator which comes from sequel light
which is overpaid as I you know I'm
learning Python so it's enough work for
mother now to get everything going as it
has been but this is an active
development I'm not gonna be stopping so
keep going I'm hoping maybe other people
would be interested in contributing I'm
doing passive TNS research as well
there's a really great three passing TDs
different you can run on your system and
database or text file malware analysis
and to doubt the ability to download
malware specifically when it comes to
the honeypot actually you know but mass
downloaded all of you want to do and I
want to play log CSI cyber style gets a
red code code and download season just
been kind of lazy that's a really simple
thing just need to make its rights to
see its feet but I so you need metrics
continue to move a little faster
dashboards need searching and you need
that that threat map so I've got to that
map as you see in very exciting this is
searching I searched for a spot I got
some results this is the this is what it
looks like the Intel Poor's in its kind
of mess just let in class so it's not so
durable yet but I will sort it and it's
just give me that whois informations
that is really not a whole lot I'm
getting the login information I'm so far
I'm looking at like things like gas pipe
connections the commander types
connections I need to add in the
commanding heights
there's a lot more I can get from this
as I built it out I also have a just a
Reg txt file of all the other get
requests in basically the DUP cap mode
into a text file that works like this
you can't really read about it he look
at peak apps follow his dream of
something it's the GET request of the
interesting things trying to figure out
exactly how to make it so that this
becomes something that is you can
quickly look at it and go oh this is
what's going on down in the world so
this is where you can get it at the
school
fade so I'll actually just real quick I
think I have a seconds so you have it
open you know I demagogues so I this
morning I couldn't connect to my mind if
I can connect to it
wondering what the heck was going on and
it turns out it got the IP address
changed like on Amazon Web Services I've
never seen that happen before
kind of a pain to really get to but we
can you guys see connections coming in I
can we make it smaller portion which is
way more interesting in my opinion what
you decide screenshots of second see
connections I've got some testing those
me this morning actually led to that
stuff but there's that's not me testing
that went down there and I can look at
unsuccessful as the stage which is
useful call outs to IP addresses moment
demands I'm sorry that the screen is so
I can but this is the part that I like
but it's a mess so his mouth where that
has been found on virustotal
it's a lot of Lenox Mall where a bunch
of stuff indeed US stuff I had a link
way over there right its formatting but
you could see him go and actually go
look at the look at them ever stole Inc
well whatever you can you get the gist
of it so you can read about it all sorts
of cool stuff so I'm gonna keep adding
to it hopefully become more awesome and
something more useful I wanted to become
a threat to you something that you can
use in your organization or your
personal life or whatever you want maybe
get some statistics but also to add is
more pretty metrics because people do
like that and actually is very useful to
get a quick overview of what you think
people are going to think I'm almost
done I have two questions what's the
last web framework it's like django but
it's much smaller yeah it's a it's
pretty easy to work with
go back to this thing better than anyone
available just go ahead and take it and
use it do what you want with it it's all
right there it's very easy to work with
I'm gonna keep on updating I i i keeping
committing almost every day one issue is
of course if you don't have to
investigate access or whole API key
those things will work yet for you but
I'm gonna add other stuff I don't think
it's right to have just things that are
cost money so I like he should be able
to pull from our dot com L W R dot com
which is a complete sandbox online but i
dont server
don't have an API really available but
we have a awesome in turn I think he's
an employee now but he's written an API
for it so he's like he's allowing me to
take that and imported into this recall
who I will thank you very much