ok yeah alright this is last table
talking tonight we're going to talk
about how to use breakable dependencies
for managed so it will be a stable talk
brought to you by too unstable people we
know you love us as usual standard
disclaimers apply
represent our work yeah this is just our
incentives yeah that's ok I'm Stacy
banks so I'm going to be talking about
the red team approach my background is
heavily Unix Linux based policy and
telling people how they're just wrong
and of course you know a girl and I'm
and honey I'm representing the blue team
I have a lot of experience complete team
stuff inside environments operations
product security educational so
talk about library reuse so it's a good
thing right
using libraries however what's not so
good about him you have increased attack
surface and you have no clue what so
labor ears include things like open
source software to burn a lot of
examples of that commercial libraries
are not just open source and also
primarily internal versus external
pressure miss you guys are and security
for those stuck around me to that man
database level during the fund support
stuff that we don't want to do thank you
very much thank you but also looking at
this this is this is the difference in
approach between going slow on attack
taking the red team outside approach
where you can either have full knowledge
due to being part of it having a
complete open inside into it or acting
as an actual attackers think what you
can find on your own during your open
source and tell during a network spans
and see just what role as hacker would
actually get those actually that tends
to be better since it gives you a full
sense but
not many places actually like red
teaming because they don't want their
ship broke so it tends to be more of a
blue team with the code don't mess up
anything so you can balance that
everybody need pushing management to do
red team that's where the fun that so
you guys know talked about the actual
history the lovely libraries are they
use well we know things when we don't
know the attack services and
vulnerabilities come out they do things
like a break the internet so everybody
remembers her plead and prove that you
see the heads going yeah I don't remind
me I don't remember that and then Bosch
oh my god literally going to do about
that yet again another thing here we go
more stuff affecting the people but we
really should have vulnerabilities this
should strictly be you know commercial
people but that's also an impact to its
not just open source right by other
libraries there were something that be
safe for instance
oh that's been back toward by the feds
those people aren't surprised by that
but still it's it's a backdoor in its
attack service into your software or
your network much like the proposed an
exception because we all know you have
they know what they're doing
remembers the OMB attack
it's not my fault no so we're gonna pick
on OpenSSL because everybody yeah
everybody loves OpenSSL it's it's
everybody's favorite open source library
because its security all sorts of
encrypted transactions for money banking
and its purchases
password so nobody actually added to the
code actually really went through in
like checked it major did you know
either before people came out before
before her plea came out it's still just
had numerous health benefits people just
horribly very right well it still having
problems so now at least libri SSH SSL
is coming out with with the OpenBSD guys
but still it's nobody's going to OpenSSL
right now and stopping gripping their
traffic and something that's just a test
so it's always a balance and much like
OpenSSL there's still been continued
get more vulnerabilities that are out
there beyond just the huge branded ones
that we've had so far and they're not
alone
they've just gotten the most news
nothing like a boner ability with its
own website yes and please whoever is
branding them stop letting your
five-year-old name level
what happens when you have the ability
in your library what you do and you can
take some more and then eventually come
down over the panic ok now what
let's look and see what's affected right
let's see if we actually use the code
code accessible how are actually you
know using the library how were impacted
before you know after the panic settles
the other thing you have to do you have
to think of a correct way to respond to
the public because everybody wants to
fix the vulnerability right near the end
of the day after it came out have you
fixed it was released a patch up so no
fix it but you have to have a proper
response for legal and things like that
procedure it's a necessary evil yeah I
know and just as guidelines for
everything
do it just do it so from a red team
perspective however when you gonna do
when it comes along with it i mean
you're gonna go after them to your gonna
take it because you know what dennis is
gonna be freakin flower
yeah we have an opportunity that could
span weeks depending on who exactly the
vendor is that has the issue and how in
denial they are and going on so
researchers so they're within their time
doing that we can leverage it as an
attack vector ya go there
utilize what researcher is looking to
add more towards injection really get in
here already I'm really has an advantage
because the team you just gotta get on
what you're at the mercy I'm at the
mercy of you so much so so after the
panic
Cincinnati you run your incident
response rate shelter after work so you
going to response mode rate you and your
instant response boat so while you're in
response but what do you do you write
your security now CBS escorts to make
sure everybody knows very the
vulnerability and really hope it's not
an easy task easy to break
remote exploit doesn't require a hope
it's not one of those usually somewhere
in the middle and then you go into this
is on particular product side website
you want to get things patched as much
as you can but you wanna make sure your
legal basis do
they're worrying and attempting to get
their vendors to respond well patch
management is being attempted you want
to go out there and yeah I swear this
works too and real-life such a situation
you know we should be doing regular red
team against our networks are you should
be attempting to do these exploits when
they come out to see how are you better
know whether this has actually been
patched if your attempts if you're
trying to do something internally while
you're waiting for your vendor to
finally resolve the issue is something
internally so have the red team's go out
there do they're scanning the attack
vectors because honestly it's gonna be
awhile ya gonna have over here paintings
and we have plenty of networks to play
with yes so once everything's pat pat
we're safe know we have built in
libraries are included with other
products director other applications and
in this case they don't usually a parade
their libraries with every rap so a lot
of ways the rivets oh yeah you still
have to go back and review and if it's a
previous Rev know you have the courage
exploit that's possibly got its own
website you might have other things you
have to fix as well so that still needs
reviewing testing inventory what had
this running that app what is running
that other products that for example
OpenSSL they don't necessarily use the
library on your computer so we didn't
link to a while ago here it's compiled
off somewhere else it's already in the
package so you know I think you know
ok well that's it's a lot of things you
know about you being a major web server
would be impacted by that so
but it was great I mean it's so easy for
red team if you are if you have a
product that they've internalize they
haven't included in theirs and they have
to update their software so they're not
just running off at the latest greatest
on your you know hopefully regularly
patch system especially at work
production this energy is an another
factor that is gonna stick around after
you have patched the actual operating
system and you're feeling all nice and
safe and sound in your little you know
blue team world and especially
management but management and general oh
yes check catches replied check ok we
bought the shit out ya know you have no
we can do if those vendors have not
updated their particular software and it
can be worse because you can we all know
vendors
yes so yeah it's just it takes to do it
well that's how many places actually
bother with doing you know maintaining a
whole software image they look
third-party applications that are
included so that they know oh yeah this
one isn't running the supplied by West
base so we definitely need to make sure
that we're getting an update from them
if they haven't done anything out and in
the meantime we should probably do some
proactive work most places don't again
making it really easy and even those who
do sometimes they've got so much work
that they're backlogged in their
soldiers there's companies out there try
to keep up with all these they do an ok
job the only company that really does
especially for all right you've tried to
patch everything and you realize you're
in a panic but you know what
ok we patched everything we still have
vendors not doing so this is Ben out the
exploits been out long enough now and
the script kiddies are so you need to
have to look at things like network
blocking calling me land ports whatever
you need to do to configure it and turn
it off and find a way to stop the
traffic either through configuration
files
this is all while you're waiting for a
vendor response you're like ok already
get it to me this is silly you guys noon
and then catching that when it comes out
so there's enough companies out there
who like you to patch every day you know
we always get like I'm to slash you know
that exploit every other yeah you don't
need those now you're set
tricking users need to educate users to
we need to tell them hey guys so I know
as it becomes more popular there's going
to be more vulnerabilities because
there's more people I can fuck with yeah
yeah yeah and I mean windows still has a
monthly 12 radovan one but you know
everybody's got their although it when
there's another no windows but office is
another regular weekly Excel you know
the financials are well yeah and then
PowerPoint PowerPoint so does everybody
want to ride my slides and yours
who wouldn't want this site are you
I was looking back I like you so the
whole prevention and remediation should
review its it's not very popular if it
was they were having better you know
quality assurance and renew we won't
have quite as many vulnerabilities one
would assume yeah especially when
quality assurance sometimes just doesn't
exist
you know at that point you wait for the
newest
update to be put out and you take a look
at it because you know well you've got a
good amount of people that are willing
to be guinea pigs and go ahead and
upgrade everything to latest greatest as
well as people hold back there's gonna
be holes in whatever you know the new
like to point out anything so you got
there and you try it
absolutely i mean in the thing is it's
with the amount of code people support
and Amanda libraries open source
libraries that people just hole-in-one
here in one there and they just do it
together in your own ok well let's get
it all the work great Kiwi audit first
10 we already released it secure a
production
no wait wait wait well you know it's a
pretty safe right maybe ok I I wouldn't
call that QA I just say it's secure it's
a it's ensuring the quality testing but
it's not quality assurance quality the
vulnerability veto so do with this and
test your code you guys know I didn't
because we just i kno
the world would be
and just remember