and I think it to talk yesterday I think
actually had some very good
representation right now this is my
first ever contact list and I'm like to
think so far so what the song is about
generally we're gonna talk a little bit
about how random generators are
implemented in some cases how to predict
those things I'm gonna release a tool
that will help facilitate that reduction
and we can talk about how you can
leverage the predictability of some
random generators into actual attacks
against real-world systems and unless
they're going to wrap things up with a
little bit of an explanation of how you
can mitigate this kind of predictability
how can you avoid your orange is being
protected and people attacked me so I'm
not going to tell you I'm going to
assume that everyone here knows not to
use ran to generate their their private
keys to private keys need to be like
strongly cryptographically secure so I'm
assuming that everyone uses SSL or
something reasonably decent to do that
no one probably rights Python little
python script to generate the properties
I sent that using a strong security and
I'm not gonna talk about school attacks
it is possible that you can have Cisco
anomalies in Orangi that will you know
an attacker could leverage for example
if you had a gambling website it would
be pretty irrelevant if the numbers that
you generated had some Cisco anomaly
that an attacker could be like oh I can
if I felt like this and I make millions
of dollars from you so there definitely
are ways that there could be problems
like that but it's not the kind of thing
that really focusing on very much so
before we really get into things going
to cover a little bit I'm gonna assume
that you know basically nothing about
random number generators are a little
bit about the difference between
cryptographically secure and not enough
to secure loans as you're told that
before we get into the rest of the talk
so completely secure our energies are
characterized by three properties right
the first of which is the most obvious
they must be unpredictable so given any
number of outlets from the orangey you
must be impossible to say what the next
one will be that's probably the most the
most evident thing about security the
second one is a little bit stranger if
someone is able to compromise your
system so they have total control of
everything they can make the RGA out
they want they can completely it still
must be impossible for them to recover
prior values output by the RNG it really
bad for breaking your system in recovery
RSA private key generator last week so
far from secure on geez you can't then
that needs to be impossible and lastly
there are statistical requirements are
not going to get into but suffice it to
say it must be fairly difficult to
distinguish outlets from such a
cryptographically secure our energy from
just ran about it right so if you're you
when you look at this point I don't know
if this is just the cosmic microwave
background or what or if it's actually a
random number generator should be it
should be really hard to tell the
difference
nonproductive guarantees fail in one of
these three categories either you can
predict the following numbers you can
recover prior ones or they're very
obviously not truly random so for
example one might always out but even
numbers even if it's unpredictable it
still always even so obviously that's
not just like a random thing it's it's
an output from some kind of typically
most actual oranges you're likely to use
that are not secure bail in at least two
areas in many cases they fell in all
three so they'll be clearly they're not
really random their predictable and you
can recover profits that's pretty rough
and the real problem here is that while
languages and platforms provide a lot of
different ways to generate or injuries
they are almost always not secure about
a fault usually you have to learn more
about security and you have to reach for
the tools to generate secure private
secure unpredictable random numbers
almost always their fault and I i say
that to the extreme that I am unable to
find a language that by default gives
you can secure R&G almost always it is
something you can usually fairly easily
Tripoli predict and doctors can
definitely use this if you're doing
something like generating session IDs
with a truly critical value that's
obviously a problem hopefully not doing
something that obvious but there are
more subtle ways that you can you can
use not guarantees so we're going a
little bit of a demo for the uninitiated
you don't know anything about see this
just that there is a default see random
number generator and so you can call us
around and you kind of initialize it
with a value
to get a value from it so this just see
the thing with some input that i'm gonna
ask you for that you know I haven't
there's no sleight of hand going on here
and then I'm gonna put 50 values from it
and we're going to a little
demonstration with particularly here and
I'm not standing way and I like in the
middle of the night alright this is what
it was all me I could do that I'm coming
back and you can probably tell so what
you throw out a number that is an
unsigned integer and don't try to
undercut me or something and always take
a number
anybody any number
alright so many numbers that are based
on the 727 immunity to the disease are
nonsense here to do in the Windows
command prompt come with us
carpet alright for season 2 I'm gonna
talk about here you can see he helped
train for it here in a sec is the name
of your underwear of the kind of
Microsoft's compiler now you'll notice
here that I copied the first three
Valleys not sure to be a little
disconcerting has a lot to predict the
dot exe thing just kills me knows that
this is the same values right the ones
that follow so I said you got these
three numbers the next one's going to be
one thousand eleven thousand 53 and sure
enough 7053 is in fact there is in fact
this number in this is
should be kind of distance learning to
you unless you turn your life around
just obviously not the scary but I mean
with three outputs you can predict not
just the subsequent 10 but subsequent
hundred or user moved everybody there
will ever be out so once you have three
you know every song though every
predicted for the rest of time and
that's kind of an issue and it's not
remotely unique to the Visual Studios
randon see this is a really call it a
problem across basically all non-secure
Angie's once you know a little bit about
it usually are less than people suspect
you can predict all future once and
that's kind of an issue so in this
particular case was work I promise it
won't be a lot of math alright I'm gonna
go through the question everybody calm
down so no one's run for the door that's
good so acts in this case is just an
outfit from the oranges simple enough
right sex offenders the accident was one
of the next hour so all this is the next
outfit from the orangey is just whatever
the last one was time some constant a
plus some constancy modulus some
constant and that should be cause
because that means if you have any
output you just beat it through this
thing in a loop and you can just keep
doing it for everything that you can get
the next one of the last that long after
that and so on and so forth
time and that's these are constants here
and there are trivially findable with
reverse engineering or they're usually
fairly often they're just documented
just read through the Java documentation
and they say hey are and uses those
constants here they are and you can just
beaten into this thing and predict the
future once these are generally called
when you're hungry until generators
which is quite a mouthful some refer to
them as LCDs and they're used in the
defaults for everything from here and in
C and C++ to PHP 10 next end in Java the
mice equal one uses a fairly similar
mechanism and all of them have this
trivial predictability in addition to
that they also have obviously by
statistical characteristics because
those are points generator from LG and
they just make lines
three-dimensional space like you can
just pick some points and they just make
it on the line so obviously he just
grabbed some outlets from it as very
poor system characteristics that is
obviously not true there and if I get
injured he doesn't like that there are
of course other things that are not a
cure but are not LCDs are common when
you may have heard of emerging twister
the cloud of points here is generated
with Python this random which is a
Mersenne Twister implementation and so
it obviously looks a bit more and it is
like has better statistical gold is not
going to get into what exactly that
means but suffice to say it doesn't make
a bunch of lines but they're still
predictable you need a few more news
after twenty four outputs to predict
future ones which that certainly makes
some attacks not feasible but for sure
their situations where you can still get
624 output and their other ones like
added feedback which is restored this
weird thing that you go to use it as he
tried to trust me so to release the
exciting presentation so you don't have
to do all the things because it's not
quite as trivial as I made it seem
earlier with that thing usually they
shift away a bunch of bits in an effort
to obfuscate things and they tended to
modulus and if it's PHP the devs have no
idea what they're doing so they just
make you some random nonsense verse so I
made it to a dozen for you currently
supporting PHP Java Eclipse II
species randomized sequel so that's a
fair Friday I plan on adding more that's
the future astronauts because it's kind
of a big like people think they're
making stuff more secure when the user's
interests which is not true so I'll
probably Python next and give me a bunch
of other things like into your and thats
foresight on github there that link will
be at the end as well so if you want to
take a picture of whatever you can but I
appreciate that did not reserve program
like using Python libraries do things so
there's also a command line interface
called for C which is in that same
repository so if you wanted to for
example predict the output from the R
and R function in Gillette CSIS a decent
person sharing lol I know they can
follow this with with gcc I see they're
using radar so I know I've got his out
what's going on with the next one as
well you can stop in to see liner a life
is this command line interface you say
and our data show in the output and give
you all of you shop with something
that's you know hopefully fairly handy
for you
PHP has you know it has like there and
function takes like an upper and lower
bounds even say like I want numbers
between one hundred so if you have that
situation just put data are 100 figure
it out if you want to limit the output
which you probably do because otherwise
you get that gigantic stream of school
and stuff for the US you can just look
at it with that the hundred and by pure
coincidence happy for instance during
this kind of predictability like
requires that you basically implement
the orangey that they are using in
whatever language you're using so you
can also just passes seed and get off
your loans if you just happened at the
scene
hopefully don't open it was given away
the seed but it's just a nice looking
out there and we'll see actually a case
where someone does get with this in a
second right now so examples from the
wild actual the sexual stuff that people
have done again I'm gonna get walk to
this something that you don't know
anything about code PHP good if you
carry PHP terrible so again much like to
see there's kind of this restaurant or
and then going on in PHP and you can see
today seemed random with this guy does
this real code it was not been patched
so slight break this new stuff but this
is used to generate a capture and it was
fairly widely use like you can have a
schedule things a little bit but like I
mean there were i did some searches and
it was like a few thousand websites that
is used this as their capture and it is
completely worthless because they go
okay we're gonna see the random number
generator with the time and then they
generate Randall Luthi I kinda doubt it
was a bunch of crap and they make a URL
which ends with the time that they used
in the sea which is not not as good as
problematic so you don't have to use
Python for this you can just drop the
thing in and there you go you just say
around and I know the seeds you put in
the time that they used as the seed and
you're done and I'll give you all the
future ones they patch this one's before
I talk to them about it they pass this
one's very recently and they said we're
gonna remove the seat heater and that's
not as dumb as AM I seeing because PHP
employees
around with the combination of the
processor I D in time and some stuff
that you can't predict but they're still
generating the values with rand which
means all you need to do is break one
captured by hand and you recover the
state of the orangey and then use
predict our future and that's like bob
one spot on so you just say basically
from your side obviously I'm poor and
ran from outputs and then the outputs
and it will give you all the future once
again that doesn't actually solve the
problem I give them another patch
unfortunately they want to target 55
which doesn't really have a like
built-in security things I said using
your and wishes I guess as good as you
can get there now see one that's less
bad this is used in kind of a pastebin
style things like you upload files and
it gives you like a URL that's that's
kind of the access control for the side
because like I don't people have to make
a counselor again but also everything's
not really public like you you can't
there's nothing good will I crawled out
or anything so what they do here is they
just call Rand ZAR and aloo and a
modulus it by the the link they've got a
list of these letters and they just say
we're gonna car and on his letters and
there's obviously some logic that I cut
out that prevents you from selecting
previously made obviously you could run
you could happen to generate one that
was already used but they were smart
enough to actually do that but clearly
that's actually work because all I have
to do is upload one thing see the URL
but I get back what letters were chosen
in our everyday R&G in the future once
that's again kind of a problem once a
valid one thing to the file I can
remember the URL of everybody else that
ever will upload it so again just see
importer and R&R from out but you're
seeing a pattern here there's a flight
here that you can say output module is
so if you just know the sterile and
that's always going to be 52 it's just
like upper and lower case letters and
then like there you go so you just stick
that in there in your sleep is not care
about see then so how do you prevent
prevention and this is pretty low
hanging fruit and you crazy like packing
their stuff and I found like race
conditions on their IDs and like it's
just I looked I did some get up searches
random shows the first few things like
everyone messes this up and I was doing
the master make them more like trying to
find a little later but the problem here
is that people inadvertently a lot
unpredictability I think that's like the
greater problem right they they don't
really think about it and they just see
the specs it doesn't have to be right
there is like well whatever the specs as
used to generate random values as gotta
be uniformly distributed across this
range right is not a secret anything
it's not a secret people treat like you
don't need YouTube Google+ Karen G
the problem is your implementation may
often implicitly require the
unpredictable for example suppose you
have a system that generates user IDs
within some range and just uses like
empty right reasons and 24 out but it's
a few but it's not like enough to
actually prevent me from recovering
anything so what happens when your
system's about injuries or I D I predict
what the user ID is going to be a nice
in your request without user IDs at the
same time that you're about to generate
it is there is condition I have no idea
probably your testers have no idea
probably no one ever tested for that
because that's crazy nonsense because
nobody nobody thinks about what if they
predict my number generator and then
they put in an idea tech like that just
one more convoluted nonsense but it's
like definitely doable like that's
that's an interesting avenue of attack
that i think is like entirely unused now
because people really consider the
practical is treated like an academic
exercise when I just close to people
a response that I got almost verbatim
from one person was I don't know how
practical that attack would be right
he's using random you'd like I'm like
well that's going to really easily
predictable and he says that's almost an
academic exercise no one really knows
like there's no tool to do that and
other is so he can I get home and I'm
going to actually after this release at
all so the the solution here is fairly
straightforward as a user you wherever
you can if you haven't been smart and
found out that you can use to secure our
energy just don't do that just using
energy and let you know that you can't
because seriously there's probably some
nonsense I can do with race conditions
or i mean
there's just no like you have no I think
they're so hard to test that sort of
thing are you gonna test like what
happens when I D as you sent that is
supposed to be generated a second that's
just crazy so basically a reply from
someone to do this is just more and more
difficult on Linux you can read from W
random an independent received your
items just better are random is like a
BSD thing ran devices OpenSSL round ass
on Windows apparently I'm really used it
but it's there are implications
randomized pretty fast open a cell does
this pretty quickly that your enemies
and fortunately the slower but I mean
just profiling and see what's going on I
hesitate to say it but otherwise use
your sister if you've been charging you
absolutely cannot use across from Sakura
wanna
twister a bunch out what's predicted has
very nice tits what characteristics so
that's probably your next best bet to
compare security but seriously things
and there's the oral bottom check it out
star things you know content they have
any questions questions I've explained
everything perfectly sure at the moment
yes but it depends on the orangey for
LCDs in principle you don't at all thats
Telugu version 1.1 is just that cuz it's
super easy is basically just you advance
the you just feel like an underscore
where you don't know about you and
there's no reason that one or more
problematic because they're just like an
array of values and it's a little weird
but with like LCDs and some of the other
ones it would it would be no problem at
all tonight
I would have to think about the
implications of it you could not buy
just trying like you could say basically
assume there's one thing between it and
see if it works out and i mean Iran's in
less than a second so I mean probably
could afford to do it you know for
assuming you have some ideas not like
there are a million between you know if
you know like probably the only like 10
or so between it for some of its I mean
you're you're basically brute forcing
like to do the 16 which is just like
nothing on a modern computers I mean
it's not a big deal to try that so
that's definitely something that kind of
like you know less restrictive
interfaces future is very similar i
focused on getting like a wider range
like platform supported rather than like
one thing and being able to afford the
yeah for some of them you definitely can
also go
homer in for hackers as a previous