an introduction to real-world
cryptography
cover today in a relatively short amount
of time this is a somewhat ambitious
talk and that about 25 minutes to cover
a huge amount of information so I'm
gonna go kinda quick and I'm going to do
my best not to his entire process here
so I A
independent security researcher and
software developer more than fifty years
experience
security has been a major focus of my
job my entire career and one of the real
people that has a real passion for both
development and for security and all too
often there is a gap between those two
worlds so anytime I have the chance I
tried to break I try to bring these two
communities together so today
I hope everybody here is one walk away
with a better understanding of
cryptography is a very challenging world
but very rewarding area to study also
think I'm hoping that you'll end up with
a better respect for the care that's
needed for dealing with cryptography
because of the difficulties that come
with this talk is about giving you a
brief introduction this doesn't mean
that after the stalk you would sit down
and write a NSA approved chat
application or no sit down on your
laptop and break RSA what you should be
able to do is be able to talk
intelligently with other people when the
topic turned to cryptography
enough of the basics to understand
what's going on
fully you will then choose to do more
research on your own
the talk we can learn more about the
topic so the goal here is to impart as
much knowledge as I possibly can in 25
minutes on this one is important in this
is something that everybody needs to
understand
cryptography just the first talked about
what he gets for too many ppl
cryptography is seen as a magical fairy
dust can sprinkle on to something that
wouldn't do it with security I think we
all know the doctor when you just wake
cryptography often does more harm than a
dozen good it provides a false sense of
security and it provides a layer of of
obscurity and it's hard to understand
what a system or protocol is even doing
photography can be a great and powerful
tool when used correctly when used as
part of a system that is properly
designed proper design though is far
more challenging than most people
realize there is much that must be
understood even seemingly simple design
properties if you don't understand how
things in iraq can end up exposing fatal
flaws in the system can anyone hear
guess the most common reason that a
cryptosystem fails
sensible people making steaks almost all
over almost all of them are simple
avoidable mistakes that occurred because
they didn't have a solid understanding
of what they were doing
I'm not blaming people that have made
these mistakes because they happen but
there's a lot to learn there's a lot to
understand when you're putting together
a system like this
anytime that you don't talk of either
interactions that are not obvious but
you have to understand it to make the
system more correctly
almost all of the significant failures
over the last several years have been a
direct result of somebody making an
avoidable mistake this list covers all
of the key topics you need to understand
when discussing crypto
attention here you walk away with enough
understanding of the stuff to hold up
your end of a conversation so it's like
that encryption for symmetric or secret
key encryption algorithms fall into two
basic types stream ciphers and block
ciphers since I first are fairly simple
they are typically very fast and they're
fairly easy to understand they really
aren't that complicated generally a
stream cipher is a strong
a random number generator where you use
the key as the seed
the output that it generates which is
referred to as a g-string it explored
with a plain text 0424 text it's a very
simple operation
so the RNG random number generator
creates a shaky stream that is the same
link as a plain text in function this is
very similar to a one-time pan that was
in some cases extremely successful
during ww2 in shortly after and in other
cases failed completely
the problem the one-time pad is your
message can only be the size of the key
and since you're keen your message or
the same size makes it kind of hard to
transmit your key is if you have a
secure me to Trenton Vicky Pope you can
just use your message on the topic of
our C four was probably the single most
popular general purpose stream cipher in
use and it's a great example today of
what happens when an algorithm fails and
how it can cause issues many years after
the fact our c4 happens to be very very
fast because of its speed and its ease
of implementation there's actually
challenge a while back trying to fit in
a hierarchy for implementation works at
a very simple algorithm because of this
became extremely popular especially in
the world of tell us but while it was
becoming popular being noticed an estate
back to 1995 by then it was understood
it was no problem is nobody understood
how far they want
in 2001 a major attack was released that
allowed the other primaries or Farsi for
web to be easily broken after the attack
in 2001 it was largely considered
insignificant by the Economic Community
it was broken it was boring now moved on
to other things so for many years
our C four was basically ignored there
was no real research going on there were
attacks released in 2005 2007 but they
weren't that significant and like I said
for the most part the academic community
just simply moved on and didn't care
anymore unfortunately nobody else was
paying attention to this pls continue to
use our c4 as did all kinds of systems
across the world it was still incredibly
popular despite the fact that was going
to be fought in 2011 said the attack was
announced which was attack against
CBC mode as implemented
the best short-term fix that was
available at the time was to stop using
ASM transfer all your traffic over to
our C four which is exactly what this
points most Internet traffic was our c4
kept it just known algorithm was
encrypting everything the one good thing
that came out of this is it put or c4
back on the radar for the academic
community they realize they still need
to look at this one it wasn't dead yet
early days it was known that there were
certain biases in the first few bites of
the G string certain values came up more
often in 2013 the academic community
finally finished the way you think there
is actually pattern
the beginning of the key string if that
was done correctly you just see random
there should be no parent should be no
discernible anything the fact that
you're seeing this nation that there is
a clear pattern to it being generated
the biases that were thought to be only
the first you might actually extend
throughout the quiche with enough
connections it possible for an attacker
to recover the key and decrypt
get back to the plaintext in general in
cryptography it's rare for an algorithm
to fail but when it does it tends to be
catastrophic r/c force a great example
of that
block ciphers are in some ways simpler
and more complex where ships are for can
least theoretically handle plain text of
any size block ciphers can only encrypt
up to their blocks ice for a yes that's
a hundred twenty eight deaths 16 points
that's all you can encrypt show to make
it useful to go beyond that we introduce
block notes which are a higher level
operating they impact they they define
how blush reflected in how one block
affects others around it the most common
block mode is CBC or cipher block
chaining for the first block user random
I V or initialization vector exercise
that was a plain text before performing
the encrypt operation for subsequent
blocks it uses decipher text of the last
block as its Ivy this way every block is
different you don't get patterns in your
data there are many many different modes
they're used some are good some are bad
here see this image before the lights
this is for those that don't know what
you get when you encrypt a bitmap of
talks in ECB mode ECB mode is basically
just encryption operation performed 16
nothing is carried forward nothing is
altered nothing has changed
ECB mood is actually dangerous in many
if not most cases it's something to be
avoided if at all possible what you're
seeing here is the amount of structure
that is being leaked for Sun some types
of data structure can reveal what's
actually in there as you can see here at
one point sometime back I was doing some
research on snapchat as an interesting
note they use a hard-coded key in the
application to encrypt their images
before they're being sent to the server
their images are encrypted and ECB mode
when the sued snapchat for misleading
customers about the security of the
application they act the FTC actually
use my research to prove that snapshot
was aware of the problems and win they
became aware of it
proving that they have been like four
years in general you should never use
ECB mode for anything it's dangerous
whenever possible you should be using
GCM note if you're free market Royce
doesn't provide GCM CBC with an HMAC is
a acceptable alternative but not quite
as strong
on the public key crypto we have
asymmetric or public key encryption this
is my favorite area tour because allows
you to do things that if you stop and
think about is really quite fascinating
being able to exchange encrypted
messages without revealing a key is a
remarkable thing I can send you
something and nobody else has inability
to see it unless they possess the same
private key you do modern public key
encryption also falls in two basic types
and they are primarily defined by what
hard math problem you have to solve to
completely shattered that for me it is
so clean so simple
the concepts behind our assay were first
detailed unclassified research in 1973
four years later the concept was
independently rediscovered published
publicly which leaves us with RSA RSA it
is still a key factor in chill us it is
becoming less popular because of
performance and other issues but it is
still widely used as you can see here
the math behind our assay is actually
fairly simple to encrypt you simply take
a message as a binary number raised it
to a certain value called E
in we're in is the product of two secret
prime numbers the values for CNN are
both part of the public he their public
knowledge but without knowing what to
prime numbers made up in there is no way
to complete the secret operation
take a system secures the two prime
numbers in play have to be quite large
today it's considered an in of less than
2048 bitch isn't secure easy on the
other hand is just a little bit more
complex while ECU or elliptic curve
cryptography was first developed in 1985
it's only in the last few years and it's
been in widespread use this is largely
due to various patent issues complex
topic not gonna get into it I will say
though that it has closed a sale last
four years the public Red Hat threads on
the topic are absolutely fantastic
there are implementations though
suggests curve to 5519 that are
completely unencumbered the code is in
the public domain there are no patents
are no trademarks know nothing he says
he has a major advantages over IRAs
saying the keys are smaller at the 128th
pitch security level keys are on 256
bits and links RSA at that same security
level is 3072 bets is much faster than
our essay which eliminates a lot of
scalability issues that come with it
generation is also much simpler you
don't need these huge prime numbers it
is basically a random number there is no
she was certain curves there is no
structure to it whatsoever is literally
a random number
hashing functions contacted a frequently
were block cipher scrambles data in such
a way that it can be reversed if you
know certain secret hash functions are
one-way operations there is no efficient
way of getting back to the input value
and efficient being defined as anything
less than brute force in 25 still widely
used thankfully is being phased out
secure is completely broken if you're if
and if I should not be used
sure one was designed by the NSA to
replace indy five it also broken jaw to
which was also designed by the NSA this
time to replace shot one has actually
hold up fairly well it has multiple
output prices shot shot who is also
known as shot 56 shot 34 and chopped 512
which is about to get confusing because
we now have shot three which also has
output of 256 384 512 that's the big
difference between shots which are three
ish i three in a completely different
type of structure it was selected from a
contest it was not designed by the NSA
the security level 32 is roughly
equivalent at this point I'd like to be
the best research candidate for the SHA
three competition was Blake after
another candidate one debate team came
back to it is faster than 85 and a
secure shot three with variable output
so if you're retrofitting a system that
uses him 25 it is a great option
password storage
have to decrypt a script passwords or
anything else it's plain and simple PDF
to is common it easy to implement but it
has enough memory
the big thing to take away from this one
is you've got to find a balance with his
stuff because
if you go something like a script with
the top trainers it will bring your
service to an absolute crawl so finding
the balance on how to protect passwords
is tricky I'm sure all of you know speed
kills when it comes to password hashing
29 runs a company that they build
password cracking rick's if you look at
this chart this is based off of a single
GPU system that he recently built in
millions per second indy five it is
modern GPUs can just absolutely destroy
it
this is another one of his systems a
cheap use one box and they close to
these things together for certain
unnamed alliance that want to crack
anything but he's together it's pretty
effective validating data there are
various programs DSA ECDs AEDT si than
others
these are all built on public key crypto
they allow you to verify the message is
from somebody holding a specific private
key while widely used BSA must be used
with extreme care it relies on a good
random number generator if the RNG fails
it can expose the private key on the
symmetric side there are Macs or message
authentication codes these are
effectively secret key signatures if you
know the secret key you can compute the
Mac and verify that the data when
implementing this H Mac which is a hash
based Mac using a strong hash function
a one other thing that's important to
note here is something that should
always be remembered never reuse your
Christian he's if you are encrypting
entering the Mac from the same piece of
data use different keys if you use the
same key you can reveal information
which could allow both of them to be
broken right here
an example of the DSA issue this but
Sony in 2013
community fairly hard because an issue
with Bitcoin wallet to have been
generated off of Android devices because
the random number generator was
improperly seated that reveal patterns
in the signatures next thing you know
somebody has the private key and in the
Bitcoin world if somebody has your
private key they have your money which
is exactly what happened I could spend
an hour on this one just bites off
random number generators are fascinating
topic and something that you've got to
be very very careful with the device
would give you at this point is simply
use the operating system provided random
number generator don't use usual and
generators and for the love of god don't
try to rally around if you're using some
nicks various UN used f you random not
random you r and using Windows Script
Jen random if using anything else you
doing it wrong
you want to learn more by this book this
is the single best piece of material
available today on practical applied
cryptography she does a lot of stuff out
there that goes deep into theory that
goes deep into the mass for most people
you need to know that you need to know
how to apply it that's one thing I
really like about this book there are
projects such as the underhanded crypto
contest that study different ways that
intentional floss to be introduced to
understand their impact if you want to
understand how systems are affected by
the flaws that can be introduced either
intentionally or otherwise the results
being produced by this contest are
absolutely fantastic some great material
there and what that everybody thank you
so much I think I nailed it I'm
perfectly thanks