obvious you don't have the edge in a
given to get the giggles from reported
that it does otherwise yeah I'd start
recording in order to help Jack ok yeah
you know the fun just to hang the next
generation thanks for joining us today
in the cyber frontier here is our first
Star Trek mean right and sorry for using
cyber writer I'm sure you're not too
happy about it but life goes on and that
is the last Star Trek mean presentation
so my generation remembers when
technology was complex and had certain
kinds of basic skills right frank who
are these skills were things like
reading typing in patients but but today
but today through mobility and
consumerization righty this current
generation they don't have those
requirements
gets ok to share your passcode with
people so we know better but he's so
last year when my son was to any really
didn't speak that much and then he had a
tablet he was getting in to YouTube and
other things that are on their goodwill
bility and the ability just do certain
things without needing tech support when
we put a passcode on it he learned the
pass code which is really cool but today
he still receives it out loud on that so
hard to that though is just kids are
wired to learn and if it's something
that's fun for them they're gonna do it
and they gonna get really good at it
when I think back to my youth and
frankly I used to spend a lot of time
reading these tones it had tables and
matrices in them that we're pretty
complex pretty dry in order to play
Dungeons and Dragons a little better
because an incentive had a hard time
focusing on my education because there
really was no incentive for me and
that's why we created have four kids so
you believe we're responsible teach the
next generation than you and I have a
lot of it is our responsibility to teach
this generation Internet safety best
practices and give them a safe
environment to explore step which is
science technology engineering and make
it fun to use what they're wired for
their own good
whether they like it or not so little
bit more about you know how the case was
created when it started to have you back
in 2013 I see this Tweet go out with a
few people's names on the other you see
who wanted to start thought con kids
and furlough time deep inside of me and
burn and to create a condo to do
something like something like that we
can just bring your community together
but he didn't really know what it was in
there was really no need to create a
common issue so I was thinking about
these things like swap meets in bringing
that back but I just and then when I saw
this I was like that's what you want to
do so I contacted them and was very
excited when they accepted the fact that
I could be the fifth person help
organizing this event that really kind
of spoke to me in a way being a parent
30 thoughts on board got together and
they decided they really don't want to
expand into a kids event so that fire
inside of me was burning but it kind of
went to a smoldering still wanting to do
something like this I just got home my
head for a while and wondered on it
until then one day I said so I contacted
them and they were cool with it he said
go for it and we created have three kids
in 2014 and this is the opening
ceremonies from last year in chicago the
synagogue and it was great we had a good
amount of attendance we had a lot of
kids it learned it had a lot of other
things that we had there with things
like homemade hand in their robot
garbage can and payload somewhere
between 0 and a tablet showing our
website we also were able to get a
donation from a link over the creator of
the award-winning Snap Circuits are not
obligated by contract say that I see
true and the kids had a great time
learning electrical engineering
then this year one of the things that we
were one of the kids came to me with
some friends to a scavenger hunt this
year and I think about it will come up
with something to prove that UPS and 3d
cases road we knows we put the items
that need to be found on the Arduino and
in the schedule just set it up to use
morse code of the kinda got stuck and
they need to go find it they had to
learn
Morse code teaching them to have to do
something which is kind of like a dying
skill he knows Morse code from memory
see nobody raised their hands you know
what it is but nobody knows it and
that's one of the things I want to do
kind of like revitalizing and they loved
it had a great time and here's a picture
of the wildly successful technology
destruction essentially we're teaching
them technology reverse engineering so I
remember as a kid taking apart that
large piece of furniture my parents have
they called a TV which I took the back
off and I started pulling out all the
transistors the first time I did it may
just turn the TV off and burned myself
there was no meant to around say you
should wait for those bullets to unplug
the TV it was yes they would be so I
yeah I learned some lessons and so in
this environment or even now so if you
give your smartphone or tablet or laptop
whatever don't take it apart right we're
here we're seeing take it apart
go ahead nobody is gonna we want you to
do it conceivably think one of the only
injuries with somebody who got cut but
it was so really which is a good thing
in my opinion that they got hurt I hope
you understand what a little bit more
what is hacked version foremost we we
think it's important that we're charity
registered public 513 charity so that
means that not everything that we bring
in donations thanks
the people who were out there bring in
donations to help us we're just giving
it back to the kids and it gives a
certain tax benefits because we're
really not trying to make a profit this
is really about giving back to the kids
as much as we can and again the simple
mantra this is a real takeaway someone
says oh you know what is a cricket it's
a conference for kids to teach them
Internet safety and best practices while
exploring science and technology I think
that's really the the simplest and
easiest way to explain it so that when
you get a really cool things is the
community that burning inside me to take
on it really didn't know too many people
familiar faces I really wasn't in the
community and once they start to trust
you and it does take some time they open
themselves like the kimono is wide open
you have a right to Franks kimonos gonna
be open up later so that the truth so
here we are able to partner with circles
in Econ this year so we did a lite
version of the village so parents
dropping the kids off and kids are just
exploring standing there doing stuff and
they were in a junior CTF where they
were winning prizes and had a great time
we provide incentives we gave them a
safe place to learn and we're just
basically using their natural curiosity
got the better so we were in
Indianapolis next week we're gonna be in
Ghent Belgium in partnership with which
I'm really excited about this is now
it's the first actor kids done in
another language is not English it's
gonna be in touch in French
basically useless as we speak English so
the staff speak English but all the kids
I can say you know something high in the
AM I get it I think it's really cool
that we're gonna have all the content
into French they have the content there
and even I save it securely online
presentation is gonna be done in both
languages we also partner with the folks
Grand Rapids and we're gonna be there on
October 10th on Saturday in
juxtaposition with the regular
conference of the volunteers are in this
room right now thank you for your
support is without the volunteers none
of this would happen it's everybody's
contribution that brings us together you
know now inside of you you have that
same kind of burning desire where you
want to start your own condo yuri havoc
on and you want to add this to your well
don't do it alone
use our use the lessons that we've
learned to help it make it easier for
you and there's just certain things
related to child safety and to some best
practices that we've learned that you
can also benefit from without making
things so we have a Google formats
available online
don't worry about writing this down a
president can be available to sell being
recorded just got to enjoy the
presentation for what it is now but
unfortunately that's about the length of
your entire thing to do for me to finish
it off but if you want to give me your
card today after this presentation we
can exchange to email and have a
conversation now at Hector kids having
gotten the message yet we take use
protection
very very seriously and is one of my
other kids playing a video game but we
really mean by use protection is a lot
of my training also comes from the Boy
Scouts of America of the BSA Scouter I
have to get trained every two years I
have to keep it current in order to be
so rest assured someone like me use
protection like me is also being
monitored by another organization that's
greater than for kids but some of their
principal their fundamentals adopted so
for example one of them
leadership think about it maybe if you
have the same exact meaning or somebody
has a different that really means a
two-to-one reach you
is always going to be no less than two
adults one kid where it gets indexed to
actually really protect both sides
already so if you ever have a one-to-one
situation it's your word against theirs
and more than likely the kids words
gonna be taken to be the true so that's
why we do it's to protect the adults as
well then you get the situation where
the restrooms
it's really kind of you go into a
restroom there's a kid you walk around
you week if you're in the rest as a kid
you hurry up and finish the business and
get out you know right now when it comes
to volunteers we're very very careful
about the volunteers as well you have to
be vetted by someone on the board or
someone thats on staff in order to
become a volunteer for kids online form
it's always a bit but it's not public we
don't want to have to go through and
every single person it's really true
either someone that knows somebody from
your way more than a year and not just
once a year Derby Conn I think you're
pretty good person I trust you will not
that simple
somebody that we don't really have
someone involved in the community if
they're doing something with a
third-party organization like a soccer
coach organization every year and makes
them go through their willing to write a
letter to say yes we've known Bob for
five years and bobs great around the
kids and Bob could then potentially be a
happy to hear this guy may not qualify
photography there's another thing that
we have a strict policies on as well
why we do have staff photographers and
parents have phones we do communicate
with the parents in the beginning of the
conference and it's really important
that if they're totally picture of their
tire oh and explain what that word means
shortly
other kids are other Tyros are out of
range or wait until that you know it's
just there kiddo just gonna change it
because we don't want anyone to be used
in any situation of doing anything that
they did not have any amount and is very
easy these days with socially correct so
even the staff photographers they might
take frontal photos as well as their
instructed to take more back or side
shots so that we can use that in any
like documents or on their website to
show people like a little on the tires
are having this particular example
nobody knows who the styro is probably
maybe his friends siblings and parents
or relatives right nobody is there busy
doing something that's really cool has
the latest circuit to shoot a propeller
off and then he's got an Arduino in
front of probably did the Morse code to
sorry there is another example is a
curly hair tire oh we don't know if
that's a boy or girl is a great perfect
example but there's a parent helping the
kids with project so moving on to
something else as cool as 3d printing is
one this year we decided to do something
a little fun and we printed their badges
for them so we sat down with designer
bag was actually but then it really
worked out and give them the the glider
symbols on their thoughts but then we
created a simple specifically for them
and it's called so Tyrone means novice
your learner but we don't want to use
that so we went with Cairo which is a
genuine word and
when I was trying to figure out what the
symbol can look like I came across the
arrow which is a Nordic let her meaning
shrink warrior and its cold tire
to finish off the look forward and
circles grow but now in addition to
shrink them warrior the circle
represents the unity of the hacker
community
laugh and his never-ending thirst for
knowledge so I think it's really cool
and it belongs to the tire there's
badges do not have this if your child or
tarlow speaker you get this on your
speaker bad it's pretty cool stuff I get
chills talking about and it's upside
down so when you saw the previous upside
down since when they hold their bad
you're looking at it it's a bright to
them secret codes of upside down they
don't know what it is gone so why you
where kids so if you've heard of DEFCON
kids which is now roots asylum great
conference the opportunity to go and I
was guided around I had a tour guide
with me he did not let us wander alone
before the kids wake conference but
they're only once a year in Vegas kids
is based out of San Jose another great
but they're also once a year in San Jose
so what's the common denominator their
west coast so pack for kids is really
intend to be global we're building a
global do you see a more familiar brand
whatever you think of the idea here is
to have it available to anyone who wants
to do this
globally
so we started in Chicago we went to
Indianapolis going to Grand Rapids and
we're going again
wanna do something also in your area let
us now will talk to you now think that's
labeled to hear some of the content that
we do have tickets to the presentations
they're all the ideas really have youth
based presentations or someone who's a
new speaker or an established speaker or
just has a really good idea to share it
that's what we're about
but we don't have aged women so
regardless if you're eighty your welcome
to present at how the kids if it's
appropriate for that age group but we do
encourage younger speakers because we
just feel that generation gap generation
is it gonna be a lot stronger we have
activity station so this is the stem
activity station but we can do anything
for Python for kids
village spider-man he told you gonna be
doing like crypto in number theory be
allowed to just hold a wide range of
things and we try to change it up so
every year we keep the Snap Circuits and
stuff that we know people over the
terrors love like technology destruction
village I know I like clothes and stuff
but we can we change it up so it's
interesting
workshop will do workshops and he was
gonna workshop to share in Chicago so we
do workshops and those are more
concentrated the activity stations are
really designed to be about 20 minutes
or 90 these are usually at least two
hours and then we have a mandatory safe
and secure online presentation here is
Robert Wagner the board members
delivering the same safe and secure line
visitation alliance with ice and he's
talking about specifically here
anti cyberbullying that kind of talk to
our Internet safety and best practices
no back to this young man so you guys
know he's speaking here i think is
actually speaking right now he was our
very first keynote room appropriate to
deliver their very first keynote and a
nine year old focused on cyber
protection for kids and I was great it
was so well received the kids loved it
ago and she's pretty cool and they were
younger older than him there like that's
kind of what we want we wanted a night
that fire inside of them that might have
been smoldering and in this particular
recycling images this one in the stem
station Kiro is learning how to build a
catapult popsicle sticks of glue gun
rubber band and a plastic spoon it
sounds like what they're actually
building this be built these catapults
and we didn't know this was
unanticipated when they started having
some sort of balling up little pieces of
paper and then having a competition who
can shoot I thought that was pretty cool
actually using what they built and then
they get to take it home and the
marshals or whatever it there so early
and so this was the sheets we provide a
sheet we have some instruction just kind
of step through a good idea of what
needs to do what they need to do and in
this particular case if you see like the
gear and that little circle there again
going back to Scouting if they're going
to do something so if they're scout and
you can also earn achievements towards
their standard just saying hey what the
heck am a certified or registered call
it counsel in Illinois counselor in
Illinois and become the main tour later
which just means of projects with this
magazine I know they did this in this is
what the qualifications are the parents
love it is a kid is good to go
if you have a question I gotta take it
later cuz the time but definitely in the
workshop will face teaching them web
application pen testing he's using all
the tools a regular web at Penn test
adverts we're running and the kids are
learning how to analyze all the traffic
and stopped the request and then monitor
the response he gave me challenge after
the course is over he said whoever would
be able to figure out how to pee into
the response we get a prize and two kids
did it
googled it had to do it and gift cards
but I'm happy to I'm incredibly happy to
know that was really good works guys
doing a Raspberry Pi workshop for us and
it's gonna call because not only they
know they're gonna learn Robotics robot
like beginning robotics mean how cool is
it comes to the pipe station on time so
it gives the Python for kids station
again it's building on the knowledge
they never used Python before a concept
in an exercise ball on the concept is
another exercise until they get to a
point where they're actually doing some
challenges and when they complete the
challenges to get a token of some kind
of recognition which is an entry into
the drawing at the end of the day where
they can win some prizes anything from a
$10 gift card
all the way up to have their own virtual
minecraft server or $150 snaps are
giving away some big prizes and then
here's some other challenges like the
Fibonacci series was an interesting one
now what if the kids the tyro
maybe we have a library online content
in 2014 they can go on there and do
something challenging the continent when
this year is over
get it done before the new year is gonna
take all the 2010 content and make it
available can keep expanding on this
library not just for kids who went there
to do a review but what about the kids
who can't make it for whatever reasons
may be here is a learning and education
opportunity now the prices we giving a
talk about the price is the incentive
heart that's $150 retail kit we gave two
of those away so far that's pretty cool
considering its a $40 ticket for the key
to enter
we partnered with her partner with no
starch press they gave us a bunch of
books was a dreary accelerate his kids
can learn even more in some other schwag
you like stickers in some way or do we
know how they got to the user and then
some of them to walk away with a custom
tyro for kids case which is pretty cool
and then who knows what this is its Dec
darknet badge so last year when I was
able to bring back a couple of them and
we gave away her kids and the kids love
him is it $20 soldering kit project
going to the kids pick discover the
hundred and fifty dollars and his dad
was like you know you want that way it
was kinda cute but he got what he really
wanted which was that kid and the parent
was pretty happy because they say the
toll on the folks at GDC dark awesome
they gave us several more badges this
year and next so we go to brew Congo
have a couple to give away in a girl
comes to give away and even more for
next year which I get chills when I say
that because they're just awesome
the road so how do we know how well it's
a hard thing to know so first you got
the safe and secure online presentation
right what does that mean how do we know
if this feedback you don't know somebody
tell your story that yet its work and
got me out of this situation but we
don't know but it's hard and we're
trying to figure that out surveys
another way challenged surveys is
sometimes people filling out quickly and
data is wrong for example the first item
there is how many how many hectic and
attended I asked my nine year old da me
an answer that I was expecting not to
malign my wife and kids she watches this
which different answer she read it
differently that's a challenge if you do
surveys you gotta tested on different
people people just putting a number for
likewise number 41 they thought that
meant we were kids that were there I was
not expecting and then there's just a
series of ways to make it easy for them
give them something to circle
another problem with that some of the
kids go to one workshop and allowed to
go to one with the circled an answer for
both
normalize that show you some of the
stats put together here and we're almost
done so this year we had 53 participants
was about 20 percent growth from last
year we had forty kids registered but
actually 38 showed up this year we had
53 registered and I think we actually
had 53 show up pretty good so you could
see the gender breakdown 39 boys 14
girls 36 always worth it was their first
time attending and for twelve girls it
was their first time attending two girls
two boys second time attending a hack
for kids one kid has gone to all three
dozen related
the age range is interesting because it
tells us all we talking to the right
audience is this appropriate for
teenagers we had a really low number of
teenagers do another one that's specific
to teenagers were you know we're just
not getting to the high schools soon
enough
nations outpace their popularity the
technology destruction village most
popular everybody loved it got a bunch
of fives most attended lockpicking
village doesn't want to pop a lot
especially when you're young you don't
want to we do want to get your first
level security right you see a lot can
you want to know how it works you wanna
get past it specially if there might be
something behind it that you don't think
so
20 K kid went to the lockpicking village
12518 him pop all the pins before that
616 pin and only one of them before it
and then you can see nine kids pop the
cops but one kid went right to the cuffs
the cops and they never did anything
interesting interesting data network
security section 209 kids of the nine we
had 92 all exercises and then there was
a hidden challenge and those we had
seven of nine sorry that I thought for
kids 10 kids showed up at an old old in
the first three exercises to only able
to finish the second challenge the
g-series none of them got by Matt crypto
did it to actually provided proves we
did not ask for proof but to did it
that's really interesting technology
destruction village 14 kids went there
are five of them identified all the
components but like all of them
capacitor was again more interesting
data here are some people had a really
good time the data back to wrap up you
want to do your own happy kids talk to
me in the hallway and we can discuss
further have any questions about
talk to me the whole way here is our
social media at happy kids Thank You
MobileIron a memorable line employees
sponsored me to be here and again this
is the next generation of cyber frontier