alright so my name is Timothy D Block
welcome to the blue team 30 hit rental
there is a very basic talk this is for
iced teas
professionals with limited resources in
both time money people a lot of the
tools I have used here and you know I
sound very effective and useful when I
don't want to share with the community
yeah I'm speaking on my cover or she
does she believe it I do have a pod just
got to study at the PVC security podcast
in the exploit information security
podcast and I mention those because a
lot of these tools I found on listening
to podcasts and pretty much podcasts
addict i dont always I may come but I
also listened to home security weekly
being one that I found some some of
these tools that a tech project which
will be going through is one of those
tools that I heard on the security
weekly podcast and I was given a
challenge to start doing some have sex
at my organization that was a great
resource for that so I have worked for
the state of South Carolina for the last
seven years
any government employees know that as a
state employee you have limited
resources and both time money and people
so but we still gotta get a job to do so
this is why I want to create this talk
is getting a lot of other people out
there they could use these tools so
several the challenges that I was given
included you know research finding out
about these tools research in them
staying up with some of the latest
information security news application
security you know we're getting infected
with malware why we get infected with
malware what can we do to improve upon
that and you know we know Adobe Flash
has come out with its $7 billion in the
last week that we patched that
an easy way not easy problem to solve
and sometimes expensive if you wanna go
to talk to some of the vendors there so
right there are all the tools to
straight up Google Twitter us that I
proxies maintenance red line tool and
Microsoft's enhancement gatien
experience toolkit otherwise known as
Emmett and then admin arsenals PDQ
deploy so the first challenge I was
given was research I don't think this
will be a surprise to anyone
this is the tool number 12 a choice for
ITV professionals everywhere and that's
Google you know using Google Dorking
which is a lot of security professionals
know about but there's also little
things techniques that you can do with
Google for example if you search for a
specific tools you gonna get a lot of
emphasis SEC and the sentence later
there's the word tools for quotations
around that you're gonna really refine
your search to any any heads with
InfoSec tools in that order
so really learning how to manipulate
Google to improve your search processes
is very important for you know research
and stuff and and discovering stuff
there's no really damn I think Google is
pretty straightforward so challenge ever
to strike intelligence yeah ok says
Google hackers Google hacking for
penetration testers 2005 version ok
thank you for that
of anyone got any tools that can help
with that you know this is being
recorded and let's get that out their
threat intelligence is you know you
gotta keep up with him four seconds and
ever-changing thing so you need to
really keep up with that and I found
twitter twitter is is really free you
can set up lists if you need to restart
a local user but I used that to just
follow 400 information security
professionals so when something happens
like hacking team getting four hundred
gigabytes of their internal data chopped
on the Internet
everyone's been talking about that
there's there's a ton of fun from that a
lot of snark there's a lot of fun
comments but as you can see appear
there's a lot of people doing analysis
on the data in starting on this they
discovered three adobe has two or three
doubles on abilities in that internal
database error in that turn internal
data ok let me know followed up you will
find out when they're gonna be reading
the news new vulnerability tests I go
patch on my machines in the agency also
I've really found use from Twitter when
all the OpenSSL bugs came out
heart bleeds probably the first one that
said that off a lot of people discussing
it was also very hard to ignore
so when something big happens you can
see a lot of people talking about a lot
of people discussing it you can ask
questions of people they're gonna be
sharing links Sharon tools I was able to
find some tools some Python tools that I
was able to then run against my websites
to find out if its
if they're vulnerable so Twitter can you
know don't like Twitter yes there is
drama but you can like any other
appliance you can tune it out you can
people are sharing pictures of their
kids too much and not really giving you
much value can unfollow people so she is
very much up to you and how to control
it and it's true of course it's for sure
behavioral data but my third challenge
was a security so I was tasked with we
got its start doing security assessments
on all our applications go do don't have
no idea how to do that like I mentioned
on security cleared them talking about
said it said they said at a proxy also
known as they put that out for anyone
that doesn't know open web application
security project is a non-profit open
source community so you can get a lot of
invaluable tools there for web
application security is being one of
them and there's that's the interface
right there so would you want to do is
you first wanna set up as a as a proxy
and then you want to click on everything
within the application click on every
link fill out every form submit
everybody and then from there you can
start using some of the the automated
tools that they have their I don't know
how big that is I hope you can see that
but essentially from there you spider
decide you can do a check spider for
Ajax type of content there is a force to
browse
which will you know has a list of
directories and it'll go out and look
forward and directories you takes a long
time depending on how big of a list you
have that hasn't default but like
anything in that it has a lot of
granular control so you can get some
low-hanging fruit then from there you
can really start digging into as you
start using it more digging into it the
other tool that I I forgot to mention
again this is bird sweet I think if
you're going into web application
security burbs we'd is the tool of
choice
zap has I think been catching up in
terms of usability
the downside to burp suite is that is at
$300 your subscription is that is
completely free
I've had developers start using SAP
because we put the city and their
process and you know it's kinda like a
test so they want to figure out what
their get wrong and so I started working
with them and I was surprised when they
came back and said we're starting to run
their own reports and I don't need to go
through and COS but the burp addition
you have struggled a little bit you get
the free version but struggle is not
ronald so you can give it to them and
let them go go go play with it you know
your web developers using a two legs app
is just just makes the process go a lot
smoother and it's a lot more value out
of it they they find the problem before
they get to you so after you done after
kinda mapped out the application you can
run ActiveX scan as it and as you can
see there in the active can you it
starts running through several different
techniques a path traversal remote file
inclusion cross-site scripting
releases the top 10 every few years
although I don't change and everything
they released it has really changed all
that much but it runs through all that
for you she takes forever be at gatien
is going to take a few minutes to a few
hours and then we can get this nifty
generate this report here which can be
you know you can take this is an HMO
report they have an XML report so that
you can put that into something like the
pics or trade is there some kind of
tracking applications and keep track of
this stuff because it's one of the first
things I found out was we'd have this
but it wasn't feasible to fix it at that
time we had you know couple months from
now we'll go back and fix it but it's
upon me to go back and make sure that
thing like to try to fix as a community
version enterprise version implement
that really check the stuff but what's
great about this report is that you can
take this HTML reporting you to
developers and start working on some of
those problems
before you do that don't make sure
there's a it shows you the URL that's in
there the description of the attack and
then the attack itself
you want to verify and confirm his appt
is not perfect it does have false
positives in need to go in there
confirm that it was found was actually
there might not necessarily being and
it's also got links and references and
all sorts of sorts of goodies there so
one of the so I did you know along with
the confirming part I did have some SQL
injection confirmed the developer didn't
necessarily believe me so I took him
over to the computer and they said you
know I showed them and the technique and
they said something pretty pretty
amazing to me which was hackers are so
smart so you know that the developers if
you're willing to give them time and
work with them they're they're very much
they want to get it right to just like
we did so much for challenge was
forensics or getting these stock alerts
within the state there's a there's a
state idea that monitors all the traffic
of all the agencies and we get rid of
stock alerts so initially were just
Raymond James off but we decided we want
to look into what what's actually
getting us infected what are people
going to can we implement some kind of
Defence's or you know change some kind
of web filter rule or something to to
stop some of these infections and that's
where men in red line that then there is
the alternate told this is volatility
I've never used the hotel room and Iran
is something that I've got real familiar
with its a free tool you can just do a
google search for and go download it all
these tools are very well documented as
well document redlining and just about
everything so it's pretty easy to start
downloading and using and so once you
build out your packages as the folder
structure all you really have to do is
click on the run red line script there
at the bottom of the batch file and
it'll probably command prompt and
depending on how how much processing the
computer has and how many miles are on
the system it'll go through go out and
collect all the events from the machines
are registered registry settings
browsers event details all that stuff in
a report in one place for you so you run
run that and then you're gonna open
previous analysis and you'll be able to
open up that session file and it'll do
some more analysis on the actual session
file itself you click on I'm
investigating a host base on external
investigation Lee and there you have the
layout there everything within a time
period so what you want to do is a time
when call option you said it to like a
two to five minute period cuz right
there that's that's about a 22 minutes
on either side of a time period I have
742 items to go through so if I don't
have an exact time I have to you know
really kinda expand that out a little
bit but you can get pretty pretty big
into that so one of my wins from this
was we had a phishing email come in
hit thirty different users seven people
know I'm sorry eight people the
seven-person send it to their manager
and clicked on the attachments we had a
total of eight people open up the
attachment luckily we had our users are
very good reporting that kind of stuff
they open the command prompt command
prompt flash and then went away so it's
pretty pretty obvious and luckily our
pay attention but we took the red line
to put it on the first couple found out
that it exceeds the file had been
dropped within the windows temp folder
so we will remove that nothing else was
installed ur done so
we were pretty confident that we had
gotten infection 8 users having a
reimage um it's gonna take you know two
to three days if it's all aidid wants
you know we have guys doin PC refresh of
dredging machines could be so this was
all within one Friday and we were able
to get everyone back to work so the
other one is on top of that how do we
keep these machines from getting
infected around you and our organization
we've finally got rid of Windows XP but
it when it rolled past the winds
extended support so we had an issue of
Wired News machines we still need
welfare legacy applications in this
particular instance we had an Internet
Explorer vulnerability come out that we
wanted to remediate and Microsoft emmett
was the solution for that a lot of these
articles are coming out with there's new
Internet Explorer vulnerability in at
the last sentence of that article is is
a mitigates this vulnerability and it's
well documented
you know you got trusts a good day
Kennedy is very much
corner of the tool has written a lot
about your curls Perez another pretty
big name that is worried about the tool
Sansas written about it Microsoft
TechNet so it's it's it's out there you
can deploy 200 organization and then you
can grab it with Group Policy to manage
it you get some very basic control group
policy which can do from there so that
you can fully test and export an XML
file that can then be used during log on
as a logon script that they can then we
can grab control then we'll explain why
you want to do that here in a minute but
this is the interface is very very
simple basically whatever it does it
take some of the normal process is in
the machine kind of hide them a little
bit sore in a malicious attackers of
some kind comes in
it will find it comes in trying to
exploit that a little block it and
usually which again is that when a block
occurs the program in the bottom right
corner probable occurs in this program
was blocked due to this kind of defense
and this is the other screen so you have
a very basic setup they also do popular
software recommended software Adobe and
Java are two on the basic suggest
putting those in place is going to
really help strengthen your endpoint
security and you can go in here and
uncheck so something like a year a DAF +
pops up you can check that for the
program and get back working so I tested
this on my dream machines and i actually
pushed out four points in my
organization just fine no problem
whatsoever
tried to push up 5.1 and I had issues I
tested on my three machines of course
work fine so I decided to test it on
just the atty floor and I dared the
mainframe developer machines during
their Microsoft Office and Internet
Explorer so I was running around that
morning on checking year plus for them
so it is very important that you test
this out and even on Mike Simons tool
they have they have some programs there
that it isn't working with to make sure
you but there's i've seen you know like
I said microsoft office whatever reason
was done by a minute so it's it's got a
unique environment so make sure you test
that their league in this scenario you
wanna try to grab my computer from each
department and make sure putting it on
there and see if there's any issues and
then pushed it out
so finally the last one is is patch
management as Sherlock people struggled
with it there are very expensive tools
out there to help with this I think I
found a solution that was relatively
inexpensive PDQ deploy has a free
version and all these tools by the way
you can go home today gone up in your
room and downloaded start playing with
PDQ deploy has a free version it is
throttled you can't download certain
packages but it's only 500 bucks for the
Enterprise version and you can
essentially go in there and this is the
downloads going right there it even has
a limit on their redeploy
Adobe's on there there's just a whole
host of programs that are already in
there so they have programs that you can
download prepay pre-packaged and set up
for you to deploy silently I've pushed
to be flashed on ability or Adobe Flash
updates throughout the day during
business hours and never had an issue so
pretty much agreed to all so when she
had to txt download it you can deployed
Active Directory PDQ inventory
Spiceworks and you know a good old text
file so it wasn't all that PDQ in toy is
Russell's inventory and they they lost
$500 but it does go out and find out
what's installed on their what versions
on there so all you do is approved
package and put it out so here are some
more resources I will make these the
slide deck available on my website
Timothy D blog.com and there's just a
bunch of stuff out there was talk about
Google talked about just using the user
guide for all these tools you to convert
is like this have a lot of great stuff
on there and hear all the tools again
posterity and that's pretty much it has
any questions