their undoing gender because no one here
for your first year because we're going
to talk about detecting and preventing
spear phishing attacks antennas and I
said before I realized spearfishing
might be more appropriate
speaker fact you can't advance the
slides yes USB connector is not a place
right
hey there we go alright so just let me
have an idea about seventeen years but
insecurity for about nine years I'm
standing on ice
Twitter handle hardware hacker that is
hard water that's the north country that
is hard water that's what I came from
I'm currently a pen tester but I come
from a long defender insisting mysteries
background so I'm talking about today
detecting and preventing phishing
attacks using DNS I'm talking about
problems title squatting so how many
here I'm sooo most you know about types
wanting anyone not know what I was
getting us okay so I'm talking about the
kinds of type of squatting that are
specifically dealing with misspell
domain names or using like Hamid lives
where you have characters that look like
other characters there's another kind of
type of squatting that would be like
hibernating characters together so like
Service Desk paypal.com updates dash
microsoft.com it's a different kind of
that we're dealing with the
intentionally misspelled why is that men
drug samples out yesterday I thought it
was appropriate if you send it they will
click that's true right
our users are not trained especially
with these with these type of squatting
domain names that are misspelled using
home unless they're very difficult to
detect when you first look at him for
something as his professionalism and
hard for us to see see it on first
glance and as a result our users don't
know they get an email the thing so it's
legit and then click on it and now the
attackers got
credentials they might have a shell in
your system doesn't matter how good your
department of defense is there now on
your network obviously a lot of
motivations bout type of squatting back
in the day was about advertising
financial kinds of things redirecting
through ad networks delivering malware
but then it really started getting used
for phishing attacks it is highly
affected and I have some examples of
kinds of type of squatting on the screen
hear things like repeating characters
google.com with 3 O's or things like
omitted characters amazon.com missing
you also have the things like missing
dots so www.microsoft.com vs
www.microsoft.com Dec find out or vs
DEFCON dot org filters we also use
things like making something singular or
plural or exchanging vows around there's
one called how phones which are words
that sound a leg not really useful and
fishing its next one that is very useful
is homeless again characters that look
like other characters using an eye in
place of an L or using a winner Ellen
place of an eye and soaked up the wrong
TLD whitehouse.gov right
you guys know you also have things like
different country code swapping the TLD
to be like evil Corp dots p.m. instead
of ppl Corp dot com these are different
kinds of title squatting that are highly
effective and phishing attacks something
to show you a couple of the couple of
examples a traditional texts body right
now we have things like real world
examples twitter.com is the type of
squatting for profit
advertising Tesla Motors dot com evolved
swab and its advertising you can see
here you click on the ads for generating
money in the case of Microsoft I want to
make her soft and i ended up at stored
at hp.com after bouncing through a bunch
of advertising networks in the case of
low as 10 I ended up after bus
advertising networks know these are your
trips all kinds of typos squad the
question is are we seeing these kinds of
type of squatting use in real-world
phishing attacks with real-world cases
the answer is absolutely yes things like
anthem and Permira we all heard about
him earlier this year
very large attacks and analysis after
the fact
pointed to some common actors and some
common things happened one there was
type US productivity and to register
they were used in testing attacks in
case of anthem least you as well . this
foreign services under wellpoint dot com
and there was a domain registered W E 11
point dot com list had to type of
squatting in the case of Premera there
was a domain registered in there I dot
com two ends in a lot of browsers and in
a lot of email clients depending on your
using two ends looks very much like a
single and more recently CareFirst
BlueCross breeze and they had care flirt
with an L and CareFirst with the water
so these are definitely happening in the
real world with real it
real implications write this case it
didn't happen
a researcher Paul Moore tweeted this out
and this looks like Lloyds Bank UK I
mean that looks like to else I looked at
it I couldn't figure out what was wrong
with it at first there to capitalize not
to lower his house in the only
difference if you would put these side
by side is that the capital I like one
pixel heavier is just slightly wider and
some funds then the lowercase L I don't
know the season security professional
indeed be able to tell you what's wrong
with it without doing some more analysis
so type of squatting can when combined
fishing taxes highly effective and it's
a defender what can you do about it
what tools are available to you well
there's your all crazy mutual written by
and recording it's a really cool that's
included with Callie and backtrack and
works as you get a domain name and it
generates possible title squatting
variations for that domain you have some
more recently more senior cows kiro a
tool called DNS twist in its Python tool
that does a lot of the same things you
get a domain name and it generates
output
both these tools do one thing that you
can use as a defender they have the
ability to tell you if a domain name is
registered or not
sofa domain name is registered I can run
these tools I can collect the output in
five days from now I can run this from
these tools am i doing again and I
collect the output in a different and I
see are there different registrations so
my demands example.com five days from
now I see examples dot com what does
that mean so you can do it but it's kind
of clunky its manual it's not anything
that works I mean it's just not easy
right so I wrote it to all cuz after
looking around I didn't see anything but
I wrote a school called crazy parser
because the time only you were all crazy
existed Python to all and it consumes
the output of both DNS twists and you
were all crazy and it will compare that
against a baseline that you will set up
to be able to detect did a new domain
get registered since the last time
around the program so that way and
attackers registering the domain in
advance the attack you can see that
registration and you can have a chance
to possibly at least prepare yourself
you may not be able to stop it because
there's not enough time you're not
prepared it is good to know that it's
going to happen to me show you how it
works it's configured and show you
actually what happens right so
can see that here when you download
files you get crazy parser you can have
smaller files known domains that
seriously in my tummy is jesse is she
will talk about those in minute first
thing I want to do is show you what's in
crazy parser that you need to modify
this is horrible ok so it talks about
dependencies we see that we've got URL
crazy little too big for yes we need to
tell the program where these programs
live so i knows how to use them right
underneath the imports are two variables
URL crazy path and DNS twist path just
point to where they exist on your system
you're in Cali year old he's already
cracked just point where they're at
that's all you would need to do to start
using the program for modification this
there are few command line arguments
available if you run without any
arguments will see those we have things
like dashed see that house where the
configuration directory is well-known
demands that serious he might slip
that's the important things seem to be
the director you're running from unless
you tell it they live somewhere else
dashiell was what file as we see the
results in defaults to results
Dashti is a directory where you save
those results can assume you're
Directory directory unless you specify
otherwise
and then there's dash MNE and that
allows you to send an email so if you go
and look at crazy parser look forward to
seeing here it tells you that you just
need to configure user name password and
recipient if you're using Gmail it can
it's already setup to relay through
Gmail username and your application
specific password putting recipients and
it'll send an email when it's done if
there are no new results says everything
is clear and if there are no results
she'll put file to the email and I have
a chance to review it if you're not
using Gmail just go down here to mail
server depose and say your mail server
appropriately so that you have your
internal details for your mail server
and that's all you need to do to using
male alright so there are two other
files right there's a CSV files in the
first one is my domains CSV formats the
domains that you want to monitor for
phishing attacks or type of squatting
attacks against right so it's gonna say
example.com so it's saying we're
monitoring for your become.com so we put
that in there now if we had another
demand that we wanted to monitor defense
is so it's a binary defense systems that
2010 company doesn't even know let's
pretend it's this right so you can put
one or more demands in here you can put
as many as you want one per line we're
just gonna do do become so you're also
gonna have known domains that CSV and
when you first open it up it says
examples dot com and WTF example.com
this just shows you how the file works
the first time you run it though we're
just gonna leave it empty and let's see
what I talked two options so there's DNS
twisting around crazy and that tells you
to use either one program or the other
programmer role so alright so what's
gonna happen here the networks working
yes that crazy parser calls both DNS
twists and you're all crazy they're
going to do what they do with the domain
term become.com they're going to do
their lookups going to determine what
domains are registered for sharing that
information super sturdy duplicate that
so we have one master list and then it
can save the results file the reason we
cleared out the non demands files
because that's like your whitelist tell
it things we've already seen so with it
empty everything it sees is new so it's
going to run gonna do is look at what's
new already undergoing a file called
results that CSV which will contain any
type of squatting domains order because
I dot com that currently exists today is
the day going to work
tempting I didn't kill any money goes
alright there's no eres here so let's
look what's in results that CSV alright
it worked so now we see that have a
number of domains Debbie conduct com
Derby khou.com Derby coin dot com you
know things like that so these are all
the demands it actually exists that our
type of squatting alternatives for Derby
kind of calm so we need to do is we need
to review these
we need to review these demands and we
need to determine what is their intent
what is their purpose so what I would do
as I would go to each domain and I'd use
a non attributable admin vem that's art
something that's outside my network
because if it is a phishing attack you
don't want to tell people that you're on
them she uses something is outside your
network ghosts are looking at these
domains and figure out whether they do
or they just traditional squatters are
doing advertising see that a lot
all kinds of just trying to get people
that miss type on the keyboard summer
gonna be a legitimate with business
websites Derby khou.com is Debian
company and some if you actually had a
phishing attack who knows what it's
going to look like right it may be
blamed for the shooting in prep stage
maybe they use something like set to
near the page and if you if you go to
one of these type of squatting
alternatives and it's your site that's
when you know that something bad is
about to happen so you need to know
configure crazy purser to know about the
things that you want you don't wanna
know about anymore and you do that by
using this file you got to make common
reason you put in a domain and then a
comment and this reason isn't actually
important it's just for you to use hi
everyone I tend to use a valid site and
squatter but you can use your blogger
ticketing system and record the details
about that domains help you understand
why decision in your record the incident
number here you could do that whatever
you want to just know that crazy party
doesn't use it you just need domain com
account so hard to classify this I went
looked and said that Derby Derby hull is
a valid website to calm and conduct net
is a squatter site is not actually about
what you notice they don't have their
behind at Oregon here and the reason is
were pretending that it hasn't been
registered yet it doesn't exist so once
we see this file will be run again
using the same arguments is gonna do it
same thing it's gonna call her crazy
gonna call DNS twist they're gonna do
they look up to return the results but
this time it's going to look at known
domains does she is fancy does this
entry exists if it does it's also crazy
person hey this is good we've already
seen that we don't want to know about it
anymore so the only thing that's going
to exist when you're done in the results
file our demands that didn't exist
the last time you read it baseline so
you can use this and continuous
monitoring mode to sit there and monitor
for attacks on you can run it once had a
baby run it once an hour if you use a
large number of domains it takes a while
to run right now there is a bug that if
you run it more often than it takes to
continue our to finish executing it'll
clobber its temporary files and never
finished executing so that will be fixed
I didn't see it already I would
definitely use both DNS twists and URL
crazy DNS twist is still under active
development and it has a ways to go to
catch up but it is getting close it's
it's very good and you will find things
that the other one didn't find now that
we're done running let's look if this
worked during conduct or sets the only
thing in the results file that means a
derby car door it was registered since
the last time we have to get a baseline
which means there's probably a phishing
attack that's about happen if this if
this site after analysis isn't just an
ad squatter alright so the demo you see
how it works what he do afterwards right
you need to do some preventative
measures are needed a funny cat pics so
is every talk has to have blocked the
domains in your web proxy if they're not
valid sites even if they're just
advertising sites you don't know that
they're not going to deliver some kind
of malicious add a week a month a year
from now supply kit in your proxy
made you want a black hole TNS no one in
your networking get to it
increase your monitoring look for those
fishing domains coming in in emails are
those type of squatting is coming in and
email scams that means an attack is
happening so there are some drawbacks
hear it works in certain situations and
doesn't in others in the case of
WellPoint dot com I wanted to know what
anthem have seen this attack ensuring of
crazy our URL crazy detects it they
would have had a warning that this
domain was registered case of Panera
with double and glittering M was not
detected but it is now I submitted a
request for CNN is included in DNS twist
hair forrest was fifty 50 ml cliff was
was detected the one left when I was not
but West Midnapore request and it is in
there now it will not detect those
hyphenated demands that we're talking
about things like Service Desk
paypal.com it is just not set up to do
that it's not gonna protect your
external users our customers are people
who are outside your network boundary
but you do have some options there to
WIPO the World Intellectual Property
Organization has something called you
know universal domain name dispute
resolution policy that allows you to
petition to seize that domain if it's
someone that's trying to profit off your
brand someone is trying to keep you from
try steel business from me whatever it
is or they're attacking you
usne cybersquatting Consumer Protection
Act is also available at this link here
for I can if you're interested in making
bail for afterwards tells you how to
file the legal proceedings the
documentation you need to seize a domain
this type of squatting with that the
code on GitHub I'm hard water hacker on
Twitter my email address is out here in
the slides will be on my blog her
daughter sector blogspot.com
you guys been great this my first time
speaking at Derby and you are awesome
and I want to thank you for being here
it and are there any questions
sure you know there yes to the question
is like is there any way to find things
when demands are registered really fast
this isn't gonna work things like anthem
though that WellPoint domain was
registered well ahead of the attack that
actually started they started building
they're proud she was going to catch the
ones where they're doing big prepping
for him but it's if they register a
domain and restart the TAC the only
thing you could do is schedule it to run
every 15 minutes in hope that you can
respond and the remaining 45 and there's
one other question we got one minute
left I don't drink man sorry if it was
warm red well I told will be on it
yea again if if you don't have much time
there's not much you can do it it's
depends on how fast can respond if
they're preparing out in front you have
a better chance I am working however on
the way to do some of these kinds of
detection on the wire hoping to release
something for bro maybe someday bro
signature and I'm hoping to do is talk
and that in future so keep an eye out
think I got to get going here I'm
getting cut so do you have any questions
I'll be in the hallway outside