my name's Jeff man I'm a strategist with
tenable network security at like to
thank Derby Conn for letting me speak
here this afternoon to you at the
beginning of conversation give you my
contact information if you still wanted
by the end of the conversation I'll try
to remember to repeat it that's what I
used to look like my younger days
minute try to move quickly through this
especially the early part my background
is I'm not here to talk about myself but
the point of this talk is really I've
been in the business for a long time and
I've been pondering the last year or so
you with all the bridges that are
happening at all the vulnerabilities
that are being discovered and some
trusted tools know how far have we
really try so little bit about my
background in to where we stand today
from a security perspective why was
failing to continue to fail I will offer
a solution and it's my opinion based on
a lot of experience and hopefully that's
not here to tell you the right thing I'm
here to generate ideas get you thinking
feel free to disagree with me but
hopefully it's a discussion started to
allow time at the Q&A that interrupts
during the talks have been in the
business information security for about
32 33 years I did start the bulk of my
career working for the defense
department at a certain three-letter
agency had been doing this in Internet
information
network data security thing pretty much
since the beginning twenty years twenty
some years ago at some point I ended up
in PCI purgatory ended up being there
for about 10 years so my DOD background
is primarily with the National Security
Agency I started out as a panelist one
of the first things I did is equipped
analyst at an assay was we had customers
back then the customer was primarily the
army the military and these guys that
were using secret codes to talk to
people that we may be enlisted that
might be citizens of other countries
giving us information they communicated
with something called a one-time which
is the only hundred-percent secure
system unbreakable if you use the
correct but they are these the guys we
were dealing with the customers they had
these PCs on their desk and they were
asking is there some way to do this
encryption decryption thing using his
computer and we decided the other is so
to my knowledge I was responsible for
her safe for the first offered base
cryptographic system that has ever
produced
they semi automated one time those
things in the middle of those are called
floppy disk even though they were
actually hard plastic and that's where
the key was added another customer that
was special forces they used a different
type of one-time pad with a different
type of algorithm called a visionary
square just a simple substitution table
as you see there is the alphabet 26
different slides so it's like a Caesar
cipher
26 offsets they memorize this thing that
this this this this type of algorithm
actually translates to something like
two hundred and twenty-three unique
stream letter characters and they would
memorize it I was working with them in
and I didn't have the opportunity to
memorize it but I just been through some
crypto training classes and learn about
site for reals so I came up with a site
four wheel that was actually division
here we all they liked it so much when I
would go out to the field they kept
stealing them from me so we ended up
just making thousands of them
shipping route to Special Forces so
whenever I run into a special forces
person I asked them they they told me
that they called it the wizzy real and I
always ask them if they have ever heard
of this is the guy that invented I
didn't talk about a month ago a guy came
up to me afterwards I said I didn't do
you invented the winds we like got one
of those was kinda cool I told him I'd
autograph see him again in my time and I
say I had this thing happened where and
I read this article just couple years
ago
2013 where they're talking about this
crypt of statues anybody ever heard of
that trip to the statue in the courtyard
CIA headquarters was reading this
article
group of Venice a in terms they were
there and they took the code back and
basically wired had an article
couple months before this saying that
there was some guy at CIA that had
broken the things done it at lunch time
over the years kind of pet project but
this article revealed that people from
an assay had broken it years before this
guy and I can say I was one of those
interns have been mentioned in Wired
magazine
towards the latter part of my career
Tennessee moved over to what at the time
was called the InfoSec site I think they
called information assurance these days
and got in kind of hit the ground floor
learning how to do what's come to be
known as red teaming penetration testing
that type of things as part of the
organization that kind of first started
developing methodologies and started
starting to do that type of work in a
little bit of forensics little bit of
threat detection and really what
happened was I was getting I got
together in an office with a bunch of
guys and at the time and it happened
twenty years ago why this talking about
that we went down to visit this place
called the Air Force Information Warfare
Center at the time twenty years ago they
were they were they were the primary
agency within the DoD that was doing all
this pen testing thing they set up the
first serve they were doing the
monitoring the air force was responsible
for all the networks within the DoD so
we went down there to learn and i
actually gave this talk for the first
time back in February of this year in
San Antonio that's that's what got me
thinking hey it's been 20 years since
the beginning I should do it based on my
twenty-year history in a little bit of
forensic work on my customers which was
the Department of Justice has anybody
ever heard of this website defacement
remember back in the early days
hackers deface websites and that was it
like you leaving any string I can get
here look at me I was part of a team
that went down there to try to help them
figure out
you know what had gone wrong who had
done and of course the first thing they
did was unplug everything and rebuild
the servers so in a whole lot to do
actually I left Tennessee went out into
the greener pastures and commercial
sector and wanted to do this testing
thing commercially and try to help
customers solve all their problems and
be secure and I was naive in the
beginning it was mentioned this morning
during one of the key knows what happens
when we fix all the problems when we go
on until all the holes in and we're done
what are we gonna do maybe that's why I
ended up in PCI I was it was accuracy
for ten years and i actually had a very
unique experience I was involved with
PCI practice that for whatever reason we
were the practice was called in for a
lot of the companies in the mid to
thousands of suffering breaches mostly
the Gonzales ring to Jackson's in there
for them for six years
Heartland they were payment processor
that popped I've had a lot of experience
going into a lot of different companies
if you look up here there's there's
banks there's retail obviously there's
gas stations 1 800 flowers e-commerce
grocery stores
lot of different companies lot of
different corporate environments lot of
different corporate culture lot of
different expertise levels but really a
lot of companies security is not really
a core competency so coming in
presenting them with PCI was really an
opportunity to teach security to talk
these days I teach about security so
that's my background in the context of
been in this from the beginning and then
so so where do we stand today twenty
years later
obviously there's been lots of breaches
in the news
vulnerabilities that have been around
and some of the tools of the use of
being discovered and and they've
apparently been there since the very
beginning
social engineering phishing attacks
shared passwords are still weak
passwords there's still default settings
that was a problem twenty years ago and
it's still a problem today which gets me
an old-timer thinking gee I really
really really accomplishing anything as
it is a security industry is a hacker
industry are really making a difference
what has changed technology certainly
change certainly gotten a lot faster
you've heard talks and probably will
continue to your talks about the the the
concept of a network perimeter and what
is that these days
mobile devices bring bring your own
device BYOD there's cloud virtual
there's just so much more going on from
a technology perspective that some of
these fundamental things haven't really
changed all what are the threats today
wire people doing what they're doing the
back after you know there's all sorts of
reasons why they do it inside outside
threats you really when it comes down to
it in the early days it was more hey can
I get there nowadays they figured out
how to monetize make a little money lots
of some political reasons sometimes and
get into the whole nations state to be a
believer that it's it's out there is a
possible motive was just so why are we
feeling going wrong
business literally hundreds of different
companies the biggest problems is
there's just too many solutions out
there it's it's a very common saying
within the industry especially from a
vendor perspective that there's no such
thing as a silver bullet solution to his
that's what everybody wants they just
want to buy something set it and forget
about it a lot of companies but there
but there isn't really a single silver
bullet solution there's really a whole
magazine for the silver bullets that
companies have to buy and this is kind
of from a PCI perspective these are the
types of things that you kinda sorta
need to have approached PCI compliance
so there's really too many silver
bullets out there and there's a problem
in that respect to companies having an
over reliance on technology because they
have to have some discussions morning
during the keynote panel about
automation and augmentation what the
role is and they were speaking the
context of pen testing only extends to
any security technology that's out there
you to what degree do you rely on the
automation necessary but the
over-reliance the false sense of
security I think you problems the other
big problem is this may sound a little
bit old school that the lack of written
policies and procedures
i think is a huge problem and if you if
you're looking for a definition of
an information security policy it starts
with a goal was also believed it was
Katie that said you know what are you
doing what's your goal
what are you trying to protect lot of
companies don't understand that they
know that they have to buy a fire or do
they need an ideal solution they know
they need a sim solution they know they
need to this they needed that they've
got into the compliance thing and they
run around and do all that stuff but
fundamentally if you sit down and ask
them a lot of people in the company
don't really know what it is that
they're trying to protect all we have to
do a PC I think it's got something to do
with credit cards
ok to do with credit card information
there's other personal information
associated with that also needs to be
addressed so you know what it is maybe
you know where it is we have no idea
where it is so on and so forth
lot of slot there's a lot of silos
within companies within I T departments
within business units people actually
work in some sort of consulting role you
people out there maybe this has been
your experience to be very often when I
was going into a company's aqsa and I
would have to talk to each and every one
of the sailors each and every one of the
groups it was rare that anybody that I
talked to understand the big picture of
what the company was about you know they
knew there were grocery stores groceries
but in terms of the network architecture
that apology where sensitive data store
where it was flowing most people didn't
know in fact was very common if you
talked to the network guys well we set
up the network we set up the firewalls
and that's about it if you talk to the
server people will have the UNIX guys
and then there's the windows guys you
know
well what's running on your server the
church ministry I mean even talking to
TVA's database administrators tell me
about the scheme of the databases show
me the fields were thus the data stored
and they could do that and you know what
this database is about you know what
kind of information is on here a lot of
them didn't know they like now it just
needs to be a certain size and accept a
certain type of data so very common for
me was I would walk away after spending
a week or two of these companies having
a better picture of the operation of the
company than any one person that I
talked to a less you found someone guy
in the company that's been there forever
started in the mailroom knew how to do
COBOL program so we ended up working on
the mainstream and kinda knew how
everything worked but those guys are
becoming more rare to find so companies
don't understand sort of the sort of the
process and starting from some
foundational point of having a policy
having a plan they focus more on what's
the what's the minimum amount of
investment we need to make whether it's
buying something whether it's paying for
assessment or consulting services so on
and so forth
there's a lot of reasons why
companies don't approach security from a
store but programmatic prospective some
of these are here this is some of these
guys are just rambling thoughts and
they're they're mostly to prompt me and
I will make slides available sure if for
any reason you want these later what I
tried to teach my customers over the
years is to help them understand that
security first and foremost is not a
desired state that you get to a life
cycle it's an ongoing process and you
exist as a company somewhere in a
process of doing security if you're
approaching it all you can argue maybe
some of the stages but in general
especially in the early days it all
started with assessment where r you doin
gap analysis what are you working with
what's out there what's missing
especially from a PCI perspective
usually the first pass is so many holes
in the months of how do we get to where
we need to be and that next step
involves having a strategy developing a
policy policy at the highest level is
we're gonna be secure or insecure the
state are working to secure corporate
reputation
we're going to see a website whatever
very high level and it's pretty sure
when you get into the standards how do
we do this and then the procedures of
the actual step-by-step guide into that
closely as the architecture building out
the solutions and then of course you
have to live with them implement them
you run with it and then that's when
this work comes first circle and you now
becomes more of an audit because you're
hopefully measuring against your own
policy your own strategy is how well are
we doing what we set out to do is are we
missing things we need to fine tune it
so lifecycle continuous
obviously systematically you need to
have a policy to kind of make it all
work anybody know the name Marcus Ranum
saw him talk some years ago and he was
talking about firewalls and the need for
firewalls and he made a statement that
stuck with me he said if you don't have
a policy you don't really have a
firewall meaning if you don't have
something written down as to what the
firewall is going to do not allow how do
you measure with your firewalls working
that kind of stuck with me and I said
what kind of works for every aspect of
every part of this whole thing that
really policy is the key
what is a policy addresses already it's
it's the game plan it's the way that you
justify budgets and it's something
that's written down the plan to measure
yourself against its really key to
enabling business and business and
business operations has to be a part of
the strategy is well this is what you
usually see from companies in terms of
their attitude about policy because a
lot of PCR requires that you have to
have two things written there and
they're supposed to be reviewed annually
it was very common to go win to do the
on-site assessment get the stack of
policies and lo and behold the annual
review it happened the week before we
showed up on site and fifty documents
have been reviewed in one day they had
to date we knew there was a game being
in the configuration rules for a
firewall its Marcus reference
a lot of times the policy companies
might be like this
seen this policy is collecting dust on
the shelf but it's not meant to be there
and and and what i'm saying is policy is
necessary and there's a way to use it
use it productively you can use policies
of dozens case was very common
especially in the early days
PCI to go win and I could make friends
with the idea in the security people
that didn't like seeing you there anyway
to alter the look you know what your
problems are you know what you need
work with me as I slap PCI on it guess
what you'll get your budget is your
management doesn't understand your sea
level people don't understand PCI
insecurity that they know they have to
get by this PCI thing so tell them you
need it slapped PCI on it trust me the
budget and lo and behold it was and I
made France and then we could have a
better discussion about what was really
going obviously having the policy is a
way to meet PCI another compliance
regulations and compliance you know who
is sort of address this morning again if
peace I didn't exist a lot of this
industry really wouldn't be doing a
strong as it is and that's a that's the
reality
providing a framework a way to measure a
way of having understanding way of
getting everybody in the company
involved these are all things that help
justify why you need to do policy other
than the right thing to do and I keep
underscoring this our focus is an
industry is always on the technology
technology without context is just
technology there's more to it than that
obviously policy is not popular not
popular to write things down it's much
easier to just make things work and its
nothing's going wrong everything's are
ok this is not new but this is this is
neglected the positive spin of why you
need to have a policy and strategy is to
take into account the whole business
operations take into account the
corporate culture I had never seen it
work effectively where the wasn't
management buy-in too often i've seen
there's a lot of rules in place that the
rules are kind of ignored by the admins
by the sea level people running some
simple you're the CEO secretary does his
email and has a password on down the
line the sacred cow being the
administrator gets to do what he wants
to do because he's got the keys of the
kingdom he can do what he wants to do
that's gotta gotta be transcended in
order to make it really work it also is
keep forgetting all the employees the
company no matter what level no matter
what role to to sort of understand how
they are turning into the big picture in
my opinion that's the only way you begin
to defeat social engineering fishing
exercise if you get people to understand
their little insignificant role that
they think they have no impact on the
comp company really does have an impact
so what they do really does so in some
sense the question to start out with
whether it's in your own company you're
working for other companies try to
pinpoint where you are and so the
confession to make everything I've just
presented to you is from is verbatim
from the presentation that I put
together in my first commercial job
eighteen years ago they don't know maybe
put together these slides and run some
of them make them pretty but word for
word the same to stop and think about
that a minute I've given you eighteen
year old information that still valid
today and it's still daunting today and
really what's scary is when we used to
present this idea of the security
lifecycle eighteen years ago we were
talking in terms of 12 to 18 months life
cycle but the reality today the way
technology is moving is this life cycle
repeats itself months weeks days maybe
even hours
you know it's a moving target is really
fast faster than this whole day so what
really needs to change
understanding that you have a problem
like that first step to getting past the
problem that's really key getting past
the fact that a lot of companies don't
really care about securities securities
not our core competency and there's a
lot of companies out there especially in
the PCI world they have not nor never
will
dedicated security staff they might have
I T staff and then they have to do
double duty but within our industry we
sort of envision a certain
organizational structure that every
company has and that's how you do it
right
reality is many companies out there that
don't have that never will have that
which only compounds the problem our
security industry is largely vendor
driven and I'm saying this is a fender
benders lie I used to hate vendors when
I was a consultants what I've learned
now that I am offender is vendors are
always line and a lot of them do lie but
sometimes and often the vendors aren't
any more well-informed row we're hopeful
than anybody else that they're trying to
sell so they they repeat the buzz words
they repeat the marketing phrases but
they don't really understand the context
they don't know that there oft this much
the silence create lack of ownership
lack of responsibility
lots of finger-pointing I was spent 10
years not going to hacker conference is
coming to them over the last year to you
now that I'm outside of the bubble lot
of finger-pointing
I think there's a need for introspection
as well as finger-pointing be the
solution that you wanna be silenced two
pipes not not my problem it's somebody
else's problem and then you get this
whole well we're in business to make
money at the end of the day we lot of us
work for companies that are profit
driven and especially this is especially
problematic when your consultant and
advisor or an architectural engineer
working for a product or vendor and and
the recommendation recommendations for
the solution magically is that you're
selling so there's often times as
built-in conflict of interest
warranted some degree that we want
solutions we want the silver bullets
wanna do by something turn it on its
working and we don't have to think about
it so we can move on to something else I
would like to say suggest a vendor that
sells solutions that there really are
owners such thing as solution only
useful if they're being wielded by
people that know how to use them there
was an analogy made up for it he said it
this morning they were talking about new
do you want a house painter or do you
want to use someone who can paint a
masterpiece
where that analogy fell short there's a
whole bunch more demand in need for
house painters in the world than there
are people that complain amounts master
but the point is knowing how to use the
tools that you but there's a significant
need for people that have a basic
awareness and understanding of how did
not sure where that goes I just didn't
completely earlier than the traditional
view of network security the other
economies have a conversation outside a
little while ago the idea that you build
a castle wall you build a fortress you
put all your stuff do you want to
protect inside a bit and then everything
on the outside can't get in and that
whole mindset that whole sort of
paradigm of hell
network security works is kind of going
away
has gone away because whereas the
perimeter these days when you have so
much technology in the clouds much
technology that spiritual so many
business critical applications are
running personal devices that are going
in and out of the network I worked from
home how many people work from home you
know your party or corporate network if
you happen to VPN in but very often
you're connecting to your mail whatever
its all its loud based business
applications so where is the perimeter
so again what I believe is the solution
not sexy and its doesn't mean you
the problem if you're your own company
working for a company if your customers
figured out what it is you're trying to
do
protect is a data is a reputation and in
making those decisions the definition of
risk assessment you have to make some
value judgments how much we going to
invest in the protection of this
protection of that how much you just
gonna have to deal with the education
awareness I can't come up with a better
solution than everybody needs to be
smarter at all levels of the
organization of law at all levels of the
industry
tell what the real risks are what the
problems are the challenges are this
community knows really well what can go
wrong and what can be done what can be
exploited that there's millions of
people out there that don't have access
to this and never will
they're not going to hire they're not
gonna bring it on but they have the same
problems that they're trying to solve
and there's a lot of people outside of
this community that are still within
what could be boosted security they care
about these things and are trying to do
the right things and they're trying to
make an impact in that sense I think
center before I'll say it again the
assigning blame to others it's really
easy especially when you're a group of
your peers it's developed
have secured yeah that's true but
there's more to it what can you do to
changed what can you do to make the
changes a lot of that starts with
education awareness don't assume that
the person you're talking to
understands the world that you wait the
way that you do don't soon even if
you're telling them they have a clue as
to anything you're saying I've been
giving this I'm actually trying to
develop what will be a training course
just trying to teach people as I've been
doing this for a lot a lot of years as a
consultant speaking the lots of
different types of people having to read
them having a try to understand the
language they speak having to speak
their learned to speak their language on
the fly
explain complex concepts things that we
don't necessarily think you're terribly
complex we take it for granted but they
look at us like you got snot coming out
our news they have no clue what we're
saying but explain it in a way that they
begin to understand painting pictures
using analogies speaking their language
trying to put together of course the
kind of helps to teach us know the
answer how to communicate that answer
other people all types first and
foremost saying this for years security
as a verb something you do not a state
it's not not someplace you get to and
you're done a lot of people want that
where they want to buy something that
gets in there don't have to think about
it I don't have intimate knowledge
direct knowledge new cribs came out with
an Oracle the last week or two about
what was going on at Target I suspect
and I haven't read the details on this
article
but I suspected were numerous multiple
failures and it what it appears is a
reputation of being one of the better
merchants actually had a pretty solid I
T staff they had a dedicated security
staff they invested heavily in
technology but I think they fell into
that trap we've got all these silver
bullets that were ok rather than
continuing to monitor and look at it and
realize the kind of information that was
at their fingertips they kind of the
scene today Roque as they had this great
panacea this false sense of security
because they had it obviously that
didn't work too so in terms of your
where we go from here and this is again
this is meant to be just to get you
think get you thinking and approach this
whole prince with your thinking twice
about everything you're hearing how can
I expand and rethink this and this and
look at it in a different direction i've
seen it already this today there's a
severe need humility calling the people
that don't know what you know stupid or
dumb I don't think is appropriate as you
need to be able to speak to them because
often they are the ones that hold the
purse strings that the decision makers
and it's on it's on you to help them
understand there's more to it than pen
testing in hacking this is an important
component but there's a larger business
problem there's more things to go into
the hole to the whole package that helps
a company be secure whatever that is the
best way to learn how to
communicate to others is the first
listen some this is like basic a speech
class colleges persuasive speech
education where we all need to be
teachers we know we know more than the
next guy teaching we know more
we don't know what we know find out what
the next they might have something to
teach you as well I really like to talk
about security being a game I prefer to
think of it is a puzzle puzzles tend to
have solution there might be more than
one solution that there's a solution and
I'm not talking just about the
technology but going into a company and
having to learn what the corporate
environment is the corporate culture
being in a room with a group of people
and learning who the learning with the
power structure is learning who's really
in charge and influencers in a group
that's something that you know it's part
art form I think but I think there's
ways techniques that you can learn to
try to figure that out so that you can
read the company and give them the
recommendations that are tailored to
them that's again it's a communication
skill if your gonna be if you are in a
capacity of advising you've gotta be
trusted you need to be trustworthy you
don't usually gain trust again by
calling somebody stupider or snickering
out them if they ask to see the question
asks stupid questions yourself I used to
play dumb all the time
explain this to me I don't know how to
explain it to you got a lot of juicy
information about how the routers and
the rest in the networking worked
Company two great little too it's not a
stretch
perfect security is not a is not in 10
games not the desired state it's a
process that's ongoing
sprint certain amount of paranoia
paranoia is overboard with some of these
are just rambling thoughts
the overall goal is perfect security the
best thing you can do is monitor the
crap out of everything so you detect
early when something happens minimize
questions feedback heckle anybody there
sir sir microphone proportion I don't
think the issue is it's not the issues
not the PCI standard and what PCR
requires you see more so is the way that
the industry has allowed people to game
the system and do the bare minimum just
to get a check box do so
way that against the the good PCI is
done or compliance is done in terms of
ten years ago when I got started in PCI
my first customer was a payment
processor one of the rather large ones
and there is credit card information
everywhere there was sensitive
authentication data to the three for
digis you know
by the millions in in rather log files
as somebody would turn on for
troubleshooting and never turned it off
I mean it was everywhere in every
company I went to data was everywhere
the accounting department the finance
department they wanted to do a database
query to get some information about her
transaction the previous week so the
most convenient search item was the
credit card so they would use out of the
search criteria and they didn't know how
to do you know efficient search and so
is just easier just dumped down all the
data on their laptop in on the share
drive I've been to too many companies
were everywhere so the game at PCI has
become limiting scope which means you
segment the network which means you
isolate your card data environment you
can argue that segmentation is a good
concept the game has become what what do
I limit things to so I don't have to
bother with PCI the benefit has been
they've had to understand how their
their network is working how the data is
flowing and and limited isolated and
clean up their mess basically and get it
down to a few places there's been a huge
benefit to that company's I didn't you
recently do a lot more lo and behold
they find out they don't need to keep
the credit card number at all and that
makes everything go away so you know
there's pros and cons there's certainly
a way that it's a large way the
compliance is being gamed and that
contributes to the problem again the
root cause i think is the lack of
education and awareness awareness having
Aqsa
altered come in and explain this is why
this rule exists this is why it's
important this is why you should take it
seriously in this is how you should do
it rather than just show me something
and I'll check the other questions just
a really tough question the question is
can I comment on coming up with ROI for
solutions to the real trick is if your
company has been broken into an
experienced the loss of a breach you
must be doing ok but there's no return
that or you don't know unfortunately
it's sort of an inverse you you know how
expensive it is when stuff goes bad and
how much that costs but it's really hard
to convince most people you know how
much they need to invest to prevent that
from happening you know there's all
sorts of formulas out there and
determining risk in and stuff like that
I had CEOs and CIOs and CTOs and I
talked to over the years were you ask
them what do you want your company's
name in the newspaper so I'm old school
what do you want them on trips to be the
next article and Crips and the like 10
of course not how much do you want to
spend to prevent that
what's appropriate there's really no
right answer to that question
start talking to put yourself out there
in the middle of lead by example don't
wait for somebody else to do it first
you might get the door slammed
rhetorically but start doing it would be
my advice to begin in the classical
sense trained security was you develop a
policy which is sort of the ten
commandments thou shalt we're gonna do
this do this then you come up with
standards that say this is how we meet
this policy goal in this environment in
this platform this operating system or
application or system but even then it
still kind of high level without the
details but begins to drill down and
then the the the the highest drill down
as the the actual procedures were
actually this encryption algorithm can
use this key length we're gonna this is
how we're gonna do key management so on
and so forth so it kind of bills so the
idea of not being able to tackle it all
really goes up to the
figuring out what the problem is you
know what are the absolute in some ways
it's all the risk management what are
you gonna do what do you not gonna do
you think you can't do it then what in
your view what are your alternatives and
usually the alternative is know what's
going on your network monitor you know
maybe you can't stop everybody at least
try to detect it happened that makes
this and I'm not saying that just
because my company does monitor that
maybe I M
any other questions a question you know
I think there's a lot of us that are
smarter that I think there's a lot of
this by no fault of our own especially
if you're new to the business we don't
always we older people don't always
teach the historical context the meaning
what why do we do things a certain way
why is this good why is this dad we just
kinda latch onto all things have to be
this way things had to be this way one
of the other talks I'd given his
lunabelle penetration testing I used to
do penetration testing I stopped for two
reasons one has the guys that I did
better than me and i said i remember the
day when we were at a site and I found a
few vulnerable X servers and so I was
capturing keystrokes and I showed it to
the guy was with his oh yeah I wrote a
Python script I found ninety servers
monitoring right now
ok I'm done
but but the main reason I stopped was
because I got bored because like many
people that are penned testers you'll
hear this
find vulnerabilities that should have
been fixed shouldn't be getting into the
default password you shouldn't be
finding a default setting you shouldn't
be finding something that was turned on
it shouldn't been turned off or was left
on or you come back six months later a
year later and even though you told them
how bad it was
it's still there I decided gotta be a
different way to to go about doing this
especially being hired to be a pen
tester pen testing is a very expensive
inefficient way of doing they're
scanning technology that does that it's
where PCI is an interesting framework
PCI assumes that you build secure
networks he built secure servers you
hard and everything you securely
configured everything you've got
patching programs in place you've got
monitoring in place then you run the
skin shouldn't find anything but our
industry I know leads with the scanning
leads with the vulnerability assessment
and and and that's tied up in pen
testing as well and I'm not talking
about pen testing this hacking the
breaking stuff i'm talking bout pen
testing that's that usually ends up
finding vulnerabilities that there were
other more efficient ways of getting to
that point especially if somebody's
paying you to do it to answer your
question it'll yes we'll talk more
overburdened any other questions in the
back first
hoping I'm retired and i really often
sometimes wonder if we've gotten any
better i mean the technology changes we
plug one hole but a new one pops up and
and and they're sort of this built in
everything that exists in technology
these days is designed to be seen was in
fast information sharing kinda publicly
from wherever to wherever and oh by the
way responses protected so that there's
sort of this built-in it's always gonna
fail kind of thing so probably I could
give this talking
yes one question I think it stopped
under wraps yes
largely done for the wrong reason and
it's largely ill-defined disorder talk
been recorded their son where the pen
testing time and time again is really
efficient and expensive way of doing
vulnerability is what pen testing should
be in again they mentioned it this
morning
pen testing should be imitating the
threat you've closed all your holes
you've done everything you can to patch
and and lock everything down then hire
the pen tester come in my experience
especially in the DoD implementation is
where things fall apart and that's what
needs to be tested but the emblem
implementation be tested by
impersonating the threat not and it's
not a matter of finding other
vulnerabilities the other point to make
is if you're doing pen testing your pen
test report finding should not be I
found a missing patch the system was not
patched thats not defining that's the
symptom the finding is your patch
management processes broken fix it
because I found a bus you understand the
difference
our time as the next