as TV talk quickly
start or wait
have they been closing doors when your
sister I don't know how behind it as
other people starting are you ready to
go so I'm going wow that's pretty
enthusiastic goodness gracious lots of
people are coming in here today I'm
talking about problems in the
information security industry that's a
theme to say I haven't noticed of the
people who talk about the problems very
many answers to many of the problems
they bring up I'm gonna talk about the
art and science of communicating with
your developers this is a problem with
easy answers but it requires a certain
level of understanding from someone with
their foot in both camps and there just
aren't very many of those people I
happen to be one of them over who I him
in a minute
the nice thing about this is that it is
a series of problems that are really
clear to understand have social
implications but potentially solutions
can solve some of the really big
problems that were spoken about the
panel yesterday morning how many people
were the opening
I was really good wasn't I'd love to do
that some of the developer conferences
get some security people out do that so
I mean explain his problems from the
Middle that's where I live between
development security and then we all
talk about the solutions that i've
encountered so far so because of that
unlike my normal talks if you've heard
me speak before I I don't normally mind
this time right now in your questions
because I'm probably an answer in the
second half
alright so developers are difficult to
communicate with the reason too
difficult to communicate with us because
we have more telling them that despite
what their users say that their coats
socks and as it turns out they don't
care for their kids like telling them
their bibi is ugly
many of these developers that you're
working with on a day-to-day basis
consider themselves artists and very
reasonably so development is an art it
is very techincal but it is an art in
these people pour a lot of their own
energy into the code especially the good
ones but even the good ones make
security vulnerabilities in their coat
and it's our job to tell them about
those in this is what they go and do
afterwards
we've got to solve the problem 89% of
recent recent breaches that have
resulted in data loss or in some way to
do it is a big part it isn't everything
that is always web apps that are the
problem but it is a major problem that
we have to be dealing
someone had to write the code that
caused the breaches we are the people
who get to talk to those people so
that's what we're gonna talk about money
is built on Twitter that's what they
asked for my name I used to be an IRC
fanatic I spent a lot of time talking
chatting on IRC I enjoy that quite a bit
but I have switched over to Twitter even
though it's a little too hipster
did I do something wrong even a little
too hipster for me in a lot of ways
because its global conversation I love
that I love to chat about this stuff I
love to bring up idea so if you're a
person followed me in and let's chat
about application security I'm husband
my way to actually attend easier for the
first time in three or four years
sitting there between social engineering
and talks and whatnot
many of the camera couldn't get up this
morning to the home school and so we
hope that the father of two young
children that's just heartwarming to see
the kids want around here
of my youngest to sport a little young
to really get anything out of it my
oldest is 10 at Circle City Khan
attended her kids and is still talking
about the wifi hacking clinic it was
your house I mean he'll tell any anybody
who asks about he's sitting in scouts
else talking to people about wifi
hacking and they're like so didn't have
the password that you did have expressed
in Birmingham the one widely bottom in
2004 I moved to that end zone 16 books
and software development starting with
the earliest dotnet looks back in ninety
nine and finished up most recently with
a Windows 8 Store apps book we all know
how that went it was a fun book to write
a software composer
term because of a second term architect
coder which isn't exactly I'm not great
term from a book called lorem ipsum
lorem Ipsum is a hundred and thirty-six
pitched children's book about software
engineering and frankly I learned more
in this book that I didn't so if you
have a chance to pick it up at your son
or daughter and learn something yourself
in the book Lauren travels through the
skin tactically and with these towns are
all based on software engineering
principles both good and bad for
instance Saunders the waters who piled
walks off to build houses when it
collapsed to the only PayPal more rocks
on top of them
I'm but then there's the composer's this
beautiful land with with his late Terry
spires and the people who do the work
composers because the big beautiful
things and that is what I do I stand on
the shoulders of giants
coat that other people have written and
private with code that I have written in
meet beautiful things that is what I
like to do most recently the application
vulnerability doesn't even fit on the
damn slide does it well this is what we
call everything pen testing right
the fact is there's a bit of a
difference between pen testing and
vulnerability investors have a very
difficult job they're given a goal at
the password file then they have to
write down how they did it they have to
use a wide range of skills from
lockpicking to driving the secretary to
leading us he's outside and getting show
of workstations all these different
things on the other hand are given one
application and are asked to find every
flaw and that is what I do I take one
application and everything that I read a
report in a way that's harder because of
interest really only one way to find all
of them in a way it's easier for
instance I'm very rarely threatened with
jail
sometimes so personally I'm home I bring
for many years I recently but i just ask
anybody here happens no friendly
friendly used to be the risk
guy for PNC Bank and I have had the
pleasure of working with leaders in fact
in Columbus
John Schneider who I think stuck in the
back here recently moved to Texas like
that to take over the Columbus locks
Power Systems join us we meet at the
boundary I am a ninja throwing I need
actually fifty been to Japan in July
study for a number of years and it's not
just a martial art there's a lot of
stuff concepts involved in it that I
find very handy in this industry
constructionist I have a habit of saying
exactly exactly the wrong time as it
turns out this is a huge benefit and
security business whereas it was quite a
problem in the in the development
industry so so there's react that's who
I am so let's talk about what's wrong
with a pretty large collection of things
that's wrong but don't get depressed on
me
will soon moved its solutions and the
solutions are much easier than you think
there's a breakdown in communication
between information security ok the
program the stuff and us as security
people have this gap in court things
that I will go over the first is the
security is concerned about risk whereas
developers are concerned about usability
ok the second is that security sees
things in terms of vulnerabilities
whereas developer see things in terms of
defects the third thing is that security
has an unnatural kind of shocked truck
will catch you later when it comes to
severity of things
severity of finding and the fourth is
that there's something of a culture
break between the people who participate
in the people who participate in the
development industry
I'm not gonna lie this middle section of
the talk is Travis panorama a little bit
because I deal with this on both sides
every single day and it's a little
frustrating so is part of the reason why
this talk exists if you think you drink
because you try being a developer in
InfoSec there is a reason why oo has
lasts with their logo on its ok it
doesn't get worse problem risk back
developers are just trying to make
something that's what they want their
vehicle and save your passwords wrong
user is in our system security says who
are right we we get upset about this
write-up they see what we did I'm trying
to do something next to the user I'm
trying to trying to make it so that they
know what the pics too bad they can
harvest user names using that gotta get
rid of it
generic error message for this I don't
care what the problem clickjacking
another one you know all they want to
say it's allow people to frame their
site if they need to we see didn't you
see kaminsky talk black right it's not
if you don't know jack and jackie is you
a redress vulnerability and more or less
what you what I can do the developers I
can if I can dream your site I take my
able site not come up with an iframe on
top of your site in internet with with
CSS
sheets but I put my site under he shows
through I push my buttons strategically
where your buttons would be if we are
looking to do something transfer money
changing password change email address
whatever delete all your emails in the
example here provide a bunch of Monaco
and also you can do things like putting
invisible iframe on top of potential
deal on top of a free speech that then
collects your credentials so I put
invisible deal on top of your login
login it actually goes to my server and
then I just redirect to the real lock
right so it's a real possibility I like
I said Dan Kaminsky literally did a talk
on black hat it's on YouTube watching
its really good but it's just losing
potentially losing user names one of the
time and it's just it requires a
phishing attack and it's just not that
severe and the devs just want to let
people from the site
institution and this is a great one
across a scripting normally but you know
those times you just can't get the
popular sure why work shows it's there
you can see very clearly and Jason
response like this but they've got their
content types that the Jason and there's
just no place in the application returns
and scripting but she still wanna write
up here I have insufficient
implementation will this means that the
developers to go and find all of these
weird imports of this API and do a ton
of crap to it later this is why they
don't like you
another example of these crypto
vulnerabilities b2 and b3 r/c for safer
all that traffic cure your whatever page
or you know Automobile Parts research
page was going to do this this yet its
PCI and they require us to do tomorrow
even the fact is one phone call today
helped is 100 million times more
effective than trying to decrypt the T
lest I forget somebody's credentials
frankly it's probably more effective
than any getting somebody's it's just
not small-scale her abilities get picked
on yet we write them up to be like he's
nice PCB reports to explain our interest
then the devs see it year after year
after year and they keep going back to
visit people say people talking about
this doesn't make any sense to me at all
so there in lies the problem with these
sources do we really need to be talking
vulnerabilities presenting more should
we be talking about bugs in software
defects they don't care about that meets
your day with the chain exploit they
just want to know what's wrong with
their codes they can fix it but yet all
of our templates in reporting your setup
to describe the vulnerabilities yes it's
true some developers kinda get that
forbidden knowledge to induce 2010 the
dark side of its own and it shows up in
training which will talk about a little
bit later but for the most part what we
need to be doing is putting our reports
in such a way that they can be entered
in the bucket the bug tracking tracking
system which is jerry is a defect
tracking system for me with it if you're
not you should be a look at that a
minute to this is gonna be a kind of a
big sea change will talk about it
section of the thirty pieces right we
really want to shock people with the
severity of our abilities we label
security specific get the attention of
Management ok and also frankly it's
easier to back off than it is to push it
up we realize it's worse than we thought
so we have good reasons for doing this
but it's got
a little extreme and you have to read
your seat 944 site for high because of
PCI but you really know about that man
that's how many they just care and were
reading too many things hi it's just
what we were creating this just just
blind spot in the developers they just
don't see this is what we look like to
them okay and there's a good reason
because that is what we look like you
get the idea
one last thing to
doesn't really have any solutions but I
think require some understanding is that
there is something of a dramatic
personality difference between the kind
of people who do development and the
kind of people who do information
security sometimes just find it two
different categories of people don't
have enough in common data meaningful
conversation and this is one of those
cases there's not a lot we can do about
that you probably all no one of those
men right Chris Dickerson of course you
don't know him he should be able to stop
hands woman who is kind of the pool of
Microsoft
fool the justice s brilliant technology
is also a trained mediator guy and
stand-up comic in his talks are amazing
mind blowing never seen two different
person if they were in the same room
there might be like an issue and they
pretty much mark a lot of the chasm
between development interests there's
not a lot we can do about that the
careers draw different kinds of people
pay the reason why I'm in both is
because I'm so socially awkward doesn't
matter anyway anybody so because of that
kind of in with everybody but thank you
but I know normal people
they work with people best to sit with
them best
normal people so yeah so that culture of
violence itself another whole category
of problems right there's a different
language a little bit but is a community
department whatever we're not just our
customers who are the developers in many
cases understand right we ask yourself
questions equipment to receive a Taser
inputs a few percent in just another
readout call and remembered that
reflected cross-site scripting was in
the last report and the one before that
and the Liberal Arts will explain why
program is really really have you tried
and I don't mean Python scripting
autonomously module I mean in a
structured environment in a statically
typed language with libraries given to
you by architects that left the company
years ago with the style guide with
five-year-old development tools and then
make the software work and make it
secure
it's not easy to do and then you got
people to please and thank you for your
understanding as it turns out developers
heavy schedule the features they have to
implement a certain time if certain way
this is what it looks like ok we need to
do no matter what whether its
months-long traditional documented cycle
or weeks-long actual super quick let's
get use your card and a pencil cycles of
hipsters do you know you always have to
decide how it's gonna do it decide how
we're going to convince the damn
computer to do it for us to test it out
there keep it working and eventually get
rid of those things happen every time no
matter what and guess what's gonna
happen when you walk in the middle of a
cycle and say these books for next
deployment
they just aren't going to do it it's not
even that they don't want you
the fact is very very rigid even if you
actually get all these supposedly a
judge was to be able to move around but
it's not very structured developers are
very structured
software tools are very structured
throwing a document them in the middle
of the cycle isn't gonna get you
anywhere and we simply as a community
understand that instead we get buy-in
from business it is that I have a whole
sex right solutions but I couldn't
resist using the slide saying we need to
find someone who can prioritize the
security problems on the business side
solve this problem
need to understand the dats Yi
developers business side not unlike a
normal social engineering right you just
gotta find the people who actually make
the important thing to on the language
side you need to understand the platform
for developers are building and I've got
the big players in in in big boxes with
the fact is in Java there's a really big
difference between jelly beans in like
WebSphere that you have to understand
what the platform is if your asp.net
webforms UMBC
version of NBC Ron do you know what that
implies you need to truly understand
that and I don't mean you let you know
you watched the launch video and
investing in something like that I mean
actually understand development tools
installed on your workstation oh im
sorry I forgot to put those are the ones
I was talking about earlier
so yes the big players right so we know
what the problems are now right we've
got culture rift we've got language
problems mostly about naming and
severity but other things too and
there's generally a lack of mutual
understanding these are all social
problems and most of his part really
solid social people so what are we gonna
do exactly
well there's three things you need to
focus ok first second is well everything
else the stuff we shouldn't talk to me
right in the third trying to find ways
to hone their relationships without
having to be a psychologist social
engineering to understand the problems
to social problems in order to implement
solutions you need to have maps the
relationships I mean I don't mean you
need to necessarily start a month ago
file on your company may not be aware my
idea frankly so let's start with enemies
so it's odd to me what we can so much of
the stuff ends up being done by hand or
just ignored because we have the
machines doing the wrong things right
where we can we just need to script it
and forget it
the effort requires joint work between
InfoSec and development because you
don't know where they're built server is
and they don't have any idea when you
got to work together the first thing you
wanna do is give them the tools to do
their job
ok make sure developers and QA have
security tools at their disposal
one of the smartest things I've ever
done is give that way it's free it's
good because you a people goodwin's
really get off on software just like we
do they just do it a little differently
they want to bring it from the business
process ID but if you shown that the way
the fact that you can take Japanese
characters in there and you shouldn't be
able to probably means you can't right
ankle brace should look what you can do
that all that slick let's look for some
more right there aren't enough upset
people getting this little more later
this is how we make more ok declining
Columbus did training said hey we're
still exists here to use a security
training awesome is there to wait while
I was jus is already testing your apps
shouldn't they be looking at security St
should Cartwright QA shows up at two
locations that group in Cleveland and
Columbus reviewing all the stuff in the
training gives training dilemmas awesome
afterwards but I need to know that
someone to read up about and you get
that book thanks love least 88 people in
the room
kept me there for an hour asking
questions how do I type this in my
testing session how we built can we
integrate this with the right now
the really good ones like I said I
already like to bring the song when they
really very much enjoy finding new ways
to solve the problems they face every
day
fantastic they already know how to use
the lower probably and yes well tools
this is just a slightly better version
from our perspective that's all it is
then on the development side of things
get people using Python to automate
their tools
amazed how many really phenomenally
talented developers don't know any
scripting I dot net Java Ruby is
technically scripting language I guess
but the greatest intestine code but if
they need to whip something up real
quick to move some files over here and
check the integrity of them the right to
counsel and see sorry I was one of those
people for 15 years I kid you not I
always I mean we back in the Daniel
Pearl back in the early nineties but
when perot kinda fell out of favor and
it all diverted and everything got
messed up I just kind of built
everything in its charm so giving giving
developers the tools and showing them
how to use the tool to automate tasks
that should be fairly straightforward is
a great start towards aiming towards
more secure coaches you can check things
you can you can modify things you can
take care of your source code better
with the two like Python you can with
many other things and it's not just for
the right home builder deployments if
you don't wanna get a big fancy to like
optimist or something like that
to do what to do with big large-scale
deployment training medium-sized
shopping you looking to see twelve
thousand dollars a year a lot just my
code but you need something for
deployment to end up moving up the web
config file in your comments and your
javascript and we find your developers
names looking up on Stack Overflow not
that whatever happened that
deployment scripts are good to see your
deficit people probably already python
is this anyway but get that tire right
make sure that the developers understand
what they can do with those tools
analysis is a good counterpoint to this
ok tools for the people are good too
machines are even better right automate
ourselves a little bit of staff in-house
testing program at rest or at rest
looking at the source code for potential
death that the reason why this is there
gonna they're gonna push back if you try
to implement it
the reason why is because its most often
used for style checking which no to
developers agree on all right where you
could truly braces tapped her state's
all that stuff but it's very very
powerful tool for security check under
some circumstance so there's a lot of
good tools and I am NOT going to go
vermont certainly go walk around in the
vendors will be more than happy to talk
to you about static analysis however
there aren't very many free tools
because static analysis is a development
tool and what we learn about development
it's hard very hard
only recently actually have the tools
become any kind of these recently maybe
in the past six seven years I personally
have used to fortify which now owned by
HP I he's their code check marks and I
like them all for different things in
different kinds of shops you're gonna
have to do some analysis on what's best
for you but use the vendors developers
like bankers security people hate him
because everybody's coming to us saying
one thing but internet working to solve
all your problems
new developer told us that developer
tool vendors are very very unfocused he
wasn't here is a plugin for Visual
Studio give you access to release of
security source control modules and it's
only $150 victory and that's that's how
it works with death I was shocked when I
started moving into the urban street
fifty years ago or so how much everybody
hated the vendors I understand why but
it's not like that for depp's so what
does static analysis tools do well the
first thing that you will see check your
input validation right they can look and
make sure that you aren't so input
sources and we have six where this input
comes from and where it could go the
delegates reflected back on the screen
to process my backend system or whatever
it's relatively easy for automated
system to discover that now they can
make false positive we'll talk about
that a minute but it is relatively easy
to find we talk about bounds checking
reports overflow problems were counting
is involved computers are very good
accounting they're very good at looking
at source code figuring out he made a
mistake with your cult are also very
good at finding deprecated code and this
is where it's really interesting David
libraries all algorithms incorrect
encryption all pieces even when you're
using parts of the language that there's
a better version for static code
analysis time those very very easily
however you have to have a triage
process if you run veracode in throwing
three hundred page report over the walls
of the developers it will get thrown
away I have done it a hundred and fifty
times in my career
literally just thrown the report way
click Delete I just it doesn't do me any
good it's p
will this might be time for the man I
got features I've got a place where
we're trying to figure this already got
to do a story cards for the next sprint
I don't have time for this
you must do triage you must do triage
and then translated into something
developers will understand we'll talk
about it automatic game image analysis
is good at certain things to write so we
all want to just skin running out what
they need scanning those uses a template
of a site so many people here who is
purposely or is it a crazy with it so
sweet
the idea is you generate a sitemap you
use the site as a user would it find all
the content putting real data
remembers everything you said all the
requests then you say ok look good in a
spider anything else that discovers and
you look through those in so many other
floors then you say here's the
interesting forms of interested in those
can go and look for certain things that
binds well based on the dealy you
provided so it's not completely you have
to set up a template first but once
you've done it so automatic looking at
output encoding the other side of
community action Sunday people are going
to figure out how to really put that
together and genuinely able to find all
the way across its gonna happen someday
but if that can happen to their very to
discovering information disclosure ok
we're your your API is leaking per
account numbers or developers names in
comments or birth dates or credit card
numbers and said that already or new to
the slightly don't
discovering exceptions ok so it it's
scanning your state it generates
exceptions and look I got an exception
back in his source code in it
see that and report back to you would
take you forever to do that manually
choose you have to look at every single
response but it does it very quickly so
anything is very response to another
question is something you can find very
well off problems to request forgery and
application no indication of those kinds
of pieces of stuff the stuff that the
machine finds well once again there's a
human element here you absolutely must
reoffer just like with the source code
scanning if you screw over the static or
dynamic analysis report you will get
thrown away I have thrown away more of
these I have my guarantee you it's just
not useful by itself you must have a
triage process in place so that leads to
another way of looking at this sometimes
the human has to drop I know I just a
bunch of human task but sometimes things
done by rehearsal
so the reason why humans are needed for
some of this is because of insight we
can make connections that the machine
simply can't make like cross-site
scripting we can make the connection
Emily between the input which destroyed
do well and output which the dynamic
skinner's do well we can do that
ourselves so there's some things that
need to be done by a person pen testing
is the obvious one what is interesting
or application vulnerability analysis
which isn't that interesting there see
my entry was good for something it is
dynamic and there's there's anything
else that's what one really knows
something's only human is gonna see only
a human is going to look at that get
that post for this get and say I wanna
what happens when you get that number of
machines not gonna do that she has a
preset list of putting it just came in
there and report on the results it is
not gonna think the seven but we know
what happened to me that the seven you
get the next Facebook user try it
sometime
UCP over someone's 2018 you can read a
Python script 11 lines down everybody
human is going to go find helpers named
in an XML file comment on Stack Overflow
and find new machines gonna do that only
human can do this
ok there's some things to do humans too
well but the fact is you're still gonna
have to explain results cause of
quarters are over there following their
little process cutting tools on it if
you give them that Pinterest even though
the dentist reporters only three pages
like 300 pages they're still gonna throw
away because it's written in languages
and you need to fix that also remembers
third-party testers will not understand
your environment you must take that into
consideration ok they're not going to
know the different tiers of your
application
what the OP services for the fact that
some of them don't matter of public
teasing there's a dozen examples
sometimes you can go a long relationship
with a vendor sometimes but frankly most
of the time to report a black box in
that doesn't make it any easier for the
developers reports really don't
understand is the person who wrote the
report didn't understand the bed people
just because they're so we've got
automated static analysis automated
dynamic analysis me with an image
analysis the last manual static analysis
which is personal code review I talked
about last topic overview and this is
something to Debs do anyway all you need
to do is insert your own code review
under a discrete list are short discrete
list of things to look for
not not like let's talk actually short
humans check the things that they can do
well make sure that the access control
meets the standard make sure it's
encrypted properly looked back doors the
developers of last cause those are
unlikely to be found accidentally fired
stacked or dynamic tools you know when
the devs leave the company they're gonna
remember there there and show their
friends on Friday night after I had a
couple drinks trust me it happen
making sure to properly secure service
call talking the database server
security and things like that that stuff
it's much easier for a human to just
look for that term she defined so fine
rescue here's your application and most
importantly logging never something to
the tools were gonna find for you in any
case but absolutely so important when
you're dealing with disaster Recovery
Minister Gerry key to make sure logging
poses teens humans have foresight
ahead and think about potential issues
they can run into it you fix the
problems before they occur
your life is so much better
next door by the way which I would
totally be in his doctor wasn't giving
one so this is the first route first but
I'm gonna watch when it when it gets so
as it turns out there's a list for this
alright the product of top 10 it's an
awesome project how many people know
what all is OK
half asleep or don't know so tell you
what's the open web application security
project it's a non-profit international
organization that is entirely designed
to do what I'm doing right now which is
spread the word about what up what up
the security there specifically about
spreading at the developers were I try
to do both come up here and say is a
developer and talk to the security
people in her so so they have projects
in place and also local chapter meetings
which are you going to is there Luva
lost chapter in Louisville lost chapter
there's the chapter leader of the
Louisville off after go see him after my
talk so the pro pro ActiveX controls for
development Jimmy echo chamber and kitty
in a casket out many of us just made it
up myself included and what they are is
a list of security techniques should be
included in the design every single
project ok so what are we talking about
here we're talking about you know one of
the first to the first two are we would
call him
scripting see projections mean injection
right but just spoken language
these are the things that you have
talked about privatizing queries
encoding down in the first three great
indication authorization and access
control me about thirty US top ten year
the are implementing appropriate access
controls establish identity right
protecting privacy then we get well
logging talked about that earlier but
then we get into the architectural
sightings leveraging security features
of your framework because you know all
know you're framework because you listen
to the beginning of the top and we found
out
includes the security specific
requirements in your carpets gathering
design architect security in these are
the controls you can use as for sites
are talking about the digital divide
earlier and there's a real social
divisions in the second evidence true
and none of us are probably not a good
social and social people were good
engineers advantage of vulnerabilities
humans building relationships are
sometimes hard for this community things
like this are fantastic but not always
even with this have the skills are a lot
of looks leading developers notes it
just works well with so many things for
instance training which we all have to
do or get done
deaths listen better when they're fed
it's true and not just pizza we've all
had peter the dot net users group and
stuff i mean good food I had a lot of
luck with a pattern like this we start
out with some security principals right
minimize tax service areas establish
secure the whole release privilege
defense in depth deal securely all the
things that are standardized matter here
and then turn that into testing your own
stuff right training with with said
attack proxy understanding with the
attack postures are and then finally we
try to secure coding look at what your
platform are four star security how best
to implement it roll that back in the
security principal just keep going
around in a circle around in a circle
where do you find materials for this
send you back to all those search for
training Charles you might wanna try to
just go to Google and say oh i paint
ariel's
all of medical slides up there you can
use them to do the training freedom
you'd be surprised how receptive them
very hard to find application security
people
recent client of mine one of their
people that worked out last funny
because one of the people who worked for
that company sitting in the crowd on
trying not to look at it and they they
tried to hire somebody with using their
own recruiting group in and it didn't
work as well and so they did what most
complete doing you know blasted out to
the world everything I got 46 phone
calls and six weeks for the position
because my title on LinkedIn for six
years has been application security
architect which as it turns out that's
turned into the term for what those
people do I don't either the application
to people who do get sex stuff finally
the guy called me directly
the recruiter at the company he just
come help us out so I can help and it's
good stuff actually a lot of my eye I
have many people understand offended by
the way I'm just a myself together I'll
run our company we just meet her and I
mean you're so the fact is that we have
to make more abstract people there
aren't enough of them we knew train them
you find that they like it if you did
you teach don't just train
actually you all over this wouldn't be
any training like that of all this you
must love it
wire right we're just holding tools for
people to do cool things on the internet
right
we're trying to effectively solve the
same problems developers trying to meet
users lives better with their software
to protect your wants to make sure that
the people that uses offered to get
screwed you know I'm on both those camps
sometimes I don't get along with me
ok I understand how this all works but
the fact is the social skills aren't
really our thing but we need to least
understand what the developers are going
through when was the last time you used
your developer tools for developers used
walk in their footsteps truly right do
you know which hospital systems have
asked right now to go into the system
and get the production version could you
look at the coat ok I'm seems Nottingham
that makes me happy with it if you don't
do that so where does this leave us we
didn't talk talk because it's too long
as it is only have a couple minutes left
that's a whole other thing but when I
found her usual is really a three-part
thing that kind of breaks into four
parts I like this graphic for it at the
top we start to get the architecture on
both sides and poultry ok which will do
next year then static analysis both
automated and manual and dynamic
analysis both automated and manual all
wrapped around a soft chewy middle of
training ok this is how we start to
build some kind of a social dynamic a
technical solution to a social problem
we build things that the developers in
the security people have to work
together there's no other choice you
must work on it together because we're
all seeing team the end right we're
really all just trying to make things
happen we need to sit around the table
understanding that everybody off the
table does something slightly different
well I should have put the graphic up
you know the graphic that everybody
talks about with the imposter syndrome
and it's got here's what you do well
circle in the middle and here's what
everybody else does well with a little
circles all the way around you and it
looks like you like surrounded by his
knowledge but really they're just two
circles themselves just like you are
that's the that in a nutshell is the
development and security divide
I know it sounds like I'm appreciating
platitudes but sometimes it's a
platitude because it's true you know it
really is
gotta remember the security is not
developers first or second or third
concern and it frankly it shouldn't we
shouldn't be in this position but we are
so we need to make sure the securities
are concerned and we're supporting them
they need to understand that we've got a
job to do and they need to work with us
when we get the time at the time will
have to give a little teeny bit I'm at
some point Twitter a lot of us get rid
of a blog post the clock at I wrote
earlier feel free to go to reread it
slipped my mind on twitter if you have
anything I'll take any questions anybody
has now
of the map and we'll see you all the
rest of the car and very much