everyone down but today I'm gonna be
into it because I'm kinda bought stuff
to go over so much for us still works
out
silver lining is open only I could see
that our city and gender so over
exploitation basics recover some of
their common vulnerability classes so
that explains that we see and then we're
going to dive into what those classes
need to us when it comes to things like
our reliability text tricks that we can
use how do we take up four billion take
it and use it to get code execution
which states were always after eckstein
code and hit on mitigation technology
sometimes little bit like asking for
things like that some of the newer
technologies at the problems that we
have their running into these armored
how bad are correctly display framework
so how they're actually implemented we
talk about the basic two different types
of the exploits as a framework and then
some of the common techniques they use
which is very very interesting at least
from my perspective is a lot of
domestically exploits are some of the
more reliable exploits in my opinion
sort of the techniques that they are
using how can they be applied to other
exploits stand-alone ones if you are so
inclined to write a 4-1 and finally
talked about improving reliability is
really the reason why I wanted to give
the stock is that there's tons of really
awesome curl research exploit research
out there is really good but I find a
lot of it is not particularly
edge cases that you know the stars like
white right now like its December
meeting type of portability but a lot of
times they're not always the most
reliable exploit and a practical
actually needs to be reliable
a lot of you in here are probably Penn
testers CSR Hebel quick up ten testers
ok so on the flip side if you consider
yourself a plurality of researchers I
see I see your hands ok so not quite as
many vulnerability researchers I hope
that somebody everybody gets a little
bit of something in here but a lot of
you are penned testers and what's
probably the most important thing to you
is these reliable
exploits need to be able i was the first
and foremost thing because if you're not
like we're gonna lose that shell in and
nobody wants that this never get that
money slots are you saying you are
indeed going to cut that short a lot of
the things in this presentation will
cause you to death under just like any
other problems there is no one solution
that fits every day and try to try to
minimize the blue screens and different
techniques used to do that so that's a
blue screen right there that's running
into with an AK-forty board you will
find out a little bit last year some the
basics on so y creo exploitation why why
do we care there's been a downward trend
remote code execution vulnerabilities
arguably one of the last great once was
a mess of a 267 all depend testers
favorite that reliable code execution
that you can still find I found on a
domain controller kind of sad but it is
starting to become less and West
apparently people are actually catching
up so she is now generally being found
in Lex 3rd party libraries and things
like that so you're getting things we
are still seen RCG but they're not quite
as like traveling in the window of
source
curl exploits is that the kernel is
always there the Windows kernel is
always going to be there soon attack
surface that is not easy to get away
from unless you're running Linux you're
probably going to have to win two
scoreless not really any way to to
mitigate that also come into why you see
a lot of plants that exploits that
drivers
abilities a sort of second phase 2 once
an attacker compromises of like a
browser something like that deliver to
Kurt Warner ability to escalate
themselves and they usually get out of
some type of sandbox and things like
that a lot of these loans were seen are
being released from I told our own lives
like fantastic bugs that are coming out
there and enacted the researchers
released then there they have their day
on there were at least in like write-ups
afterwards people can actually to figure
out like what they did and you know they
just closed the vulnerabilities that
we're seeing a lot of great research
coming out the podium competition as far
as Colonel bugs another fantastic
resource that we're seeing a lot is the
Google security research six they're
releasing a lot about colonel bilities
as well
to look back on it and these are a bunch
of kernel bug that I found to be notable
the reason why I found these wants to be
notable is that other than the typical
Microsoft boilerplate something was
wrong in the current overfished there
were some type of additional research or
some type of coat to go along with
somebody actually looked into taking
this budget and making it into a actual
full blown explains leveraging it was
quite a few they're the latest the
senate's 1597 was actually really sought
to exploit TV as a proof of concept now
serves that's actually earlier this week
so a lot of really great stuff their
classes so I happen here broken out the
top three are the primary right what
we're under a pointed reference and then
use after free and then finally have an
honorable mention people think about it
talk about sex off road was just not
quite as prevalent in like colonel and I
can't really think of any recent
exploits like Microsoft driver that
leverage saxophone flute not to say they
don't exist but what's really gonna be
focusing on the cost of building classes
so all they are common in other types of
software code execution things like that
not always and colonel and specifically
the first right what we're so what is it
it is sometimes attacker controlled data
can be written to an attacker control
location now this is fantastic because
an attacker can
usually leverage this by writing data to
a location that they control now it's
usually the attacker to be able to
control the location of the data more
than what the data actually is of course
they have full control over both of them
usually getting code execution it is
trivial from that point deserve a lot of
really well documented techniques of
what the window structures you can
corrupt our that will give you access to
up to code execution if you control both
white and where she know where it is to
go
expectation using this is often
relatively stable are the reason why is
because you're right what we're
conditioned people end up attacking the
end up hurting too how dispatched able
to do special point in the past year but
yasser for on a 32 bit system that is a
call back so you can target as you're
aware and you have your what data you
can trigger the code that is written on
at that that is pointing to by that
point that you cannot overwrite to be
executed on demand and that is to be
done on demand is very key to us for all
the liability because what we can do is
between execute exploit multiple times
to for example I'll be ourselves and
then clean up the system after dawn
things like that in addition to that are
usually corrupting that table on it it's
not it generally doesn't meet you it's
less less likely to lead to you
instability because the system calls
that I trigger that expose the pointer
to be called or not quite use as
frequently as some others
exploits that utilize this technique
1188 join these are rare condition those
released by a setback in 2011 and then
more recently released as 1475 that
factored out windows server 2003
movies like fourth quarter of last year
so next up you have no pointer directs
this occurs when like a pointer is
referenced this referred to as as an
object of course why this is bad is that
if an attacker can map to a memory out
that ad
then they will actually be able to
create a potentially malicious objects
at that address that can be used and
depending on what that object is gonna
depend on how it is actually being used
unfortunately the attacker to need to
know what types of objects that could
put there and how it's being exposed to
sexual tension can be a little bit more
complications are gonna have to have an
understanding of what the structures are
how they use and how hard boner ability
is treating them when it is trigger so
sometimes I cannot always be mapped
others medication for that page mapping
and includes that and I believe on
Windows 64 bit systems by default I
guess she's always on you can't allocate
the lower pages can allocate that no
paging everyone just a little bit of a
problem
one thing that is interesting about this
though is that sometimes as we've seen
in MS 14:58 is that a point or I can be
truncated so whereas on a 32 bit system
update of one was actually being used on
a 64 bit system it was the psych 000 F
and what's very interesting to us about
that is instead of control page being
referred to as objects address that is
much higher in a user memory space was
being used and so because of that next
week for 64 bit was able to be written
because that is outside the boundaries
of where windows as their protection in
place they're able to leverage that and
so there's a reliable 64 bit codex
feature that because the deployment was
truncated right to use after free
secretary is kind of similar in the
sense of a pointed reference the night
invalid memory locations being used to
refer to an object I'm so out of the
three classes are described the one that
is most difficult you are lively
actually because usually it requires you
to successfully reallocate the memory
that was originally free and this is
very critical and it's not always easy
thing to do
additionally more difficult at that
issue don't always know can't tell the
issue
have successfully reallocated that is
that a little bit more later point time
but when the examples of this morning he
was an assistant end but was a scrollbar
info use after Sri
so how do we take these vulnerabilities
actually get code execution out of them
because a lot of times you can trigger
the ball until you get a blue screen
that that's fantastic you know you're
able to trigger that border ability but
we don't want that once again like I
said all is as Penn testers you want to
expletive you alive we want to work
first time every time should not gonna
lose your shelter thank you to be able
to do that very carefully like I said
with the right what we're conditioned
upper much to go to technique is to be
corrupting the hell dispatched a boxer's
a pointer at that offset is on all
versions of Windows XP all the way up to
understand and you can actually result
that simple that's another very nice
thing about it is that with and to you
Karen LPGA you can resolve the symbol
out so you can calculate the offset to
where that is in memory I say that
however you should note that in order to
do that to exploit the native
architecture of the offering smear
tactic that what I mean by that is that
if you are running 64 process should be
a lot more difficult because you can't
load data executable tend to think all
those library a lot to get Rach actress
so it works a lot better to 32 bit or 64
bit process in terms of Medicine however
such as usual
session needs to be a the need of
architecture of the system in order to
be able to resolve that address which is
why you see a whole lot of while 64
exploits just complicates things are
going to open though a lot of times they
are forced to do that so if you want to
look at them that some of the pond own
research it comes out there is fantastic
and to query interval profile is that
function that I've mentioned so once to
help dispatch table is corrupted because
you control what data is written and
where it is written to set out where to
be this offset ninety how dispatch table
after you have done that
you have that though what conditions of
what you wrote to that point your
shelter that's going to do whatever it
is that you would like to do after you
have that you can call and to create a
full profile to trigger the show on
demand just very flexible from an
attacker's perspective because if you
have control over where the show is you
could potentially change the shellcode
because it's in your process memory
space with outreach recurring the
vulnerability to think all antique
oriental profile again to execute
different shellcode in the context of
the kernel with outreach Treasury
explosive that happened where tuition
again and a few times you can trigger
the actual conditions of course going to
increase your chances of stability so
you don't have to anymore
business reference and use after free up
there they're similar in the sense that
they are dependent like I said it's
gonna require the attacker to know what
the object is and how it's being used as
an order to be able to get some type of
a structure corrupt in such a way this
can be useful to that end up reading a
lot of write ups on issues after
cerebral modalities pointed references
I'm convinced there some secretive like
restaurants everyone has like points to
like the different locations like what
such structures can use and how there's
not really good reference to my
knowledge on that is kind of up to the
attacker to figure out how that
structure is being used and then look up
the usually nonexistent documentation I
usually end up forcing a lot of how the
code is being referred to in order to
find a way to leverage it ends up
getting it ends up being corrupted on
either
corrupting it or you're providing your
own object in it is sometimes corrupt
because you don't always have the
ability to create a fully legitimate one
any use after free
object is that that is free you end up
having to replace its not always with
the same type of object but it is it
does have to be the same memory location
which definitely impact stability is
that you need to be able to allocate
region that had been free and there's a
lot of different factors that go into
that such as the different types of
sheets have added an additional tax
cheats and so objects can be free to all
the same time but not all objects are
used on
are in the same destination is targeting
know what objects are used in the same
that you're targeting so that those
objects they might be able to initialize
over the area that read so usually wind
turbine to look for an object to replace
the one that had been freed you're
looking for some kind of a primitive I'm
just the the primitive ends up being
ideal lead something that can be used to
once again and she like a right what
we're conditioned you're looking for
some type of appointed call function on
this object that allows you to write
data to a location that you control as
you try to go for promised I feel like
right conditions would be ideal the most
ideal second course you call but that's
not quite as frequent but read
conditions are also beneficial because
you can seek out additional data that
I'm 21 object I just want to point out
that is a fantastic object that you can
corrupted is relatively easy to achieve
code execution within as the tag und
objects that is the window object that
stored in kernel memory space as it has
all of the information as pertaining to
the window they are interviewing and so
what's a very useful about this object
is that it has two fields in the
structure on the peace server-side radio
project is that is a bit like this
problem set to 0 on but if that's
lacking be set to one then this out yet
and WMD Proc the pointer points to a
call back and win that server side
window Proc slack is set on we send
events to the window that w and
approximation will be called in the
context of the kernel so you can set
that flag I'm usually already have
relatively easy access to the window
boxes to call it relaxes me to set it
because it is set to an address in usual
and when does makes it easy to set that
but that
service I went to prague flag is what's
always your own is what is really
protecting the system usually from
Darfur bilities so if you can set that
flag you can then send an event to the
window and once again you can usually
achieved code execution on demand in a
relatively reliable communication
technologies unfortunately the day's
jumped yes she died with expertise is
long gone and it's just not realistic to
think that you're going to be able to
exploit the SLR is semi issue because
usually when you are running a local a
local privilege escalation when you're
running attack against the current you
already have code execution usually I'm
in terms of Medicine this usually means
that you're loading a DLL interpreter
session groovy hii calls you see railgun
you can usually used to resolve
addresses at least out of our User land
on suka now I'm have that ability and
once again like I was talking about the
and see how dispatched it would actually
load the kernel executable into memories
you can resolve the address that anyhow
dispatch table I'm so is or it isn't
issue with only an issue so it depends
on what exactly you're trying to corrupt
and where it is it's not as much as his
code execution works purely a black box
usually no idea where the addresses are
unless you have some kind of leak so
some addresses are also still usually at
static offset sometimes some of the
tables are always out like jack off
thats if you need to use those those are
available as well for the most part the
kernel modules are randomized but once
you can still usually a result the
address is base addresses of the windows
curls and then Data Execution Prevention
absolutely because you have code
execution ahead of time
XE XE Execution Prevention is not use
the products you can set the permissions
on the page now that did change with the
introduction of Windows 8 but we'll talk
about that just second
so initially there's no page mapping
that's when the protection provided by
admin
I believe you can also enable it within
the operating system without and like I
said about 64 bit Windows 7 64 bit
Windows has that baked white cannot
allocate those really low level there's
no number of pages on a 64 bit Windows
from the user process just doesn't allow
you to do that what they end up actually
doing to mitigate that is that the
operating system maps that ahead of time
and such the permission slip no access
so it's basically the operating system
squat on that on that page that process
cannot not allocated and so there's
estimate was originally designed by
Intel and introduced into their
processors long before Windows 8 came
out but it wasn't till when do they came
out that the operating system did start
to take advantage of this feature I'm
not what does prevents usual and
addresses from be executed within the
context of the kernel which can
definitely be a problem for an attacker
because usually their shell code is in a
useful and address space if they're
trying to get around like death or
something like that you probably
allocated to page with rewrite execute
permissions wrote their shelter to there
and then had some type of a primitive in
order to get that to be executed because
that isn't usually SMS going to prevent
that from being executed go through an
exception
looks just like that on Windows 3.1 so
that attempted executed no extra memory
on Sunday they asked me yesterday a
fantastic technique used to disable SMS
it is in my references what they ended
up doing was they ended up signing rock
gadgets in the Windows kernel that is
those gadgets could be executed they
could disable on s map so what you end
up doing in order to disable ass map is
you end up resulting these addresses out
of the Coeur d'Alene executing those and
then when that returns you have to have
some type of the technique North 14 Mb
executing into your shelf and so on this
fantastic research on that is great
white paper on it
the more difficult things about this
though is that unlike dnt how dispatch
table the address of these rock gadgets
to not be directly result because it's
like barry down within a function and
like the page out a section on what you
can end up doing this you can still do
something similar by loading the kernel
executable into your closet space you
can search that KLK section processing
orders and you can search for gadgets
and you can use data to determine the
address of the Jag suitable for
disabling estimate and what that's going
to do that gadgets can disable SMS by
setting the UCR up a flag in the CCR for
register and then after that can disable
you can execute your code in a usually
happens from the context so once again
the current campaign loaded in 1644
system 32 bit processor is 64 bit
executable so I suppose you could write
your own research to do that but it is a
little bit more difficult to text can't
use the Windows API calls just load it
and the process if sex talk about how
the are in bed asleep
understanding of the different classes
in how they can use levers to gain code
execution super much all the kernel
exploit and legislature although
escalations on that you find under
Windows XP Windows Mobile so they're
dividing into two different categories
based on their implementation they have
exploits that aren't entirely and
exploit are implemented in C as
reflectively verbal deal well so there's
advantages to both of these approaches
so there aren't but most of the ones in
medical and certainly under that
category are there are a couple of that
one is correct there outside of that
specific tree and so what we're focusing
on focusing on this privilege escalation
vulnerability there are these two
classes I'm so most of them are gonna
try to directly either steal the target
or duplicate the system token now each
process has a token of reference in it
which is what identifies the process is
being controlled by a specific user and
so the object of local privilege
escalation vulnerability is going to
usually beaches swap that token out for
a system-level token which can allow
these hackers do things of course with
system-level privileges because the
system is going to think that that is
that the system process death token
there's one exploit and modestly that
does not attempt to modify the token and
there's the MS 1353 exploit this was one
of the ones I came out of the pond own
competition and that one takes an
approach different doesn't directly try
to you either copy or duplicate
assistant token what it actually does it
clears out the ACL of a system process I
believe its wind walk in and what's the
ACL is cleared out is that the process
able to inject a payload into the wind
log-in process so we can utilize that so
that's that's a different technique but
that's the only export that you said
most of the other ones are all going try
to either copy or duplicate duplicate or
create a new token there is a Windows
kernel exploit nixon for us onto these
methods exist to be able to you like
result the address the NTL dispatch
table on your stockings stealing shelton
in there and things like that so
implementation so why would you want to
ride out the whole kernel exploit in
Ruby might eventually be deprecated in
favor of DLL steps because there's a lot
more advantages to that concert
currently there are not a whole lot
they're being done in this round but a
lot of the older local exploits are
entirely as ruby files using rail got so
this technique is well suited for Xmas
that are very simple that generally true
sometimes you're right but we're
conditioned communist like ENT devices
profile centre-backs boys I would like
an 81 on is one of them so you can
utilize the device outro function was
like a specially crafted author and
that's what's necessary to actually I
miss levin et is that deck specially
crafted buffer allows you to
control what data is written where as
one of the benefits
entirely self-contained revival I know a
lot people shy away from writing in see
what people like your pen tester just
trying to get into you may not want to
write Excellency the code I think if
you're looking at it might be a little
bit more intimidating but if you're
writing in Ruby like this technique can
be very well suited for once at a
relatively simple to just meet that one
called you sort of Rightmove air
conditioned
implementations there are a lot more
flexible they allow faster easier access
to the Windows API and so one of the
other nice things about this is that
because the exploit is implemented as
the DLL load that either into its own
process or can elevate another process
for you which is something you can do
with the route that it was now why would
you want him to escalate another process
is because if something goes wrong and
that process becomes unstable and
crashes so the reason why you'd want to
escalate another process that that if it
fails and it doesn't lose screen you'll
still have your session that's a big if
thats requires that you still that it's
not going to fail in colonel and
snacking on your screen but if it fails
and use the left you'll likely still
have a session a lot of the exploits are
implemented this way so what they'll try
to do by default assault ride spawn a
new process injected into that and then
injected he allowed to elevate the other
process like no Patrick out on sometimes
us and boxes prevent this though I miss
you like a browser exploit you can
actually start those other processes
will scale back to you
loading the DL low-interest loan process
to elevate down one instead that way you
can still tried as as for last-ditch
effort but once again if its sales gonna
lose your session it whether the SATs
are not okay so most of the exploits
take like a basic like four steps that
you sometimes like environment attention
to check to see if it is already running
a system if it is
bailout because there's no point in
continuing any future texts weekend is
always a chance of instabilities you
don't do any more than is necessary
a water Windows local place a mess but
also they do you check out the damage
that's gonna try to see if this horrible
and Wimbledon due Tuesday and uploading
the end up looking at the driver on disk
in the end up checking the the final
version of that against the Packers and
check to see that version is patch on
the small subunit face revealed wanted
you any type of sex and gets like the
person does make sure you're running
tests in need of architecture not unlike
a while 64 process a lot of times they
also brought in to check out the new
exploits 10 you it doesn't look like the
systems but once again they cost system
instability in addition to BSOD in the
box most likely to get so they get deal
process is that you want to start up a
dummy process of like Notepad or
something and you want you inject and
elevate that once that there's something
useful and you're not going to lose your
session and hopefully that will do its
job
X elevate you to a system-level ok so
should I shocker time either implemented
as like dropped bytes is what kind of
all started to see a shift in some of
the newer exploits to using icy Bay
shelter which one it is not something
you can do with their exploits but not
reflective yellow ones you can write a
function and have that be executed as
your show sonya damages to that is that
the show can be a little bit more
flexible when you are dealing with the
law by Tony you have like an assembly
stuff that's going to steal your token
that's can be dependent upon the version
of Windows that you're running two
different versions of Windows Store the
token and different part of the
structures different offset to the
shelter has to be specific to your
version of Windows which once again that
can be a source of instability so if you
can use Joker that implemented in C on a
couple of the latest exploits in
Metasploit have used ones that actually
searched for and copy over the shoko and
then that implementation because it's
searching for its lot more dynamic and
it's not going to be specific to us
single version of Windows in addition to
coach me exude a host system 64 bit
systems are which is also something that
you just like the rock by code which is
really popular ok so what's going to
talk about why billy just nobody wanted
BSOD ok so source of instability what's
gonna cost things to be unstable can be
corrupted structures in terms of things
like use after free despite me the
number one most common source of
instability that kind of like a system
structure weather be like out like
something on the sheep or some other
type of object a windows like a linked
list of possibilities are endless
there's a lot of things that could be
corrupted another source ends up being a
token reference count so it when the
stockings are identifying the processing
who owns it has a reference count so you
sit there and you exploit exploit
multiple times and its blindly copying
hope this system token what happens is
that when that elevated process exits
that system talking on the reference
count on it is decrypted and because the
show could most likely to not increase
the reference count once the reference
count reaches zero that token objects
can be freed and that can cause
instability when there's references to
dad that missing object you don't want
to cause instability and then returning
control after elevation so after your
show code executes how'd you get control
back to the attacker should continue
what they're doing they need to be able
to watch the procession elevate
themselves somehow the heat actually do
something with the process that they
were able to tell
structures one of the nice things about
Windows is that there are certain
objects there in a shared recent memory
between the user and the current address
space so on his original memory that's
read only to the user laugh but you can
actually walk through this and only the
right to it is included as read only to
you as performance increase because
every time something is done in the
context of the kernel the context has to
be switch neck very slow speed this up
windows makes all of these structures in
this
specific reached a memory available from
the usual a process that does computer
read so if you're messing with is within
this region which you can actually do is
you can book through this region to see
if perhaps you've been able to corrupt
successfully orgy been able to like
allocated you can sign it look at that
and see if you think that continuing the
exploitation process is going to cause
instability or not and ideally if you
see that there is something wrong that
you weren't able to corrupt structure in
just the right way you can bail out of
the actual process required to trigger
some type of instability so this shared
region it exists in portions prior to
Windows 7 however Windows seven thunders
a pointer to it that's used 32 DLL that
actually tells you exactly where that
region is that we know where that is she
can walk through that I'm some the
objects are stored on there's the handle
table at like the Windows objects like
this just active you and you can be
stored in there and they're not usually
used by like you they are available from
UCL and one of the things that you can
do if you are backing up structures on
this page that you can reach as you can
back it up prior to starting your
exploitation process you can take the
structures that you might end up
corrupting and copy them over to another
recent memory and you can copy them back
to anything happening as you like the
last step if you're up shellcode last
few show could you copy that data back
you can usually avoid system instability
from that perspective not always the
case though just once again that
requires you to be able to read it from
the use of land before getting started
up again once again like its structures
are be corrupted could actually two
dozen her then
system is going to die almost always
caused you don't have that 30 execution
is very difficult to be able to clean up
after yourself in very much depend on
what has two things are being corrupted
you access most the time the system is
going to die so talking reference count
she becomes a problem when like
exploited stealing to token and it's
executed multiple times they have that
reference count on certain types of
things you can do to avoid that is we
can use that out that ACL I technique
those used by I miss 30533 actually
clear out the ACL overpasses inject into
actors then you're not messing with the
tokens United adjusting the reference
count however if you're as you probably
know as a pen test don't want to inject
into an already running system process
doctor also cause system instability
processes that you inject into that
something goes wrong that process dies
probably gonna shut down it's not always
a good thing so duplicating the actual
Hogan and duplicating it intelligently
see you can believe there's a a function
in the kernel that you call to actually
duplicated token so that's going to you
safely copy that token over into the new
process the elevator process exits that
reference count is not going to be
corrupted you can back up the original
token do what you need to do and then
restore it now this is very useful if
you have a right what we're conditioned
to once again like you can trigger door
code execution on demand in the context
of the kernel you can have two sets of
shellcode you can have one that's going
to blindness deals that ok and after
that executes get control back to the
attacker they can do what you need to do
a system process you can do whatever it
is but before that process dies you swap
out that shellcode michelle is gonna put
the original token back as you put that
original talking back did
process can exit out cleanly and it can
be that ritual tokens records count
tickets deeper minutes you can put it
back if that's an option as well
on desk exploit trigger twice that's not
always a good case depending on the
class but it is that like right what
we're conditioned you can up the ante
how dispatch table this is a viable
factor so return to chill so what do you
do after after process after elevations
how to get back to you just want to get
you elvin for reason you want to
actually do something with it I'm still
find allocations you can actually return
control to turn execution back to it
1112 stacked in assembly Microsoft uses
a standardized calling convention so
what that means every time its function
is executed and returns it the calling
commission is what dictates how the
registers are set up as a because it's a
standardized calling convention almost
all the Microsoft code is going to
utilize this one convention which means
that you can actually like unwind the
stack of what that means you can
determine how many frames up the
different functions are held like DDR /
how debuggers are going to be able to
work using this because it's relatively
trivial to be able to determine if an
address is a useful and address or
chrome and address basically can tell by
looking at the numbers on which you can
do as you can unwind the stack and you
can look at the cul-de-sac and see what
function is the last function before
switch contacts into current land and
Richmond / before it goes back I'm
switch you can do is you can actually
returned to NGK I system service post
call which is one of the last addresses
in colonel and and what that's going to
use its going to switch the context back
and it's very critical that you support
the context i just want to get it you're
just back into usual and directly it to
colonel is going to be an inconsistent
state and republican cause a lot of
problems but if returned directly from
your show code is causing issues because
the function is using object you
corrupted somehow or something like that
it's not very comment you need a way to
turn execution after axing shellcode
10 you so the chaos system service post
call is is is executed gorgeous which
the context backs of set everything back
up so when the user can the usual and
coat continue executing and use code is
where the attacker is it has full
control so that's what they can do
whatever malicious things that they need
after that I'm using this technique you
can also manipulate the registers upset
up whatever return value you want to
have for that system on most the time
people would probably the first instinct
would be to have it returned up success
that may not necessarily be the best
idea because if you're calling you
select how if it takes that the system
call completed successfully it's
probably going to try to continue it
doesn't know any better if you told it
works it's gonna think it works it's
going to continue and it continues it
once again my trigger something
everything is in its state state that
might cause like a BSOD on like us up
another system call so you actually
might want to look at doing as an
auction is play around with the
different errors that you can actually
use your returning error codes probably
going to return control directly back to
the attacker without continuing audience
using those corrupt structures so you
can see that but this is 32 shoko that
demonstrates that up so it's just
basically unwind stack and compares the
addresses of each one on some counts of
how deep it is and then calculates
upcoming friend Steve the kernel
addresses are so we can jump back into
the last frame system service post call
Jessica return back into that and the
switch contacts back as you continue to
64 bit exploitation is starting to pick
up there is actually the latest
weirdoes local privilege escalation as
adding too much weight was just
targeting Windows 8 point 1064 exploits
ODIs trying to pick up things is that on
64 bit use this one calling convention
which is very nice on 32 bit Windows
they had like standard call last call
this called for the most part I 64 bit
systems on everything can be just the
one calling convention which is nice
mentioned about 64 complicates things
I'm specifically resulting addresses
caused a lot of those addresses that are
like that colonel executable executable
64 bit extra load data into a third
shift process so you need to have
different ways to resolve this address
is out and those who are looking at a
value on a 32 bit system and for
whatever reason it doesn't work out or
even if it does if you want to look at
64 bit system check for up for
truncations if the pointer is actually
if the value is different that might
mean different things for you
indicates that if like an ass 14580
closing thoughts
explanation is really flexible on
speaker attacker has correct solution
ahead of time they can set things up to
have more pieces to deposit they can
sort play with things they can massage
this system to such a way that it
benefits that mean that the attack is
more likely to 60 also like made attack
they can sometimes be able to check out
the structures are corrupted bailout
things like that so it's a lot more
flexible than it is
code execution typically decisions
complete black box has no way to know
anything on there I'm additionally size
doesn't matter through local food
escalation on the water the exploits in
windows or like full blown DLL so you
don't have to worry about like size
restrictions like you do in a remote
code execution vulnerability I can show
code will fit you have been tired yellow
Lotus memory so that's that's not a
problem at all very nice personal
hypothesis is correct but he's going to
stick around
is one of those factors just because a
growing trend of my client side attacks
whether he liked browser exploit your
job or / 20 days
fishing fishing is definitely one of the
biggest set we're seeing a lot of 10
testers are most likely using things
like empire and things like that you get
compromised systems by fishing and when
they do that usually hopefully they
don't already have a system
administrator access so this might be
one of the techniques to elevate
themselves something you can do you want
to continue on just practicing and
learning up there is a global driver
does least get a view or else out there
was a really nice things about this
drivers that when you're playing around
is that it does have two different
portability classes broke out shortly
around the different ones I'm so I
didn't close out with some things on
Windows 10
everybody understands talks about this
good up so
gadget that I did mention is in the
exact same location so I can tell
technique and assessment by executing
this gadget on it still is on it after
it's in the same function but he can't
resolve that function but it does still
exist
one thing that comes very interesting is
that starting in 2010 20:32 case is
actually broken out three different
parts not sure why my accepted a private
was growing very large but a lot of the
windows vulnerabilities are in the
Winter Kate assist drivers so very
interesting see how if that affects
exploits moving forward
I'm so I doubt I have any time for
questions are an incredibly late but
there's a ton a fantastic resource out
there on this I have two full pages on
some really great white papers they're
really talking everything I know about
Windows corrects location so I want to
kind of share back my experiences with
everybody in the tips and tricks that I
found that increase reliability exploits
cause a text book lacks what
specifically is no good of sour apple
says the first page that was the second
page
ok and thank you everyone for waiting to
get these presentations are spending
your afternoon