air so thanks for coming out this is
going off the rails on a crazy trying
just a brief introduction for who we are
my name's time I am a senior security
consultant at NCC group I used to be a
Rails developer now I break rules out so
far less forgiving this is just a
gesture I got a lot of real were great
man a little bit and show you our from
NCC group headquartered in the UK were
both from the Chicago office just
operates protesting domain services so
what's happened to the outline of what
we're going to be going over here so I
just go over a brief introduction to
Rails just gonna get happened to
authentication I'm gonna talk about
authorization and then we're gonna do a
demo of a dynamic analysis tool that we
can make testing authentication
authorization you see there so when you
start off well as an NBC framework so
this is the kind of output that you'll
start seeing for the directory structure
when you run the command rails new
sample out in the main app directory
we're just going to go over the files
that we kind of are going to care about
for this talk got the models directory
of the models are gonna be mappings
objects to data to database rows and
tables and then you got their views
that's going to be the templates that
the client are actually gonna see when
they go to your website and the
controllers that's a piece that you lose
them on the piece together encounter get
everything ready to present to the user
and the configuration directory you have
the right style this is going to be
going to go over this a bit later but
this is a mapping of all the URLs in
your application and to which controller
actions and maps to the junk file is
going to be pretty much a list of
libraries
external jams application uses it is
going to be interesting to see how are
they using like devised or can can
repugnant the Gemfile dot lock is going
to give you the specific versions of
those jams said then you can start
looking for things like this there's a
specific version of the CMS available
you can look into just found out like to
see what version are using so the rails
way rails is kind of nice because it
provides a lot of protections for
developers by defaults so here we have
the MVC architecture coming out again
through these three different mechanisms
to Active Record is how the models are
set up in Rails that's gonna give you
equal protection by default now there
are ways to get that wrong so we have a
link there for Rails SQL I dot org it's
a pretty comprehensive list of how you
can still get single injection in Rails
applications we refer to that pretty
frequently action view is gonna buy the
fall apart in code user and quote again
there's ways to do that wrong but if you
just kind of used the framework as
intended and you're gonna get access
protection by the fall
action controller is gonna give you
things like sea surge protection by the
fall through things like protect
reporters so just going to kind of start
going into your authentication here so
you know it's like rails gives you a lot
of scary reactions kind of out of the
box but we're kinda goes off the rails
when it comes to authentication
authorization that's something the most
you know reasonable applications are
going to need the concept of the user
and what the prediction model is it
things like that but there's really not
a lot of native sport in Rails 44 either
so the first point is that
authentication authorization or two
distinctly different things rates
authentication is focused on who is the
user just identifying them in an
authorization is you know
what permissions they're allowed
oftentimes I see that people mix the two
together into a single you know and that
can sometimes be a little bit of the
source attribution identification from
all that you really get out of the box
with Rails is you know basic cost I just
off which you probably don't want to use
population from there's really nothing
native but there are some helper methods
of things that we'll talk about that can
help so you're kinda last 22 you know
come up with your own authentication
system so you have two options in the
first is to write your own
authentication system there are some
pros and cons to that approach you know
you're kind of reinventing the wheel and
doing things that people have done
before you know so you're kinda likely
to fall into some common pitfalls that
we can talk about there's also a lot
more to authentication than just
verifying the user is and a lot of times
people don't think about something other
ancillary futures in Rails since 31
there's a helper method called has
secure password will talk about it a
little bit more detail but I can make it
easy to get kind of a simple
authentication function built pretty
quickly
your other option is to you to take it
off the shelf Janet someone's written
open-source you know and use that again
pros and cons so vulnerabilities in
Jamestown to be really attractive you
know two attackers because their common
across a lot of different applications
but on the other hand though you know
welcome for that reason you know you you
can't have two you make sure that you
manager dependencies and you know and
keep updated as new versions are
released and bug fixes things like that
you're still gonna have to do some work
to integrate to john Lynch your own
application and Anderson caveats to that
cautious but on the plus side the core
code in you know popular authentication
Jones is generally pretty well reviewed
you know there's a lot of a lot of eyes
on it sort of the many guys make small
bug shellow theory and then you know as
the community learn new things on her
abilities are found their fixed
you know over time the whole thing gets
a little bit better as a result of that
some of the common authentication James
device is really the the big one
you know it's safe to say that the vast
majority of Rails applications are using
devised for for authentication the
author is you know I know wats consumer
so if you want to do things like you
know a lot of users to authenticate with
Facebook or Google or something like
that
got this really you know the common one
there there's some some hooks in devices
that allow you to call back Tom not so
that you can work together so you can
have the ideas for your standard you
know username password authentication
and then have it call I'm not
automatically you know if you're doing
you know authentication doorkeeper the
third one there is is a little bit
different cuz that's a lot provider so
instead of allowing users to
authenticate with Facebook or Google
allows you to come to the provider in
other applications can seem that logic
is you know one of the other popular
John's it's not nearly as common and
it's a little bit different and it's a
model that kind of blends sessions with
authentication rather than implementing
it was part of the user model so it's a
little bit unusual and I don't see it
quite as often as you know devised but
it's it's worth noting there's obviously
you know any number of other gems but
these are kind of the really popular
common ones that say a lot when it comes
to writing your own authentication
there's a lot of a lot of arguments that
people commonly make this is a quote
from from the rails tutorial book is
also available freely on the internet so
it's really popular you know
introduction to writing Rails apps and
it's you know it's kind of the Bible of
how people code rails but they say a
couple of things here about writing an
authentication system
authentication requires extensive
customization modifying a third party
product is more work than off the shelf
systems can be black boxes and these are
things that we hear a lot when we talk
to clients and their describing their
approach to authentication and why they
chose to write their own I don't really
I don't agree with these arguments for
the most part to say that an off the
shelf system as a black box can
certainly be true but that's just a true
a Rails itself as it is you know of the
third party authentication jam as far as
being more work to write to integrated
than you know write your own that that
to me is just flat out false you know we
did some work to do integrated with your
application but you know it's it's it's
not nearly as much work as you know is
writing a system from scratch and making
sure that you get all the little details
and nuances right but when people talk
about you know writing their own
invention has your password earlier and
that's a really useful helper method so
this is kind of an example of how you
use it we've got a user model that's got
a really simple scheme up with two
strains for name and password I just and
you know in that model you just include
a secure password what that does is it
allows you to do things like this you
can call you know user New to create a
new user pass it a name password
password confirmation you'll notice that
the the the schema doesn't actually have
the password or password confirmation
feels those are provided by the has
secure password helper which
transparently then uses be tripped in
the background
taking the password password
confirmation making sure they match
decrypting and storing a digest securely
so right there you've got a pretty
decent you know password storage system
with you know one line of code you know
then you say even though you know say
the user returns true
you know you're also as I mentioned the
digester stored with the crypt so you
know reasonably secure password storage
mechanism I wrote a really long blog
post talking about you know kind of my
thoughts on your password storage so if
you're interested in and more
yeah there's a link to that some of the
other things you get with that has
secure password authentication method
that you get you past the password to
the user models authenticate my third
and it returns false if it's wrong if
it's correct it returns the user model
itself so you've got a really simple
authentication function you can also do
things you know since you're inheriting
the model inherits from Active Record
you get all your Active Record you'll
find her so you can go to a query on the
user root last 20 find the user by name
and I call authenticate and if the
password matches it's going to return
the corresponding user jack but there's
still a lot more that you need to do you
know storing credentials and
authenticating is really just an
authentication function it's not really
an authentication system so you're
definitely gonna have to think about
things like you know session management
password complexity requirements what
you gonna do in the case of a lost or
forgotten password and that's a really
really big one depending on the
application you might have to deal with
things like API Tolkien's multi-factor
two factor auth earlier so this is
really just the beginning so let's talk
about session management is being kind
of the next thing you need to do so
sessions are basically the idea of
exchanging user credentials for a cookie
for Tolkien and then using that talking
to identify the user and subsequent
requests are not changing credentials
and every request
step 3 you there is kind of important
than people forget about this a lot that
you need to invalidate the token at some
point whether it's when the user logs
out or you know after some period of
time when it's just expired and in Rails
there's a couple of different approaches
to wear session state is stored spent
some time here talking about that the
current default is encrypted key
sessions on recent versions of rails so
we gotta an example here what kind of
walk through the flow you got a simple
sign in page user comes in provides
their you know their user IDs they give
their password sent to the application
that looks up the user by there I D
authenticate them using that password
assuming thats correct the user model is
is returned and there's a session object
created on the server side with
encrypted cookie sessions that session
object is then serialize encrypted and
presented to the user as their as their
cookies to the important thing here is
that the cookie that the user has is
literally an encrypted serialized object
that servers gonna be used to create
that session the next option that is
database back sessions so we got kind of
similar flow but in this case there's no
database on the server again the user's
going to provide their password
indicates that password
creates a session object that's then
stored in the database
there's also then cookie tour alongside
that session object and then a cookie
value is provided to users that's just a
random token that that allows the
application to look up that session
object in its own database so on
subsequent visits the users can provide
that that random tote in a database
query retreat this action from the
database so there's pros and cons of
each of these approaches
on the database front the user cookie is
just a random value as I mentioned you
know on the serialize cookies it's it's
an encrypted serialized object
italicized the database column because I
feel like that's a win for database
options there's a little bit less you
know
attack surface they're exposed moving on
when we talk about like how we're going
to revoke the session with database
actions you know you can just delete
this action from the database and it's
gone
cookie sessions it's a little bit more
complicated because you know once that
that values given to the user you really
can't can provoke it so you have to have
things like you know a time stamp on it
that expire or some other token included
in that session male on both cases
you're going to need to be conscious of
having a maximum lifetime to your
sessions neither won by default is gonna
do that so we'll talk about how to get
out a little bit I mentioned the attack
surface again I think this is a big win
for database options the only way to
really attack that is to steal or a
numerate that random told in with the
serialize sessions you've still got that
option you also have the possibility of
you know cryptographic attacks against
against the session object itself you
know you've got a higher probability of
longer internet live sessions cos cos of
revocation issues if the encryption key
is ever exposed its fatal
you know then I can create my own
sessions arbitrarily and the application
will honor them and then there's also
some issues surrounding the the
serialization and I kinda relates to
some of the the rails deserialization
issues for a couple years ago we will
talk a little bit about that too
the overhead here is kind of a big
reason that people tend to favor
encrypted cookie sessions with database
sessions on you to request you gotta do
a query to retrieve that object from the
database so it can identify the context
and user session so there's a lot of
overhead involved in that caching can
help you know I've heard of people doing
things like like a number of databases
to you know to try and reduce the
overhead and active record in recent
years and the rails it had a lot of
caching and performance improvements so
I don't think that the overhead is is
all that bad except I'm really large
applications but for this reason
database options are really are no
longer included in Rails by defaulters a
separate Jen that you need to include
and I'm a little bit I'm a little bit
disappointed by that cuz you know
whether our performance issues on large
applications I feel like you know
there's a small percentage of times when
that's really a practical concern
developers and so removing it you know
from even being an option in the
framework seems a little a little
heavy-handed
cryptically sessions you've still got
some overhead which is validating the
cryptographic signatures you know
decrypting the data and a juicy
realizing it I haven't really done the
measurements to compare the two directly
so I'm going to trust the rails team
when they say that database options are
are more overhead but I kind of question
exactly how much at some point I'll
probably do the math ok so we talked
about having a couple of different types
of sessions those are going to configure
it in your session store initializer
file photo lineup looks a little bit
like this you'll know if they're on on
this particular one we've got the
session side has cookies store and I
bolded the expire after setting that's
not there by default so if you don't
have that there are sections are gonna
live forever so that that's one thing
when you're assessing applications you
want to look at you know is there is
there a session timeout obviously did
you that black box just you know just
had a session active
and wait awhile and see if it still
honored but it's a lot easier to just
look at the source so such an extra time
has to be manually configure that could
restore setting is where you would you
would change your session storage type
if you want to use Active Record Store
you do still have to include the German
the application to to support that ok so
with cookie sessions then going also had
a setting in secret Seattle that
contains your secret key base that's the
encryption key that used for encrypting
those sessions so you wanna make sure
that that's you know a fairly fairly
secure value and you know let it rain
secret if instead you have a secret
token you don't get encryption at all
what you end up getting his is just
encoded serialize session so that's kind
of interesting because if they're
storing sensitive data within the
session object you can take that could
you just basically portico it and you
know you've got a serialized object so
you can get a little bit of exposure of
sensitive information that way within
the session store initializer you also
have a sudden here that determines what
the serialization method is for that for
that session currently its defaults to
JSON this is the case since rails for
one prior to that it defaulted to
marshal marshal load was the vector for
the the rails gamble deserialization
palms of 2013 I think it was so if it's
up to marshal and I know the encryption
key I can craft a malicious session
object that when deserialize going to
execute arbitrary code on the server
it's not quite as bad as the original
doctor because you have to have that
encryption key but that over leaks not
only democrats session objects I can
also get code execution on the server
this hybrid serializer is kind of a and
operate path so in hybrid mode at the
applications gonna issue JSON serializer
cookies but it's going to honor either
JSON
Marshall serialize could use so it's
meant to allow you to migrate
transparently i've seen a number of
applications where people turned on
hybrid mode tattoo you know to
facilitate the operator and just left it
and you still have the vector therefore
RCE where applications not issuing
Marshall serialize cookies if an honors
and it's kind of interesting you really
don't need to have that hybrid mode for
very long as if you have a maximum
lifetime configured on your sessions
you're only gonna need to honor the
legacy Marshall sessions for the
duration of your social life time Tues
at that point they're all expired your
number to see him again so it's really
the sort of thing that you probably need
to have you know I have enabled in
production for a couple hours but a lot
of times people just you know don't go
back and so that's something to watch
out for
we talked a little bit mentioned lost
forgotten password recovery is kind of
difficult there's a lot of different
approaches people people you know used
to handle s most of them are kinda poor
in one way or the other
there's really only one approach that
that I'm fond of and that's this process
generate a random Tolkien you wanna make
sure that that's generated with a
cryptographically secure random number
generator so it's not predictable send
that to all stored in the user object
along with the timestamp of when it was
created
send it to the user our fan from the
application so this is the usual you
know you get an email with a link that
says click here to reset your password
you don't the user's I'm gonna visit the
site that Tolkien applications go look
up the user by that token verify that
that Tolkien you know the time stamp on
a token it was stored is within an
expiry time you know what these things
to be valid forever you know if I issue
a result ok you know then forget about
it never going to reset my token you
don't want that's it and you know days
or weeks later and then you change the
user's password and delete the token
that's another caveat
that people often forget you know after
password been reset you want to leave
that so that someone else can reset it
again using same token machine cures and
talk about devise a little bit mentioned
that that's the way that you know the
vast majority of applications are gonna
gonna handle authentication
example here about user model that was
generated by devised when it installed
and it's really simple and got to devise
helper that includes a number symbols
represent different modules that allows
has to include various functionality the
names here are pretty pretty self
explanatory explaining what they do you
know register a bowl allows a user to
anonymously visit the site and create a
new account YouTube e-sata cable was
kind of self-confidence it's the main
authentication mechanism no recoverable
allows for a password reset flow when
when a password forgotten there's a
number of other modules here that are
common to doubt that just aren't enabled
by default you know so too so it's kinda
nice that you can just enable and
disable these modules and get different
different components of functionality
once you've got a vice installed if you
look at your routes are be you're going
to see a line that's device for users
just that one line this calls this
device helper on your user model the
effect of that is going to be if you run
rake routes and see what your actual
routes that the application has no has
configured are you see this so you've
got a whole number of different routes
with you know various methods and these
do things like you know give the user a
sign in page except their credentials
and authenticate them you know presented
a password reset slow so it without a
lot of work you know you get a lot of
functionality
so then tying devised to the application
you've got a bunch of helpers provided
the main thing is this controller filter
implemented as a book or action in the
application controller that all the
other controllers inherit from and
that's really easy way to just say ok
across the application for an
authenticated users will talk a little
bit about that relations side the other
helpers are you know pretty well named
user signed in other users sign in or
not current user user session return the
current user and the user session
current user is really the big 12 you'll
see most of your your queries are gonna
be built from that objects the root
device has a bit of a security history
this is a snippet of some of the the
recent versions that have had security
relevant changes the key point here is
the most of these are really tiny minor
flaws and all that sort of things that
are really easy to get wrong but over
time
communities kind of benefiting from from
you know incentivize the true there are
bolded going to talk about over the next
couple of slides tournage back of of
recent tokens now instead of the
probability of the token itself and then
there was a type confusion vulnerability
gonna spend a couple of slides talking
about this this is a really interesting
vulnerability was disclosed in 2013 by
your ensign so let's look at how that
works
Rothley devices password reset function
is not look something like this this is
kinda pseudocode its across a number of
different you know different classes and
slap more complicated but the basic idea
of it is that you know when this reset
method is called we're going to get the
user's reset password token from the
parameters look up the user object
associated with that Tolkien and then
you know it exists were gonna change the
password to the new value with that in
mind
the bug actually stems from bicycles
equality operators so this is really not
what I would expect you know when you do
a query where the injured one equals a
strain that starts with one it's
actually true
gonna return data similarly the integers
euro is going to be equivalent to any
string that begins with a non-injury
character i dont i dont get their site
have no idea why this is the case but
that's how am I supposed equality works
and it doesn't seem like they're likely
to change it because it's gonna break
all kinds of things that they do but
that's really the root of the Pug yeah
right like it's it's it's so late but
anyway how to exploit this in Rails in
devised in Rails there's this this has
called params that's usually a bunch of
strings that are the user's URL
parameters so if you've got a query with
rhubarb is buys you get a Brands Hatch
where you know who it says bar and so on
a few passengers and the second example
there it's interesting to note that
those are quoted so they're they're
strength as you know even though it's an
integer value it's it's handled as a
string in prams hash we don't need
strings here we need to get any jurors
for that but that bicycle confusion
there some rails magic the let's do that
rails will when it receives a post with
a an XML or JSON body is going to
automatically parse that body and
typecast things as analogies on formats
dictate
XML is no longer supported out of the
box in 40 and later there's a suffrage
and to enable it but that was kinda
disabled again as a result of the
realization bones JSON however is still
supported automagically out of the box
on all versions rails so if we decide to
post with the XML example like this you
know with with an object to his you'll
notice we specify the type is an integer
then we're gonna get back Rams hash
where is the integer ones now we've got
injured in the crash that killed the
first stop similarly with JSON represent
a sign like this in just don't quote the
reset password took in you know it's
gonna come through in Jersey now we've
got 20 so if we send something like this
to the application what we're gonna end
up with these brands hash you know where
we control password password
confirmation result token is the integer
0 as a result of that the ActiveRecord
period gonna do I find my token with the
integer 0 is the argument of records
that could build a seat will guarantee
that you know that looks like this we're
talking equals integer 0 and the result
of that is that we're gonna get back the
User objects of the first outstanding
token and there's a little bit because
due to the comparison is the first
outstanding token that starts with a
nine incher but in most cases you know
your tokens are generally not gonna have
any injuries or if they do they're only
to be you know one or two digits before
it you know before its character so
that's kind of interesting has now we've
got you know we got a user objects from
the password reset tool that we didn't
know that's the core of the
vulnerability I wrote him a display
module for this couple years ago the
Metasploit module will loop through and
you know monitor the response codes to
clear out any existing tokens the
benefit of doing that is that then we
can sign up
you know a password recovery request for
a given user and know that that's the
only token outstanding there's a little
bit of a race condition there if the
applications you know other people
requesting things at the same time but
generally it's passed now that you know
I can be too much of an issue once we
got an outstanding token we can go ahead
and and reset password without knowing
that token the caveat to this is the
legitimate user the account is gonna get
an email there's nothing we can do about
that you know they're going to get the
password reset email with their token
but I think you know by the time they
see that you're generally can already be
so that's kind of fun so why are we
talking about this you know this
vulnerability it's from 2013 it's
patched in recent versions to devise the
devise patch all it really does go back
to let's go code there we go so I said
that the the reason not to look
something like this
the patch essentially takes that that
fine by Tolkien and adds a toString so
we just casts it explicitly to a string
so you can get injuries through that's
how devised matched it
rails also see oh ok well make this
point that the core hole mobility here
being in my sequel and you know dr.
records gratis
thanks a lot more than justifies so
while while it's a couple of years old
vulnerability in most people have
operated device in the meantime you see
that same thing a lot of times when
people write their own their own
recovery functions
tokens recent tokens things like that so
it's it's a good one to be aware of what
module can pretty easily be tweaked to
you know to interoperate with nine
points that would be vulnerable to the
same the same issue
I talked about the devise patch the
rails fixes for this kind of interesting
in Rails 3 to 12 a push to change that
would cause after record to build his
queries using the type of the database
so if it's looking up a string in the
database it would cast the parameter to
a strained automagically they ended up a
reversing that in Rails 3 to 13 because
it broke some other functionality so on
the 32 branch there's really only one
version where that that function is
enabled in Rails 42 in later however
will build agrees that way out of the
box so that's an improvement but even on
42 and later if you build your queries
using something like where you know you
can still introduced the same the same
sort of issue
the supreme and ice cream so it's not
sequel injectable but I can you know I
can control the type of the parameter
and that's that's really all I need to
know to exploit something like this so
what that we're gonna move on
authorization to talk about that right
now that we have an awesomely
authenticated go over authorization so I
kind of think about this as what can I
do this tends to be tied to the concept
of roles within applications like to
break it down into two separate groups
have the notion vertical authorization
sitting examples here you might have a
site at minutes full access and
organization had man that's gonna have a
more granular access controls applied to
it you know maybe full access to a
specific organization a regular user is
going to have limited read access and an
unauthenticated should have no access
anything horizontal authorization on the
other hand is
is a regular user an organization one
shouldn't be able to see the data of
organization to so what does this look
like an authorization we tend to see
that for vertical authorization that
gets implemented with the use of before
actions so here we have some examples at
the top you might see something in a
controller that says require admin so
before actions is pretty much a method
that's gonna get run before any action
is called within that controller and
then you can specify options to say
things like only accept if you only want
the actions before actions to be run on
certain controller actions so far
horizontal authorization this tends to
get implemented with the use of
associations so we had the notion of a
current user object into my eyes and
then we're going to do here is say okay
for the current user let's get their
organization get all the posts within an
organization and then look at your
lookup methods on that so what that does
is it a pretty much keeps this subset of
data that's going to get queried two
things that belong to that user
going into you how routing works in
Rails is going to briefly go over this
this is gonna be a line that you'll see
in the configuration file and routes
that are being and so it's pretty simple
here you have your HTTP method the pass
the UN expose in your application and
then you pointed to the controller and
action and here this is an ocean have
controllers that class in an action is a
method within a class so this is gonna
be a typical Rails controller you'll see
that is inheriting from application
controller here
index is gonna be
you know the the method with in this
class is going to be exposed to test the
action and rails but yes you'll notice
the use of the application controller
here so we kind of go inside and talk
about control hierarchy so the
application controller is the main kind
of class that by default all the
controllers are going to inherit from
says very common that you're going to
see he kind of site-wide authorization
and authentication before actions within
this year also gonna get things by
defaults that protect from forgery line
just generated when you generate the
application so again going back to the
post controller that's going to inherit
from application controller and then as
you go up you have more lighter weight
classes and so you're gonna start losing
functionality that you get by default so
for example work we sometimes see
applications where you know people
inherit from application or action
controller base and so they're gonna
lose things like Caesar protection to go
into how callbacks work within rails
tend to have three different ways you
can apply this to you before around and
after but with the way that
authorization tends to work you
unauthorized user before you start
running any code that might change the
database so we tend to focus on before
actions you're gonna see this in a few
different flavors you can't touch on
this earlier but you can say only accept
which is gonna be pretty much an array
of actions to say only run on these or
running on everything except these
actions you can also provide other
conditional methods and say you know if
this method returns true run this before
action or unless you can also skip
before actions so you can say you know
if you have the application controller
and it's calling authorized user which
means that it's going to get run and
every single action by default you can
say skip the authorized user before
action on specific
controller actions you also see things
like you can pass it or Prague with
custom authorization logic if it's small
enough that it's gonna fit there but
this is pretty rare so there are some
authorization gems for Rails funded and
can can can formally can can are two of
the more popular ones so pundit you're
going to see something like this when
you look up a post object and then you
call authorized on that and so that's
going to be a national method call
within the controller action itself can
can can works in a very similar way but
you kind of specify the actual ability
as you call the authorized in my head
and it provides some helper methods as
well like loading authorized resource
which is smart enough to know that hey
you're probably looking for a post
object so low that by the idea program
and look that up an authorized user just
a quick note on that opening Canyon can
are pretty popular I think we tend to
see more often than not that people
implement their own authorization logic
go over things to be on the lookout for
calling fine by methods directly on
models so we kind of talked about
associations earlier this is just
something to be on the lookout for its
not automatically going to be a
vulnerability but when we find
authorization flaws
it's going to be around patterns like
this so we like to see again the use of
associations limit the subset of data
that you're clearing
ones that belong to the user so be on
the lookout for whitelisted actions so
here we're saying authorized author for
only the update destroy and create
actions in the post controller so you
might think about this scenario where
developer comes in as new controller
action and they don't add that new
controller action to this list
so that's what you might find
authorization bypass around that so we
tend to like more kind of like a black
list approach we're saying run this
authorized author before action on every
single action of the post controller
automatically except for the ones
provided so that same scenario the
developer comes in as new controller
action they have to explicitly added to
this less so that it doesn't get run
lightweight controllers a touch on this
little bit earlier but the farther you
go up that hierarchy the more you're
gonna lose here again
inheriting directly from action
controller base you're gonna lose things
like sea surf now that doesn't mean it's
gonna have been avoided billion
necessarily because you might want this
for things like API's right but when you
get down to like action controller medal
you just lose the ability to even call
before actions because that's a
middleware so you would have to include
that explicitly say if you see a
controller that just inherit from
application controller you're probably
not going to say anything to walk around
that authorization logic in use so again
missus
developers correctly checking for roles
see if there had been but they're just
showing and hiding that in the view and
so on the back and you want to ensure
that the actual controller logic that
corresponds to this do you want to make
sure that they're properly checking
roles there's the use of skipping of
filters so again this is just more try
to get it if you see it because you want
to make sure that the developer actually
meant to do this sometimes we might see
things like developers trying to test
with a curly client they don't wanna
play around with authenticity token so
though say skip it for action verify
authenticity token and then forget to
take that back out and they committed so
then you have sea surf across a
controller
real scaffolding is really nice in the
sense that it allows you to get control
actions up and running very quickly and
it'll generate things like views and
controllers for you
the problem is that it generates some
artifacts that developers don't really
know about and so here we're just
running rails generate scaffold and then
you can specify the attributes for that
model and again it'll go through
generate the views these JBuilder files
and then the ActiveRecord models so what
happens with that is that for example
for the JBuilder files this is kind of a
review template so that when you request
a JSON response at all it'll generate
this and then at all of these attributes
automatically so every single attribute
you generated rail scaffold will be
available by default if you have some
secret token or something that you don't
want users to see its gonna show up
automatically in the same way for strong
parameters which is kind of the
protection for mass assignment
vulnerabilities and rails all of the
attributes will automatically get added
to the permit method so everything on
tributes gonna be mass assignable see
all those are going to be some of the
patterns we're gonna talk about
parliament right now so we only looked
at one controller and the post
controller you can imagine
checking every single before action for
every controller and application it can
become a pretty big hassle here so man
tries to bring every single before
action and across every controller into
one place that you can query and look at
dynamically so just a bit about how it
works it plugs into existing Rails
applications and it gets mounted as a
Rails engine so you do need pretty much
shell access to the application
with rails assessments and it being more
towards the startup kind of crowd our
clients tend to be pretty open with
giving us access their box or they just
quickly stand up like a staging instance
again as a minimum requirement rail
access to the rails councils gonna be
needed once you have it mounted you can
just go to for its last man in the
application and start running through it
so I'm actually go through a quick demo
here looks like
the example when I use here is the rails
going is unintentionally vulnerable
Rails application kind of release
through the Oscar organization so this
is a full application if you guys are
interested in our testing rails after
getting started doing security
assessments you can get this up and
running really quickly and then start
going through some common trails
vulnerabilities this is this is a full
web log in and play around with that but
if we just go to four sites where a man
here I've already installed it into this
application you're gonna start seeing
this is the main view so you have basic
filters to say show me only the
controllers and include a strength give
me every action that you know has a
specific before action or without 10
here you're going to see a table
breakdown of every single controller and
every action and a controller so here we
have the controller use the Forgot
Password action and hear all the before
actions that get run out there any
people out there that assess Rails
applications for a living but if
anyone's part of our ability right now
based off of an action that should
probably get on every single action
controller
well it so it's not actually here is the
thing is these are all the actions that
are gonna run exactly so by default if
we look into the application control arm
will see that is commented out here
what's known about security guys talking
about see surfing so if we uncomment
this out and refresh the page here we'll
see verify authenticity token is
automatically added to every single
action is kinda nice to be able to spot
things like that automatically but we
have an example here so there's a mobile
API endpoint available here so if we
look at API will see there is an API
controller available for users and then
one available for the mobile controller
said I kind of open up the Red Cross is
really nice red cross was gonna show you
every single controller action here this
is my car show where this is pretty much
something I ask every client right off
the bat and going to show you everything
a patent applications are you don't have
to enumerate them manually but if we
look here hasn't shown to but we have
this kind of so if we say a PIB 1 users
so this is gonna go to the user's action
or the users control over the index
action so we pulled out of here we'll
see things like valid API token so I'm
pretty certain that that's going to be
some kind of authentication type action
so here we're getting HTTP token access
denied so that's probably going to be
from this ballad API token if we look up
the actual users controller will see
that they're saying before filter valid
API token and so we look at that method
they're doing some kind of
authentication around that side want to
say I'd probably want to find any API
controller actions that don't call this
method so they go back up to the filters
and say you know for the API controllers
give me every single action without the
valid API token you will see nothing
comes up and the user's controller but
every mobile controller controller
action is going to be a seemingly
vulnerable and has no authentication so
if you go back to the rake routes and we
pulled one of these guys we've gotten no
response here but you will see you see
ever know learning the HTTP token error
back so if we look at the Mobile
controller for our index action which is
what we've just called will see first
there's no before filter that's expected
and an index action it's it's requiring
in this class parameter and ultimately
what's going on here this is a bit of a
non-standard code pattern you normally
gonna see this too often apart from the
dynamic classification I guess but
they're saying given whatever class you
passing as a parameter turn into a class
constant eyes it and then just called at
all on and which is going to return
everything for the provided class so we
can do something like last week was user
and it'll call user . all and returned
everything here
r so that's the damage but if you kind
of assess Rails application for a living
and see this like this should already be
something really nice hopefully it's
going to be useful
its new applications so it's going to be
a bit rough around the edges but I
encourage anyone with acid rails app to
use it if you ever see anything wrong
with it but again to to use it you can
do gem install boiler man but primarily
you're going to add it to the Gemfile of
your Rails application and then run
bundle install the takeaways is even if
you don't use break man rails console is
extremely powerful and assessments
that's kind of where this came from I
just started kind of playing around and
then realise like hey you can pretty
much query programmatically any aspect
of a Rails application if you have
access to it
future ideas endings and III
visualization were kind of working on it
on the way up here but didn't get quite
done source clearing is going to be
coming soon as well so in the cases of
like pundit and can can you can say give
me all the controller actions that don't
call authorized yeah that's everything
any questions
yeah she was supposed to do that show
that really quickly here so yeah if you
don't have access outside of the app you
can run off the rails console directly
some cases where you might have shut
shell access the box but for one reason
or another you can add it to the Gemfile
relaunch everything so you can foresight
load it through rails console having
some instructions on how to do that but
yes the rails console if you don't want
to use actually sure thanks we had lunch
yeah i know i mean so this is you can
just kind of programmatically get this
year but