good morning guys sorry to keep you
waiting so this is about getting access
with spearfishing
I became interested in spearfishing
because it's such a powerful attack
vector and it's a fun mix of social
engineering and technical skill so I'm
Kevin
like you said I'm a network security
analyst I'm a colleague Brown we do
defense contracting I really like
offensive security but offense is
defense and defense is offense so
hopefully by learning how to spear fish
you guys can bear defend against it so
just to prove I'm not a robot I also
like nature video games and DIY projects
I don't really have a Twitter so here's
my github and the company I mean the
opinions are my own and not the
companies
so unless have you been living under
Iraq I'm sure you heard of what
spearfishing is basically it's a
targeted form of spear fishing that
includes your name your company relevant
information that might impersonate
someone you know and basically it's
going to be really hard to distinguish
from legitimate email and humans are the
weakest link in the chain for security
so that's why spearfishing is implicated
and the vast majority of data breaches
come generally even among a trained
staff people report a 10 to 40 percent
success rate when doing spearfishing so
that's pretty significant because if you
have like 10 people then you can almost
guarantee someone would get caught there
is a difference between Red Team
spearfishing and penetration testing
spearfishing red team basically emulate
the attacker and you use spearfishing as
a means to an end so you use
spearfishing as a method to get what you
want which is the data or access or
whatever
whereas with Red Team your test I mean
with penetration testing your testing
for a specific thing such as house
except how susceptible your employees
are to spearfishing
so you could have like a hundred people
being tested or even everyone in the
company whereas with Red Team you want a
much smaller target set like five to ten
or 15 at most because you don't want to
get caught by Blue Team so this
presentation is mostly going to focus on
Red Team
and it's also gonna be black box meaning
that you're an attacker from the outside
without any knowledge of how the company
works or what they use so who here has
heard of the cyber kill chain ok so
quite a few of you basically this is the
process that attackers go through when
they're trying to hack into your stuff
how spear phishing fits in all this is
usually it's used for initial compromise
it's used to get access to the network
so they can escalate become admin
however is such a powerful attack vector
that you can use it to escalate
privileges as well because if you can
fish the admin then like you have admin
privileges so I'm sure you've heard of a
dragonfly or energetic bear apt the
Russians trying to hack our national
infrastructure or whatever basically
they use beer fishing to gain access and
also spear fishing to gain the admins
hash and then they just crack the hash
and they have the administrative
privileges so there are four steps in
spearfishing
first you have to do recon have to scope
out your targets in your environment
what kind of defenses they were using
and then you craft your email and then
you send it and then you get your shell
and then profit I guess so there's all
kinds of ways you can get your targets
but LinkedIn is an amazing resource and
you should definitely use it it's got
like all kinds of information just so
much information and it talked up to
date and everything and the web
interface itself is really nice it
includes the options to search by job
title in school and all kinds of stuff
that's useful so when you're looking for
targets you want to select people who
are not technical so like people in
marketing or whatever because you don't
want to target the people who are
technical first because they're less
successful to fishing and also they're
more likely to report it there's no need
to target the admins right away because
you're looking just to gain access
that's really for the second step
so you want to choose a 5 - 15 targets
not too many there's also this great
tool called LinkedIn by Vincent he did a
talk called
a year in the red or something like that
and it's a really great talk and
basically what this does is it takes
information from here the search results
here and it just scrapes it and puts it
in the HTML file so you can search
through it locally and what I can also
do is convert names and to email
addresses so how that usually works is
they have a pattern like first name dot
last name @ domain so I can do that I
also create a tool called
hunter/gatherer which you know which can
also do that it can also do email
validation so it can check to see if an
email address actually exists so that's
useful because you have people who have
like first names like Michael but they
go by Mike and then their email address
is Mike instead of Michael so it can do
this in two ways they can do this using
the SMTP received to command which is
kind of already known but most mail
servers have already passed that so that
may not work but what does work and what
would probably continue to work in the
future is bounced emails so if you send
an email to an email address that
doesn't exist you will get a bounce and
then you know it doesn't exist
another lesser-known method is a
directory calling so if you call one of
their employee locations after five when
they were such in their sleeves it can
press one to dial whoever you want and
in some less secure environments you can
press one to get directory listing so
you could get information from there and
their cool thing about bounced emails is
that it can leak additional information
people usually have like an auto reply
when they're out of office so not only
do you see the name and email of the
secretary you also know the relationship
between the two and you can try to
exploit that for social engineering and
you also know that that person is out of
office so so now that you have your list
of targets you want to find out what
kind of environment the company is using
so what kind of defenses they have what
kind of antivirus firewall and all that
stuff so again LinkedIn is a great
source of information you can search for
people
who already worked there and then you
can find their job descriptions or you
can look for new job positions and see
what they're looking for so here we see
that they have carbon black which is a
pretty good antivirus so you want to
make sure to set up a lab using those
technologies and then try to bypass it
so another thing you can do is you can
send the bounced emails and then I'm
sorry you can send an email to a
non-existing address and get a balance
and a lot of times that week some juicy
details for example here we see that
they're using Proofpoint and not only
that we actually see the score for this
exact email so you can use this to test
your actual email and see if it gets
categorize the spam like this is a
pretty big company so this you know
isn't like a thing that only works in
less secure small environments they do
like health care stuff I think so now
that you have your environment you set
up your lab you have everything ready
it's time to create the actual email so
there's all kinds of ways you can do it
here are some tried and proven ones
basically you want to pray on importance
fear and privilege as well as urgency so
here we have like some kind of holiday
schedule or whatever change so all
employees are worried about things that
matter to them like holidays and salary
especially so those are great things to
exploit you also improve your also
exploiting privilege because you're
impersonating the director of HR who may
actually send this kind of email who
everyone trusts and loves and everything
so there's all kinds of ways you can do
it you just have to make sure it looks
completely legitimate and make sure it
contains the right footers and headers
this one is kind of plain so nowadays
most people use html5 footers where they
have like green text and a picture of
the company or whatever so this email
can probably be improved by adding that
and another thing is if you get a
balance you also get the footer so you
can steal that
so now that you have your actual email
basically you send the email it's going
to contain a link or attachment that
contains your malicious payload so now
it's time to create that payload there's
all kinds of ways to do it you can have
an executable you can have a j/s file
VBS file but what I really like or
office payloads because people trust
them more and people think that there's
a less chance of malicious things
happening because people send office
documents around all the time and
they're less suspicious of office based
documents so there's all kinds of ways
you can run code using office macros
it's pretty popular but nowadays it's
getting locked down so I wouldn't really
recommend it all nice if you know it
works it can also bypass application
whitelisting if they haven't blocked
those attack vectors
there's also click once which only works
in Internet Explorer but as the name
suggests you get this prompt and you
click run and then you can run whatever
code you want but with all of these you
you know you see some you see some kind
of security warning that the user has to
click through so you want to try to
convince them to click through that so
this year is server around somewhere and
as you can see is trying to convince the
user into clicking that enable content
so you want to trick them into doing
that and then after they do that if
nothing happens they're going to be like
what the hell did I just get hacked so
you want to deploy decoy so they're not
suspicious and you can just steal these
templates from actual malware samples
there's all kinds of great sources for
that and generally when you're doing
this you're gonna have the host on your
own domain because you want to track
clicks and everything like that but it's
optimal really to host them on
third-party file file-sharing services
like Google Drive because those are more
often used and they're less suspicious
you can either host it as a link
download link or an attachment by prefer
a download link because attachments get
scared more often and they're also
getting stripped of their executable
content and in the case of Office
documents so I couldn't actually find
any open source
templates for fishing with office
documents so I decided to create my own
I was inspired by this ransom this
server ransomware so it's on my github
and I added some VBA code to deploy a
decoy document and it's all contained in
the same document so it doesn't go out
and download anything so check that out
if you want so basically you have your
document the user runs the macros the
ole le or whatever and then that in turn
runs your malicious payload which gives
you your shell so I'm sure you know what
a remote administration tool is
basically that's what gives you the
shell remotely so there's all kinds of
tools to choose from codec is
interesting because it's written in J
script which is a scripting language
that's inherit and windows but it's not
PowerShell so that's pretty good
there's also a QP which is written in
Python and it's got a really great
credential dumper I would highly
recommend the credentials um per the
Metasploit and cobol strike is kind of
like the traditional one that everyone
uses the most popular one and it is
really a focus I would definitely
recommend that so here you see the
basically how you create a remote
administration tool with PowerShell
Empire and you can see like the default
value so basically in the case of each
of these you want to change that because
they're usually not the smartest values
or they're not the you know most
stealthy or whatever and they also
contain static strings that could get
picked up by antivirus or IDs so just
change all of those things to something
better
so here's an overview of all the
defenses that you're going to encounter
basically the mail is going to come in
it's gonna get scanned by the gateway
mail antivirus it's gonna be run in a
sandbox that determine if it's acting
maliciously and then it's gonna get
through into the users inbox the user is
going to download it and then it's gonna
get scanned again by the users antivirus
on his or her computer and then it runs
and then there's going to be IDs systems
that's gonna be trying to pick up on
that intrusion that compromised and then
finally it goes through the firewall and
then you get your shell so you want to
keep in mind all
defend this because if you fail any of
these points and that could screw up
everything so make sure you don't screw
up so here are some tips for trying to
bypass those defenses you want to blend
in with legitimate traffic so by
spear-phishing your are we kind of doing
that because you're blending in with
legitimate email that's why anti-spam
has a hard time filtering spear phishing
messages there's also the concept of
living off the land or using use reusing
resources are already available for
example PowerShell which is like
scripting languages that's used by
system administrators for legitimate use
but it can also be used illegitimate Lee
another thing is you want to stay in
memory so whenever you write to disk
there's the risk of the file being
scanned and detected by antivirus but
sometimes you have to write to disk in
order to get persistence in case the
computer reboots so you want to keep
that to a minimum keep everything in
memory if you can and most importantly
you want to set up your lab environment
that emulates the actual environment and
you want to test your payload you want
to test your email and everything
because not only can you have bugs that
would screw it up you can also get
detected and then if you do get detected
you want to find out you want to find
out why you got detected and then you
want to change it so that it doesn't or
you want to use a different method so
that it doesn't get Detectives so
sometimes it's a lot of trial and error
but eventually you're gonna get there
just about every defense can be bypassed
so here are some more tips for
implementing that you want to be careful
or PowerShell it's not like the Wild
West it used to be where you can run
PowerShell and there's no defenses
whatsoever oh you have constrained mode
you have a logging you have a AAA SMI or
something which is like antivirus
scanning PowerShell so I'm not saying
don't use it it's a great tool but you
want to be careful when you use it and
what that said scripting languages are
great because antivirus is for some
reason have a hard time detecting
scripting languages there's a PowerShell
Empire which has been around for
you know forever and yet with minor
modifications you can bypass almost all
antivirus so it's pretty effective and
you can also easily obfuscate scripting
languages so what that does is it
changes to clear text code into
something that's hard to distinguish so
anti viruses can't pick up on it so
here's an example of obfuscated code
there's this script called invoke alpha
station which is really great I would
recommend it but it doesn't always work
sometimes there are some bugs in it so
it's tricky
so there's also domain fronting it's
kind of complex but basically how it
works is that you're using a high
reputation domain like google.com or
CloudFront net and then your proxying
your command and control traffic through
that into your command and control so
that's really great because on the
network all you're seeing is a bunch of
encrypted post requests to Google or
CloudFront and that's hard to
distinguish from legitimate traffic and
also what's cool about that is that with
SSL stripping usually they have
exceptions for these kind of domains
because they're used so frequently so
you're gonna go through a strip you're
gonna skip the stripping as well another
thing you can do is a third party
command and control like Dropbox that's
a really great drop I mean sorry
PowerShell Empire has a really great
Dropbox module so you can use Dropbox as
your command and control and that's
going to appear similar to the actual
Dropbox app that people install so one
thing to be careful there is Dropbox
doesn't want you to be using them as
command and control so they're going to
be actively looking for your PowerShell
Empire based you know traffic basically
so you want to make sure to change the
defaults and make sure you test it so
that they don't kick you out and another
thing is a PowerShell Empire has this
msbuild
a package basically msbuild is a
legitimate microsoft binary they can
through application whitelisting and
also powershell constrained mode so
that's definitely a great payload to use
because it gets through those two major
roadblocks so here's a great example of
all this being applied in the wild I
believe this is ocean Lotus apt but I'm
not complete
so there's a guy called John Lambert
he's got a great great Twitter so I
would recommend following him so here we
have an office document with macros and
then what the macros does it's basically
a renames w script which is a thing that
runs jscript or VBS and then renamed
that because the defenders could be
watching for that specific executable so
that gets through that defense and then
what they do is they use this pub PRN
VBS script which is the legitimate
Microsoft signed VBS script but there is
a vulnerability where it can inject any
code you want so you can run this script
and have it run your code with your VBS
code so enigma tweeted or posted about
this he's also got a great blog and
another thing that they're using is this
thing called dotnet tjs so basically
that converts dotnet code like c-sharp
into J S which is a scripting language
so again they're abusing this scripting
language thing but I'm seeing this being
detected nowadays so you might have to
modify it so here are some anti blue
teen techniques basically after you
bypass all the technical controls you
still have to bypass the blue team which
is like actual people so they're always
trying to find you and your network
they're always trying to kick you out
and really and all the fun so you want
to make sure that doesn't happen so
unless secure or honestly in most
environments they get a phishing
notification they're not gonna like do
Avast reverse engineering or all of that
stuff they're basically gonna email
everyone that clicked on the link they
can find out who clicked on the link but
they can't find out who actually ran the
payload so they're just going to email
dating or email them saying did you run
the payload so the cool thing about that
is if you've compromised them
you have access to email so you can just
write outlook rule to just block those
kinds of emails and then they're never
gonna get that notification so I wrote a
PowerShell script to do that are called
hide phishing notification which does
exactly that another cool thing is
environmental keying basically what that
does isn't it encrypts your payload and
then it can only be decrypted using
certain environmental strings like the
domain name or the existence of Outlook
XE so what that does is not only does it
bypass antivirus and boxes it also makes
incident response a lot harder so like
you can have it so that your payload can
only be decrypted at this ran in an
environment with the domain of example
comm that contains Outlook exe or office
that exe or whatever so there's this
cool tool called sharpshooter which
basically can do environmental keying it
can also do anti VM detection basically
detect when it's being run in the
sandbox and then don't run the malicious
code if it is and it can also create a
scripting languages that basically run
shell code so you can have it run
Metasploit meterpreter or whatever you
want so it's a pretty great tool so I
would recommend it the other thing you
can do is have separate campaigns so if
you have twenty email addresses you can
divide it in two through four groups of
five and then have different missing
messages and different payloads for each
of them so it's gonna be hard for them
to detect each and every one and you
know kick you out for all of them so now
that you have all that ready it's time
to send the actual email some things to
keep in mind is SPF D command D mark
those are kind of caught too complex or
too you know
it will take too long to explain them
but basically in an email you have to
balance email address and then you have
the from email address the from is
actually where what the user sees but
the bounce is also important so SPF
basically blocks spoofing for that
balanced email address and then D can
block smooshing for the from email
address now most companies have already
implemented
SPF but there's still a lot of companies
that haven't implemented D chem so if
you know your target company hasn't
implemented that it's a great thing to
take advantage of but you can even spoof
their own domain and it's gonna look
completely judgment includes a picture
of them and everything well if they
blocked it then there's nothing you can
do about that you can also use a
third-party a high reputation SMTP so
like SendGrid or MailChimp or Google or
Amazon or whatever those services have
high SMTP reputation and are less likely
to end in spam and you can also use this
tool called mil tester com to test your
emails basically it goes through and
checks for comment spam things and it
can even scan it through a bunch of
anti-spam filters so you can use this to
test how good your payload is and
there's all kinds of ways to actually
send the email but what I really like is
go fish it's really a vast and it's got
all kinds of tools but really any method
is fine so we're gonna do a live demo so
let's hope this works
looks I can't see the top cornerback
okay so we're going to target google.com
since you know there are really good
security and stuff so here I have
LinkedIn and I'm searching through for
people who may be public relations or
public policy or whatever so I just
searched up policy I mean public and
there's all kinds of stuff that shows up
but I've already chose a list from that
subset I'm sorry I don't have to go
through all that so here's the list I
created so these people are going to be
targeted well I'm not actually going to
target them but for this example I'm
going to target these people so now that
I have their names I'm gonna convert it
to email addresses so first I got to
find out what their pattern is so to do
that you can just use Google
okay so I've searched this guy's name up
as you can see there's this WikiLeaks
thing that contains his email address
and you can see that is at is the first
letter at the first name and then the
last name at google.com so that's the
pattern you can use so I'm gonna use my
tool or hunter-gather to convert those
names into email addresses so here we
have our list of email addresses so
those are the people that were going to
send the email to so what we're gonna do
is we're going to import impersonate the
head of HR and say there's some kind of
a charge change or whatever some kind of
a vacation or schedule change to be
exact so to find that director of HR you
can either use LinkedIn or if they're a
bigger company you can just use Google
so we're going to use Google against
Google there we go well that's actually
an outdated one that guy got replaced by
this person so we're going to
impersonate this person so normally I
would do the bounce emails checking with
this to check to make sure that these
email addresses are valid but I don't
really have permission to do that so I'm
not gonna do that so that being said
let's send the actual email I'm not
going to send it to them obviously but
I'm going to send it
myself and then we can test the actual
payload the one that you saw earlier
that's on my github that's what I'm
gonna use okay so to send the email I'm
using a custom script that I created but
you can use any method so I'm gonna send
the email right now to myself and that
is my email address by the way all right
so here it is I already sent it to me
before just in case it didn't work so I
have two of them so we're gonna open it
as you can see it's got all the right
details and it's got a link to some kind
of Google Drive so we're gonna go ahead
and download and run this and we want to
open and what we have here is Kaspersky
and endpoint protection so this is one
of the best anti viruses so that's why I
chose that one because I had a hard time
bypassing it and but at the end I still
was able to bypass it so it shows that
everything can be bypassed even if it's
really hard Black Hills actually made a
blog about Kaspersky and how hard they
are to bypass and how they did it is
they used it like an old obscure remote
administration tool but I don't think
that's like a truly legit bypass because
you can always create your own remote
administration tool and it's not going
to get detected because it's brand-new
but eventually it will and there's no
point in like and then you're gonna have
to keep creating new ones so that
doesn't work so I think the trick is to
take into
justing one that already gets detected
and find a way to make it undetected so
that's what I did and basically what I
did I talked about QP which is written
in Python basically I'd use that but I
used an actual Python interpreter so I
wrote a script to install Python as a
user and install all the dependencies
and then run QP so it will get caught by
application whitelisting but those are
legitimate applications python is
legitimate and it's not going to get to
take the antivirus
so i've already installed it from a
previous test and I didn't want to
reinstall it because I don't know how
slow the internet here is it's probably
pretty slow ok there we go so it ran it
deployed the decoy document I would show
you what it looks like on the server I
got a shell and QP but I forgot my SSH
password and I couldn't find it so sorry
about that but on the server there is a
shell and I can prove that by doing an S
that
and then you want to find Python I know
it's in there oh I know there you go
haha scripting language to rescue so
yeah as you can see that's establish the
connection there so unfortunately I
can't show you the actual command and
control because I forgot the password
but we know it works and you know it
gets through Kaspersky so that's pretty
cool so back to the presentation so here
are some key takeaways do your recon
using Lincoln it's an amazing resource
and be aware of what the defenses are
doing make sure you have a lab setup
that matches that of your target and
make sure you're testing it all the way
be sure to test like not only the
payload itself but also the email and
everything because like that could
potentially get caught as well make sure
you're not using the defaults and make
don't be afraid to customize stuff don't
be afraid to go in the source code and
change it
because like when I was doing this there
was all kinds of problems I ran into not
just for Kaspersky but also other anti
viruses like Symantec detects long power
show commands so I had to get through
that as well so there's all kinds of
roadblocks you have to get through so
here are some remediations for defense
so being aware of fishing you know lets
you know how to defend against fishing
so users can get fished with militia
with remote administration tools that
they can't even run code so if you
prevent their ability to run code that
would greatly reduce the attack surface
you can also train and educate your
users and make sure you're testing them
because like just training them it's
like having a lecture without a test
like they're not gonna actually remember
anything I'm also probably going to be
looking at their phones anyways and not
really care so that's the end of my
presentation if you have any questions
I'd be happy to answer them sure that
would work as long as you have some kind
of API to develop it in the c24 Dropbox
is you know specifically for job box so
you have to create your own whatever
adapter I guess honestly I've never
tried a SWAT domain but there are a lot
of defenses against those kinds of
attacks like I know for a lot of mature
environments they will block all domains
registered in the last 30 days so I
don't see any reason not to use Google
Drive or Dropbox since they're already
legit and they're already trusted but
yeah as far domains you usually you have
to use that so there's a tool called
catfish which can find squad domains
including ones that are about to expire
so that's a great tool for finding those
all right
thank you