[Applause]
Thanks um so I'm just gonna jump right
in
can I give a little bit about me I am a
consultant for Optive security I try to
pose as a full-stack developer some of
the time and that's kind of led me down
to creating this tool and this all kind
of arose from really doing like a base
of testing there's a lot of manual
procedures that go into it spinning up
taking down services in various content
delivery networks trying to hide source
of attack and trying to kind of bypass a
lot of these controls existing on the
perimeter and on the internal networks
that will detect anomalous activity such
as port scanning data exfiltration and
stuff of the like as well as um you need
to protect your this infrastructure from
potential investigation from the
defenders looking at this traffic so
this kind of led to me thinking more
about this and as you all know you might
have seen tools like Red Baron and the
like come out that really involve more
long-term persistent Red Team
infrastructure stuff that you're gonna
keep up for a long time you're gonna
manage and you're really gonna harden
down and kind of do your whole
engagement from but the the whole idea
that I that I kind of went with is I'm
looking for a ephemeral infrastructure
stuff that will not last more than even
so a day I want something that'll come
up come down so that there can really be
no correlation to its traffic in any of
your activities going through a red team
activity so any investigation it will be
that note that IP is no longer live or
that IP now belongs to someone else on
this various cloud services that we're
using this leads to a very small
footprint so that again it's very hard
to correlate what's going on if you have
this these type of server
that aren't lasting very long are doing
very much but combined they're getting
your whole goal accomplished but making
it much more hard much harder to detect
on and I have the link here for the
github the teaser site the code isn't
quite live yet um I was trying to get it
ready but it's still a little bit packed
together in a way it needs a little bit
more fleshing out um we'll go through a
demo later but if you want to follow
that that github site then you can go
ahead and get it as soon as it's
released so one of the main components
about this is managing a cross provider
platform we want a single interface to
manage multiple cloud providers in their
various VPS and bps services API
gateways firewalls we want all that
stuff in one spot so this tool really
aims to give you that singular view of
let's say I spent up a tea serve a tea
servers and they're all distributed
between Google AWS and digitalocean I
don't want to have to go through and go
through each console and manage each one
individually I want to be able to look
at my entire landscape of my
infrastructure and be able to make
decisions on that rather than trying to
have to correlate them all together and
manage them individually though this
kind of plays into I can deploy destroy
start and stop instances on demand um
that's uh that being said it really
makes it again easy to manage multiple
cloud providers also I can easily send
and get files from these uh these
servers and I can drop into a command
shell on anyone on a whim just by
sending one command in Maya basically in
be the tool interface furthermore I've
added protections that you can put in
place
basic one is firewalls or security
groups that you can place on individual
servers so let's say I have 10 servers
and I want to open them open one of them
up and run Apache on it for some type of
fish
engagement I can open up just port 80 on
one of my servers and have that have
that maintained as my fishing
infrastructure also you can add in
redirect errs that will redirect based
on certain rules let's say that if you
don't meet a certain user agent then
that will redirect the request to
wherever you want to go oh this is
probably one of the biggest things in
this framework that is really useful for
an evasive test let's say you're running
a port scan you don't want to run top
1,000 ports it from one server if you're
doing an evasive test that's gonna hit
every single IDs and IPS there is is
going to notice that's a port scan block
that IP we're done with what you can do
with this tool is you can distribute
those jobs among your entire
infrastructure and then they are tasked
with very small jobs making one or two
requests to eat to your targets and then
bringing all that data back and
correlating it back on your end on your
central central endpoint so that way you
get all of the data but when someone's
looking when a defender is watching
their logs it looks like normal Internet
traffic a port here a port there and it
doesn't necessarily look like someone is
port scanning unless they're really
really looking for it and this yields
for future developments where I want to
be able to distribute commands across
this entire infrastructure let's say
you're doing directory brute-forcing you
want to split up that word list and
split up the job among all of these
hosts so that the job can be done
quickly efficiently and relatively
quietly because if the traffic isn't
coming from one endpoint oh another
thing is speaking of proxying those
requests oh you can create Sox proxies
on any of these hosts so theoretically I
could spin up 40 hosts put a socks proxy
on each one of them and then use proxy
chains to send each request through a
different proxy this is simply another
method of kind of distributing commands
it's a bit slower and that distributed
this should be a command example I went
through before but it still achieves a
similar effect of each request is going
through a different proxy and stuff that
can't go through proxy chains there's
also Sox T configurations that you
printed out as well in the tool um this
kind of plays on the other one it these
are use cases for those proxies that
you're using so you can use it for
discovery and exploitation you can
separate those activities you can have
one socks proxy that's for your
discovery one socks proxy that's for
authenticated discovery and one that is
for a pure exploitation so that when
they're going back on the server logs it
won't be the same server doing the
entire attack chain so it will be hard
to correlate who's doing what and
following that narrative from an IR and
investigation perspective this also
includes two brute-forcing and if your
if one of your servers gets blocked from
spidering and a laff detects that
activity blocks that IP it's really not
an issue you can bring it bring it down
bring it back up and now that IP is or
that server is no longer blocked with a
fresh IP furthermore I implemented an
API gateway you can't see it that well
on here at all um but the idea is that
um Amazon API gateways allow you to
configure an endpoint that you can hit
and it will make a request on your
behalf to another server so I have an
API gateway that will make a request to
a certain endpoint but each request from
that API gateway generally has a
different IP cycling through about 500
ish per region so it allows you to a
password guess the the screenshot I have
up here is guessing an OWI portal if
anyone's been on a Red Team engagement
they know OWA guessing is an easy go to
but this allows for the OWA guessing to
be distributed across these services and
coming from different IPS it again
furthers that the difficulty in
detecting this kind of activity in
tracking it to a single endpoint in this
way you can separate yourself from the
brute-forcing itself a big thing I
wanted to add in here because that's
something that I've been using a lot
more is domain fronting for those of you
who don't necessarily know what domain
fronting is originally it was a
technique that the major content
delivery networks used to bypass
internet censorship so in Egypt during
the Arab Spring they used domain
fronting to make signal available to
users in Egypt and that made it so that
you could request to google.com but the
but via the host header you could
actually still access signal even though
that signal itself was blocked so a lot
of the major content delivery networks
made signal available and that way they
could still access signals still act and
still have communication going on inside
this country with a restricted network
the reason that they did it is because
stopping it looks a whole lot like
turning off the internet so if you're
gonna stop domain fronting you got a
block a good portion of Amazon a good
portion of Google as your basically any
cloud provider out there and if you're
turning off as your amazon and google
you don't really have much internet left
right so really the thing is is that
people hear this and they're like so
what the reason domain fronting really
matters and especially in terms from red
team and blue team perspective is that
it's able to bypass a lot of egress
controls so if you're doing domain
fronting through Google and with a
Google endpoint you your actual TLS and
SSL negotiation happens with that Google
site they're requesting so if you're
requesting WWE google.com you're TLS
negotiation is happening with Google if
with Google com it's not til it gets to
that Google infrastructure that it's uh
that it is routed to your App Engine
instance which is acting as your your
redirector and this
that this is now encrypted with HSTs and
this makes SSL stripping very hard on
and I am not aware of any I'm not really
big on the SSL stripping and the SSL
interception technologies but I'm not
really aware of many if any that can
actually strip HSTs encrypted
connections with Google and so a lot of
a lot of companies disallow Google
outbound um it's not something that they
intercept on their SSL appliances then
the big thing is is that it's not only
restricted to Google on you can do this
over is your you can do this over Amazon
you can you can do whatever Akamai I
believe and the really possibilities are
endless because a lot of these major
content delivery networks domain
fronting is a way that they ensure
robustness of their platform so let you
can really leverage it in a lot of ways
in terms of an attacker and this kind of
leads me back into the tool of right now
you can deploy Amazon and Google based
of Amazon and Google base cloud domain
fronts and this allows you to set in
your source and your endpoint and click
in your go it's it's very simple um this
really arose from the fact that it's
kind of tedious to set up multiple
domain fronts and just being able to
manage them all in one spot set them up
on a whim was really really appealing
furthermore allows you to restrict
access based on let's say subnet or IP
and also even user agent a technique I
really like to use for user agents that
if you restrict it based on user agent
then when you make that request to the
domain front you can put an extra space
in a valid valid user agent and so any
investigation will look like a valid
user agent except for that extra space
is actually what it's a the reg X is
teen on so you will not be able to
access the domain front and the the
reaction from it will be it will
redirect you to wherever you
so if I'm posing as inbox at google.com
all have my redirector based on that
user agent string redirect inbox at
google.com so let's say you need
offender that's investigating they type
it into their browser they go to the app
spot instance where my redirector is
actually hosted and they get redirected
to inbox that google calm so that's
really perplexing so they may just think
this is just some Google craziness
that's going on so now I'm gonna go
through a demo of the tool itself okay
see if this okay that's not looking good
give me one second we change the display
on here there we go
alright that better can everyone see
okay so the the tool itself is built on
is built with go and it's built via the
ghost specifications and I will yeah
just talk through it right now um as you
can see we are deploying the cloud
providers um it currently supports AWS
digitalocean in Google I'm working to
support as you're currently and more
cloud providers in the future so here
I'm just applying for servers and it
will divide them between the two cloud
providers in any regions that I choose
have in my configuration file it takes a
little while to initialize all the
instances so I can do all the operations
on them but as you can see here we can
deploy destroy start stop list um drop
in to come
and she'll add a socks proxy created
domain front
distribute an nmap scan of among the
instances print out the proxy proxy
configuration for proxy chains and Sox D
send files retrieve files and set up a
firewall I'm working on in the future
developments of importing existing cloud
infrastructure so that your firewalls
domain fronts and your VPS is can be
imported when the tool initializes so
that any existing infrastructure you
have in there will be manageable from
this interface as well as a this
interface was mainly made for for this
con so forgiving e forgive any things
that are a problem with it because it
was really just hacked together and in
that regard and I'm working on more of a
web-based interface or you can get a
more of a visual view of what's going on
so as we wait for this I'll kind of go
into the the framework that is being
used it's built on go and via the go
specifications everything is a package
right so the all the Amazon stuff Google
digitalocean all that stuff is package
space and that means that if one of
y'all wanted to go out and write a tool
that deployed Amazon instances and did
some management of them you could simply
go import the package from this project
and use the deploy and deploy ec2
feature in your own project so that's
why it's a framework and not necessarily
a tool itself so it's not restricted to
using the entire framework you can
import the the digitalocean
you can import the just cloud fronting
on so anything that you wanted to do on
your own you could simply import it and
just run it inside your own program so
that's that's what I really wanted to
have a package based system so that if
you wanted to just take a few of these
and kind of make it into something your
own that's something you can go ahead
and do no problem
so all these functions are already
written and you don't have to wrestle
with this tool you can really kind of do
what you want if you're looking for
something a little bit different but now
we have
our servers have been deployed and we're
gonna go ahead and list them if as you
can see um it gives you the type the IP
the region and various states of what's
going on so we're gonna go ahead and add
Sox proxies and as you can see we
created Sox proxies added all the
servers to the proxy and started on port
and then now it'll increment through
each one and now I have four Sox proxies
then we printed out the proxy config so
you could copy and paste this into your
proxy chains config file or you could
use this in Sox T also it's not limited
to anything if you got 80 servers you
could spin up 80 instances of a socks
proxy if you so desire so now we're
gonna go ahead and kill one of the Sox
proxies and for for the for the server
one so now as you can see the Sox value
is in a so that means the sux is not
live for that host so we're gonna drop
into that host because we're gonna want
to make this host like a web server
right so we're gonna open up a shell and
just a little confirmation of where I'm
at you got the ifconfig and so what
you'd be doing here is you would go in
there you would make manual changes to
the server that you would want and let's
say you want to install Apache
kind of do some custom requests on it or
just anything customized that you want
to do to it it'll be easy to drop in and
do it manually so there you have it
right there and now we're gonna make a
firewall for that server that we want to
act as our web server so we're going to
create a 443 inbound and we're gonna
make it globally accessible and then
we're gonna name the firewall
and then we're gonna list the firewall
that we have active so now as you can
see we're able to create a firewall just
for that service that server so we're
not creating anything like a security
group that has everything in it just
this server now is 443 inbound and I can
make it a web server and kind of do what
I want something I'm looking to add in
the future is a bit more customized
ability in terms of deploying web
servers I do have something on my github
right now that'll automatically deploy a
let's encrypt cert - to a server of your
choice so that's going to be implemented
in this and probably the coming weeks of
being able to deploy a web server deploy
let's encrypt cert um just on the go in
one command so now we're gonna create a
domain front and we're gonna do a google
domain front and where we want it to
point to is essentially where we're
gonna wear the redirector for is where
we're where the redirector is going to
point to our c2 server for example so I
think going through all those and we're
not going to restrict based on user
agent or subnet but that is an option to
kind of as I was talking about before
redirect based on that user agent or
subnet so you can kind of provide a
little bit more defensive measures to
this domain front not make it really
globally accessible and we're using
g-cloud here and so I'm going to go
ahead and make my appspot instance
so now what's happening is that it's a
basically updating the app engine
service that it's using because with
Google domain fronting you use an app
engine service that you can request any
Google URL and you set the host header
to your app spot URL provided by the
service so now that it's complete we're
gonna go ahead and list the domain
fronts and so as you can see this the
URL if we request let's say if I if I
did a curl command and set the host
header to inbox a ninety-day p.m. but
the URL that I requested was inbox
google.com it would actually be
redirected to http example.com so how we
use that in a Red Team situation is
let's say I have an agent inside the
basically on a restricted corporate
network where they do kind of a web
content inspection outbound so what's
happened or what web content inspection
so the thing is is that when they're
reaching out they're actually making
that request that negotiation with inbox
on google.com and so as my agent is as
it's traffic the data it's exfilling
is actually being encrypted with a
Google certificate going out to Google's
infrastructure and then getting routed
to my c2 infrastructure so that means
that this malicious agent a trojan or
whatever is now communicating with
google.com from outsider's perspective
but it's being routed to my c2
infrastructure and I now have a robust
encrypted c2 channel with HSTs via
Google comm and I believe that that is
the end of the demo right now and then
let me just move on
ooh the future improvements that I'm
looking to make this in the coming weeks
or adding more cloud providers and a
web-based graphical interface you can
get more of a basically more of a visual
view of what's going on
what you're doing kind of more graphs
and this a better interface for the user
to deal with this I'm also looking into
adding docker containers and vagrant VMs
in order to push them up in the
infrastructure make it a little bit
easier to install dependencies and
things like that on also working out
working out the distributed commands and
adding more cloud services such as AWS
lambda and integrating those more into
the platform furthermore looking for a
little bit more robustness in the way
I'm basically the way I'm taking input
in the way I'm deploying things it's so
it's still very immature but right now
it's I'm using it in the wild and it's
it's it's worked out pretty well for me
on engagement so far um that was the end
of my talk I will open it up for
questions if anyone has any yeah yeah
for sure I mean I'm definitely like
lambda functions and um that that kind
of idea is definitely in the works right
now because that's my that's much like
what I'm using for Google App Engine you
can just deploy a single go script into
Google App Engine and do that but lambda
is definitely in development pipeline
for sure yes but on the it's because
it's
wrapped in the TLS yeah no see what
happens is is that they what happens is
it reaches Google's front-end
infrastructure and then now that URL is
gone and then it redirects based on the
host header once you get to Google's
infrastructure it's supposed to match if
it no yeah
they do not care yet yeah exactly
because I mean I forget which RFC it is
but the RFC that defines the host header
um and if it's a compliant proxy it'll
rewrite the host header and thwart that
but because it's encrypted with HSTs
it's um really really hard to intercept
that SSL connection right yeah um but
like I said there that's actually it's
part of what adds robustness to the
internet you know because basically
making domain fronting work is they can
by Pat they can ensure availability in a
way so it's it's one of those things
that until it really becomes an issue I
doubt they're gonna do anything about it
um even then I'm sure that if they get
like a subpoena or something like that
they'll just give the owner of that
instance to whoever so I'm not sure that
from I'm not sure to ever become rampant
with script kiddies enough that it will
actually become that big of an issue but
if it does change then I'm gonna be very
disappointed anyone else oh yeah for
sure um if you wanna if you want to
collaborate just on you can get in touch
with me via like LinkedIn or Twitter
it's at our my kagaz and you can uh we
can flesh something out I'm very very
new to the whole collaborative
development and my wife is actually like
teaching me everything about
not pushing the master and using
branches and everything but yeah I'm
definitely open to it because I think
that would uh it would add a lot of
value to it because the whole idea is I
want to create more of a framework that
people can use and not just restrict
them to the tool and kind of give
everyone this capability of kind of more
this is DevOps II kind of pen testing
and um kind of this Red Team framework
um what do you mean um with the with the
Google domain fronting um yes because
the it's encrypted all the way to the
appspot instance and then it's kind of
like in the Google domain fronting I'm
using more of a reverse proxy on App
Engine in the Amazon Cloud domain
fronting I use cloud front so both of
those if you set an endpoint for HTTP so
it's reaching that that redirector and
it's being inside that redirector VM
it's actually it's being decrypted and
then re encrypted when it negotiates
with your HTTP encrypted a C 2 C 2
server so if they were inspecting the
contents of the VM they could see what's
going in but then again if they're
inspecting contents of VM traffic that's
kind of a no-no if people were figuring
that out right um great question so uh
me a colleague of mine and a couple of
more of the network architecture guys
adoptive we actually did a study on this
and ran basically ran Google - ran this
domain fronting and ran it through
various uh basically ran through
Wireshark and sent the peak caps off to
them and what you find is that B core it
be ratio to certificate negotiations and
requests is abnormally high
so that is that is probably your best
indicator that this is happening is that
there is a new certificate negotiation
each time the request the it beacons
outright so that is that is one way you
certainly could like there are agency or
you could build in reusing that sir
Tipene that connection but as of right
now the that is probably in my opinion
the best way because um it's not
necessarily feasible to strip SSL on all
of this but I would say that that is
probably your best indicator if you want
to get more information on this
technique specifically um the Optive
blog has a we did a write-up on this and
also we had the more of our defenders
come in and do their write-up on what
they saw and how to detect it it's
called I think it's egress and evasion
and restricted networks part two so if
you want to go check that out and kind
of more information about this um I
would highly recommend taking a look
it's a pretty good pretty good
collaborative piece between red and red
and blue on that one okay um I'll wrap
it up thank you for your time
[Applause]