alright fuck yeah I feel really loud am
i loud I do alright yes sir you spotted
it already yeah yeah whoo Carolina God
cheers cheers to you by all means this
is gonna hopefully be fun and it's
hopefully not gonna run too long so I
might I might talk fast I'm probably
talking loud but in general we're gonna
learn a lot of fun things and you're
gonna taste a lot of fun things and if
you finish your tasting and a bottle
goes somewhere I don't know how that
happened it went somewhere else big big
thanks to a lot of people a lot of
voices and a lot of help that went into
this Jack Daniel and I had the original
idea for this way back when well he had
the idea of liver strong the the
wristbands that are not saying
LIVESTRONG they say liver strong which
you will get in this audience so he's
just yeah so he's a wonderful soul and
I'm a maje to him he had to be elsewhere
but I'm wearing a shirt for him tonight
friend of mine Kevin head owned a bar
and Missoula spent a lot of time there
when I lived in Montana taught me a lot
of things that I didn't know and had a
lot of whiskey's I couldn't afford my
buddy Chris Dickerson a fan of pushing
one's limits especially chemically or
physically or other ways so yeah Jim
manly the whiskey tasting force if you
ever get around to any of the tasting
events at various hacker cons very good
people hackers in general are very kind
and sharing and and will open your
horizons he is one who did that my
friend Katie a bartender and InfoSec
wizard and taught me about other mixing
of drinks in the past huge tanks as you
will see my psycho holocrons who built a
circuit with me I have never done a lot
of shit in my life that involved
electronical x' and this part of this
talk is like I am an idiot and so can
you but
you can make shit happen amazing ways
Scotland if you've never seen her around
just another contributor to this and
people who are generous at cons if you
ever go to the no starch booth and drink
some of bills liquor if spam and his
brother mr. glass are ever running a
tasting like people give the whiskey
leak screw oh my god the whiskey leaks
bottle shares that happen at Milly ways
or another hacker events with pronto and
his friends here share with your friends
try new things and this is all going to
be about trying new things so I love
Karolina con very much I love the
shenanigans that happen here okay
mirrors it is it is a really fun and
really special place and I I travel to
hundreds of cons all the time but I
always miss being here when I'm not here
and I always save new stuff every year
for Karolina cons so this has never been
done before and hopefully it'll work out
[Applause]
right on so this talk is gonna be a lot
about whisky but just for a second we
got to talk about wine I like wine I
talked last year and my talk about you
know the Vivino app and finding cheap
wine and you know things in grocery
stores but this meme went around right
someone was like hey everyone's crafty
on that Pinterest for like who's ever
made wine in their insta pot you're
slackers well this dude up and did it
and that's his blog all about it and
it's fucking easy you can make your own
pruno hooch like you can you know get
some grape juice get some sugar all you
need is yeast and an insta pot you you
load that shit in on the yogurt mode you
yoke that up for 48 hours
it's a super slow cook and bam and then
you pour it right back in the giant
64-ounce err put a little airlock and
just let it shoot for a while and there
you go you've got wine you've got I did
white wine too
I have red and white wine up here it is
it is just as good as you expect it with
taste what she got she got 10% on the
ABV s so right off the hop we're gonna
we're gonna go ahead and say look at
that that hop if you want to try prison
wine hey G Martin what's going on
adilyn all right on sit on up so right
now my tasting my esteemed tasting panel
it's gonna be subject to a lot this
evening so a hand for them please and I
want to know if anyone up here is bold
enough to try the wine yes all right use
your small tumblers or plastic tumbler
glasses to I will warn you this now did
you all did you all eat first okay
everyone on this table small pores if
you have a full serving of everything
being presented by the end of this talk
you will have had 17 drinks so even the
darling doctor deviate does not
recommend that particular level of
dosage of the marvelous and magical
mutters milk I'm down all right what do
you what do you think like it's awful
it's really bad well you have the way
you could try the red by the way you can
these bottles can kind of go that
direction if these fellas over here want
to take a little sip unofficially
unofficially
all right seems like this yes despair
when a high crime rate Karl says it's
very very kind of Mena Arizona tasting
right so insulting the red that's not
it's not that awful well it's been aging
for another week in shipment I drank it
when it was very loose tea but alright
well where do you where you want if
you're making wine where do the flavors
in wine originated you have inputs right
you have grape and different grapes
different varietals will taint the
flavor in one way or another
the choice of yeast that you use which
is that good isn't it
it's awesome your choice of yeast will
change the flavor which is why improving
imprint who knows what kind of yeast is
most frequently used in prison to make
life to make brunette girl reg East I
heard it red yeast we use actual wine
yeast so it's not that god-awful but
mostly you know you've got your
post-processing you're aging and that's
you know leaving wine around wine will
continue to mature it actually are you
saying it's a little bit better than it
might have been let me take a sip I
wouldn't go that far either but it's not
it's not complete bum-ass right all
right
all right well let these let get the
wine bottles somewhere else now if you
have wine and you buy wine or you make
wine this one can get out of here to
like elsewhere elsewhere else so you can
add your own wine right like you have a
bottle of wine quiet down quiet down if
you have a bottle of wine you stick it
on a shelf that's how you effectively
like a hack wines flavor right you can
age it yourself and if ain't a wine will
mellow with age some elements would
become you know pronounced some will
soften so I mean you can hack wine by
aging right you can't change the fruit
that went into it you can't change the
yeast that was decided before you came
along but you can age wine and I by all
means instead of building some bullshit
rec room in your basement like don't
have kids fuck it just build a wine
cellar it's it's a very good thing
so we're gonna talk about hacking a lot
of drinks flavors and if some of you
think it's not that bad okay I think it
kind of is I'm gonna stick with a three
buck chuck that Vivino is telling me to
buy but you can you can trim maybe you
know if we don't drink it all tonight
maybe we'll stick it in you know your
closet and see how it is in a month
because it'll keep aging wine will keep
aging but that was a little segue that
was can't hear you Oh your pet yeah
behind you there go ahead so yes that
was a little side note just because some
crazy guy wrote a blog instead we're
gonna talk mostly about whiskey or or do
we mean whiskey is it te or not to e
that is the question where are we yeah
well that's the thing right so whiskey
versus whiskey the pronunciation the
spelling so these are the countries that
spell it with an e these are the
countries that spell it without any yes
now if you ever curious about that Jim
manly who I mentioned earlier he gave a
wonderful talk called hacking grain it
was all about whiskey he is a distiller
and a producer and he talks about how
the history of whiskey with an e started
in Ireland when the Jameson cousins and
you know John Powers George Rowe they
wanted to separate their product on the
market from scotch and much American
distilling tradition comes from Irish
immigrants that's why we are one of the
other B nations now I love Irish whiskey
I will talk a lot about Irish whiskey if
you want not tonight tonight we are
talking about Scotch because we can do
different things with scotches who is
who as a fan of scotch right on so what
do you have there sir oh you have open
all right
Macallan so these gentlemen are drinking
primarily better scotches or what some
people might think of as better scotches
the idea of single malts people go nuts
over single malt whiskey and you know
that what what grain goes in on the mash
bill is it just one malt from just one
distiller versus not why do people go so
nuts about this and if you're not this
this talk is if you've not really been a
tasting person if you've never dove into
this this is my series of analogies that
might help you understand I use kind of
a theater analogy when I tried to
describe once to someone why people
think single malts are this
amazing thing so imagine a huge Broadway
production with all the budget in the
world and the light show and the rigging
and they're flying people in and out and
you can be like oh yeah Broadway I saw
the show yay
but imagine seeing a super minimalistic
stage show right no set black box like
seeing I saw Waiting for Godot when it
was you know basically Professor X and
Magneto I saw you know Patrick Stewart
and Sir Ian McKellen and it was the most
amazing thing I'd ever seen on the stage
not a huge production doing more with
less is is praiseworthy and it's
remarkable when you say wow you were so
constrained that you only had this to
work with that's I can't believe you
created that that is your single malt
blended whiskies by their nature are you
have all the money you have all the
budget you have all the options and
master distillers with their nose will
kind of blend all different sources to
come up with this specific flavor and I
get that and there's a place for that
I'm not gonna poopoo it you could get
crazy deep into like learning training
your nose with these nose and kits and
taking tasting notes together tonight
again because this is a lower
introductory talk we're not gonna get
crazy deep tonight we are gonna talk
about blended Scotch because it's an
easy bar to rise to and we're gonna have
a lot less challenge on your palate when
we get your feedback okay so tasting
blended Scotch deviants super help super
helpful chart Jesus people if you're
gonna show up don't be in the front
fucking row all right
super simple chart ready we've got
intensity and character all right you
can think of this as how loudly it
speaks and how much you actually care
what it has to say imagine you're in a
bar right you can think of they're in a
bar right you've got a person who sits
down next to you as a total stranger how
loudly they speak and how much you care
what they have to say most of your
blended scotches more or less will fall
on this kind of parabola and there's
kind of sections so you've got this
first section right here okay this is
think of this as like a 23 year old from
rec reddit with a mag aha and who really
wants to talk to you about his new idea
involving blockchain you're like oh my
god fuck the fuck off leave me alone go
away this is like anything in a plastic
bottle up to like doers all right
the quintessential blended Scotch here
is Johnny read suitable only for mixing
with soda or pouring down the drain okay
then you got this next section on my
chart here this is this is like look I
don't know who you are just don't make
trouble and maybe you could sit there
I'm not gonna tell the bartender to
throw you out so this is you know like
Shiva J&B the classic like shot and a
beer kind of Scotch drinkers we'll add a
bar a shit ball bar
Johnny Blackie or anywhere around the
world it's never gonna blow you away but
like I know what this is don't make
trouble yeah I've got a scotch in my
hand fine
and there is a place for that on the
market now we start to get into an
interesting spot in the spot I kind of
dig on blended scotches what I look for
when I'm trying to be cheap but not
having just the same bullshit experience
this is the oh wow who's this guy he's
kind of interesting so let's that's all
right he's not talking too loudly but I
like what he has to say
all right monkey shoulder pigs nose you
got monkey shoulder right there that is
the favorite scotch of bartenders
nowadays when they want to make
something with a cocktail with scotch
because it doesn't speak loudly it's a
blended scotch that will taste like
scotch but it's not like crazy
introducing weird flavors if you can
find pig's nose by the way it's fucking
marvelous you should get a bottle of it
and then as we come back up this side
was that better than top I don't know
about that but this is that many things
are better as you get up this way this
is the zone where you're like oh do you
come in you're fascinating what tell me
more about yourself this is where you
know like you don't have to be a well
like an obscure name well know named
doers doers 18 is amazing and it's got
all this character still a blended
Scotch you can get up into like you know
Red Seal by the cannon Rock oyster is
this briny it's it's a very very full of
character but it's worth it it's a good
it's a good experience and this gets
very subjective up here so we're gonna
taste some whisky does that sound good
to you does that sound good to you maybe
okay how to taste whisky a few notes
about it the biggest questions that
people have and there's a lot of
misinformation about do you add ice do
you add water do you need either one
simply simply put a little bit of water
will open the flavor just a little bit
if you have any waters in front of you I
wouldn't even
you're not gonna pour it I wouldn't
recommend you use any water if you have
just like a water bottle yeah a
little-little from a little dribble from
a cap and there's a whole study that the
Linnaean university did in sweden about
molecules of why a call and how it
changes the surface tension but nothing
nothing is wrong about a little hint of
water if you want to experiment with
opening a flavor you see this more in
single malt land tonight I don't think
we need to and if whisky is too much for
you it's just you're not a whisky person
scotch oh my god it's so powerful you
can put ice or cool it down ice cubes
are fine but they melt whiskey stones
are this kind of trendy thing because it
can be cold but not melt I will
occasionally just drop an ice sphere in
there thank you very much
why-why-why spheres well sphere is your
best density to surface area so that's
why people like ice spheres they resist
melting while being cold a fun fact one
of the
left the one on the left is clear right
shut the fuck up all right
the one on the left is clear why is it
clear if you want to make clear ice you
know this it's you're exploiting what's
called directional freezing directional
freezing is as ice starts to freeze any
impurities in the water will be just
pushed away just pushed out of the way
right eventually though ice is usually
in a tray or something it will hit a
point where this is freezing clear but
your impurities eventually have nowhere
to go and they start getting into the
crystal lattice and that's why you get
discolored or cloudy ice most clear ice
kits are insulated in some way and
exploit they leverage this idea of
directional freezing winter smiths is a
really cool kit if you want big like
clear ice balls it's an insulated vessel
with a mold the ice that you put in
starts freezing freezes clear and then
this is all just sacrificial space and
it might be cloudy it doesn't matter
when you crack the ice balls out they're
clear and this you can remelt or you can
pour down the drain who gives a damn
that's an expensive kit this is not you
can put a cooler in your freezer start
freezing but arrest the process pull it
out before it's a hundred percent frozen
everything will be perfectly clear and
there's a guy on youtube who shows you
just take a knife whack it apart you can
make beautiful big chunks clear ice in
your home just like you're a high-end
cocktail bar today again if it's a
little something you want to try you
could dribble some water but I don't
recommend it I think we're just gonna be
fine with our glasses so there are three
steps when tasting the whiskey that
you're about to taste there are three
parts of a tasting and you should imbibe
and enjoy all of them approaching before
you've tasted you're gonna look at it
you're gonna enjoy the how it swirls
you're gonna see if it gives you some
legs and you're gonna give the aroma
when you're breathing in and whiskey's
aroma for wine you just kind of get your
nose in there all right
whisky tasting open your mouth because
you can nuke your palate if you just
work a big snot full of that open your
mouth kind of breathe in your mouth and
through some extra action other a little
bit of whisk will go through your nose
across your palate that's your
introduction that's your nosing of the
whiskey obviously yes imbibe and don't
just belt it down there's an old like
statement that says one
second in your mouth for as long as it
has been in the barrel for a year so a
10-year whiskey you're gonna keep try to
keep down your mouth about 10 seconds
there's almost this is somebody called
the Kentucky chew or you're like mmm get
it all over your tongue coat your tongue
and once you've finished you swallowed
then there's that there's a finish
beyond enjoy the sustain enjoy what's
remaining and that's when you're gonna
get other other notes that'll open up is
that is it a long tale it is a short
tale does something new pop up on your
tongue after you've swallowed down so I
oh yeah you can just make all kind of
innuendo here - stop - stop that
craziness we're gonna start off with
Scotch number one please go ahead and
pour yourself a little bit in your Glenn
Karen glasses thing you know there that
will be you're about to find out you are
flipping ahead in class I see I see the
peanut gallery has turned over duties to
a second voice up here yes so this is
this is these are all blended scotches
alright so we'll just bang it through as
fast as we can and then send it back to
my my fellas over here like additional
auxilary tape you're like the alternates
in the jury box you listen to the whole
case and you're not on the hook
oh very nice very nice so this is scotch
number one coming around
alright go ahead there sir was it not
clean glass this is this establishment
not professional enough for you I don't
know that was your hair then sir these
are branded alright so what do we think
how might and this is the microphone is
here for my tasters right yeah go for it
handsome oh yeah just past the boxing
room sure there grab the rock the mic
like a boss medium mouthfeel test test
yeah all right any other thoughts give
me give me a thought
got a nutty kind of nutty I don't like
it
what is it I don't like it okay so I
think it's mild
Merkers I agree your mouth is not needed
to pass something out just pass the
fucking box it's like it's like an
offering plate just move it around Wow
where do you think where do you think on
this scale it ranks I'm seeing you're
seeing obscene pointed up here okay yeah
that was famous price I am I am so
fucking sorry I apologize for that that
is kind of a shit ball blended Scotch
but it's all uphill from here he started
with the pruno Famous Grouse and I'm
gonna I'm gonna take you on a journey
alright so yeah since this is not
revered as a particularly good scotch
its revered for having a good price and
that's about all I don't recommend it if
you you know don't need it and that
bottle went over somewhere to them okay
I recommend that you water refresh in
your glass go ahead and swill out your
glass if there's any left in it you can
pitch it if you need to what did I
choose to start well maybe I did maybe I
didn't let's see alright
you let me to dump that for you there
yes or no you're gonna have a lot of
drinks in you alright refresh your
glasses we've refreshed glasses okay
we're gonna try scotch number two I got
to start putting these bottles out
quicker so that you can you can move
beyond what I'm talking about here yes
that'll work better know what no this
has got two three and four
alright so scotch two is coming around
as it comes around I would love to hear
your your thoughts there
I know it's all fucking action up here
but Jesus Christ if you want to talk sit
in church has more it has a stronger
that's us
to me this is a stronger flavor but a
little sweet almost like sweet to me
woody woody well I think it's got a
better nose than it does taste I haven't
tasted it
yeah the nose is kind of nice it's not
very sharp but the taste is really flat
mm-hmm
everything anyone said I grew it now all
right so where where do you think we are
on this spectrum dead in the middle you
say you're not wrong
that's banknote banknote is my go-to if
I don't really feel like drinking
something that's going to challenge me
if I if I'm with a bunch of people and
we're in a Scotch bar I will ask if they
have a bottle of banknote if you find
banknote in the store it will fucking
flabbergast you how cheap it is you will
find it a decent enough Scotch that is
not going to attack your palate for well
under 30 bucks it is priced like shit
ball and it is shocking and I'm pretty
sure the markets gonna correct on that
soon because the supplies of it are
starting to dry up in some cities at the
price that they the the distributor put
it in this country I don't know how it's
this cheap so yes it is I was getting
these kind of thoughts from a lot of
people it is it's still clearly a scotch
but it doesn't speak very loudly all
right
water refresh again if you finished your
lips it is the Mike Pence of Scotch Mike
Pence is like off the he is way up in
the toilet bowl for me all right all
right all right why are we already
getting onto three here all right
remember take your time nose nose and
breathe taste and the finish you can say
a lot about three go ahead and say a lot
about three three is a very polarizing
scotch
tastes like use band-aids Wow
it's got some barnyard in it from
barnyard a bandage I don't think its
brand name band-aids
I think it's off-brand yeah exactly
so mediciney I will describe medicine to
me it tastes like cow pull float smells
Wow so it's just a smokey peat trying to
be in LA so so it's a blended that's
trying to have airs on itself it thinks
who it is right believe it or not you
know what you are enjoying and passing
around Scott sample number three where
do you think we are
really shocker shocker Johnny blue you
are drinking Johnnie Walker Blue Wave
yep that is Johnnie Walker Blue yes oh I
bring it for my fucking friends when
you're in my talks maybe it is a very
polarizing experience it has a lot to
say
some people like what that is and some
people do not it's a very interesting
experience absolutely so making
distilled spirits I'd like to get
through a lot of get through people I
mentioned jim manley in his talk hacking
grain if you haven't seen it it's
amazing he talks about every step of the
distilling process you can get way into
this crazy I charted like all the
different flavors that a spirit can have
and you know if you're doing this like
the high-end tasting like oh what are
these different notes of oak and
cherries and dirt and crushed rock but
where do those flavors originate where
do they actually come from in a spirit
well you've got sugar as an input when
you're distilling so like you could you
can crush up fruit and make distilled
spirit out of that sugar if you ferment
it what is a distilled spirit made of
fruit what is it brandy yes you can use
a plant like this not exactly a fruit
what plant is this agave what have you
taken ghave nectar yes that is tequila
what if you refine sugar and make nice
white sugar for people to put in their
coffee into your leftover with this kind
of shitty browns what is that molasses
if you just it ferment
Lassus and distill it that is rum and
everything else everything else comes
from a mash bill of grains yes
gin is green gin is green plus plus
herbals neutral brains would be vodkas
not always some potato and all whiskeys
are are as a various type of grain now
the input that you're getting to
germinate your sugars that will have a
flavor because obviously brandy is very
different than whisky is very different
than rum we're getting to that we know
you already jumped before you weren't
told to oh my god well wait a minute
people all right well all right this is
awesome it's going somewhere it's going
somewhere if we talk about malted
whiskey malting is just germinating the
the grain you actually just lay it out
on a malting floor you allow it to be
wet and then start to sprout then you
arrest that process so if you hear about
if you hear about like peat and smoke
and a lot of whiskeys that's literally
the old way of doing it would be smoked
under this this grain floor this malting
floor coming up and the heat would
arrest the process and again get
particle particle --it into the mash
bill again yeast what yeast you chose
will change the flavor how you distill
it how you do your separation in your
distillation column when you trim your
heads and your tails all of these things
will change what what actual like long
chains are in the spirit that'll change
flavor but of course maturation the
Proust the post processing the aging in
barrels where the wood sugars will
caramelize when they toast the barrel
and then you sit with the barrels all in
a rack house like this and they're just
going through temperature cycles over
the years leaching in leaching out the
whiskey's picking up color and all kind
of mellowing agents that's another
flavoring then people often talk about
how expensive it is because this is how
like takes a lot of space and a lot of
goddamn time now we jump the gun but
that's okay we're already ahead of the
curve on time we need to keep moving
am I talking too fast is this working
for you felt like a little
Hey all right you've had water you've
tried to blend in scotch number fours
blended Scotch number four also over
there right on what we're what did you
think about that what do we got kind of
sweet a little pretty pebbly mm-hmm for
me
pass around so like everything tells me
it's gonna be to the far right except
for the fact that I know you and I don't
think it's gonna stick over in the far
right all right you're smart man that
was easily the best one in my opinion
and had a real floral flavor and a lot
of interest intricacies yeah as you
tasted it there was more and more things
revealed yeah there's a lot of campfire
or burnt wood I don't I can't help it
spine or oak but I can definitely tell
like some kind you know the wood burning
things yeah yeah Pete you liked it all
right ready for what it was yes house
bank note again yeah but i hack the
flavor what did you change it yes you
can hack whiskey's flavor you can hack a
spirits flavor so let's talk about the
flavors that come into a distilled
spirit in this case a mash bill of grain
well that was chosen long before I
picked up this bottle and I don't get to
fucking change that they didn't actually
do a whole lot of malting and smoking so
I don't get to change that the distiller
has a yeast a straight and by the way
it's very tragic that when Prohibition
happened and distilleries like went out
of business we've lost yeast strains
that were being you know cultured for
different lifetimes and they're never
get them back so we've lost a lot of
distilling tradition because of that
because the yeasts are all specialized
in many different distilleries but I
don't get to choose it somebody way
smarter than me long before I bought
this bottle chose it distillation can
you read distill a spirit like yeah this
fucking thing exists this is an air
still you can put this in your house and
make your own proper hooch probably very
off buck this is a proper moonshine
still that I know some of these exist
but flavor-wise I mean that's
effectively pushing the reset button on
flavor so that's not really what we're
doing here the big number right maturing
which again is the big cost because you
lose whiskey over the year if the
angel's share vaporizes off and it's
just a big cost to maintain a rack house
where the distiller wants to save money
and push a bottle out and say all right
10-year is fine
twelve year is fine you at home can you
try to do more maturing there's some
interesting ideas here so there's
there's a front like this who saw this
weird-looking thing by the way out on
the bar in this very hotel the little
smoky box if you want to make something
smokier if you've never seen it it's
connected to this little Pacific and
Auto Bowl that you pack with like wood
chips you put the whiskey in the box
they do this out at the bar if you want
to see it they spark that shit and they
effectively hotbox your whiskey right
and it goes in there at churches for a
minute or two and you take it out and
they're like a look smokiness and age
and new flavors now I would not really
call this aging the whiskey you are
adult your adult trading it with new
flavors and sometimes they compliment
and sometimes there's goofy and it's a
beautiful pageant when the guy does it
it's a really fun thing to see very
impractical at home what people have
tried to play with at home our whiskey
sticks the idea of giving your butt your
bottle because the whiskey is
effectively dead like it's not gonna
mature just sitting in a bottle but
giving toasted wood dropping it into the
whiskey and letting it just sit there
for a while
has been debated as to whether or not
this changes the flavor now I can tell
you these products which are stupid
expensive they're like seven dollars a
stick they will change the flavor this
this was a pure virgin raw neutral
spirit completely illegally distill and
after using those little whiskey sticks
and cycling them out every you know few
like months or something lady who made
this BAM you've got colored flavored
you're getting flavor that will work but
again dumb expensive takes a long time
somebody for the expensive thing there's
another blog and instructable they said
dude you can do this yourself like yet
you know just get like chosen barbecue
wood you know it's food grade wood put
it in your oven for 400 degrees let it
shoot for a few hours
comes out mmm do it yourself whiskey
sticks I didn't want to pay for the
freaking thing so I just got a log and
busted that thing up
Hey look whiskey sticks so yeah hey
white oh yes that is exactly what I'm
tasting in there man that is awesome
so again foil foil wrap your packet like
you're making fish in the oven 400
degrees your house smells fucking
wonderful when you're toast in white oak
I made one at two hours at in one at
four hours I took some outside because
this would be like a level one or two
toast on a barrel I want to do like a
four or even a fourth less so I took the
the Sears all out there give her what
four and they did in the driveway and
sure enough like you can make really
crazy dark char the foil just manages it
keeps no contact so again I'm Rufford
Scotland earlier if you don't know
Scotland the hacker she made the Mad Max
flame guitar you see there sometimes at
Burning Man and other hacker events so
Scotland I were talking we're talking
about using you know the whiskey sticks
and you know doesn't they take a long
time and we started mentioning with
however there been studies that people
are doing weird things with ultrasonic
cavitation because you're trying to get
the whisky to get into and out of the
little crenellations in the wood to get
the sugar the sugars from the wood into
the flavor okay I was like shit
ultrasound
let me see oh there's sure pbs.org Nova
must be real I'll try it so you go on
eBay you get yourself the cheapest
Chinese ium ultrasound machine you can
find start dropping whiskey sticks in
bottles start pouring whiskey in and
just boom just let her choose for life
there you go this is literally just
going to town vibrating ultrasonic
vibration to cavitate and crash the
whiskey into as many little
crenellations as I can get it into and
after a day or two you pull that out now
I say a day or two because it wasn't
running the whole time for a reason I
will point out it's a really cool idea I
was like I can't believe this is
actually not blowing up sure and it's
changing is it change in color and I'm
pulling the bottles out and putting them
on my truck I'm like look Wow holy shit
different colors things are happening
it's a science right there
I tasted it didn't kill me didn't make
me go blind I said alright this is
really neat but I have a problem the
problem is this little unit has a
30-minute timer that's a hard limit edge
free malware yes I'm getting a lot of
steps in running downstairs every like
half hour to my basement to like re-up
this thing I'm like this is what's a
cornball well you'll tell me what that
reference or maybe so here's what I did
and this is like you can do dumb things
to it if you never have like I I know
some electronic start I know how to like
fix oh the soldering iron doesn't work
anymore find where the break in the line
is okay the little Pixies can't go
through the wire fix it that's kind of
my level of electronic work I get like a
a circuit has copper so I said alright
this thing I noticed as I was running
downstairs every now and then it
wouldn't have been completely out of
time and I could just kind of Rhea admin
it's like putting quarters in a machine
so I'm like alright these buttons I got
to find a way to like trigger and hit
these buttons with some circuit some
timer some something so I took the thing
apart looked on the inside I'm like well
re these pads are clearly where the
buttons are on the outside and already
I'm out of my depth because they have
four through-hole solder points and not
two and I'm like well that's weird
why aren't there two so I was like how
do I figure this out so I just turned it
on and took you know a wire and I just
started touching and we don't do what
Donny don't does but it was fast I mean
high yeah what you got email me in the
future I see mail yeah I could save you
some problems you start touching things
and it beeps and the number goes up and
you're like wow if I are these are the
contacts that I can close cool well what
can I do here
alright
I don't know how a multiple beer works
actually again this is above my favorite
but I know how to tin wire and I know
how to like solder some water and wire
points on of this so now now I got
myself wires coming off this board and I
can simulate button pushes to turn the
heater off or to add time so alright I
didn't shock myself I didn't die put it
all back together you put it all
together
and you go to fries and you're like
alright I don't know what the fuck I'm
doing
but let's get baby's first Arduino and
figure it out I am 40 years old on this
earth and I know a lot of hacky things
and people come up to me and say hi a
lot of cons never ever think that the
person you think is like oh look at that
person they do cool shit never think
they know it all because I fucking don't
I literally started with never planning
anything so like I made LEDs blink and I
knew that was like well I know what a
relay is from tripping them out on like
door sensors like I know if I can make a
relay turn clove button close I could
probably figure out how to make these
wires dry contact so I'm reading like
data sheets and not quite rocking it but
I'm talking on slack to the cycle holux
and they're explaining things at 2:00 in
the morning and I'm hand drawing ideas
and in there they're editing them and
sending them back on slack and I'm like
art I got to buy more parts okay let's
get this thing and in the end yeah I
made this thing and it's like a circuit
and then I hooked it up to the wires and
then when I plugged it in I could start
adding time Wow who knew technology
[Applause]
this is just for you Vic
I finally have an electronic based
hacking talk right on so I made I made
like a circuit and I was like that's
ugly let's package it up into a little
enclosure cuz I like everything nice and
neat and organized
so yeah I box this sucker up and there
we are now it's a nice little thing that
runs effectively forever so that works
for Ballmer yes so now this little
Chinese iam cornballer apparently can
just run infinitely okay so yeah and
that you can really start cooking so
over like add a really dark flavor
because it's nonstop hitting on this
vibration now I think the Scotch was fun
but who thinks it's bourbon Tommy we're
gonna do the same thing as before we're
gonna start putting bottles oh I can
[Laughter]
that's a thing it's almost the exact
same thing except one sniffles crying at
once meant for bourbon or not program
alright
bourbon bourbon bourbon bourbon question
yes sir what did the ultrasonic do to
the flavor well that is what happened on
Scotch number four that was a whiskey
stick dropped in a bottle of banknote
for maybe like a day I won't say that he
grabbed a lot of the flavor from that
but it shouldn't have it only a day's
time yeah it had a lot of nice sweet
wood flavor from the white oak so now I
did that yes question of the back shout
it out hockey balls the surface area of
the wood yes I tried to do like a laser
cut with all these little crenellations
and I made this super zig zaggy thing in
Inkscape and the laser at the makerspace
could not penetrate the wood without
lighting everything on fire so yep
didn't work that way for me now lots and
lots of crazy flavors of bourbon people
in the hacker community have been
sharing their
list of favorite Bourbons for a while in
this underground way and Jim Manley has
this piece of paper that's probably the
most photographed piece of paper in the
hacker world so this is a list of
Bourbons that a lot of people the slides
are all gonna be online you have to do
the phone thing like you're at a concert
come on now
so again tons of flavor tons of
interesting stuff a lot of different
bourbon out there I would like to have a
little bourbon tasty tasty taste alright
so again usually age equals cost the
more its age the more it costs to make
the more it's costing you at the store
which bourbon are you on right now
alright so you put a little water in the
glass
you tried bourbon number one talked to
me about it it's not bullet it's very
you could just start naming the most
popular variation talk to me you haven't
spoken enough I thought it smelled and
tasted mapley okay maple leaves a very
thick common thing you will hear yes
okay any other thoughts but we keep
going just anger everyone it's better
because it's not scotch it's quite thin
and got a lot of alcohol okay anyone
else all right okay so that was number
one did you like number one at all it's
got a slightly sweet flavor to it that
you don't see within a scotch sweeter
sweeter had some higher notes but with a
scotch it's a little bit more fulfilled
because normally scotch takes years and
years and years they aged Bourbons aged
a lot more quickly because they'll have
more temperature difference in the
United States go ahead and put bourbon
number two down your gullet all right
you just did keep passing the model did
all of you put bourbon number two in
yeah I'm about to all right
so we're going to tell you a minute all
right I'm not saying yet I'm not saying
at all well she's she's letting people
on that side taste
number two tastes medicinal but in a
good way interesting interesting I don't
think it hits medicinal you don't think
it's okay
QR there's some driest syndrome a
syndrome see
Astrid in C all right astringency I
think your ass is very trenchant okay
any other thoughts from this end okay
we're getting we're getting vague thumbs
up over here all right we're gonna water
refresh your glass again that is it yet
you chose your seat very wise what
happened whoa what did you do are you
drank number three no I got handed
probably close to like scotch number
three and two combined why did you put
that in you two you shouldn't have done
that
remember don't do what naughty don't did
don't do that don't don't do that to him
again I need him to last for another
half an hour
all right all right all right we got to
hear what the panel has to say I'm
feeling a hardware store in this thing
I'm gonna just go down like aesthetics
like one was the one was good two was
great three was not good okay they taste
like glue too much yeah pretty rough
okay so the nose on three is actually
pretty an area not great but the flavor
on three is actually not bad
okay two was better oh yeah two was
better go ahead go ahead Dean that's
what I remember
yeah if I mix anything up one no you're
good chalkboard on the tongue it is
definite I smooth if we get really nuts
I got number four over here which
carries the thing further okay I the
real wild shit about it all three of
those for the same bourbon yeah it
doesn't
they were larceny so what'd you do to it
what did I do to it that the original
bottle 24 hours in the ultrasonic 48
hours in the ultrasonic now this is not
a perfect process and the results are
never guaranteed to be exactly what you
want but if you want a super cheap very
easy way to try to fuck with flavor and
see what happens this is remarkable in
my opinion that that can be achieved in
so little time will it or Heaven's Hill
is larceny is I think everyone is owned
now by well this is longer than that I'm
going forward a question in the back
shout it out this is with the ultrasonic
with the whiskey stick for 24 or 48
hours
were they in order yes one two and three
yes question yes you got a shout at sir
do I swap out the sticks no I didn't
have two single stick the whole time do
they eventually change and wear out
yes do I have good data on when no
alright does if anybody if you stick
around to the end if anyone wants to try
this I made you a fuckload of whiskey
sticks toasted at home just a warning
it's gonna look like melange it's not
alright before is fuckin brutal four is
too much you don't have to taste for
that wasn't even on the official roster
right on will send for around but
alright alright alright keep what do you
need very mom ignoring you over there no
no no no hold on hold on for is amazing
alright like it's got a definitely like
heavy or woody or flavor than the other
ones but it's it's I like it better
alright but I like to like dive
face-first into a bog as well before you
pass that away just give me a little for
in this guy well I like I like all
whiskey like someone asked me once do
you drink coffee because I get asked
this when I stay with friends and stuff
I say no I don't drink off it they say
how do you wake up I say stop drinking
whiskey I do that eight hours ago get a
doubt on the rack and then Hey look I'm
awake now alright though yeah alright
that was that was a lot of different
flavor hackings that was a lot of fun
but if if straight liquor is not your
thing the original idea behind this talk
when Jack and I were first kickin the
idea around was to be a cocktail talk
and that's the other great thing if you
have spirit that may not be to your
liking you can make a cocktail
why yes by all means what is a cocktail
what are we do we define cocktails you a
thought are you suggesting that one
could combine both alcoholic things and
and non-alcoholic things at the same
time you can
oh my and the actual set what's that now
you've got spirit and bitters I know
sometimes people can't hack it and we
have to accommodate all types we are
welcoming big tent if you have a spirit
a base spirit and you change its flavor
with any of the certain classic elements
that go into a cocktail that is that is
a definition of a cocktail cocktail is
civilization yes sir what is inside of
bitters yeah it's amazing you ask I can
talk about bitters but you know who can
talk even more about bitters that's okay
let's not wake him up
Larry Pesch II can talk a lot about
better ease Larry Pesch II made most of
my bitters in my marble
I bet if you were to tweet at him and
ask hey how do you make bitters sir why
did you extract the thing and the stuff
he will probably talk about that again
DIY hacker fucking Punk culture fruit
fruit will often go into a cocktail or
fruit juice or fruit garnish by the way
this is not a bartending class but learn
this fucking shit that is a lemon wheel
that is a lemon wedge that is a lemon
peel that is a lemon twist they are not
the same thing use them right
again not a bartending class but don't
look like a douche in the bar there are
a few standard way standard terms of
preparing and serving a cocktail this on
the edge neat that is not a cocktail
there's the only thing about neat is a
spirit taken right out of the bottle put
into a glass and into your mouth
no adulteration no flavor no chilling
that is neat on the rocks many of you
know that is ice in the glass to chill
it and served in the glass to you at the
bar yes and no does not have to have the
fruit garnish this was just happens to
be a picture I pull and lastly up up is
just a chilled cocktail served up in a
cocktail glass where you can get a
little and most people this is like old
news here right pretty well-known but
some people will fuck around with terms
for example I want that straight up what
the fuck do you mean there is straight
whiskey
or there's up right assist you want a
whiskey and I martini glass and you know
that's dumb don't a little or don't
order something straight up you sound
like an idiot
you crop you might mean you want it neat
or you might mean you want it chilled
which would be in a low glass but
without the ice in the glass you'll see
a cocktail prepared that way so
untangling that the history of cocktails
when did when did cocktails really
emerge when did cocktails kind of come
out a lot of people say prohibition a
lot of people you are wrong prop
cocktails really came into their own
during Prohibition because when liquor
wasn't that good we had to change the
flavor we had to do what a cocktail is
meant to do yes cocktails are way way
older cocktails have a very venerable
history and in fact tonight we are going
to make a couple cocktails from the pre
Prohibition era we're gonna make a
couple cocktails from Prohibition
certain Prohibition classics and a
couple cocktails from the modern era
which Carolina Cano is that you asked I
don't know that was a that was the
Chapel Hill Hotel I think long ago we
make some cocktails are you still
enjoying this all right so certain very
venerable cocktails all of which
predates predate predate prohibition
absolutely the old-fashioned which is
something that a lot of people don't
drink anymore in our generation but I
think is wonderful the flip old fashions
are solid shit man but I'm gonna make it
in the old style and Sazerac which I'm
even gonna make to sazeracs one with the
brandy you make Sur and the traditional
now using whiskey okay the old-fashioned
old-fashioned in the old style using a
lot of seltzer water in the mix as you
chilled a whiskey this is not done
anymore but this was a very common thing
to do a whiskey and soda and then you
you know give it some bitters give it
maybe a little fruit garnish so a note
about Seltzer by the way club soda is
not Seltzer Seltzer is not club soda
although they are usually very
interchangeable the flavor profiles of
each are very close if you want a lot of
Seltzer in your home many people have
heard of the SodaStream if you sell
yourself boy I would love something
taste
my palate but I want a a pricing model
that's akin to ink cartridges boy is it
SodaStream for you
hey deviant yes sir what if I happen to
want quinine what if you want quinine
well you'd want gin and we're gonna use
gin all right but so by the way so
district who is who has a SodaStream who
pays for those fucking cartridges chumps
chumps all of you fucking who has a soda
mod they take the asshole proprietary
threading and then they made it up to
paintball tanks which you can refill for
like pennies
get your ass to soda mount or if you're
in the same guy like me and my wife we
like a lot of soda all the time
what's that Patrick yeah yeah get this
thing this allows you to connect a
SodaStream to a giant you know twenty
pound frickin tank down here right so if
you look at the SodaStream in our house
you'll actually see weight out behind
there's like this line and you look
behind our stove and where does that go
it goes to this 20 pound fucking tank so
in making in making the old-fashioned
I'm just gonna need a glass over here
and we're going to use in the old way it
would normally be bourbon we're gonna
keep with the Bourbon we have all we
lost all the Bourbon didn't we
I actually LS did we lose all the
Bourbon I'm gonna use right just
literally like that freakin Mad Men
episode this bar was set up by a blind
man there's no bourbon rye okay we're
gonna get some Angostura bitters yeah
I'm gonna make that camera available why
not do magic BAM
[Music]
[Applause]
I know it's the the clarity is amazing
on this video right
[Music]
I need a little tip of water from here
he's gonna steal a bit of my water and
also just man the crap out of the sugar
with I believe a little bit of bitters
am I wrong that is Angus twitch
Angostura bitters as I pronounce it
incorrectly that's alright that's
alright and he's gonna mix the crap out
of it okay he's now going to so that's
some ice to a we're gonna put whisky
nicety again the old way of doing this
would involve rye whiskey
where does fuzzy water come from
well usually just from shoving a bunch
of co2 in water although there is
naturally sparkling water do you think
they shoved a bunch of co2 and water
back in the 1870s or do they like they
would have only got spring I'm trying to
help here so that people know what
things are happening historically rather
than just like surprise seltzer water
there is one old fashioned let's try the
old fashioned all right
I can do that yeah we're good we got
this it's got a great citrusy like rye
wonderfulness we're gonna make it's
really good right on yeah the water
doesn't really kill it the water just
changes the flavor right now we're gonna
get through it we're gonna get through
this all right here we're gonna keep
going I'm just Iverson I was enjoying
that selfie face I could taste the
orange
I think overall it's thank you say as
the quickest old-fashioned because I
made it selfish yes don't pink the drink
thank you for not muddling the fruit the
the sugar actually was muddled where the
fruit wasn't so you didn't get like the
destroyed fruit flavor to go along with
it yeah exactly not mash yeah good call
well so bitter part of the orange peels
actually a good different part of the
drink though yeah exactly
get the nice flame orange peel which is
great oh we have fun
congratulations deviant you got an
applause so it's all good we're good
we're good as applause applause all
right all right all right keep it moving
keep it moving because we got hacker
trivia and stuff going on hacker trivia
all right I am gonna make a flip which
is easily one of my favorite fucking
drinks to make it's always funny because
it blows people's mind when you take an
egg out and you say oh I'm gonna put an
egg in this drink and they say really
and you say yes I'm actually throwing an
egg in the drink
but deviant everyone always only use
this egg white in their drinks not
entirely the whole egg you can use a
whole egg there's nothing wrong with it
and in fact of this kind of flip which
I'm first incorporating with a dry shake
[Applause]
what is in here besides the egg what is
in this besides the egg we have two
measures of whiskey we have one measure
of Drambuie which is a cordial based out
of scotch and we have a one that was one
measured Rimbaud and one measure of
Benedictine so you'll have a little bit
of sweetness in here in Ojai so well
we're gonna so the the first shake
called a dry shake which is just a shake
with no ice is to incorporate the egg
really well then we're gonna drop the
ice and I'm going to look for cream
I am so this is gonna come out almost
almost like an eggnog but we're gonna do
some fun shipyard so yes this will be a
double shakin
yeah the double shake I think it's gonna
actually work out really well in our
favor I mean it's gonna suck to be
everybody else that doesn't get a sample
of this but I think it's gonna be
amazing
because you don't see that very often
like usually with a egg drink you'll see
like just the egg whites and you'll see
them shaking for like a minute and a
half and they'll feel really bad and
then you'll want to tip them really hard
because they worked really hard to make
this drink
so exactly you only get one shake
usually like this lovely man said here
what is if this is almost an eggnog what
is a typical typical spice that would go
on top of an eggnog definitely not
nutmeg yes you can or cocaine you can
use ground nutmeg if you want if you
want to you can but I'm more of a fan of
grabbing a microplane because there's a
little bit of there's a little bit of
fanciness ready for this hey hey deviant
that that looks a little familiar that
like design there oh something's gonna
happen you'll see with would that have
anything to do with like the game of
life am i Conway am man oh oh you can't
see it but we got we had a little bit of
glider eggnog what do you think yeah
yeah you had a little preview there yeah
it's very eggnog you but it's all good
right I would say then that is highly
integral approved oh we need our taxi
yes okay we need I'm gonna need extra
glasses
if I can have you probably i love eggnog
and it tastes just like eggnog toxic and
still be on like a keto diet if you can
alright alright we're still doing okay
we're still making it more delicious
are you still enjoying this alright as
keto approved I don't know I'm not a
nutritionist you know no I don't
someone's holding shit up there's too
many inputs too many inputs for deviants
oh my god are you gonna throw me out is
that what you're walking toward me don't
throw me out okay who is still who wants
to see you next cocktail alright we are
gonna make a Sazerac a Sazerac is rye
base and the Rye will have a type of
bitters that you normally don't wanna
fuckin measure it I'm just gonna BAM a
type of bitters that you normally don't
see used do you know what type of
bitters it is well it says push odds up
there but it is yes it is patience what
so what exactly would that be hey shows
bitters there are very mediciney tasting
bitters actually they are tell talking
about it you know history most bitters
were introduced as some sort of patent
medicine and the cocktails associated
with them were a way to distribute their
medicine and sell it to an audience but
people enjoy the taste and realize it
happened digital no real medicinal
quality so we just turned into cocktails
there you go so out of curiosity would
you say that this is entirely different
to things like medicine or marijuana or
or I would say the controls and
restrictions on them are very similar
actually push those bitters actually
came out of New Orleans this was a
doctor in New Orleans who was trying to
produce this as a as a medicinal herb
Carl spends a lot of times down in New
Orleans there is a relation to snake oil
so this New Orleans place is that any
different than this nollans place that I
know of
New Orleans is what tourists say before
they get mugged
the whole thing with a Sazerac is it's
quite a pageant right you're gonna stir
your bitters and your clear spirit here
we have a cognac and we have a whiskey
and yes I'm using the same spoon but
that's because we're trying to hustle
here a little bit of absinthe we're
gonna get kicked out yes I did you
connect one which one had one for you
five six we can make this in six since
that sazeracs originally were made with
cognac but then after a parasitic a
parasite destroyed wine and cognac
production in France it switched to rye
whiskey so so the original old-world
Sazerac is made with cognac and the
modern Sazerac is made with rye whiskey
bad still there's some sort of absent
the component no matter what correct yes
originally there was a real absinthe
wash but when absinthe was he legalized
they actually switched over to what's
called a pastiche or a essentially a
fake or earth Ott's absinthe like Pernod
or things that were similar to absent
without wormwood
so the wormwood itself would you say
that that's actually like the the part
that was the problem or was there
something else it was the part that was
demonized although it turned out to
actually have no real effect on people
it's just another moral panic so all of
these authors that happen to think that
wormwood was the thing that gave them
their wonderful cake essentially what do
you say about that they're in the same
wonderful category as Alex Jones
impossible to beat that what do you
think it says her excerpt I think I need
another taste after the Alex comparison
so we're not gonna talk about this whole
video Viet there's video of me like
making a Sazerac on a plane and the very
end of this talk he's gonna explain how
I'm doing that with you know things that
you normally don't just like get the
flight attendant to have patience
bitterness or absence right so you can
absolutely do that yourself but we'll
show you how in a second prohibition-era
- awesome cocktails so we're gonna make
back-to-back the martini and the sidecar
now the martini the ratio what is in a
martini gin and gin and a stayer a a
bottle of other yes so you know sir so
the idea of gin and vermouth in
different different amounts over the
years this sort of ratio has
changed a lot we started to see more and
more gin less and less vermouth in fact
for a very long time this the sort of
Montgomery martini is that fifteen to
one yes hold well right it's really
almost no vermouth yeah that's like a
range in half thought oh so if you ever
seen the old mst3k or they talked about
a date with your family they should have
sounded I don't know we don't have sound
there's a joke that they thrill in a
mother to her village in convalescent
Field Marshal Montgomery that was a joke
that was a reference to orgy Montgomery
martinis drinking straight spirit and
calling it a cocktail at that point we
can we can make one of and you know as
you referenced obviously the best drink
order ever in a Kingsman what can I get
certainly not vodka
obviously stirred for 10 seconds while
glancing it's an unopened bottle of
women's thank you so yeah we can we know
what because we're tight on time we can
make the martini afterwards I have
plenty of gin I hope it's like
homeopathic martini yes
like seriously homeopathy is exactly how
I want my booth inside our martini but
what we're gonna make instead because
it's really neat is a sidecar talk about
a really really fun kind of beverage
right also popularized during the
Prohibition also using gin which we have
here and we're gonna go three two one on
the oh no it's not so it's a con yak I'm
sorry damn I almost put fuckin gin in
the sidecar look at me Jesus I would not
be opposed to gensai card but I love a
good like juniper bush in my mouth push
push it up feel free to make your own
bush in the mouth jokes well I am I'm
still gonna stick with it juniper bush
in my love you're still talking
we got ourselves a Cointreau
what is Cointreau three minutes we can
do it
Cointreau is an orange liqueur it's
essentially a triple sec there was a
difference between triple sec and
coração we can get into that in a side
room it's a man's got it got it it's
something you mix with other things now
I should have some lemon juice where is
my lemon juice there is my lemon juice
I'll take that from you no I got it
right here now why am i stirring as
opposed to shaking well we'll talk about
that in a minute you well you actually
do want to aerate and really incorporate
juices you stir pure alcohol
you shake juice and alcohol now on this
glass before we rock and roll well while
you're rocking and rolling can you say
that thing that you said just again
because I think that's a really
important you stir pure alcohol
you shake juice and alcohol and this is
a partially rimmed glass thank you
there is your sidecar all right oh I
didn't put on the fucking camera that
whole time shit there you are here's the
parsley rim yay nice day for rimming yes
we got a running joke in there oh shit
so today we're trying you wanted to be
here silent recipe so we're gonna wrap
it up with a sidecar and a final note
we'll show you the last couple cocktails
right yeah we have fun friends we're
going to jail at this point a ton of
them that's cold
that is really cold it is cold I mean it
could be better but that's just because
he hasn't brought me on you all right
because we are running long on time
we're not gonna do every last cocktail
but I will keep making these tonight in
some side room what I was going to show
you and they're all gonna be up online
they're already online the mini mix kits
that I travel with I have Amazon links
to all the little you know pieces that I
put together so you yourself can show up
wherever you want to be and make a solid
cocktail any last minute reactions from
our tasters thank you pass these around
for liver strong wrist bands start these
on this side of the room please for the
toasted wood
bring baits oh yeah prohibition-era
cocktails back bring Eric cocktails back
but without the prohibition please
without the program yeah no prohibition
but yes cocktails so there's an
important important thing I want to say
and this is really in in the hacker
community listen up for a second this is
this is a thing shut up a lot of us have
really interesting relationships with
alcohol and I have a really interesting
an edge case relationship with alcohol
the reason I like this and the reason I
wanted to share this is because the more
you think about it
the more you put like time and
consideration into what you're having
it's not just AG like I used to be like
everyone get it down get it down get it
down get it down get it down these
feelings won't suppress themselves being
measured and considered about what
you're having and liking it for a reason
has actually allowed me and a lot of
people I know to kind of just barely
step it back from that edge and if you
know someone or view yourself maybe have
a little unhealthy relationship with
alcohol ask why you're drinking and if
you have any meetings why you're
choosing what you're choosing I want to
end with a toast and it's a toast from
Ireland there's there's an old song it
was um basically there's a story about a
guy who's out late drinking and he gets
thrown in jail and in jail the devil
confronts him and he you know doesn't
really want to listen with the devil has
to say he still has a flask on I mean he
pours himself a drink instead but yes if
you've if you've ever felt like the
outsider and if you've ever felt kicked
around and pushed aside to the margins
this community can really not be a bad
thing and an unhealthy influence this
community can be a lifesaver and to
anyone who has ever felt like they
didn't belong I will toast you with a
song called the wrong company and if you
know it from flogging.molly or anyone
else you may have heard this so it
basically it goes um when I fell into
prison about a quarter to three and I
found in mice
a glass waitin for me so a food what was
empty and I pulled up a stool but he
stood in nikana the old devil wouldn't
move
he said you drink when you're alone II
know I drink when I am and he said
she'll never be sober why should I want
that I only drink to be merry but
unfortunately I'm in the wrong prison
cell with the wrong company thank you so
much for the extra couple minutes
there's a whole lot more the slides are
online love you never let it go on
[Applause]