already mentioned items killing ditch
and be talking about this tool that I
created it's really a gimmick hope you
guys enjoy it because it's kind of a lot
of fun in my opinion the more important
thing is the concept kind of moving away
from the idea of needing yet another
screen yet another window in order to
monitor what's going on in your network
or to review as well as bring back fun
into what we do or amplifying the amount
that we have if you want to be really
bored I've got like two posts on Twitter
and I've recently put up packet racket
on github I plan on doing a little bit
more that overcoming that initial
paranoia is somewhat difficult in order
to get the exposure you kind of need in
order to progress yourself I am a
penetration tester for coalfire they're
based out of Colorado I work out of
actually Kansas City
unfortunately Kansas at the moment I'm
from Missouri so what is this this is a
kind of a tool debut I've actually got
lucky enough to spam out this talk a lot
and was able to refine it a little bit
but the more important part is that if I
can patch together some crappy lines of
Python including about 600 lines of
if-else statements you can to do it put
together something publish it and come
talk about it these are lots of fun to
attend why did I bother with it quite
honestly I thought it was a cool idea I
really wanted to bring us more towards
the age and era of interactivity and I
feel constantly like we're in the age of
text-based videogames still when we deal
with security it's a lot of fun but yet
I mean unless you using something like
Armitage it's pretty much all tech space
you got your manuals got your codexes
etc I want to do the next step
mu movies like hackers they're flying
through hacking the Gibson completely
inefficient wouldn't be very know really
just efficient is the best way to put it
because but it would be so much fun and
if somebody can put that into a VR
headset that's going to be a lot of
that's gonna be
unfortunately cool idea doesn't make for
a very good CFP submission so the
explanation I actually give is an
alternative means of network analysis
because we are constantly dealing with
alt tabbing switching windows wondering
what tab what is what and Wireshark is a
great tool it's a fantastic tool yet
it's another window and if you're not
looking at it the packets are gone and
you don't necessarily notice the emails
that your log monitoring and network
monitoring systems are sending how many
emails of those do you get that you it
can actually parse yourself and read it
gets a little bit overwhelming TCP dump
while fantastic for capturing packets I
have issues with its output I'm gonna
also go through some demos of these just
to promote some familiarity of anyone
who's unfamiliar with these interfaces
I'm gonna do a little bit asking auntie
flub as seen on tv' flubs because
they're really good tools in order for
me to be able to have a case of
presenting an alternative I have to
point out the drawbacks so why can't I
store my soda on the side of the couch
it's because I don't have the handy
couch hook so disorder I also wanted to
experience network traffic in any way it
is all around us like that Wi-Fi hotspot
I've always wanted to be able to see or
experience in some way the knowledge
that a lot of people or so many devices
are connecting to either the hotspot to
the cellular networks through these LAN
cables we're not quite there yet but I
feel like it changing the way the
perception is conceptualized is a good
step because all of those yet again it's
using the eyes we start using sound
instead it becomes a new medium letting
our eyes still perceive and proceed with
whatever they need to I have some faint
hopes of expanding the appeal of info
SEC to those perhaps from the humanities
background I taught English
to college freshmen prior to becoming
and InfoSec professional there are a lot
of people in that area who don't want to
do this job but a lot of them like music
if you can create a correlation between
the two that may start understanding
that one is far more lucrative than
teaching and you don't have to grade
additionally the idea of accessibility
if we are trying to fill these roles in
the companies in these gaps that we have
that we keep hearing about and I'm again
propagating that we can't necessarily
keep ruling out people just because they
are not necessarily seen as customarily
fit my vision is terrible I actually get
tired of staring at a screen for well
since when since Windows 10 you can only
look at your screen for 18 hours a day
because you can only adjust through
active hours for an 18 hour window which
that's a rant for another time
but but the key is you get tired of
looking at it all the time this provides
a way to stop looking at it
and listen and someone who knit might
not necessarily be able to run through a
packet capture using wireshark
because of the font this can be kind of
like the narrator feature for network
traffic so this is just a basic
screenshot of TCP dump I'll go through a
little bit more interactive this is one
of the reasons why I like to point out
the fact that it's not necessarily
eighth grade interface because it dumps
lines out on the screen you can adjust
the options but it's just it has no
pizzazz
Wireshark they bring in some colors they
got color coding they have buttons
they've got actually with the telephone
though these stuff you can record voice
and play it back so they actually have
some sound wire shark's good but yet
again it's another window my option is
packet racket
I've already discussed it what the idea
is what the conception the name of it is
it is taking the digital signal and
bouncing it into an audio tone that hits
your ear
therefore packet racket and it sounds
like an absolute racket right now I've
doing a fair amount of tweaking with the
tones but it takes work and I'm not the
greatest I will admit I'm not a DJ with
the basic comprehension and big idea of
if you know what a baseline sounds like
you can hear what something aberrant
would how it would differ and with any
baseline of course if you get used to
the traffic patterns of somebody running
a CNC channel over perhaps tour you may
not realize that it's something you
should be concerned about but if it's
not there while you're learning how your
network sounds and all of a sudden you
start hearing it that would be a red
alert style sound and basically a flag
that you should start looking at what's
going on it's really useful too well I
say it's really slow it could be really
useful for either an analyst as in a
stock analyst IT Network an analyst etc
or a pen tester for the tester I rely on
responses from services I send if I'm
testing web application I send a probe
I'm expecting a response if all of a
sudden I stop getting responses it's
entirely probable that I crashed the
server if I don't know about that until
three hours afterwards maybe I'm just
running out of native tests maybe I'm on
another conference call who knows
converse calls not a great example
because this would be noise but the idea
is once the sound stops coming back I
can realize that something's going on
and I can start paying attention to it
for an analyst or IT tech
is there an attack on your network or
did somebody just plug a switch into
itself and you're dealing with a packet
storm basic kind of ideas behind how it
works I currently have two scripts going
on one is basic racket which is
precisely that it is an incredibly basic
it only covers a small range of services
because it actually has a function that
crafts the beeps of dot WAV files it
does the math writes it out to a WAV
file saves it so theoretically you
should be able to download basic racket
py into a standard Linux system run it
and have it work I don't know if that's
actually a case can't I'll be all be
candid it's weird it's it's missing the
peak operating functionality because
that's hard I'm not I'm not a great
developer I'm honest about this but I'm
willing to throw stuff together
and try to read why it doesn't work one
of the reasons why I created the basic
version is I really really hate sending
a script that I've been working on to
somebody and say hey this is really cool
check it out they run it and say was it
supposed to spit out import module not
found or importer no it wasn't and I
don't want you to have to go through the
process of either using pip or app or
whatever a third-party library I was
relying upon basic racket is supposed to
address that I can email that to someone
they can run it it'll work if someone's
more calm more not necessarily competent
but more familiar with Python and its
peculiarities I'm doing a more robust
version with packet racket that's the
proper because scape II is a wonderful
wonderful library it allows for a far
more if it's a far easier way to parse
packets instead of calculating the
offsets yourself
and people are willing to download
another library perhaps they'll be
willing to download sounds I'm still
working on getting sounds I can
distribute because the number the one
that I found that I can use come with
tags of this maybe royalty-free but
please don't distribute or this is not
allowed to be distributed so I'm still
working on coming up with waves with
files that I can actually send so people
could just do a git clone and have it
work yeah that'll be good so that's the
idea I'm not touching my computer my
computer just doing all these it's also
got that super annoying sound however
and like I said it doesn't have the pcap
functionality but if we want to look at
peak apps say for instance what does FTP
traffic sound like we go to
[Music]
snoo jet it's a new generation of
dubstep also thank you thank you so I
introduced a bug recently that I haven't
quite been able to fix where control-c
doesn't kill it I have to I have to
background it kill the process and
foreground it I'm working on figuring
that out I don't know what I did but in
comparison look at this I do - in
because otherwise I'll try to resolve
you - - or one super-useful you guys can
tell exactly what is suspicious about
that pcap you can your eyes are better
than mine
if we look at it in Wireshark you start
getting a better idea especially because
of the color coding and you can see on
the side that there's a nice pink purple
section and any gurus in here probably
have a good idea what that means
I'm just gonna skip past that for the
sake of making my point and you'll
notice that it takes up the entire
screen in order to use Wireshark you
can't win do it very effectively oh by
the way for those who are unfamiliar
with Wireshark this is a great tool this
is a TCP packet for an HTTP session here
it has all the breakdowns of the
particular layers the data in each layer
as it was for HTTP you can also do a
really stellar good and view an entire
HTTP stream this is why HTTP is bad just
as a throwing that out there in telnet
really any clear text protocols the
point that I'm making with that is now
let's listen whenever I feed this
through packet racket
[Music]
we're stopped because like I said I
really need to find better noises it's
it's so however they're going to get
better I just need to whiten because the
way that is going about is I'm mapping
out the Etsy services file to the
individual sounds then I'm having a
default sound for the first 100 then I
think each thousand and then after ten
thousand I start breaking it up into
chunks of ten thousand so 10,000 to
20,000 has one sound 20,000 to 30,000
has another sound just because at that
point you don't necessarily care so much
about it but if it's a specific thing I
want it for it to be have a context now
where does this become something you can
actually start doing besides pcap files
well one idea that I've had is that it'd
be kind of cool if you could crack your
music with it for example a standard
port scan not standard but just kind of
incrementing through ports that I have
configured here and this is a PowerShell
script that I like to use whenever I
have a foothold on a host in a network
and I don't want to upload anything or
pivot through
[Music]
never happen and if you will observe
which is going to be difficult to do
right there until I don't I haven't
of ports which means that if I had any
real musical talent I could construct a
sequence of ports and this is where you
would be expecting me to rickroll you
the sounds don't work that way that way
yet but one of these days this which the
idea that any packet crafting or port
connection tool becomes an instrument
becomes a never happened you saw nothing
see yeah
[Music]
so as it stands it's technically
functional it's not great but it's
functional enough that I get to come and
show it off and have some fun with it
things that I really want to do with it
is implement it in Python 3 because
people should be using Python 3 I
started learning Python Python to 7 so
it's what I started creating the project
I need to make with you know the future
and start using Python 3 becomes it
before it becomes Python 4 and have to
overall everything biggest issue is
print like the parentheses I want to
implement pcap functionality so that
someone can get that script and if they
just have pcap sitting around or if they
get them from a place like malware
traffic's website part of your traffic
analysis could be listening to it and
you could start becoming attuned to what
ok this is a that's an SMB packet
capture interesting hey there's a bunch
of DNS queries I wonder is happening
with a venous and all of a sudden ICMP
starts getting into it you can start
familiarizing yourself with what's going
on the tune catalog it's going to be
expanded it's working it really comes
down to just the time it takes to open
up all these files in your audacity oh
and so I don't want to bore people too
much but for those who find things
entertaining this is my module 4 packet
racket processed packet py where this is
all the F else's for assigning each
different type of traffic a file and
this is why I admit that I'm not great
at programming
sooo well the thing is that it's it's
it's coming along and it would be
appreciated so I really want implement
and attacking and defending flag because
if you are attacking you don't want to
have offensive traffic be offensive to
your ears whereas a defender you kind of
do one thing that I basically want to
try to put in is our our packet capture
filters so you can you don't care about
HTTP potentially
what you want to hear things like tor
you want to hear things about known
backdoors
maybe it's like mirai comes out and you
want to know when the next when people
start banging on your pork quad 2 2 2 2
you could start listening for those
specifically so here's where I tricked
you all this isn't functional if you
tried to run this on an enterprise you
could have it take a packet capture of
like 30 seconds you would probably be
playing that for the next hour because
any time you take something that is
across the network and nanoseconds
picoseconds and you tag on maybe a
hundred or so milliseconds you are
automatically extenuating the amount of
time it takes to parse that data I have
contemplated a couple different ways
such as having a smooth tone grouping
doing more statistical analysis so it's
it's not necessarily every single packet
it's variety if it hits 5 6 7 maybe even
10 maybe 100 then player tone but in
working with that would yeah wouldn't
work very well on a real network so it's
not actually gonna do away with
Wireshark and TCP dump because they're
fantastic tools but I really do believe
that it can serve as a companion in that
you don't want to parse it with your
eyes anymore
what does it sound like what is a way to
experience that net flow instead of just
looking at it this tool oh and the
biggest part is you can jam out to it
somewhat but it really plays into
whenever I'm testing I love to have a
soundtrack some of my hardest decisions
of the day is what am I going to listen
to while testing today once I get this
off functional I want it to be able to
be this that I listen to
any questions come special all right
everything was live with the pew-pew
that is the thought worth pursuing it is
a fun give better better
please be better because this right now
[Music]
the nagging precisely precisely idea for
the defending flag we're just have that
be either lower completely removed so
that way only the points where you
really want to be interested would come
in and one of the things that I am
really keen on with presenting this idea
this talk isn't the tool itself is it's
the idea of maybe you want to monitor
Splunk with this maybe want to do some
sort of other monitoring that isn't in
every packet on the network got your
hand up what's that when do you have a
pcap file
so that is not implemented yet that is a
thought that I've had in order to solve
the scaling issue that is pure future
Killian once he's mastered his Python 3
is going to be able to knock that
question out of the park for now it's
probably going to be a flag that I put
in to sort it instead of sound so I keep
being suggested that in quite frankly my
familiarity with MIDI am i familiar with
programming is not up for the task but
yes it's something that is valid and
that is one of the reasons why I created
this because I miss it was a terrible
sound especially you know at about 2:00
a.m. when you really aren't supposed to
be getting on and you don't want anyone
to know that you're getting on yeah I
can miss those I had not individual that
have actually heard that because yeah
you can do birdsong
and that's about all the time I have
really appreciate you guys being out
here
[Applause]