you guys are gonna thank you you guys
are gonna get drunk tonight
one of my demos tonight involves a lot
of tour all right so what we're gonna do
today is I'm gonna have a little bit of
an egotistical moment talk a little bit
about myself all people are filing in
we'll talk a little bit about FreeBSD
what it is and why it's not Linux and
why you should care and then we'll talk
a little bit about lib hijack a post
exploitation runtime process infection
tool for FreeBSD then we'll talk about
the mandatory access control framework
we'll talk about Mac rootkits and we'll
do a demo so today's demo is the most
complicated demo that I've ever done
I've sacrificed the required three and
three-quarters goats to the demo gods so
let's hope that that works so about a
little bit about me I'm an offensive and
defensive security researcher and
engineer but in the field for around 15
years on and off and human rights really
matters to me being able to have free
speech and freedom of thought is
something that's close to my heart and
so as part of that I run a high
bandwidth Tor relay at home it's a non
exit relay because I don't want feds
knocking on my door especially since I'm
the co-founder of hardened BSD and I
have some of harden vsts infrastructure
out of my home like the packaged
building server I'm an open source
enthusiast in advocate I owe my whole
career my entire life to open source
because of the generosity of others I've
been able to establish a career I
flunked out of college and studied open
source and learned how to code through
the generosity of others so thank you I
consider myself a noob I like to learn
new things and I find that if I'm not
learning that least one new thing a day
I kind of feel like I'm failing myself
it's a little bit about FreeBSD FreeBSD
is a unix-like operating system we say
unix-like instead of UNIX because of a
lawsuit back in the early 90s but it has
its roots directly with UNIX might have
heard of a few companies that use
freebsd heavily netflix juniper sony
cisco dell emc isilon
netflix is open connect appliances
they're big servers that get installed
in internet exchange points around the
world those open connect appliances
deliver your streaming video content and
last time net craft ran a survey they
estimated around 36% of all peak North
American Internet traffic is delivered
by Netflix that's FreeBSD your
PlayStation 4 at home runs FreeBSD
NetApp appliances run FreeBSD junipers
switches and routers so FreeBSD is used
a lot especially in the corporate scene
the problem is is that FreeBSD security
is lacking FreeBSD has some great
features like DTrace jails ZFS but the
exploit mitigations are laughing they
only have a stack cookie which is pretty
stupid because exploit authors today
they don't really care much about stack
cookies especially with today's
techniques like raw up and job and s
crop and all that fun stuff they don't
have a SLR they don't have W X or X or
for your windows folk DEP DEP no CFI no
save stack so really literally the only
thing that they have is a stack cookie
all system hardening options are
disabled by default and so if you're
getting started in exploit authorship in
reverse engineering or any offensive
aspect of the InfoSec industry freebsd
really is a good system to learn on
because you're in 1999 era of security
it's really easy to write copy and paste
style mass exploitation of ulnar to a
few different topics and right now i'm
gonna jump to the executable and
linkable format or elf file format linux
and freebsd and solaris i'll use elf elf
described describes how your program
gets loaded it tells the operating
system where where in memory to load the
application there are different headers
within the elf file format the elf
header main elf header is required in
the process header which describes which
tells the operating system at what
address at what addresses and weight
with which permission bits to to load
your different parts of your application
the dynamic header is required in one
case if your application is dynamically
loaded and you will not see it for
statically statically compiled
applications section headers are
optional
when you strip a binary your stripping
out the section headers now when we want
to talk about process infection we want
to talk about getting injecting
arbitrary code and running that
arbitrary code there's a few techniques
for doing that you can overwrite a part
of the processes address space that is
executable the problem is is that when
you do that you are destroying a part of
that executable image when as an as as
someone who writes long lived exploits
and long-lived malware we want to be
able to have our code
running indefinitely we want to have the
program continue its normal behavior but
also do malicious things on the side we
can overwrite parts of the heap the
problem is is that the heap is not
executable on amd64
and armed 64 we could override a part of
the stack but again the stack is also
non executable on AMD 64 + RM 64 so
we're really left with no options with
injecting arbitrary code and getting
that code to run the procedure linkage
table and global offset table is a
lookup table of sorts so when your
application calls printf for example it
won't it will never directly call printf
for dynamically loaded applications
instead it'll instruct the operating
systems runtime linker to resolve the
address of printf because printf could
be loaded anywhere in memory and it'll
stuff that resolved address it'll cache
it in the PLT G ot the procedure linkage
table global offset table and the next
time your application calls printf the
resolution has has taken place and and
so and so it can use that entry in the
PLT G ot to call printf no further
resolution needs to happen there isn't
any tooling for making PLT g OT
redirection techniques possible when you
want to hijack a function you simply
overwrite the PLT G ot entry for that
function so if I wanted to write a
malicious printf and have the
application call my malicious printf I
would simply write my malicious printf
skoda in assembly or shell or in shell
code or in a shared object that gets
loaded and then I would replace the
print the lookup table the cached
version of the printf
address which is in the PLT ggot with
the address of my malicious printf so
that's where lib hijack comes into play
lib hijack is a post exploitation
runtime process infection tool that aims
to make in injection of arbitrary code
and the hijack of PLT G ot entries
really easy I originally wrote it for
Linux way back in the day and around
2010-2011 and I got really busy it took
it took a few years for me to develop
lib hijack in its current state and I
got really busy and around 2013 2014 I
gave live hijack to a community called
soldier X and soldier X is an online
security community filled with people of
like minds people who do reverse
engineering people who write exploits
and the really talented group of people
and I said I told him hey I I don't have
much free time anymore so here's Lib
hijack you guys can now develop it and
maintain it and and so I left for a few
years I left the project to live to
soldier X for a few years and then last
year I was curious would it work on
FreeBSD anymore and it did after a few
changes and so I picked up the project
again and I removed the Linux support
and I ported it to arm 64 so now live
high Jack only supports FreeBSD and it
supports two architectures AMD 64 and
arm 64 I removed Linux support because I
haven't really used Linux in around a
decade in any serious manner BSD has has
really caught my interests and I can
pretty much do anything in FreeBSD or
harden BSD that I could do in Linux
so so lib hijack does not support Linux
anymore
it relies heavily on the elf headers
when you attach Lib hijack to the victim
process it will cache a lot of that elf
headers because we need to parse through
the elf headers to find the PLT G ot so
remember we can't store our shellcode
where the application is executed is
currently executing we can't store
shellcode on the heap or on the stack so
what Lib hijack does is it is it forces
the victim application creates a new
memory mapping that new memory mapping
can be read only or read and execute it
can have the right bit dropped but we
can write to it ourselves because we're
using P trace and you by using P trace
the operating system gives us godlike
permissions over the over the victim
process so we can inject our shellcode
into the new memory allocation the end
goal for lib hijack is to be able to
inject anonymously full shared objects
if I'm an attacker and I'm attacking and
my target is a web server maybe running
Apache and I want to have a patchy send
me pcaps whenever I send it a special
string perhaps get /a get /p caps HP /
1.1 if I have if I have Lib pcap opened
in Apache via deal open then if it's
this admin suspects the box has been
compromised and the sysadmin can go and
look at the apache process and see what
files the apache process has opened and
if the sysadmin sees lib pcap opened
within Libya within Apache the sysadmin
is immediately going to know that
something has gone wrong
so what we want to do instead is
anonymously inject lippy cap which means
that lid P cap is loaded within Apache
but it's not backed by a file so that
means that we can still sniff packets
off the wire use lippy cap as normal but
the memory allocations for live P cap
just look like a JIT or a heap they look
like normal memory anonymous memory
allocations the system administrator
might be fooled into thinking that
nothing has nothing gone nothing wrong
has happened that's the end goal of clip
hijack we're not there yet in lib hijack
does not support file back to memory
mappings because of the stealth aspect
of Lib hijack we don't want to leave a
trace on the file system
now FreeBSD has this really cool sandbox
scene a framework called capsicum it is
a capabilities framework that is
extremely strong
it works on a per file descriptor basis
so when you open when you open a file
and create a file descriptor you say I
can only read from this file I can't
write to it I can only do certain types
of operations and when you enter
capabilities mode or cap mode for short
then the operating system expects you to
have all of your file descriptors all of
your sockets everything loaded and
connected prior to entering capabilities
mode so once you enter capabilities mode
you have no access to the global
namespace so you can't call open you
cannot call socket or connect you cannot
call those system sis calls anymore so
capsicum is really a pain in the neck to
use I have a love-hate relationship
because capsicum expects you to have
everything open already and if you're
trying to integrate capsicum
a complex application like tor tor will
open sockets arbitrarily during its life
cycle and that that is in direct
conflict with capsicum and so it using
capsicum takes a bit of work to do
properly one of the things that multiple
FreeBSD developers have told me is that
once you integrate with capsicum
once you enter capabilities mode
attackers will never be able to gain
arbitrary code execution so tonight
that's what we're gonna do most
applications when you're one you're
integrating with capsicum most
applications will write wrappers around
those global namespace functions so open
becomes a sandbox underscore open socket
becomes sandbox socket and because of
how difficult it is to use capsicum
properly
they've abstracted out helper functions
to make using capsicum easier and for
those of you who are a little bit older
in the exploit authorship arena scene
you'll you'll understand the phrase ret
to Lib C style attacks that's when you
write an exploit payload that returns
into Lib C I'm going to abuse that style
of of exploiting and I'm going to do
something similar with ret to sandbox
and you can do something if you're using
the Casper abstraction library you could
return into that as well now last year
when I was integrating capsicum into tor
eyes that wrapper style capsicum ization
requires a SLR WX WX or X and CFI at a
bare minimum to be effective
and this year Microsoft in Israel at a
presentation in their Israel labs they
noted CFI goes hand in hand with
sandboxing CFI is control-flow integrity
it helps it aims to prevent rhop and job
and rob bearings so right now tour
officially only supports Linux
sandboxing so that's set comp 2 which
uses eb PF filters which whitelist
syscalls so what you do is you whitelist
all this is calls that you want to make
like open and socket and stat and and
then after that you can call those
syscalls arbitrarily within the
applications lifetime lifecycle with
with when i integrated capsicum and this
integration has not landed upstream yet
in tor it's still in a in a in a private
github repo what i did was i i figured
that i needed to create an IP c socket
and fork off a child process the child
process would remain uncaps Akamai's and
the parent process tour itself would
enter capabilities mode and I would
write wrapper functions in the parent
process and those wrapper functions
communicate with the uncaps atomized
child and they do file descriptor
passing between the two between the
parents and the child so the child can
do those privileged operations on behalf
of the parent and Pat and they can pass
file descriptors back and forth so
there's a contact structure with a ton
of function pointers and and so if you
want to implement a new sandbox with tor
you just implement a new contact
structure with your own custom wrapper
functions
so in my shellcode instead of calling
deal open directly
I'm gonna call sandbox deal open our
sandbox open and then FTL open on the
resulting file descriptor
because freebsd doesn't have a SLR and
it does not have control flow integrity
we can hard code addresses and jump to
them directly we can we can do anything
that we want within the context of this
process we can use copy and paste style
exploitation so if you're running tor on
freebsd maybe a relay or maybe a client
maybe an exit node and there's a
vulnerability within tor then we can use
the exact same exploit without having to
modify it in the slightest against all
of those vulnerable nodes so what we'll
do is we'll use Lib hijack to emulate a
control flow hijack will bypass capsicum
by you by mixing sandbox open with FDL
open so much for no arbitrary code
execution so what we're going to do is
first call sandbox open that alert that
will return us a file descriptor then we
will call FDL open on the resulting file
descriptor that will open that will load
the malicious shared object we will call
DL sim which will resolve our malicious
function within that shared object then
we will patch the PLT G ot with the
address of our malicious function then
within our malicious function we can
peek into the context structure and
replace sandbox open replace those
function pointers without maybe
malicious file function pointers so this
is what I'm going to do the demo and
let's hope that this works
let's see yeah I'm gonna try this I need
to plug a few things in so I have here
this is a firewall that is it's running
tor and it's set up so that all all of
my network traffic from my laptop
automatically gets routed through tor I
don't have to configure my laptop to do
even a single thing I just have to
connect it to the torrefied Network and
all of my traffic naturally just goes
through tor so I'm going to try to
mirror my screens here let's see if this
works
all right now we're going to bump up the
font can you guys see that in the in the
back okay perfect all right I'm going to
do this and actually
all right so we can see that when I curl
for my IP address it took a while
because it's going through tor
automatically now we see that 185 our IP
address is 185 to 20.1 o1h 8 which is
not the hotel's IP address it is the Tor
exit node I'm going to stop tour oops
there we go and then what I'm going to
do is I'm going to start start tour
again but as my local user alright so we
see that tor is running as paid 1793
we're going to take a look at the memory
mappings for 1783 which is tor and we'll
see that ASLR is not applied now if I
grep for evil because that's what my
evil shared object is name is live evil
SOS oh we can see that the evil shared
object is not loaded but what we're
going to do is we are going to hijack
we're going to inject the Takei option
says inject a deal open shelke shell
code that is assembly code that has been
pre-compiled or preassembled that
shellcode is going to load a special lib
evil shared object and that's the tack s
option the attack F option specifies
which function it's going to hook in the
runtime in the in the PLT G ot so we're
gonna hook the receive function it takes
a few seconds because P trace the
debugging facility is a slow debugging
facility so we see down below if sorry
some heads might need to be chopped off
you'll see a special string evil SL
loaded so if I do proc stat again and I
grep for evil we see now that live evil
s o is loaded now for a bit more fun
we're gonna run the Bitcoin demon we're
gonna just sync the Bitcoin block ledger
and on my laptop I want to grab the kid
on my laptop I'm going to I'm going to
connect to FreeBSD org I'm gonna use net
cats to connect to FreeBSD org on port
80 and I'm gonna send it a special
stream this special string now instructs
the now infected tour process to go and
infect another process so I'm going to
use an infected process to pivot and
infect yet another one which in this
case is Bitcoin
we see that tor is now running the
infect command and it outputted some
debugging messages and if I go over to
Bitcoin D we see that Lib evil has been
loaded so if I prep for evil in the pit
we see that evil s o is loaded so we
pivoted from one process to another we
can use we can inject Lib hijack into a
prot into a victim process and use that
to pivot and infect another now Bitcoin
block letters about 150 gigs in size and
this hard drive only has 15 gig fifteen
gigs free so I'm going to go ahead and
control C that and in fact I'm going to
do that too
all right what's that alright so that
was a non capsicum eyes tour process
that's just regular straight-up tour and
what I'm going to do now is in fact a
capsicum eyes tour process now you see
that underneath that log notice file
line you'll see that sandbox one is set
that means enable the sandbox enable
capsicum mode so when I run the capsicum
eyes tour we now see that there's two
pits a child's process and a parent
process and of course the parent process
is paid 1877 and the child processes
1878 because freebie
Estie does not to randomize their pits
and so the pits are sequential alright
so now what we're going to do is we're
going to inject the same type of thing
we're gonna inject in an evil shared
object into a capsicum eyes - tor now
because we're capsicum eyes we are
limited in what we can do so this isn't
the same evil shared object it's a
miniaturized version of it it is a very
limited version of the original evil
shared object if we're gonna go ahead
and hook receive again we see many evil
loaded all right so now I think that's
it for loop hijack back to the slides
all right the Mac framework mandatory
access control framework Oh before I
move on does anyone have any questions
about what I just demonstrated I
demonstrated using Lib hijack to infect
a non capsicum IIST process and we were
able to use that to pivot to another
process to infect to use one infected
process to infect another we also
demonstrated an arbitrary code execution
gaining arbitrary code execution in a
capsicum eyes tour process so intro to
the Mac framework the Mac framework
really is just hooks in various parts of
the kernel so whenever you open a file
or delete a file or even call stat
file whenever you execute a binary there
are hooks for those things in the kernel
and so by implementing by utilizing
those hooks we can implement security
measures within the kernel and in fact
OS 10 and juniper do that
OS 10 actually uh helped develop the Mac
framework in FreeBSD you think Apple
doesn't really a lot of people think
Apple doesn't really contribute to open
source but that's not the case
Apple contributes a lot to open source
in conjunction with DARPA and the
University Cambridge in England Apple
helped in help to develop the Mac
framework and they use it along with
juniper for executable signing so they
sign all of their executables hardened
BSD uses it to toggle exploit
mitigations on a per application and per
jail basis in FreeBSD there's something
called you GFW which is a user space
filesystem firewall so you can use the
Mac framework to say these users or
groups should be able to access only
these parts of the file system in this
way you can implement a discretionary
access control with Mac bita so if you
want to experience pain go ahead and
port SELinux the Mac framework really is
is is complete enough for that you
probably wouldn't want to write rootkits
using the Mac framework in in production
in the real world because there's an
audit trail you can use the Mac rootkits
to give you ideas of what you can do in
in the kernel though you can break out
use mat Mac root kits to break out of
jail you can break out of capabilities
mode you can perform trove traditional
privilege escalation attacks and
overwrite other hooks of the Mac modules
one of the things that windows taught us
though is that if you need if you want
if you need to have a gain trust in a
system you know just name your objects
something trustworthy like ntdll sec dll
and so if you wanted to if you did want
to use the Mac framework and for writing
root kits you know use a trusted
trustworthy name like super secure
awesome Mac thing so because that that
that name gets outputted into D message
so it gets its auditable so what we're
gonna do is we're gonna dem do a demo of
three things we're gonna do a jailbreak
a lot of people think oh hey Linux has
docker that's awesome that's a new thing
containerization is great it's new it's
wonderful well freebsd has had
containerization for almost twenty years
now through its jail-jail framework and
so what we're gonna do is we're gonna
break out of out of the jail using a Mac
rootkit then what we're gonna do is
we're gonna force all Network daemons to
bind on all interfaces regardless of how
that demon is configured even if it's
configured to listen on localhost so
127.0.0.1 we will force that demon to
bind to all interfaces and the third
demo for the Mac rootkits is to disable
capability this mode
all right so I have I have an existing
jail called jail - and zero one it's
already booted up and it's already
running in the host environment if I
look to see if I'm jailed that zero
means that I'm not jailed so I'm looking
to see sis CTL security jail jailed
checks to see if I am in a jailed or in
a containerized environment so if I run
that same command within the container
that'll show me that by returning one
that I am jailed so what I'm gonna do is
I'm gonna load the jailbreak rootkit and
I'm going to go ahead and check to see
if within that jail I'm jailed so I just
round J exact space the name of the jail
which in this case is JLo one sis CTL
security jail jailed and that shows a
now a value of zero because the Mac
rootkit is going through all the jails
and and setting the jailed property or
the prison property to be the the the
host so if I go ahead and unload the
jailbreak module and rerun
that to check to see if we're jailed we
now see that we're jailed again now this
I have it I have a test application for
capsicum it accepts one argument and
that argument is an application that
it's going to execute so what I do is I
open that application then I enter
capabilities mode and then I execute
that application under normal
circumstances that fails because once I
once I enter capabilities mode I no
longer have access to the global
namespace which means I cannot open any
new files when the operating system
attempts to run bin LS it cannot load it
cannot open the runtime linker which is
Lib exec ldlt so dot one so now I've
loaded the rootkit that uncap suka mises
applications so now when I run the
capsicum eyes dap location and try to
run bin LS within it
I now can so let's go ahead and unload
the rootkit and retry running our
application again and we get an abort we
can no longer execute open access the
global namespace so now remember that
capsicum eyes dat or take another shot
in
[Music]
have it configured to listen on a sock
sport on 127.0.0.1 pork 9050 so if I run
tor then I see that tor is listening on
127.0.0.1
9050 now if I load the bind all rootkit
and rerun tor
now we see that it's listening on all
interfaces port 9050 so we're gonna run
i just unloaded the bind all rootkit
we're gonna run tour again and we see
that still now localhost so there's more
stuff to do with the Matt Mac rootkit I
want to add more templates there's more
more in the repo the the rootkit repos
public it's on soldier X's github and I
need to add in rootkit templates and tie
them all into one all-inclusive module
to show what you can do with those root
kits with Lib hijack I need to write
that remote runtime linker that is a
really tough thing to do to load shared
objects in a remote process over P trace
that's not an easy task and I took a
stab at it once around
around 2013-2014 and it took me six
months and I gave up so I'm currently
still doing more research in that area
so that we can inject anonymously those
shared objects I'd like to port to more
architectures like 32-bit Intel arm
could be done RISC five would be fun
there power 9 power 9 would be cool and
power 8 is there a power 9 board out yet
dev board I think that is the Raptor to
I think might be a might be out that
could be power 8 though risk 5 would be
really fun for loop hijack there's now a
risk 5 dev board that costs 1,200 bucks
and I'm having a little bit of trouble
right now convincing my wife to give me
a $1,200 toy I don't blame her at all
but that would be a lot of fun to port
it to risk 5 64-bit yep FreeBSD on risk
5 though only supports a 39 bit address
space which is weird they actually they
tree BSD first supported 32-bit risc 5
then they went to 64-bit then they went
back down to 39 bit I don't know why so
if someone wants to bring back Linux
support that'd be cool
I I don't really run Linux so I'm not
really all too interested in it so we've
showed that lib hijack is an effective
post exploitation tool that can even be
used to emulate to control flow hijacks
the Mac framework could be can be abused
but really it's it's fun and it shows
you what you can do when writing a
rootkit some powerful things and it
makes writing bits and pieces of your
rootkit pretty easy to do but really I
mean shouldn't really do that in
in the real world to mitigate lib hijack
disabled unprivileged about debugging
and that means that users can only debug
processes that they themselves fork so
like gdb and LDB can only attach to
processes that they themselves fork
implement implementing PACs no exact
would be an additional help because then
with PACs no exact you cannot write to
non writable memory allocations PACs no
exec applies to the P trace boundary
implementing PACs a SLR would mean that
you need to make your your payloads
dynamic and it just adds another layer
of complexity
you know harden BSD has all of this
stuff so maybe just run that to mitigate
Mac rootkits you could disable Mac and
the kernel and you could disable the
kernel interface entirely kernel module
loading interface entirely so on
the code is on github so if you go to
soldier X's github you'll find both Lib
hijack and the macro kiss and any
questions comments heckling right there
is so you can you can hook the the I
octaves
I believe those are grabbed via I
octaves when you create it you create a
special routing socket that will
that will tell you you can get
information about the routes and melvin
you know netstat under the hood uses i
octaves with routing sockets so you can
hook those interfaces and mock the right
output any other questions alright so
because time was limited i didn't really
have much time to go dive into the code
so if anyone wants to sit through and go
through the code with me i'm here all
weekend and i'd love to show you how
everything works under the hood i can be
reached on twitter and mastodons and a
torrefied signal so that's a lot of fun
thank you very much
[Applause]