[Music]
hi
i'm cecila testert and in this
presentation i'll be showing you our
work
in finding and profiling pgp hijackers
this is a work done in collaboration
with philip richter and david clarke at
mit
and aleister king and alberto denoti
from cada uc san diego
and this was originally presented at the
acm imc conference last year
so our motivation for this work is the
fact that bgp hijacking is pervasive in
the internet
as you can see here in these headlines
some of these
very known hijacks are from a long time
ago so this one that i'm showing
is from 2008 but the other ones
are much more recent from just last year
or even
earlier this year so even though it's
known for a long time
bgp hijacking is still a problem that is
far from solved
and in trying to find evidence of this
hijack i
realized that sometimes operators
disclose these hijacks
in males sent to nanak and
going through the mails in nanak and
noting the perpetrators of this hijack
we found that there are networks that
repeatedly hijack
over different periods of time and we
start calling this network
serial hijackers so these are networks
that hijack
a prefix at some point and then a few
times later there's another um
evidence of some other prefix and let me
tell you
the story of one of this quintessential
hijacker that i call
which is bit canal so this network
there's evidence of its hijacks that
comes to light for the first time in a
blog post in september 2014
and it keeps being connected to the
network then again there's another blog
post
with some evidence other hijacks that
come to light in january 2015.
and then uh three years later there's a
lengthy email going on
in nanak uh where the author is calling
to the transit provider to disconnect
this network because of the
large evidence of repeated misbehavior
of this network
and this network ends up being
disconnected uh in july 2018.
so it took four years for this network
to be disconnected for deceiving
hijacker to be disconnected
and i was inspired by this and i'd like
my research to help to improve that
so to do so the research goals of this
work was to find several hijackers in
the internet
and identify their distinctive routing
characteristic
then use them to build a machine
learning model that would allow us to
look at the behavior of more networks in
the internet and flag the suspicions
ones
evaluate the results of our classifier
and finally see what we can learn from
the serial hijackers
so the first step in doing this is to
find a ground truth for serial hijackers
so going through many emails for about
five years on the nano
mailing list i ended up finding three
networks that
i call serial hijackers these networks
uh look starting from the evidence of
the
of the emails i'm able to find at least
10 prefixes that
they have hijacked at different points
in time most of these network
have been acting for over a year when
looking at their bgp data
and also looking at their overall
activity in bgp
i found that some of them have
originated up to 30 000 different
prefixes
in the five years window of our um
experiment
and here on the right you can see the
map uh where the black dots
represent the countries from these
networks and you can see that they're
distributed more or less all over the
world there's not a one country that has
a larger concentration of them there's
some of them in europe in the us
in asia and in africa then
to keep on building these ground truths
i need the legitimate
networks and for that i based my
selection on the networks that agreed to
be part of these
mutually agreed norms for routing
security manners
so because this network voluntarily
agreed in
increasing their or adopting certain
routing behavior that would improve
security i
um we interpret that as they wouldn't be
persistently
misbehaving and that's why we include
them as legitimate networks
at the point of the study there were 191
networks that were part of this
agreement
and we augmented them with 26 minor
selected
yeses just to add more diversity to the
set of
networks and autonomous system that we
were studying
so with that ground truth then
we need to come up with the btp data for
those networks and for that
we use the publicly available collectors
so we use
all libraries and route views collector
these are over
40 collectors and there's over 1400
networks that provide bgp information to
these collectors
for the time window of our measurement
we process
all the bgp updates that are sent by the
different networks to these collectors
to reconstruct the routing tables of
these networks
from those routing tables we extract the
prefix and origin
aes in the bgp
in the pdb path and then
we count how many peers have a given
prefix and origin is in the routing
table
and that gives us the visibility of each
prefix
on as pair and we do this from january
until the end of december 2018 so it's a
five-year window
so at the end we end up with
um we end up with a database
that has prefix the origin as the
visibility in surface the number of
prefixes that have that
given prefix is in the routing table and
a time stamp
from when we computed these and this is
every five minutes
so with this very large data set of uh
all these vdp information going on in
bdp
a first step was to try to understand
the behavior of networks in our data set
and for that
we used a graphical representation that
allows us to
better understand the behaviors network
so here for example
is a graphical representation of an es
of british telecom
so this is a network in the uk and here
you can see on the x axis are the dates
of our measurement and on the y-axis
each line represents
a different prefix that has been
originated in bgp by this network
so the green lines that you see crossing
from one side to the other
of the graph are actually prefixes that
this network
has been originating all the time and in
every five-minute
snapshot we're able to see that prefix
being originated by this network
and of course you can see that some of
these prefix are um
start to be advertised in the middle of
the graph some of these prefix stop
being advertised
and this is usual behavior that we would
expect in
network operators and also you can see
that there's a column
in red and it is in red because those
are prefix
that uh reach a very low level of
visibility in our data set
less than 15 and that's why we graph
them in red
and also you can see that this happened
for a very short period of time
so although most of um of these graphs
show a very stable behavior there can be
routing events that look a little bit
different
so overall this is a very stable
behavior
and in comparison this is the same
using the same representation this is
what the serial hijackers looks in this
representation
so here you can see there's a large
difference
mainly the amount of white that is in
these uh representation
and that means that most of the prefixes
that are originated by djs
originated by a very short period of
time in our data set
and also you can see a huge contrast in
the number of different prefixes
so this network originates over about
different prefixes in this five-year
data set whereas british telecom
only originates about 200.
so the syrian high dagger bgp activity
looks very different
from the legitimate one
and now we need to um derive features
that are
going to allow us to capture this
difference in behavior
and from this example it might seem that
it's very easy but of course there's
variability in the behavior of
legitimate yeses and several hijackers
so here you can see some other serial
hijackers
what how they look like in this
graphical representation
and here you can see other benign
networks and what they look like in this
representation
so our uh these different graphs were
our inspiration
to come up with hypotheses of how
a serial hijacker would
how the behavior of a serial hijacker
would look like in our data set compared
to a benign network and we
one thing is that sierra hijackers would
tend to have repeated absence from the
global routing table
because they um sometimes they're
originally prefixed sometimes they're
not there
whereas most benign networks once they
start originating prefixes
they keep on originating prefixes for a
very long time
then um stereo hijackers when looking at
the specific prefixes
they're trying to have shorter
origination times
whereas again in legitimate networks
usually they're
um once they start reaching their prefix
is relatively stable
then uh we looked at the conflicts that
the prefixes originated with by this
network could have with other networks
in the internet
and our hypothesis was that they would
have more conflict with legitimate
networks
although we acknowledged that there are
legitimate reasons why this might happen
and then again uh we believe that
the syria um street hijackers would have
much more volatility in the count of
prefixes that are being originated over
time
compared to benign networks and for
example
here is a graph that looks at the number
of prefix being
originated by a given network in five
minutes bucket
and on the left side you can see comcast
and you can see that is mostly
stable except for a huge peak that
lasted
about a day and then it goes back to a
relatively stable level
and we reach out to them and it turns
out that at the moment that had a
an infrastructure problem which made
them
de-aggregate most of their prefixes and
that
hugely increased the number of prefixes
that they originated at the
during that time in contrast
for the serial hijacker you can see that
this number goes up and down
and many times is go this line goes down
to zero which means that at that point
they disappear from the global routing
table
and another difference uh between steer
hijackers and benign networks
is the fact that the ip.use have a
broader geographical distribution
so ip blocks are distributed by the five
rirs and most networks have
their ip resources from one riyar or
from a few of them but most of the
resources are concentrated in one of
them
given the geographical zone where
they're operating
however given that serial hijackers do
not go through the delegation process
that other neighbors go
they can use just any uh ip
prefixes and their distribution
tends to be more equal between the our
years and not be so concentrated
so to measure this we use the guinea
index which is heavily used in economics
to measure the inequality of wealth
distribution
and here we measure the inequality of
distribution of
our of ips per rr so a guinea of 0.8
means that all all ip resources from our
network are concentrated in one rir
and in this graph we can see that serial
hijackers the orange line
tend to have lower guiness which means
that their distribution is more uniform
between all five rirs
so in our data we found confirmation
of this different behavior in this five
point between several hijackers
and uh benign networks and then
we derive 52 different features that
capture
the different behaviors and the um and
the different flavors of this difference
between serial hijackers and legitimate
ess
and then using that we build a machine
learning system
to then run it with other networks
but there are challenges in applying
machine learning uh to find
more potential serial hijackers the
first challenge that we
we get is that our data is actually
really heavy-tailed and skewed
and by that what i mean is that in most
of our dimensions
when looking at aess these networks
they're
most of them concentrated in just one
part of our dimension
but then there's the long tail that
really extend the size
of our variables and then we have
variables that are very different
in size so for example um one variable
could be the number of prefixes that
they're
originating in a certain period of time
and it could go to a few thousand
but we also have the guinea index which
just varies between 0 and 0.8
and these difference make it very
difficult to normalize
our data then again
we have a very small ground truth
because
building the ground truth at the end we
end up just with 240 networks
when there's over 70 000 networks in the
internet
and of those network about 20 000 of
them originate more than 10 prefixes
and lastly we have a huge class
imbalance
because we were able to find only 23
different serial hijackers
and we have over 200 legitimate networks
and we need to be to carefully train our
classifier
uh because of this class in balance
so our approach to solve this is to use
a tree based classifier that is able to
handle
all these variables with very different
dimensions
and we also use a voting ensemble of
extremely randomized forest
because that allows us to train every
different uh forest with a different
base um a different breeze
that comes from different sampling
techniques and that way
because each sampling techniques create
uh the
synthetic data points a little bit
different we're able to gather uh
to have a better trained classifier
using this technique
and finally for the 52 features that we
built
we wonder if we could have uh select a
few of them that are more relevant than
others
but it turns out that looking at the
looking at the accuracy of our model uh
every time we took one of the features
out it was less accurate so we ended up
having
all 52 features because they all had a
positive median drop columns
importance so at the end using this
approach
a classifier ends up having uh almost
eighty percent position and hundred
percent recall
and what this means is that our
classifier
is able to select all the serial
hijackers from our ground truth
but it always includes a few legitimate
networks in that set
so knowing this limitation we went and
run this classifier in all the data from
the networks that we
um got from from the bgp collectors
so with the goal of finding uh networks
with similar behavior to the serial
hijackers we start with the 75 000
networks that we find on our data set
of these only about a little bit less
than 20 000
originate at least 10 prefixes in the
five years of our data set
and we only run in the data from these
networks
given that if we're looking at silver
hijacker we'd expect them to have
originated
at least 10 prefixes in five years
our classifier flags a little bit over
900 networks
from this set and this means that it's a
little bit less
of five percent of all the aess seemed
to originate over 10 prefixes in those
five years of time
and it's about 1.2 percent of all the
ess that we see in these five years data
set
so with this result we wanted to learn
who were these networks and the first
approach was to look at
their behavior in the same graphical
representation i showed you before and
these are
the representations from networks that
were flagged by a classifier
and we can see that uh they're very
similar to the ones that
we saw earlier and then
studying a little bit more what are this
network well
we started first by looking if we could
find
any indication of malicious behavior in
these networks
and the first place that we want to look
at this were block lists
so we look at the block list from spam
house that
that tags yeses because of repeated
criminal behavior
and we found that 84 of the network's
flag bar classifier are in the spam
house asn drop list
this means that network flag buyer
classifier are 10 times more likely
to be in this block list that the
networks that were not flagged by our
classifier
then we looked if any of these
iss had originated prefixes at the same
time that they
had been blacklisted in spam
blacklist and it turns out that about a
third of them
have originated prefixes that end up
being blacklisted
at the same time then
we looked for indications of
misconfiguration
and in that we uh find that a little bit
over a hundred
of the networks number the aess that we
find are actually private ess
that should not be using bgp and because
there are misconfigurations and
they happen all around the network and
they're quickly corrected
they appear to have uh when looking at
just one network very volatile behavior
and this is what gets caught by a
classifier
and also we find that all the single
digit ideas are caught by a classifier
and
these come from these five fingers
errors when
configuring sometimes the border routers
these numbers are added at the end uh
for doing some pre-pending
but because of mistakes they they appear
to be
the origin in bgp and it happens again
all around the network they're quickly
corrected and it looks like these
networks have a very volatile behavior
and connecting multiple points of the
network
which is the behavior flag fire
classifier
and finally we look at another category
of known of false positive
which is networks that offers ddos
protection on vgp
to do so these networks actually
originate a prefix or subprefix from the
client
where they're under attack and this is a
benign sort of hijacking
and again this is exactly the behavior
that we want our classifier to
flag and this is why uh we flag these
networks
so after looking at all these categories
we're left with
uh 441 networks which we cannot
immediately find in these categories
but in these uh 400 over 400 networks
there's still some pretty interesting
networks so this is a network for which
we couldn't really find any um
evidence but looking at its behavior
it turns out that um over half of the
prefixes that it originated
last for less than 12 hours and
um over 80 percent of the prefixes
originate
are also being originated by other
networks at the same time
and honestly i think this is really
interesting and
uh part of our future research is to try
to understand
any legitimate reasons why your network
would behave this way
so just to conclude um
43 of the networks that are flagged by a
classifier we can find them
in one of these uh known categories but
they're still these uh
very interesting 47 percent left of
networks
so we know that our classifier is not a
bulletproof identifier of malicious iss
again we are just looking um for aess
that exhibit
similar behavior to a hijacker not
necessarily malicious behavior
and we also know that this doesn't
capture all kinds of behavior
we're really looking at this repetitive
sort of behavior
and also we're heavily focused on prefix
origination
so this is just prefix hijack and would
not include something like path hijack
so this work uh for the first time we
bring to light
these networks that we call serial
hijackers and study their
um their behavior in bgp and
with the different features that we
derived to understand
how benign behavior differs from the
serial hijackers
they indeed end up giving us a state of
affairs of bgp wide behavior of network
and the outcome of a classifier can
indeed be used
in network reputation scoring system as
an
additional input and finally
our classifier really narrows our focus
on these more
interesting networks which we would like
to understand
uh their behavior in the future
and with that i'd love to get your
feedback on
how to how to continue this line of
research
so that this information could at some
point be integrated in operational
practice
to make routing more secure thank you
yeah thank you cecilia and welcome
so we have you live here let's go and
check if
our audience has had any questions for
you uh
okay so i'm just trying to scroll
through and see
okay so it doesn't look like uh other
than the fact that uh
people you know uh concur with the fact
that past fingering has led to a lot of
problems i don't see
a lot of questions but let me ask you
something i found it very interesting
not coming from a security domain but in
terms of the data that you collected
what were the challenges
that you faced in collection because you
have to make sure you have good data so
that your
model and your machine learning can give
you
more legitimate and real-world results
um so i think uh what is challenging is
that these collectors captures
the bgp data as it goes in the protocol
and as
happens with the false positive there's
a lot of mistakes that can go
in in this protocol so um for example
gathering this data um
i could sometimes have a prefix coming
from an origin that only one collector
could see
but how could i be sure maybe it's some
stall router that is sending that
information or something happening in
the collector so i need to discard it
so a lot of it at the beginning was
trying to understand
the data that i was dealing with and how
could i be certain
um after studying the data that certain
part of it
everybody was seeing it and that's when
um we started looking at visibility
and for example all the things that were
really not visible for
like one or two points uh by then we
discarded them because
those could be just very local
misconfigurations
okay and i believe i see a question on
the chat
so uh it seems hijackers also need a
real link
to get into the internet to be able to
uh create disruption
so have you uh in your research have you
investigated patterns
who these serial bgp hijackers peer with
do you have any uh date or any insights
into that
um yeah i think that's a really
interesting question
and uh it's something that i'm working
on as a
future research and for example well
starting with this list of hijackers
something that i'm kind of investigating
now
i realized that sometimes some of them
since they're originating
they have the same next hop and
somehow it seems that some of them have
this structure where you have this
maybe this next club that is not the one
um
doing the hijack like the origin high
tech but is the one that has the link to
the rest of the network
that is pro um providing for them a way
to get into the network
but it so that's one thing so there's
definitely some structure and how they
get connected to the network that is
really interesting to investigate
the other thing is for example in the
case of a bit canal the hijacker that
was
disconnected um after this lengthy
emission to nanog
they reconnect to another point of the
network so they were disconnected from
by
some transit provider and then they
found out a smaller one that could give
them connection and
they got connected again so i think this
is kind of
um cutting uh and it'd be interesting
that
um main like a large part of the network
actually blocks them
because otherwise they can always find
kind of connections
okay so now we have some uh other
interesting questions popping up
in terms of the speed of your machine
learning processing
are you able to process a real-time
stream of pgp updates
um i haven't uh
checked the the real time i think we we
would have a lag for maybe
half a day or something like that as it
is for the moment so
because this was a historical analysis
um
processing that data took a very long
time because it was like five years of
data
once we have that computed then adding a
year a day of data is much faster
uh and this is based on bgp stream from
uh
cada and that system has about
um i think 30 minutes lag to two hours
lag
um between real time and processing some
of the
the announcement and that would be like
the faster that we could go
but um this is not the other plugin that
is ready to
perform there and and as far as the time
horizon goes
how long it would take for you as you're
doing your processing and trying to
figure out how long would it take for
you to classify
for your classifier to go ahead and flag
a hijacker
so once you have this in a live stream
oh if i'm seeing
well it depends on the amount of
historical data that i have so some
sincerely that we've seen is that with
less than three months of historical
data from a network it's
it's much harder to figure out is it um
doing a lot of hijacks or not
okay okay all right and in terms of uh
there's another question
uh that is post on the chat is that uh
have you guys been using geolocation as
an input as well
we haven't been using geolocation as an
input what we've been using that it's
not as close as um the rier that is
delegating the ip
prefixes that are being used by the
different networks
and uh we're checking the concentration
of the resources that the networks use
in the different irs okay all right i
think we have
time for about as many questions but if
there are any more that come through
i'll make sure
pass them on to you so that we can get
them addressed but thank you so much
this was a very uh refreshing and
insightful talk and
uh for a novice like me who shies away
from security i definitely learned a
thing or two
thank you so much thank you for having
me bye
you