[Music]
good morning
hi i am jezebel gilmore i am the chief
commercial officer
and the co-founder of pocket fabric i'm
also
a member a proud member of nanog
and i've been for many years today i
wanted to talk about
growing up with nanog and the gift
that is the nanak community and what it
had helped
me with my life and how i've benefited
from being a part of this community so
a legend a personal icon
hero to me justice ruth bader ginsburg
has once said that if you want to be a
true professional
you will do something outside yourself
so from my perspective
i have always wanted to be a better
person
i don't know about you if we were in a
physical audience
i'd ask how many of you want to be a
better person
from my perspective the meaning
and just like justice ruth bader
ginsburg had said
of life is not
for oneself but for one's community and
something that i want to say is that
we all want to be a better version
of ourselves because that is human
nature
and something as we start right our
discussion
want to remind every one of you that
so many of us are working so hard
to be a better version of ourselves
that we forget we're already beautiful
and just by putting in the work in
trying to satisfy our desire
in being better
is a huge step forward
and i want to say
that something i learned in yoga
which i'm really not that great at but
just showing up at the top of the mat
is more than half the battle
we can often find satisfaction
in the way we help each other to achieve
our goals
and that is really more than half the
battle
in becoming a better version of yourself
so in exploring for
this talk i was trying to figure out
you know what makes nanog
great so i was thinking that
nanak's a community what is
a community so i looked up the
definition
and apparently it's a really old word
it's
highlights commonness everybody
and from wikipedia part of this
community
it says that a feeling of fellowship
with others as a result
of sharing something in common
so what do we have in common
at nanog love for bacon
sushi the latest gadgets
faster routers or bigger ports
i know some of you may be laughing
but really when i dig dump
deep i realize that it's the love for
the internet
so what is the internet
i'm not going to read you what i've put
on this slide
but the internet
is a system that relies on the kindness
and trust of everyone
especially here the internet
didn't have a business plan it did not
have a ceo
it's not expecting returns
from anyone and something that
i truly want to highlight here
is that in
a comment that professor jonathan zitron
of harvard told bbc about nanog which is
something that
i think is the most fitting description
of nanook that i've found
is that we are a team of volunteers
unpaid unauthorized
and largely unknown to most people
would wrote into action
and it's like the bat signal that goes
up and the batman answers
a random act of kindness of
unsung heroes that quietly keeps the net
working together this is something he
said
after the 2008 pakistan and youtube
incident i think
many of you still remember the people
come together from a feeling of
fellowship with others
that they may or may not be able to
physically
touch or meet in person
that yet to share a common attitude
interest and goal
to gain the sense of community is what
internet really is our ability to help
the world connect and form communities
i think it's kind of ironic that the
internet itself
is a community to help form communities
around the world
and it's held together by
a powerful community of misfits
and that's ourselves when i say that i
have this image in my head i know that
we don't all look like that
but i think of us as the unsung heroes
the the people behind
the scenes keeping the internet running
in making communities possible
now i've talked about a little bit about
what i think
nanak is i also want to talk about
what is my first impression of nanog
and how i got started we can only
look forward when we know our history
when
i started with nanag i was a young
operator my first time at anag i thought
oh my god
these people like to argue and they're
not afraid
to tell it like the way it is
sometimes it's really really rough
to hear but
they are the people who are in the
trenches
we are the people who are in the
trenches we're not
just doing something that's hypothetical
you know it's not written it's
doing it's making it happen right now
the people are real they are they may be
a little rough on the edges
and they may they may tell you things
that's tough to hear
but there are real people
that's affecting changes around the
world
something that i learned as part of the
community
being conscientious always trying to do
the right thing
even when it is hard and i think
that's a great reflection of
them saying things that i wish that
i was smart enough were quick enough
i don't know about you but how often do
you wish that you had come back
come up with a response
while you were in the discussion that
were clever
or even really courageous enough to say
there were many times that i'm sitting
in the great hall in the main session of
nanog
wishing that i could say what's on my
mind
at the speaker
to stand up and ask the question
as i get older i'd say that i wish i had
done that more
i'd implore you to go and do that
as well the courageous of others inside
the nanak
community has shown me it's okay
to go ask questions even when you're
unsure
what other people may think
and most importantly that i found from
our community
is that people are willing to help each
other
and they helped so many people have
helped me
without expectations of return
they may laugh and say
all right buy me a drink or
anything but really in reality there
were no
expectations of
return for the help they've given me
overall everybody in our community
care about more than just themselves
they care about this great thing that we
call
the internet and our community
and so i would say
that what can you do
be the community
follow the discussion there's lots of
discussions going on
around the community about the
technology the policy the politics
the people so much
be a part of the discussion don't be
afraid
to participate don't be afraid to ask
questions sometimes
it takes that one piece to fall into
place for you to truly understand
what everybody else is talking about
because you missed it
or you just didn't know it happened to
me a lot
and don't be afraid
and be open-minded because not everybody
is going to agree with you and or you
agree with everyone else
be open-minded and agree to disagree
share your ideas because sometimes your
ideas is great
sometimes maybe it isn't but
without sharing it you will not
know it that requires you to step
out of your comfort zone and i have to
say that is a hard one
it is so much easier said than done
and even as i sit here to talk to you
about
being a part of the community
i'm trying to show you and lead
by example in stepping out of my comfort
zone
because i hate public speaking and i
really am not very good at it
you know sometimes you have that buzz in
your head
when you're starting to feel nervous i
might have that right now
and um but push yourself
push your boundaries step out of your
comfort zone
that's how we all grow
and volunteer help others
be a part of the community
help others to learn the value of the
community
and so we can all evolve for the better
and sometimes you got to ask yourself
what can i do that someone else can't
and often that answer is
not really that much of anything but
however
if you always have the expectation well
somebody else can do it better
so somebody else will do it for us
then you end up with taco bell being the
best mexican
restaurant in the united states so
do something and express
your own
authentic self
so i'm going to come and talk about
myself and how i grew up in this
community
a little bit to help you understand
how it helped me and how it had helped
me
accept myself
so i was just
a small young operator in the community
and i always thought oh people who are
successful
who are big who are experts in areas
are the ones that should be contributing
what have i got
not much right and
so i i've been participating in the
community listening
quietly i always thought that others
have better things to say than i did
because i didn't quite accept me for who
i
am for my capabilities my voice
carried weight as well
just because that other people have
something to good to say
doesn't mean that i don't and
the more that you
stand up for yourself the more
confidence
you will gain i started as
a volunteer in the community when nanog
became neonog and
we had some financial challenges as a
community
and i love the community so much and
i had so many friends in the community
or that i've built over the years
i wanted the community to continue so i
thought well
um maybe i can help
do an outreach program be a part of the
sponsorship
community a committee and
help the nanak to raise funds
and sell sponsorship to become
sustainable
and self-sustaining that's when i first
started as part of the community
the committees in volunteering
what i learned being a part
of the sponsorship committee is it's so
much harder
than it is then so much harder
um done than said because
i was not very good at asking other
people for money
i really never felt that was a thing
but i felt so strongly about the
community
and nanak that
i was willing to step out of my comfort
zone to help it
to help make sure that we were
self-sustaining
i went to large companies that are
potential sponsors
and spoke to them about the value of
being a part of the community and part
of the sponsorship
what i was able to do is to speak from
heart
because i felt it and i knew what had
done for me
and i wanted to express that
to others but moreover
as i was raising funds for nanog
i realized that i was able to
communicate
in this fashion
better than i thought i could and the
more i did it
the better i got and
not only i was able to raise funds
but i was able to listen to what others
have to say
in return and how they wanted to see
the sponsorship evolve and what
value it would it could bring for them
so i worked with the staff of nanag
and the board to help shape
the new sponsorship programs back then
we have much better ones even now today
to build better sponsorship
programs for
the sponsors of our community
they are also a part of the community
they make it possible
and guess what i learned from that i
learned that
maybe i can do more than just being an
operator
i can explain the value of
what i'm trying to do and what my fellow
engineers
are trying to do i can become a conduit
between the engineering and
the buyers the business side of
nanog and our community and thus
it helped and led me into being
becoming or stepping into the next stage
in my life from an operator becoming
someone in the business development side
of my personal career
and just to be honest i thought long and
hard about being in business development
because that sometimes that's considered
sales and
it is and i always thought to that
as a position that people looked down up
to engineers
don't sell but
nanak helped me realize that
i was good at it i
had to accept through the process of
growing up with nanog
that i am good
at business development i can do more
than just being an engineer
and being on the operation side of the
business
and all of that contributes to the
belief
of something bigger than just ourselves
and along the way not only that
i was helped by so many others
i realized that by
helping others that it had created to
greater return
for me and
from volunteering on the committees
i went on to become a board member of
nanog
two consecutive terms
and that helped me gain incredible
perspective
to see the bigger picture to understand
what others need
and hear what
they are looking for from this community
and stand up for something that
i cared about greatly whether that is
nanak as a community or
is a fellowship program for
abba huja a great personal friend
who had passed away that helping
women in networking
by providing some resources from the
great nanak community
so i
would say that
although that i gave some of my time
and effort to nanong i got
a lot more in return
because it had pushed me
to advance to the next stages of my
career
and something that i also want to talk
about is
learning to push my boundaries
while others pushed me because people
uh friends within the community
every day help me to understand
that i can be better sometimes it's
really hard
to learn that lesson that
community tells you like how it is
it's hard and
so i would encourage you
to do all of that by participating
and volunteering with nanak
here's some things that you can find
the nanak website working together
for a better internet of tomorrow
a community built on openness
authenticity and collaboration
with eye on equality and
here in the netherlake community
we learn to be accepting and we are
accepted
by each other and in a community
that we have this great community that
we have
we learned that life is about others
and we need others to better
understand ourselves and they help us
to become better versions of ourselves
so lastly i leave you with something
that i recently read i'm not religious
i'm not trying to push any religion on
anyone
but what i want to highlight here
is that we're all born to help each
other
no matter how difficult it is life is
good when you're happy
and much better when others are happy
because
of you and how do we
[Music]
find happiness compassion
is really what i think is the most
important
and compassion is relationship between
equals
and at nanog we find each other doesn't
matter what we do
to be equals and
we find our own darkness and we get to
know it
we help each other explore that those
challenges and in becoming better
versions
of ourselves and then we can be there
for each other
please
i ask you at the end of today
to do something for someone else
so they can be happy because of you
and thank you thanks to the nanak
community
for giving me the opportunity to share
my experience with nanak
and my joy from this community
thank you so much zezebel for recounting
your experiences
i think uh it resonates with a lot of us
and
uh as for me i think the big takeaway is
that
even though we are very technical uh
being the engineers and geeks that we
are in our professional lives
having that business acumen to be able
to translate that
idea or the you know the talent that we
have into the next big thing
i think that's equally vitally important
um let's see if you have any questions
coming in uh from the audience
uh yeah please feel free to type in
anything that you would like to ask her
but for me uh if you've seen those
changes coming across over the years
where which direction do you think we
are headed in terms of bringing in new
people infusing
you know invigorating the uh the core
membership base
of our audience well over the years i've
seen a lot of changes
uh at nanag there were a time when i
thought
350 attendees at a nanak was an
enormous conference and i think
in february this year when we had our
last in
person conference we had well over a
thousand and ten days
so um the community is growing
and it's it's maturing in addition to
you know being the unsung heroes behind
the internet
uh there are so many other businesses
that's
heavily dependent on what the networking
industry provides
as a foundational service and so as part
of that
i think that we're going to be seeing um
new talent coming in maybe freshly out
of college
uh maybe just joining the workforce
and moreover transitioning from other
uh areas of the industry of
technological industry
um we're transitioning out into other
parts of the supporting industry
um into supporting networking like i
have
um personally from being an operator
into leading the business side of
um networking just because it's
business it's you know business
development sales um
or anything in support it doesn't mean
it's actually any worse
um it's not a lower position or
you know that's not as honorable
so um i'm proud of what i do
and what i do for the industry and i
think the
the maturing of the industry is going to
continue to expand
our community and we need to be
open-minded and accept
everyone that wants to be a part of this
community
thank you so much and we couldn't we
could have been happier to have you
do our keynote presentation so on behalf
of the program committee
thank you very much