[Music]
hello
my name is jen i am a network engineer
at google in australia
and i've been with google for like more
than 10 years
initially working on production backbone
and for the last
six years i've been looking after
corporate part of the google network and
all of the time i've been mostly working
on itdc
so today i'm gonna speak about something
really exciting what i've done
about something i broke so let me show
you some slides
and another thing you know uh you need
to know about me
is that i'm a big fan of comic sans so
some people might be suffering for the
next half an hour
sorry about that so
what i'm going to talk about today is
something people might consider almost
impossible
almost like unicorn my talk will be
about
turning ipv4 off in the enterprise
environment
and migrating an enterprise network to
ipv6 only mode
why why would anything person do that
i actually had plenty of reasons to do
that
first of all believe it or not we run
out of ipv4 address space
yes private one it's possible
secondly i am getting more and more
requests from various business units and
developers
for ipv6 only environment for dog food
and
tasting and last but not least
i am heavily involved in operations and
i
found that dual stiffness will come
through the cost
operating dual stack is actually harder
than operating symbols tech network
because you basically created
two networks at the same time and you
need to make sure
their configurations are consistent and
troubleshooting is a bit tricky
thanks for happy eyeballs so in our
attempt to save
private address space activity for
address space
and simplify the network we decided to
try something impossible
and turn off ipv4 in the part of the
network
to do the pilot and proof of concept
we decided to take the low-hanging fruit
and migrate our
corporate guest network to ipv6 only
mode
our guest network actually consists of
two parts
one is guest wi-fi if you ever visited
one of google offices you'll probably
notice that you have google guest wi-fi
which is open in most of the offices and
you can connect visitors can connect
their device
actually it's the biggest wi-fi network
we have in the corporate environment
most most of our wi-fi users modern
house
are actually using guest wi-fi
also we have a wired guest network which
is used for
unauthorized unknown devices connected
to a wired internet
and also it's used as a fallback
network in case of dot one x
authentication
so how we did that
obviously we still need to provide
access for
guest devices to ipv4 only internet
resources
so what we needed is not 64
and dnf64 which obviously are the key
element of
uh providing access to for destinations
for dns we were using google public dns
which we launched in 2015 as far as i
can remember
because for normal dual text network we
also using google public dns
so it was of those choice we didn't have
any form of the
it's pure slug so we were providing dns
explore information to host
via rdnss dns
ips were sent in our router
advertisement
for not fix for for translating
ipv6 traffic to ipv4 we were using the
same
devices which were indulged that
environment doing translation from
private ipv4 under space to public id
for address space
those devices located to fight age so it
was easy basically no new network
elements the same
path for traffic we just replaced in one
form of not with another
when we started the pilot for guest
network
i wanted to answer a number of questions
which could be summarized as
what exactly will be broken because you
don't know what you don't know
and guest devices by definition devices
we do not control
and we have no idea what they are how
many devices
actually can send music from the network
i had some guestimate
because it's not the first ipv6 only
network i've seen a number of
conferences do the same
for example arrive has v6 only network
uh as well as far as i know
first game is doing v6 only and we
actually did some experiments
at itf network as well i expected that
maybe 75 percent of devices would be
okay but
obviously it would depend on the
environment so i needed more solid
numbers
also another interesting question was
how our tech support
would survive because some people were
concerned that
we might get too many unhappy customers
so we decided to do some tests on this
i connected 12 sites for the pilot
and obviously if you decided to try this
at home your experience may vary
i had four uh primary criteria
first uh low size uh
i had to have network operations people
inside to simplify the
troubleshooting so i actually started
from my home sydney office i wanted to
do the pilot on locations when we have
large number of users
to make the the data more statistically
reliable and also i took into account
customer demands so sites where we get
most number of requests for ipv6 on the
network from developers were included
into the pilot
because it meant that we'll get users
there
and those users are willing to try that
network and help us
finding issues so as i mentioned
we had two segments wireless environment
and we did pilot for them separately
provided it was easier for about
six or nine months we just turned
off ipv4 on the segment converted
into v6 only i mean replace dns with dns
x4
and for users who need ipv4
we provided a self-service portal to
re-enable
ipd4 on the given wordport but
users were asked and encouraged
to tell us why they requested atv4
because
as i mentioned one of the goal of the
pilot was to find out
what is broken and why so we'd like to
enumerate
all possible issues so
for any deployment story the most
interesting part
is always one good broken right everyone
wants to
hear the worst story so the biggest
brokerage
i caused happened on the first pilot
site
right away and it probably was the
biggest issue we discovered
i mean in term in terms of number of
people i'm happy and how urgent it was
to fix it
and what i broke was treadmill
yes we have a number of officers where
we have
gym gyms on site and those gyms have all
these smart
uh exercise devices which are connected
to the internet i did not even notice
until all this project happened right
apparently those devices need internet
connection
and most of them are really not happy
when you take ipv4 away
so fortunately we were able to recover
those devices providing them ipv4 and we
started discussion with treadmill vendor
actually about fixing the problem
and we still waited for them to come
with
a new version which will support ipv6 on
your network
so as i may as i said about six or nine
months of the pilot
the results were actually quite good
most of the sites
except ones which had treadmills
did not need many ipv4 enabled ports
the maximum number we saw like five
devices per site
which allowed us to save a lot of other
space because
a wired network had to be provisioned
to allow all our corporate devices
to end up on the guest network if uh
dot one x authentication failed so we
had to provision a lot of other space
for dual stack wireless gear and by
making
eight v6 only we were able to recover
i would say two three hundred thousand
addresses actually
and main ipv4 use case we discovered
from the wired guests
was various types of embedded systems
like treadmills ied stuff
not actual laptops it was mostly some
special devices which
uh did not even know about v6
so for virulence we decided to take baby
steps
so we did the pilot in two phases
phase one was opting
which lasts for a year and a half
during that phase we created a special
dedicated new ssid
on the pilot site we sent an email to
all users outside
and asked them to try the uss id
and report the issue
and after we became confident that
we're not going to see too many problems
with
itv6000 we switched to opt out
we for about nine months
we made our primary
standard google guest ssid
six only but for users who still need
ipv4 we created a special dedicated
fallback ssid
which had not existed on those sites
before and again
we asked users please come and tell us
what broke and don't just switch back to
dual secret id because we need to know
what is broken
so what we found during the pilot
on those 12 sites for wi-fi
phase one about 10 percent of users
actually tried new ssid which was much
much better than i expected you know
people tend to ignore such emails
but yet ten percent of them
we asked users to report banks
and we even uh offered a draw
so the winner person who reported the
most number
of banks was supposed to win 100 dollars
donated to a charity of their choice
actually we got 15 bucks reported
and three of them were fixed as a result
well as a typical situation with
operations nothing gets fixed until
people complain right
so before even we start moving majority
of the users towards examiner we already
have
have some bug clips when we moved
majority of the users
to v6 only we noticed that less than
five percent of
users fall back to dual security
that was actually much much better than
i expected
my guesstimate before the start of the
project was maybe
25 percent well actually 10
of those users were
using 2.4 gigahertz for that id which we
did not migrate to v6 only
so out of all guest users they have 10
percent which stayed on dual stack
because we didn't touch them
five percent fall back to dual set of
society so basically about 85 percent of
our users
were quite happy being on v6 only
network
in absolute numbers it's actually quite
a lot the peak device counts in one day
was 25k
so i had 25 000 users only heaps on the
network
and not so many bugs reported 12
in total and we bought four of them
fixed
mostly internal style but we also
reported a number of external
applications
so remember those questions i wanted to
get answered during the pilot
what percentage of users need you for as
i said
we got about five percent explicitly
falling back
and 10 percent were just staying on 2.4
and they were not even affected by this
project
so wi-fi and for wired as i say five
devices per site
maximum except special locations with
treadmills
as a result we saved a lot of address
space
for wi-fi our adhd people utilization
dropped by
five eight times which actually matches
fifteen percent of users stand on gold
stacks
so we basically were able to downsize
uh dhcp pools by four
in some cases eight times which again
was huge savings of other space
and for virus we basically reclaimed
hundreds of thousands of ap
what did not work well i think my
current list is about
20 items i have a special
a list of things which do not work top
five number one is definitely dream
revenue
number two this one actually got a lot
of complaints from users
and i need a community help here spotify
application
on the laptop it works perfectly final
phones
it works in the browser mode but if
you're using a dedicated app
on macquarie and i think on windows as
well
it's very unhappy there is no ipv4 so
please
if you ever use spotify click on this
link and upload the feature requests i
opened with them
to get that fixed well the third thing
is bpm
we knew it's gonna happen there is no
reason
why vtns protocol would not work over
ipv6 only and it does work if vpn server
is properly configured unfortunately in
many cases
server administrators do not enable ipv6
on the
vpn system and as a result servers don't
want to establish a connection with a
client which doesn't have ipv4 address
but again it's not a protocol problem
it's just configuration machinery both
sides
well yeah some people complained about
start crafts not
not working i am not sure it was built
on critical applications but people
aren't happy
also i got reports about marquez
recovery image not working over which
it's only but also what i've heard
that go away so probably it's not such a
big of an issue
one of the important questions for us
was how we're going to provide
fallback mechanism for users who need
ipv4 because
i've i never expected that we can
migrate all users
i understand some of them will need ipv4
so one of our
options where okay maybe we can use
dedicated assess id we can use dedicated
network
but how we're going to do that convert
or what we're doing currently a user
must open a ticket and tell us that they
need ipv4
because we want to know who those users
are
why they need ipv4 and we're only
granting them that exception for 18
months
because we do not want users to relax
and sit forever and do nothing about
fixing the application
for wi-fi when the tab doing dedicated
ssid
but i thought about strata general
explained a little bit later
why any showstopper
no that actually didn't discover
anything to block the project
because they were providing a mechanism
for users
to get dual steps in the unit
obviously your experience may vary
because it depends on the use cases and
devices from the network
for example my laptop has been
technologically network network
since the start of the pilot so for at
least two and a half years
and i'm perfectly happy but my use case
is both lessons agent browser
people with millions of applications
windows laptops might have different
experience
supportive impact surprisingly was very
little
but we planned ahead we notified the
users about the change
notification will contain the link to
report the issue
and the first step how to recover how to
switch the dual set
so as a result most of the users
actually didn't even need to talk to
support him
but in case they do support team were
provided with the troubleshooting flow
chart
they had a link to known issue page so
they could check if the issue has been
reported already on how to troubleshoot
lessons learned well the most
important lesson i've learned never
allow
your tech support to disable ipv6 of
user devices
we found a number of cases when users
just had ipv6 disabled on the laptops so
we'll see nothing not for that
white because a while ago it was some
issue
and tech support people decided as a
workaround
advise users or just disable atv6 once
you do this
there is no way you can come back find
out how many people did that
do they still had music disabled come
out until you turned off ipv4 and that
problem backfired
also until return of ipv4 you're not
really getting an operational experience
with v6
what you get it is hyper eyeballs and
it's completely different story all
right
we found a number of issues which were
not visible to us at all
thanks to high five vote until we
disable ipv4 right
first of all we found a lot of vendor
bug
very funny one i can talk for hours
probably should be another presentation
about what we found things like only
unique packets to particular
source of distillation porta broken and
all that kind of funny things
we actually found an interesting problem
with neighbor discovery design
neighbor discovery state machine allows
patients to be
dropped all the time when a new device
connected for the to the network for the
first few seconds
so there is an idea of a draft which is
going through working group plus call
currency to update the
neighbor discovery state machine and to
fix the issue
also there are a number of process
issues we discovered first of all indeed
in the mindset
people still think about ipv6 as a
second class citizen so they never have
physics connectivity
is before it's working and so on we
found the number of designs which
claimed to be ipv6 uh
enabled but they still had
number of dependencies on ipv4
like application might send ipv6 traffic
but it's never used in ipv6 dns for
example
so another lesson is that early adopters
are crucial for the success
so we did this opt-in phase when we
asked for volunteers
and it was a very good idea because we
got people on board
who are interested in physics willing to
try
willing to troubleshoot and they're also
capable of troubleshooting so they can
give you a which are much more
informative than just
something doesn't work right they can
help you they can run tp down for you
and so on
as a result when we switched majority of
the users to visit congress we already
uh had some issues found and fixed
which allowed us to minimize the user
impulse and improve the user experience
yeah another thing is that it's a very
good idea to start recreating
activities support from your vendor as
early as possible because obviously it
takes
years to get proper basic support but
that request must be very explicit
i've seen rfps say ipv6
must be supported it basically means
nothing
if you then tell you ah my equipment
supports ipv6
it most likely means you can configure
an ipv6 address
right it does it might not mean that
that device
can use ipv6 dns
it does not necessarily mean device
would receive dns and router
advertisement
it doesn't mean it could be managed over
ipv6 and so on right
so we start we have started making those
requirements explicit
and talking to all our vendors
so dedicated assets id why it's not
ideal
first of all we actually spent a lot of
time discussing
what the name of that ssid should be
our normal ssid is google guest how
should we name a fallback ssid
so the name is less attractive to users
still by default connect to google gas
but it's still attractive enough that if
google gets does not work
users will try this one hard right
also the problem is in most of the cases
people do not know which ssid the
device is connected to right now
because some devices have explicit
preferences some may
make a decision based on the signal and
so on
so we actually found the number of cases
when device which supposed to be on the
six on the ssid because it worked very
well
just decided to switch the dual steps
which basically increased in atu for
consumption and so on
so uh one of the options is actually do
not broadcast
the full brackets id so users need to
explicitly configure it only if they
need to
and also once your device remembers the
fallback society there's always a chance
it will be connected
to it even if someone is available and
working so it's hard
and for wired network fallback is
actually even harder because
for the guest network is just one
segment for us so we were
able to create additional dual stacks a
lot
but as i'm thinking about doing the same
uh migration for internal network when i
have a lot of villains
it means that i would need to double
number of villains in the network which
doesn't scale
so what we really need to make
transition to ipv6 only
smooth is ability for ipv6 only
and ipv4 enabled hots to coexist on the
same network segment on the same
villa and actually there is a draft
uh in adhd working group which is
currently with rxt editors and will be
published too we describe
how we can utilize dhtp with ipvd
mechanism to allow coexistence of ipv6
layer
physics only and ideal for enabled codes
together
so the current status of this
is that we have completed the migration
of our offices to icv6 on the network so
vast majority of them are now physics
only so when all this
convenience sanity is over and you
decide to comment here
in one of our locations your device will
be connected to ipv6 only guest network
so that's all i have for today
so believe me or not ipv6 all the
enterprise networks or maybe
let's call them ipv6 mostly enterprise
network
are actually possible and i guess now we
have time for questions
[Music]
uh thank you very much jen um somebody
is asking if you
enabled high availability on the nat 64
and dns-64 guest network and if so how
so uh actually for
for not 64 we're using the same devices
which we're using for normal not for
four
so it has the same level of high
availability because they will have a
cluster
of firewalls so the same set of devices
which vary initially even for not for
four mode
in high availability mode so we didn't
do anything special we basically enabled
additional form of not on the same set
of devices
and for data64 well i got like i was
using a google
uh public dns-64 so
it's because it's sweep and the whole
google infrastructure is provided
without high availability for us
someone is asking if the recording or
presentation will
uh will be made available this along
with all the other presentations will be
made available
a few weeks after the conference closes
we don't have any other questions but uh
jen i was wondering if you had
a favorite war story to share
i actually have two and i cannot make it
you can make my mind which i like more
so one was quite funny we noticed that
when i connect to the hex only network
which we did not even make
public at that state my device has
ipv6 connectivity for five seconds
and then it disappears until the next
array came
apparently what happened we had a smart
wireless device
which was trying to do kind of nd proxy
and it was pretty it was trying to
respond to neighbor solicitation from my
laptop for default router address
but while responding it was actually
clearing up rb in may which means
it was training my device i am not a
router anymore so my device was losing
default drain as a result of holistic
connectivity
after five seconds and the second funny
story was
michael complained that the respect
some of them are disappearing on v6 on
the network
and what we discovered the issue was
affected
you distributed with some particular
source for
and because different platforms using
different set of source ports for
dns packets it was only affecting some
platforms
and we found that another type of
equipment was
actually trying to drop
ipv6 mlg packets
and it was looking for item pv6
type in the packet without even checking
that it's actually 18 pv6
and as a result some source sports in
udp looked for that device as particular
icmp
ipv6 emergency package so those packets
were drawn
yes i spent some time at troubleshooting
that kind of many things
uh what was the most unexpected yet
positive feedback you've heard from the
v6 switchover
unexpected actually
i was surprised that how many people
actually responded to our announcement
saying oh yeah that's really cool thank
you very much for doing this
because we we did uh have some requests
from some developers
asking could you please give us the
ships on the network but i did not
expect that
so many engineers at least were actually
really happy to see it happening
because it actually allowed them to do
dog food and find out what kind of the
what kind of physics problems their
products have
well thank you very much john