this talks about the wit machine which
is created by memory deduplication a
feature offered by some virtual machine
some some hypervisors and lately also
windows 8.1 and higher so it the yeah
our paper presented at security and
privacy yesterday explains the whole
thing so this will be a kind of an
improvised talk with some extra thoughts
of about so yeah how the how does
deduplication attack kind of well fits
into the yeah I would just realized too
weird machines so the so in our paper so
the people the authors of roham rjs have
shown that it's now possible to use the
row hammer attack fit a hardware uh-huh
a hardware attack which allows for bit
flipping in memory also work that also
works from JavaScript and but the
published attack using a row hammer to
do privilege escalation is kind of
difficult to do from JavaScript because
it requires spraying of memory player at
paging memory paging pages in memory so
it basically allocates lots of file
backed memory pages and then yeah make
sure the a lot of pages and memory are
actually used with using the before the
paging mechanism so with this is kind of
difficult to achieve from JavaScript so
in our attack we present a reliable
pretty reliable exploitation methods to
exploit Microsoft edge from JavaScript
using a memory leak a memory leak it
stems from the memory deduplication
functionality in Windows 10 so in order
to do our row hammer attack we need to
lick some information in this case heap
he put a heat pointer pointing to data
we control and the code pointer to the
JavaScript library itself and in our
exploit we pack this into a fake object
and and then we will use row hammer to
flip a bit from a pointer from one fake
object from one from one real object to
our fake object and from that we can art
achieve an arbitrary readwrite primitive
so but in order to lick this information
will be using a memory deduplication
side-channel attack so how this is work
in short if an attacker wants to
you verified that a victim process or or
virtual machine or anything has a
certain specific picture of the Mona
Lisa in his or her memory then like this
then an attacker can replicate the
memory pages and then the memory
deduplication memory deduplication
mechanism in the OS or the hypervisor
will will merge that will identify that
these pages are the same and then will
point the page tables to the same
physical location but then the problem
is if anyone wants to write to this page
yeah you can't change this in the other
process as well so the page is marked
copy-on-write and that's where the
problem lies because this is detectable
and it's also detectable from in
JavaScript because if you write a change
one page with a single right it takes
doesn't take a lot of time certainly
when the cash is not cold but when you
do this on a copy on write page the
kernel or the hypervisor has to do all
kinds of stuff before you can write to
the page it has to deduplicate d D D
duplicate the page and before you can
write to it and this is measurable so
this is this is a neat trick but all we
can do is is leaked one bit of
information a confirmation that the
certain page is in memory so can we
generalize this to licking arbitrary
data so turns out in some cases you can
but there are some problems with this
because the the secret you want to leak
might not be the size of a page if you
can so you need to have a way to encode
a secret into a page so the thing is
that this is not really something and so
an application developer should have to
worry about that you cannot you cannot
create a page with a secret in there and
then some other data that an attacker
can guess so it turns out this this yeah
you might have a socket and you write
your your data to the socket and then
it's written inside a buffer but then
you cut off just before the end of the
page and at the end of the page there
are still some data you might want to
leak so this is not something an
application developer should have to
protect against then there's another
problem and that's that the thing you
want to leak might have more entropy
than you could probe for because you for
every possibility you have to craft the
page in your own memory and then you
will get the confirmation of which page
exists in memory but if you have say a
pointer with 24 bit of entropy you need
64 gigabytes of memory to probe for
every possibility so that's not really
feasible so there are some in our paper
we describe some ways of of some ways of
leaking this data anyway so one thing is
if you can control the alignment of the
secret that you can you want to lick you
might be able to have a page which with
almost with all known data but with part
of the secret you want to lick so you
only have to probe for part of a secret
if you don't control the alignment there
might be a different way of getting what
you want which is to overwrite part of
the secret the in in our exploit we use
the first first
primitive so in the Microsoft edge there
is a jet the JIT compiler creates
machine code but it has a the which is
but the different and the last part of
the function is always the same except
for the code address and the code
address is carry some a SLR information
so we want to lick that so by creating
JavaScript objects we can we can we can
we can create pages which only carry
part of the secret of the part of the
SLR information by having controlling
the alignment such that the code address
spans multiple pages and then we can
lick it in multiple phases and get the
code address but there there might be a
situation where an attacker kind of
craft is just a page that where where
where where it kind of reduces the
entropy of the secret at once a leak but
yeah and this is the case for this was
the case for us for the hip pointer that
we wanted to leak but there there is
another trick which is related to the
birthday problem which is the into which
is the observation that giving a group
of people the chances of someone having
the same birthday as someone else in the
group yeah for that is non-intuitive
lilo so and and the reason for this is
that you're not comparing one person's
birthday with a few other people's
birthday you you're comparing every book
every
person's birthday with every other
person's birthday so in order to lick a
hip pointer with data we control we use
the same principle so we don't care
which he point or we leak we just want
to lick one of them so we just create
lots of objects and then and these
objects represents and we yeah and we
make sure that we have pages in memory
with references to these objects and
then we in JavaScript we can also create
arbitrary binary data and we guess
references to objects and then we use
the binary deduplication mechanism of
the OS to do an end times M comparison
it will well basically the the the the
yeah the whole mechanism of
deduplication is doing compare is
basically compare everything with
everything so well that's what we abuse
in this case and will
yeah so yeah so basically this is a
slice art are our demonstration of this
so yeah the chance of getting one hit be
too yeah so it's slightly different
compared to the birthday problem because
the you have two groups but the the
intuition is the same and you only need
the square root space complexity to get
the right head I get a hit so yeah so
and then it gets duplicated then we can
lick the address so this is a figure
from the from the paper we I added so in
practice we kind of have a side channel
where we leak objects with with a on a
megabyte boundary so we kind of leak no
no the the least significant bits and
then and then these objects represents
pointers which are very close together
and then in our probe pages that we the
other pages we guess might be in the
address space we we take big jumps and
then cover the whole address space and
then we get matches so and recovered
over the pointers that we are looking
for so to complete the attack we now can
controller create a fake objects inside
the JavaScript array there's another
JavaScript array which has a reference
appointed to it and then we need to
change this pointer to our fake object
for that we use the Java row hammer
primitive in row hammer
when you activate a certain role
repeatedly there are some physical
properties of the Durham memory which
are made amid for out of capacitors
which yeah which caused charges to leak
and and if you do this quickly enough
and you have bad bad memory bits may
flip and so using this bit flip we can
change a flip say one what a 120 and it
will point our fake object and from that
we can escalate to arbitrary read right
so yeah so yeah the main thing to bring
back it is i guess that memory
duplication is a bit more powerful than
one bit side channel and yeah row hammer
is the air yeah we're browser
exploitation using row hammer is
possible