okay yes yeah all right thank you okay
so to give you a really quick recap the
hammer parser Combinator library for
those of you who have not ever seen it
is a library meant to well bring bring
more grammatical parser specification
into the world of C so this what you see
here is a few examples we have print or
primitive parsers that are then combined
by higher level Combinator's into more
complex structures and you can also
define your own combinators using those
and by that we hopefully will arrive at
a specification for our protocol which
is at the same time kind of a grammar
and also its implementation so to give
you a little spoiler where this is going
to go this is a circus favorite mantra I
think start with a grammar stay with a
grammar now that's what we're hoping a
hammer lets us do but the question of
course is what is that Graham are
actually for protocol like dnp3 there's
a very large specification but it does
not contain a dnf for something we've
already heard a lot of talks about
trying to derive grammars and that's
something that we did here basically by
hand and it's the interesting lesson
here is if you look at the beginning of
the specification you don't have to be
able to read those very small text there
obviously this is an overview picture of
the d mp3 protocol layers it has a lower
link layer transport layer and an
application layer at the top so that's
basically kind of mirroring the
situation you'll have it on the Internet
but this is meant to run over modem
lines and such as well so it has all
these three layers and if you if we
concentrate on the application layer
here you'll see that
still looks pretty neat this is still
from the first pages of the spec and
this is this is a kind of regular
expression representation of this
structure of this application layer
fragment as they call it a packet which
consists of a header and that's followed
by an arbitrary number of objects blocks
so to speak and each object block
contains another object header which
specifies the type of objects basically
and then the object data itself those
can be multiple as well the stuff below
here is then the detailed structure of
well the header as well as the object so
you'll see there are several fields you
don't obviously need to know the details
of those but it's it's relatively easy
to explain the structure and write down
a regular expression that fits it but
the problem is that fails to capture the
dependencies and constraints that exist
between the flags in the header of the
particular function being involved being
invoked and the function and the groups
and are the types i should say group
variation is the DMP three-term the
types of the objects that are expected
or allowed with that function and then
also a bunch of more particular fields
in that in that header so these are
things that we had to somehow capture
and yeah if you want to look at the spec
for this information you'll find a lot
of tables and descriptions this is a
slide of a screenshot of a slide that we
had in the talk where we presented this
this year at s4 to the industrial
control system community so to speak and
yeah there's these tables that that show
valid combinations of flags and here you
see a little bit of a text snippet out
of the semantics or a description of
some function and if I blow that zip it
up sorry I'll read that red part to you
it says this is
about a certain type of object says read
requests and responses shall use
qualifier code 7 and range field value
of one for this object this object can
be included in a write request so this
is clearly actually syntactic
information this is the types of codes
and flags you're supposed to use with
this object type and the type of
function that you're allowed to use this
with but if you talk to dnp3 users
they'll tell you well yes that's but
that's semantics right that's in the
semantics of the thing because it's in
the in the pros description of the spec
but in our view this is not actually
semantics so our job is to find the true
syntax of this protocol here's another
example where you have a structure
that's for basically timestamps on
events and to save bits on the wire they
allow you to specify these relative to
some common time of occurrence that's
what the term is and there's an obvious
constraint here if you don't have a
common reference point you can't have
relative time stamps but the spec
actually never says this and the reality
is that different implementations will
behave differently if this this common
time of occurrence object is left out of
the packet so you have instances where
the where the complexity of the language
is kind of shifted out of the syntax
into into the pros description and you
have cases where it's actually just not
there in the description anywhere yeah
yeah yeah okay um here to give you an
example of what this looks like in our
code the top part is just short names
for the stuff stuff that was defined
elsewhere the interesting part is here
in the middle you can see a 2
Combinator's use choice and sequence
sequencing is just you know two things
after another
the interesting part is there's a this
is for the Select function that selects
a relay to be switched or something like
that it's a you can see it has three
possible forms of first one is a
sequence of something called a PC be
followed by multiple things called a PCM
the third one is a thing called krob
that's a control relay object blog or
something oh yeah yeah yeah exactly
those are the data structures that say
what why what are you supposed to do
with this relay and how often and so on
so you have these different forms you
can specify these and then the whole
object data for the select request is
supposed to consider the contain consist
of many of these blocks defined up here
the point here is we can already see
that this is this leads us to some some
good questions about the about the
syntax about the protocol which are also
sometimes answered in the spec and
sometimes they aren't like is it okay if
we have none of these things in the
Select request so should this actually
be M anyone Combinator or is it or maybe
is it is the idea that you only have one
of these things and have individual
requests if you want to switch multiple
relays so those are some some good
questions that the grammatical approach
already leads to yeah so as a very
simple application we built a validating
proxy for this protocol where we just
intercept TCP stream and run it through
run both the both directions of the
stream through our parser and then drop
anything that that isn't valid and pass
anything on that is and then we connect
a fuzzer to that or something else so
really simple really basic app and what
we also did for this application was to
integrate that with the system called
elf back
which yeah maybe you should do that
intro is in process memory protection
system enforcing the fact that some elf
sections should only be accessing other
sections but not others and so in our
case for the proxy the idea was very
simple if you do put the craft we want
to catch it and we want to isolate
whatever might be crash and presumably
taken over at the a memory corruption
from writing over the areas where Duncan
to write and also wanted to limit full
of the logic code from ever excessive
parole input data because this is the
joke flow director is a UNIX kernel
patch exists for arm and x86 in the x86
prototype village he developed by julia
over there and the arm prototype was
developed by a protector company so we
hope that this thing takes in industrial
computers because the proxy that
revealed was one in industrial computer
we wanted the industry to give us one us
so we took ahead and pray my already
mentioned on board so that with a
certain that this thing was performed
and would run on the same hardware that
does mine this way into substations
it's it involve humor as a part of the
parser obviously and so you okay fine so
one of the things that we are some of
the challenges we faced with this out
back system yeah again the idea is that
we separate the parser logic precisely
from the processing of the of the
message some of the problems were that
well first of all of course your
application has to be designed for this
kind of separation and we kind of did
this or but yeah we can imagine that if
if you if you take a previous
application it might be a little more
trouble and yeah so what we found
afterwards or yeah near the end was that
our memory allocation from that we did
in the in the hammer library was not
captured by elf back because it's just
regular ml ox and elf back at this point
at least doesn't support marking those
as coming from a particular section so
what we can do with modern systems that
allow you to overcommit memory or that
will overcome it to memory for you is we
can say oh we like a very very large
section here and just use a custom
allocator to to pull from that which
hammer allowed us to do very comfortably
we just had to implement this alligator
in the first place yeah but we also
found that the overcommit handle of
Linux will sometimes get in the way
because it it has an accountant an
accounting like sorry yeah counting
system that will say oh I've already
given to you this much memory if you're
going to use all that no I'm not going
to give you more and we actually
we just want the address space we're not
so much interested in the memory itself
we just want address blocks so it would
be useful if we had a different API at
that point but yeah alright so summing
up at the how we kind of validated this
implement this implementation to see if
if our approach actually works first of
all we did lots of unit tests during the
input during the implementation that
also kind of validates the lange starke
approach in there because if if we have
a parser that basically follows a
grammar then it naturally decomposes
into smaller pieces that have natural
unit tests so we had a lot and a lot of
those that got a huge coverage of the
whole parser and we also had some
particular tests done for common bugs on
d mp3 that are well basically always
happen then we did the typical val grind
and also the fuzzing with the first of
all AFL american fuzzy loop which is
covered coverage based and also Aegis is
the fuzzer by adam crane that yeah he
famously used to crash all kinds of d
mp3 systems and then lastly we ran this
thing through different compilers as
kind of a stand-in for the fact that we
didn't do any particular static analysis
but we figured of compiling it with
different systems will at least give us
some something anyway well the punchline
for fuzzy lop is yeah where's my t-shirt
I forgot that one but yeah we survived
American fuzzy law basically it it it
actually pointed to one problem that
that was in Hammer itself which we
subsequently fixed and interestingly
this is a this was due to what lengths
fields and some packets where the packet
says hey I'm containing five million
objects hammer would allocate five
minutes
allocate 5 million objects for forests
and that would be denied by the ml
awkward fall fair so we fixed that so
hammer will only try to allocate the
allocate these as a as a par system and
the second one that we ran into is that
I actually did the the basic integer
overflow a mistake that was one of the
one of the standard dnp3 bugs because
they have this have a wonderful
representation for their particular for
a particular count field so this is
another one of my yeah it's one of my
favorite topics these length length and
count fields so it's interesting to see
that these actually cause the to cause
the two problems we had fun by the
fuzzer all right yeah in the very last
if we look at the line shack approach is
kind of a roadmap towards developing of
such your system we can sum up that
thinking about a grammar and specifying
grandma and deriving a parser from it is
not everything but it seems somehow it
seems to help with everything so that
validates validates that lengths like
worldview and my am I in my eyes yeah
like says the parsers at least parts of
the decompose naturally for testing the
code is easier to maintain hopefully and
it also helps us with separation of
privileges using that elf back toolkit
in this case alright some some downsize
or downsize or potential downsides I
think we should mention is we have
potential impact on speed and memory
consumption with such a library where a
in the speed case i'd like to say if the
current implementation and hammer
because it's because the protocol
because it uses non context-free
Combinator's uses a packrat back end and
that result in for instant or
particularly in these choice
Combinator's
that I showed before being tried
sequentially every option is tried until
one matches this is of course not not as
efficient as one would sometimes like
because you can have things wherever
we're simply all the functions are
listed in a long choice Combinator and
the yeah the the options are just tried
until one number matches where in the
real implementation you'd have just a
simple a table lookup and in one case we
actually do say I think it is what the
function we actually do say okay we're
going to not do it the the context-free
way here but do a do a table lookup
however if it were all context-free we
could just run this through context-free
parser generator algorithm like ll Kol
ALR which we actually have in hammer and
that would just compile this all down to
a lookup table of course and then we'd
have exactly that but we could still
specify it in the nice chromatic away
all right the memory impact there's well
this is a potential problem with
higher-level libraries in general we
have a very generic representation for
the semantics semantics results of the
of the pars and d mp3 goes to through
great lengths to save bits on the wire
so if we have a very tightly packed bit
structure a hammer will blow this up
into big c structs so we haven't seen
any particular problems with this but
it's a potential thing to look out for
and then one question that came up is
can we can we separate can we make
separate parsers out of the same
implementation so to speak out of the
same code that we're we're one of them
simply skips the semantic values like if
in our part in our application if we
don't actually want to do anything with
the packets we might want to just just
only recognize and then obviously this
memory problem doesn't appear or
shouldn't appear
in our current implementation because
the library is supposed to be able to
use for all kinds of things we always we
always generate semantic representations
so this is an interesting yeah direction