howdy folks see more people are
filtering in slowly but surely like to
announce our next speaker good friend of
mine Jon Benson Esquire he's a lawyer
yeah Oh Esquire yeah it's fantastic
magazine yeah and John's going to talk
about when lawyers attack he's going to
talk be talking about electronic
discovery and some of the perils that go
along with it having had to been through
this myself previously it can be a
nightmare so there you go good morning
like no it said my name is jon benson
and set Esquire and and today we're
going to talk a little bit about
electronic discovery I know that you're
probably going to have some questions as
we go through I do ask is I've got a ton
of material to cover in the next 50
minutes just kind of hang on to those
questions until the very end and then we
can address them then what we're going
to do is we're going to go through the
history of electronic discovery what it
is why this is only now really coming to
light and why this is only now really an
issue talk about why the process costs
so much to law firms to individuals to
corporations I'm going to talk about
some very simple things that can be done
on a policy level to control some of
those costs even if you don't anticipate
litigation right now and then I'm going
to talk a little bit about some of the
vendors and some of the technologies
that support electronic discovery and
why that's some pretty scary stuff but
first I want to tell you a little bit
about myself if you don't know me I went
to the University of Missouri in
Columbia where I learned to hate k you
and I got a degree in finance
after that I went to the UMKC School law
and then took the bar exam I passed the
bar exam and was looking for a job and I
really wanted to find something where I
could use both my technology skills and
my skills as an attorney and most firms
just didn't really understand why that
was why that was necessary so you know i
SAT around looking for a job and did
some freelance web design which of
course means I was just unemployed for a
long time after that after running out
of money I went to work for a very large
defense firm in Kansas City doing
electronic discovery analysis work which
is a nice way of saying that I was a
document reviewer which translates
roughly in this age to reading other
people's email eight hours a day I did
that for around ten months well that may
seem like a dream while you're trying to
get into somebody's email trust me it's
not worth it it's dreadfully boring and
terrible now I work for a firm called
Stenson Morrison hecker based in Kansas
City and I am an electronic discovery
consultant I work early in the stages of
litigation and prior to litigation to
help companies prepare for that so now
that you know that I am an attorney and
that I am employed you can imagine
what's coming next nothing of what I'm
about to present is anything directly
from my employer or any other
organization that I've been affiliated
with certainly none of this is meant to
be legal advice to any of you all or
your organization's in this context at
least and while I am an attorney I am
NOT your attorney and of course since I
am an attorney I am not to be trusted or
relied upon in any kind of way
so on with the show what is electronic
discovery and where did this really
large sea change come from well in the
law the civil litigation process is
google is governed in the federal courts
by the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure
and up until two thousand six there was
nothing explicit within the rules to
address electronic evidence whatsoever
everything was conducted the same way it
always has been well finally people
started realizing that there's
interesting stuff there and we need to
deal with the exchange of information
between opposing sides and litigation
and they made a number of sweeping
changes to the rules of civil procedure
which addressed this I want to address a
misconception though that this does not
affect criminal law and depending on
situation this may not actually affect
state law cases so if you are being sued
in federal court in the civil system you
will be subject to this if you are being
criminally prosecuted this these rules
do not apply but there's a little bit of
a caveat about that a lot of federal law
out there involving technology will have
a criminal component as well as a civil
component that's definitely the case
with the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act
and as well as the the DMCA so you can
be prosecuted and then you can be sued
on top of that that's not clear we all
remember oj he was he was criminally
prosecuted acquitted and then sued in
civil court based upon some of his
alleged actions
so up until december two thousand six
there were no provisions that required
attorneys to address electronic data at
all why is that you know we do a lot of
the times that you hear lawyer speak
there are lots of questions and you here
we don't know yet we don't know how the
courts are going to address it which can
be very frustrating so the reason that
you get that answer a lot is because the
common law system is designed to move
very slowly and very incremental e and
that common law system is pretty well
reflected with the attorneys that are
out there they're very old timey they
they like to cling to their to their
ways and they're very resistant to
change and that you know that's fine but
it can definitely create a lot of
ambiguity in the law whenever you have
new technologies coming up and new
things like this attorneys are not
exactly what you'd call the most
technologically savvy individuals if
you've ever worked with a law firm or
worked with your own attorney and tried
to correspond over email I know lots of
attorneys that don't read their own
email they have their secretaries print
them and then bring the moon and then
they actually still dictate on tape and
then their secretaries will go back and
then type emails and send them out on
behalf of their bosses I've got I've got
that I know some attorneys that some are
just now running into spreadsheets and
wondering how to navigate around
spreadsheets which can also be kind of
shocking in this day and age so the
where the where the federal rules
themselves come from these rules of
civil procedure well they come from the
US Supreme Court and this is not exactly
a spry group of individuals that is
ready to embrace new things and new
technology before Chief Justice
Rehnquist retired the average age of the
Supreme Court was seven
one years old so whenever you see new
cases coming up and you have real hope
for some sweeping changes that make a
lot of sense to those of us gotta be in
the trenches of Technology realize who's
going to be making these decisions it's
the I had a professor actually once
refer to it as you know think of think
of getting in trouble and talking to
your family about getting in trouble you
go talk to your grandmother your
grandmother is usually pretty cool well
your aunt and uncle they're probably
pretty cool but there's always that one
grumpy old bastard grandfather that just
hates kids and wants everybody to get
off their lawn think about that as far
as an analog to the Supreme Court in a
lot of cases but technology in general
is really new to compute it to two
attorneys it's just now that they're
realizing that there are interesting
things in computers and and we might
want to take a look at them when we're
going through lawsuits it's it's it's
very frightening because this lack of
understanding of technology is what's
really shaping the conversations
involving electronic discovery and all
of the exchange of data early in
litigation before they bring in experts
and before a lot of people involved in
technology at organizations become fully
involved electronic discovery is the
descriptions are largely driven by
buzzwords the people here in CLE s and
by urban legends attorneys are
frightened of metadata I remember going
through law school and we were talking
about the coming changes and and and how
technology is changing things and you
know I was thinking along the lines of
the amazing things that you can do with
forensics and backing in going back and
seeing what people have done even though
they think that it's all been white and
some of my professors say well no it's
all about the metadata
all about metadata I'm like what the
hell is meant what so you know I start
looking and there's not really a lot of
stuff just describing metadata but it's
all it is is data about data but
attorneys think that it is something
very frightening something to be feared
and you know you this is a screenshot of
a weblog post by this attorney I'm sure
is a very nice gentleman and a pillar of
the legal community but he's expressing
his shock in this blog post that there's
hidden information in digital photos
gasps I mean it's it's it's it's it's
everywhere you know and and you know I'd
be I'll come into it to a conversation
some of the times and it you know the
the questions are not where is the data
how is it preserved how are we going to
get to it it's what are we going to do
about the metadata and a lot of the
times I say well do you really
understand what metadata is and the
general consensus within the attorney
within a lot of attorneys is that it's
track changes in Microsoft Word and the
reason that and in which which is true
to a certain extent but the the fear of
Microsoft Word and track changes comes
from this urban legend that has spread
all around about an attorney that he's
typing up a bench brief for this judge
and he doesn't really like the judge so
whenever he writes the judges name the
first time around he calls him some very
foul name and then before sending it in
to the court he he changes everything
back and sends it in and this judge of
course is this mythical judge was savvy
enough to open up track changes and see
all the things that was the that were
written about him and he wasn't pleased
but that kind of urban legend has spread
and now this you know this is where the
focus of a lot of thought is with
attorneys when they come into new cases
before I move on I want to clear up a
little but some confusion about what
these rules are and what they aren't
these rules are not per se a compliance
requirement like sorry bye
oxley companies don't necessarily have
to do anything new as a result of these
rule changes and most companies haven't
what they do is they change what
attorneys do and the way the process
works so unless you're in the legal
process then you don't necessarily need
to do anything different than you did
before and that's that's leading to a
lot of increased costs for companies as
they approach litigation at this point
that said companies really should be
making changes to their structure and to
their policies as a result of all of
this I think potentially that the rules
of electronic discovery could have a
more sweeping level of change than the
sarbanes-oxley requirements that came
into effect a few years ago and how many
people in here had to had to make
changes or do anything different as a
result of elect of sarbanes-oxley okay
it's quite a few but but most people
haven't had to make any changes unless
you're in litigation at this point in
response to the the electronic discovery
rules the ironic thing of course is that
companies spent millions and millions
and millions of dollars getting ready
for sarbanes-oxley and since sarbanes
came into effect there have been only
two instances of fines or sanctions
against the company for non-compliance
then they came into effect in what
2004-2005 something like that since
december of 2006 we've already had over
60 cases of sanctions against attorneys
and companies as a result of failure to
comply with the new rules of electronic
discovery and the changes have mostly
just kind of flown under the under the
radar and I think that because of the
amount of money in the amount of effort
that had to be expended because of
sarbanes-oxley the companies are now
kind of saying you know we had to spend
all that money now we got this other
going on I don't have to do it do I okay
we'll just kind of deal with it as we go
along so let's move along and will now
talk about how the electronic discovery
process works this is a chart from the
the electronic discovery reference model
which is a kind of a industry think tank
and it's there's a lot of great
information within this chart but it's
kind of confusing so I've got it
simplified over here let's say that your
company gets sued we're going to work
this all the way through litigation a
very simplified state the first step of
course is to say what information do you
have and where is it seems like a very
simple question but of course we all
know that it's definitely not for any
organization of virtually any signs now
I can't find things on my own computer I
could I can only go see it gets even
worse with very large companies so you
have to identify what you have then you
have to take a look at what you're being
sued about and you need to preserve that
data which this means stopping your
recycling of backup tapes a lot of times
coming in and taking images of hard
drives it all kind of depends on what
the what the attorneys negotiate at the
very beginning after that all the data
that's going to be potentially
responsive to the lawsuit is collected
and you can collect in a number of
different ways it all depends on the
case sometimes you'll be having forensic
work done on the other side of the scale
you can have just individuals dragging
over files that relate to a certain
matter into a folder and putting them on
CD and science their attorney it that's
very very common after that the all of
those emails and all of that data needs
to be reviewed for a number of different
things somebody needs to see if it's
actually responsive to the lawsuit a lot
of times you'll need to look at the
documents to see if they're privileged
or not depending on the case they may
have negotiated that certain trade
secrets will be redacted so that
information will be needed will need to
be redacted
it's very very time consuming as as all
as all show as we go on after the
initial review is done you narrow this
down to a production set than you give
to opposing counsel and opposing counsel
then we'll sift through all of the data
that you've produced and eventually a
lot of times years later you will
finally get to trial or you'll use a lot
of this in depositions things like that
so how does this work more in a more
detailed way a company needs to start
preserving data and taking steps to make
sure that stuff isn't deleted as soon as
they anticipate litigation when does
that trigger exactly certainly if you
called your attorney it you can
reasonably anticipate litigation if you
get a threatening letter or demand
letter that needs to happen then or of
course if you get served with you with a
complaint then you'll need to start
preserving data of course does that
happen not in all cases a lot of the
times you'll have some lag which can
lead to data loss which can cause some
serious problems for the client down the
road after the litigation is anticipated
in-house counsel will usually issue a
litigation hold saying to to a certain
number of employees or the entire firm
saying hey you need to start saving this
stuff a lot of these holds are very
broad I'll talk a little bit about some
of the problems that can happen with
that and then the the data is then
collected this is where this is where
the wheels start to fall off as far as
an organization's information the data
is then usually sent to a vendor and
that vendor can be a very large outfit
that will be will host everything or it
can be an individual law firm they've
got to then process all of the
information there's a lot of file
conversion that has to happen the
preferred file format for all of these
documents electronically believe it or
not is not their native form gets
and a half by 11 tiff images white if
because it's very flat you can't you
can't really mess around with it but it
you've run into a lot of problems with
things that were never meant to be on
paper in the first place like databases
Excel spreadsheets you know you you add
that to the idea of needing to go back
and read acts and trade secrets or
financial information out of daily sales
reports that can be thousands and
thousands of pages long it's a very very
time-consuming process so you take a
look at the document you say is this
responsive to this litigation yes or no
is this potentially privileged a lot of
the times you'll have multiple levels of
reviewers so they'll say yeah it looks
like it might be privileged so that goes
into a separate bucket and somebody else
going to look at it later on a lot of
times you'll have some problem files
because the processing is not really all
that effective so you'll have people
going through individually looking at
native files then the redaction process
happens and what redaction is is you sit
there and you draw black boxes on the
screen over and over and over and like I
said a lot of times you'll have
spreadsheets to cascade over thousands
and thousands of pages when I was doing
this actually sat down and I was going
to play some video games and I've
started to play command and conquer and
I got about two minutes in and realized
that I actually physically couldn't do
it because I was so sick of drying boxes
on the screen I just wanted to kill
myself after the after all the
information is redacted everything needs
to be re ocr'd and reprocessed again so
that the extracted text doesn't have all
of the underlying information which then
you want to you want to hide no I'm
sorry I can see it but you can't then a
lot of times you'll have another overlay
applied to it and then finally at that
point you have a production set well how
much money are we talking about here
right for this review process you're not
depending on the case and how big it is
you could have anything from new people
out of Law School like myself contract
attorneys
going through things all the way up to
associates big firms and sometimes even
partners of big firms going through
reading it reading your email and and
spending a lot of money it's a full
hourly rate for your attorneys i
remember how much i was making and you
just a rough estimate i have no idea
what it actually billed to the client at
but you can imagine very easily around
seventy five dollars an hour for a
contract attorney and in a lot of these
situations you have floors and floors of
attorneys building $75 an hour doing
nothing but going through and reading
documents so the cost just starts adding
up so fast at this point and that's
after you've already spent a ballpark
estimate of around fifteen hundred
dollars per gigabyte just to process the
data to get to the point where the
attorneys can start looking at it so oh
here's another one a lot of times you'll
have to deal with backup tapes think
about the cost of restoring backup tapes
and putting them in a format that can
then be reviewed it just it just
snowballs very very quickly a lot of the
costs though are caused by users and in
just how people interact with computers
because a lot of general users were
never taught how to do things
efficiently and how to never do things
properly so one of the things that
organization can do to reduce their
potential cost let's teach people how to
use their email no reply if you're going
to be quoting the entire message below
if it's if it's less than five words do
you really need to send it you know here
take a look at the spreadsheet do you
really need to send a reply saying
thanks because what happens then is it's
not a duplicate message that can be
removed an attorney is going to sit
there and read that email now twice so
you'll sometimes you'll see these long
email strings a lot of the times that
take place on blackberries where you
have just
versation after conversation you know 20
pages long where initially you're
starting out talking about you know a
product or something that you're being
sued over and by the end you're talking
about football but either way if you're
talking about trade secrets or other
products all intermingle with each other
an attorney has sit there and draw that
box over and over and over and over you
know how do you like to spend an entire
day reading the same email thread over
and over and drawing about 200 boxes
over it it's it's nonsense trying to
send links to things instead of just
sending the file you're going to be
creating duplicate duplicates of the
file sending it all around I don't
insolence is I've heard of places who
sent out daily sales reports for the
entire company to all of their middle
management sales staff it's all
cumulative it's all responses of
documents so the day you know the day
after you get it it's completely
irrelevant but it's still sitting there
on your machine and because it's
responsive and because you're going to
need to redact it people are going to be
going through it over and over and over
and over he'll just change the way
BlackBerry's work you know the corporate
executives love to tap away on it and
every single time you quote the entire
message below and yeah it doesn't make
any sense to have to sit there every
time and delete everything if you want
to reduce the overall volume of
information so we you know things like
that here's a good one a lot of the
times in order to identify ways in which
a document can be privileged or not
they'll do a full text search for an
attorney's name throughout all the
documents will be pre flag you can
imagine that in a very large corporation
if you have an attorney named I don't
know Johnson you know every one of these
documents is going to come up as
potentially privileged and so you're
going to have two lawyers looking at
that so here's a very simple idea if you
have in-house counsel who's going to be
talking about privilege and
formation as well as non-privileged
stuff why not make him use two different
email addresses make him use one for all
of his privileged communication make him
when you use one for all the other
nonsense that Creed that could cut quite
a bit of cost out of things so outside
of user education what really can be
done to reduce some of this cost single
instance email is big they that's that's
a very emerging trend among companies to
go to send links not actual documents
use a document management system you
know users will hate it I hate my
document management system they all suck
they're just terrible to work with but
in the long run that's the best way that
you can take care of a lot of these
problems and you further for the cissp
is out there treat litigation just like
any other issue in business continuity
have a plan and be able to implement it
at a moment's notice whenever you hear
from the lawyer that it's time to start
preserving information learnt you teach
your users to delete things there's no
need to have you know your top executive
of course who's definitely in charge you
know he everybody else may have a one
gig limit on their inbox but when he
calls up and says I don't want to clear
out my inbox increase my size to 10 gigs
of course they're going to say yes but
is that really what needs to happen
another thing that you can do to reduce
risk of some serious stuff down the road
is IT people in technology people like
having backups multiple backups and we
don't want to lose the data so a lot of
the times you'll have you know rogue
backups don't you got it you got a DVD
burned sitting in your desk that nobody
knows about that you're ready in case
something happens but down the road if
that's already if a lot of that
information has already been purged the
right way and then somebody finds out oh
wait you've got that Thanks now your
company could be facing a lot of
potential sanctions and maybe some very
bad
the jury instructions when you get to
try now I want to talk about another
buzzword that's data map a lot of
lawyers will now say well we need to get
them a data map going where's the data
map what data mapping is is just an
enumeration of where all the stuff yet
it can come in a lot of different forms
in fact is kind of what I do and every
every data map that's done looks a
little bit different depending on the
organization but think instead of not
what it is but what you want to do with
it and where you would want to use it so
if you're facing a hearing about
potential spoliation of evidence and
accusations of improper preservation you
want to have you know essentially a
binder sitting there of all the
information how you know where it was
originally what the policies were what
steps we took logs narratives all kinds
of stuff it'll get very large but it's a
very effective way of protecting the
company if you're already in litigation
but the beautiful thing is you can do it
before litigation that way if you get
served your attorney just pulls it right
off the shelf and instead of spending a
lot of time wondering where everything
is they can go right to identifying
individual custodians and preparing for
some of the early pretrial conferences
and of course you can't secure
information unless you know where it is
so this is information that could be
very handy to the organization in
general so if you're if you're looking
to try and sell some of these changes to
infrastructure you know like single
instance email like coming up with it
with a with a data map of some kind
pitch it in all different ways that
improve security we can reduce cost of
storage and it reduces litigation risk
you can get inside and outside counsel
to get on board and agree they'll twist
some arms and they'll get a lot of these
changes done that'll make everybody's
jobs a lot easier in the long run but
hey this is a security conference
we're not talking to all business
continuity experts here we want to hear
very frightening things well we've got
some frightening things for you where is
all this data going when I say
production where is it going to go we
already talked about sending all of the
data to your vendor or your your law
firms vendor and so it's going to go
there after that it's going to go to
your law firm then it's going to go to
their law firm then it's going to go to
their vendor so all of the data that
that a lot of the security professionals
are paid a lot of money to sit around
and protect is going straight out the
door to organizations that we don't
trust we don't we don't know anything
about maybe completely insecure it
hasn't happened yet but I think it is
something that is a somewhat of a
forebear was the outfit that was working
for the RIAA they were they were you
know catching users that were sharing
files and one of the corporate policies
was to back up all their email on to
gmail well that you know somebody used
some tool and got he got ahold of all
that stuff and the entire company's
email showed up on BitTorrent so that
well that didn't happen in a litigation
context we don't want that happening
with an entire company's whole data set
and let's let's let's not forget what
data is maybe there's a tendency always
to think about this in terms of you know
gigs of data and just data in a very
abstract way you know we're talking
about people's personal email talking
about instant messaging logs you know
things that go on an email fights with
spouses your HR file in many
possibilities personal financial data of
course there's a whole lot of porn on a
lot of people's stuff and you know on
top of that then you have all the stuff
the business really cares about like
trade secrets financial data all of your
customer data so all of your data for
anybody that you may have interacted
with could be going out to a lot of non
trusted places a lot of financial
forecasts engineering drawings patent
proposals it's you know we're dealing
with beat the whole enchilada if you
will all going out the door all to a lot
of non trusted organizations what's
let's dig down a little bit let's talk
about law firm security like we talked
about earlier it's just in 2006 that
attorneys started figuring out the
computers are interesting right can you
imagine the way that you know how they
approach information security at this
point probably not that great I know my
firm takes it very seriously we've got
it we've got a pretty decent we've got a
decent team dedicated to that a lot of
firms won't and that's the corporate
defense side of things let's talk about
the plaintiffs attorneys the ones that
are eventually going to be getting all
of your data these are a lot of times
one man operations five-man operations
they may not have the money to invest
into a lot of security infrastructure
they may not understand I worked for a
plaintiff's attorney wants and when I
started this summer when when I was in
law school this is 2004-2005 something
like that I walk in and all the client
files were sitting on one machine at a
Secretary's desk that happened we
running windows millennium edition while
she was showing me how to use the
computer it blue screens of course and I
say does this happen a lot oh yeah all
the time at least three or four times a
day well where's the backup backup so
you know I did its extrapolate that out
to a lot of other attorneys and that's
kind of what you're dealing with and
that's where your data is going right so
what about the attitude towards security
in general within the leaders of
ediscovery i was up at a certification
course and one of the attendees getting
a certification in e-discovery asks the
presenter a very very valid question he
said you know I work for this
organization they're very concerned
about sending
our data across state lines to other
places and the response from the trainer
in this certification course was well
just tell them that the odds of this
vendor getting hacked her about the same
as the law firm and they just don't need
to worry about that at all I was I was
shocked i mean i had been very quiet the
entire time but i couldn't i couldn't
raise my hand up fast enough to
introduce the idea of I don't know maybe
had a third party penetration test done
before you send your stuff to a vendor
the woman said wow you know that's
that's a really good idea nobody's
nobody's really ever brought that up
before it's it's and this is a person
giving certifications in this stuff
right so what about these vendors right
now I'll leave you all to make the
conclusions about the potential
vulnerabilities in a lot of these
underlying technologies but let's talk
about them a little bit everybody and
their brother right now is coming out
with a lot of tools to review data and
this is a hot area so great way to make
a buck I mean all you're doing is you're
making a front end for a database so
what what the law firms and attorneys
love and just like everybody else they
love web-based applications you know if
you guys saw the presentation yesterday
web applications are just in general
broken a lot of these applications the
vendors of these tools will they they'll
give you an option they'll they'll
either host the data for you just
overall very positive thing if you don't
have the capacity there or they'll
actually sell it to you so that you can
install it on your own stuff so just
like with with any major software
application you're going to have a
slight lag before between patches at law
firms so you may have some insecure
stuff still hanging out there but but
what about some of these vendors
themselves well they did well okay the
technologies themselves a lot of them
are built on
sequel or oracle databases which of
course are really easy to secure a lot
of firms are tied very tightly with our
friends at microsoft so it's so they're
part of the very big easy target a lot
of the tools will add some flash to it
you know well let's let's add some stuff
like some java components let's let's
have some activex controls in there
what's making sure that we require
things like internet explorer 6 to use
this and let that kind of hang out there
when when these vendors talk about
security because when they're dealing
with law firms they love they love to
talk about it and they say we have the
same level of security that banks have
ssl and you know i talk to these people
i'm like okay great what else can you
tell me well it's the same level of
security that banks have okay so well so
let's let's keep this going a little bit
I was um last last August when I got
back from Def Con we had a jeans day at
work so I took full advantage of that
and and wore one of the hacks or shirts
bright red yes you know very kind of out
there in your face and the you know we
had some people from the vendor up to to
talk to us about some of the problems
we've been having with the database and
things like that and specifically we
were having some problems with some
specific formats not refreshing enough
and I'm thinking myself full you know we
can kind of change the way that apache
approaches individual file format so i
bring this up with the developers and i
said well you know can you just you know
change this in the canoe in the
configuration guy said well i'd be what
what web server is that I was like
bashing never heard of it
okay let's let's push this a little bit
further what web server are you guys
using we roll our own then I was so shy
I had no response because I couldn't
understand why in the world you would
even want to do that you know I may need
security through obscurity is one thing
but if you're having problems with up
time I don't think that you're you know
you're achieving much on that goal so
you know that was kind of my response
one of the one of the very nice things
about being one of the newest members of
my team is that I'm now kind of the
go-to guy for all the vendors to talk to
you know well I'm busy talk to the new
guy so I love asking them about security
and they just give up the goods it's
it's fantastic I was talking to one
outfit and I said well do you guys do
pen tests on the software but before we
buy it or or for your own hosted stuff
the response was well we've heard from
some clients that have had some
penetration tests done that we had some
some vulnerabilities but we we fixed
those after they told us about them and
we don't really do any of that ourselves
so you guys are going to want to kind of
test through software i said so you guys
expect me to be responsible for the
security of your software that you're
asking me to pay for well kind of okay
that's interesting so you know once
against like that here's another great
one same kind of setup I say you know
have you brought in somebody to a pen
test well this time it was what's a pen
test well you know the concept is you
pay somebody to come in try and break
your stuff and break into it that way
you can secure it if you did too why
would we ever have someone come in and
try and break our software once again I
had very little to say I'm just you know
it's like I guess this this conversation
is over at this point I know where we're
going here so here's another great one
for people that
involved in forensics you'll especially
love this or have added any kind of
involvement with law enforcement talking
to this guy and he comes to my office
and we're talking about security and me
coming out and speaking at these things
he's like yeah you know it's interesting
because at our place people send us hard
drives all the time you know we're
processing lots and lots and lots of
data and terabytes of stuff constantly
at no point of but we ever received any
hard drive that's ever been encrypted I
was like well how do you know you handle
chain of custody abut everything just
kind of gets comes and gets dumped in
the mailroom myself what seriously
you're just telling me this you know I
hope I'll be right down so let's put
this even more into perspective lots of
big law firms will host all of this data
themselves but a lots of these vendors
will host it for you but think about it
if you're an attacker looking to steal
some trade secrets commit some corporate
espionage why would we come to the
individual organization at this point
and try and go after your security with
your dedicated security staff when maybe
we can go and try and attack a vendor so
that way instead of just getting company
aid stuff who knows maybe we'll get b c
and d too it's a field day that's a much
bigger target so in conclusion what what
can we do as information technology
professionals to deal with some of these
new issues to try and continue to
protect our data try and control costs
get to know the lawyers at you know your
in-house counsel and if they're around
some of your out house counsel get to
know your lawyers in a friendly way not
just by breaking policy and getting in
trouble either as a company find your
catalog it figure out where it is and
plan ahead for litigation in this day
and age litigation is a certainty at
some point in a company's life cycle you
need to make a plan for that and on the
security and the things you need to
demand more from vendors if if if if the
if you guys know that information is
going to be going out demand to see
third-party reports demand full
disclosure from them nobody's asking for
this stuff right now and these companies
are certainly not going to give it up
you know otherwise you know depending on
your organization and what the culture
is you know it might just be time to get
right with a man and that might be the
answer so at that I think I've got about
seven minutes or so you guys have any
have any questions for me yeah
max 90 is that provide a significant
discovery people close up upper
background and be at that point that
assisted to utilize a policy that's been
long-standing building from the back
estate will you destroy these that's it
that's a great policy a question a
question involves document retention and
document destruction policies and the
example was a 90-day automatic deletion
policy and how effective that is as a
defense against accusations of
spoliation of evidence down the road
absolutely a document retention policy
should be very high on the list of
things to do to adapt to the discovery
rules now what should your policy be it
here comes the lawyer answers again it
depends you know if you're if you're in
the your publicly traded company or if
you're in the stock exchange things like
this you already had that dictated seven
years 90 days is pretty short there have
there was a case where an outfit just
said at the end of the week we delete
everything as far as email goes the
court said that's pretty unreasonable
you know essentially that that's that's
a little bit too short you know in those
instances work with your attorneys and
and figure out those policies but but
work with them and find organizations
that understand electronic discovery and
understand the shaping of these policies
so that they can find one that's going
to work for your individual organization
because they are all different and just
taking it a sample policy off the
internet is probably not going to do it
another problem that can come up is like
you said exceptions to the rule and
especially with who gets those
exceptions made for them ironically in
the ee that you the guy on the sales rep
out in the field
is probably not going to be the one
targeted as a custodian of documents
during a big lawsuit the CEO the
director of marketing all the guys that
have all of the stuff that people really
want they're the ones that are going to
get these exceptions so the information
is still going to be there so you've got
a pound away and make sure that all
these people are actually following the
policy yep
how
I don't know that bid that is that yeah
it I'm not sure you know they believe I
always believe that more legislation is
never the answer for aunt pretty much
anything you know Lee kind of let the
courts kind of deal with it that's kind
of the nice thing about the the rule
changes to the rules of civil procedure
is that it will allow a lot of
flexibility between the parties to kind
of come to agreement it kind of depends
on what kind of level of liability
they're talking about you know being
liable for somebody else's data you know
40 to expect one organization to be
responsible for the security of an
organization you know three times
removing a sub contractor subcontractor
is kind of you that that's a little bit
much probably but it's still something
that you probably need to need to take
into account just from a practical
standpoint yeah and the financial
services are really there further along
in this they've been dealing with it
because the Sox and the big major cases
you'll notice lab mention the single
case before just now most attorneys
found you with cases Morgan Stanley UBS
Warburg Zuba lake they're the ones that
got hit real early with a lot of the big
sanctions with the adverse inference
where a lot of this case law really
stemmed from so any and if you guys want
to know the wrong way to handle things
you know read some of these opinions
read that there's like five Zuba like
opinions the Morgan Stanley opinion
where where there were thousands of
backup tapes that word that were never
analyzed and they found him in a closet
you know they gotten to the point where
they were doing the what's called the 30
v6 deposition where they bring in
somebody high up in IT to kind of talk
about what their structure is and how
it's setup and the guy said
unequivocally yes we've just we've gone
through and we found all the backup
tapes we produced all the information
well he goes home and he realizes wow
that was kind of ridiculous thing for me
to say
I guess I better go check maybe see if
there are any other tapes laying around
the first place he looked he found a box
of backup tapes that hadn't been
produced it only got worse from there
and that was that was where there was an
adverse inference what the adverse
inference is kind of the worst type of
sanction for any group going through
litigation yets and this kind of scary
part for individuals that meant be sued
civilly under federal law is that if the
data is destroyed or it isn't there and
the court finds a number of factors
they'll actually tell the jury okay you
didn't see any evidence of this because
it's not there the fact that it's not
there you can hold that against the
defendant you can assume that what the
plaintiff said is there is there that's
the death knell to any defendant it's
time to get out the checkbook if that's
going to happen so that's you know we
haven't seen it start tap with
individuals yet I think I think that's I
think the adverse inference instruction
was given with torrents by which that's
also another frightening frightening
case that happened just because it the
court essentially set up a judicial
keylogger what was happening in that
case is you had all the people
connecting to the bittorrent tracker and
torrance by said well we don't keep any
logs and the judge couldn't really force
them to turn on the logs really so what
they did was they just required that
everything that passed through Ram
that's right Ram to be retained and when
I read the opinion I had to read it like
three times before I realized deed
before it really set in that yeah that's
that's a keylogger now that's pretty
rare and that was a very special
circumstance the people at Torrance by
hadn't exactly been playing nicely with
the courts or with the other side at all
so we're hoping right now at least I'm
hoping that's a very far out liner but
you never know when a plaintiff attorney
is going to read that opinion
they're going to go to the judge they're
going to have a defense attorney that
isn't really all that savvy and he's you
know all of a sudden you're going to
find out that you need to preserve
everything that was going through RAM
and all of your machines yet had your
office you know and in the end the sad
thing is they won't consult with IT a
lot of the times before these orders are
given no I've heard that sometimes that
the transmission of data to the vendor
from the client started without even
notifying information security so you
know you've got gigs and gigs and gigs
of data just streaming out to an unknown
IP address you know might want to tell
somebody that this is going to happen so
what are the questions you guys have
yeah
well that's that's an interesting case
and I get asked the that's kind of an
emerging thing because now lawyers are
figuring out that there's the instant
message logs exist it's very similar to
that you know it's all in what policy
works for you guys you know if you can
if if you have a policy at the
organization that employees are not to
use SMS for business purposes and you
can show that you don't do that then
there's probably there may not be a
reason to keep around the logs but if
you are relying on that then it needs to
be rolled into your document retention
policy just like everything else yeah
the question is which probably will
happen at some points everybody in this
room you'll get a litigation hold that
is obscenely broad and possibly even
just physically impossible to comply
with you know retain all backup tapes
from now until perpetuity something like
that if you get it you need to get ahold
of the in-house counsel and say I need
to talk to you we need to get together
with outside counsel we need to work
through this preservation be through
this hold because sometimes you get a
present preservation order from the
court which is more difficult to change
if it's just a hold that's been sent you
can tell it's kind of a boilerplate form
front in house counsel talk to them find
out what the case is about figure out
the best way to do it and work with them
attorneys an IT don't really talk very
much I me where were two opposing worlds
I don't think we're all that different
when you get down to it but they just
don't talk and a lot of times in-house
counsel just doesn't understand
technology so you need to help them
through it educate the attorneys now let
them help them understand the technology
then hopefully as you go through Ang's
through things they'll help you
understand the law and why you're being
required to do it in the first place all
right well I thank you all for coming
you guys have any more questions I'll be
around all day so thank you again