all right everybody welcome back to the
last slot in the attack and research
track next up we're going to talk about
ad networks and this is Rafael Rafael
stages us thank you very much so thank
you very much for everyone to be here
still awake for the last talk of the day
I will try to not pursue asleep now
so I mean took today about ad networks
and like how terrible they are on like
how insane what development is nowadays
so originally I was supposed to give
this talk with Quinn Norton who is
witnessed released inviter and was is
slash was UI UX designer
in today's and so she knows stuff about
you are you Excel I have absolutely no
clue about that so I'm mostly developer
for circle so I mostly do the tools
around like Incident Response for my
colleagues at in surface and I'm so you
would have to endure oh my French accent
and she is not here so she will not be
able to help you with that but yeah I
will try to keep to keep it relatively
understandable yeah and we are also in
for sectionals so we will do some
trainings to like a bunch of people like
mostly journalists but also some
companies and so on on information
security on the reason Queen is not here
today is because that's what happened to
her not long ago like two weeks ago she
had like three three discs replaced in a
neck so yeah first two weeks ago she
wasn't even able to move on to come to
the to to pass this year but still she
says hi
so yeah Allegiant of the project was in
New York on six months or six eight
months ago we were giving a training to
a bunch of media lawyers and it turns
out that once in a while you end up
seeing a news saying that some ads
network were compromised by some random
stuff
so unlike it's always really amusing for
like the computing company to report on
something malicious happening unlike on
some some competitor so like you always
have like New York Times reporting on
BuzzFeed being compromised and also
around NBC like I mean it's always
really amusing to see them like yeah
making jokes about the other network
when yeah when themselves are not
compromised and turns out that we were
discussing with those media lawyers and
we tell them you know your websites like
all of them there is like no exception
all of them happening dozens of random
stuff on like on like just ad networks
the timid even knows what they are doing
and like was he like do you want to do
something about it like do you have you
aware of that and what are you doing to
fix it and that was roughly their answer
like they know it's a case but also it's
really hard
there is no tools I know about that was
able to help them just figuring out what
was going on when you have like hundreds
of Hugh arrives loaded come like dozens
of websites dozens of ad networks and
like you want to investigate into it
like just there is no there is no easy
way for them to investigate I don't
don't forget that there are many lawyers
there are not technicians they are not
like Janet instant responders on the
websites are huge they just have no way
to do anything with it with it so they
were like eh can you help us then
because we don't have any way can you do
something about it yeah we're like yes
yeah sure I mean we will need to think a
bit about it because again I was not
aware and I am still not aware of any
easy tool for non-technical people to
investigate those websites I mean you
can talk about like some light beam for
example in in Firefox but that's like
that's not really conducive I don't
really not particularly useful for those
kind of those kind of cases so as I said
we have really complex really big
websites like the home page of websites
like New York Times or both feed our
like Lamont Spiegel can go up to 10
megabytes so you have like a lot of
JavaScript images stuff that are loaded
without any like just you cannot
investigate all of that at once it's
also extremely dynamic meaning that
depending like when you reload the page
multiple times you will have like bunch
of different codes every time like the
JavaScript will be loaded from remote
website and can be changed without their
knowledge
against telepathy components our look
coming from everywhere and most from
news websites most of the stuff part is
software T component running on those
websites other ones that pay the bills
like very few people pay for news so
that's why they have all those kind of
all those are networks running and as I
said auditing like there is no simple
tool to audit those websites if you know
something about it we can discuss the
budget like at the end I would be really
happy to hear about it but there is
nothing that I didn't find anything
that was useful for them and dr. Patel I
and I like I in a lot of cases involving
phishing websites like it's just super
common like Google Gmail login page or
the PayPal like just Google Docs
whatever like so phishing websites are
is just happening all the time well it
is a qualitatively simple like it's just
like a page of students term like
compromise what price that well that
looks like vaguely like the websites are
trying to impersonate or just like
simple ready right - like - domain
controlled by by the attacker but
sometimes it gets like much more
complicated like you will have like
dynamically generated JavaScript that
will do call out to like a bunch of
website and then it's going to be like
you'll have five arising in the hole and
so on or then it loads them like in URL
based 64 encoded content
which is like none of that is new none
of that is completely unexpected but
it's just really annoying to analyze on
to reproduce to reproduce those cases
like if you have like divisions of user
agent you will have different kind of
stuff that will be loaded depending on
like when you do what when you do that
often you do that your society metals to
be a big factor and you will just
sometimes only see the phishing website
once or twice so if your colleague was
doing the same you just you just end up
on like google.com instead of the actual
phishing websites because they were
rejecting you so it's just really tricky
to grip could use and to figure out
what's going on on the phishing website
that is like well done also most of us
have the newest browsers that we have
the most recent comes the most custom
kobzon Firefox and we will have I am
like all kind of ad blockers and no
escapes and so on meaning that
reproducing like attacks on an older
browser
having old JavaScript running and just
like seeing what's going on for like the
user versus reporting the fishing case
to you can get really complicated and
again you can do that like I'm not
saying that it's impossible to do it's
just it takes it takes time but it's
really annoying
so what we want is a way to get the get
the URL run it in like in a complete
browser that interprets everything
javascript loads iframes loads already
writes get all the cookies get all the
headers and just like you need to hunt
in actual browser you want to keep the
data set to generate out of this current
for further analysis later on having a
screenshot of the page is quite nice
because you can actually see what's
going on
unlike the full page because sometimes
you just have like the like the first
like the first page you would have in
your browser you want really you want to
see what is the wall as a whole content
and having the full HTML of the pages
when you load it is also handy we want
some cities easy to deploy because again
if it's something complete like if he
takes you alpha now to set up your
environment to do to check the phishing
website well you may just not do that or
you may just like decide to do it later
and forget about it
we need to have a flexible way to pass
parameters and bytes parameters I mean
user agent mostly because like
relatively often the dependence is
urgent you you are passing to that to
that website it's going to alert you to
different things
sunset looks legit because we all we all
have like VirtualBox running Windows XP
and insight X power 6 somewhere on our
machine and we can just like load try to
load something in it but like as we know
I use this ie6 is not really like
supported by anything anymore it's just
really easy for an attacker to say yeah
just that this one journalist I'm just
going to like read you like you to
Google on you cannot do anything and we
want something that is relatively easy
on that simple for human to use because
again if it's a really complex website
loading a lot of stuff if it takes you
what you just like figure out what's
going on it's going to just like you
will lose time so that's why I found two
tools that are like really cool for that
splash which is instrumented WebKit
meaning it's like a really restaurant
WebKit so you can just send a URL to it
you're going to load everything in depth
at the JavaScript and like the same way
coma chromium would do it let it lets
you define a user agent and you can also
set up the death of of the calling so
you can just like send a URL and like
get the world website and see what
everything everything else is going on
it it will stay can take a screen shot
of the website and it comes in a docker
image which is just pretty cool you just
do not have to install anything because
it's a lot of by thing and yeah if you
just want to run something simple and
fast docker image is going to make your
life way easier
on the really cool thing is that it's
going to return you an HTTP archive file
that you can actually work on the reason
I'm editor library is because copy and
splash so copy is the one that seems
like older website and plus if splash is
the browser it really wants to learn in
a dedicated process and I was like I
want to connect all that stuff into like
other tools so I just want to have like
a libraries that I can just give a give
a URL does the magic gives me the output
I'm just like not care about it so if
you want to just like add in some of you
in another project something like like
that just giving URL getting an output
as an essay a file on processing it just
choose that library it's going to make
your life a lot easier
yeah so I was talking about HTTP archive
document HP archive cache is a standard
that is going to give you like a list of
all the requests on all the responses
coming from all the servers that this
URL was was loading so that's what I'm
going to that like all those requests in
the industry archive as everything that
was loaded from anywhere based on the
URL you passed so it's like a nice nice
way to check that you are actually
processing everything and that when we
will generate the output we'll just like
see how useful that that part is the
HTTP archive contains all the header all
the cookies also any rights and also all
the bodies of every responses of the
wall of the like everything you loaded
as independent parts so you can just
like at the end get get like a specific
body like a specific output like what
what has been darling from any server
you were contacting
during this during the rule of the
so it's really Andy will see later on
for investigation
the thing is on new websites that's a
lot of entries that's like hundreds of
entries really really easily really
often I have some website that look like
the homepage is going to load around 800
unique URLs not all of them to surpass
the website but like a third-party
website we will have like examples later
on so that's like what that thing is
like when you have the wall H verify
that so dumpster fire on that yeah how
you feel when you see the output at the
beginning but let's take a bit more into
in the har file so two to two keys in
those files are really interesting so
very direct URL is going to tell you a
case this URL was reading this is
reacting you to this second URL it's the
location key in the headings HTTP error
and the other one is the referrer key
against HTTP header
the letter F key means that all the URLs
with this letter of key in the header
come from oh I mean it can be can be
modified and so on but it at least gives
you an idea of like where that where the
weather URL loaded comes from so that's
just like looks like a tree right like
you have something loading something
else
that could be resented as a tree so
that's how it's going to look like for a
simple website like I just pasted
situations in Luxembourg in in in my in
my search query is going to vary like me
to encrypt it versus HTTP version of the
website artist loading all those those
subdomains simple clean that looks fine
but while in practice there is a bunch
of interesting stuff going on here the
body erect key can be anything from the
full URL to just the parameter so ever
seen coming after exhausting McCullen in
the URL so you have to when you get the
location header you need to reattach all
that stuff to the URL that was calling
it so final file if you have like you
load second team image in a loop and
then you have in the location header
just a fine name this one is going to be
the path to attach to the original
domain you are loaded on that's all
completely normal way to do Hadi writes
in in a website and something I
discovered is that you can also just
pass a query so if if the location
header contains semicolon on something
it means that you need to get the world
URL cut at the first semicolon on attach
what you hide the location header and
then you have your world URL interesting
I did not know that it's disgusting but
yeah web development
also sometimes the location header will
contain the port number I guess it's
just to mess with you like at this point
you have like something you have like a
URL and they decided to enter of the
port number sometimes eighty sometimes
four four three because you know reasons
I guess so we need to like strip it out
because in my area file the URL loaded
will be like the fool URL and not just
like a part of it so I need to like do
he attach everything to be able to find
out what is connected to what in my tree
and as I said earlier the wayfarer
header can be stripped because just of
course it can so you don't you will end
up with like a bunch of URLs that you
cannot with the attach in your three
anywhere again dumpster fire and then
you have iframes because of course also
life times I mean I didn't really expect
it to be a thing but turns out it's
everywhere you have iframes everywhere
on all those iframes will be able to
load other iframes
would you like you to all to web pages
containing other iframes contain
JavaScript we'd say cookies I'm just
like everything like just pick one and
put it in your lifetime
something will happen but the cool thing
is that flash is going to give you a
tree like format with all your ice
Cream's so you can just like have all
the URLs attach it to your three don't
have a nice view and figure out what is
reading what from your website so that's
pretty handy at this point but tip that
was not enough to attach all the URLs I
had in my har file so of course I end up
using reg access so I just like get all
my buddies of all everything I load I
get I look at the body have I ever just
dragged X looking for URL like string
all my buddies and if I find it I just
attached it to my tree at that point
so it's it works and but still I have
like a bunch of URLs sometimes that I
guess loaded yeah that I get loaded by
by like a JavaScript dynamically and I
don't really know why but they are not
like I don't have any clear if ever one
like where they come from on what has
been loading them so I will just attach
them at the end to my tree as often URLs
and who will see it later on in the
examples it's quite interesting yeah so
I hate reinventing reinventing the
wheels so as I did with a splash on
scrappy - having to use a tree
I found a llama vehicle ET toolkit
developed by a bunch of biologists to
present photogenic trees meaning that
they have the world away that is like
properly running each node of the tree
can have features so the features I
decided to add to attach other type of
the content the cookies
the full-body so I will just like attach
all kind of information to my to my node
in the tree so I can I can then search
it later on all the bodies in the tree
are also hash so I can also search for
hash in in the body and you can from a
specific node in the tree you can also
get ancestors on children really easily
so like when you when you search into
the tree like ET toolkit as like all the
levels all the message to it or that you
just get in your three get a particular
node and on search search in it and use
it to figure out what has been homo a
transform on what is loaded from there
that's pretty cool but still I have at
this point I have a huge tree containing
like I don't know 800 URLs on those URLs
are like can be like hundreds of
character alone so it's really really
hard to represent them directly like you
have huge data set containing pipes of
information but still not really useful
so what I decided to do at this point is
to attach to to like aggregate my URL by
domains so for each for each URL I look
at the sub the sub URLs attached
attached by domains on generate my tree
out of that anti aggregated tree so I
always like I get all the meta
information for each domain so for
vilifies okay this this domain is
loading three URLs on in all those two
URLs I have like ten cookie on how the
content type on everything and again I
made it a library because I like just
making small libraries doing like one
thing and thing so you just a give it
give to this one and hof file is going
to give you an ET toolkit tree
which is already something that you can
start to play with but as you can
imagine major lawyer-like
around 60 plus year all years old lawyer
you don't really want to tell them so
now you need to open I bison and you're
going to like the whole bunch of
commands get this a gif file load it in
load it in the library and then search
like use some like look at the
documentation of et torquetum
do your thing that's just not going to
happen so I really needed to have like
something more like easier to to play
with and I'm much more much like like
much more visual as to to to start to
work on that so that's why I also
developed a web interface on top of it
so on the web interface I will make a
demo just later you have like all the
trees you have like also all the nodes
in your in the web interface you so you
can see like what is loading what which
domain is loading what you can collapse
part of the tree let's say you see okay
this part of the tree is like something
I know I don't want to see it anymore
just like collapse it so it's going to
be easier to to work on you can expand
homes or Mustang your instance to the
full URLs you so you can see details for
each URL which kind of contents I have
in is there any effect on like just you
can have all the information you need
from those particular URLs and the other
really cool thing that you can get the
body loaded by this particular URL out
of the tree so let's say like you have
somewhere in that tree some JavaScript
is loaded you want to just get the
JavaScript to investigate it you can
just get it out of out of the tree which
is pretty cool so I'm going to have a
demo now so if you want to look at it
unlike directly on your own on your own
computer look into the circular tell you
is the domain you can use for that you
won't be able to scatter website because
I don't want you to blacklist the domain
of like one of the items in our pool but
you can really look at a bunch of a
bunch of examples and I'm going to show
you now what I have here locally so so
again this one is as a simple of the
simple one so just like you have like
you have liked all this information here
but let's take something like bit bigger
let's go for let's go for women that if
you remove that the Fair is still
relatively reasonable I mean by virtue
is enabled I still mean looks like that
and that's credible I have works so as
you can see here you have like my
starting point on my starting point here
is HTTP bloom on that affair I can just
do it no into it and this one is loading
this one here which is a very low moan
that remember affair and then this one
is loading a bunch of other stuff the
icon here means that this one contains
night time and I have like a bunch of
other domains loaded not only from drive
time but also from it so and then you
have like then you will relatively
relatively fast recognize some notes
like like that where you have a lot of
stuff loaded out of it so this one is
like muscle time is going to be some
JavaScript that is loading a bunch of
sub component doing a bunch of other
stuff so you will have like images so
images are most of the time gift like
just like the wanting sell gifts that
just are use for tracking
I don't have any way right now to
display the cookies that generally like
you have a bunch of cookies that are set
on generate later on and as you can see
here like all those bunch of haughty
rights going in different websites
I didn't investigate yet and like if all
those websites are hosted by the same
company or just a bunch of different
companies exchanging indicators about
like the users but my assumption is that
for those ones it's it's - to identify
which kind of browser you are using
they just like to direct you from one
domain to the other and do some testing
to just acting your print what's going
on unlike white which which domain you
which browser you're using
so again loom on the Deaf area so that's
also all the UMS I was able to attach to
this particular node and then I have a
bunch of cure hats down here the term
not that I was not able to attach to
anything those ones are I guess
technically generated from somewhere in
the tree on the hair is tripped so I
don't have any way to do it to do
anything directly I mean those ones also
come from ice cream so I don't really
know exactly what happened here but
still that's that's like an interesting
thing and exhaust ones you only have
like four of they're like three of them
times I can have attached to anything
let's still like when you click on those
them on those last name you can just
like look here and see all those witty
interesting URLs that I have no idea
what they are doing
let's be clear like I don't I don't know
like something is going on here but I
need to investigate further it's it's
right now with each wiki to just figure
out how that thing work so as I said
this one is relatively reasonable I have
works
like this one is slightly works but like
no disability okay like at least
everything can be attached to the domain
and and here it goes like relativity but
yeah that's that's okay
like the really crazy one is going to be
Stallone so it's taking a while to load
because I have some stuff to do
and this one looks like that so again I
have here like oh that's my offensive
URLs so those ones are like I was able
to attach them directly to mine to my
node but still I have like zoo sub the
sub part of like I was able to attach
the Savio Al's to one of my often URLs
here so like this one for example like
this domain is I see it alert on
American websites like lyg y-t-dot-com
and this one just loads everything to
like I don't know like I don't even know
what they how what they are doing here
but like that six or seven level deep
and again all that stuff you see here
generally like most of us we use ad
blockers or we use no escapes
so we will not load any of that or we
load like tiny sub part of it but that's
what like anyone else see and that's why
tracking is so insane on on websites
nowadays
so yeah that's on ya such a didn't show
you right now is that you can also when
you when you click on on the domain here
and then you have the URL you click on
it it's going to download the content so
let's hope this one is working yeah oh
that's a just crashed
[Music]
so let's see if something happened here
okay maybe not
why
okay so that's that's a way to to start
investigating and I've seen what's going
on here so these are lots of idea right
loading some Google content later on so
again that's not going to be really
interesting when you have some sketchy
JavaScript you want to investigate
because we're letting your friend you
have like some like I would be an
attacker I find out some of those
websites here that are like something
called something like venerable - like
venerable in here compromised them add
something in like in a JavaScript is
loaded in here and like do it every 10
queries or something like that nobody
will ever notice it like it's going to
take a month before anyone starts
investigates because investigating but
at least funky I have all the parts of
everything loaded and from the websites
and I can then connect it to third-party
third-party services I can start to
connect it to very static and connected
to tools like mist I can do get into
like passive DNS pacifist cell just like
figuring out what all those domains are
doing I can do is also for example to
just see okay who is the owner of like
all those domains and then further on
like work on it and like have an idea
like what is going on on that so to that
at this point is not directly I cannot
really give it to a lawyer right now but
it's getting there like it's a it's
something that at some point we can
imagine giving to non not too technical
people willing to investigate their own
website and at least they can start
pinpointing domains that they are not
expecting to see in that tree
yeah so I'm going to back to the slides
now and then we will have some time
later on if you have like specific
questions of domains you want me to look
at I bet you there will be some some
questions here so again as I said I want
the UI of this tool being like usable
and nice-ish so that's what's good
what's going to happen in the next in
the next questions I'm going to like
have a proper expansion box on the URLs
so I don't have like a URL that is like
on words 50 character long and like
really hard to understand and to read
but I want to have like two smaller
books like that that they can expand the
URLs to compare them it's also useful to
have like when you have like five times
the strength or similar you want to just
like being able to see what the
differences like so being able to expand
everything be able to download all the
contents of all those few are ELLs to
see what's going on and then I also want
to be able to to add more more meta
information in my tree so like if I miss
her hair like if the affair has been
stripped but I found the I found the way
to get to the tree from regex I have
like I want to have like more content
types also displayed like do I have like
Flash content do I have an X a
executable somewhere being downloaded
are like big warnings because like if
Nexus don't read something bad is going
on like Flash content and I want to
connect it to services
fish tank for example just like to be
able to look at known malicious stuff I
want to be able to compare hands between
different user virgins so let's say I
found I use a version of Firefox iPad I
user agent of an old Firefox iPad user
agent of like home that has known
vulnerability and I want to just be able
to see if the ad networks are responding
differently depending on like what I
give to what I what I just load which
kind of content I'm loading and then I
want to be able to also call web site
when I'm logged in for example what's
going on if I start browsing Facebook
being logged in and like having like
what what is what is what will be loaded
at the end and after that I also want to
be able between different ones seeing ok
which cookies are loaded from which web
sites when I learn like when I open like
three or four different news websites
like if I if I if I open New York Times
on BuzzFeed and Guardian which which
tracking network knows that I water was
what I was doing because I didn't
investigate much in the cookies yet but
like the good part is is to reduce the
access to a specific domain for a cookie
but in practice it's open bar for
everyone like most of the time it's just
like the limited access limitation for
the cookies is like star star so it's
like yeah just open it like anyone get
the cookie and often with it
yeah like if I have a cookie loaded like
set by someone in my tree and like read
by someone else I also want to be able
to see it so like being able to click on
the tweet on a cookie and seeing where
it's actually accessed as some other
places will be really important yeah so
yeah everything is open source
everything is accessible on github the
Des Moines stands maybe down oh yeah
like I have no promises here that's
going to stay up all the time it's again
demo version I would recommend you if
you want to play with it I really
recommend you to install it locally on
your machine and just like run it I just
like instant the doctor won't run it
it's going to be like much easier for
you and yeah if you have any like if you
are like JavaScript developer and you
have like specific IDs and stuff you
want to see happening and you want to
implement in the in the web interface
I'm really happy like just I would like
to have contributions and everything
else is why is written in Python pattern
3 so just yeah if you are if you want to
contribute
I welcome pull requests so that was most
of what I wanted to talk about do you
have questions or do you want me to give
a try on some domains yeah
so let's see on the live instance
so yeah as you can see here our seconds
to put the depth on the website I'm the
death of the oyster on the website means
I load the homepage and then I get all
the link in that page containing
sfe that come in that case aunt I go one
one layer deeper if you put anything
else than one it's going to take a very
long time but that's how it looks like
right now I mean it's not it's not that
bad like it's it's I mean it's like at
the same level as a news website but
yeah it's it's setting it's getting
quite a few cookies here I mean probably
all SCP cookies but I don't know like
yeah that's like all the time I mean
that's all sfe that chrome domains
it's a bit but I mean it's it's all fine
like all those ones are just like images
from a city and then you have like other
things yeah I mean some yeah not a city
for sure
but yeah it's yeah I mean it's
interesting to just like start to
investigate and dig dig a bit more into
it
like if I get some JavaScript that might
be interesting somewhere like for this
one I don't know what that is
it's like cookie pixel if that's okay
well this one is probably empty that's
why it's not
oh yeah sometimes I mean still have a
few bugs as you may notice the different
ones this one seems to contain some JSON
somewhere okay well just going to not
work obviously but yeah like I mean do
you have other websites you want to show
I did it and leukaemia syphilis nu so if
you want to take a screenshot like it's
this one you can access it directly from
your browser if you want like it's going
to be just what's right here
so yeah if you just go on the website
you can click here and you will see it
yeah right
oops
let me call someone over the mic that
can answer questions this one is this
one is this one fine yeah like no cookie
at home yeah
[Music]
let's see
I already tested this one at some point
yeah yeah nice
yeah yeah it is yeah this one has yeah
you I mean again it's it's interesting
needs further investigation that like
it's yeah it's it's a good way to start
looking at those website and see okay
what what like what do I want what is
expected what isn't expected on those
websites in a way that it's not just
like a full blood of thing out of in
your in your browser debug or like yeah
debug interface yeah
oh yeah yeah yeah like if you if you
install everything locally on your
machine it's just I don't want to have
people putting like a domain unlike 10
10 level deep and like getting the IP
blacklisted because it's just like
downloading your old website
yeah yes
mm-hmm
yes
absolutely I mean that would be
interesting to start asking asking
lawyers yeah yeah yep absolutely
I mean that's really important that's
like having a tool like that to just
like show them what's going on is also
like making making the problem much
clearer for them so they have also some
leverage on like the marketing
department that just wants to run
everything and get as much information
as possible about their user like if you
if you pick any of those domains in
those pages and start contacting
contacting the website or build with the
D or something
to ask about them that's going to be
really interesting
[Music]
and the wall javascript cleverly I'm
using to displace a tree is called d3
the GS which is a really good library
for that so I just like give it a bunch
of big JSON blob and it displays the
wall tree yeah if it's taking too long
it's also possible that the backend is
just not working anymore I can just do
it I can just do it locally here that's
going to work probably faster maybe some
questions in the meantime are there some
questions
everybody's blown away and shot
sorry not yet as far as I know I mean
may happen but I mean I'm basically just
loading one page like I'm not really
doing anything it's the same as if I
would be opening the URL in my browser
so it's it's not really doing much more
than that I mean it's not doing anything
else than that but yes that's ft it's
yeah it's loading stuff open X that net
is relatively common I've seen quite a
lot I mean you have double-click all the
time I mean everyone is using Google
basically sorry
yeah is there an easy five somewhere I
didn't oh is it
do you mean here it's religion yeah so
it's just yeah no there is no like I
don't think there's an exit file I
didn't see any excess file in the entry
but yeah it's just if that happens I
have like a detection for that but yeah
like some stuff we see relatively often
is also like likely library like jQuery
mini fact because all those JavaScript
stuff are minified all the time so it's
basically one single line of like
everything so when I talk here just like
replace jQuery by like their own jQuery
containing some malicious content
somewhere in the middle figuring out
what's going on is again complicated so
I want to I will I will cut database of
like known JavaScript libraries I just
have the ash and look it up against
everything I have in the tree to see if
I have like known legitimate content so
you can just discard it when you want
because that's again relatively common
what do you mean the trigger like where
it comes from or what the way yeah yeah
yeah I mean I'm I'm trying to figure out
what where that comes from like it's
generally is the way the the debug like
the Developer tab of the browser works
is by looking at the same stuff as I'm
doing with Rafael or also location
header but something is here sometimes
to be removed so yeah that would be like
I need to end to look at to look it up
and see whether come from but like as
everything is JavaScript asking columns
and so on
like it's possible to hide it relatively
easily and I have quite a few domains
that just like quite a few case where
the URL loaded is loaded is dynamically
constructed in the JavaScript on the
server is removed from the HTTP header
and I'm like yeah that just I have no
idea where that comes from
I mean it doesn't seem to be the case I
mean I need to look it up now in the in
the developer tools
I had cases where I literally have no
idea what has been what tray of that
yeah I mean definitely needs improvement
it's like it's working progress but yeah
I mean very important so and I'm
definitely looking forward to yeah to
improve it right now I cannot change
from web interface or user agent so I
put I put like one of the most recent
chrome chrome user agent in here but
like really soon I will just like add
one more field to to just like have a
list of user agents to to run it on
together to to just see the difference
yeah
so the doctor yeah
no no it splash so the tool in the
docker image is called splash I don't
like it's yeah it's like you can just
get it from from the splash developers
yeah yeah I mean I could do that yeah
that's that's true
it's I think a splash can get support
you can continue it like a splash is
like really big ant you have a lot of
options
yeah need to need to investigate a bit
further but yeah that's that's most
probably possible yeah and then you can
also like roadie right like if you want
to like if you want to load a page from
a specific IP you can also like if you
have a proxies and just like use that to
just like give a try from like ft from
from Russia aversion ft from the US and
see if there's any difference though is
probably some interesting stuff here
yeah yeah
yeah so yeah like the idea will be to
able to click on the down here on the on
the legend and just like to only display
stuff with JavaScript for example yeah
I mean it's like it's not limited yet
but yeah that's that's the plan and then
clicking on like when you have a cookie
you can just click on the cookie I need
to figure out how I can do that in the
tree because with more complicated but
like I have one cookie I want to have to
click on it and see where it's loaded in
my tree because that's also going to be
really interesting yeah yeah and you
just like also there are filtering it's
possible to in splash itself to pass
block list the same as the ones you have
in you block for example Michael block
you can just like get the get the list
block list put it in a directory and the
of passage to splash when you do the
query and automatically blacklist those
domains so if you want to use a huge the
difference between with that block urban
wizard and that block here you can also
do that in splash directly
no more questions thank you very much
[Applause]