all of us gated and you know I wasn't
trying to like reverse engineering
engineering what they had over there so
that was a problem at least you were
going to spend you know quite some time
you know trying to you know figure out
how to do skate the results it wasn't
that easy then there are other sites
that require like kind of require you to
have some kind of like state in order to
be able to do queries which is not bad I
mean once you figure it's not that bad
you first request like you know your
first BC decide there's some sort of
cookie in the you know in the page and
in order to actually you know do like a
query you have to you know submit that
that that cookie that they have it's
like you have to be said the you know
the the page beforehand I mean that's
easy once you figure out what the cookie
is so it's not bad and the other one
which is not mutually exclusive with the
other you know with the other two is
that many of these search engines they
try to do a good job at detecting
whether you are a robot or whether you
are trying to scrub the results okay as
an example if you try to get results
with something like cure or double you
get usually you get nothing because if
they don't like the user agent and they
think that if you are accessing the
search engine with you know that kind of
like application well that's not the
kind of visitor that they want okay so
I'm going to discuss a bit of this once
okay so first one I essentially avoided
it so I said well let's try to find if
there is one that is not hard and if
there's not well we will come back here
we didn't have to do it this third one
was kind of like easy I mean just get a
list of strings of popular user agents
so you get you have like you know double
you get or cure to just spoof the user
agent and that's okay and also you can
you know change it all the time so that
it pretends that it's like different
browsers and this one no but so let's
see
what we came up with so what's the one
that I got to work well being I had
never used before but you know when I
was I actually I was researching what
search engines were there and I came up
with this one which apparently is
popular and it's funny because I read a
little bit about the history of this one
at some point they were scrapping the
results of Google and they had issues
with Google now so for me was like
really win so I could scrub their
results now because they had already
stolen from Google so what could we
couldn't now do some justice in the here
well the good thing about being is that
it doesn't do anything of the stuff that
I mentioned before
so you just request the webpage you get
just you know plain HTML did you know
the page is not alpha skated what else
it doesn't require any cookie and you
can't request as many pages as you want
and you never get banned ok well so far
I you know to be honest before including
this here I say well this is the stuff
that usually you don't want to tell
because if people you know use it a lot
it's going to be gone but well so far
it's working so the idea is that I mean
I don't have my laptop in here but if
you use the toolkit that is you know you
can download it we'd get there's this
specific command which is get Bing and
whatever you specify after this is the
domain name that you want to request
name record for ok so what the tool is
doing here when you execute it like this
is essentially just you know run a
search using the keyword site and this
stuff in here
obviously it scraps the results from
their webpage and it opens their results
ok there are a few let's say tricks you
know in the you know running in the tool
like for example if you just specify
this you might get a lot of the same
results right because you are just a
specified
the site and you want to you know
differentiate from one page to another
so for example one thing that this tool
does is like submitting like keywords
different keywords to try to change the
results from the search engine to try to
get different results or for example if
you get some specifics I'd like just you
carry for for example for this domain
name and you get some domain name now we
redo the carry the query but explicitly
excluding what we already got from their
results okay the idea is obviously that
you know we want to you know obtain
different results as opposed to go
through many many many different pages
that all contain the same name so this
one actually works quite well and I mean
obviously you're not going to be able to
get like you know the whole sound data
for like side but for example you can
get this tool running for let's say
about a day and you might get something
between sixty thousand one hundred
thousand top-level domains from some
country for example so I was building
like my own song files obviously very
with you scale but you know at least
having something like you know fifty
thousand hundred thousand dnase names
that I didn't have before
okay again you don't get banned with
this so that's that's a good thing you
can you know keep this tool running even
with you know it's a different queries
at the same time and it's it's okay then
there is this other search engine that I
didn't even know it existed but
obviously the thing here was that I
couldn't use Google because I didn't
want to spend time you know figuring out
what the JavaScript was about so being
worked and I wanted to try something
else I came up with this one I had never
used it in my life I have the idea that
the you know on the background they use
services from Google so it's not that
they have you know the the arm engine so
what are they correct
mystics of you know this search engine
the results are good so you you know if
you search for some you know domain name
you can expect to get similar results as
this results that you get with Bing or
with Google it doesn't obfuscate the you
know the HTML so it's easy to actually
scrap the page the only problem is that
they do ban you when you do many queries
and they are kind of like aggressive I
mean I think that at least I was banned
for like I mean you tried the tool for
you know like half-hour and they might
ban you for more than a day okay so it's
like the extent to which you can use
this command which is you know
implemented is well for you know if you
are doing a pen test of a specific site
died that's okay but most likely you are
not going to be able to use this if you
want to build their you know they all
this own data for a specific zone
because you cannot perform as many
carries and again you're going to be
banned so you use it you know they
detect that you're scrapping the results
and you know for a couple of days you
know you're not going to be able to do
anything with this all the stuff that
was that turned out to be needed I was
mentioning that you know we already have
this tool address six which essentially
allows you to do virtually everything or
virtually anything that you can do in
addresses for example you can you know
analyze patterns of addresses you can
filter addresses you can have like a
whole file with addresses of different
kinds and you can you know ask the tool
to filter addresses based on prefixes
scopes and other things but there were
some more features that were needed for
example think about for a second about
you know the way in which you know you
can print or represent addresses first
of all you have what we call the canonic
format or i don't even know if it's
called economic format but is the more
compact format in which you can you know
represent an ipv6 address okay
that's what we normally do or what we
normally use for everything you know
when you are you know login and address
when you are entering an address and so
on but it turns out that for you know
for other stuff like when you are script
in doing scripts it's actually very
painful because if you want to you know
if you want to for example analyze an
address as a piece of text as opposed to
you know in binary format you know that
compressed format obviously makes it
very painful so what you want to have is
you know an address that you know it's
always the same fixed length without any
compression at all this was something
that was required but you might have
read his paper
David Blanca he did analysis on you know
patterns of addresses and originally he
had implemented you know these feature
himself in the tool so now I
incorporated it so if you are you know
analyzing addresses us you know strings
I suppose in their binary format
normally what you want is to have the
addresses in this way not the compress
it format but you know the long format
you want all the zeros you want
everything in there it's easier to you
know do everything that way so this is
something that is implemented - there's
another thing that you know came up
while I was trying to do this this thing
of you know finding a lot of sites if
you want on the ipv6 Internet so you
might remember that we have the DNS
reverse enumeration in which basically
you start with some prefix okay and you
know based on that prefix you walk the
you know the reverse DNS tree to find
you know names and to find addresses
okay now what I wanted to do is to be
able to automate all this so that if I
was somehow discovering addresses I
could you know come up with the
corresponding prefixes and use those
prefixes for reversal numeration
so this is what this tool here does
address six over there
essentially you give the tool an address
you specify the length of a prefix and
it just sanitizes the prefix de
low-order bits and it gives you a string
that is a prefix okay that's simple it's
just useful to you know to for example
do a script that you know can base on
one address just do reverse enumeration
for the corresponding prefix so what we
want to do again is we have an address
from that address we want to come up
with the perfect so that with that
prefix we can do reverse enumeration
pppp what else so all of this
essentially all of these pieces of of
tools were kind of like needed to put
other stuff together so no ad you know
at this time we have like you know a
scanner on one hand the tool for reverse
enumeration on the other but all those
tools are you know separate from each
other so they require you to be like you
know running a tool getting the results
do something by yourself with the
results so that you can you know use
those results as input for other tools
so the goal here was to try to be able
to automate all this like for example
having a tool that you just give the
tool some domain name or some prefix and
the tool tries everything that it needs
to try to get you the results that you
want okay this is like a zero point zero
zero zero or something version of that
tool meaning that it's certainly not
where it should be but it's a start okay
okay
the tool was named after of course this
is the year of the World Cup and being
South American there's nothing more
important that as that they woke up we
haven't won a work up in the last thirty
years yeah
for some funny reason you kick us out in
every single workup
like you know 2014 2010 2006 well we
should talk about that yeah yeah I
figure yeah that was our last bad thing
is like us we were talking with my
brother we have this belief that if we
cannot get this guy to get us the world
cup we're not going to win they woke up
anymore and since he's in his last days
so we have all our hope on the next
World Cup hopefully we will not play
against us against you again you cannot
kick us out again
but so what is this tool about the name
is obviously for the soccer player and
this is the what the tool does
internally okay first of all what the
tool receives has input you let's say
you run the tool and you give the tool
some hints like information that you
know you know about the site that you
want to do naval reconnaissance like for
example let's say you want to pin tests
aside and you know that that site has
some prefix that it's employing you know
some DNS zone that they employ and so on
so what you do is you give this tool all
the all those pieces of information you
know prefixes and you know DNS names if
you want
and essentially the tool works like this
so first of all you get domains from
search engines okay this is if you for
example if you want to find names
related to troopers you start with
troopers de and you try to see what you
get from a search engine like you know
try to start from somewhere with those
know me
domain names you get ns and MX records
you are generating again more names
starting from what you have so at this
point what's the
is this well the point is this one at
least pony here you at least have some
number of domain names you know the ones
that you got from the search engines and
the ones that you got from the MX and
the NS records okay once you have domain
names here you can of course get ipv6
addresses for those okay so you at that
point you know step number three here
you should be able to have a bunch of
addresses now those services might
already be of use because that those
services might correspond you know to
size that you are already interested in
but obviously the idea is to you know to
get more like get more names get more
addresses so what you do is from this
addresses we build prefixes so if we
have some address blah blah blah okay so
we come up with a corresponding for
example slash 48 prefix for that address
okay
essentially what we do is we 0 we set to
0 all the low-order bits and we shall
and we just put a slash something to
come up with the prefix okay so at this
point in here we have many domain names
we have many IP addresses that we have
already phone and we have a bunch of
prefixes now if we have prefixes we can
do reverse dns reverse enumeration so
this is the step where we go here for
each of those prefixes we do dns we were
Sanu Mauritian and obviously what you
respect is that you're going to get like
a bunch of addresses and you're going to
get a bunch of domain names okay now at
this point you go back to step 1 because
why you might already have like a bunch
of you know dns names for which you
don't have MX records NS records or
anything so you get you know those MX +
s + NS records then again you get the
ipv6 addresses
you build prefixes you do the NS reverse
enumeration again and you go over and
over and over again so the idea is that
at some point you get to a point in
which you don't get any new results so
you stop discovering stuff so you
already go through the same results so
that's what essentially distilled us now
obviously there are a few more bits that
are added to this for example setting
filters and the filters at this point in
time are very simple you can tell the
tool for example if you are finding
domain names I want domain names only in
this zone okay because it's very easy to
get out of your way for example it's
quite usual that if you have a domain
name many of the name servers might you
know belong to you know DNS zones that
are totally different like totally
different from what you are interested
in so what we want is while this tool is
finding your names and addresses it's
okay I only want I want to focus you
know on the DNS zones and on the
prefixes that I know correspond to the
site that I want to scan I mean if you
don't do that eventually you might be
you would be learning you know dominant
from all over the place same thing with
the prefixes okay you might be getting
prefixes that correspond to completely
different sites so the tool lets you
very easily specify two things domain
names and prefixes and the tool limits
the result to those prefixes and domain
names so whatever it finds even if it
finds you know domain names that don't
correspond to what you're interested in
same thing with ipv6 services they are
discarded okay
[Music]
essentially they are this is like a
preliminary version I mean there are
other things to include and you know if
you wanted to have to say it like
improve the tool most likely you do it
much of this stuff in parallel so now
it's serialized
so you go like you know one step at a
time and you know honestly speaking you
don't really need to wait for one step
to actually to proceed to the other one
in particular there are some you know
some steps that can be slow like for
example getting domain names from search
engines can be slow particularly if you
want to get many of them so right now
what we do is we limit the time that we
spend for example with a search engine
so that we get some domain names and
then we can proceed but you know at some
point what we like to do is to have many
of these things in parallel like having
you know the tool look at search engines
at the same time for example do DNS
reverse enumeration and have for example
different threads or processes that are
always you know providing information
for for the tool to the side people oh
yeah are we
so the goal was to I might what we might
do because the goal was to do like a
demo okay so what we might do if we have
like since we have like the break in
between after we do the question stuff
you know we can finish with the
presentation I can pray a little bit so
that I might get the laptop to work and
or you know somehow figure out how to do
it to you know show some of these tools
in in action okay the tools are
available at this website okay so the
everything that I mention is already
there any questions questions no it
isn't
nobody so then I would suggest we are
going into the coffee break now and we
both tried to fix your laptop so that
you can show the demos afterwards yeah
cool okay thanks and enjoy your coffee
break
[Applause]