all right from toothbrushes to CCTVs so
thank you very much as we all know we
are watched by toothbrushes now also IOT
cameras so I'll be talking about IOT
CCTV devices and there are miserable
security okay first of all I'll show you
my to-do list for today as at first we
will talk about a little bit about me
Who am I what I do and then we'll switch
right into IOT CCTV devices and their
security a little bit of history and
yeah okay
right after this we'll switch to the
device itself I will show you how I
found what I'm presenting today and how
is it how easy is it to to exploit it in
a new way because this device is rather
boring we all know all these devices
terrible insecure and exploitation is
trivial okay so about me I am I started
to learn weapon application security at
the age of 14 so I'm quite a long time
in the information security industry
already and I got into infrared
we are back bounty programs and I'm now
working at collide I TS as an IT
security consultant and head of
offensive security department
okay now as mentioned - the IOT security
CCTV history okay those devices have a
long history of being compromised so we
can I don't know if you can see about
the first article I found was in 2016
and was not ticked by brian crepes he
talked about AI IP cameras ddossing all
around and destroying the whole internet
yeah that continued and even led to a
web crisis okay now we'll look at the
device itself let me show you the device
so that's the device we're talking about
it looks really innocent doesn't it okay
yeah the device supports Wi-Fi and
Ethernet connections so it's really easy
to get into your network it's has
subtropics support and microphone and
temperature and motion sensor so it's
even advertised as an awesome system so
you can deploy it into your home and
yeah I don't know what you wanted
watching the burglars at your home or
you aren't able to do anything anyhow if
they are already in your home okay
it has a OS and Android app ok I didn't
look at it but it might be interesting
also ok how do you attack such device
first of all you do enumeration in
relation is key so you end map it you
really read the manual yeah you do it
you check it you you use it as a real
customer so you deploy it and you check
how would you fail at something and once
you test it every thing every feature of
that device you get an idea how the
device is working ok and the basic
results basic access authentication is
used so somewhere in the device needs to
be a hash password you'll find it but
that's later ok
week before credentials I think admin
and no password is used so but I found
out a lot of customers change the
credentials okay no input validation or
CSRF projections so there are stored
cross-site scripting vulnerabilities
everywhere but yeah okay exists as is
yeah boring ok CSRF is boring too so we
want remote code execution ok now we'll
look at the firmware the first tool you
you would use to get an idea how the
file system is working you use pin walk
you use pin walk to extract from press
data and hopefully they didn't obstacle
it somehow or yeah in this case it was
pretty easy you could use pin walk - e
to get to extract the whole compressed
data files you find in the binary blob
and it's yeah not really a big deal ok
you can you can also combine combine it
with DD and gzip and Adrianza
because sometimes bin work is a bit
unreliable so you need to use pin work
for detection and Jian sip and DD to
split files ok
now we are in the file system we look
for juicy files it's yeah it's a
standard Linux system so check the check
if you can find any private keys or
password hashes make a list of users if
you find them ok but we checked if we
check the camera before somewhere it
needs to be there needs to be a HTTP
MIDI file because basically says all the
authentication is used so ok let's have
a look maybe we can find it
because IOT is famous for bacterial
counts you can almost you can find in
almost any IOT device and back to our
account so I was thinking there must be
one so I need to find it ok but it
wasn't that easy I looked around and no
HTTP read if I was anywhere because it
was generated later of course the user
sets its own password and then the own
password is hashed and put into the HTTP
APIs VD file so yeah ok then c'mon ok
but let's try harder there needs to be
somewhere if a bacterial count is there
there must be a string somewhere and in
the binaries and often the binary is
containing those strings other pests VD
binaries so the bin HTTP VD a binary
order the path VD dot CGI file ok will
create a short but I know that list of
the web strings really not something
that special ok
simply piped in the text file no problem
okay but now we looked at the firmware
yeah you want a shell so we need to look
at it if you can find a common injection
because IOT and common injections
okay best friends so we need to find and
check all fields where it might be
possible to find a common injection
often those things are hidden in their
server parameter is used or as a SSID
parameter and bingo SMTP server and SSID
parameter on VLAN site CGI and SMTP set
CGI were vulnerable to a common
injection and of course that IOT it's
always route okay so I used been busy
box reboot but I wouldn't recommend it
anymore
because what happens is the camera tries
to connect to the SSID you inject with
your proof-of-concept at every start so
the parameter containing your reboot
payload gets executed every time the
camera starts so we have a really nice
boot loop and sometimes the reset
functionality isn't working at all so
you need to send it back to the vendor
good luck explaining how you got into
that situation okay but you can use
obviously different comments okay
because we check the software and
eternal service installed so awesome ok
we need we body found the payload and
insert the terminal server
insert the telnet server to start it
because it's not available at startup so
they didn't up so hard okay so we
start the talent server and connect via
talent to it
okay now did revises started everything
is running okay the HDP 3d file is
existing because the user defined is his
own password okay
so and there we go admin and supervisor
admin reno admin that's that's our
that's already right man
okay that supervisor supervisor nobody
has heard of supervisor
no no word in this manual mentioned
supervisor okay that's our back to
account and of course hash badly so we
try to break it and we created our word
list just 30 minutes before and because
of the string is because the string is
in the binaries we get it and it's
supervisor dangerous so dangerous nice
they knew what they were doing okay
let's put it all together into a quick
python proof of concept so you see it's
not really rocket science you see you
know you payload SMTP port but that's
not that's not really the basic base fee
on the base64 encoded credentials okay
yeah boring that's boring that's remote
code execution
we got routes we are telnet but that's
boring I wanted it to be a bit more
special so okay
exploitation let's look at it we have
like 100,000 affected devices directly
connected to the internet but yeah if
you only pull 100,000 devices that's
also boring we want to go for all of
them so okay
maybe it's possible to export it
indirectly what about the browser what
about combining it with JavaScript might
be possible to submit the post request
containing our pay notes somehow hmm I
did a bit of research and yep it works
but first of all let's check the boring
exploitation video
okay so yeah we sign in just to show you
how it looks like
then a small nmap scan to check that the
tenor part isn't already open so the
talent server isn't running okay now we
execute our Python park
waiting a few seconds because yeah the
CPU is not the best
yeah voila the teleports open the ten
servers running and of course configure
password less so perfect we'll just use
root and we are in
yeah that's working but boring
okay let's have a look at the and
indirect exploitation way I think
everybody knows brute logic he's famous
for his XSS and CSRF parks and his
research okay he last year in June he
talked about embedded credentials being
dead because Google Chrome disabled the
feature that you can sign in into a
entry device by by supplying credentials
in the URL like yeah admin admin at
device so okay that's that isn't working
anymore for image tags or iframes yeah
that bit set but they missed something
okay you can use J's reckon I don't know
if it's already known I'll explain a bit
how it's working it uses xhr and
WebSockets connections - yeah to find
all the reporters open closed or
filtered and how is it working it checks
how fast the ready state property is
changing and if it's changing in a fast
way you can be sure it's open and if not
you can be sure it's filtered or closed
okay that's not really working reliable
on Linux but it's working pretty awesome
on Windows in Chrome okay then you will
use image based fingerprinting image
directories on IOT devices never
password product password protected so
you will choose an image file that is
somehow special to the device the logo
of the vendor or whatever you like okay
and then when you put some JavaScript
together to outer submit a form once the
device is detected
okay so shouldn't be that hard okay
let's show
okay first we verify the Tanner port
isn't open isn't running Google Chrome's
up-to-date so I'm not showing any all
software here okay and that's our POC
website that's a nice video and you need
to watch it just for a few seconds so
you need to stay on the website because
a network scan is running in the
background
searching for IOT devices in your
network okay so that's running a bit and
all the debug information shows my
network is not really active but it find
that IOT device soon okay the problem is
here if you have a large network it will
take ages so you need to find a way to
yeah better guess the range where the
IOT camera is located or for consumer
device is that perfect okay
easily you can implement it in an
exploit kit or something like that yeah
should be working perfect but
incorporates networks yeah you need to
find something different okay yeah it
detected an app device and it exported
it successful okay the user won't yeah
he will notice that the page changes
something different but I don't know if
he will recognize what is happening at
all
so we can see the telnet port is open
again we have root access and that's
really awesome because we can reach
every IOT device and every consumer
network now and just the limiting factor
is time so we need to get the people
long enough on our mouches website okay
yeah as I told you and the disadvantages
yeah are there you need to have a chrome
and Windows OS to target because on
Linux you need to have different times
because the ready state property changes
in a different manner okay
the advantages are obvious you
significantly increase the targetable
devices that's really awesome and it's
easy to to build exploit and
fingerprinting modules so you had just a
few lines more JavaScript and yeah you
added a different device different
exploit yeah it's yeah really awesome
okay the impact yeah it's pretty
worst-affected renders I didn't even
know how many are there so we have like
five renders where I found a logo and
like 20 shiny Chinese renders with no
contact information and yeah that's a
just a few vendors I found okay
patches yeah EDI ot only sorry dia
provide patches and yeah one nice
feature of those devices is they miss
now to update feature so those patches
never will reach the devices so yeah fun
there's a patch but nobody will use it
okay
[Music]
resources I found the OVAs resources on
IOT analyzers pretty awesome you can
check those out yeah if you don't know
bin work you can check it out it's a
really nice wiki on github yep you can
check out my block and there you can
view the pox on check your it exactly
okay if you want to contact me you can
contact me anytime I'm working at
carbide IT s we are offering pen tests
and red team assessments so yeah just
give me a call any time stay safe robot
any questions we have quite some time
left for questions
is it possible to patch it on your own
so you have a way to own it can you
change the passwords can you close the
ports yeah I don't know if you can patch
it without breaking some features yeah
you could remove the bacterial count of
course yeah you could do that but that
wouldn't remove the common injection
vulnerabilities so somehow a little bit
vegetable further questions
all right then thank you very much again
thank you
[Applause]