okay so the next talk an hour
it's a kind of very special one we have
three guys of erw here free twat
Heinrich and Nena and they will present
or talk about a very interesting topic
at least from our perspective it's about
development developing a metric yeah how
secure is your overall Active Directory
and I think that's kind of new because
at least I'm not aware of any kind of
comparable metric for that so Friedrich
Heinrich Nena your time on stage thank
you Michael
welcome to our talk developing a
comprehensive Active Directory security
metric our agenda will be this one after
a short introduction with the problem
statement and why security metrics we
will focus and how we develop in Active
Directory security metric we will
describe where we stand why we want to
go and what are the lessons learned
together with me I hear two of my team
colleagues Heinrich and Nina and we all
perform security assessments of
different kinds we perform audits we
perform pen tests we write hardening
guides we write security concepts for
Active Directory and Microsoft
environments helping our customers to
build a more secure Active Directory and
now after having this great overview
from Sean I think it would fit quite
good
to speak a little bit a little bit about
the possible Active Directory metrics I
would like to begin with a short memo
the text of the memo was taken from from
pragmatic what's the title exactly
pragmatic security metrics from Gary
Hills
it's a highly recommended book and he
introduces posing some questions in this
memo Dear John
I'm under renewed pressure from the bots
to clarify a few things about your
budget proposals for the financial year
ahead please don't you address the
following issues in writing before the
next board meeting a we have spent a
small fortune on information security in
the past three years
naturally this seemed justified at the
time but it is perfectly reasonable for
the board to ask what we have actually
achieved in the way of return on
investment to date can you put a figure
on it can you demonstrate the value of
information security B how does our
information security stack against our
peers in the industry how secure is our
active directory and how secure do we
need to be some of the most cynical
members of the board are starting to
express the opinion that what we are
going that we are going for gold
when sever will do it I must admit I
have some sympathy for that viewpoint
so if budget cuts are necessary in which
areas can we safely trim back on Active
Directory security spending without
jeopardizing the excellent progress we
have already made looking forward maybe
three to five years can you please give
us a clearer picture of how the
information security management system
will pan out probably would say
congratulations for this kind of MIMO
what do you feel as an ISO when you
receive such a kind of memo and such
requests the kind of in this position
uncertainty you become headaches why
this could be a question why do you feel
like this until now you probably have to
a big extent ex trusted to your gut
feelings
do they have with respect to numbers
that is where security metrics came in
place and with what what you feel the
uncertainty the fear is because of the
lack of knowledge the lack of knowledge
based on numbers you have and that's the
reason we're securitymetrics enter
I like the tittle and I I like the book
therefore I recommended replacing fear
uncertainty and doubt only if you know
your state you will be able to improve
it and you only know it if you are able
to measure it in a meaningful way as lot
carrying set to measure is to know so
that's from a very very general point of
view the reason for security metric you
may ask why Active Directory
securitymetrics first reason because it
doesn't exist as as to our knowledge
until up to now there is no Active
Directory security metric of course you
there is the security event lock there
are hundreds of thousands of events that
might be relevant to some degree or not
but you don't know how to measure them
so our goal is to design a well-defined
Active Directory security metric that
looks at the crucial security sensitive
measuring points
and that having the crucial security
measuring points taking into account
tries to measure them in a meaningful
way based on numbers not on gut feelings
I don't want to blame gut feelings
because if gut feelings are based on
long experience in your environment they
always a good indicator but if you
remember the memo it was not the
question for gut feelings
it was the question for numbers and as
we say in German Zionist Namas don't lie
so you have a better chance with numbers
the metric that we are developing is
intended for Active Directory experts
and personal it's not intended for
managers but the important point is in
Active Directory expert with this metric
might be able to present something
meaningful to managers and so the reason
is to get knowledge about the security
state in your Active Directory in a
comparable in meaningful way to doing so
we had we have to go a little bit into
the terminology of metric as the Oxford
Dictionary defines metric is a system or
standard of measurement and the
well-known terminology we will use is
the measure to measure for the measuring
action the measuring points are the
locations where the measurement is taken
for example the height of the dog the
measurement itself is the value of the
measuring action it is the result
of a parameter for something eerily
expressed and defined in units in
well-defined units such as the height of
the door is 2 meters and finally the
measuring instrument in short is the
device that is used to for measuring of
course we will adopt this terminology
for Active Directory security then we
found it useful to divide to define key
security indicator that's a term defined
by us and it is adopted from the key
performance indicator but we thought
first we thought of using this term but
then we thought that performance
measuring M at least don't have so much
to do with security measurements of
course you might be interested in the
performance of the replication of your
active directory but that's another
thing so we we decided to define key
security the term key security indicator
the key security indicator is in number
or a percentage it's a value with
respect to the security item on active
directory we will give some samples and
we will describe where key security
indicators might be derived from they
might be right they might be derived
from findings respectively their
corresponding security best practices a
common security best practices to have
no end-of-life systems in your
environment especially in your active
directory so the corresponding key si
would be the number or percentage of
end-of-life systems still in use
Kier's eyes could be derived from
professional experience as well
the sample recommendation is have the
secure configuration of your admin SD
holder object or a secure configuration
of your domain object always secure
configuration of of your domain
controller object the corresponding
corresponding ksi would be the number of
accounts with read and write permissions
on the object that differ from the
default this could be a good key
securely in the indicator they could be
derived from vendor recommendations as
well and one of these recommendations of
course is to have if possible no disease
of your internal Active Directory in the
DMZ so the case I most simple would be
number of disease of internal Active
Directory in the DMZ what are now the
prerequisites of a well-designed
Active Directory security matrix first
of all we have to have a good metric and
then secondly this metric needs to be
well defined with respect to Active
Directory so we would like to define
what are attributes of a good metric
first of all the results need to be
consistently measured that is if you ask
two persons of the same environment the
same security question the answer should
be the same that's often not the case
therefore you will probably gather the
information via a script that gives the
same result then the information that we
need together should be cheap together
cheap together
implicates in our case that the
information can be gathered in an
automated way and for example with lease
privileges if you only need standard
user rights together a lot of
information that's far more preferable
then using admin or domain admin rights
if you want to have domain admin rights
the active directory responsible of
course will ask why
then the result should be expressed as a
number or percentage and not on a scale
the scale would be for example from one
to five and one would be very low and
five would be very high and and you
could ask for example the operation sky
how good performs our patch management
could you give me an answer on the scale
from one to five he probably will say
it's a four we are not at the best state
but we are quite good and then you ask
the security guy and he says hmm it will
be only a three so this is this is
another sample for information that is
not consistently measured and that is
not expressed in numbers that is for
example in systems that have a certain
patch not applied the last light
criterium is contextually specific that
means the information must say to some
something to someone who is who works in
the area for example if the information
given would be 50% of our systems have
security state slower lower than the
default value this is a very general
information you can't what do you do
with this information it's it's it's
nearly worthless but if you give the
information
50% of our Windows servers in the US
site have UAC disabled that's already
acquired good information and it's
contextually specific enough to say
something to the person prerequisites of
a well-designed Active Directory
security matrix are the measuring points
must be chosen very precisely and very
carefully if you look for example F on
the event log capabilities of Windows 10
on Windows Server 2016 you have it to
tremendous amount of information you
could be really you could be literally
knocked out by this information so you
have to choose and define very carefully
at what security sensitive sensitive
points you will have a look for us as an
Active Directory team that's a good
starting point
because you already know why we have to
look but then the real work began
because it's not sufficient to know why
you have to look for you have as well
well-defined measuring methods and I
will give a simple example we will
elaborate on this later on how do you
measure the security of a UAC
configuration USC has ten parameters to
be configured so it turns out at this
point it turns out to be difficult and
the laborious part of the work began I
am a short disclaimer the metric is
still in progress
we are not presenting but we are
developing a security metric and we are
not developing
kind of security monitoring framework
this could be a step further on later
but first we wanted to begin with a
security metric so I would like to hand
over to highlight okay so in the next
section we want to show you how we
approach the development process of an
Active Directory security metric and for
you to better understand us we have to
go a step back and look at one specific
project that we had before the actual
idea of an ad security metric so one of
our customers approached us with the
project requirement that we assess more
than 50 international ad forests in a
way that was quite similar to an active
directory audit and from the get-go some
goals and requirements were pretty here
for us so we swear later on also
significant for the actual performing
for the actual performing of the
assessment so our requirements were that
we standardized assessment methodology
as much as possible so that we can
rapidly gather and analyze the
information of multiple ad environments
we also knew from the beginning that we
most probably won't get direct access to
any of the active directories that we
assess and the assessment should take
place in a way that we require the least
possible privileges so we don't need to
go with domain admin privileges in every
single environment but our only using
for example standard user permissions
and but at the end we still wanted to
have data that enabled us to
meaningfully assess the security level
of one active directory and at the end
the security of all active directories
that we wanted to assess so you might
ask what does an environment of the size
look like if you remember our talk from
last year we have shown you already
shown you the overview so here you see
most of the active directory forests and
all of the trust relationships between
the forests
like I said our goals and requirements
that we set for ourselves had some very
broad and general implications that we
had to adhere to during the whole
assessment period so it was clear that
we had to define all possible findings
ratings and recommendations beforehand
so that we had more or less aesthetic
framework that was applicable to every
single Active Directory and we had to
define clear guidelines for everyone
that was performing the assessment so
that different people would still come
to the same conclusions and would
identify the same findings and what more
or less have to report in the same way
at the end and of course we wanted to
automate as much as possible just to be
most efficient but also to be very
consistent and less error-prone what you
have automated and it works in a good
way it will most probably provide the
best results and also with the
automation approach you you remove human
interaction as much as possible and the
last thing I already mentioned is that
we wanted to perform the assessment in a
way that we do not need necessarily any
high privileges in Active Directory
itself we have seen in the talk before
that often the tools or appliances or so
that you use in Active Directory
often require domain admin privileges
but not for for a very specific reason
okay
is it coming back
okay sorry for that yeah so we wanted to
limit the permissions that are needed
for actually performing the assessment
and for one this of course raises the
acceptance of the people where we
performed actual assessment and it also
limits the discussion with
administrators yeah what were the actual
assessed areas that we had to look at we
did not want to only look at the
technical configuration of Active
Directory but also wanted to incorporate
stuff like the design actual processes
as much as possible so we had to ad
security architecture we of course had
ad security configuration and also ad
security processes which represent your
organization operation to be able to
assess all of these areas we had to
create some tools that would enable us
to do so and the first thing that we did
was to create an ad auditing question
here so that we could gather information
about operational processes and also
about the design in a way that gave us
the possibility to yeah come to a
meaningful conclusion and this question
yeah covered five areas of ad security
that we defined that ranged from the
documentation to passion vulnerability
management and to something like
monitoring an incident handling we also
developed several ad auditing scripts
all of them were partial based where of
course were mainly intended for
gathering configurational data from
Active Directory and also to a certain
degree already interpret the data that
we collect so we ourselves had as less
effort as needed to compile the actual
report at the end and in a way not
really a tool but what also had to be
defined where all the findings that
could potentially come from the
questioner and from the script so from
our experience and in discussion with
the customer we
defined a list of 34 findings that were
later on could be possibly be in reports
and half was from the audit script and
half was from the questionnaire and the
findings themselves were predefined but
at some points it was necessary to
modify it slightly so that it better
represented the active directory that we
that we assessed the presentation of the
results was quite basic we had a
traditional report for every ad
environment where we had the typical
parts of a report the management summary
all identified findings of course
ratings for every finding and also the
recommended controls in addition there
was also an excel file which consisted
of basically the same information but
with some additional infos
like statistics which domain had the
most findings and something like that
and we also had an overall report which
tried to actually create all of the
results we had up until this point and
also some graphical representation of
all of the findings so what have we
learned from this project for ourselves
at first it was that the assessment and
the report of course greatly benefited
from this standardized and automated
approach but later on we also realized
that some characteristics of a good
metric we are already met by this
approach so the data was chipped
together because we used a question a
quite basic question here which was
complex in the evaluation but the
question in itself gives you data rather
easily and also the script being in this
case only run with standard user
permissions also gave us a possibility
to cheaply gather Active Directory
security configuration data and what we
also realized later on that in in great
parts the results that we are collected
we are also consistently measured which
is also a characteristic of a good
metric because if we run a script it
gives us the data that we need this is
already consistent
measured so but we also had to realize
that the traditional assessment in in a
style of an audit has some inherent
problems if we look at the direction of
security metrics because the findings
were more or less treated independently
in the management summary you of course
tried to correlate the findings and
present them in a way that they play
together well the ratings for the
findings are quite subjective if you use
a traffic light scheme for example what
is the actual difference between a low
and a medium rating it is based on the
experience of the security professionals
that perform the assessment but it's
quite hard to measure in the context of
a security metric the reports in turn
were also interpreted by the client or
by the customer so this could
potentially lead to some
misunderstanding if you have very
specific numbers that give you an
indicator for something it is less error
prone to such misunderstandings and what
we also often see is that the customer
takes parts of the report or of some
other result documentation and gives
only parts of the report to specific
persons and this can also lead to the
problem that the people cannot make
sense of this part they received on
their own without the knowledge of the
whole document and one of the biggest
downsides that we have identified over
the time of this project is that the
results did not really allow for direct
comparison of the different IDs so you
of course had numbers like how many
findings does this ad have how many
funnies does this ID have you could
compare them but do more findings
automatically mean that it is in a worse
security state if you have only a few
findings but we were very high rating
does it equal a lot of findings with a
low rating so
it was very hard to compare and it at
this point idea for an ad security
metric was born and in the next part
here we want to show you how we actually
came from the results of the project and
the lessons learned from the project to
the actual security metric because we
did not want to start at zero we have
seen that we have we already have
something that can be reused for a
security metric and the idea then was to
translate the audit findings into
security metrics and our audit findings
I already mentioned some of the problems
audit findings do not work that well in
the context of security metrics the
results are not always consistently
measured if you have a question here and
there's a user-defined text field how do
you measure this in a consistent way in
this text field there could be anything
the results are not always expressed as
a cardinal number or percentage if we
come back to the ratings we have
something like low medium high these are
only qualitative labels but what exactly
is the difference between low and medium
medium and high and so on and this is
also a problem of the next thing that
stands on yet results are not expressed
using at least one unit of measure if
you have a qualitative qualitative label
it has no unit it's just a word in this
sense and yeah so we had to define a
process for the correct translation here
we have an overview of this process we
begin with our findings that we have
defined before and from these findings
we abstract the actual underlying
security problems these are very general
very broad at first it it serves the
purpose for us to better understand what
the actual problem is with this finding
and on the other hand we also abstract
one or more measuring points
when when we performed the assessment we
already had to know where we have to
look at to identify if this is a finding
or not so in a way we already had our
measuring points that are necessary for
a security metric and from the security
problems we when have defined
yeah well-defined security question
questions which at the end will lead to
our case eyes and if you measure your
measuring points you of course receive
some sort of measurement and the
security questions you when try to
answer with your measurements and in
many cases this is not possible after
the first definition of your secure
security questions questions and
measurement measuring points so you have
to re-evaluate both you have to look at
your questions and you have to look at
your measuring points and at the end if
it works out and you can't can answer
your security questions with your
measurements you have your chaos eyes
this is a very abstract definition of
the whole process and all that you see
on the left and at the bottom this is
the actual security metric that you
develop so I will go quickly through
some of these steps so with the
measuring points like I said you
abstract them from at the beginning from
the audit findings because you already
had some idea of how do I identify if
this is a finding or not and one finding
can result in one measuring point but it
can also be multiple measuring points
and the measuring points are then in
turn measured with your so called
measuring instruments like we had before
on the definition and this is your
actual device or tool which give you
measurements from your measuring points
so here in the slide you just see a few
examples what measuring instruments
could be in a DSO scripts questionnaires
interviews they show documentation it
could be monitoring tools and also that
everything that comes from event logs so
you have a lot of tools already at you
disposal to work in the context of a
security metric and if you perform your
measuring process you of course have
your measurements and every measuring
point can have one measurement but it
can also have multiple ones and some
measuring points have a predefined set
of measurements think of a GPO setting
for example that can be enabled or
disabled at the end you only have a set
of two possible options and you know
that beforehand this can be very
important for analyzing your data later
on and the the most crucial part is that
you have very well-defined security
questions which can result in relevant
answers without this relevant answers
you cannot have your case ice in place
and they also said security questions
can be answered with one or more of the
measurements but you have to keep in
mind that not all security questions can
be answered with the measurements you
get directly from your initial
measurement of a measuring point that's
why we have defined several levels of
measurements you could say the initial
measuring point if it does not give you
the answer to your security question
that you have posed before it requires a
mathematical or logical operation to
come to your second manager measurement
so we have called them primary and
secondary measurements and if this is
still not sufficient to answer it you
can repeat the process and what is also
very crucial in developing a security
metric is to re-evaluate your measuring
points and you see security questions
because if the security questions cannot
be answered in a meaningful way this can
be due to two reasons either your
security questions are not precise
enough or just wrong you do not ask the
right questions all the selected
measuring points are not sufficient or
again are just wrong so in an iterative
process you have to reevaluate both and
at the end then have more completely
different measuring
or you have a reformulation of your
security questions now I will hand back
to Fleet what he will explain this in
one specific example so we would like to
go through one example and the example
is still nowadays in most organizations
heavily discussed security setting that
is the land manager authentication level
interestingly yes by Johansson one of
the windows Microsoft security guys some
years ago who wrote a lot of interesting
articles wrote one which in which he
talked about precisely this set of
settings and named it as the most
misunderstood security setting ever with
respect to Microsoft environments so we
had the following out at audit finding
defined insufficient land manager
authentication level on multiple systems
the underlying security problem is that
in insufficient land manager
authentication enables for the use of
ntlm v1 and LM authentication protocol
we rated this security setting on a
scale from one to five from very low to
very high as high M now if we want to go
through the process we have to abstract
from the finding to the measuring points
and the measurements so the setting land
manager authentication level this
finding you find in GP all so the first
measuring point is the GPO where this
finding is defined and the second point
is the the location where this GPO
setting is linked to of course you might
have different gpo's that set this
setting on different values then you
have the set of measurements and in case
of a Windows system is acting as an
as a client then sent and sent LM and
ntlm responses is the lowest setting and
sent aunty LM V to response only is the
highest setting the finding was
triggered when the setting was set or
set below to send aunty LM V to response
only so if you look at the security
problems behind the finding you might
come that you might have to come out
that there are more than one security
problem the first security problem is
that outdated authentication protocols I
use that is LM and ntlm v1 but M the
connected second security problem is
that possible that outdated hash such as
the LM hash I news because if you use
the LM authentication protocol the LM
hash will be used or not and not ntlm we
won or v2 so we have two security
problems behind this finding and then of
course we could ask fo as well if there
shouldn't be any different
differentiation between LM and aunty L
and we won now we can define the
security questions out of the security
problems the relevant security questions
in this case would be what percentage or
number of systems do we have that may
support LM hashes what number do we have
that may support LM authentication and
which number do support ntlm we run
authentication
looking at this we may ask if the
measurement and the measuring locations
are able to fully answer the security
questions M I will translate this pass
the use of LM hash depend only on the
cent ntlm V to respond setting I could
ask this the audience no it does not
other factors come into play for example
the operating system version if you use
if you use Windows 8.1 and above the LM
hash would simply not be generated mmm
if you use a strong password policy with
the length more than 14 characters LM
hash will not be generated although the
group policy setting allows
theoretically for the use of LM
authentication protocol so we have
additional factors influencing and the
patch level as well this is quite tricky
if you think of a Windows 7 system a
fully patched a Windows 7 system that
has all security Petrus M will generate
still the LM hash unless you apply a
certain patch that is not rated as a
security patch that will backport the
possibility to not generate the LM hash
from Windows 8.1 to Windows 7 so M we
have to taken into account that we will
need more measuring points and measures
in order to answer fully our three
security questions and these are the
attribute on the computer of the
computer object the operating system
version
questions regarding the patch management
and the question year the gpo setting
minimum password length and where these
GPOs are linked we have an overview of
this process in the slide and the
important point is that starting from
the finding abstracting the security
problems formulating the security
questions and then you have to ask
yourself do the measuring the original
measure measurements and measuring
points do they answer the security
questions fully we detected that's not
the case that we have to take into
account further measure measuring points
and measurements so finally there we
could derive for now three KS eyes and
these KS are KS is our number of systems
that may support LMS number of systems
that may support LM our authentication
and ntlm V one authentication and if u
opposes this information to the
information of the original finding that
is insufficient land manager
authentication level on multiple systems
you see that this information is quite
more precise in the sense of what makes
a metric if we evaluate this the
information as you already know is
consistently measured and chip together
it's expressed as a number a cardinal
number or a percentage it's expressed
using at least one unit of measure that
is the system that uses for example an M
hash and it's contextually specific that
is it it says something to an ad admin
but we find as well some obstacles and I
will hand over to Nina
so after now the process was described
that we followed I will now talk about
the obstacles that we got these
obstacles always start with the same
problem we were asking the wrong
questions asking the wrong questions led
us to getting lost on the data we
gathered and then trying to fix the
unfixable I will go through an example
to make us clearer so the audit finding
user account control disabled on
multiple system which had the underlying
security problem that any application
started by an administrator runs on the
privilege runs in the user and privilege
context of the administrator what the
audit finding I started with the
question how good is the USD
configuration in the environment this is
not a good question because it's not
specific and a good question should be
answered by KC case ksi that conforms to
the criteria of a good metric but you
cannot put any measuring unit for
example after in an answer how good is
it so this is an excel spreadsheet where
I tried to get ahead of the data we had
on the left side you see all the
settings that apply to USC then you see
the possible measurements that could be
derive from this and then parameters I
assigned to this
[Music]
you see there that I was not able to
fill everything to put everything in
because you see empty spaces on the
right side and you see like strange
numbers like 0.5 to 0.75 and so on I
write explain how I came to this numbers
and why this was a bad idea
so from this parameters I try to do an
algorithm and there again you say like
straight strange numbers 0.8 0.2 also I
came back later to this um this
algorithm I put into a bigger one to
assess the whole environment and I still
not did not consider ever measuring
point because I didn't know how to the
problem was that there are 10 GPS
settings relating GIC and they all kind
of declare important in assessing how
good the USGS but that's the wrong
question like I said before so I wanted
to put them all in like one algorithm
these measuring points mix different
aspects of USC so how can i connect
these resulting measurements and they
have qualitative differences between the
different measurements they can the set
of measurements it's just like a
qualitative reference it's like an
ordinal scale yeah so how do i quantify
this like you saw before I did not go
back and reconsider the taken approach I
applied an algorithm with Wang's so I
waited I put a weight on things like
okay seek your desk something on secure
desktop is not as important as having
your C disabled so I say it's zero point
two of the importance or I waited
inside the ordinal scale I put way
doughnuts on set okay if you have it for
everything besides windows binary CSA
does evidence like half as good if
you're ever following security
prospectus so I got back to gut feeling
this thing we wanted to get out of the
problem still sounded good to me until
etic tested it so it's not consistently
it's consistently measure and chip
together and yeah I have a card a number
of percentage as a result but it's not
expressed using at least one unit of
measure because there is no unit of
measure and it's not constantly context
really specific because it doesn't tell
you tell you anything actually so how to
make it better I always have the
criteria of a good metric in mind on any
set of the way both imposing the
appropriate questions or three lot of
information security also from the book
pragmatics is the one thing you should
always have in mind go back to your
question and adjust your question and
select your measuring points according
to your questions and not the other way
around
don't go through the information your
health and think oh I want to put this
in I think what you really need this
might lead to questions not being
answered or not answer by with your data
then change the measuring points or your
measuring instrument I would have made
it better there are some things you can
ask sensible it's like the percentage of
system where your C is not enabled then
you have to also put other things into
account to drive the case I like the
attribute computer operating system can
operating system version oh and how many
systems and environment USA is
configured according to security best
practices if you have these two question
answers you can go further and ask okay
if your C is enabled but not according
to best practices what are the main
they're diversions
so you go back and use it as an ordinary
you make algorithm on an ordinal scale
which you're allowed to do
actually so now where do we stand we
have we had 34 original audit findings
to have over 200 measuring points we
have now just 22 K size which we are
which is sufficient to be a good metric
and we're working on 16 more where do we
want to go of course more employed a
security question should be answered
with this so we want to define more cash
eyes and you Steve get here I've as
measurements to answer broader questions
again then we want to include more
measuring instruments to get access to
meant more measuring points and in the
end we would like to test our metrics or
consecrated et to assess if it really
assesses with security of 90 therefore
we have to define external factors and
that's I think through so we are not
sure how to process at this so what are
our lessons learned um first of all
doing metrics is quite hard at the
bidding at the beginning we thought or
of course we are in a good positions
because we know where to look but then
when it comes to metric and how to
really measure things in a consistent
way it's getting hard and therefore we
considered other areas where the
application of metrics is far more
involved then in information security
especially in Active Directory and as
Nina already said posing the right
questions is crucial
and keep always in mind that if you are
stuck to something and don't succeed
keep in mind what are good criterias for
metrics and try to apply them on your
security questions measurements and
measurements locations please stay or
get in contact with us help us to make
to develop an Active Directory security
metric in order to be able to finally
secure to finally measure Active
Directory in progressive sense if you
like follow us on twitter at iraq to
arrange our and so far thank you for
your attention
[Applause]