so next topic will be from gabriela ipv6
in the cloud I'm really looking forward
to this presentation because as an
offset um quite some enterprises do now
have some plan for ipv6 and of course
also have plans to move more stuff into
the cloud so it's a really relevant
question okay can we leverage our ipv6
approach for our data center in the
cloud as well so I'm really looking
forward what the answer will be well I
mean I have a feeling but let's see what
Gabrielle has to say and then without
further ado the stage is yours thanks
Christopher
thanks for being here yeah well the
question is if you're going to back to
square one or not and this will be
basically the scope of this talk okay
this is about my company about myself
I'm living in Switzerland originally I'm
from Germany near Cologne but then I
moved to a Zurich to to study at ETH and
now I'm living close to Zurich in
winterthur
with two kids and my wife and I'm
working for a w-k-n-o for nine years now
as a project manager and net Network
expert supporting our customers in
various projects okay so motivation for
this talk was that was last year an
autumn I was talking to a customer and
he said how well we were very fascinated
form this error cloud and we really
considering to move mall as one of our
two data centers into the cloud and I
said hey perfect
you have to redress everything all you
have to address everything so you can do
this with ipv6 right and then in the
afternoon I went home and said let's
have a look and basically this was the
motivation for my talk today as you can
see the agenda I will give a quick
introduction to more less cloud
definition to also to make you well in
which area we're talking today because
cloud is quite quite a broad area too
and you could spend I guess weeks to
talk about it then I focused on for
let's say cloud service
right us and looked what they can offer
with respect to ipv6 there will be a
quick demo and I also would like to
discuss if if this kind of
implementation which are now reporting
about is really the way to go in general
and I'm really excited to have this
discussion later on them okay so this is
a definition about cloud computing by
NIST which is I think it's a very good
one even it's already several years old
and this makes up good definitions to my
understanding if you have definition
which persists over time and what this
definition is emphasizing is the network
access so this would be a justification
for me to have network access over ipv6
as well and for this introduction part
what is important to realize that you
have five essential characteristics of
cloud three service models and for
deployment models which we briefly will
now discuss in this introduction apart
so essential characteristics as you can
see here it's on demand capability and
you can do it yourself so it's not yet
we have to call some cloud provider to
to get some resources you have a broad
network access so emphasized again on
the network axis what is important to
understand that usually you share these
resources so the resources are not owned
by our explicity assigned to you with
some cloud providers you can request for
dedicated computing resources but what
we have to understand especially the
network infrastructure is to my
understanding always shared with other
customers you are able with this rapid
elasticity to to scale and this is very
important I had heard a very interesting
talk and it was
at the cows Computer Club passing three
or four years ago whereas a Obama IT guy
was reporting about that was a election
campaign they used cloud infrastructure
and it was perfect because I could scale
from 0 to infinity more or less very
easily so it was if they had lower
demand on resources they used only is
what they needed all the time this was
really interesting to him and obviously
because cloud service providers need to
make some revenue so there must be some
measures to monitor control and also
invoices the services you you you use
then we have the service models and in
the NIST definition you only have this
there's a lower three parts which is
infrastructure as a service platform as
a service and service as a service
there's a very good book which is
details you can find and depend in the
pendings of the slides which introduces
two additional service models one is
about information as a service it's
about provide and or process information
and the other one is about deliver
business process to you to your
organization and I think this is some
kind of obvious that your higher you go
the less control you have over the the
data right because especially in the
information as a service model you give
the information away away to some other
entity to process them and with business
also the service provider access to the
information increases
so then we have the deployment models
which I think most of you would have
heard all of those already so we have a
private cloud which is not very
interesting at least not in the scope of
this presentation because this is a
cloud you maintain on your own in your
with your own data or a data center with
your own infrastructure the same similar
to community cloud which is restricted
to some to a limited user audience and
then we have the public cloud which is
basically what we are talking today
about and the hybrid cloud is a mix of
the three first cloud deployment models
to use any questions so far then yeah
well what you do if you need to select
some cloud prova service providers to
look at so there are a lot of service
providers they are also some service
providers which which do not hold the
definition of NIST so they don't fulfill
some of these characteristics but I was
then looking at Gartner and you know
this famous metric quadrant and I
selected for leading let's say cloud
service providers this is the definition
of cloud service providers from from
gardeners himself also they have some
characteristics which more lesson
matches a nester definition and also
they emphasizes again the network
capabilities and again for me network
capabilities as of today would be also
ipv6 should be supported so this Magic
Quadrant so what I selected for this
talk was I selected Amazon Microsoft
Google and Alibaba cloud and
things that provide a majority I don't
have to go into detail because this is
quite some kind of obvious or the ranked
recommended mode to the best what I
understood from Gartner
is said mode one is Moser let's say is a
classic approach and mode two is more as
as I say it some selves the agile
approach so and this is for me it's
Google right so Google has it's not
there's a classic classic provider of
that kind of work before I started with
my analysis I was thinking what I want
to do and I came up with a very let's
say easy network diagram let's say so I
wanted to build some I is so
infrastructure-as-a-service topology
setting up a network within this
topology having some gateway to the
internet having some routing and
switching infrastructure within my my
topology and having some basic very
basic services such as DHCP and DNS
[Music]
so then we would already come to the
results so first one would be out I did
it alphabet alphabetically so no just in
case
so first Alibaba I always the first
slide always shows you the entry
dashboard so that you get an impression
of how it looks like and to say it
straight away so they have no ipv6
support at all nevertheless I will shown
our several slides because this gives
you good let's say basic understanding
what in this typical
infrastructure-as-a-service and why I
meant which key components you have so
basically at the beginning when you set
up such infrastructure-as-a-service
let's say network topology or also most
of the service providers call it it's a
V PC the virtual private cloud and this
relates to the network setup you can do
here which gives you the possibility
here since you don't have any ipv6
support to define an RFC 1918 network
and use this then in the in multiple
subnets and using chunks out of this
network to to configure let's say
subnets or layer 2 switching domains or
whatever you call it this is more some
more details about this then you have
the virtual router functionality
obviously like in in a router base layer
3 functionality or in a firewall you
have all this directly connected
networks right so all the sub internet
sub sub networks you create within this
V PC what what this routing table is
also then used for is if you were for
instance connect some VPN canet work to
this virtual cloud so if for example if
you have a data center within your
organization locally home and you
like to communicate between the cloud
and your DC you will set up some sort of
VPN connection and then of course it's
quite important to know the remote
remote routing information right to
access the remote networks so an you
have says these switches it's basically
the subnets you create and for each
subnet you create you will get this V
switch infrastructure or zone and then
in at the end when you send setup a
computing a VM virtual machine or
computing instance as I usually say then
you connect to one or more of these
subnets VM exactly so then you have also
obviously especially in the case of ipv4
when you have private address space it
does not have a lot to to communicate
with the outside so we use NF
possibility to assign public addresses
and most of these vendors have two
flavors of doing so so you can have a
often they call it elastic IP and this
IP is not by a bounded one two one two
let's say a virtual computing instance
but often Xen is terminated on a on a
load balancer or might be related to one
one to one that to a private IP address
of an instance but this elastic IP you
can very easily move to another instance
so if the instance goes down or you if
it's a shared main downtown two downtime
or not whatever you can migrate this
elastic IP very easily which helps you
to to keep up the service provided by
the society and the other one is more
there's a static IP which you basically
assign one to want to this a computing
instance or the network interface of
this computing instance and this by my
tendency is then used to for outgoing
connections so if the server's in your
in your V PC need to get some updates or
for whatever reasons to connect to the
outside say they used
more aesthetic opinion and this static
IP often then also is removed as soon as
you tear down this computing
infrastructure you you lose it and it's
not it could be assigned to another
customer right away afterwards so
elastic IP you have more control over it
I would say that Gateway is also very
very important functionalities of for
inbound connections you could as you
know it you could choose this
destination not to terminate or to
forward the traffic to some computing
instance within your V PC and you could
also do a destination source not for for
outgoing connections so and then you
have obviously load balancer to to load
a lot of incoming traffic load to
multiple instances of your V PC to to be
able to to company or to to accommodate
a lot and what does as I mentioned
before in the introduction all these
cloud providers offer very advanced
functionality to to create more
instances more or less on the fly so you
can set threshold values on CP or
bandwidth or whatever and as soon as
this threshold is overstepped so new
instances out of more or less
automatically provisioned and attached
into the network for to add to the load
balancer for handling the additional
load and the same applies when the load
decreases so to summarize as I said in
the beginning I would like I wanted to
show you the let's say the building
blocks of such a V PC because we now see
it in all the other three service cloud
service providers
and as I said also there is no ipv6
support and of course you at least I I
then asked to support hey I would like
to have ipv6 and the recommendations I
made they told me look you have this
computing instance with some Linux box
so you can set up a hurricane Electric
channel and then you have ipv6 yeah well
it's nice but for let's say moving my
data center into the cloud
I would not rely on this one and I also
always asked if they have a roadmap and
also I can also tell you right now the
answer was I'm sorry we don't have a
roadmap please look at these websites
for for first announcement and they also
don't have another now a roadmap for
ipv6 at all in the VP see yeah this is
what about Alibaba next Amazon it's by
far the most advanced when it comes to
ipv6 this is the dashboard which I
really like because you see as you can
see the recently visited services so
you're very quick and navigating through
your EPC and all the other components of
it yeah and as you can see here you have
ipv6 support so as soon as you create
this VPC network you can state yes I
would like to have a v6 space and then
you get / 56 assigned out of out of the
Amazon ipv6 address range and you can
then use up to obviously up to 256 / 64
networks in in your V PC
which is quite nice and so I will also
share the slide so you don't have to
take pictures as soon as long as you
don't want to publish it no yeah there's
some example so I this is the ipv6 space
I got ok it's me okay the ipv6 range I
got assigned but you see I'm not used to
it should practice in advance ok next
what is next
yeah and then you could see that I have
created two subnets and I got a subnet
allocated for each of this subnet and
ipv6 / 64 allocated to each of these
subnets and yeah Jen you have the
routing table which obviously now also
includes the slash 56 network then you
have sir yeah this was the first
disappointment that you cannot specify
ipv6 domain name server so dinner
service they cannot be specified as I
always did I asked by when this is
available and if they do this there
seemed to be other customers which would
like to use it so it has already been
escalated and they are currently working
on the implementation but once more
well you can you can yeah so this is to
give dhcp options right so in the DHCP
offer that you specify the main serves
and you can enter the ipv6 IP for
Chryslers obviously that's working
yes that's working a may edge him in for
one question yeah
the prefix we've seen in a V PC the ipv6
prefix um is this pre-allocated from
Amazon yes or can I choose whatever
preachings I want to use no you have to
use Amazon prefix or space thanks
okay sorry we have a question how big
how what is the minimum prefix size it's
it's there's only one which is /v 56
okay so we asked them I intend to say it
later but I can say no so I asked him I
wanted to have let's say slash 48
because slash 48 is if you have a if you
have a data center so you salacious 48 4
4 side is quite common right and this is
also what I recommend my customers so I
asked them can I get a slash 410 said no
it's technically not feasible and I
could issue a feature request for this
no which I didn't because I don't had
unique ways but I told them look there
might be customers coming and they have
to slash 48 in the DC in their premises
and now I want to do a let's say more
les121 set up in the cloud and then it
would be really nice to have also slash
48 2 to reapply your address planning
one to one and not straggling around to
is having multiple V pcs maybe connected
because this was one of the
recommendations they gave me they said
well you can set up more than one V PC
and interconnect and we are routing and
four slash 48 I would have to set up 256
V PC so yeah and all the routing table
maintenance so no and
you know okay what I also looked at was
DNS and I had a special focus on PTR so
first what I did always I allocated
let's say this more legal net this is my
domain and I delegated a sub sub domain
to to all this cloud service providers
and this was working easily and I could
query all the a and quota records from
any Public DNS server but I then oh wait
also all this all these types which are
supported by Amazon but I was a specific
entry interested in setting up reverse
DNS entry because this is expected for
example if you utilize or you operating
a mail server this is a lot of sending
mail service or no the receiving mail
service look if they can find the
reverse can see a find a host name for
this IP source a source IP address and
so I I tried this and you could actually
do this so obviously you could very
easily do it in the in the DNS in this
zone 53 as I call it at Amazon or DNS 53
you could do it in this internal DNS
server but there's also form on the
website
Adamo zone and then you can ask for this
reverse pointer entries and the ends I
set it up in there because this needs to
be set up by the owner of the IP
addresses right and so then they set it
up for me and afterward this was it was
working from even my company company DNS
servers he could reverse lookups the
host name of the quad a record for this
ipv6 address which is quite nice and it
took Sam nine hours only to set it up
for me so I should the request and nine
hours later it was they confirmed that I
have implemented it
as I mentioned already in the Ali Baba
introduction this VPN topic is also an
important one because as soon as you
want to to intercommunicate for example
between two data centers you you need
this and it's also not available with
Amazon so they have already featured
requests for this so I assume they were
pretty soon and supports this as well
which I needed to my opinion here
to summarize as I said also by far the
most advanced i'm amazon with regards to
ipv6 support now dhcpv6 support yet oh
it's no it's not a dns story there's a
typo dns and i thought i fix it in some
slack
so it's dns and you have as i already
answered to your Christopher it's this
Slayer you I don't know this is the
slash speak / 50 side and you can only
have let's say you cannot give them your
ipv6 address range to and routing it to
this close this is not possible at all
and here's again this statement says I
wrote to me about this what I can how I
can combine scissors / 56 boundary but
it's not even even a short that you get
a consecutive IP address space so for me
it would be not usable
okay one bag for you okay next is Google
so this is the dashboard of Google which
also lets you navigate very easily you
have also you can set up sis your your
recently or your frequently used
functionalities or subsets and yeah so
there's also as you can see no ipv6 here
anyway so it is not there and then what
you do next you google you Google what I
care how ipv6 Google cloud platform and
then they say it's possible you have to
use load balancer so you then can define
an ipv6 address on which terminates on
the on the load balancer and this is how
it works so you terminate ipv4 and ipv6
on the load balancer and within the
Google or if is in your local or your V
PC you only use ipv4 and then there's
obviously then there's net 64 which for
example if you have an HTTP traffic it
yeah it's for BOTS exit traffic's we to
the target your computing instance
within the cloud via ipv4 and as you can
see they support quite a lot of
protocols so not that bad and especially
if you operating of let's say your web
server you might be interested in who is
connecting and obviously if you have
this net 6 for every time the source IP
you see which is connecting is a load
balancer and not as a source source IP
of your customer and what they offer for
example for HTTP is a adding in the HTTP
header in the
I don't know get requests or whatever
they add ahead of its a colleague's
forwarding header and there you can see
the ipv6 address of the of the load
balancer where the traffic terminated on
and also the source IP address ipv6
address of the customer ah this is the
same so you have this external this
elastic IPS and they call it not elastic
party ephemeral and similar to to
Alibaba as you could have then you use
them to to to connect your internal
let's say computing instance with an
ipv4 address with the service a public
Internet DNS again so you could set up
this Eric quat a record for the load
balancer but there is no support for PTR
on ipv6 so they supported on ipv4 but
they do not support it on ipv6
and there's not even a
yeah so I could follow up a block to to
see when it's available
yeah nothing to it
to the summary to order set the last one
is Asia also very nice GUI which easily
lets you navigate to all the signs and
there's also no ipv6 support this is a
statement what they implement is net six
six so it's similar to what you can have
with Google you can have having the load
balancer terminating ipv6 and using
another ipv6 address or address space to
took then internally translate before we
go to the details what I really liked is
this web-based PowerShell so you could
obviously you can you can with your
local PowerShell installation you can
log in via let's say shell to your cloud
with service or security credentials but
after you had logged in into the
web-based portal you could start
PowerShell browser embedded which is I
really liked it because you can really
easy then work on and there are certain
commands you can only issue here via the
via the Porsche which are not available
in the in the GUI Singh
so as I said are using net Six's net 66
and there is one example so again if you
google for setting up ipv6 in Azure
which is a very complex example where
you have first to even set up this whole
load balancer infrastructure with
multiple virtual machines in an
availability set and it's all CLI based
and I love the CLI but I'm not familiar
with edger CLI so I was looking for
other ways to achieve this
and basically the only thing you have to
do outside to go is to to create a
virtual machine in the command in the
CLI and detaching and network interface
to it via the CLI which has enabled ipv6
support this is the only step you have
to do and all the other steps you can do
in the GUI and in the Penix you can find
a detailed step-by-step guideline how to
do this ok yeah so again the DNS check
mark yeah you can imagine that similar
to Google they do not support reverse
DNS for ipv6 only for ipv4 summary yeah
what-what I have to admit I did not ask
as a support but I I was thinking not
sure if support can answers it at all
but I'm I don't understand why they
implemented this net 66 nat64 with
Google I can understand so if you don't
have an ipv6 in the in the in the
internal VPC ok then you translate to
into another IP version but using ipv6
net 66 I don't get it the motivation for
that so it's a big picture very familiar
very similar to the picture I showed at
the introduction I what I now edit given
the results I found I said I added this
load balancer because you can only
achieve it we allowed balancer at some
point in time and then yeah I stated
where you have ipv6 support for this
different cloud service providers and I
still as you recall most efficient most
sophisticated support is with Amazon Web
Services
and on Microsoft Ezra and Google cloud
platform the only as a way to work with
a load balancer which I really think
it's not the way to go if you really
it's it's like this first first or this
quick quick win implementation of ipv6
you implement or deploy ipv6 and the
edge right and then your your accessible
via ipv6 but on the on the long run if
you if you really intend to move a whole
data center into the cloud into such a
VPC environment I would not do it
because then in a few years time I have
to touch it again andrey address and
there was some guy in before today which
says do not redress it was more meant
for ipv6 ipv6 but same would apply for i
before type ii six I would assume yeah
and this is some comments yeah as you
know me there's always a demo in my
presentations so time oh you're good
there's another feature today coming
later so first what we could show first
okay this is better no okay let's go
success rate and so what we can do I
have this one as I mentioned in the case
of Google this is a solid
uhh
computing
what is really nice well it's nice from
a user perspective I'm not sure how nice
it is from a security perspective you
can connect to be as a browser to the
compute instance and as you can see it's
in German as I say key is going to be
transferred to the machine so they have
access to my private key now okay so as
I said it's a nice really nice from a
user perspective and so this is now my
computing instance which are just
installed the default Apache
configuration and you know you can you
see there's only a private ipv4 address
and so I'm also receive ok I'm connected
now because in the Google and what we
could do
so I'm not going to him this is to show
you this ex forwarding entries so I know
this is C what is used here
oh nothing
demonstration effect strange
yes no it should work
I see now here in the x4 when can you
reach this by the way okay okay so you
see this is Krista fide look familiar
yeah so this is a two-person network and
this is IP res the connection was
terminated on the load balancer and yeah
I fee I'm not sure if I can this well
this is no also I guess Google Chrome is
no everything
oh no he's for whatever reasons he's
using ipv4 I don't know but you see now
there's a public IP of the troopers
router and enter the IP of load balancer
public IP owns a Google so this what
about this what else I wanted to show
well exactly so we have for Amazon we
really have this I do it's tech support
this is is it too small or can you read
it so here you really have
global you can see the glows and you can
also access any external ipv6 research
so the really cool thing I cannot show
you today because I prepared too late it
was about that in an Amazon Cloud you
can have on the Amazon Marketplace you
can have various appliances and one of
these appliances as virtual ezarik
juniper firewall and I was able to
deploy it into my cloud but I was not
able to connect this patient or be ipv6
but this is really nice and this is a
really good also marketing idea because
people like me which currently
administrate our X file in in in our
let's say local data center
infrastructure if you give them such
such tools attend say a known as I know
it they use they know how to use it so
it's quite smart move from such
companies you can have also Cisco ASA
and everything so a lot of such I apply
appliance are virtualized and can be
used in the clouds also is edger and
services it's not restricted to Amazon
necessarily anything you would like to
see if I'm just I'm locked into all the
clouds or
any
ah it's a good one it will it's it will
only it will not work with i simpiy
trace or their support yesterday told me
yeah they're using some TCP trace what
I'm never used that before now as I said
my life so I can show his may later from
the externals trying when I set up the
virtual ethics I was trying because I
was troubleshooting and but it will not
finish and I don't want to display the
Amanar here but he sent something but in
the supporting can in problem
no it's if you apply for audits is
testing so where you get free whatever
one year and so and this is this is also
a thing of those edges itís always in in
the main region so in America how you
are singers
let's see
see oh it says not reachable at all wait
and he used some TCP can you notice I
don't know the command at windows at
least dress no windows only supports ICP
based around my new company laptop I
don't have sir yeah Ubuntu VM no not yet
anything else
okay otherwise I would come back and
restart continue with the discussion
this was not discussion so and as I said
I know no no posters today but given the
time and it's only 15 minutes to lunch
I brought some chocolates to give you
some sugar for hen it around just it
contains nuts
someone allergic to nuts don't don't eat
it okay so discussion for me would be
especially especially for companies my
size so a small medium enterprise should
you really go for
infrastructure-as-a-service because it's
a lot of hazard to set up you need a lot
of knowledge it's quite different to set
up things in the cloud compared into a
with your data center so should you
really should you really go for
infrastructure service at all because
you can all have especially the window
stuff you can SharePoint Skype for
business you can have all this in the
cloud so why should you
[Music]
would it be easier to just purchases as
a service as a service from this catalog
they all offer and only if it all
restrict let's say the infrastructure as
a service usage on let's say
self-developed applications things you
cannot get out of the catalog would this
be a another way a better way I don't
know and in addition if you operate
especially through it operate as on
infrastructures and service you you're
responsible right you get in this
virtual machine image but it's more or
less naked so there is nothing no
security updates nothing only if you go
for platform as a service you you might
get it because then they the cloud
providers usually take care about let's
say the operating system part but in the
infrastructure the service part it's
your VM and you have you're responsible
for it and this includes also the
security part and now given all this
complex constraints I was asking myself
where's the benefit to to use the
infrastructure as a service environment
whatever any comments
I mean I could make a snarky comment it
doesn't take two weeks to get a server
deployed when you're using ISS but if I
purchase I have to admit I never
purchased any service as a service does
it take two weeks I would say assume it
takes also well I mean in the typical
large scale enterprise environments
there is some time associated when you
need a server and when you get a server
especially when you have a third-party
provider or responsible for deploying
this server it might take a couple of
weeks no I think we're talking about two
different things I was saying instead of
moving my service because at the end you
offer some application or some service
to the customer internal bid internal
external and instead of doing this in
the infrastructure as a service in the
cloud you doing still in the cloud but
you purchase the service on a let's say
on the application level so you you
purchase from Microsoft SharePoint
Server and you you just configure let's
say the content and the application
level and but you don't set up Windows
Server in the infrastructure as a
service environment then installing
SharePoint on it and then another server
you running the Active Directory and so
on so in this I meant of course I know I
and I also recognized this is if you
really if you need or you you need a
server it's it's a few mouse clicks and
the really spending a few seconds and
then boom the server says this is really
attractive to have this in the cloud
compared in what just what you said that
in even if you're virtualized in your in
your local data center at some point in
time you need to maintain you need to
increase so you have to touch metal
right and this you you never do in the
cloud
and what I also recognized is that on
infrastructure as a service as a pricing
model is as such as that you pay usually
some some fee per operational unit so
every our drums you pay depending on the
size of the virtual machine for example
and you pay for traffic and this is
regardless if 10 10 users using the
SharePoint application or if it's one
user and in the in the service as a
service pricing model it's it's usually
that you have a price per user
regardless if this user is transferring
10 gigabit data to the SharePoint or 2
megabit and it's it's it's very firm so
let's say OPEX perspective for the
company it's very easy because there's a
most probably even have a estimate how
much they grow in the next two years and
they can very well estimate as OPEX
costs for for this services Senya
no clear pro and con for any sentiments
but I can see
say align our integrated offerings much
better I don't know
running collector
as in soccer systems but I would say our
customer space and there's many people
still going for each my sources as they
provide some flexibility and we can do
it the way we have done in them before
just what you guys take that Center
running in the cloud yeah I always
everyone their operations moles oh yeah
images that's amazing
yeah it wasn't what you what you said
was good that they assume that it's very
similar to what they have in the local
data centers and especially we can when
it comes to monitoring on network level
I would totally disagree because as far
as I know you don't have the
capabilities to create some of this
virtual routers via SNMP for some
statistics and you let's say from the
application perspective you have a lot
of tools to monitor the health of your
application in the clouds but this does
not necessarily show you if there's some
tech attack ongoing especially on
network level so for me there's some
missing feature let's say that how how
to to detect some you know malicious
activities on network layer okay so it's
me in between you and lunch break so so
any more question regarding the ipv6
supports or general questions Eric a
typical deployment we see now in private
data center is to give a slash 64 per
oast so that each container can get this
unique v6 address so is it any way to do
it with those clouds PPC I would have to
check but I would say when I would say
no because I think pole yeah well it's
only in Amazon and what use and you the
host is configured all the VM is
configured in that way that it just
requests India tube is the IP it's a
time via DHCP v6 and well I could I
could try to to change the configuration
to request prefix delegation but I I
didn't try to be honest static state
static it's not possible static it's not
possible so Amazon assigns it to be a
dhcpv6 okay
can I use ipv6 Network ourselves yeah
yeah you can have security this is a
dinner shows it you can have the
security they call it security groups
and I think with both Asia and also
Amazon and and Amazon you can attach
such security groups to the network
interface basically and you can yeah you
can layer 3 4 like protocol report let
me maybe I can quickly show one example
could you observe here this we are here
for example
so you have involved in outbound rules
we can't anything oh this is very smart
to us right for that Windows PC
yep so this is not a good example
because it's only before let's check
another one
it's also not good to you don't ever
releasing this one I guess
No
just want to show you something with
ipv6
the others could also be looks and but
yeah so great
and then he can also assign the V PC
which is belongs to
test
and here you can say for example all
eyes in pv6 and you can say very secure
I'd say
and this in terms you can then apply to
the virtual network interface on the
Vienna and you when you create VM you
can also define default security groups
and they automatically create a set or
assigned to the VM so if you especially
if you automate all the scripting and
everything this is very nice and I know
you had a question or comment
in Rocky so the reason you excretion yes
I mean it's lunchtime so we can do
discussion during debt
any more questions alright then thank
you very much Gabrielle very interesting
you lots
[Applause]