what we had pending from the
presentation before was to to test some
of the tools that I described okay let's
go with each of them like in time so
first one that I mentioned was for
example was the address six tool and it
was about printing addresses in
different formats maybe when I was
describing this without you know showing
you you know an example it wasn't that
easy to see so let's say for example
that I have an address such as this one
so if I print the address in this way
this is supposed to be or I can can
write it this way and so it's more clear
so this would be the canonic form of the
address okay which usually if you are
blogging or if you are configuring a you
know system or something that obviously
the the way in which you write down the
address but normally if you want to
process an address with with a script
like a regular expression or something
these services in that format they are
not that that helpful
so usually you want something like this
and you I mean if you have done some
scripting you could probably tell why
it's easier right it has like you know I
mean for example if you try to come up
with a regular expression to be able to
pick every possible ipv6 address that's
a pain that's a pain I have something
let's say sorry cool
well it's not easy to see their let's
say
this is really like the regular
expression and actually still has like a
small problem that I need to fix okay
I mean obviously I I was proud of myself
when I came up with this now you'd be
proud of myself for understanding it but
because of the you know all the possible
ways in which you can write the you know
the addresses like compress form with
more cereal with least zeros and so on
it's actually a pain if you want to do a
script so the idea is that you want to
move away from this so if you print the
addresses in this way obviously it's
much much much easier if you want to
analyze the addresses such a say a set
text string another thing that I
mentioned was that the tool could
actually produce like a set of prefixes
as a result from some addresses so let's
go here
so I have a text file and obviously it
means nothing it's just like a bunch of
addresses which they could I could have
got these addresses for example by
mapping some domain name to the quad a
record there's I mean this is quite
simple now let's assume for example that
I wanted to do dns reverse enumeration
for these prefixes well obviously I had
to come up with a prefix for each of
this okay so what you can do is for
example if you pipe
whoops
[Music]
being unique prefix I think it was this
one they go
so these were the addresses now what we
got here is we have slash 48 prefixes
that we got from the original addresses
I mean obviously that's trivial you just
need to set to 0 all the low-order bits
and just add this slash something to
make them a prefix now with these
prefixes you can you know produce DNS
reverse enumeration you know for the
corresponding prefixes so the idea of
these small tools or these small
features is that eventually you can you
know build a tool where you can automate
everything so you get addresses
automatically you produce prefixes and
out of these prefixes you do read the
DNS reverse enumeration and so on and so
on and so on like the tool that I was
describing before that puts everything
together needs this kind of stuff so
that when you get addresses you come up
with the prefixes so that you can do DNS
reverse enumeration ok what else did we
talk about we talked about search
engines so for example you can one of
the search engines that I described was
being and if I run something like this
this is for the top level domain Mille
military ok
the tool obviously as I was describing
before eliminates the applicate results
and also you know once it you know spend
some time finding domain names for
example it finds this one then it tries
to go deeper into the hierarchy okay to
try to find as many as possible
okay
this is the same thing or should be the
same thing if you run with this other
search engine tyoma
I mean the order and the results might
be different but the idea is exactly the
same no actually I stopped it myself but
it has like a kind of like limit for
example the tool internally says okay if
I visit so many pages without actually
getting any new results at all
eventually I will give up now obviously
there is a trade-off between you know
trying to get all the results and for
how long you need to wait because what
you are doing with a search engine is
for example specifying this now you
might get like multiple pages like
multiples pages of you know search
results in which year the patients are
different but all correspond to the same
domain name so the tool has to play some
tricks inside to actually not try to get
to different domain names and eventually
if it tries he tries he tries he tries
and gets nothing eventually it stops so
for example when I when I was running
the tool to actually try to build like a
sewn data I was leaving the tool running
for maybe like a day and obviously once
you know it has already run for like
let's say four or five hours maybe it
gets like a new domain name you know I'm
like every five minutes so there's a
trade-off there for me much of you know
for me the the the main usage that I was
given to this tool was to come up with
you know song files that I didn't have
the other tool that I mentioned
[Music]
what's the tool that puts everything
together so what you do is I mean this
is very very preliminary version of the
tool you start for example the H option
gives like hints to the tool ok so you
are telling the tool ok I know this
information about this side like you
might know some domain name you might
know some prefix or something it's
information that you give to the tool so
I could start for example just with the
name of with some domain name ok so this
is the H is for hints and then you can
also set the f FS for filter so that
means if I set the F to the domain name
that means that I'm going to require the
results to belong to the domain name
lacnic net okay if I just do this this
is just a hint I'm telling the tool try
learning domain names and IP addresses
and ipv6 addresses and everything
starting from here but I don't care
where you get the result from so it
could be from a completely different
domain name zone and in practice at
least you are trying to map the whole
internet well that's not of much use if
you are trying to do a Penta stuff aside
obviously you want to reduce the you
know the the DNS zone or the prefixes or
whatever that is it can take some time
but I was running the tool already
so this is the results that I was
getting with a tool as I was running it
before essentially the tool gives you
two different kinds of output one is
domain names
the other one is ipv6 addresses okay
the tool eliminates duplicates so if
there were any duplicates you know in
the in the you know in the DNS reverse
elimination or anything you're going to
get only one copy and as I said before
since I'm using filters you can see that
for example all the domain names belong
to lacnic dotnet which is what I was
specifying in the tool if I were to run
for example the tool like this without
the filter okay here I run it without
the filter so you see that for example
you have like are in dotnet which has
nothing to do with the zone that I was
targeting okay so you can tell the tool
start finding names and IP IP v6
addresses from here but I don't care
where you get the results so you get
stuff like this which in most cases is
not going to be useful for you and if
you don't want that
besides specifying a hint you also
specify like a filter and this means
start from here but I also require you
that the resource that you show me
belong only to this DNS zone and you can
also specify prefixes so you can say you
can say ok I know that my target network
is that specific one so I only want
results belonging to this domain name
and some specific prefix the tool you
know essentially runs in a loop it gets
domain names starts with the you know
getting domain names from a search
engine then from those domain names it
obtains different kinds of DNS records
ma NS MX and so on it obtains ipv6
services and then it performs DNS
reverse enumeration it goes in a loop
until you get to a point in which you
don't get any rest
any more results that's where the tool
stops okay to poop
yeah
look you okay
what it
so I'm going to continue with the next
part of the the talk essentially much of
what you have seen in the you know what
I presented in the previous talk was
motivated but this other work okay
so again I was trying to build like a
database of full of ipv6 information
like domain names ipv6 services and so
on and then you know I had to figure out
how to get that information one you know
one thing that is important is that you
know for the project that I was working
on I didn't just need like IP addresses
but I wanted for example I needed to
also learn what were the corresponding
domain names for them okay you know just
having random addresses can be useful
for some things like for an attacker
that you know just wants to you know
find some vulnerable device but for many
other things what you want is you know
to learn information about your feastin
systems that are important for you
so this is the you know this is what I
studied from like say okay let's try to
build like a database with all this
information and then the question was
like well how do how do I know for
example that in my database I have like
information about systems that are
supposed to be important not about just
you know some random system out there
that nobody cares about like you know
for example you want to learn
information about the websites of
government institutions you know
security sites and all of that obviously
ideally speaking you might be able to
get the DNS on file okay I had never
actually bothered that much about that
so when I got into this I started
researching a little bit and it was kind
of surprising to me that the information
that I was that iPhone available which I
will discuss later even there are like
more base
questions let's say that this is not
just something for participate for
pentesting for example one of the things
that I wanted to do was for example
measure measuring ipv6 deployment for
example let's say that you wanted to say
I want to measure in Germany the extent
to which ipv6 is deployed in let's say
education education sites government
sites private sites and so on you have
to find a way for example how to map all
those all those sites and if you want to
do that at the larger scale
well you even need basic information
like what are the suffixes that
different top-level domains employ
simple example like in many countries a
commercial site uses com dot the
top-level domain but for example in the
UK they don't they use Co not com
obviously the one in the UK is an easy
one but if you won't do that that mass
scale is not that simple because you
have to be no wonder about you know
every single possible TLD so these were
all questions that you know I had never
wondered but now I needed some answers
the other thing was to try to figure out
you know to what extent some of the
techniques that we have been employing
for you know targeting specific sites
could be used like more at the larger
scale okay you know usually if you are
targeting like a single site or a single
company you know the scale of the
problem is more reduced usually you know
more you know you might know for example
the some patterns that the address is my
you know my heart and so on but if you
want to do that my skin if you want to
do the same thing but mass scale it's
not that simple
first one some files okay I had never
bothered much about this and I have a
friend in in a regional registry in
Chile so for people that you know work
in NICs
this is the stuff that you're you know
more aware about that and the question
was essentially well I'm interested in
as many domain names as possible where
can I get them from so the piece of
information that I already had was you
know these three different list of
important or popular domain names I have
put them available on github actually I
put it there for myself
usually I you know I need to look at
those files and I never know where to
find them so if you synchronize that
give repo you get the you know the three
lists one is a Lexus top 1 million site
I think that they don't I think that
they don't put that list available
anymore as far as I remember they do
okay I think that at some point they
stopped publishing that list so I mean
you don't know if the list that we have
right now is really the top 1 million
more important size but you know you
don't care then there is that I think
it's a company majestic I don't even
know what they do I think it's like CEO
or something like that but they had a
you know something similar to Alexa I
don't remember if it was 1 million sites
but you know again lots of domain names
that's good and the umbrella list I
think is published by Cisco I don't know
what for but when I was searching for
that I found that so that gives you like
three different sets of domain names of
there that are popular still that
doesn't give you much about less popular
size that you might be interested in
like you know military sites you're not
going to get anything there
so let's see
so originally I said okay if we were
able to get the DNS some files will be
great I mean is that information
available so I was talking with this
friend of mine I wasn't even aware about
this and apparently I can which makes a
lot of money you know in the business of
DNS among other things they set up that
website and the idea are kind of the way
understood about that is that if you are
the administrator the administrator of
you know some top-level domain you can
voluntarily join and share the you know
the some data for this on you administer
okay it had been a long time since I had
like look at you know top-level domains
in detail I was surprised with the
amount of crap that you find on the TLD
is like anything dot anything so there
was a time in which it was comm dot e du
dot org and the top-level domains now is
dot anything essentially it's like like
hundreds of top-level domains what are
the interesting ones that you can find
over there
for example dot org is available and for
free and you get the official some data
so you can get all of the dot org sites
another thing another site that I found
quite interesting and that's actually an
interesting point of view there's the
people from Sweden in which they
actually publish the wholesome data on
their website and what they say is like
well you know one way or another you
know if people really want to use this
information to for attacks they're going
to get it anyway so what we assume is
that if we publish this information we
will allow people to do research for
example to measure things on the you
know on the DNS zone for a Sweden so if
you go to that side you can essentially
download everything for dot s e and dot
and u which I don't know what and U is
for about this
something related to Sweden there are
other interesting ones like this one
which somehow the sound data for Russia
was licked out so you can also you know
get that one and I don't remember where
but I did find some copy of the dot-com
song which is probably them among the
most interesting ones so this means that
besides the you know the list that we
had in the Alexa top 1 million majestic
and umbrella there's actually a bunch of
stuff that you can actually get if you
research a little bit as a kind of
advice because I see yeah what do you
mean uh-huh no I haven't but that's
interesting too yeah yeah so far these
are the ones that I looked at and I was
going to mention that for the first one
essentially well you have to create an
account on the website but obviously
that's all free now the funny thing is
that nowadays since well it's a it's a
business it's an industry so you know
there's a company let's say Amazon they
go and they one dot Amazon so they go
and pay thousand dollars to get that and
essentially every big company does the
same thing so now you have at the
top-level domain thousands of domain
names when you get to that side you can
the easiest thing that you can do is
just apply for all because you have to
tell them which sound files you want
obviously if it's free I want no that's
just a mentality right and I did apply
for all now the funny thing is that
somehow I don't know how it works but
you get a notification when you're
access request is approved and then they
end up mail bumping you with thousands
of females in a second which ended up
cows in trouble our cows it trouble in
my mail server because of these guys
were bombing emails are proving and for
some reason for each zone that you get
approval I was getting like two or three
different emails so it was like three
thousand TL DS x three so it was nine
thousand emails in a couple of seconds
the same I from a programming point of
view where you have aggregated the
notifications into a single email but
the guy at ICANN the thought otherwise
okay so there's a lot that you can get
there still we are not getting much
about you know other let's say less
popular songs like military sites and
one place or another universities and so
on and obviously those are interesting I
was measuring just a little bit but in
places and that's you know traditionally
it works that way like you know in
educational sites you get interesting
stuff usually I don't know if that's
everywhere but they don't care that much
about you know how everything is set up
so you get some interesting and very
open setups so to speak so what can you
do about them well what I did is use the
tools that I was describing before like
for example get being to actually try to
get as many domain names for each of for
each of those zones okay obviously you
are going to be like very very far away
from the actual phone so for different
reasons one is that in some cases you
know there could be systems that have
nothing to do with the web or you know
FTP or those kinds of services so they
might not be indexed into Google at all
but you know at the end of the day it's
something just you know to to give you
some idea I
think I have left like this to get being
running for about a day and I got about
65 K different dominance for example for
the UK okay so you can get like a fair
share of you know domain names obviously
after that you can elaborate a little
bit more let's say you could start from
the domain names that you have you could
let's say get the homepage for that
domain name and just you know scrap the
HTML because there might be links to
other places or domains that you know
you might you might not have yet so
let's see I wanted to show you how you
can how you can do this sort of thing in
a very automatic way I wrote it down
here so that I don't forget so in the
same in the same script six tool you
have a bunch of tools they don't do much
interesting things but they are useful
like for example let's say that you want
to know all the top-level domains for a
continent like I want to do measurements
in Europe okay so I need to know what
are the top-level different top-level
domains so just run the tool like this
obviously some you can recognize there's
Belgium and so on right
you could already start using the gate
being tool with this output you can do
something like this
when you run it with the batch rather
than taking the domain name from you
know the common line
it reads domain names from standard
input so what's going to happen here you
get the first command that all puts the
top-level domains and the second which
takes each of those top-level domains
and uses Bing to actually find domain
names so you start getting something
like this that was the first one that
was in the list okay dot al I think it's
Albania or something like that
okay now the two will run and run and
run and run and run eventually when it
doesn't find any more domain names for
Albania or if this is Albania it will
switch to the next one okay obviously
this is a trivial way I mean the idea of
these tools was to be able to automate
this thing off for example discovering
different zones there's another thing
that you can do let's say for example
that you want to target some specific
country okay we were talking before
about the UK and we were saying that in
the UK that if you have a commercial
enterprise it's not comm is dot Co okay
there's this tool which gets you this uh
fixes for some specific tool level
domain so I run it with UK and what you
get is AC dot UK etc etc etc so in a
similar way instead of showing it on the
screen I can pipe it
and now the tool again we'll start you
know building like like the data for
each of the suffixes usually the more
specific you are about the domain you
specify the more results that you get so
that's why it's usually a good idea if
you want to target like specific country
rather than just given the tool like the
top-level domain like UK you use the
other tool to produce the suffixes too
so I could run the tool like this I
could just specify UK oops I think that
for this one as far as I remember I
fought on the web some file which was
kind of like a text file so I figure out
the instruction how to parse the file
and as far as I remember the toolkit now
contains a local copy so essentially
what it contains is like you know the
top-level domain and below that it
contains like the different suffixes and
for some places it's quite interesting
this one I remember because you know in
order to parse the file I had to go
through it because it didn't have like a
very very specific format for example
for Brazil look at all the ones that you
have because for example they have like
for the second level they have like
different names for the CDs and so on so
for many countries is quite interesting
I mean you might assume ok well every
country has dot org dot the name of the
country but for example in this case if
you were just focusing on those you'd be
missing a lot ok this is just one
example that I remember that
country that has its you know the the
second level of domains with so many I
think that in Germany that's you don't
have like a second it's like kind of
like flood right uh-huh yeah well yeah
let's see yeah nothing ok then you also
have things like for example this is if
I remember correctly so in this case you
get top-level domains for different
regional registries ok for example this
is something that I you know needed to
some extent because I was doing
measurements for the area of latnok so I
actually I didn't just need the you know
the the continent because for political
reasons I guess there are parts of Latin
America that belong to airing and not to
latnok so for example for measurement
purposes you know you can do something
like this right the same thing for you
know afrinic and so on so different ways
to you know query a database so that you
get the top-level domains that you might
be interested in well for continent I
settled on ok
again with this one with the Bing you
can let the to run for a long time and
you know build around database with
tyoma you're going to get done so you
know using tyoma it's just for targeting
a specific site because after that you
know you're going to be blocked other
stuff you know this part of the
presentation or this second presentation
again was about building a database with
ipv6 related information so previous
lies was a discussion about stuff
related to domain names now the question
was what about addresses years ago like
maybe five years ago or something I had
you know done measurements analyzing the
addresses that were employed by popular
web servers mail servers and name
servers okay what I did at the time that
that was polish in RAC 7707 is
essentially start from the alexa top 1
million domains obtain all the query
records and analyze the addresses to see
what are the patterns that the address
is followed at the time we're talking
maybe five years ago most of the servers
had very predictable addresses okay like
low byte addresses where the interface
ID is virtually all zeros except for the
last byte so when I was looking into
this I say okay let's measure that again
to see if that situation changing now
you might wonder why why why could he
have changed well in the recent years
there were two RFC's on the topic that
were published essentially to replace
the traditional scheme for slack so we
slack usually you put or you used to put
the MAC address in the interface ID and
what these two RFC says is that instead
of putting the MAC address you should
put a random number there so the
question was essentially will
has the publication of this document
result in any changes in what we see on
the internet so I did the measurements
again and to some extent I was surprised
about the results because I don't follow
I don't really understand the results so
these are measurements or this is an
analysis of the ipv6 addresses
corresponding to web servers so I got
the alexa top 1 million domains and for
each of those domains i obtained the
query records and for each query record
i analyzed the address to see what was
the pattern that the other was following
so you have you know the you know the
the references here what's interesting
is that this bit over here which i think
is something like i don't know for this
one know for alex maybe it was something
like 15% or something like that
this one the larger part is addresses
that embed an ipv4 address in the
interface ID so that's a very common way
in which people configure their servers
like if you know for example that your
server has the address say 10.10 dot
in the IP leaf in the ipv6 world you
have the ipv6 prefix and you put your
ipv4 address as the interface ID why
because well if you remember the ipv4
address then it's easy to come up with
the ipv6 address because it's just the
v6 perfect and the ipv4 address this is
these are the same measurements but
using the list of domain names that is
available from umbrella ok umbrella was
the least that I was telling you there
was that is distributed by Cisco know
what for or why now what's interesting
here look at the
of random addresses it's actually quite
large when I did the same measurement
about five years ago usually you'd find
like only 5% of addresses that were
random all of the other addresses were
predictable one way or another they were
like low byte addresses with the
interface ID said Oh to all zeros they
were addresses that we're embedding an
ipv4 address or something like that but
certainly not that many addresses so
certainly not as many as these ones now
the part that I'm curious about because
you could say okay well the reason for
this is because we published those two
RFA's so now people replace whatever
they were doing with a new scheme okay
now the part that I'm curious about is
that you still have the same number of
focuses these ones the ones that the
ones that embed the MAC address in the
measurements that we did like five years
ago we measure the same number of you
know i PB six addresses with MAC
addresses so I'm really wondering why
this is the case why we have so many
randomized addresses because it's not
that we have like lots of fallacies with
MAC addresses and that they were
replaced with the new scheme that's not
that's not the situation there so I
don't know why I mean this could be an
indication that people used to do manual
communic in manual configuration and now
they rely on the slack addresses I'm no
idea but this was kind of like a
surprise I when I was measuring this I
was expecting to get like roughly the
same results that I that I got like you
know five years ago and these are same
measurements but again for a different
data set you can see that you know the
results change quite a little bit but in
all cases like this is Alice's that
America before the majority and in the
previous ones it's kind of like the same
these are you see the ones that are more
more popular so to speak now what you
can essentially conclude from you know
these measurements is that when it comes
to target like public servers like
public web servers main servers name
servers and so on you can still rely on
the patterns of addresses for the most
part because all of these here and
actually this was to are predictable so
it's only these addresses that are
random and that you cannot really target
like you know with a usual ping sweep
still all of these services are
predictable so while obviously things
like doing DNS reverse enumeration is
very very useful still people are using
predictable addresses and that makes you
know life easier for the guy doing the
pen test or the attack or whatever that
is well this is something that I was
that I was mentioning to again according
to the measurements that I did that I
was presenting in the previous lights
there is even in the worst case scenario
you have at least like 15 percent of
random addresses that's still not good
you might want to have much more of
random addresses but he said big change
if you want from the measurements that I
did five years ago where the amount of
random addresses were about like 3% or
5% the only thing is that I cannot
really explain the results because it's
not that we replace the MAC addresses
with these random numbers so we still
have the same amount of addresses with
you know that use MAC addresses but for
some reason there are some addresses
that are that converted to using you
know random interface identifiers so I
don't have an explanation for that
bpp so so far most of what we did here
was to you know cover finding servers if
you want whatever kind of end system
that is there is also the thing that if
you are building a database you might
want to find routers obviously that's
straightforward you use traceroute and
the only thing that these tool does is
essentially run trace route but
eliminate the last address because the
last address doesn't correspond to an
actual router but to the server that
you're targeting okay so for the purpose
of you know mapping the ipv6 internet
what I did was once I got so many
addresses of servers of different kinds
then I did trace route to each of them
so that I you find their routers in all
of the directions okay actually what I
did I have beautiful machines in
different places like different
countries because for example if I do
the trace route from let's say Argentina
you goes through some route ok but you
for example your packets are likely not
going through let's say Asia usually ok
so what I did was two things first first
thing was using virtual machines that I
have in different places that's one
thing the other thing you probably use
it hurricane electric they give you like
free ipv6 tunnels which for production
maybe is not that great if you want but
one thing that is interesting is that
they have pops in lots of different
places so you can get like a tunnel with
an end point in Japan you can get a
tunnel with an end point in different
places so I was doing my I got like
different tunnels not because I was
interested in the tunnel itself but
actually so that I had a point of
presence in places that I otherwise
wouldn't even wouldn't be able to
measure so I run the same trace route
using a tunnel in Japan I run the same
trace reducing
some tunnel in the US the same town in
Europe so now if you do the math they
say the world is America something here
there's Europe here and the sapphic are
here and here near here and you start
with the servers and then you have the
pops that Huracan Electric gives you for
example so you do this from here from
here from all over the place
so obviously you cover a much
interesting region in that respect you
probably didn't get all of the routers
but you do get a a large number of them
okay some notes on DNS reverse mappings
of course I was using all of the
techniques that we know so far
essentially using them and trying to use
the information that I already got as
input for doing something else and you
know among the things that I did was use
DNS reverse mappings now let's see some
of the things that I found one day I
left the script somewhere running DNS
reverse enumeration for some prefix
right some weeks later I go back to the
server and I get like something like two
jjigae bytes two Jigga wide file of the
result so I say well that's great I
learned a lot now not so great because
these people this guy was this
particular sample was Yahoo they have
all these I think they are like
dynamically generated you know DNS
records so for another space that they
have but they don't really use so my 2
or 3 gigabyte file was essentially all
of these for all of their addresses ok
same for Deutsche Telekom with the
dynamic prefix aha so is not just a will
card so it's a different name for each
others so that's a that makes the thing
interesting because I mean I haven't
done it yet but one will have to start
to think about doing some sort of
filtering on this because obviously
having three gigabytes of this stuff
it's not worth it and I did try many of
these sad races because I mean there are
phenomena if there are some funny names
one some of them they say the irony of I
don't know what I mean even here you see
its migration bla bla bla so I did try
the addresses to see if you know some of
them were useful if they were reachable
know the whole address space is empty
essentially so they have reverse
mappings but the addresses are not
useful for anything so for the purpose
of you know my project this was a waste
of time and a waste of resources because
obviously I had then to enter all of
these so what I'm doing in my project is
entering all of this information in a
database and for each of these you know
each domain name each IP address and so
on I run like a lot of tools like a lot
of different tests like for example a
poor scan just to give you an idea now
if you go like you know 10 million
entries of these ones then you are
wasting your resources for 10 million
addresses where you're not going to find
anything so my you know without knowing
the in Deutsche Telekom you said that it
was the case well I didn't know about
that one but I did find just by simple
inspection of the of the files because
you know when I got so many results I
say well what's going on there there's
noise too in the you know DNS reverse
enumeration so in my to list you have to
figure out how to
you know and for some sort of filter I
think that in the DNS reverse
enumeration that mark o/s implemented he
tried to do something like do a DNS
reverse mapping of let's say five or six
different addresses random addresses and
if all of them mapped to something then
you assume that there is some kind of
like wilter going on still you know this
is stuff that I you have wanted to
eliminate another thing that I got from
you know us conclusion from some of the
tests that I did without actually
inspecting so much about the reason for
for for you know the reason for which
things were happening in my experience
when you are mapping when you are trying
to map a network with DNS reverse
mappings if you do the reverse mapping
with a slash 32 in many cases it fails I
guess that in when you go more up in the
you know in the DNS tree for some reason
I don't know if some packets are
filtered or what but I wasn't getting
much information that way so as a result
of that what I decided was rather than
try to do DNS reverse enumeration which
with slash thirty twos do it with slash
48 and you might say well what if I have
a slash 32 well you can use a script and
produce for example you know 65k slash
48 ok so you are covering the same
information but rather than you know
starting more up in the tree you want to
do it like with you know with longer
prefixes because otherwise it doesn't
work
[Music]
what else all the stuff this is I mean
I'm mentioning these things in this
slice because for quite a few of these
things are things that I had never pay
attention anymore
and when I found them I said well how
come that I never I have never looked at
this so I don't know if you have ever
checked this side is awesome being DV
essentially I'm kind of like surprised
that it actually works so it's
essentially a project that is not for
profit okay and what you find there is
information about I don't know if all
but about a lot of ixps internet
exchange points okay internet exchange
points like everywhere what kind of
information can you find over there like
anything like you know the postal
address of where the place is
email address telephone addresses and so
on but for the purpose of this project
what was quite interesting is that for
each IXP which you can actually list
them like you know you go through the
side and you say okay I want to produce
a list of all the IXPs that there are on
the planet you can obtain the the subnet
that is employed for the peering like
let's say in this IXP they are using
blah blah blah slash 64 and you can also
learn the ipv6 addresses that these
routers are using for peering over there
so what I'm saying is with you know in
the previous slides I was learning ipv6
services of just random routers which is
okay but the interesting thing here is
there from an importance point of view
these routers are actually much more
interesting let's say bad guy that had
an exploit for a router would probably
be much more interested in you know
attacking some of these systems than in
actually attack in some random router
out there
on this website I mean other than the
you know like webpage where you can
actually do your queries and you know
with with much without much work they
also have like a restful interface for
doing the queries so you can codify your
query in JSON and you get the results in
JSON so it's quite easy to you know
produce a script to actually go through
all of the all of the IXPs
and obtain the IP vc services of each
router in each IXP again the importance
here is well first of all that you have
a different vector for learning
addresses for routers but also that the
importance of these systems is that
these systems are much much more
important than the routers that you
might get with traceroute in the sense
that these are routers had internet
exchange points if someone went to hack
one of these systems there's much more
at stake okay what is another one is
ripe Atlas and I'm not talking about
ripe Atlas in the sense of the you know
you you might know these ripe Atlas
boxes it's essentially some kind of like
I don't know what is like a 4G router
that they rewrite the firmware and
essentially they give away these boxes
these devices usually are conferences so
they give that for free what people
normally does is they connect the device
somewhere usually at home or at their
job ok so the end result is that most of
these boxes get connected at ISPs
because it's a technical community so
you get people that attend like these
meetings they get one of those boxes and
they put it at the RSP or at home now
what's interesting is that in the ripe
Atlas website you can actually access
the data of most of the probes actually
I was stupid enough and thought that I
had to crawl the web pages so I did a
script to actually similar to what I did
for the
search-engine only to find sometime
later that there was like a restful
interface too late so then I had to do
it again because obviously it's nicer to
have a restful interface and what's
interesting about this is that it's not
it's not really the learning the address
of the ripe Atlas devices okay at least
my interest wasn't the address of the
ripe Atlas devices but actually learning
/ 64 addresses or their or the address
of subnets that belong to different
clients if you want you know obviously
the basics outer space is quite large
and you know learning you know how to
say user they are the prefixes of user
networks is not that that's simple so if
you start from you know the ripe Atlas
side you can you know at least like if
you can at least learn a few thousand
ipv6 addresses and you can identify
let's say a few thousand ipv6 have
networks it's not that you might be
interested it's not that you're
interested about the these devices
themselves but about the networks and
also the thing is that if you learn one
network then in the same way that a
customer has been assigned let's say
slash fifty something or its last sixty
four you might be able to come up with
the addresses of other subnets okay this
is about or the reason for which I found
this useful is to again learn
information about clients if you want
not servers for service we have you know
the DNS own files they all of the stuff
that we saw already but the interest
here was again to learn addresses that
were being employed by my clients at
what time do we have time three
but okay we're good so among the
conclusions that you know I can I mean
this is actually working progress so
this is right now I'm still measuring
stuff okay so the conclusions prolly I
will have them like in some P of time
like the full conclusions but from
either the the partner was quite
interesting was that if you are able to
put like all of the pieces all of the
different pieces that we have for
enumeration the results that you can get
are much much better and the other stuff
that I that I learn and that I mentioned
you know doing this presentation was
other sources of information that you
had them available and that at least me
and all the people that I know of were
not employing one of the one of them
that I was that I have been employing a
lot was the peering the V database that
I was that I mentioned before I was
surprised that I wasn't using that one
before that period he also has
information about ipv4 too so there's
lots that you can learn from from their
PP DPB any questions yes
so when you're putting all these this
stuff together so what's what's your
opinion what's a rough estimation on how
can we successfully scan the whole ipv6
Internet compared to ipv4 so as we know
they are played before internet can be
scanned completely and no problem so how
much percent do you think
can we scan today with all of these
techniques in the ipv6 Internet
I don't have much of a clue to be honest
but I would say that it is certainly way
way way way more than you would assume
way more because of for example when it
comes to servers and so on I don't think
nowadays it's much of a problem I mean
so far because the information that you
get with the DNS like using search
engines and so on and what you get with
DNS reverse enumeration at least when it
comes to servers I think that you are
roughly at the same level of where you
are in the ipv4 wall if it comes to
clients that's a different game because
in the in the case of clients you might
assume that for example they don't they
are not published in the DNS so you're
not going to be able to learn their
addresses you know with a search engine
it's quite quite likely that they are
also not in the DNS reverse path I mean
you might because if you want to map the
full address you might say that your ISP
Maps you know the reverse path till they
slash 64 if you want but then you you
still have the you know the 64 bits to
play with and there are two options
either you are delegated the authority
to do the DNS reverse mapping which I
have never seen like a case where that
actually happens like you know a normal
client the normal kind doesn't usually
do that you don't you don't connect at
home and
okay I'm going to make sure that my
address maps into a domain name it's not
the case for instance in the ipv4 wall
it was the ISP that inserted you know
the reverse mappings for your address
since the addresses were small for each
address that they were leasing they
would have something that worried what
that was identifying the client but
since we're ipv6 you have like you know
the 64 bits to play with those addresses
are not being mapped
I guess that something that is that a
nice pin my do is for example use
Wilkers but if they are if the ISP puts
a Wilker from the point of view of the
attacker that's the same it's the same
thing of the yahoo case let's say if I'm
trying to learn how the size of a client
and all of the possible addresses have a
corresponding DNS name you know that's
not useful I'm kind of like surprised
about the usefulness of the DNS reverse
enumeration I would say I mean obviously
for things like main servers you do need
reverse mappings because I mean
historically speaking there's like kind
of like I don't know how to call it it's
no security is like sanity check that if
you have a main server and somebody
connects to you usually you reject the
relay of messages if they don't have a
reverse mapping so obviously for you
know for mail servers you can you could
expect that I guess you might expect the
same thing for routers because when
people are doing traceroute usually for
troubleshooting it's it's nice to have
some name associated with with the
router but I have seen so many cases
well there's there's this one I mean
these guys are nice so it's not that I'm
you know mentioning them for a bad
reason but
well
Slovenia Slovenia we'll see
ESPO well funny thing I have a server
somewhere there what I don't remember
them okay what's this one okay
say
this is an educational network in
Slovenia okay I mean this is just one
example you do the same thing with ripe
you get the same thing you do the same
thing with a magnet you get the same
thing hopefully this will work let's
change this to
that
so if you think about it it's kind of
like ridiculous the you know the and it
happens it's not just this case and you
have systems that there's no reason for
being in the you know in the DNS reverse
mapping and you know the fact that they
put them there it makes it so easy to
actually find them same thing goes for
you know if you look for the reverse on
four ripe same thing reverse on for like
Nick the same thing and let's say from
from my perspective you'd probably say
that they would be better off removing
all this they are you know still giving
you know too much information I was also
surprised that I should say about the
number of sites that still allow some
zone transfers I thought myself that
that was gone like you know this the
kind of stuff that you don't try because
you say ok at this point they don't
nobody does it and still you know songs
all open
yeah well actually there's some one
thing that uh I don't remember the the
site is something like this census I
mean if you look on Google you are going
to find it this is actually the this
site is quite interesting whatever then
real name is there's a site in which
people actually post the results of
their port scans not just that they also
for example they're different people
post different results for different
kind of scans or measurements so some
guy for example he tried every single
ipv4 address for some transfers DNS zone
transfers and you can find the list of
all of the ipv4 addresses that have Open
DNS zone transfers available here now I
got the list and I assume like whoa if
this is posted here if we was probably
abused already so it's probably not
available anymore and yes it's still
available so yeah so one of the
advantages of ipv6 is the to my mind is
following in Germany we have the home
rooters of course and I think last year
there was some some disclosure that
there is some routing protocol Ruta
protocol where you can inject something
into the you route and it was
immediately abused over ipv4 however
when the route has nowadays you have
something like dual stack lights so that
means they don't have an ipv4 address on
their untrust interface anymore but only
ipv6 but to my mind you won't find the
ipv6 address of the route itself that
easy in the internet because the route
itself does not initiate many
connections nor does it has a reverse
DNS
so probably the rooters are a little at
the home connections a little bit more
secure or safe because you Volvo won't
find those ipv6 addresses well what I
was mentioning about ripe Atlas is
exactly that because in many cases I had
one
at some point in time many people have
the the ripe Atlas prove connected at
home yeah listen Germany then it's out
of a different prefix so you say that
okay that the periphery is employing is
different from the one that they are
using for the local subnet exactly I
don't know
listen Germany it is okay yeah there are
other I mean when it comes to this is
not let's say not that related but it's
for me was also interesting to see you
know the the size of the prefixes that
ISPs were leasing customers for example
word I've seen in Latin America I know I
haven't looked at many different ISPs
because there's not that many people not
that many ISPs that have deployed ipv6
but it's being quite usual for them to
lease a slash 64 for example which in a
sense makes it like easier to you know
to it reduces the search space in a
sense because if they are granting the
slash 64th let's say from the same place
it would be easy to easy to find them
but yeah I guess it depends on the on
the policy that I am that they employ
like you know if but at the same time
I'm thinking out loud you're saying that
they employ a different prefix for the
router then for the internal network now
from that point of view I would assume
that it's extremely likely that the
prefixes that they employ for the
clients they follow patterns now if you
learn one it's quite likely that you
learn all of the others so that's why
I'm saying maybe like finding the home
network maybe might be more difficult
but finding the routers they probably
you know get all of the addresses from
the same pool anywhere
six before for the transfer segment okay
well the thing with the Mack the I mean
depends but the other thing that you
might have there is that let's say that
they say Deutsche Telekom I mean I don't
know what are the devices that they
employ right but if they purchase the
CPS like you know in large numbers which
is what you would assume the MAC
addresses are going to be consecutive
like the it's the same thing happens if
you go to some you know regular shop
where you can buy electronics you find
like for example two IP cameras you look
at the IP at the MAC addresses are
usually they are contiguous because at
the end of the day they end up being
like serial numbers it's not that
they've been the randomizes the address
when they are manufacturing them so you
don't be surprised it if if you look at
the CPS let's say Deutsche Telekom or
whoever that is that you find out that
all of them MAC addresses are clustered
so you know that you know the MAC
addresses are going to be in this range
so it's going to be easy to reduce the
search space a lot I'm not saying that
it it's going to be trivial but and what
I'm saying is that the search space
might be smaller than you think
any more questions
Thanks oh just I just curious when they
try to perform the reverse domains
through the ipv6 our address from time
to time do you climb across we saw a
very interesting domains or those
unknown and but they are not supposed to
be to be publicly available publicly
seen in the Internet's so you're
wondering why they are there
I wonder I'm wondering have you seen a
lot of cases where those fresh those are
supposed to be secret domains for
organizations but eventually it is
publicly available that well I don't
know if secret but there have been I
mean for example even if you look at
even for example in I don't know if it
was in landing core ripe or in you know
one of the registries you get like some
boxes like you know engineering server
or which looks like it's not stuff that
should be published you know what I mean
it looks like it's information that
should be internal for the organization
but you know somehow they polish it for
the whole world I don't know the reason
for that I mean I consider that that's a
bad idea
I mean you make it way easier to find I
mean not only to find the systems
because one thing is just to find like
an address that is alive that's one
thing but when you then when you get a
string that gives you a description of
you know what the system is supposed to
be about that's even more interesting
you know if I find an address that is
alive I don't even know what that is I
don't know if the system is but if you
get it you know a domain name that says
like you know payment blah blah blah our
database blah blah blah and there are
some like that you know that's for me
that's like too much information and
that's part of you know the you know the
the project that I was working on part
of what was very interesting for me
wasn't just the IP addresses but for the
most part the domain names because
having you know learning addresses it's
like I don't know to what extent that's
in I mean can be interesting but we
you have a name associated with the
address that gives you more of an idea
of what that box is about any more
questions so then thank you for Nando
thank you
[Applause]