welcome our next speakers vihan and
vladimir from earpiece can there will be
speaking about sa p box so basically the
SP netweaver again
so let us welcome them hi everyone thank
you
today Latimer and I will talk about a
safety security about security in CP new
tool for few slides about us I'm senior
security researcher earpiece can company
and I like and like back hunter bug
bounty Malvo researching and my name is
I'm scoot in reverse engineering and
encryption we are star wars fun though I
think you enjoy patient here is our
agenda the agenda in contains of five
main points in in the first point will
talk about s AP about newest CVE
in ASAP network platform after that
we'll review how kind of how what kind
of application are present in CP for
application server Java and how you can
use these applications and after that
we'll review Redwood component and will
show vulnerability in Redwood and after
that we'll review sa PCRM component and
we'll show how you can escalate
privileges in s AP and how you can get
remote comment execution we a lot
ejection in s AP network
and in the fifth slide we will show how
you can protect and what kind of a CPA
security notes you need to install in
your ACP servers to protect to protect
so I think everyone know about ACP
company he has a lot of applications for
banking for gas and oil for
manufacturing industry and s IP every
every month releasing a fiscal two notes
for example last three years the Sepik
company released around 300 security
notes each year and last year in 2017
accounted that sa P patched around 3:13
critical
he released 13 safety notes to protect
critical vulnerabilities enters our top
four critical vulnerability which we
found about first vulnerability we
talked in last troopers troopers 17 and
we showed how s AP administrators can
get remote comment execution in s AP
company in company customers where s AP
GUI last next to vulnerability was
present in a safety net we were
application server Java and use using
these two vulnerabilities and attackers
for example can get full access to ACP
network platform and for and for
vulnerability was present in say P HANA
platform in a say P tracks component
and some of you may remember that last
year when we talked talked how you can
get admin privileges in a say P server
we say that so we sent some unknown
directory traversal to a say P company
but we don't have any patch yet but now
they say P released a few security notes
and we can talk about this vulnerability
here is a Sapien at river platform
platform structure he contains of two
main parts is a say PA a BP stack and
ASAP Java stack and we today will will
review just only sa p Java stack so they
say P Java stack has a lot of
applications which were written in Java
language and here is a screenshot of our
tests ap server you can see that in this
server we have around a thousand and
four hundred Java applications all Java
applications are allocated in a say P
not come forward in file system and to
understand how you can how you can call
how you can use these applications via
browser let's review one vulnerability
which we found in 2016 this
vulnerability of information disclosure
and in videochat component so you can
draw easy parallel between web URL and
physical path when this application is
located and as every java application is
a s AP application to
have some web deeper or web web dot XML
files which describing the application
names for example here you can see that
this video chat component has two
application name a chat and mesh
messages so and if you will open this
URL in your browser you can get s AP
users list with nicknames without any
credentials so the Redwood component is
java application - and to install the
result component in your CP server you
has you you have two ways first you can
download the Redwood component from a CP
launch launch pad and deploy it in your
say P server or when you installing this
ap server you can check the center of
protest scheduling checkbox and after
that in your SCP server out at eclis we
will deploy we will do playing Redwood
component so the Redwood component you
can you can get you can find a redwood
component in apps folder me ASAP does
come forward and a redwood right
component has scheduler servlet and if
you will open schedule servlet in your
browser you can see this this portal so
when we opened this portal we heard that
this some kind of very interesting
application because previous we only
researched application in s AP dot-com
folder and we started research it
we we opened we open the HTML code in
main page and we saw some metadata some
links some scripts but we but first
script tag is look like very interesting
because he has UI util JavaScript GS
servlet who gets JavaScript old and
utils parameter which are the parameter
U tilde JS file we found in SA P server
and also we found JavaScript and old
folders so what we have we have some
physical file in inter server and we
have URL in the you know we have URL
which can use to read the util dot JS
file so and after that we took the
scheduler server and put dot dot slash
many times and finally we can read wing
any file from server so you can see that
directory traversal is very - reducing
vulnerability just need to type dot
slash ok and immediately we reported
this vulnerability to ACP it was
February of 2016 and so cool directory
traversal vulnerability is cool but how
you can how you can get another sentence
another critical information critical
data from the CP server you need to read
and
creeped sex store dot properties and sex
store said you need to decrypt sixth or
properties file and after decryption you
can see that mr. utter passwords from
the CP server so but before let's see
the demo of directory traversal
exploitation here's a CP Java server and
you can see that we don't have any
privileges on server who opened
scheduler servlet
after that we called UI YouTube
JavaScript servlet web browser and you
can see that we can we can open any read
any folder and we can get file lists
after that we try to read secure storage
of ACP server the our s AP has DM 0s ID
so here's our hair is a secure storage
and who can read the key file and
properties file
about sixth or decryption algorithm
we'll talk what Amir
yeah if you remember the stuff Star Wars
the Death Star was really great but
there was one weakness in the center and
using it Luke Skywalker completely
destroyed it so sex store in sa p system
is just the same thing so we have sex
store dot propias file containing
information about administrator lock
like password and our credentials
database connection string and something
in our sensitive data we have also sex
store that key file containing
encryption key for sex talk dot
properties and so if an attacker can
gain access to to this file here she can
completely can gain administrator
privileges to a CP system and to asset
in database so we analyzed encryption
algorithm and we wrote our tool sex
store decrypter this quick get sex about
key file we also found a half coded key
in java source code so we need to solve
this well this really with safe solid
key and this way we can get very low key
phrase this key phrase is used as a key
for sex or dot properties the algorithm
is Triple DES in CBC mode and whisper
you can get administrator password but
in fact the real algorithm named is
whisper I don't want to pronounce it so
the main idea is that not the plain
key key phrase value is used but it's
hash value so let's have a little demo
so we have six of the deck file we have
key file and our properties file so we
start down screen with you can see we
can decrease Excel files and useful in
can decrypt information from j2ee config
table in John state so we just started
and get credential from a city
administrator connection string to a
city database
well it's username and password in clear
text
so you can find we decided to share our
tool so you can find it in a tower I
give up
please enjoy it so yeah now we have
credentials of a city administrator we
can return to nice window and try to
login so we input our new credentials
and this we're missing the appears we
don't have felt reasons so we just put
sucked in bla bla bla and try to
activate free whistles and oops we got
it
so and you became a city administrator
very easy way so let's refresh our
knowledge about our findings we have a
long direct with reversal in schedule we
have decryption tool to get adminstrator
password from sex store and I think it's
time to look closer at CRM so yeah the
second episode so She'arim customer
relationship management what is it in
general is an approach to management
company's interaction with current and
potential users so CRM accumulates
information about customers like emails
telephone social media provide analyzing
these data to determine exactly target
audience so we can share this data to
our customers so it's kind of
collaboration that's how sharing OOP
swipe
console so on the left hand you can see
some submenu slide 36
and our settings and the most
interesting is login so let's go where
you can see lot of parameters like
destination pub location so we try to
change destination parameter we use the
same technique dot dot slash but it
didn't work so we try to put the
absolute path on file system and
suddenly we was no use mistakes
exceptions
it seems that sharing service just saved
new configuration we also change not
just a folder of log files but it's
extension so let's going check if we
knew all the file appears and here you
can see we change log file name on
shelter GSP and change folder file
system and it's really cool because we
we can change although you can change
extension and I will describe why this
is so cool
imagine a city system to simplify our
model we just choose Java step so there
are a lot of publications in ASAP system
there are a lot of users calling these
applications and while allocation what
if exchange information with database
and all years exceptions and mistakes
writing in log files like twice like
lock so that's how it works before
and after attack we have a safe city
system with same applications exchange
information with database they send
users calling these applications but now
we change log file location on
application directory and we change
extension of where log files so when a
CP system find dot JSP file in
application folder it parsed it as a
belt GSP application so it means that
you can get access to this file and all
code will be parsed as GSP and as you
remember we can still write in
exceptions and errors in this log file
and we can call it removal and if we can
write any code in this log file we can
execute any comment so let's have a look
how we can change a log file directly
the first 30 seconds is so boring so I
just
so we go to schedule we'll login with
our new credentials administrator
it's not so fast so we need to wait
yeah
we are
a service schedule so we are authorized
in a city system we can go to MIT to be
in CRM service
- with this page
so we go to admin console
so one in sub menu on the left hand
and now we can change this nation
if you can see the default log file name
is tres resume zero the TRC
so now we change on our one test a lot
without an extension
and now if we put special URL in the
browser we can for example download this
file without any extension
so if extension of this file will be the
GSP a city system will parse this file
as valid application and environment
story about twist
so before the second directive travursel
exploitation we have log file which
extension log XML or TRC and we couldn't
read this file via browser but after the
second directory traversal exploitation
we can read we can write sir we can
write the log file in any folder on the
system so we found the fouled servlet
where we wrote the log file and we
rename log file to shelter GSP and to
get remote comment execution in SA P we
need to we need to write the simple Java
shell code in log file in shell dot JSP
and as you can see that this shell code
gets only CMD parameter and after that
he will execute value of Sindhi
parameter so to write this JSP code in
the log file we need to send some bad
request to ASAP server because after
after after after then that acp several
will receive some bad request he tried
to parse the parameter and he of course
couldn't do it and he will write in log
file message that i'm sword your
administrator
I couldn't parse bla bla bla parameter
and instead of blah blah blah we we can
write we can write any code
here we write GSP shellcode here is a
shellcode in log file and here is what
what it looks like if you take a closer
look so and after that if you will call
Sheldor GSP via browser with IP config
you can see the result of comment
execution yeah
to sent bed request to a CP server we we
wrote the Python code we need to write
also we need to input administrator
login password and after that the Python
code will send but request and and we
will get shell code and so on a sip
server so here is law blah blah blah
Oh
yeah
and there is a result of ipconfig
comment
yep
so let's make a little conclusion and
when we when we found and when and they
say P released security notes of first
director terror so the director
traversal in Redwood we scanned the
internet to understand how many servers
with a redwood component are present in
the wild and we found around 500 public
s AP server which which have in which
have available a redwood component and
to protect this to vulnerability you
need to first install and upgrade your
CRM component and you need to set
special rule in your firewall to limit
to limit 8 the CRM CRM connection to you
need to upgrade the redwood component
and after that you need to upgrade the
you need to install the second s AP node
and from nist.gov Wow
yeah and from the nice gov website we
saw that this directory traversal
exploited it in in the wild we don't
have any information just just it and
so let's see thank you if you have any
questions
[Applause]