yeah yeah yeah growing also the ones
yeah funny Santa
good morning everybody welcome to the
second session in these strings at the
first day of 2017 for the next session
we have brian spring and Marilyn Nelson
talking about their implementation of
ServiceNow from nothing to fully
influence in six weeks with AMT and
their security operation center just
before we start just usual reminders
make sure your mobile phones on silent
and don't forget to use the app to rate
sessions anyway could everybody please
welcome Marilyn Brian good morning how
you going so my name is Brian frame this
is Marilyn Nelson and we're going to
take you through the 6-week journey in
terms of what an P was able to beadle to
deliver as partners for and paid to
deliver security operations specifically
around security incident response and
also vulnerability response okay so
let's let's kick it off so there's going
to be a couple of topics if I'm talking
about give introductions we'll go
through some of the challenges with
respect to security response and then
also talk about some custom results and
also specifically around a and P and
we'll talk about a few different key
takeaways but first we just want to kind
of give a little introduction into who
we are thank you so I'm Marilyn Nelson
over in Australia from the United States
based out of Texas originally and I have
been doing
cyber security and security incidents
for quite some time I spent quite a few
years in the military doing black
operations which are operations that
don't really exist where we used cyber
security everyone always asks out of
that why are you doing security
operations on a ServiceNow platform now
for organizations around the globe is
because on 9/11 I was in the Pentagon
and I walked out of a briefing with my
entire staff at which time the planes
hit direct impact and I lost my 12
people and I never went back to the
Pentagon but cyber security plays a
roué
any big important role and in life not
only for people individuals but also for
major organizations and so it is very
very important to be able to tell and
understand in advance what the bad guys
are doing and I think that's the key
thing of where the KPMG risk consulting
as well as on the ServiceNow platform
the security operations implementation
or operations within ServiceNow comes
into play great thank you here's a
little bit about KPMG KPMG were one of
the major consulting firms one of the
big four we do everything all of the
from risk consulting management
consulting strategies and obviously tax
as you all may know but I don't want to
spend a lot of time on KPMG I just have
the honor of working for them great
thank you
and so my name is Brian spring and I'm
with ServiceNow don't we service now for
almost a year now of 20 plus years
experience in IT and just to let you
guys know I come from traditional IT
vendors where there's a lot of different
individual pieces of the puzzle put
solutions together but the reason why I
joined ServiceNow is a couple of reasons
number one it has a platform so that
multiple different types of capabilities
can actually be deployed throughout an
organization but most important it's not
about putting the pieces of the puzzle
together and ServiceNow is a great
platform currently that a lot of people
already may know about for IT Service
Management and HR but in the last 12
months actually 14 months what we've
done is that we've actually created a
security incident response and a
vulnerability response platform for the
security folks because of the 1213 years
12 plus years experience we've had in IT
Service Management and we're going to
talk a little bit about that one of the
first things one of the first
conferences that I've been to as the
ServiceNow representative a lot of
people asked me service nobody gets
doing security conferences and so my
answer to the question is fairly simple
we've been in response or service
automation for 1213 years workflow
automation collaboration notification
etc and also
management and we actually own the
market from an IT service management
perspective what we're doing now is that
we're branching out into other into
other businesses so for example we're
branching out into IT business
management
I see operations management security
operations HR customer service
management and it's because of the core
platform and its capabilities it's
basically taking off like wildfire
all right so ServiceNow globally about
4,000 plus customers mostly on the IT
Service Management just within the last
year we picked up over 200 customers for
security operations specifically around
security incident response and also
vulnerability response we're going to
talk a little bit about that right now
so a couple of the key things that we
want you to be able to understand today
is what is the ServiceNow platform and
how can it help you with your security
incident response your threat
intelligence and also your vulnerability
response using a unified platform that
you may already have implemented in your
organization or if you haven't
implemented it in the organization how
you could use the ServiceNow platform as
an entryway into really getting an
insight into how these you can you can
early detect you can early respond and
you can understand what threats are
coming into your organization and take
action on those in a more expeditious
manner instead of the three-month time
frame from detection to mitigation which
is normally what we're seeing we
actually on the InP case study will a
little teaser will show you how we took
that three months and reduce it
absolutely significantly down to where
they feel like they are able to respond
in a in a manner which is saving not
only resource time and energy but also
threats and vulnerabilities from when
inside their organization all right
thank you so service now with respect to
Enterprise Security Response and talk a
little bit about some of the challenges
with you guys probably if not I already
know you already know what the
challenges are but I'm going to recap
that because what that's going to do is
help me to actually explain to you
exactly what we do all right
so first thing why is there a system of
actually needed to address response so
first thing before I even go even
further let me kind of
addition where we are in the market
because I think that will help set the
scene right first of all we're not a
firewall we're not in the protection
space we're not in the detection space
we're not an ids/ips vulnerability
scanner and all those capabilities we're
not a sim all right so we don't do any
of the sim work right so what it has
been missing truly over the last X
number of years response so we fit
perfectly into this capability because
we've been doing it for 12 13 years or
12 to 15 14 15 years whatever maybe and
that was based on it's based on building
out a platform to allow organizations
the leverage workflow automation
collaboration mobility etcetera etc it's
a fantastic platform can I just ask how
many people in there actually their
organizations or agencies use ServiceNow
great-granddad so one of the things I
will stress to you if you're going down
the path of the security folks are going
down the path to actually remediates
security instance and also
vulnerabilities and you're trying to do
that within the core ServiceNow platform
I would really ask you to stop because
what we've done is we've actually scoped
an application specifically for the
stock and also for the vulnerability
response teams okay the specific
security around it methodologies and etc
so that you can actually take what you
have with respect to the existing
security tools and integrate those
directly into the security operations
platform so I would just ask that if
afterwards if you might have a
conversation I'm love to have a
conversation with him and understand
what you're currently doing okay so
again we are response so basically the
standard understanding goes something
like this
you guys have everybody has a lot of
tools right what do you do when there's
something that happens what do you do
when something goes wrong all right also
with respect to the majority of breaches
where they usually come from
vulnerabilities and this is what we
targeted to or actually three specific
areas which is security incident
response vulnerability response and then
leveraging the threat intelligence
capabilities of certain types of feeds
so core problem number one is
organizations and agencies are facing
you guys are probably feeling this right
just a ton of stuff just coming
at you right ids/ips vulnerability data
and if there's a problem it's pretty
hard to actually sort through that stuff
right second core problem and I've been
in many many socks if there is an
incident or something going on what's
happening running something run
something run something put the pieces
of the puzzle together try to figure out
exactly what the hell happened and
actually report on that stuff that's
what's actually going on right so
there's all these processes that
actually have to take place the problem
is is that well maybe it's not being
tracked correctly right and it's
definitely in some cases ins in people's
head so core problem number three that
we're seeing is this well to get the
security folks you got the IT folks HR
IT support everyone's communicating via
phone text email all that stuff right
the problem is how do you actually
collaborate how do you track how do you
actually manage exactly what you're
doing by the way how do you learn from
it so that next time when it happens you
actually already have a solution to deal
with it
so this is the core value proposition of
service not because we've been doing it
for so long
so really the conclusion is this and by
the way we've been working with IP for
quite some time I see a little bit ahead
of the game they have incident problem
change configuration management
processes in place they leverage
isolette cetera we're just trying to
help out the security folks that's all
we're really trying to do leveraging the
capabilities that we have and actually
bringing on some really really smart
people they actually create applications
for the sock for people do vulnerability
response and leverage that it leverage
that level of information so this is the
core problem and it's not the same
problem that or it is basically the same
problem the IT folks have been facing
years ago and actually currently so this
is the key ingredient guys the key
ingredients really this you know people
talk about posture and all that right
posture from our perspective is not
necessarily number of incidents
vulnerabilities endpoint you know what's
actually happening in terms of like the
threat from a specific location it's all
about the business service so you should
be focusing on exactly what matters what
are the critical business services and
the incidents and the vulnerabilities
that are associated with it that's your
prioritization that's what the see
those and also the board want to know
about that's what risk is okay so we
address that and the reason why we
address it is because ServiceNow its
platform has a built-in CMDB we already
know what's happening we already know
the business services we already know
the app the application structure or the
infrastructure that's associated with
the business services it's as easy as
that so if I know that there are certain
business services and a certain
components that make up those business
service and is a vulnerability or
security incident or whatever it may be
against it I know that can prioritize
and I know what will potentially be
impacted
so how ServiceNow helps to resolve it's
fairly simple process first one we
integrate the security products so we
usually sit down and I usually have a
conversation with you know to see so or
the head of SEC ops or the vulnerability
folks and like hey what are you guys
doing right now that's my steps
basically my first question what do you
know now and so what we do is that we
understand what the current processes
are and we want to automate those
processes is step one automation of
those processes right and out of the
boxes see with our with our platform we
have a number of different workflows we
have a number of different integrations
specifically 40 integrations with like
you know the tenable x' the quality of
the Splunk s-- CrowdStrike
all these guys right so the top 40 that
are out there we already integrate into
the platform so the first things
integrate the security products step
number two automatically prioritize the
security incidents and vulnerabilities
and that's what we were just talking
about so once I integrate the security
products and I have instance coming in I
can also start to prioritize whether
it's a good CMDB because a lot of
organizations have excuse my language
with shitty ones right or what you do to
leverage IT asset libraries etc but we
would love for organization to leverage
the current investment of the CMDB that
they've already paid for okay
so automatically prioritize security
incidents and vulnerabilities next step
automate the investigations so when a
security incident comes and looks say
from a Splunk or an event or an alert
that turns into a security incident we
kick off workflow and that workflow
actually goes through a series of
different individual steps so that the
responder doesn't have to do all those
individual steps themselves by the time
today
get to that incident there's already a
workflow that's kicked off pulling in
information from third-party vendors
whether it's PA or Palo Alto or whoever
it may be
and we're actually enriching the hell
out of the incident right now so that by
the time the responder gets there they
actually have all this information at
their fingertips and they can make a
decision so they're not doing the manual
menial tasks that they've been doing or
you guys aren't doing currently so
automatically prior to security for
incidents of vulnerability automate
investigation and then what do we do we
determine the response to action this is
where the human intervention comes in
and we actually do some sort of
interaction or response now it could be
manual or it can be met automated now
what the whole false-positive thing a
lot of organizations who want to put the
brakes on right so we can actually
provide it as a manual task for as a
part of the workflow next up it's around
orchestrating the remediation so for
example let's say have a vulnerability
and that vulnerability require let's say
you get a scan let's just talk about
this we'll say here - vulnerability scan
back from the Koala settle you know NVD
whatever it may be right and what you
want to do is that you want to take that
scan data ingest it in the service now
we start parsing it and it based on the
priority of the vulnerabilities based on
business services and things like that
what it'll do is it'll go out there
match up the IP addresses business
service and with the with whoever owns
it and then we'll send an email
automatically to the person and they ask
hey can we run a patch response comes
back ok we can run a patch execute or
orchestrate a patch manual or automated
however you want to do it the patch
executes because somebody an IT did it
manually or was automated comes back we
do a rescan automatically and it comes
back that those vulnerabilities god our
customers with respect to wanna cry
there really weren't any issues because
this was already first of all they were
already protected the moment the
majority of them the second thing is
that when it did come out and when it
was you know understood that this is
actually what's happening it was easily
fixed so let's look at all the
vulnerabilities create group once that
group is once we understand what these
vulnerabilities are in this group what
are the IP addresses execute the patch
we're done okay and then Marilyn talked
a little bit about that as well because
what AMT have done they want from 12
weeks of going through that whole
process that just explained down to a
week and you're going to get
down to a day okay finally final step
this is the best one
PIR it takes organizations agencies
weeks to X to actually put together a
PIR because of all the interactions
within the platform the workflows with
steps and the handoff of one thing or
one portion of the incident or
vulnerability that somebody else at
cetera every single interaction is
captured that means that at the end when
you have to actually close it out the
PIR is already created but if you
actually want to get feedback from
everybody was on that team guess what
happens we can automatically generate a
survey to all the people who are on
deliver a response with specific
questions directed towards them we get
that information back and make it a part
of the PIR even further when it is
closed out that PIR what we'll do is
we'll put create a knowledgebase article
and it'll be a core part of the platform
so the next time an incident like this
comes up you reference the knowledge
article and by the way it has all that
information in there so you guys are
familiar Potanin 271 days identifying
container brakes I'm sure you guys are
hearing about this all the time what we
did is that we actually surveyed our 200
customers and we figured it so illnesses
but everyone knows it's as ridiculous
right 200 201 days but you know that's
what they say
201 days industry average 4824 hours you
how many hours our customer it took for
our it takes for our cars customers
identify 29 hours 70 days of contain one
thousand six hundred eighty hours 33
hours this from our customers and the
reason is it's pure and simple we ought
to be just because we do what we do we
what we do really well we automate we
assigned tasks we manage those tasks and
integrate with the existing platforms
that an organization's invested in and
so we've come up with some fantastic
results 160 times improvement 50x to
prove just cut that okay let's forget
the Pawnee money numbers let's just cut
that in half cut it in the quarter it's
Valley I mean what we're doing we're
customers right now is valuable right so
for example this is a slide that MP and
also KPMG put together
three things I want you to focus on this
slide first one six weeks to implement
vulnerability response and security
instrument response and also threat
intelligence number to see at 60% 60%
reduction and vulnerability response
time 60 percent reduction right below it
30% reduction in security incident
response time this is this is a pretty
large organization here in Australia
they're leveraging it and getting a ton
of value with that I'm going to pass it
over to Marilyn no she's going to talk
about Kyle yes so Bryan great job on
setting up what what the secure the
ServiceNow Security Operations
application within the ServiceNow
platform can really do for organizations
but let's take that the next step and
look at some practical application you
know it's great to hear about that what
the platform can do but this is what we
with iymp KPMG and ServiceNow it was the
perfect trifecta coming together to
really get these results so really what
drove iymp to this to wanting to put in
service now
KPMG had just implemented their incident
problem change CMDB service catalog
service request fulfillment on the
ServiceNow platform so the head of cyber
security came to the security came to
the KPMG team and said we hear that
there's a security operations component
of ServiceNow can you talk to us a
little bit about it and tell us how we
can leverage what you've already done we
already know the CMDB is there we
already know that we have incident
management so how can we use the
platform to extend the capability and
really use what's already been built
so when KPMG was implementing the CMDB
for a MP what we did is knowing kind of
the roadmap because we had helped them
with their strategy as well knowing what
their roadmap was around the GRC around
security operations around some IT
finance transformations that they were
wanting to do all on the ServiceNow
platform when we built the CMDB we put a
couple of components in so that they
were already light years ahead of where
maybe other organizations are in their
CMDB we put the business criticality on
each of their applique
we also the underlying support systems
the servers that supported those
business critical applications we put
business criticality on there and what
that did was that allowed us to come in
and when we did security operations now
is to put qualifiers on when an incident
when a security incident came in or a
threat was identified or detected or a
vulnerability was exposed through fire I
or some of their other scanning systems
it ingested into ServiceNow platform and
they could absolutely determine from all
of the noise as Brian said what what
they needed to respond to quickly and
then that kicked off a major incident or
the security incident response from that
perspective so really what we did is we
wanted to look at helping InP understand
how to prevent security incidents from
within their organization there are
large financial services organization
there they have a banking component as
well here in Australia so they they
didn't want to be a target obviously
they are a target so the first thing was
helping them to prevent also they wanted
to be able to improve how they were
tracking security incidents how they
were closing them out how they were
responding going four months two weeks
two hours was with the key objective
also detecting identifying those those
security incidents understanding what
the threats were that we're coming in
bombarding as you can imagine as all of
you are experiencing the threats and the
vulnerabilities they're coming in and
exposing your organization to a cyber
security attack and then as Brian said
using the ServiceNow platform to be able
to respond to these in an expeditious
manner so that they could they could
identify and and prevent mitigate or
eliminate those those responses those
security incident responses all right so
really what we did is we looked at their
current process we looked at the current
ways of working if you will and we
determined that there were some gaps in
there these were the quick wins these
were what was going to take iymp from
zero to fully operational in the six
weeks
by understanding what those gaps were
understanding where the the improvements
could be made and really targeting those
specific areas while giving them the
whole entire capability on the
ServiceNow platform also roles and
responsibilities what was IT doing what
was the CMDB already doing how could
they leverage what was in the CMDB and
then who was doing that who had access
to security incidents who who was
mitigating them how were they
communicating back to IT from when a
change needed to be implemented to
implement that patch or two to shut down
a server if there was a vulnerability or
a threat that was discovered on that the
two tooling in automation there was
absolutely zero automation at iymp with
how they responded to the security
incidents prior to going live on the
ServiceNow platform and then also the
the service level gaps months as we said
down to weeks those service levels they
am he felt that those were not actually
viable service levels months to mitigate
a risk and that was actually putting AMD
at a risk obviously as most of you all
are if you're taking months to respond
to security incidents what was the role
of ServiceNow in this so the automation
part putting in the workflow that comes
out of the box with the ServiceNow
application and platform hooking
together the IT incident response along
with the security incident response so
if there is a incident that happens or a
security incident that happens it's
automatically creates a ServiceNow
security incident there's linkage
between IT and security operations can
now communicate it also linked into the
change management application where it
could automatically generate a request
for change to put in that patch to
mitigate that risk on so automation
automation automation automation is the
key and also visibility into what is
going on when you're working in
spreadsheets and emails and texts and
phone calls you don't really have that
visibility and ServiceNow provided
i MP with that visibility so how did we
do it in six weeks right it seems a
little bit crazy we had a kickoff on
week one we did the system design so
what does that mean
that's when we did that process gap
analysis we looked at their service
level agreements we looked at how they
were operating
what were their key priorities and so we
designed we did workshop to design out
what the system needed to do to that
then set the stage for what how do we
determine success then we went right
into the configuration of security
incident response for ability response
and we also did threat intelligence in
there as well we had in its Gration to
fire AI and necess so fire I we ingested
the the information the threats and
vulnerabilities that were coming in from
fire ID and then also necess with the
known vulnerabilities that is are coming
in so that integration took us from
about week three to week five people say
well you must have skipped testing to do
it in six weeks absolutely not I'm a
pretty big process freak
so SDLC back in the old day you know the
way of working we still did testing we
did about a week and a half of testing
it was a very small team so we were able
to execute testing within this time
frame and then at the end of hike at the
end of the six weeks we implemented we
were live and we actually were able to
those results that Ron showed just a few
minutes ago during this the hyper care
week is when we started to get the
analysis and really understand the
impact of what we had done over these
last six weeks had on ANP as an
organization one thing I like to add to
this as well so if you're familiar with
ServiceNow
we're a staff based platform right so
you don't go through the procurement
processes and things of that at getting
infrastructure and this also talks about
the security of the ServiceNow platform
- if a MP is allowing vulnerability data
and security incident data to be in the
cloud locally here in Australia then
there's something to be said about our
security alright and the other thing
with that run is the data centers are
here in Austria
so EMTs data never leaves the shores of
Australia it's all that all here and
within the ServiceNow application there
is unless you're on the security team
and you have it all based on roles
unless you have that role you don't even
know that the security incident
application exists so there's really
just an amazing amount of security
within the ServiceNow platform that
allows this critical data you have to
imagine the data that's coming into
service now and so the criticality and
the security wrapped around who can see
and who can do who can see the data and
who can do anything with that data
one thing that I'm sorry the one thing
to add to that with respect to this
curious I said it's a scoped app there's
a ring fence around it data at certain
pieces of data from vulnerabilities and
security instance can't be seen from
other people within the platform that's
that actually is that's actually quite
important yeah so all right and one of
the other things in in the configuration
we also built them eight Service Catalog
items so they had previously gone live
with the Service Catalog and how many of
you within your organization's if you
had a phishing email come in actually
know what to do with that I mean you're
all security folks - right you know but
if I was talking to a group of just
normal users out there in your
organization's I just got at KPMG I just
got a phishing email asking for all
kinds of information and I went what do
I even do with this I don't even know
who to send it to I don't know
clearly I don't want to open it and
click on the links I have enough smarts
not to do that but think of the other
folks that haven't been in black ops for
the last 30 years that would just start
clicking through my dad for example
right so so we built them on top of
their Service Catalog we put in a secure
IT security incident catalog items so if
they get a phishing email they can
attach the email to a Service Catalog
request send it off it goes right to the
security incident team they have the
email they have the data they have who
it came from who it came to when it was
sent and they can start doing that
investigation right away
to make sure that they don't have any
kind of in the last session that worms
or any kind of malware that's released
through emails or phishing attack
another another example of course is how
many developers you have in your
organization just want to run a
vulnerability scan on the on the I'm
basically the service that they're going
to actually start creating that with
it's so private service catalog you
click on the link put in the IP range
and then because of the integrations we
have with koalas in tenable and other
folks like that it'll execute that
vulnerability scan and the result will
come back and basically the developers
on his way or her way absolutely and
we're actually doing that at AMD right
now we're on a Phase two of security
operations and that's actually one of
the components that we're doing for them
to be able to do that yeah okay so
really just we've kind of touched on
this but just sixty response sixty
percent response and vulnerability
response time months two minutes so
three months they've gotten down to one
day and they do want to take that down
to even minutes to be able to do that
and again that comes with more
automation you're learning more may be
integrations we're doing an integration
to Qualis next and then three times
faster security incident response comes
in they know about it there's workflow
behind it the right people are notified
the right people are able to immediately
react and respond to the security
incidents that are taking place and then
the top takeaways documented processes
are really important so if you don't
have your security operations processes
documented I would definitely say that
is the starting point to be able to get
your operations up and running it also
identifies gaps and it helps if you have
a partner come in an implementation
partner they can then help you
understand where you are and where the
potential opportunities are for making
things operate a little more efficiently
your CMDB it is absolutely a critical
component but if you have as Brian said
a shitty CMDB it's alright what has
happened is with a MP a MP is actually
implementing and updating the CMDB
because of security incident response
and security incidents is coming in so
they're actually enhancing
CMDB through security operations out of
the cyber security team that's something
you don't hear about quite off which is
a benefit of course I - absolutely and
then start with the basics don't try to
bowl the ocean don't try and solve world
hunger all at once understand from the
processes what are you trying to resolve
go in and do it incrementally because
you get those incremental values you get
the incremental benefits and still are
enhancing the capabilities within your
organization ok with that we thank you
very much and if you want any more
additional information come by for a
demonstration
we're located all the way at the other
end over the main wall you know where
the main ballroom is basically we're
right outside the may involve all the
way to you and we love to have a
conversation with you give you a
demonstration so thank you very much
appreciated we've got a couple minutes
of questions if thumb anybody has any
I've got one quick question yeah you
said that the platform was scoped f what
are the boundaries in terms of data
boundaries and also entire segregation
between different clients oh that some
of the scope that well first of all
which if you have an instance of service
now you're separated from everybody
everybody else other organizations the
other thing is that with a date with the
datum there's a actual data model that's
separate from the actual main data model
within within a service mount platform
so the separate tables that are
associated it's a plus segregation do
you mean the front end components that
each large client uses on an entirely
different virtual infrastructure or is
it within the same can pump up part of
the platform it's a set it's a part of
the same platform ok any other questions
thank you all for your time I appreciate
it thank you ticker
on behalf but I just like to run Thank
You speakers thank you don't forget to
rate this some presentation through the
conference app and enjoy lunch the next
session starts at UM or the 120